<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:17:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Person Found Decapitated in France Terror Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/terrorist-attack-reported-france-factory-dead/story?id=32044062</Link>
        <Description>One person was found decapitated and two others were injured following an apparent terrorist attack at a factory in France, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Charlie Hebdo's New Issue Sells Out Around Paris
The factory is owned by Air Products &amp; Chemicals, a Pennsylvania-based company. The company released a statement following todays attack.
"We can confirm that an incident occurred at our facility in L'Isle-d'Abeau, France this morning. Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for, the company said. Emergency services are on site and have contained the situation. The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities. Further information will be released as soon as it becomes available."
At least 17 people have been killed in terror-related violence in France this year. In January, gunmen attacked the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo . The men suspected in that attack were later killed in raids at a Kosher supermarket and print shop.
Get real-time updates as this story unfolds. To start, just "star" this story in ABC News' phone app. Download ABC News for iPhone here or ABC News for Android here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:57:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Investigation Into Apparent Terrorist Attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/apparent-terrorist-attack-france-factory-32045039</Link>
        <Description>The attack happened at a U.S.-owned facility in southern France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Apparent Terrorist Attack at France Factory
+

French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Julien Reunaud/APS-Medias/Sipa USA/AP Photo
French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Julien Reunaud/APS-Medias/Sipa USA/AP Photo
French President Francois Hollande speaks during a media conference at an EU summit in Brussels, June 26, 2015.
Geert Vanden Wijngaert/AP Photo
French security stand next to the enclosed area near the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmaze/AFP/Getty Images
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:43:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sochi Inundated by Flooding After Torrential Rains</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/sochi-russia-inundated-flooding-months-rain-falls-day/story?id=32032427</Link>
        <Description>The Olympic city of Sochi was inundated with flood waters after torrential rains.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sochi, Russia Inundated by Flooding After More Than a Month's Rain Falls in a Day
Moscow  Jun 25, 2015, 4:39 PM ET
By PATRICK REEVELL
Sochi, Russia on the Black Sea.
Getty Images
Heavy rains have flooded Sochi, the Russian city that hosted the 2014 Winter Olympics , leaving one dead and some areas under several feet of water, according to officials and reports. It is also forcing authorities to consider an evacuation, the mayor's office said.
More than a month and a halfs rain -- 100 mm, or about 4 inches -- fell in 24 hours on the seaside city, according to the Russian news agency RIA Novosti. Despite now being best-known for the Winter Olympics, the city is a popular summer resort for Russians, squeezed between the Caucasus mountains and the Black Sea .
According to the AP, a man was found dead during salvage operations Thursday. No further details were immediately available.
Sochi Airport! Hot, cool, yours! https://t.co/5FG1eo0K7b pic.twitter.com/M1b6z8aGMd
 Maria Antonova (@mashant) June 25, 2015
Pictures on social media showed Sochis airport, refurbished for the Olympics, filled with brown water, with passengers standing next to baggage carousels up to their ankles. The citys mayor has told residents to prepare for a possible evacuation and to remain indoors, warning that water spouts could form offshore.
????? ?? ????????? ????????? #???? #???????????
A video posted by @shpakovev on Jun 25, 2015 at 3:36am PDT
Sochi and its Olympic reconstruction is one of Vladimir Putin s prized achievements, with a colossal $50 billion spent on transforming the city. So far most of the sports facilities built for the Olympics have reportedly been undamaged by the floods, according to Russian media, with most of the flooding confined to residential areas.
#????? #?????? #?????????? #????#?????#????? #????????? #?????
A photo posted by alesya1502 (@alesya1502) on Jun 25, 2015 at 5:26am PDT
#????? #???? #?????????? #?????#?????? #????? #????? #?????????
A photo posted by alesya1502 (@alesya1502) on Jun 25, 2015 at 5:25am PDT
????, ????? ????????? ????#????#?????#????#?????????
A video posted by ??????? (@hibushkaaa) on Jun 25, 2015 at 3:30am PDT
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32032427.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:43:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UberPop Banned After Taxi Driver Protests Turn Ugly</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/uberpop-banned-paris-amid-taxi-driver-protests-airports/story?id=32017565</Link>
        <Description>Paris officials announced a ban on UberPop after about 2,800 taxi drivers staged a strike across France today in  protest of the  ride-hailing app.</Description>
        <MainBody>UberPop Banned in Paris Amid Taxi Driver Protests at Airports
PARIS  Jun 25, 2015, 3:39 PM ET
By HUGO LEENHARDT via Good Morning America
Taxi drivers on strike burn tires during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Marseille, France, June 25, 2015.
Jean-Paul Pelissier/Reuters
Paris officials announced a ban on UberPop after about 2,800 taxi drivers staged a strike across France today in protest of the ride-hailing app that resulted in numerous arrests and injured cops.
The taxi drivers briefly blocking access to airports and forced passengers to finish the journey by foot.
Some drivers vandalized several Uber cars, even flipping some over, and riot police were forced to intervene, arresting three taxi cab drivers, according to police officials.
Charles Platiau/Reuters
PHOTO: French taxi drivers, who are on strike, block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, June 25, 2015.
How Uber Helped a Recent Grad in Texas Plan an Epic Marriage Proposal
The demonstration was organized to protest against UberPop, the service that connects customers to drivers without professional taxi or chauffeur licenses. These drivers use their private vehicles to pick up clients, and UberPop is usually a second job for them.
Prices for the UberPop version of the Uber app are generally 30 to 50 percent cheaper than cab fares and drivers pay far less taxes.
The UberPop service had already been deemed illegal by the French government that accuses it of unfair competition, though the Uber app has not been officially banned. And today's action does not mean UberPop, and other services like it, will disappear but that police can arrest drivers in Paris and its suburbs using it, and also fine clients. But the thinking is that it will be difficult to enforce.
Michel Euler/AP Photo
PHOTO: Taxis gather at a major entrance of Paris, June 25, 2015, in Paris.
Thibaud Simphal, director of Uber France, said on French TV BFM Business that the company will challenge the "prefectoral order." "We will challenge it and see what comes out of the appeal, Uberpop can continue," Simphal said.
In the middle of the strike today, customers were taken hostage by the conflict. Musician Courtney Love , on her way to Paris from the airport, tweeted: they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
The Interior minister announced that 10 people had been arrested and seven police officers injured, in addition to the 70 cars vandalized during the day.
One of them appears to be shown in this YouTube video where a man on an overpass sends a rock crashing down on the windshield at Porte Maillot on the west side of Paris, where taxi drivers were demonstrating all day.
Also, an Uber car transporting a couple and its baby was hit by a rock on the way to the airport, breaking the rear window. "It was very scary," the passenger told French TV station iTele , but no one was injured.
Uber had warned earlier in the day that "demand will be very high today and the service could be disturbed. Good luck to all."
At Orly airport, an Uber driver reportedly ran over a cabbie who was blocking off his car, injuring him. He has been taken into custody.
Reacting to the clashes, Prime Minister Manuel Valls "condems with great severity" this "unacceptable" violence regarding today's events, he said.
Michel Euler/AP Photo
PHOTO: Striking taxi drivers stand behind an overthrown car during a taxi drivers demonstration, June 25, 2015, in Paris.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32017565.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:54:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mom and Baby Survived 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/mother-baby-rescued-surviving-days-colombian-jungle-plane/story?id=32028463</Link>
        <Description>Marie Nelly Murillo and her baby were rescued after they spent almost days stranded in the middle of a jungle following a small plane crash, the Colombia Air Force said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother and Baby Rescued After Surviving 5 Days in Colombian Jungle Following Plane Crash
Jun 25, 2015, 2:44 PM ET
The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
fac.mil.co
Copy
An 18-year-old woman and her baby miraculously survived a small plane crash in the Colombian jungle and then survived five days on coconut water before rescuers finally located them, according to officials and reports.
Colombian airmen and disaster relief agency workers discovered the mother, Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son Wednesday after five days of search and rescue efforts that immediately began when their plane was reported missing Saturday, the Colombian Air Force said today in a statement.
"It's a miracle. It is a very wild area and it was a catastrophic accident," Colombian Air Force Col. Hector Carrascal told the BBC. He added the mother's spirit must have given the baby "the strength to survive."
Nepal Earthquake: Teen Rescued After 5 Days Trapped in Rubble
Murillo, 18, suffered injuries and minor burns, but the baby was apparently unharmed, the Air Force said. They were flown in a helicopter to a hospital in Quibdo, Colombia .
The pilot of the small plane, a Cessna 303, was discovered dead on Monday before the mother and her baby were found, according to the Air Force. It was not clear what the relationship between the woman and baby and the pilot was or why they were on the plane.
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
Murillo, 18, and her son were passengers in the small plane, which was carrying fish and coconuts from the town of Nuqui to Quibdo, the the BBC reported .
A trail of clues including coconut shells discovered near the plane site and a discarded flip-flop in the jungle gave the rescue teams hope during the nearly week-long search that ended Wednesday, the BBC added.
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
Murillo wandered in the jungle carrying her child, surviving on coconut water and trying unsuccessfully to trap rodents for food, Red Cross volunteer Acisclo Renteria told The Associated Press (AP).
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
The 38-year-old rescuer said he saw the success as a blessing, the AP added.
"I thanked my little God for allowing me to save these two people," Renteria, who has been asked by Murillo to be her son's godfather, told the AP. "One thing is telling you on the phone what we experienced but it's quite another is to have lived it."
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32028463.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:24:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi F-16 Fighter Jet Crashes in Arizona</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/iraqi-16-fighter-jet-crashes-arizona-training-mission/story?id=32024137</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi pilots are being training in the U.S. to combat ISIS, officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
The F-16 fighter jet that crashed in Arizona overnight was actually owned by the Iraqi Air Force and flown by an Iraqi pilot, a U.S. Air Force official confirmed to ABC News today.
Local law enforcement has been on the scene since the crash last night near Douglas, Arizona, but Air Force officials have yet to confirmed the identity of the pilot, who they say is an Iraqi trainee. The crash caused a large grass fire and its likely the pilot did not survive, authorities said.
Officially, the Air Force is saying only that the pilots status is unknown.
Mamta Popat/The Tucson Citizen/AP
PHOTO: Smoke rises Thursday, June 25, 2015, from the site where an F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed Wednesday evening near Douglas, Ariz.
The Iraqi military is involved in a program to train Iraqi Air Force pilots in the United States before it receives the jets in Iraq. The first two of 36 jets purchased by the Iraqi government arrived at the Tucson International Airport, Arizona this December, where Iraqi pilots are training, officials said.
The F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed during a training mission at about 8 p.m. on Wednesday near Douglas, Arizona, with one person on board, the 162nd Wing of the Arizona Air National Guard said in statement.
Mamta Popat/The Tucson Citizen/AP
PHOTO: Cochise County Sheriff blocks the road on June 25, 2015, miles away from the site where an F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed near Douglas, Ariz.
The 162nd in responsible for the international training mission, which the Iraqis are depending on to combat the militant group ISIS .
Iraq has received a total of 12 brand new F-16s, all of which are currently in the U.S. The first delivery of the jets to Iraq is expected this summer.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32024137.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:40:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Space Shuttles Captured in Abandoned Hangar</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/captivating-photographs-document-soviet-space-shuttles-abandoned-kazakhstan-32001246</Link>
        <Description>Photographer documents two abandoned Soviet space shuttles.  </Description>
        <MainBody>Captivating Photographs Document Soviet Space Shuttles Abandoned in Kazakhstan
+

Russian photographer, Ralph Mirebs, traveled to Baikonur, Kazakhstan to document an abandoned hangar that resides in Kazakhstan. Inside the hangar, which has been inoperative for the last 20 years, remain two Soviet Space shuttle prototypes in decaying conditions. An aerial view of the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan is pictured.
Ralph Mirebs
Russian photographer, Ralph Mirebs, traveled to Baikonur, Kazakhstan to document an abandoned hangar that resides in Kazakhstan. Inside the hangar, which has been inoperative for the last 20 years, remain two Soviet Space shuttle prototypes in decaying conditions. An aerial view of the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan is pictured.
Ralph Mirebs
The abandoned hangar is left from the discontinued Soviet/ Russian Buran space program that was discontinued in 1993. A view of the engine from one of the shuttles found in the hangar .
Ralph Mirebs
A view inside the cargo hold
Ralph Mirebs
A prototype shuttle that was left in the abandoned hangar in Baikonur, Kazakhstan
Ralph Mirebs
A view of the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan.
Ralph Mirebs
A view inside the cockpit of one of the prototype shuttles.
Ralph Mirebs
A test model is seen in the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan.
Ralph Mirebs
The two space shuttles found in the hangar are in bad condition -- parts of their thermal protective tiles have fallen off, windows are broken and the equipment is inoperable.
Ralph Mirebs
A view inside the cockpit of one of the prototype shuttles.
Ralph Mirebs
Exterior view of an abandoned hangar in Baikonur, Kazakhstan.
Ralph Mirebs
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:26:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China Debuts Newborn Panda Twins</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/china-debuts-newborn-panda-twins/story?id=31994921</Link>
        <Description>The twin pandas born through artificial insemination </Description>
        <MainBody>China Debuts Its Newborn Panda Twins
Jun 24, 2015, 12:26 PM ET
ABC NEWS via Good Morning America
Newborn twin female panda cubs are seen inside an incubator at the Giant Panda Research Base in Chengdu, China, June 22, 2015.
China Daily/Reuters
Visitors to a panda breeding center in China got the first, up-close view of twin pandas born just one day earlier.
The pandas were born Monday at the Chengdu Research Base of Giant Panda Breeding to their mother, 7-year-old Kelin, the Associated Press reported .
The cubs were conceived through artificial insemination, part of Chinas effort to increase the panda population. The twins mother was artificially inseminated in January, according to the AP.
China Daily /Reuters
PHOTO: A researcher feeds one of the newborn twin female panda cubs inside an incubator at the Giant Panda Research Base in Chengdu, China, June 22, 2015.
The chief administrator at Chengdu said the twins were born in good condition based on their body temperature and milk consumption.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31994921.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:59:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How the US Trains Wounded Warriors to Hunt Child Predators</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/us-government-trains-wounded-warriors-hunt-child-predators/story?id=31942508</Link>
        <Description>Soldiers have found a new way to serve their country. </Description>
        <MainBody>How the US Government Is Training Wounded Warriors to Hunt Child Predators
Jun 24, 2015, 10:43 AM ET
Sgt. Justin Gaertner, who lost both legs in Afghanistan, stands with his service dog Gunner.
Courtesy DHS and Justin Gaertner
Marine Sgt. Justin Gaertner lost both his legs in a roadside bomb explosion while serving in the Helmand province of Afghanistan on November 26, 2010. No longer able to serve his country in the U.S. military, Justin now has a new mission: Bringing to justice child sexual predators.
He took a risk and signed up for a year-long pilot program run by the Department of Homeland Security , called HERO Corps, where he and other wounded or ill warriors are being trained in the computer forensics needed to track and trap criminals involved in child exploitation.
In an interview with ABC News, Gaertner acknowledged it was a major adjustment, but said words cant really describe, how good it feels to put these guys behind bars. Its never ending ... [the] despicable things that people are doing to children."
EXCLUSIVE: Undercover DHS Tests Find Security Failures at US Airports
Last Friday, the Secretary of Homeland Security Jeh Johnson personally swore in the third class of 22 HERO Corps graduates.
In 2013, Gaernter graduated in the first HERO Corps class, also known as the Human Exploitation Rescue Operations Corps. The unit was created by the Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), a division of DHS with a long history of combating cross-border child exploitation and related cyber-crimes. The program was successful enough that it received permanent funding when the HERO Act was signed into law earlier this year.
Courtesy DHS and Justin Gaertner
PHOTO: The Homeland Security Investigations team executes a search warrant with local and federal law enforcement.
The demand for jobs like Gaertner's with Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) is astounding. Last year, ICE seized more than 5.2 million gigabytes of data related to child exploitation cases and arrested. That same year the HSI units arrested more than 2,300 child predators on criminal charges.
Justin accompanies special agents on search warrants, dissembling computers, running forensic software and scouring hard drives for illicit data that can be later used in court. He has participated first-hand in the arrest of hundreds of child predators. The raids he conducts are often done early in the morning to ensure the target it at home when it happens.
ABC News photo
PHOTO: Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, Jeh Johnson, stands with 22 graduates of the HERO Corps program at U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement headquarters in Washington D.C.
Earlier this year, Gaertner helped put away Benjamin Cuadrado for 80 years. The 40 year-old Florida man plead guilty to producing 70 sexually explicit videos of himself having sex with children who were ages two and younger.
In 2014, he helped in the conviction of Melvin Bridgers in a child sextortion case. Bridgers was found guilty of extorting 130 young girls over Facebook, using fake profiles to lure them into sending explicit photos of themselves and extorting them with those images for more sexually explicit material, threatening to share the images with their parents.
Courtesy DHS and Justin Gaertner
PHOTO: Sgt. Justin Gaertner with best friend Sgt. Gabriel Martinez, both of whom lost their legs fighting in Afghanistan.
These men and women have a natural desire to contribute, Johnson said at the recent graduation ceremony.
You want to rebuild, you want to get back into the fight. That strength and character is what we see reflected in the 22 graduates we have here today," he said.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31942508.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:59:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Huge Saw Blade Slices Truck but Not Driver  </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/huge-blade-slices-truck-driver/story?id=31970994</Link>
        <Description>A man in China is counting his lucky stars after a huge saw blade came crashing onto a highway and right into his car, and he survived. </Description>
        <MainBody>Huge Saw Blade Slices Truck but Not Driver
Jun 24, 2015, 9:01 AM ET
By CORINNE CATHCART via Good Morning America
A view of the accident site after a massive circular saw blade smashed into the front of a pickup truck on the Chongqing-Guizhou Expressway in Chongqing, China, June 17, 2015.
Imaginechina / Splash News
A man in China is counting his lucky stars after a huge saw blade came crashing onto a highway and right into his car, and he survived.
The man, identified only as Mr. Xiang, was driving on Chongqing-Guizhou Expressway in Central China when the blade of a giant circular saw blade fell of the back of a truck carrying equipment in a nearby lane, according to The Telegraph .
The blade flew into Mr. Xiang's car but he reportedly walked away unhurt. It lodged in the front of his truck as Xiang tried to keep control of the vehicle, according to the Telegraph.
"I heard a 'bang' and then I saw all the white smoke in front of me. I almost lost control of my car, Xiang told local reporters the day after the incident.
Police reportedly said that if Xiang had been driving faster or if the blade had hit at a slightly different angle, he could have been killed.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31970994.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen Kill at Least 7 in Tunisia Beach Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-gunmen-kill-tunisia-beach-attack-32046356</Link>
        <Description>THE LATEST: British tourist describes deadly Tunisia attack: 'we thought it was firecrackers'</Description>
        <MainBody>Gunmen Kill at Least 7 in Tunisia Beach Attack
TUNIS, Tunisia  Jun 26, 2015, 8:28 AM ET
By The Associated Press
The latest news from an attack on a beach resort in Tunisia (all times local):

Tunisian state television says the number of people killed in an attack on a tourist resort is now 19 after two gunmen opened fire on beachgoers.
There have been no details on the nationalities of those killed in the resourt of Sousse on Friday, but during the holy month of Ramadan , those on the beach tend to be tourists.
Interior Ministry spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said security forces intervened immediately and killed one of the attackers, the other fled the scene.

1:20 p.m.
A British tourist close to the scene of a deadly attack on a Tunisian beach resort has described his experiences.
Gary Pine said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he told Sky News. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
He said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms, and later to gather in the lobby.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach in the coastal resort of Sousse Friday, killing at least seven people.

1 p.m.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least seven people.
Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
Aroui said the death toll could rise.
Tunisia has been battered by attacks by militants, most recently in March when two Tunisians returning from Libya killed 22 people at the national museum.

-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046356.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Refugee Response Exposes Divisions, Meagre Ambitions</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/eu-leaders-agree-relocate-40000-migrants-32042300</Link>
        <Description>EU refugee deal exposes divisions, meagre ambitions, limits to solidarity with Greece, Italy</Description>
        <MainBody>EU Refugee Response Exposes Divisions, Meagre Ambitions
BRUSSELS  Jun 26, 2015, 8:16 AM ET
By LORNE COOK Associated Press
The European Union decided Friday to share 40,000 of the refugees landing in Italy and Greece but foot-dragging and verbal sniping over the move exposed deep divisions about how to deal with Europe's massive migrant influx.
While the size of the challenge is daunting, the EU's response has been underwhelming. More than 114,000 migrants fleeing wars or poverty have been plucked from the Mediterranean so far this year as they try to cross in unseaworthy smugglers' boats. Some 2,600 have died or are missing along the route, according to the International Organization for Migration.
"It is  to tell the disturbing truth  a very modest effort," European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker said Friday after EU leaders agreed at a summit to decide by late July on how to distribute the refugees.
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi agreed.
"It's not a big number," he said. "For Italy it's a small help, but there's still a lot of work to do."
Greece and Italy have been swamped by the arrivals, while Hungary and Bulgaria are also under pressure from thousands of migrants traveling over land. Things are likely to get worse amid the summer high season for migrant crossings.
Radical action is being taken around Europe in response. Hungary has pledged to build a fence to keep out the torrent of migrants crossing its border with Serbia. France and Italy have been at loggerheads over the movement of migrants along their common border. Police have dismantled migrant camps in northern France, from where people are hoping to cross into Britain.
Greece and Italy have been accused of not properly screening arrivals and allowing them to move deeper into the 28-nation EU.
In an effort to ease some of their burden, Juncker's team has tried to force northern EU countries to share the burden, but any notion of mandatory migrant quotas for each nation was rejected at the summit.
Belgian Prime Minister Charles Michel called Friday's decision "saddening and disappointing."
"There is a lack of ambition, a lack of will," he said. "It wasn't a sense of solidarity that dominated around that table."
With some 60 million refugees in the world, this effort from a wealthy, half-a-billion-strong bloc appears paltry when countries like Lebanon, Jordan and Turkey are hosting hundreds of thousands of people displaced by conflict.
Even the decision to share 40,000 Syrians and Eritreans arriving over the next two years  and a separate move to resettle 20,000 refugees from outside Europe  only came after an emotional appeal from Italy.
"If you don't agree with 40,000 refugees you don't deserve to be called Europe," Renzi was quoted as saying to the leaders as the debate dragged into the night.
"If this is your idea of Europe, you can keep it. Either there is solidarity or don't waste our time," he said, according to an EU diplomat, who asked not to be identified because the discussions were not public.
The emergency plan was launched in response to the deaths of hundreds of migrants in the Mediterranean earlier this year. At a hastily organized summit, ships, planes and other equipment were pledged to help rescue those trying to come. But as the media spotlight faded, so has the EU's commitment to its partners.
Ultimately, around a dozen EU nations oppose the obligatory quota plan. A further 12 that would support it want the method for sharing out the refugees reassessed.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:16:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS Claims Blast at Shiite Mosque in Kuwait's Capital</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bomb-strikes-shiite-mosque-kuwait-32044671</Link>
        <Description>IS claims blast Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers</Description>
        <MainBody>IS Claims Blast at Shiite Mosque in Kuwait's Capital
KUWAIT CITY  Jun 26, 2015, 8:23 AM ET
By HUSSAIN AL-QATARI Associated Press
The Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claims the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt.
The attack was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group calling itself the Najd Province, the same group that claimed responsibility for a pair of attacks on two Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32044671.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:16:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thailand Junta Cancels Human Rights Report Launch on Vietnam</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/thailand-cancels-rights-groups-report-launch-vietnam-32041944</Link>
        <Description>Thai junta forces rights group to cancel public launch of report on Vietnam's ethnic minority</Description>
        <MainBody>Thailand Junta Cancels Human Rights Report Launch on Vietnam
BANGKOK  Jun 26, 2015, 8:15 AM ET
By THANYARAT DOKSONE Associated Press
Thailand's military government on Friday forced a human rights group to cancel the public launch of its report on the Vietnamese government's persecution of an ethnic minority, saying it could affect national security and bilateral relations.
The report by the New York-based Human Rights Watch describes persecution of Montagnard Christians in Vietnam's Central Highlands, whose religious practices have been described by the government as "evil."
Thai police said in a statement Friday the scheduled event at the Foreign Correspondents Club of Thailand could "have an impact on the country's security or could affect the friendship and cooperation between Thailand and Vietnam."
It is the third event in one month that has been canceled at the venue. Two previous seminars involved topics about human rights situation in Thailand and the country's harsh law protecting its monarchy.
More than a dozen plainclothes and uniformed police officers were waiting outside the club, along with a police truck parked nearby. The club said it received a written order from police, issued on behalf of the ruling junta, to cancel the news conference where the report was to be launched.
The human rights report was available on the group's website. An electronic version was also sent to journalists by email.
The cancellation of the event is "very disappointing" and is "another affirmation that human rights organizations can no longer report, not only about situation in Thailand, but situations in neighboring countries in Southeast Asia," said Sunai Phasuk, Human Rights Watch's senior researcher in Asia.
"Thailand is now going to be known as the defender of human rights violators in (Southeast Asia), which added more damage to Thailand's already tarnished international reputation under the military rule," he added.
Thai authorities have cracked down on critics and dissents since the military seized power from a civilian government in last May's coup.
The Thailand section on Human Rights Watch's website was briefly blocked by the government.
In its report, Human Rights Watch called for the Vietnamese government to "end abusive policies and practices" that have forced hundreds of Montagnards to flee the country.
It said the Montagnards' beliefs and faith practices, such as De Ga Protestantism and Ha Mon Catholicism, are suppressed by the government on the grounds that they are not religions at all. It said the Montagnards have been subjected to intimidation, arbitrary arrests and mistreatment in custody.
There was no immediate response from the Vietnamese government on the report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32041944.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:12:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Russian PM Yevgeny Primakov Dies at 85</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/russian-pm-yevgeny-primakov-dies-85-32043554</Link>
        <Description>Yevgeny Primakov, former Russian premier, foreign minister dies at 85</Description>
        <MainBody>Former Russian PM Yevgeny Primakov Dies at 85
MOSCOW  Jun 26, 2015, 8:11 AM ET
By JIM HEINTZ Associated Press
Former Russian Prime Minister Yevgeny Primakov, whose career included desperate but unsuccessful diplomatic efforts to avert wars in Iraq and NATO's bombing of Yugoslavia, has died. He was 85.
President Vladimir Putin on Friday offered condolences to Primakov's family, Putin's spokesman Dmitry Peskov said. He added that the president saw Primakov as "a statesman, an academic and a politician who has left a very big heritage" and that he always wanted to hear Primakov's view on global issues.
The cause of death wasn't immediately known.
With his slow, rumbling speaking manner, hooded eyes and a face whose default expression was a sly smile, Primakov, a seasoned political scholar and Middle East expert, looked like the embodiment of an insider operative for a country full of opaque intrigues.
Primakov began his career on a classic Soviet path. Trained as an Orientalist, he worked as a journalist for a decade-and-a-half in the Middle East for Soviet radio and the Communist Party newspaper Pravda, positions widely seen to be covers for espionage work.
He later moved through an assortment of senior academic positions and joined the political scene in 1989, when he became chairman of one of the chambers of the Soviet parliament, helping spearhead Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev's political reforms.
As the international drumbeat for war against Iraq increased in 1990, Gorbachev sent Primakov as an envoy to Iraq, drawing on his deep knowledge of the Middle East. He was said by some to be the outsider whom Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein knew best and trusted the most.
Gorbachev in a statement praised Primakov for "defending the country's interests with both resolve and flexibility."
In 1991, Primakov was named head of Russia's foreign intelligence service and held the job for five years before becoming foreign minister. As Russia's top diplomat, he was regarded as a firm but pragmatic supporter of Russian interests as the country agonized over its loss of superpower status. He worked hard to dilute the United States' perceived unilateral dominance of world affairs.
After being appointed prime minister in 1998 following Russia's bruising financial crisis, Primakov tried to prevent the NATO air war against Yugoslavia over the Kosovo crisis. He was heading to the United States on official visit in March 1999 when he learned that Washington decided to launch the air raids, and ordered his pilots to turn the plane back while it was already halfway over the Atlantic, a bold move that helped bolster his popularity at home.
Primakov lost the premier's job in May 1999 while the NATO bombing campaign was still going on. By many accounts, President Boris Yeltsin feared Primakov's rising influence and popularity.
Primakov was widely seen as a top contender to succeed Yeltsin, but sensationalist criticism of him and his alleged poor health on television controlled by supporters of Putin deflated his aspirations. By the time Putin became acting president when Yeltsin stepped down in the closing hours of 1999, Primakov's chances of election had vanished.
Putin nonetheless continued to tap Primakov's expertise in tackling global crises. He made Primakov Russia's top envoy to Iraq to try to stave off the brewing war in 2003. Primakov also was among those who tried to mediate with Chechen terrorists who seized a Moscow theater and hundreds of hostages in 2002.
Primakov also continued to wield considerable influence as the chairman of the Chamber of Industry and Commerce, a Russian business advocacy group, a post he held from 2001 to 2011.
Primakov is survived by his wife, his daughter and grandchildren. Funeral arrangements were not immediately known.

Vladimir Isachenkov contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32043554.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading, Explosion at Factory in France; Suspects Captured</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/beheaded-attack-explosion-french-gas-factory-32044065</Link>
        <Description>France: Several in custody after attack on French gas factory leaves 1 beheaded, 2 wounded</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading, Explosion at Factory in France; Suspects Captured
SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France  Jun 26, 2015, 8:07 AM ET
By LORI HINNANT and LAURENT CIPRIANI Associated Press
An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande , speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack. He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo , a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32044065.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:04:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Journalist Jailed in Zimbabwe for Starting Newspaper</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/journalist-jailed-zimbabwe-starting-newspaper-32046319</Link>
        <Description>Zimbabwe jails journalist for starting newspaper without government permission</Description>
        <MainBody>Journalist Jailed in Zimbabwe for Starting Newspaper
HARARE, Zimbabwe  Jun 26, 2015, 8:03 AM ET
The attorney for a Zimbabwe journalist says his client was convicted of publishing a newspaper in a southern town without government permission and sentenced to eight months in prison.
Several newspapers and radio stations have already been closed under Zimbabwe's harsh media laws and dozens of journalists have been arrested over the past 15 years.
Defense lawyer Martin Mureri said his client Patrick Chitongo was only putting together a dummy version of the paper to apply for a license. They plan to appeal the conviction.
Although several privately owned newspapers are in circulation, the government is the largest media owner, running over a dozen national and community newspapers as well as enjoying television monopoly.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046319.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:01:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>With Nuke Talks in Final Stretch, Foreign Ministers Join In</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/nuke-talks-final-stretch-foreign-ministers-join-32046292</Link>
        <Description>With only days to June 30 target date for Iran nuclear deal, foreign ministers join in</Description>
        <MainBody>With Nuke Talks in Final Stretch, Foreign Ministers Join In
VIENNA  Jun 26, 2015, 8:00 AM ET
FILE - In this Saturday, Feb. 3, 2007 file photo, an Iranian technician works at the Uranium Conversion Facility just outside the city of Isfahan 255 miles (410 kilometers) south of the capital Tehran, Iran. State TV says the Guardian Council, Iran's... View Full Caption The Associated Press
FILE - In this Saturday, Feb. 3, 2007 file photo, an Iranian technician works at the Uranium Conversion Facility just outside the city of Isfahan 255 miles (410 kilometers) south of the capital Tehran, Iran. State TV says the Guardian Council, Iran's constitutional watchdog, ratified a bill Wednesday, June 24, 2015, banning access to military sites and scientists as Tehran and world powers approach a deadline for reaching a comprehensive nuclear deal. The bill would allow for international inspections of Iranian nuclear sites within the framework of the Nuclear Non-proliferation Treaty. (AP Photo/Vahid Salemi, File) Close The Associated Press
The foreign ministers of Iran , the United States and France are joining Iran nuclear talks, as they try to overcome disputes ahead of a June 30 target date for a deal.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius are expected to arrive in Vienna on Saturday. U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry is due to arrive just before midnight Friday according to their travel schedules.
Foreign ministers from Russia , China, Britain and Germany have not formally announced dates of arrival. But they are also expected to join over the next few days to try and bridge stubborn differences on the limits Tehran must accept on its nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046292.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:59:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Interior Ministry: Gunmen Kill at Least 7 People in Attack on 2 Hotels on Tunisian Coast</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/interior-ministry-gunmen-kill-people-attack-hotels-tunisa-32046191</Link>
        <Description>Interior Ministry: Gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 hotels on Tunisian coast</Description>
        <MainBody>Interior Ministry: Gunmen Kill at Least 7 People in Attack on 2 Hotels on Tunisian Coast
TUNIS, Tunisia  Jun 26, 2015, 7:59 AM ET
Interior Ministry: Gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 hotels on Tunisian coast.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046191.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:47:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/scotus-rules-favor-aca-foods-overcharging-customers-french-32035096</Link>
        <Description>The Supreme Court rules in favor of Affordable Care Act; Whole Foods found to be overcharging customers by exaggerating weight; French Alpine paraglider lands inside a moving cable car.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Because of this law and because of today's decision to millions of Americans. Who I hear from every single day we'll continue to receive the tax credits. We have given about eight in ten people who buy insurance on the new marketplace Schwartz of the health care plan would cost less than a hundred dollars a month. Arraignment today renewed our prisons are now taking charges tied to Shawshank style break out a written update. Officials saying corrections officer Jean Pollard admitted to passing then my backpack. To date context. Even gave him special classes as areas of the president. Never knew there GI. Where officials are banning over and similar services in an around Paris. That comes after protesters from angry taxi driver and got ugly throwing eggs at cars he. And blocking off access to the airport many writers. Forced to walk to catch their flights. Taxi drivers upset because over drivers don't have to pay the same taxes. Are to compete with Hoover's prices up. Murphy store chain whole foods with stores in 42 state. Under scrutiny after New York consumer affairs says there investigators from around the worst case of grocery mislabeling. They've ever seen investigator citing he's examples of a package of chicken tenders overpriced by nearly five dollars. His vegetable platter six dollars more than it should be credible. Video a couple of guys jump off a mountain in France terror gliding toward that cable car right there one of them flies. Way forward. Right inside. His buddies catch in the ovals all back up but they grab and I can save you had some experience that if there are easier ways let's get to write it. I doubt they are a number of up to the screen door and watch the cat has she leaves airing out the big that they are so shocking that this package falls off the porch. Maginnis has your head is usually it's scary cat but she hasn't seen their sins. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Millionaire Funds Rescue Missions to Save Migrants: Part 1
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32035096,"title":"SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car","duration":"2:10","description":"The Supreme Court rules in favor of Affordable Care Act; Whole Foods found to be overcharging customers by exaggerating weight; French Alpine paraglider lands inside a moving cable car.","url":"/International/video/scotus-rules-favor-aca-foods-overcharging-customers-french-32035096","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mother-baby-survive-days-jungle-plane-crash-32031301</Link>
        <Description>Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Also there and get a mother at a baby rescued days after their small plane goes down and a jungle the air force swooping in to help the to the crash happening over the weekend in Colombia. And search crews springing into action the first survey first found the body of the product and yesterday the mother and child were spotted. The mother had just minor injuries the baby fortunately was not hurt.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32031301,"title":"Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash","duration":"0:21","description":"Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.","url":"/International/video/mother-baby-survive-days-jungle-plane-crash-32031301","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:27:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bomber-apologizes-court-funeral-proceedings-begin-sc-32007812</Link>
        <Description>Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev speaks in court during sentencing; Funeral proceedings begin for victims of South Carolina shootings; Governor Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Boston Marathon bomber killed Arthur Bryant spoke in court for the first time today it is we'll send. I think he stated he was sorry for the irreparable damage that he costs and all of the suffering. That he caused and he left no doubt about his guilt I didn't do it's our night instead hold. Bad. His words were genuine. They were heart cells. And I hope that they were as honest as the statements that you received were from victims' survivors. Reaffirmed. The United States government. Make concessions for just. Cost us. I from the celebrated pastor and state senator being honored as the remains of the reverend Clementi asking me lying in proposing Columbia. A horse drawn carriage carrying the coffin to the steps of the state house there a public viewing taking place throughout the afternoon. And on Friday president Obama's scheduled to deliver the eulogy the lakes states. Hundreds of camps are second homes throughout the area. Continue to check these camps and secure them. We're out of time law enforcement officials in upstate New York giving an update on their church or she would date killers. Describing the rugged terrain surrounding a hunting camp where those men are last believed to beats. Another Republican throwing his hat into the presidential ring today the big announcement from Louisiana governor Bobby Jindal. Making him the thirteenth major GOP yeah. I'm conservative governance shrinking the size of government. Smart management this is this is the details and it's been a guy who's worked in the Health and Human Services Department served in congress briefly and has an idea driven governor. Management leadership those are the qualities will talk about. Finally a lot of people love going to outdoor festival during the summer the one drawback. Port of bodies except of course if you report a body has looked at this point. I mariachi band inside. I they had. That's infineon and let's mariachi band marching out of the port of hiding and that they don't have a whole lot marching bands that part. The looks on people's faces apple. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32007812,"title":"Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid","duration":"2:17","description":"Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev speaks in court during sentencing; Funeral proceedings begin for victims of South Carolina shootings; Governor Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid.","url":"/International/video/boston-bomber-apologizes-court-funeral-proceedings-begin-sc-32007812","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:24:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy,  Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Tsarnaev: 'Sorry for the Lives I Have Taken'
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32006748,"title":"Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms","duration":"0:42","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.","url":"/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 01:02:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/anti-confederate-flag-protest-columbia-sc-tornado-cleanup-31979425</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.23.15</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Tom Brady 'Deflategate' Appeal
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31979425,"title":"Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension","duration":"0:40","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.23.15","url":"/International/video/anti-confederate-flag-protest-columbia-sc-tornado-cleanup-31979425","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 22:13:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/giant-basking-shark-caught-australia-31974124</Link>
        <Description>The shark, just under 21 feet long, was caught off the west coast of Victoria, Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31974124,"title":"Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia","duration":"1:44","description":"The shark, just under 21 feet long, was caught off the west coast of Victoria, Australia.","url":"/International/video/giant-basking-shark-caught-australia-31974124","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 00:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176</Link>
        <Description>Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
And yeah. In New York fertility aid killer on the rise DNA evidence found at a campground where they are hiding out positively link Richard Matt and David sweat or we don't know obviously is how old you. An idea that they lived. In the way it's supposed to escape that jeers realist it's time to minutes to plant in the capital. South Carolina governor Eliot and pound cake along for support line. I stayed out. It's not just a matter. Did not being polite to stray. And public and that's not good measure of whether racism still exists or continent. President was discussing racism with the comedian mark Merritt for his WTF podcast and he was making a point about how our political record. And talents in this country scenes whitewashed fact that. The reasons why that we're being used in the first place has somehow been scrubbed clean because we start seeing that word pop. A grim discovery on a mountain in New Mexico searchers have located the body of the former White House chef Walter shine in a river near a trail where he'd gone hiking more than a week ago that shot but who cook for about the clintons and bushes had just recently moved. Two New Mexico. Forty million Americans in the capital dangerous storms including. Possible tornadoes target in Chicago and Detroit while much of the south is under water. I think there are busy in Southern California he wondered in the shade in the backyard for bed and Johnson won't happen cooling off we'll present them. We'll.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Update on Escaped Prisoners
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31951176,"title":"Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'","duration":"1:43","description":"Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.","url":"/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 23:20:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165</Link>
        <Description>Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Zero. That's emergency landing knees and that bully and Bloomberg. There. Oh. Now. I hope what. And running in regard him running new wave group. You know addicted to video now Mike is a quick. I.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: 10 Ducklings Rescued From Storm Drain
Now Playing: Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Now Playing: Coast Guard Rescues Endangered Turtle
Now Playing: Police Release Surveillance Video in Maryland Graffiti Spree
Now Playing: Eight-Foot Gator Makes Trapper Feel the Miami Heat
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Moment Homeless Man Attacks Teen in Target
Now Playing: Restaurant Employees Take Down Man Accused of Bomb Threat
Now Playing: Man's Rescue From Sinking Truck Caught on Tape
Now Playing: NY Toddler Survives Being Hit By Out-Of-Control Car
Now Playing: Dozens Push Double-Decker Bus Off Trapped Cyclist
Now Playing: Boaters' Frightful Near-Collision With Airplane Caught on Video
Now Playing: Man Crashes SUV Into Store to Steal Beer
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Mount Everest Avalanche
Now Playing: Train Plummets Off Tracks in Dramatic Video
Now Playing: Man's 'Crazy' Encounter With Tornado Caught on Video
Now Playing: Nanny Cam Captures Powerful Home Boiler Explosion
Now Playing: Girl Attacked at McDonald's Caught on Video
Now Playing: Store Clerk Fights Off, Shoots Robber
Now Playing: Pilots Escape Mid-Air Collision at Air Show
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31948165,"title":"Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead","duration":"0:45","description":"Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.","url":"/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 19:06:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/international-hotspot-explosion-rocks-afghanistan-parliament-31942098</Link>
        <Description>Taliban launches bold attack against lawmakers in Kabul. Security forces kill seven gunmen.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
I've let alone and I'm. It is and the terrifying moment a suicide bomber in a car blew himself up outside the Afghan parliament today. Lawmakers screaming and running for cover right now. Hot spot Kabul Afghanistan. Hello. We are it's how about took credit for the attack came hours after the militant groups he's controlled the second district in the northern part of Afghanistan. BB BBC's David line isn't cobbled with the latest. This was how the bomb fell inside the Afghan parliament. If that panics at the speaker of the writings he Brahimi. Members of parliament and officials try to find their way out and there was pandemonium in the surrounding corridors. Windows at the back of parliament with shafted in the last. Full tree when they heard sounds of gunfire coming from the other side of the building. And this was the scene outside in the road a line of can't set alight by the huge explosion. Newly trained Afghan special forces quickly arrived to take up position. The Taliban gunmen were repulsed by police in the parliament and sought refuge in a building under construction. You can see puffs of concrete chipped away it's the police attacked positions. Firing when tone for about an hour into all the gunmen were killed. As the clearing up when tone the questions were beginning as to how the Taliban go this close to a century of Afghan power. They said they carried out the attack on the day that the new defense minister was to be introduced in parliament. A passing taxi was damaged. Its drive at two of them leaders said his hand was singed by the explosion. With two passengers were injured. And outside this is the crater of the poem he blew open the seats of Afghan democracy and a reminder of the Taliban's continuing ability to disrupt this country. This Kabul attack and Taliban and balances in Helmand in the southwest. And elsewhere in the country. Put pressure on Afghan government forces just at a time when peace talks between the Taliban and the government built mold possible and for many years. David going BBC news Kabul. And you can keep up with this story in real time by downloading the ABC news that had started this story for exclusive updates ago. Anti Hernandez a New York you've been watching the international hot spot.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Sat Jun 20 19:41:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/red-devils-parachutist-tangles-teammate-mid-air-31912318</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of onlookers at the Whitehaven Airshow in the United Kingdom held their breath during the stunt.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31912318,"title":"Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air","duration":"2:31","description":"Thousands of onlookers at the Whitehaven Airshow in the United Kingdom held their breath during the stunt.","url":"/International/video/red-devils-parachutist-tangles-teammate-mid-air-31912318","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:02:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 06/25/15:  After Charleston Shooting, Signs of Change in Race Conversation</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-062515-charleston-shooting-signs-change-race-conversation-32043184</Link>
        <Description>'Magic Mike XXL' Cast on New Film, Getting Their Stripper Physiques; Trump's Comments on Mexican Immigrants Spark Controversy</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 06/25/15:  After Charleston Shooting, Signs of Change in Race Conversation
17:41 06/25/15 NR
'Magic Mike XXL' Cast on New Film, Getting Their Stripper Physiques; Trump's Comments on Mexican Immigrants Spark Controversy
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:24:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 06/25/15: Obamacare Gets a Major Supreme Court Victory</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-062515-obamacare-major-supreme-court-victory-32041131</Link>
        <Description>Authorities Investigating 2 Possible Arsons on Southern Churches; The CEO of Takata Apologizes Publicly for the First Time</Description>
        <MainBody>WN 06/25/15: Obamacare Gets a Major Supreme Court Victory
20:02 06/25/15 NR
Authorities Investigating 2 Possible Arsons on Southern Churches; The CEO of Takata Apologizes Publicly for the First Time
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:39:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 06/25/15: Boston Bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev Apologizes</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-062515-boston-bomber-dzhokhar-tsarnaev-apologizes-32025449</Link>
        <Description>Corrections Officer Charged in NY Prison Escape; Sibling Spies Watching in Ways That Parents Can't</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 06/25/15: Boston Bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev Apologizes
01:01:35 06/25/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 23:10:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20 06/19/15:  'The Wolfpack'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-061915-wolfpack-31908232</Link>
        <Description>'Wolfpack' Brothers Grew Up Locked in NYC Apartment for Years; Chance Encounter With Filmmaker Changes 'Wolfpack' Brothers' Lives; Brothers Meet Grandma For First Time at 'Wolfpack' Family Reunion</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 06/19/15: 'The Wolfpack'
40:42 06/19/15 NR
'Wolfpack' Brothers Grew Up Locked in NYC Apartment for Years; Chance Encounter With Filmmaker Changes 'Wolfpack' Brothers' Lives; Brothers Meet Grandma For First Time at 'Wolfpack' Family Reunion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 22:31:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 06/21/15: Inside the Tragic Shooting In Charleston, South Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-062115-inside-tragic-shooting-charleston-south-carolina-31927284</Link>
        <Description>Guests: Rick Santorum, Carl Anderson, Bakari Sellers, Steve Inskeep, Sara Fagen, Maria Cardona</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 06/21/15: Inside the Tragic Shooting In Charleston, South Carolina
46:09 06/21/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
