<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:12:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gov. Christie Political Ally to Plead Guilty in Bridge Probe</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/jersey-gov-chris-christie-political-ally-david-wildstein/story?id=30712895</Link>
        <Description>A key figure in the corruption scandal that threatens New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie???s political career is poised to plead guilty in federal court today, sources said.</Description>
        <MainBody>New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie Political Ally David Wildstein to Plead Guilty in Bridge Probe, Sources Say
May 1, 2015, 7:12 AM ET
David Wildstein speaks during a hearing at the Statehouse in Trenton, Jan. 9, 2014.
Mel Evans/AP Photo
A key figure in the corruption scandal that threatens New Jersey Gov. Chris Christies political career is poised to plead guilty in federal court today, sources told ABC News.
Word of David Wildsteins expected guilty plea was confirmed this morning by officials familiar with the situation, sources said.
The plea of the former Port Authority executive and one-time political blogger, who went to high school with Christie, would mark a dramatic step in the saga swirling around Christie.
Gov. Chris Christie Cleared -- Sort of -- in Bridge Scandal
The corruption probe that started with unannounced closings of access lanes at the George Washington Bridge in 2013 has, according to some, all but hobbled Christie as he seeks the GOP presidential nomination in 2016.
Wildstein was Christies enforcer and go-to guy at the Port Authority, which runs the New York City-area airports as well as the bridges and tunnels that connect New York and New Jersey. According to emails that were revealed in January 2014, Wildstein shut down two out of three local access lanes to the George Washington Bridge at the direction of Christies deputy chief of staff, Bridget Kelly. Their alleged goal was political payback against the mayor of Fort Lee -- where the bridge is anchored in New Jersey -- because the mayor would not endorse Christies re-election bid.
"Time for some traffic problems in Fort Lee," Kelly wrote in an August 2013 email.
With those words disclosed, what had been a local political brush fire engulfed the pugnacious New Jersey governor. He fired Kelly and cast aside Bill Stepien, the man who ran his political organization and was expected to helm Christies impending presidential campaign.
ABC News
PHOTO: New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie speaks with ABC News' Diane Sawyer in an exclusive interview on March 27, 2014.
Attorneys hired by Christie soon determined that the governor had no role in the scandal. But that did nothing to quiet matters.
In December, Christie himself was interrogated for more than seven hours by federal investigators probing the bridge scandal. He has denied having any role in the lane closings and has repeatedly said he did nothing wrong.
Last year, the governor told ABCs Diane Sawyer he didnt even inspire his aides and loyalists to shut down lanes to the worlds busiest bridge.
"This is not something that I think I inspired, and to the extent that any of them thought that this was acceptable conduct, then I fell short," Christie said at the time.
The governor also said that he does not believe the bridge affair was even done on his behalf.
"I dont believe it was for me," he said.
Spartanburg Herald Journal/AP Photo
PHOTO: Gov. Nikki Haley of South Carolina and Gov. Chris Christie of New Jersey show support for each other at a drive-in restaurant in Spartanburg, S.C., on Nov. 2, 2014.
The New Jersey U.S. Attorneys Office and the FBI have spent 16 months investigating the September 2013 lane closings, which caused unprecedented traffic jams for the better part of a week and crippled Fort Lee.
The scandal thrust Christie and his inner circle into a crisis first marked by a marathon news conference and then two months of dodging questions on the incident. Christie has since returned to public view, but his popularity among voters is at all-time lows and most observers see his chances of winning the GOP nomination as nearly non-existent.
In addition to the federal investigation in New Jersey, Christie and his aides are still facing continued scrutiny from a series of other probes being conducted by the Manhattan District Attorney in New York City, the New Jersey State Legislature and the Port Authority Inspector General's Office over the land closures. The results of the FBI probe could also be turned over to state prosecutors in the event they want to file their own charges in connection with the lane closing.
Get real-time updates as this story unfolds. To start, just "star" this story in ABC News' phone app. Download ABC News for iPhone here or ABC News for Android here .
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:15:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Details Fill In Freddie Gray's Journey With Police</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/freddie-gray-details-fill-journey-baltimore-police/story?id=30704154</Link>
        <Description>A Baltimore police detective announced Thursday that they have discovered a stop the police van made but that investigators had not known about earlier. </Description>
        <MainBody>New Freddie Gray Details Fill In His Journey With Baltimore Police
Apr 30, 2015, 10:09 PM ET
Freddie Grey, pictured in this undated photo, died Sunday, one week after he was arrested in Baltimore.
Courtesy Murphy, Falcon &amp; Murphy
Share
Copy
Police have handed over their investigation of Freddie Gray 's death to the Baltimore State's Attorney, which is now tasked with determining whether to bring charges against the six offices who took him into custody before he died a week later with an unexplained spinal injury.
In announcing the handover, Deputy Police Commissioner Kevin Davis, who led the group of 30 detectives during their investigation, said Thursday that they have discovered a stop the police van made but that investigators had not known about earlier.
Here is a rundown of the timeline compiled from information released by police since Gray's death.
Police Take Gray Into Custody
Police said officers were working in a West Baltimore area with a history of violence and drug deals at 8:39 a.m. when a man, later identified as Gray, was seen at the corner of North Avenue and Mount Street.
The officers approached the man, who then fled on foot, but why they moved toward him remains a part of the ongoing investigation, officials said.
A police officer was heard telling dispatch at 8:40 a.m. that officers had one person in custody in the 1700 block of Presbury Street, two blocks south of North and Mount Streets, police said.
At this morning's news conference, Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis said Gray ran from the police before being taken into custody on that same city block.
A wagon, or van, was requested for transport at 8:42 a.m., according to earlier Baltimore police statements, and Gray asked for an inhaler.
Google/ABC News
PHOTO:This is the sequence of stops made by Baltimore police after they took Freddie Gray into custody on April 12, 2015.
First Stop
Davis confirmed this morning that the police made a stop at Mount and Baker streets, though no further details about that stop were released. This intersection is just one block south from where Gray was taken into custody.
Second Stop
Davis said police have since determined that the wagon made a second stop they had not previously known about, at N. Fremont Avenue and Mosher Street. They did not release other details.
Investigators learned about this stop after reviewing video footage from a privately owned camera.
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake Defends Barring Fans From Orioles Game
Third Stop
The van then resumes the schedule that officers had previously known about with a stop at Druid Hill Avenue and Dolphin Street, which is not far from the second, unknown stop, though no further details about what happened here have been released.
Fourth Stop
The wagon then goes to North and Pennsylvania avenues to pick up an additional prisoner.
Davis did not release the time for each of these stops, but police have already said that at 8:46 a.m., the driver of the van reported that he believes Gray is acting irate. An officer asks the van to stop so paperwork could be completed, according to Baltimore police. At that point, Gray is taken out of the vehicle, and police said he was placed in leg irons and then put back in the van. Police have not specified when this occurred in relation to the vans various stops.
By 8:54 a.m., the wagon had cleared Mount Street and was heading toward central booking, police said in earlier statements.
At 8:59 a.m. a request was made by the driver of the van for an additional "unit" to check on Gray, police say. There was some undisclosed communication with Gray at this point, police said in earlier statements.
Patrick Semansky/AP Photo
PHOTO: Baltimore Police Department Commissioner Anthony Batts announces that the department's investigation into the death of Freddie Gray was turned over to the State's Attorney's office, April 30, 2015, in Baltimore.
Arrives at the Police Station
Police have not released the official time when the wagon arrived at Western District station, but at 9:23 a.m. emergency medical services directed a technician to respond for an injured patient, as heard on a recording of the call that was publicly released.
A minute later, police officers requested paramedics to the Western District to transport the man to the University of Maryland's Shock Trauma Center. In a subsequent charging document, police said, During transport to Western District via wagon transport the Defendant suffered a medical emergency and was immediately transported to Shock Trauma."
On-scene medical responders said Gray was not breathing at 9:37 a.m., according to EMS reports.
Transported to the Hospital
He was then transferred to Shock Trauma. On Thursday, April 16, Grays familys attorney said he had gone into a coma, and he died on the morning of Sunday, April 19.
ABC News' Katherine Faulders contributed to this report.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tale of the Tape: How Mayweather, Pacquiao Match Up</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Sports/floyd-mayweather-manny-pacquiao-boxing-fight-centurys-tale/story?id=30708635</Link>
        <Description>What Floyd Mayweather and Manny Pacquiao's stats and a common opponent say about the matchup.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mayweather, the highest-paid athlete in the world, according to Forbes, grew up in a boxing family.
The Ring Magazine/Getty Images
PHOTO: Floyd Mayweather Jr. poses for a portrait, June 11,1998, in Atlantic City, N.J.
His father and trainer, Floyd Mayweather Sr., fought and lost to the legendary boxing champ Sugar Ray Leonard in 1978.
Johnny Nunez/Getty Images
PHOTO: Floyd Mayweather, Sr. and Floyd Mayweather, Jr. attend the official Mayweather afterparty at Studio 54 at MGM Grand on May 1, 2010 in Las Vegas, Nevada.
Pacquiao, born on the southern coast of the Philippines , is spending his second term as a member of the House of Representatives there. As a teenager, he moved to Manila to earn money and soon started boxing.
Gerhard Joren/LightRocket/Getty Images
PHOTO: A teenage Manny Pacquiao is seen here at the LM Gym in Manila, Philippines, in 1996.
One opponent of both Mayweather and Pacquiao, Oscar De La Hoya, described his struggle to predict a winner.
Gabriel Bouys/AFP/Getty Images
PHOTO: Oscar De La Hoya fights with Floyd Mayweather during their WBC Super Welterweight World Championship, in Las Vegas, Nevada, May 5, 2007.
"My head goes with Mayweather, my heart is with Pacquiao," De La Hoya told ESPN . "I like Pacquiao. I like what he stands for, what he believes in. I like his fighting spirit. I respect the boxer [Mayweather] but I love the fighter [Pacquiao].
Ethan Miller/Getty Images
PHOTO: Manny Pacquiao of the Philippines fights Oscar De La Hoya during their welterweight match at the MGM Grand Garden Arena, Dec. 6, 2008 in Las Vegas, Nev.
"We know what Mayweather is going to do," De La Hoya said. "He doesn't change his game plan. There's nothing new to his style. With Pacquiao, there is so much room for improvement that he might surprise us."
Floyd Mayweather, Jr.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:06:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dramatic Mount Everest Avalanche Video Shows Cloud of Snow, Ice</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/mount-everest-avalanche-video-shows-cloud-snow-ice/story?id=30723557</Link>
        <Description>British hiker Annie Tinsley was hiking with friends below Mount Everest???s base camp when Saturday's avalanche occurred.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mount Everest Avalanche Video Shows Cloud of Snow, Ice
May 1, 2015, 8:06 AM ET
By ABC NEWS via Good Morning America
Video shows a cloud of snow and ice due to an an avalanche on Mount Everest, April 25, 2015.
Obtained by ABC News
Share
British hiker Annie Tinsley was hiking with friends below Mount Everests base camp when Saturdays avalanche occurred, creating a cloud of snow and ice that quickly engulfed the group.
Tinsley was using her GoPro camera at the time.
Oh my God, what do we do? one person asked.
The group headed away from the avalanche, but they were quickly pelted.
Stay down, stay down, someone instructed the hikers.
Tinsley continued filming as she was engulfed in the avalanche, her camera covered. While no one in Tinsleys group was seriously injured, at least 18 people were killed in the avalanche, and more than 5,500 others have died in the earthquake that triggered the avalanche.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:44:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dog Infects Humans With Plague for First Time in US</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Health/dog-infects-humans-plague-time-us/story?id=30710741</Link>
        <Description>A dog became sickened with the plague last year. </Description>
        <MainBody>Dog Infects Humans With Plague for First Time in US
Apr 30, 2015, 6:34 PM ET
Yersinia pestis, the bacterium that causes plague, is seen in this undated stock image.
Getty Images
Share
Copy
A plague-infected dog spread the dangerous disease to four Colorado residents, according to a new report from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention .
Health officials told ABC News that this the first report of a dog infecting a human with the plague in the U.S.
The dog, a 2-year-old American pit bull terrier, became sick last summer with a fever and jaw rigidity, among other symptoms. The dog's health declined so quickly that it was euthanized the following day at a local vet's office, health officials said.
How Two Young Sisters Cope With a Rare Muscle Wasting Disease
Four days later, the dog's owner entered the hospital with a fever and a bloody cough that became worse over the next few hours, but an initial blood culture was misidentified, according to the CDC report.
As the patient's symptoms grew worse, the test was redone and he was found to have been infected with pnumonic plague, according to the CDC report. The remains of the dog were also tested and were found to be positive for the plague bacteria.
"Frankly one of the biggest surprises of this outbreak is the source," said John Douglas, of Tri-County Health Department in Colorado and one of the study authors. "Primarily ... dogs dont get sick at all or they get a minor illness," after being infected with the plague.
Janine Runfola, of the Tri-County Health Department in Colorado and lead author of the report, explained that cats are more likely to infect humans with the disease than dogs because they exhibit more symptoms.
"For pneumonic plague a more likely scenario would be you have a cat [play] with prairie dogs and infected fleas get on the cat," Runfola said. "The cat gets sick and sneezes and coughs on its owner."
Getty Images/Gallo Images
PHOTO: A prairie dog is seen in a stock photo. Plague has been known to affect prairie dogs in the southwest region of the U.S.
The dog's owner remained hospitalized for 23 days as he recovered from the potentially deadly disease, the report said. In addition to the owner, a close contact of the owner and two veterinary employees who treated the dog or handled its body also became infected with the plague. All three were successfully treated with medication after exhibiting symptoms.
The plague is caused by the bacteria Yersinia pestis, and can infect the body in different ways. For example a flea bite can lead to infection of the glands, which is called bubonic plague -- notorious for the epidemics it spawned during the Middle Ages in Europe. Because this plague was spread from dog to owner through coughing, it developed into pneumonic plague, according to Douglas.
The plague is known to be endemic to prairie dogs in the American Southwest, which can then lead to isolated outbreaks of the disease in domestic animals or humans.
"Pneumonic plague is the worst form," said Douglas. "Its the one that you least want to get. You get sick fast and the chances of getting a rocky or even fatal course" are increased.
The plague is incredibly rare in the U.S. with an estimated eight infections in the country reported every year. Douglas said pneumonic plague is even rarer and accounts for just 3 to 5 percent of plague cases.
Douglas said the case shows the importance of considering all the options when diagnosing a patient, even extremely rare options like the plague.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:34:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sherpas Face Uncertain Future Following Everest Avalanche</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/sherpas-face-uncertain-future-everest-avalanche-30720871</Link>
        <Description>Sherpas face uncertain future following earthquake, Mount Everest avalanche</Description>
        <MainBody>Sherpas Face Uncertain Future Following Everest Avalanche
SEATTLE  May 1, 2015, 1:33 AM ET
By MARTHA BELLISLE and BINAJ GURUBACHARYA Associated Press
Mount Everest is normally buzzing with activity this time of year, with hundreds of hopeful climbers gathering at base camp to attempt to summit the world's tallest peak during a narrow 10-day window in May before the monsoons arrive.
It is also the most lucrative season for Sherpas, the locals living in the high-altitude regions of the Himalaya who support climbing teams as porters, guides, rope-fixers, cooks and dish-washers.
But Everest is basically closed after a magnitude-7.8 quake triggered a massive avalanche that killed 19 at basecamp and more than 5,800 people throughout the country. China said Wednesday it was ending the climbing season early on the Tibet side, and most major mountaineering companies on the Nepal side canceled their climbs because of logistical challenges and safety concerns.
That leaves Sherpas, who can earn up to $5,000 to $7,000, plus bonuses and tips, during the three-month climbing season, wondering how they'll make up that lost revenue in a country where the per capita income is about $730 annually. Cooks and other support personnel earn about half as much, but still well above the average pay in the country.
Ang Tshering Sherpa, president of Nepal Mountaineering Association, an umbrella body of mountaineering agencies and climbers in Nepal, said Sherpas are worried the season may be over. While many Sherpas sign contracts that will still have to be paid, they'll miss out on day rates and bonuses.
Steve Mock, director a climbing school for Nepali called the Khumbu Climbing Center, said the lower incomes also mean Sherpas now have less money to rebuild their homes.
"Insurance for that sort of thing is simply not available in Nepal so rebuilding costs come directly out of pocket," he said. "Many save up money from working on Everest for years in order to build a decent house that may well have been destroyed or at least damaged by the quake. So financially, this is simply devastating."
The financial burden could spread beyond just the Sherpas. Everest is a major economic driver for the country, which receives more than $3.5 million from Everest climbing permits annually, said Conrad Anker of Bozeman, Montana , who has climbed Everest three times.
Climbing permits run about $11,000 per person for climbing Everest from the Nepal side and $7,000 per person on the Tibet side, and hundreds are sold each year.
The climbing season runs from March to June.
A few teams are trying to find a way to salvage the season, and some Sherpas would welcome the work.
Kapindra Rai of the Sagarmatha Pollution Control Committee, which is in charge of the route through the treacherous Khumbu Icefall on the Nepal side, said staff descended from base camp because two of their cooks were injured, they lost their equipment and many wanted to be with their families.
But they were ready to return if any expedition asks, Rai said.
Adrian Ballinger, a guide with the California-based Alpenglow Expeditions, said although his Everest team had to call off their summit bid on the Tibet side, they are still paying their 12 Nepali Sherpas.
"We are paying full wages minus summit bonuses, and a separate fund for home rebuilding," he said in a text message Thursday. "We recognize this is their sole income."
Others in the international climbing community are raising funds to support the communities.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:59:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Stokes Flames Ahead of US Trip Even as He Ends Problems</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Health/wireStory/pope-stokes-flames-ahead-us-trip-ends-problems-30724716</Link>
        <Description>Pope stokes flames on environment, death penalty ahead of US trip even as he resolves problems</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Stokes Flames Ahead of US Trip Even as He Ends Problems
VATICAN CITY  May 1, 2015, 7:57 AM ET
By NICOLE WINFIELD Associated Press
When Pope Francis visits the United States this fall, he can expect the same rock-star adulation that greets him wherever he goes. But his positions on hot-button issues such as the death penalty and climate change could quickly set the stage for conflict. That may explain why Francis has been clearing the decks on a host of less high-profile matters of contention that could also have marred the visit.
In a matter of a few short weeks, Francis abruptly ended the Vatican's deeply contested investigation of U.S. nuns and engineered the removal of an American bishop who failed to report a suspected sex abuser. Had he left those issues to fester, they would certainly have cast a cloud over the historic trip  which will include the first papal address to the U.S. Congress.
On Saturday Francis will try to address another controversy over his planned canonization of an 18th century Franciscan missionary, Junipero Serra, accused by Native Americans of running a genocidal machine that tortured indigenous converts and spread disease. Francis will celebrate a Mass in Serra's honor at the main U.S. seminary in Rome.
While Francis' popularity ratings in the United States rival those of St. John Paul II, he is not without his detractors. Conservative Republicans privately grumble about his views on global warming and immigration, and his vehement opposition to the death penalty.
Here is a look at how Francis has recently stoked flames on some key issues and resolved others.

CLIMATE CHANGE
Francis got a big thumbs-up this week for his green agenda from U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-Moon , who said his upcoming environment encyclical could be a game-changer in the run-up to climate change talks in Paris at the end of the year.
Ban was the keynote speaker at a Vatican conference bringing together Nobel Prize-winning scientists, Francis' key environmental advisers and faith leaders. They were unanimous in agreeing that climate change is real, mostly man-made, hardest on the poorest, and a problem that only collective action can solve.
Many Republicans have opposed efforts to reduce fossil fuels and other pollutants that contribute to global warming, and some deny that human activity is responsible.
The conference's host had choice words for such skeptics: "It's the same people who defend the oil industry," said Monsignor Sanchez Sorondo, one of Francis' top advisers. "It's the lobby of profit."

DEATH PENALTY
Francis has gone well beyond his predecessors  and Catholic Church teaching  in saying there is simply no justification for the death penalty today. "Inadmissible," he calls it, "regardless of how grave the crime."
He has called life prison terms a "hidden death penalty" and solitary confinement a "form of torture"  and said both should be abolished.
The pope's advocacy won him an award this week from the Hands Off Cain anti-capital punishment advocacy group.
The United States is in the Top 10 list of countries that still execute people, along with China, Iran, Iraq, Saudi Arabia , Somalia, Sudan and North Korea .
While capital punishment has many supporters in the U.S.  it's legal in more than 30 states  even some conservatives are coming out against it. Princeton University's Robert George, a leading conservative Catholic intellectual, recently wrote to Kansas' governor urging him to repeal the death penalty.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:31:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House Adopts Compromise GOP Budget Targeting 'Obamacare'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/wireStory/house-adopt-compromise-gop-budget-targeting-obamacare-30710447</Link>
        <Description>House adopts compromise GOP budget targeting 'Obamacare,' boosting Pentagon</Description>
        <MainBody>House Adopts Compromise GOP Budget Targeting 'Obamacare'
WASHINGTON  Apr 30, 2015, 8:30 PM ET
By ANDREW TAYLOR Associated Press
The House Thursday adopted a compromise GOP budget that promises to speed repeal of the President Barack Obama's health care law while giving the Pentagon an additional $38 billion next year.
The 226-197 vote sends the non-binding budget plan to the Senate for a vote next week. It promises to balance the budget in nine years with more than $5 trillion in spending cuts, though Republicans make clear they aren't interested in actually imposing controversial cuts to programs like Medicare, food stamps, Pell Grants or the traditional Medicaid program with follow-up legislation.
Instead, the House-Senate budget framework increases spending in the near term by padding war accounts by almost $40 billion next year. And Senate Republicans skittish over politically dangerous cuts to Medicare blocked a House move that called for giving subsidies to future retirees to purchase health insurance on the open market instead of a guaranteed package of Medicare coverage.
Under Washington's arcane budget process, lawmakers first adopt a budget that's essentially a visionary document and follow it up with binding legislation to set agency budgets, cut or raise taxes, and make changes to so-called mandatory programs like Medicare and food stamps, whose budgets run as if on autopilot.
Republicans tout the long-term economic benefits of a balanced budget and say it's better to tackle the long-term financial problems of programs like Medicare and Medicaid sooner rather than later.
Budget Committee Chairman Tom Price, R-Ga., said the GOP plan "will not only get Washington's fiscal house in order but pave the way for stronger economic growth, more jobs and more opportunity. It invests in our nation's priorities, ensures a strong national defense and saves and strengthens and protects important programs like Medicare and Social Security ."
But Democrats say the GOP plan unfairly targets the middle class and the poor while leaving in place lucrative tax breaks for corporations and the wealthy.
White House budget director Shaun Donovan dissected the measure in a blog post that noted $600 billion in cuts from "income security" programs like nutrition assistance, cash assistance to low-income seniors and people with disabilities, and refundable tax credits for the working poor. Donovan also pointed out cuts to Pell grants for disadvantaged college students while noting that its relief for the Pentagon is temporary.
This year, Republicans are focused mostly on finally delivering legislation to President Barack Obama that would repeal the bulk of his signature health care law. Successful action on Thursday's budget plan would permit a health care repeal to advance through the Senate without threat of a Democratic filibuster. Obama is sure to veto the measure, which is scheduled to advance by late July.
While assuming expiration of health insurance subsidies and repeal of the expansion of Medicaid coverage under the health care law, the measure promises balance over the coming decade by relying on about $2 trillion worth of cuts to health care providers and tax revenues consistent with levels in place after the 2010 health care law. Republicans promise to repeal the Obamacare tax increases but don't say how they'll replace the revenue.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:21:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Abandoned Arsenal: Kids Find 60 Guns in Vacant Home</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/abandoned-arsenal-kids-find-60-guns-vacant-home-30725489</Link>
        <Description>Abandoned arsenal: Kids break into vacant Pennsylvania home and find 60 guns, knives, swords</Description>
        <MainBody>Abandoned Arsenal: Kids Find 60 Guns in Vacant Home
LAUREL MOUNTAIN, Pa.  May 1, 2015, 8:20 AM ET
Police say they've taken possession of dozens of firearms, including a flintlock muzzle-loader, an AK-47 and a Tommy gun, found by children who broke into a vacant Pennsylvania home.
The Pittsburgh Tribune-Review reports Friday ( http://bit.ly/1I2Knj4 ) at least 60 guns  plus knives, bayonets and swords  were in the Laurel Mountain home.
Police traced the weapons to a 93-year-old collector who owns the home and who's currently in the hospital.
Authorities say four boys and a girl ages 11 to 14 broke into the home Tuesday evening and shot some of the weapons in the woods. They say they also broke into two other abandoned homes nearby.
Police are holding the weapons for safe keeping. They're waiting to see if the elderly man's family wants to press charges.

Information from: Pittsburgh Tribune-Review, http://pghtrib.com
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:48:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More Americans Spending at Least Half Their Pay on Housing</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Business/wireStory/americans-spending-half-pay-housing-30723779</Link>
        <Description>Analysis finds 26 pct. surge since Great Recession in US families who face burdensome rents</Description>
        <MainBody>More Americans Spending at Least Half Their Pay on Housing
WASHINGTON  May 1, 2015, 7:46 AM ET
By JOSH BOAK AP Economics Writer
The surging cost of rental housing has squeezed a rising proportion of U.S. families since the Great Recession struck in 2007.
For more than one in four renters, housing and utilities consume at least half their family income, according to an analysis of Census data by Enterprise Community Partners, a nonprofit that helps finance affordable housing. The number of such households has jumped 26 percent to 11.25 million since 2007, a sign that the 6-year-old recovery from the recession has given scant relief to much of the country.
The government defines housing costs in excess of 30 percent of income as burdensome.
"It means making really difficult trade-offs," said Angela Boyd, a vice president at Enterprise Community Partners. "There are daily financial dilemmas about making their rent or buying groceries."
The crisis reflects one of the shortcomings of the recovery: Wages have failed to match rising rental prices. At the same time, construction has failed to keep pace with demand from renters. The recession pushed more millennials, former homeowners who faced foreclosure and low-wage workers into rental housing.
A result is that 2.3 million more families face pressures that leave them perilously close to homelessness. It's a reality faced by Lisette Duarte, a 37-year-old living in a two-bedroom apartment with her family in northeast Los Angeles.
Duarte's husband lost his job as an electrician more than three years ago. With both their son and daughter on the autistic spectrum and in need of care, he chose to stay at home while she worked a job requiring a 90-minute commute each way. The lost income forced them out of a three-bedroom house and eventually into a hotel, where vouchers over the course of five months helped them save for a security deposit for an apartment.
About a year ago, the family moved into a two-bedroom apartment in the Highland Park neighborhood where Duarte had grown up. Two-bedrooms in that gentrifying community rent for an average of about $1,600 a month, according to the online service Apartment List. The expense, along with utilities, consumes half of Duarte's paycheck.
The family relies on prepaid cellphones. They don't dine out or go on vacations. Whatever extra income they have often goes for health care.
More than 30 percent of renters in California, Florida, New Jersey and New York state devote at least half their incomes to housing and utilities, according to the analysis. Other than Alaska, South Dakota and Wyoming, at least 20 percent of renters in every state face similarly high costs relative to income.
The analysis was developed for a "Make Room" awareness campaign sponsored by Enterprise Community Partners. As part of the campaign, pop stars such as Carly Rae Jepsen of "Call Me Maybe" fame, who sang for the Duartes, are performing concerts in the homes of financially distressed tenants.
Decades of barely rising pay has contributed to the problem. Average hourly wages have risen just 2.1 percent in the past 12 months, according to the Labor Department, while rental prices have climbed 3.7 percent, the real estate firm Zillow said last week.
Many renters lack the income to pay the cost of maintaining and operating these buildings, said Barry Zigas, director of housing policy at the Consumer Federation of America and a trustee at the nonprofit Mercy Housing.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:19:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Transgender Army Major Wins Victory in Conservative Serbia</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/transgender-army-major-wins-victory-conservative-serbia-30723556</Link>
        <Description>Transgender army major wins victory against discrimination in socially conservative Serbia</Description>
        <MainBody>Transgender Army Major Wins Victory in Conservative Serbia
BELGRADE, Serbia  May 1, 2015, 6:18 AM ET
By JOVANA GEC Associated Press
In macho Serbia , he came across as macho as they come: an army major in a military culture that glorifies masculine strength. He was a perfect husband and father in a society that preaches family values. But for nearly his entire life, the major felt he was living a lie: Deep down, he was a woman.
Last year, he came out, telling his family and superiors that he was Helena  and starting therapy to become a woman. She did not remain Serbia's first transgender major for long: The army asked for her resignation, saying she "posed a threat to the reputation of the army." In April, Helena scored an important victory: A Serbian human rights body ruled that the army had discriminated against her by saying she was a potential stain on its honor.
Today, Helena appears in public in women's clothes and sporting bleached blond hair. The 43-year-old declined to provide her first or last name during her life as a man in order to protect a divorced wife and four children  but is not shy about being photographed or filmed in her new identity.
By speaking out, Helena has become a rare voice representing Serbia's transgender community, which lives under constant fear of hate crimes on the margins of the society. Tolerance for the LGBT community across the Balkans is low, and several gay pride events in Serbia have been canceled because of extremist violence.
"I am fighting for the rights of all humiliated people," Helena told The Associated Press in an interview. "This is a struggle for all those who can't enjoy their basic human right to be equal with everybody else."
Helena spoke to the AP in a friend's flat in downtown Belgrade, meticulously made up and dressed in tight black jeans and a sweater. Smiling gently as she sipped coffee, she spoke calmly about her decision to undergo a sex change program that will culminate in an operation. The decision came at a high cost  causing a split from her family and ending her career  but Helena said it felt "amazing."
"It's like stepping out of a cage," she said.
Helena's inner struggle began in early childhood, growing up in a military household in a small Serbian town. As a young boy, Helena made her hair grow out so she could curl it. When nobody was around, she would put on her mother's clothes and sneak onto the terrace to let out that girl inside  if only for a moment.
But this was impossible in a town where any hint of femininity in a man was seen as a weakness. She was confused. She thought there was something wrong with her. So she sought to quash the woman inside.
"And what better place to kill that woman than the army?" Helena said.
She finished military school and married young, another form of "self-healing." For the next 22 years, Helena served in the military and led the life of a family man. At the same time, she gradually built a parallel life, getting in touch with fellow members of the transgender community.
In 2001, Helena was detained by police wearing a skirt and suspended by a military disciplinary court. She appealed and was reinstated after seven months. But life in the army was not the same again. She recalled "everybody going silent every time I entered the room."
Finally last year, Helena came out. Though she did not resist army pressure to drive her into early retirement, she was horrified when this was cast as a way to protect its reputation. With the help of a human rights group, Helena took her case to Serbia's anti-discrimination office.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:14:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Texas Teen Gets 45-Year Prison Term for Killing Mom, Sister</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/texas-teen-45-year-prison-term-killing-mom-30725320</Link>
        <Description>North Texas teenager sentenced to 45 years in prison for fatally shooting mother and sister</Description>
        <MainBody>Texas Teen Gets 45-Year Prison Term for Killing Mom, Sister
WEATHERFORD, Texas  May 1, 2015, 8:11 AM ET
A teenager has been sentenced to 45 years in prison for fatally shooting his mother and sister at their North Texas home.
The Weatherford Democrat ( http://bit.ly/1FBavjf ) reports that 19-year-old Jake Evans pleaded guilty Thursday to two counts of murder in the killing of 48-year-old Jami Evans and 15-year-old Mallory Evans in October 2012.
Jake Evans, who was 17 years old when he shot his mother and sister at their Weatherford home, called 911 and told the dispatcher that he didn't know why he killed them but that he had been planning to do so for a while.
Evans will serve at least 22 years in prison before becoming eligible for parole and will receive credit for the 2 years already served.
Weatherford is 30 miles west of Fort Worth.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:35:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10-Day Strike by Portuguese Airline Pilots Grounds Flights</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/10-day-strike-portuguese-airline-pilots-grounds-flights-30723658</Link>
        <Description>10-day Portuguese airline pilots strike grounds flights in bid to be included in privatization</Description>
        <MainBody>10-Day Strike by Portuguese Airline Pilots Grounds Flights
LISBON, Portugal  May 1, 2015, 6:34 AM ET
Pilots at Portugal's state-owned national airline have begun a 10-day strike, forcing flight cancellations as they press their demand to be given up to a 20 percent stake in the company when it is privatized later this year.
TAP Air Portugal said it expected up to 3,000 flights and 300,000 passengers to be affected by the walkout that started Friday, causing losses of at least 30 million euros ($33.7 million).
An arbitration court ordered pilots to provide about 30 flights a day.
The Civil Aviation Pilots' Union, which represents a majority of the flag carrier's more than 900 pilots, is also demanding long-service rewards for its members.
The airline recorded losses of 81 million euros last year and is more than 1 billion euros in debt.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:52:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore Cops Reeling From Riot-Related Injuries </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/baltimore-police-officers-reeling-riot-related-injuries/story?id=30710326</Link>
        <Description>There are 98 officers who have reported injuries since Monday. </Description>
        <MainBody>Fifteen of those 43 most-severely injured officers have been put on light duty because they can perform administrative duties but not patrol the street. The remaining 15 were able to return to active duty, officials said.
Getty Images
PHOTO: A protester throws a rock at police during riots in Baltimore, USA on April 27, 2015.
Kowalczyk did not detail any specific injuries sustained by the officers, or how they received them, although many of them were pelted with rocks and other objects.
"These weren't little pebbles being thrown," he said of the interactions with rioters. "These were chunks of cement with serrated edges and glass embedded in them. That's what was being thrown at our officers."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:36:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Typo Causes $10 Million Mistake in New Jersey</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/typo-10-million-mistake-jersey-30723659</Link>
        <Description>Typo shorts New Jersey project by $10 million, leaves officials trying make up for shortfall</Description>
        <MainBody>Typo Causes $10 Million Mistake in New Jersey
PARAMUS, N.J.  May 1, 2015, 6:35 AM ET
A typo amounted to a $10 million mistake in northern New Jersey .
Bergen County freeholders approved a $115 million bond issue in 2012 to pay for a justice center in Hackensack and an $18 million public works facility in Paramus.
The Record newspaper reports ( http://bit.ly/1bkDWtk ) when officials revised the bond paperwork, they mistakenly dropped the first digit of the Paramus project's cost. That brought its recorded price tag to $8 million.
Officials say they will either have to revise the bond ordinance or find ways to carve money from the rest of the project. They're working to find out how the mistake happened.
The building is slated to open in September.

Information from: The Record (Woodland Park, N.J.), http://www.northjersey.com
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:35:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Prime Minister Wants Japan to Learn From Silicon Valley</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Technology/wireStory/bullet-train-japanese-pms-agenda-california-visit-30694232</Link>
        <Description>Prime minister says he wants Japan to learn style, risk and innovation from Silicon Valley</Description>
        <MainBody>Prime Minister Wants Japan to Learn From Silicon Valley
May 1, 2015, 12:33 AM ET
By MARTHA MENDOZA AP National Writer
Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe, accompanied by Congressional leadership, arrives on Capitol Hill in Washington, Wednesday, April 29, 2015, to speak before a joint meeting of Congress. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)
The Associated Press
Japan Prime Minister Shinzo Abe gave California's governor a hint of what it would be like inside a Japanese-made bullet train Thursday, displaying a train simulator for Gov. Jerry Brown during a meeting in San Francisco.
The Japanese leader also took time to check out tech innovations and lend support to expanded commercial ties on the first day of his three-day visit to California.
"There are some people in California who think of high speed rail as a mysterious, very expensive, exotic technology," Brown told Abe during their meeting at a hotel. "I hope people see high speed rail is a reality. If you were able to get a train in a hotel, I think I can get a train built from San Francisco to Los Angeles."
Brown has faced opposition in his efforts to build a $68-billion high-speed rail in California to connect San Francisco and Los Angeles.
Earlier in the day, Abe said during a speech at Stanford that his country needs to emulate Silicon Valley style, risk and innovation.
"We would like to capture the dynamism of Silicon Valley," he said while announcing plans to send representatives from 200 Japanese companies to "sail into the rough waves" of the region over the next five years.
He compared the effort to Japan sending players to Major League Baseball teams.
His country also will send 30 entrepreneurs to pitch ideas to Silicon Valley investors.
Abe said he plans to meet with Google and Facebook executives and visit electric carmaker Tesla Motors, which is building electric cars in a plant first opened by General Motors more than 50 years ago.
Abe's itinerary also includes a discussion with business leaders at a resort on Sand Hill Road, a busy stretch of street known as the epicenter of tech venture-capital companies that have launched Amazon, Facebook, Twitter and other tech giants.
"This Japanese administration has been focusing on changing its economy to a growth-based system built on innovation," said Japanese economic researcher Takeo Hoshi, a senior fellow at Stanford University's Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies. "This is probably the best place in the world to look at that."
The region is home to Google, Apple and other leading tech firms that help drive the U.S. economy. Average annual employee earnings were $116,000, compared with $61,000 nationally. Venture capitalists invested $14.5 billion in businesses, and 76,450 new jobs were created.
During the visit, Abe will also meet with Japanese-Americans in San Francisco and Los Angeles, encourage Japanese students who are studying in the state, and announce policies to facilitate U.S. investment in Japan.
Abe planned to meet researchers later Thursday, including Japanese Nobel-winning stem cell researcher Shinya Yamanaka at the University of California, San Francisco-affiliated Gladstone Institute.
Earlier in the week, Abe made the Washington, D.C., rounds with a White House dinner and address to Congress.
While on Capitol Hill , he declared "history is harsh" and offered condolences for Americans who died in World War II.
He stopped short of offering an apology sought by U.S. lawmakers for Japanese conduct during the war, including sexual enslavement of tens of thousands of Asian women by Japan's imperial army.
About 50 people protested outside the auditorium in Stanford where Abe spoke. A small group of demonstrators also stood outside the San Francisco hotel where he met with Brown holding signs that read "Comfort Women Were Slaves. No Cover Up of War Crimes."

Associated Press writers Matthew Pennington in Washington and Olga R. Rodriguez in San Francisco contributed to this story.

Follow Martha Mendoza @mendozamarthaap.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:18:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman Found Dead in Maui Waters Likely Shark Victim</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/woman-found-dead-maui-hawaii-waters-shark-victim/story?id=30712243</Link>
        <Description>A woman found dead near a popular beach area in Maui, Hawaii, is believed to be a victim of a shark attack.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman Found Dead in Maui, Hawaii, Waters Likely Shark Victim
Apr 30, 2015, 9:49 PM ET
By ABC NEWS
This stock photo shows Makena State Park in Maui, Hawaii. Beaches and the ocean from Ahihi-Kinau Natural Area Reserve to Makena State Park were closed after an apparent shark attack that left a woman dead, the Department of Land and Natural Resources said.
Getty Images
Share
Copy
A popular beach spot in Maui, Hawaii, was reopened after a closure today as authorities await confirmation of an apparent fatal shark attack .
Margaret C. Cruse, 65, of Kihei, Maui, was found by snorkelers Wednesday around 9 a.m. in a popular surfing area called "Dumps." Cruse was unresponsive and floating face-down just 200 yards offshore, the Maui Fire Department said in a statement. Paramedics and firefighters were unable to revive her.
Kayakers Survive Close Encounter With a Shark
The department said that Cruse had been snorkeling with two friends and then separated from them. Authorities said the injuries to the woman's upper torso were consistent with a shark attack. They were awaiting an official autopsy report.
If confirmed, the attack would be the first shark-related death in the U.S. since 2013, according to the International Shark Attack File. That year, two people died in Maui after being bitten by sharks.
Beaches on Maui were closed for a mile on each side of the attack location until noon local time today, the day after the attack, as is typical following a shark incident, according to Hawaii's Department of Land and Natural Resources.
According to the ISAF, two-thirds of all shark attacks in the world occur in the U.S., with 52 reported in 2014. Earlier this month, a Florida man was airlifted to the hospital after being bitten by a shark. The man was spearfishing off Jupiter Inlet when he was bitten, according to ABC affiliate WPBF-TV .
In southern California, 2,500 miles away from the Maui beach, sharks have residents on guard. Signs warning people of several great white sightings dot the shoreline. So far, the beaches have remained open.
Beachgoer Ryan Riske said the signs were a reality check.
"To hear [about] it and actually see a sign up, you know, it wakes you up a little bit," Riske said today.
Cruse's death would also be the latest in a long line of dangerous, close encounters in the U.S. In September, Ida Parker and Kristin Orr were kayaking in the water near White Horse Beach in Plymouth, Massachusetts, when a great white shark attacked. The two women were stunned, but not injured.
"It happened so fast," Orr said. "I was talking to her and the next minute, I'm in the water, and I just see a shark biting my kayak."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:07:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Doctors Keep Mom's Body Functioning So Baby Could Survive</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/doctors-moms-body-functioning-baby-survive-30709582</Link>
        <Description>Omaha doctors keep brain-dead woman's body functioning for weeks before delivering baby</Description>
        <MainBody>Doctors Keep Mom's Body Functioning So Baby Could Survive
OMAHA, Neb.  Apr 30, 2015, 5:06 PM ET
A brain-dead woman was kept on life support for more than seven weeks so the baby she was carrying could survive, Omaha doctors said.
The 2-pound, 12.6-ounce boy, named Angel, was delivered earlier this month at Methodist Women's Hospital. His mother, 22-year-old Karla Perez, had collapsed at home in Waterloo in early February after complaining of a bad headache. Doctors discovered a brain bleed and determined that she was brain-dead.
Her family members told doctors they wanted to do everything possible for the baby she was carrying. Omaha television station KETV reports doctors determined they needed to keep Perez's body alive for the baby to continue growing.
The fetus was just 22 weeks along and couldn't survive outside of the womb when Perez died, Dr. Todd Lovgren told television station WOWT.
"If we were going to give baby Angel any chance of survival, we were going to have to prolong Karla's pregnancy as long as possible," he said.
A team of more than 100 doctors, nurses and staff kept Perez alive for nearly two months, and when her condition worsened on April 4, doctors performed a cesarean section. Angel was immediately admitted to the neonatal intensive care unit, where he continues to grow.
Days after the procedure, Perez was pronounced dead and her organs were donated.
"I have no words for the attention and how they took very good care of my daughter," Angel's grandmother Berta Perez told WOWT.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:18:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda Hit the Red Carpet</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/photos/fabulous-50-16695746</Link>
        <Description>Some celebrities never seem to age. </Description>
        <MainBody>
Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda Hit the Red Carpet
Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda arrive for the premiere of Netflix's "Grace and Frankie" held at Regal Cinemas L.A. Live, April 29, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Albert L. Ortega/Getty Images
Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda Hit the Red Carpet
Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda arrive for the premiere of Netflix's "Grace and Frankie" held at Regal Cinemas L.A. Live, April 29, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Albert L. Ortega/Getty Images
Sharon Stone Makes a Bright Appearance
Actress Sharon Stone is all smiles while out and about, April 29, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GAMR/FameFlynet
Kathy Griffin Strikes a Pose
Comedian Kathy Griffin attends the premiere of "Ride" at ArcLight Hollywood, April 28, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
David Livingston/Getty Images
Katie Couric Brightens Up the Red Carpet
Journalist Katie Couric attends the 2015 Yahoo Digital Content NewFronts at Avery Fisher Hall, April 27, 2015, in New York.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images
Melanie Griffith Stays Fit and Glam All At Once
Melanie Griffith is seen leaving a gym in Beverly Hills, Calif. on the morning of April 27, 2015.
CMaidana/AKM-GSI
Joely Richardson Stuns on the Red Carpet
Joely Richardson attends the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival world premiere narrative: "Maggie" at BMCC Tribeca PAC on April 22, 2015 in New York.
WireImage
Kris Jenner and Her Beau Have a Date Night With Tish and Billy Ray Cyrus
Kris Jenner posted this photo to Instagram on April 22, 2015 with the caption, "Great night with great friends".
@krisjenner/Instagram
Martha Stewart visits FOX Business Network at FOX Studios on April 21, 2015 in New York City.
Noam Galai/Getty Images
Vanessa Williams Makes a Bright Appearance in NYC
Vanessa Williams is seen enjoying a walk through the Soho neighborhood of New York City, April 16, 2015.
GC Images/Getty Images
Sarah Jessica Parker Stays Stylish in NYC
Actress Sarah Jessica Parker is seen, April 13, 2015, in New York.
Patricia Schlein/Star Max/GC Images/Getty Images
Betty White Accepts a Legacy Award
Actress Betty White, winner of The Legend Award, poses backstage during the 2015 TV Land Awards at Saban Theatre, April 11, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Alberto E. Rodriguez/Getty Images
Morgan Fairchild Grabs a Cup of Coffee
Morgan Fairchild is seen at Los Angeles International Airport on April 07, 2015.
GVK/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Julia Louis-Dreyfus Steps Out in Leopard Print
Julia Louis-Dreyfus poses during The Paley Center For Media Hosts An Evening With The Cast Of "VEEP" at Paley Center For Media, April 7, 2015, in New York.
Randy Brooke/Getty Images
Diane Lane Steps Out In a Mini-Trench
Diane Lane is seen in Tribeca on April 6, 2015 in New York City.
Alo Ceballos/Getty Images
Dana Delaney Shows Off Her Legs
Actress Dana Delany attends the premiere of FX's 'The Comedian' at The Broad Stage, April 6, 2015, in Santa Monica, Calif.
Imeh Akpanudosen/Getty Images
Dame Joan Collins Steps Out in Leopard Print
Dame Joan Collins was spotted at Heathrow Airport in London, England on April 1, 2015.
Vantagenews/AKM-GSI
Lisa Rinna Hits the Pool in a Black String Bikini
Lisa Rinna posted this photo on Instagram, March 31, 2015.
lisarinna/Instagram
Kathleen Turner Attends a Premiere
Actress Kathleen Turner attends the New York Premiere of "Effie Gray" at The Paris Theatre on March 30, 2015 in New York City.
Debra L Rothenberg/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Goes Glam for the Red Carpet
Helen Mirren attends the "Woman In Gold" New York premiere at the Museum of Modern Art in New York, March 30, 2015.
Larry Busacca/Getty Images
Sophia Loren Stuns in White
Actress Sophia Loren speaks onstage before the screening of 'Marriage Italian Style' during day four of the 2015 TCM Classic Film Festival, March 29, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Stefanie Keenan/Getty Images
Julie Andrews Attends an L.A. Gala
Actress Julie Andrews attends the 2015 TCM Classic Film Festival's opening night gala for the 50th Anniversary of "The Sound Of Music" on March 26, 2015 in Hollywood, California.
Allen Berezovsky/Getty Images
Patricia Heaton Shines at the 'Mad Men' Premiere
Actress Patricia Heaton attends the "Mad Men" Black &amp;amp; Red Ball at Dorothy Chandler Pavilion on March 25, 2015 in Los Angeles, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Suzanne Somers Stuns in a Little Black Dress
Suzanne Somers reveals details of her upcoming residency at Westgate Las Vegas Resort and Casino, March 26, 2015.
Splash News
Debi Mazar Steps Out In a Cinched White Dress
Debi Mazar is seen in New York City on March 25, 2015.
Ignat/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images
Christie Brinkley Sparkles in New York City
Legendary supermodel Christie Brinkley spotted leaving 'The Meredith Vieira Show' in New York, March 24, 2015.
Splash News
Lea Thompson Stuns in a Colorful Mini-Dress
Lea Thompson attends the 23rd Annual 'A Night At Sardi's' To Benefit The Alzheimer's Association at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, March 18, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
JB Lacroix/Getty Images
Sally Field Makes An Appearance at SXSW
Actress Sally Field attends 'A Conversation With Sally Field' during the 2015 SXSW Music, Film + Interactive Festival at Austin Convention Center, March 15, 2015, in Austin, Texas.
Travis P Ball/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Makes a Stylish Red Carpet Appearance
Helen Mirren poses at the Opening Night After Party for "The Audience" on Broadway at Urbo NYC on March 8, 2015 in New York City.
Bruce Glikas/Getty Images
Jane Fonda Goes Low-Key to a Red Carpet
Jane Fonda attends the International Conference on Masculinities: Engaging Men and Boys for Gender Equality at the Roosevelt Hotel in New York, March 7, 2015.
Grant Lamos IV/Getty Images
Sigourney Weaver Stuns at 65
Sigourney Weaver attends the "Chappie" New York Premiere at AMC Lincoln Square Theater, March 4, 2015, in New York City.
Mike Coppola/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Meryl Streep Does the Wave
Meryl Streep attends the "Into the Woods" Japan Premiere at Roppongi Hills, March 4, 2015, in Tokyo.
Jun Sato/WireImage/Getty Images
Diane Lane Flaunts Her Svelte Figure
Diane Lane attends "The Mystery Of Love &amp;amp; Sex" Opening Night at Mitzi E. Newhouse Theater, March 2, 2015, in New York.
Rob Kim/Getty Images
Felicity Huffman Rocks a Plunging Neckline
Felicity Huffman attends the Atlantic Theater Company 30th Anniversary gala at The Pierre Hotel on March 2, 2015 in New York City.
Jim Spellman/WireImage/Getty Images
Actors Ted Danson and Mary Steenburgen attend the premiere of Fox's "The Last Man On Earth" at Big Daddy's Antique Shop in Los Angeles, on Feb. 24, 2015.
Getty Images
Christie Brinkley Rocks Leather Pants
Christie Brinkley seen, Feb. 24, 2015, in New York.
MPI02/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Loni Anderson Rocks a Silver Ensemble
Actress Loni Anderson attends the 17th Costume Designers Guild Awards on Feb. 17, 2015 in Beverly Hills, California.
Jeffrey Mayer/Getty Images
Susan Sarandon Steps Out in a Leather Dress
Actress Susan Sarandon attends the Elie Tahari Presentation during Mercedes-Benz Fashion Week Fall 2015 at 510 5th Avenue, Feb. 17, 2015, in New York.
Paul Morigi/Getty Images
Dame Judi Dench Hits the Red Carpet
Dame Judi Dench attends The Royal Film Performance and World Premiere of "The Second Best Exotic Marigold Hotel" at Odeon Leicester Square on Feb. 17, 2015 in London, England.
Dave M. Benett/WireImage/Getty Images
Can You Believe Vivica A. Fox is 50!
Vivica A. Fox attends the Angel Sanchez fashion show during Mercedes-Benz Fashion Week Fall 2015 at The Pavilion at Lincoln Center, Feb. 16, 2015, in New York City.
Chelsea Lauren/Getty Images
Kathy Griffin Rocks a Peekaboo Dress
Kathy Griffin attends Nylon and Fashion Police's "Fifty Shades Of Grey" Release Party at Dream Downtown, Feb. 11, 2015, in New York.
Mike Pont/Getty Images
Sigourney Weaver Hits the Red Carpet
Sigourney Weaver attends the "Chappie" Cast Photo Call at Crosby Street Hotel, Feb. 10, 2015, in New York City.
Astrid Stawiarz/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Is a Vision in Green
Helen Mirren arrives for a photocall for the film "Woman in Gold" presented as Berlinale Special at the 65th Berlin International Film Festival Berlinale in Berlin, Feb. 9, 2015.
Odd Andersen/AFP/Getty Images
Jodie Foster Hits the Red Carpet in a Little Blue Dress
Actress and honoree Jodie Foster attends the opening night of the 2015 Athena Film Festival at Barnard College, Feb. 5, 2015, in New York.
Michael Loccisano/Getty Images
Julianne Moore Steps Out in a Little Black Dress
Julianne Moore attends a VIP Screening of "Still Alice" at The Curzon Mayfair, Feb. 5, 2015, in London.
Dave M. Benett/Getty Images
Vivica A. Fox Goes Sheer for a Gala
Actress Vivica A. Fox attends the 2015 FEMMY Awards Gala at Cipriani 42nd Street, Feb. 3, 2015, in New York.
Andrew Toth/Getty Images
Courteney Cox Reveals Her Natural Beauty
Courteney Cox is spotted leaving a salon in Los Angeles, Calif. on Feb. 2, 2015.
WENN.com
Oprah Winfrey Stuns in Purple
Oprah Winfrey attends the 87th Annual Academy Awards Nominee Luncheon at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, Feb. 2, 2015 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Frazer Harrison/Getty Images
Anjelica Huston Dons All Black
Anjelica Huston arrives at Dame Edna's "Glorious Goodbye - The Farewell Tour" opening night held at Ahmanson Theatre, Jan. 28, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Michael Tran/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Elle Macpherson Stuns In Fringe
Elle Macpherson is seen at "Jimmy Kimmel Live," Jan. 28, 2015, in Los Angeles.
RB/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Kristin Scott Thomas Stuns at Paris Fashion Week
Kristin Scott Thomas during Paris Fashion Week, Jan. 27, 2015.
Nicolas Briquet/Abaca/startraksphoto.com
Lori Loughlin Rocks Stilettos for the Red Carpet
Actress Lori Loughlin arrives at the Los Angeles premiere of "Mortdecai" at TCL Chinese Theatre in Hollywood, Calif., Jan. 21, 2015.
WireImage
Lisa Rinna Makes a Face at Photogs
Lisa Rinna is seen, Jan. 20, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Bauer-Griffin/Getty Images
Sharon Stone Shows Off Her Low-Key Airport Style
Sharon Stone leaves LAX, Jan. 18, 2015 in Los Angeles
GVK/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Marisa Tomei Rocks a Long Red Dress
Marisa Tomei is pictured on Jan. 14, 2015 in New York City.
Dimitrios Kambouris/Getty Images
Jamie Lee Curtis Hits the Red Carpet
Actress Jamie Lee Curtis attends the premiere of "Spare Parts" at ArcLight Cinemas on Jan. 8, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Paul Archuleta/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Meryl Streep Looks Regal in Gold
Meryl Streep attends the gala screening of "Into The Woods" at The Curzon Mayfair, Jan. 7, 2015, in London.
Ian Gavan/Getty Images
Arnold Schwarzenegger Steps Out in Leather
Arnold Schwarzenegger is seen, Jan. 5, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Kirstie Alley is seen leaving 'Today Show' after an interview on January 5, 2015, in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
From left, Olivia Newton-John and Didi Conn reunite on stage to perform "Summer Nights" at Flamingo Las Vegas in Las Vegas, Nevada, Jan. 3, 2015.
David Becker/Getty Images
Goldie Hawn Steps Out with Melanie Griffith
Melanie Griffith and Goldie Hawn are seen in Aspen, Dec. 27, 2014, in Aspen, Colo.
Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Jane Seymour Stuns in Red
Jane Seymour is pictured on Dec. 14, 2014 in Los Angeles.
Paul Archuleta/Getty Images
Virginia Madsen Brightens Up The Room
Virginia Madsen attends the opening night gala of the 11th Annual Dubai International Film Festival held at the Madinat Jumeriah Complex, Dec. 10, 2014, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (Photo by Andrew H. Walker/Getty Images for DIFF)
Andrew H. Walker/Getty Images
Christine Baranski Stuns on the Red Carpet
Christine Baranski attends the world premiere of Disney's "Into the Woods" at Ziegfeld Theater, Dec. 8, 2014 in New York.
Taylor Hill/Getty Images
Julianne Moore Flashes A Big Smile
Julianne Moore speaks onstage during a Q&amp;amp;A following the screening of "Still Alice" on Dec. 8, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Imeh Akpanudosen/Getty Images
What Event Brought Bruce Springsteen, Lady Gaga, Meryl Streep and Bruno Mars Together?
Bruce Springsteen, Lady Gaga, Meryl Streep and Bruno Mars attend the 37th Annual Kennedy Center Honors at The John F. Kennedy Center for Performing Arts, Dec. 7, 2014 in Washington.
Kevin Mazur/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Attends a Charity Day
Helen Mirren attends The Annual ICAP Charity Day on Dec. 3, 2014 in London, England.
Stuart C. Wilson/Getty Images
Meryl Streep Is Honored at the White House
Barack Obama presents the Medal of Freedom to Meryl Streep during a ceremony in the East Room of the White House on Nov. 24, 2014 in Washington, D.C.
Olivier Douliery/AP Photo
Diana Ross Makes a Grand Entrance
Recording artist Diana Ross attends the 42nd Annual American Music Awards at the Nokia Theatre L.A. Live, Nov. 23, 2014, in Los Angeles.
David Livingston/Getty Images
Mary Steenburgen and Ted Danson Have a Red Carpet Date Night
Actors Ted Danson and Mary Steenburgen arrive at the Los Angeles premiere of "Wild" on Nov. 19, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Gregg DeGuire/WireImage/Getty Images
Susan Lucci Embraces Winter White
Susan Lucci attends the 'The Imitation Game' New York Premiere at the Ziegfeld Theater, Nov. 17, 2014 in New York.
Slaven Vlasic/Getty Images
Jessica Lange Stuns in a Glamorous Gown
Jessica Lange arrives at the 2014 Kirk Douglas Award For Excellence In Film Honoring Jessica Lange, Nov 16, 2014, in Goleta, Calif.
Richard Shotwell/Invision/AP Photo
Elle MacPherson Stuns In a Little Black Dress
Elle Macpherson celebrates Ocean Drive Magazine November Cover on Nov. 12, 2014 in Miami Beach, Fla.
Gustavo Caballero/Getty Images
Sophia Loren Makes a Grand Entrance
Sophia Loren arrives at AFI FEST 2014 Presented By Audi A Special Tribute To Sophia Loren at Dolby Theatre, Nov. 12, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Jon Kopaloff/Getty Images
Julianne Moore Rocks a Little Black Dress
Julianne Moore is pictured on Nov. 9, 2014 in London.
WENN.com
Holly Hunter Hits a Red Carpet Decked Out in Black
Holly Hunter attends the Off-Broadway Opening Night after party for the New Group production of 'Sticks and Bones' at Ktchn in The Out NYC on Nov. 6, 2014 in New York City.
Walter McBride/Getty Images
Judith Light Hits the Red Carpet in Leopard Print
Actress Judith Light attends the opening night of "Wiesenthal, A New Play" at the Acorn Theatre at Theatre Row on Nov. 5, 2014 in New York City.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images for Wiesenthal
Demi Moore Stuns In Black
Actress Demi Moore arrives at the 2014 LACMA Art + Film Gala Honoring Quentin Tarantino And Barbara Kruger at LACMA on Nov. 1, 2014 in Los Angeles.
Jon Kopaloff/Getty Images
Olivia Newton-John Steps Out in All Black
Olivia Newton-John is pictured on Oct. 29, 2014 in Los Angeles.
Michael Bezjian/Getty Images
Judith Light Shines Bright
Judith Light attends the "Lips Together, Teeth Apart" opening night on Oct. 29, 2014 in New York City.
Esther Horvath/Getty Images
Sharon Stone Flaunts Her Amazing Figure
Sharon Stone arrives at the 2014 amfAR LA Inspiration Gala at Milk Studios on Oct. 29, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Jon Kopaloff/Getty Images
Renee Russo Stuns On the Red Carpet
Actor Rene Russo attends the "Nightcrawler" New York Premiere at AMC Lincoln Square Theater, Oct. 27, 2014 in New York.
Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images
Melanie Griffith Goes Out to Support Sting
Melanie Griffith and Sting pose at The Opening Night After Party for "The Last Ship" on Broadway at Pier 60 on Oct. 26, 2014 in New York City.
Bruce Glikas/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Jane Seymour Looks Flawless in NYC
Jane Seymour attends Fashion Group International's 31st Annual Night of Stars: The Protagonists at Cipriani Wall Street on Oct. 23, 2014 in New York City.
Taylor Hill/Getty Images
Melanie Griffith Rocks a Little Black Dress
Actress Melanie Griffith attends the 2014 Power of Pink at House of Blues Sunset Strip on Oct. 23, 2014 in West Hollywood, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Bo Derek Rocks the Red Carpet
Bo Derek attends the opening night of "Pippin" at the Pantages Theatre on Oct.22, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Vincent Sandoval/Getty Images
Bette Midler Debuts a New, Cropped Hairdo
Bette Midler attends the Off-Broadway opening Night Performance of 'Billy &amp; Ray' at the Vineyard Theatre on Oct. 20, 2014 in New York City.
Walter McBride/Getty Images
Ming-Na Wen Rocks a Little Black Dress
Ming-Na Wen attends the 'Marvel Agents Of S.H.I.E.L.D' premiere and panel discussion during the 2nd Annual Paleyfest New York at Paley Center For Media, Oct. 19, 2014, in New York.
Jemal Countess/Getty Images
Maggie Smith Meets the Queen
Dame Maggie Smith is made a member of the Order of the Companion of Honor by Queen Elizabeth II during an investiture ceremony at Windsor Castle, England, Oct. 17, 2014.
Dominic Lipinski/PA/AP Photo
Demi Moore Steps Out for Charity
Demi Moore attends the Malcolm Gladwell and Lisa and Eric Eisner in support of YES event on Oct. 15, 2014 in West Hollywood, Calif.
Araya Diaz/Getty Images
Joan Jett Rocks the Red Carpet
Joan Jett attends the premiere of Foo Fighters "Sonic Highways" at the Ed Sullivan Theater, Oct. 14, 2014, in New York City.
Kevin Mazur/WireImage/Getty Images
Julianne Moore Stuns in Plum
Actress Julianne Moore attends the Still Alice premiere during the 2014 Hamptons International Film Festival, Oct. 13, 2014. in East Hampton, New York.
Eugene Gologursky/Getty Images
Demi Moore Flaunts Her Tiny Waist
Actress Demi Moore attends the 5th annual PSLA Autumn Party at 3LABS, Oct. 8, 2014, in Culver City, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Angela Bassett Has Never Looked Better
Angela Bassett arrives at the premiere screening of FX's "American Horror Story: Freak Show" held at the TCL Chinese Theatre, Oct. 5, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Albert L. Ortega/Getty Images
Blythe Danner Goes to a Broadway Party
Blythe Danner attends "The Country House" opening night after party at the Hard Rock Cafe, Times Square, Oct. 2, 2014, in New York City.
John Lamparski/WireImage/Getty Images
Glenn Close Is All Smiles
Actress Glenn Close leaves the "Today Show" taping at the NBC Rockefeller Center Studios, Oct. 1, 2014 in New York City.
Ray Tamarra/Getty Images
Diane Keaton Matches Her Mani to Her Striped Ensemble
Diane Keaton attends the 'And so it goes' Press Conference during Day 7 of Zurich Film Festival 2014 on Oct. 1, 2014 in Zurich, Switzerland.
Andreas Rentz/Getty Images
Lynda Carter Flashes Her Wonder Woman Smile
Lynda Carter appears at the Bally Technologies booth to introduce two of the company's two new slot machines, Wonder Woman Wild and Wonder Woman Gold, at the Global Gaming Expo (G2E) 2014, Sept. 30, 2014, at the Sands Expo and Convention Center in Las Vegas.
Gabe Ginsberg/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Jaclyn Smith Takes in a Broadway Show
Jaclyn Smith attends the Broadway Opening Night performance of 'You Can't Take It With You' at the Longarce Theatre in New York, Sept. 28, 2014.
Walter McBride/Getty Images
Jane Fonda and Lily Tomlin Hit the Red Carpet
Jane Fonda, left, and Lily Tomlin, right, arrive at The Rape Foundation's annual brunch on Sept. 28, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Valerie Macon/Getty Images
Marcia Gay Harden Goes Blue for a Red Carpet
Actress Marcia Gay Harden attends the screening of CBS Films' 'Pride' at AMPAS Samuel Goldwyn Theater on Sept. 23, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Imeh Akpanudosen/Getty Images
Sophia Loren Stuns at Her 80th Birthday Celebration in Mexico City
Sophia Loren attends a press conference and the opening of an exhibition celebrating her 80th birthday at Museo Soumaya on Sept. 18, 2014 in Mexico City, Mexico.
Victor Chavez/Getty Images
Kim Cattrall Shines on the Red Carpet
Kim Cattrall attends American Masters; The Boomer List NYC Premiere on Sept. 18, 2014 in New York City.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images
Melanie Griffith Steps Out In L.A.
Melanie Griffith is all smiles as she shows off her long legs while taking a stroll through downtown Los Angeles, Sept. 14, 2014.
GC Images/Getty Images
Betsey Johnson Gears Up for 'Dancing with the Stars'
Betsey Johnson leaves 'Dancing with the Stars' rehearsals, Sept. 14, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Splash News
Jane Fonda is Ravishing in Red
Jane Fonda is pictured on Sept. 8, 2014 in Toronto, Canada.
George Pimentel/Getty Images
Reba McEntire Stuns in Velvet
Reba McEntire attends a cocktail reception held at Palazzo Spini Feroni benefitting the Andrea Bocelli Foundation and The Muhammad Ali Parkinson Center, Sept. 4, 2014, in Florence, Italy.
Rachel Murray/Getty Images
Goldie Hawn Clowns Around
Goldie Hawn is seen checking out the construction site of her future Pacific Palisades home on Sept. 3, 2014.
X17online.com
Helen Mirren Stuns in Red
Helen Mirren is seen leaving Claridges, Sept. 2, 2014 in London.
SAV/GC Images/Getty Images
Gladys Knight Is All Smiles at the US Open
Gladys Knight attends the 2014 US Open on Aug. 28, 2014 in New York City.
Uri Schanker/GC Images/Getty Images
Lisa Rinna is White Hot!
Lisa Rinna is seen in Los Angeles, Aug. 26, 2014.
Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Felicity Huffman and William H. Macy Get Cozy on the Carpet
William H. Macy and Felicity Huffman attend Showtime's 2014 "EmmyEve Soiree" at Sunset Tower, Aug. 24, 2014, in West Hollywood, Calif.
Tibrina Hobson/Getty Images
Susan Lucci is White Hot in NYC
Susan Lucci leaves the "Today Show" taping at the NBC Rockefeller Center Studios, Aug. 12, 2014, in New York.
Ray Tamarra/Getty Images
Paula Abdul Stuns in a Little Black Dress
Paula Abdul attends the Television Academy's Directors Peer Group Celebrates the 66th Emmy Awards Outstanding Choreography Nominees at the Leonard H. Goldenson Theatre, Aug. 10, 2014, in North Hollywood, Calif.
Frederick M. Brown/Getty Images
Mary Steenburgen Shines on the Red Carpet
Mary Steenburgen attends the premiere of "The One I Love" at the Vista Theatre, Aug. 7, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Annette Bening Looks Fresh In White
Actress Annette Bening attends the curtain call for The Public Theatre's Opening Night Performance of "King Lear" at Delacorte Theater on August 5, 2014 in New York City.
Stephen Lovekin/Getty Images
Dana Delany Goes Ladylike in Polka Dots
Actress Dana Delany attends the premiere of Tri Star Pictures' "When the Game Stands Tall" at ArcLight Cinemas on August 4, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Christopher Polk/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Goes Elegant in Blue Lace
Helen Mirren attends the world premiere of Dreamworks Pictures' "The Hundred-Foot Journey," on August 4, 2014 at Ziegfeld Theatre in New York City.
Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images
See Elisabeth Shue Still Fabulous at 50
Elisabeth Shue arrives at the 'Behaving Badly' premiere at ArcLight Hollywood in Hollywood, Calif., July 29, 2014.
Jeffrey Mayer/Getty Images
Julie Louis Dreyfus Stuns at an Emmys Event
Julia Louis-Dreyfus attends the Television Academy's performers peer group celebrating the 66th Emmy Awards at Montage Beverly Hills, July 28, 2014, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Sandra Bullock Joins the 'Fab Over 50' Club
Sandra Bullock attends the 2014 AFI Life Achievement Award: A Tribute to Jane Fonda at the Dolby Theatre, June 5, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif. The actress turned 50 on Saturday, July 26, 2014.
Kevin Mazur/Getty Images
Ellen Burstyn Hits a Premiere in Champagne
Ellen Burstyn attends Lionsgate and Roadside Attraction's premiere of "A Most Wanted Man" hosted by The Cinema Society and Montblanc at the Museum of Modern Art in New York, July 22, 2014.
Dimitrios Kambouris/Getty Images
Glenn Close Shines at a Charity Event
Actress Glenn Close announces a $1.5 million charitable donation at a press conference at the Fountain House on July 18, 2014 in New York City.
Jemal Countess/Getty Images
Andie McDowell Hops on a Bike
Actress Andie McDowell along with 70 models dressed as her character celebrate "Debbie Macomber's Cedar Cove" season 2 premiere on July 17, 2014 in New York City.
Ben Gabbe/Getty Images
How Elle Macpherson Maintains Her Amazing Bikini Body at 50
Elle Macpherson tweeted this photo with this caption: "Super greens... After super swim", July 15, 2014.
@ellemacpherson/Twitter
Sharon Stone Stuns in L.A.
Sharon Stone is seen on July 9, 2014 in Los Angeles, Calif.
JMA/Star Max/GC Images/Getty Images
Shirley MacClaine Dazzles in Spain
Actress Shirley MacLaine attends the "Wild Oats" photocall at the Lopesan Costa Meloneras Hotel on July 8, 2014 in Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain.
Carlos R. Alvarez/Getty Images
Andie MacDowell Stuns in Royal Purple
Andie MacDowell is pictured on July 8, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Paul Archuleta/Getty Images
Martha Stewart Shows Team USA Spirit
Martha Stewart, proudly wearing her Team USA soccer jacket, leaves the "Today Show" taping at the NBC Rockefeller Center Studios on July 1, 2014 in New York City.
Ray Tamarra/Getty Images
Sharon Stone Shows Love for Paris
Sharon Stone is pictured on June 30, 2014 in Los Angeles.
SMXRF/Star Max/Getty Images
Dolly Parton Lights Up a Stage in White
Dolly Parton performs during day three of the Glastonbury Festival on June 29, 2014 in Glastonbury, England.
Jim Dyson/Getty Images
Sheryl Crow Flashes Serious Leg
Sheryl Crow attends the Happy Hearts Fund Gala with Chopard 10 year anniversary of the Indian Ocean tsunami tribute at Cipriani 42nd Street on June 19, 2014 in New York City.
Brad Barket/Getty Images for Happy Hearts Fund
Bo Derek Stuns in Italy
Bo Derek attends the 60th Taormina Film Fest on June 18, 2014 in Taormina, Italy.
Venturelli/Getty Images
Bette Midler Shines on the Red Carpet
Actress Bette Midler attends 30th Annual Literacy Partners Evening of Readings and Gala Dinner at Cipriani 42nd Street on June 17, 2014 in New York City.
Paul Zimmerman/Getty Images
Sophia Loren Goes Glam
Italian actress Sophia Loren arrives at the David Di Donatello Awards at Studi Dear on June 10, 2014 in Rome, Italy.
Ernesto Ruscio/Getty Images
Patti LaBelle Takes a Curtain Call
Patti LaBelle joins the cast of 'After Midnight' starring Dule Hill at the Brooks Atkinson Theatre on June 10, 2014 in New York City.
Walter McBride/Getty Images
Sharon Osbourne Goofs Around in London
Sharon Osbourne is seen at the Soho Townhouse on June 9, 2014 in London, England.
Mark Robert Milan/GC Images/Getty Images
Sally Field and Meryl Streep Share a Laugh
Actors Meryl Streep and Sally Field attend the 2014 AFI Life Achievement Award: A Tribute to Jane Fonda on June 5, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Kevin Mazur/Getty Images
Lily Tomlin and Jane Fonda
Actress Lily Tomlin (L) and honoree Jane Fonda attend the 2014 AFI Life Achievement Award: A Tribute to Jane Fonda on June 5, 2014 in Hollywood, California.
Frazer Harrison/Getty Images
Christie Brinkley Rocks Leather Pants
Christie Brinkley takes a walk in the West Village, in New York, June 5, 2014.
Splash News
Judith Light Hits the Red Carpet In a Suit
Judith Light attends HBO Documentary Films "The Case Against 8" Los Angeles premiere at Directors Guild Of America, June 3, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Vincent Sandoval/WireImage/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Stuns In White Lace
Dame Helen Mirren attends the Glamour Women of the Year Awards in Berkeley Square Gardens on June 3, 2014 in London, England.
David M. Benett/Getty Images
Dana Delany Hits the Red Carpet
Actress Dana Delaney attends the 7th Annual Television Academy Honors at the SLS Hotel on June 1, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
John M. Heller/Getty Images
Helen Hunt Hits the Beach
Helen Hunt donned a spring suit for a bit of boogie boarding in Malibu, Calif. on May 29, 2014.
X17online.com
Jane Fonda Stuns In Pink at Cannes
Jane Fonda is pictured on May 22, 2014 in Cap d'Antibes, France.
Dave M. Benett/Getty Images
Sharon Stone Goes Short and Sultry in Cannes
Sharon Stone attends "The Search" premiere during the 67th Annual Cannes Film Festival, May 21, 2014, in Cannes, France.
Traverso/L'Oreal/Getty Images
Sophia Loren Stuns in Cannes
Sophia Loren attends the "Voce Umana" premiere at the 67th Annual Cannes Film Festival on May 20, 2014 in Cannes, France.
Anthony Harvey/Getty Images
See Goldie Hawn Sizzle at 68
Goldie Hawn is pictured on May 15, 2014 in New York City.
Brad Barket/Getty Images
Natalie Cole Steps Out in Red
Natalie Cole is seen in London, May 14, 2014.
SJP/Bauer-Griffin/Getty Images
Jane Fonda Shows Off Her Wild Side
Jane Fonda arrives in Nice, France for the 67th Annual Cannes Film Festival on May 13, 2014.
Jacopo Raule/Getty Images
Julia Louis-Dreyfus Still Got it at 53!
Julia Louis-Dreyfus attends the premiere of "Fed Up" at Pacfic Design Center, May 8, 2014, in West Hollywood, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Sally Field Buddies Up to Jane Fonda
Sally Field and Jane Fonda attend the ceremony honoring Sally Field with a Star on The Hollywood Walk of Fame on May 5, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
JB Lacroix/Getty Images
Bo Derek Still a 10 at 57
Bo Derek greets fans outside Craig's Restaurant, April 16, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
WL-Maciel/X17online.com
Cher: Her Outrageous Concert Ensembles
Cher performs in concert at TD Garden, April 9, 2014 in Boston.
Joel Ginsburg/WENN.com
Rob Lowe: Looking Ageless at 50
Actor Rob Lowe is seen on April 8, 2014, in New York City.
DVT/Star Max/GC Images
Vanessa Williams Makes Her Broadway Debut
Vanessa Williams poses backstage after her first performance in the Broadway musical 'After Midnight,' April 1, 2014 in New York.
Adam Nemser/startraksphoto.com
Julia Louis-Dreyfus Goes Form-Fitting for 'Veep' Premiere
Julia Louis-Dreyfus attends the "Veep" season 3 premiere at Paramount Studios, March 24, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Mark Davis/Getty Images
Susan Sarandon: So Chic at 67!
Actress Susan Sarandon is seen in Soho on March 20, 2014 in New York City.
Raymond Hall/GC Images/Getty Images
Is Madonna Channeling Miley Cyrus?
Madonna posted this image on Instagram with this caption: "Still cleaning house! A Woman"s work is never done! I should have worn a wife beater. But i like getting dressed up! #bowdownbitches," March 12, 2014.
madonna/Instagram
Darryl Hannah Hits SXSW as 'Splash' Turns 30
Producer Darryl Hannah attends the photocall for "Above All Else" during the 2014 SXSW Film, Music + Interactive Festival at Paramount Theatre on March 10, 2014 in Austin, Texas.
Michael Buckner/Getty Images
Raquel Welch: Sexy at 72
Actress Raquel Welch presents onstage during the 16th Costume Designers Guild Awards with presenting sponsor Lacoste at The Beverly Hilton Hotel on February 22, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Jerod Harris/Getty Images
Lea Thompson Looks Stunning at 52
Lea Thompson arrives at the 'Vampire Academy' premiere at Event Cinemas George Street in Sydney, Australia, Feb. 20, 2014.
Brendon Thorne/Getty Images
Christie Brinkley Stuns at 60
Christie Brinkley attends the Sports Illustrated Swimsuit 50th Anniversary event, Feb. 17, 2014, in New York City.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images
Kim Basinger is 60 ? Really!
Actress Kim Basinger attends the Ralph Lauren fashion show during Mercedes-Benz Fashion Week Fall 2014 at St. John Center Studios on Feb. 13, 2014 in New York City.
Larry Busacca/Getty Images
Dolly Parton Flaunts Her Curves at 68
Dolly Parton speaks on stage during her press conference at Rod Laver Arena in Melbourne to promote the Australian leg of her 'Blue Smoke World Tour,' Feb. 10, 2014.
Splash News
Anthony Kiedis Rocks the Super Bowl
The Red Hot Chili Peppers band members Anthony Kiedis, right, and Flea perform during the halftime show of the NFL Super Bowl XLVIII football game, Feb. 2, 2014, in East Rutherford, N.J.
Julio Cortez/AP Photo
Florence Henderson
Actress Florence Henderson attends the premiere of Sony Pictures Classics' "Tim's Vermeer" at Pacific Design Center on Jan. 29, 2014 in West Hollywood, Calif.
Angela Weiss/Getty Images
Attention 'Charlie's Angels' Fans: Jaclyn Smith and Cheryl Ladd Reunite!
Jaclyn Smith and Cheryl Ladd are seen having lunch at The Ivy on Jan. 22, 2014 in Los Angeles.
GONZALO/Getty Images
Christie Brinkley
Christie Brinkley arrives at the 50th Anniversary Of Sports Illustrated Swimsuit Issue celebration, Jan. 14, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Jon Kopaloff/Getty Images
Helen Mirren
Actress Helen Mirren attends HBO's Golden Globe Awards after party at Circa 55 Restaurant on Jan. 12, 2014 in Los Angeles, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Kris Jenner Rocks a Skimpy Bikini
Kris Jenner posted this on Instagram with this caption, "Celebrate Life", Jan. 7, 2014.
krisjenner/Instagram
Jane Seymour Rocks a String Bikini at 62!
Former 'Bong Girl' Jane Seymour showed off her amazing bikini body while with her family in Hawaii, as the 62 year old British actress posed for pictures with her granddaughter on Jan. 2. 2014.
AKM-GSI
Jane Seymour Rocks a String Bikini at 62!
Jane Seymour wears a pink bikini on the cover of Closer Weekly's Jan. 13, 2014 issue.
Closer Weekly
Kim Basinger Stuns at 60
Actress Kim Basinger attends the "Grudge Match" screening benefiting the Tribeca Film Insititute at Ziegfeld Theater, Dec. 16, 2013, in New York City.
Taylor Hill/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Goldie Hawn
Honoree Goldie Hawn attends the 2013 amfAR Inspiration Gala Los Angeles at Milk Studios on December 12, 2013 in Los Angeles, California.
Jason Merritt/Getty Images
Sheryl Crow
Singer Sheryl Crow arrives at the American Country Awards 2013 on December 10, 2013 in Las Vegas, Nevada.
Jon Kopaloff/Getty Images
Julie Andrews and Dick Van Dyke Reunite!
Julie Andrews and Dick Van Dyke attend the U.S. premiere of Disney's "Saving Mr. Banks" at Walt Disney Studios, Dec. 9, 2013 in Burbank, California.
Kevin Winter/Getty Images
Nicollette Sheridan Stuns at 50
Nicollette Sheridan celebrates the premiere of "The Christmas Spirit" at The Empire State Building, Nov. 25, 2013, in New York.
Slaven Vlasic/Getty Images
Helen Mirren Stuns at 69!
Helen Mirren attends the 'Red 2' premiere at Tokyo International Forum, Nov. 24, 2013 in Tokyo.
Jun Sato/WireImage/Getty Images
Sharon Stone Stuns in India
Sharon Stone attends the inaugural amfAR India event at the Taj Mahal Palace Mumbai, Nov. 17, 2013, in Mumbai, India.
Kevin Tachman/Getty Images
Can You Believe Emma Thompson Is 54?
Actress Emma Thompson arrives at the premiere of Walt Disney Pictures' "Saving Mr. Banks" during AFI FEST 2013 presented by Audi at the Chinese Theatre, Nov. 7, 2013 in Hollywood, Calif.
Kevin Winter/Getty Images
Jane Fonda is seen leaving Mr. Chow restaurant, Nov. 1, 2013, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Splash News
Christie Brinkley
Christie Brinkley out shopping with her daughters, Alexa and Sailor, in East Hampton, N.Y., Oct. 27, 2013.
Matt Agudo/INF
Wow! Helen Hunt Flaunts Her Bikini Body
Helen Hunt was seen washing the sea salt off her body by pouring a container of water over her face after taking an early morning swim in the ocean on a chilly morning in Los Angeles. Hunt wore her wetsuit before stripping it off and parading around in her underwear as passers-by looked on on Oct. 24, 2013.
Splash News
Martha Stewart Goes Glinda
Martha Stewart attends Hub Network's First Annual Halloween Bash in Barker Hangar at the Santa Monica Airport, Oct. 20, 2013 in Santa Monica, Calif.
Frederick M. Brown/Getty Images
Helen Mirren: Red Hot at 68
Dame Helen Mirren attends the Mandarin Oriental Hong Kong's 50th anniversary gala, Oct. 17, 2013, in Hong Kong.
Jessica Hromas/Getty Images for the Mandarin Oriental Hotel Group
Michelle Pfeiffer Looks Hotter Than Ever With Robert DeNiro and Dianna Agron
From left, Michelle Pfeiffer, Robert de Niro and Dianna Agron attend the premiere of "The Family" in Berlin, Germany, Oct. 15, 2013.
Anita Bugge/Getty Images
Sally Field and Jane Fonda Share a Smile
Jane Fonda and Sally Field attend the 2013 Women's Media Awards, Oct. 8, 2013 in New York.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images
Cher Celebrates Album Release
Cher celebrates the launch of her new album "Closer To The Truth" at Tao in New York, Sept 26, 2013.
Splash News
Goldie Hawn and Kurt Russell Cuddle Up
Actors Kurt Russell and Goldie Hawn attend DuJour's Jason Binn and Kurt Russell's celebration of Goldie Hawn and The Hawn Foundation at Espace, Sept. 25, 2013 in New York City.
Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images
Cher arrives to NBC's TODAY Show in New York, Sept. 23, 2013.
Slaven Vlasic/Getty Images
Can You Believe Jane Fonda is 75?
Jane Fonda attends the 2013 Women's Media Awards Kick Off Party in New York, Sept. 17, 2013.
Mike Coppola/Getty Images
Jane Seymour
Actress Jane Seymour attends American Ballet Theatre's annual "Stars Under The Stars: An Evening In Los Angeles" event, Sept. 12, 2013 in Hollywood.
Allen Berezovsky/Getty Images
Sharon Stone, 55, Goes Makeup-Free
Sharon Stone takes a walk in West Hollywood, Calif., wearing no make up and no bra, Sept. 11, 2013.
KMM-Ionu/X17online.com
Julianne's New Look
Julianne Moore films a scene on the set of "Maps To The Stars" on Rodeo Drive in Beverly Hills, Calif., August 19, 2013.
FameFlynet
Christie's Pretty In Pink
Christie Brinkley at the Ellens Run Pink Apron Party in Southampton, New York, August 17, 2013.
Diane Cohen/FameFlynet Pictures
Donatella Versace Shows Off Beach Body
Donatella Versace spent her holidays with her family on the beach at Parrot Bay in the Turks and Caicos Islands.
INFphoto.com
Melanie Griffith
Melanie Griffith enjoys a relaxing vacation with her husband Antonio Banderas (not shown) in the South of France, July 31, 2013.
FameFlynet
Helen Hunt Rocks her Bathing Suit
Helen Hunt rocks her bathing suit in her new film "Ride", Aug. 5 2013 in Los Angeles, Calif.
Gaz Shirley/PacificCoastNews.com
Jessica Lange Wows at American Horror Panel
Jessica Lange stunned the panel in a sleek gray dress while discussing secrets from the upcoming season of "American Horror Story: Coven" at the Television Critic Association's Summer Press Tour - FX panel at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, Aug. 2, 2013, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Tommaso Boddi/WireImage/Getty Images
Sharon Stone
Actress Sharon Stone attends the after party for a screening of Radius TWC's "Lovelace" at Refinery Hotel, July 30, 2013 in New York City./Stephen Lovekin/Getty Images
Stephen Lovekin/Getty Images
Jamie Lee Curtis
Jamie Lee Curtis is vacationing in Hawaii, spotted in a swimsuit at the beach. She was seen with a couple of friends enjoying the friendly water, July 25, 2013.
starsurf/Stewy/Splash News
Goldie Hawn Looking Fabulous
Retired actress Goldie Hawn is all smiles while she rides her bike around the neighborhood in Brentwood, Calif., July 22, 2013.
Pablo/Goodwin/FameFlynet
Helen Mirren
Helen Mirren attends the Red 2 Premiere at Empire Leicester Square, July 22, 2013 in London.
Fred Duval/Getty Images
Catherine Zeta-Jones is sighted, July 16, 2013 in New York.
DVT/Star Max/Getty Images
Tina Turner
Tina Turner, 73, is rumored to be wedding her long-term German partner Erwin Bach, reports the NY Post. The couple has been living together in Switzerland for the past 15 years.
Miro Kuzmanovic/Reuters
Heather Locklear Looks Age Defying In White Bikini
Heather Locklear looks radiant while defying her age, and stunning passersby, in a white skirt and bikini top on the beach in Hawaii, July 7, 2013.
Splash News
Cher
Cher shows that she still has it as she arrives at LAX Airport in Los Angeles looking youthful and vibrant. The 67-year-old singing legend, who is known for her unique choice in fashion, was dressed in a pair of black leggings, black hoodie over a neon green tee, black hat and a pair of shades.
AKM-GSI
Christie Brinkley Fabulous At Fifty
Christie Brinkley attended her "Social Life Magazine" Cover Celebration on May 25, 2013 in Water Mill, New York. The 59 year old rocked a floral mini dress.
Jerritt Clark/WireImage/Getty Images
Goldie Hawn
Actress Goldie Hawn poses, May 23, 2013 as she arrives for the amfAR's 20th Annual Cinema Against AIDS during the 66th Annual Cannes Film Festival at Hotel du Cap-Eden-Roc in Cap d'Antibes, southern France.
ALberto Pizzoli/AFP/Getty Images
Vanessa Williams
Vanessa Williams arrived in style for the after party for her Broadway play, "A Trip to Bountiful," April 24, 2013.
Splash News
Goldie Hawn, 67, getting a workout on her bike, April 21, 2013, in Los Angeles.
X17
Goldie Hawn and Kurt Russell
Goldie Hawn and Kurt Russell enjoyed some time at Dolphin Discovery in Puerto Aventuras, Feb. 17, 2013. The 67-year-old actress donned a red one piece bathing suit for their day in the sun.
XposurePhotos.com
Michael Jordan
Basketball legend Michael Jordan, who played with the NBA from 1984 to 2003, is now the majority owner and chairman of the Charlotte Bobcats. He turns 50 Feb. 17, 2013.
Ross Dettman/AP Photo
David Hasselhoff
David Hasselhoff tweeted this photo Jan. 15, 2013 of him and Rolling Stones, Ronnie Wood. "Hangin with Ronnie Wood in Necker ! What a cool guy," he tweeted with the picture.
Twitter/David Hasselhoff
Sean Penn
Sean Penn makes 52 look &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt;. The actor showed off his bulging muscles while walking along the beach in Maui, Hawaii on Dec. 31, 2012.
Splash News
Jamie Lee Curtis: Fabulous Over 50
Jamie Lee Curtis showed off her killer figure in an off-the-shoulder white fitted dress at the Los Angeles premiere of the film "Hitchcock" on Nov. 20, 2012. Curtis celebrated her 54th birthday on Thanksgiving Day. Her mother, Janet Leigh, starred in Alfred Hitchcock's iconic film "Psycho."
Matt Sayles/Invision/AP Photo
Jodie Foster Fabulous at 50
Jodie Foster, 50, attended the 49th Annual ICG Publicists Awards at the Beverly Hilton Hotel on Feb. 24, 2012, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Mathew Imaging/WireImage/Getty Images
Heather Locklear
Heather Locklear's had her ups and downs, but 50 seems pretty swell for the "Melrose Place" star. The actress looked like a woman half her age while taking a tennis lesson in Malibu on Aug. 1. Click through to see more stars who hit the big 5-0 this year.
Jeff Steinberg/Pacific Coast News
Gina Gershon
50 looks pretty sensational on Gina Gershon. The actress wowed on the red carpet of her new movie, "Killer Joe," on July 23 in New York City.
Jim Spellman/WireImage/Getty Images
Tom Cruise turned 50 on July 3, just days after Katie Holmes filed for divorce.
Larry Busacca/Getty Images
"Mad Men" star John Slattery, who plays Roger Sterling, turns 50 Aug. 13.
Frank Ockenfels/AMC
Star Jones
Star Jones held a two-day celebration in New York for her 50th birthday on March 24.
D Dipasupil/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Sheryl Crow
Sheryl Crow, the singer and mother of two boys, turned 50 on Feb. 11. Crow recently learned she has a benign brain tumor that she'll need to monitor with periodic scans.
Rick Diamond/Getty Images
Rosie O'Donnell
For her 50th birthday on March 21, Rosie O'Donnell partied with the staff of her OWN television talk show, despite learning that the show had been cancelled.
Michael Roman/Getty Images
Kelly Preston
Kelly Preston will turn 50 on Oct. 13. She recently gave birth to her third child with husband John Travolta, a boy they named Benjamin.
Michael Loccisano/Getty Images
"The Daily Show" host Jon Stewart turns 50 on Nov. 28, 2012.
Taylor Hill/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Jodie Foster
Jodie Foster, Oscar-winning actress and mother of sons Christopher and Charlie Foster, turns the big 5-0 on Nov. 19.
Eric Charbonneau/WireImage/Getty Images
Funnyman Jim Carrey turned 50 on Jan. 17, 2012.
Kevin Mazur/WireImage/Getty Images
Rocker Axl Rose of Guns N' Roses turned 50 on Feb. 6, 2012.
Jason Merritt/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:35:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Helen Hunt Stops By 'GMA'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/photos/aprils-top-celebrity-pictures-29925980</Link>
        <Description>This month's hottest celebrity pictures.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Helen Hunt Stops By 'GMA'
Helen Hunt tapes an interview at "Good Morning America" at the ABC Times Square Studios, April 30, 2015, in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
Helen Hunt Stops By 'GMA'
Helen Hunt tapes an interview at "Good Morning America" at the ABC Times Square Studios, April 30, 2015, in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
Cynthia Nixon
Cynthia Nixon leaves the "Today Show" taping at the NBC Rockefeller Center Studios, April 30, 2015, in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
Kristen Wiig
Kristen Wiig attends the 'Welcome To Me' New York Premiere at Sunshine Landmark, April 29, 2015, in New York City.
Manny Carabel/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Jenny McCarthy Stuns in a Bright Green Dress
Jenny McCarthy attends the Mrs. &amp;amp; Jenny McCarthy's Mother's Day Celebration on April 29, 2015 in New York City.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images
Elle Macpherson at the Ivy Club on April 29, 2015 in London, England.
Mark Robert Milan/Getty Images
Anna Faris
Anna Faris attends For Your Consideration Television Academy Screening on April 29, 2015 in Burbank, California.
Araya Diaz/Getty Images
Jessica Alba Has a Serene Moment on Her Birthday
Jessica Alba enjoys a stroll in the sun on her birthday, April 28, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GC Images/Getty Images
Kevin Jonas
Kevin Jonas of the Jonas Brothers attends the AOL 2015 Newfront, April 28, 2015, in New York City.
Brian Ach/Getty Images
Jada Pinkett Smith
Jada Pinkett Smith attends Fox's "Gotham" Season Finale Screening at Landmark Theatre, April 28, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Alberto E. Rodriguez/Getty Images
Jordana Brewster
Pond's ambassador Jordana Brewster and her stunning mom showed off their glowing skin at the Rejuveness Anti-Wrinkle Cream campaign event in New York City, April 27, 2015.
Michael Simon
Tamera Mowry
Tamera Mowry shows how she gets in a quick workout when there's no time for the gym as part of T.J.Maxx's #MaxxMoms movement on how moms make it work, April 28, 2015.
Tamera Mowry/Instagram
Naya Rivera
Naya Rivera spotted at the L'Oreal Paris Advanced Haircare #PowerOn event at Ulta in Los Angeles, April 27, 2015.
Michael Simon
Nick Lachey
Nick Lachey at the NYC Hallmark Gold Crown store picking out the perfect Mother's Day card for his wife Vanessa in New York City, April 27, 2015.
Susan Waters
Mary Louise Parker In Huge Platforms Poses with Bruce Willis
Actors Bruce Willis and Mary-Louise Parker attend the 2015 Tony Awards Nominations Announcement on April 28, 2015 in New York City.
Bryan Bedder/Getty Images
Singer Brett Michaels at SiriusXM Studios on April 28, 2015 in Nashville, Tenn.
Terry Wyatt/Getty Images
Jennifer Aniston Flashes Her Engagement Ring in NYC
Actress Jennifer Aniston is seen walking in Soho, April 27, 2015, in New York.
Raymond Hall/GC Images/Getty Images
Robin Wright and Kevin Spacey
Actors Robin Wright and Kevin Spacey attend Netflix's "House of Cards" Q&amp;A screening event at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater, April 27, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
David Livingston/Getty Images
Michelle Rodriguez
Actress Michelle Rodriguez attends the 2015 Yahoo Digital Content NewFronts at Avery Fisher Hall, April 27, 2015, in New York.
Robin Marchant/Getty Images
Debi Mazar
Actress Debi Mazar attends the 2015 AAFA American Image Awards, April 27, 2015, in New York.
Andrew Toth/Getty Images
Salma Hayek Is All Smiles on the Red Carpet
Salma Hayek poses for a photo as she walks the red carpet to launch the global premiere of her animated adaptation of Kahlil Gibran's celebrated novel "The Prophet" in Beirut, April 27, 2015.
Joseph Eid/AFP/Getty Images
Chrissy Teigen
Chrissy Teigen arrives at the 42nd Annual Daytime Emmy Awards at Warner Bros. Studios, April 26, 2015, in Burbank, California.
Angela Weiss/Getty Images
Kate Upton Enjoys a Sunny Day
Kate Upton seen at BBC Radio One, April 27, 2015, in London.
Neil P. Mockford/GC Images/Getty Images
Drew Barrymore
Actress Drew Barrymore is seen, April 26, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GP/Star Max/GC Images/Getty Images
Jose Antonio Baston and Eva Longoria
Jose Antonio Baston and Eva Longoria seen out in Soho waiting for a taxi, April 26, 2015, in New York.
Josiah Kamau/BuzzFoto/Getty Images
Jamie Fox Goes Out in Shades of Grey
Jamie Foxx attends the V-103 Breakfast Conversation With Jamie Foxx at The W Hotel Midtown, April 24, 2015, in Atlanta.
Paras Griffin/Getty Images
Jennifer Morrison &amp; Cobie Smulders
Jennifer Morrison and Samsung Galaxy Edge Award Recipient Cobie Smulders poses backstage at Variety's Power of Women New York presented by Lifetime at Cipriani 42nd Street, April 24, 2015, in New York City.
Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images
Brooke Burke-Charvet
Brooke Burke-Charvet spotted donning her red nose while taking a selfie in support of the first ever Red Nose Day in America at Walgreens in Los Angeles, April 23, 2015.
Michael Simon
Rob Lowe Goes Low-Key For a Flight from LA
Rob Lowe seen at LA, April 23, 2015 in Los Angeles.
GVK/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Megan Fox seen at LAX, April 23, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GVK/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Rose Byrne Is Spotted on the Red Carpet
Rose Byrne attends 20th Century Fox's "Invites You to a Special Presentation Highlighting Its Future Release Schedule" at The Colosseum during CinemaCon, April 23, 2015 in Las Vegas.
Michael Buckner/Getty Images
Collin Firth &amp; Jeremy Piven
Colin Firth and Jeremy Piven attend the opening night performance of "La Fille Mal Gardee" at The Royal Opera House, April 23, 2015, in London.
David M. Benett/Getty Images
Brooke Shields Stuns In White at a Broadway Opening
Brooke Shields attends "Something Rotten!" Broadway Opening Night at St. James Theatre, April 22, 2015, in New York.
Jenny Anderson/Getty Images
Actress Zendaya is seen, April 22, 2015, in New York.
Ray Tamarra/GC Images/Getty Images
Arnold Schwarzenegger and Robert De Niro
Actors Arnold Schwarzenegger and Robert De Niro attend the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival world premiere narrative: "Maggie" at BMCC Tribeca PAC, April 22, 2015, in New York.
Jim Spellman/Getty Images
Sarah Hyland and Julie Bowen Share a Squeeze
Sarah Hyland and Julie Bowen, right, attend the premiere of "See You In Valhalla" at ArcLight Cinemas, April 21, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Paul Archuleta/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Taraji P. Henson is seen leaving the Magic FM Studios, April 22, 2015, in London.
GC Images/Getty Images
Julianna Margulies and Her Husband Hit the Red Carpet
Julianna Margulies and Keith Lieberthal attend TIME 100 Gala, TIME's 100 Most Influential People In The World at Jazz at Lincoln Center, April 21, 2015, in New York.
Kevin Mazur/Getty Images
Lindsey Vonn
Honoree Lindsey Vonn attends the Time 100 Gala celebrating the Time 100 issue of the Most Influential People at The World at Jazz at Lincoln Center, April 21, 2015, in New York.
Timothy A Clary/AFP/Getty Images
Actress Claire Danes attends TimesTalks at TheTimesCenter, April 21, 2015, in New York City.
Jerritt Clark/Getty Images
Joanna Krupa
Model Joanna Krupa attends the 10th anniversary of ABC's "Dancing with the Stars" at Greystone Manor, April 21, 2015 in West Hollywood, Calif.
David Livingston/Getty Images
Reese Witherspoon and Sofia Vergara Share a Laugh
Reese Witherspoon and Sofia Vergara laugh on the set of "Despierta America" to promote the film "Hot Pursuit" at Univision Studios, April 21, 2015, in Miami.
Gustavo Caballero/Getty Images
Chris Hemsworth
Chris Hemsworth poses with a young fan at the European premiere of "The Avengers: Age Of Ultron," April 21, 2015, in London.
David M. Benett/WireImage/Getty Images
Blake Lively
Blake Lively spotted leaving her LA hotel with the Henri Bendel Rivington Tote, April 18, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Michael Simon
Lala Anthony
No time for the spa! Lala Anthony was spotted stocking up on Suave Professionals Sea Mineral Infusion body products in New York City, April 20, 2015.
Michael Simon
Vanessa Hudgens
Vanessa Hudgens perfects her legs backstage at ABC Studios with Sally Hansen Airbrush Legs, before an interview to promote her play Gigi, April 20, 2015, in New York City.
Michael Simon
Chrissy Teigen Steps Out in Sexy Mini-Dress
Chrissy Teigen arrives at 'Watch What Happens Live' studios in Soho, April 20, 2015, in New York.
Josiah Kamau/BuzzFoto/Getty Images
Amy Schumer is seen, April 20, 2015, in New York.
Patricia Schlein/Star Max/GC Images/Getty Images
Rita Ora
Singer Rita Ora leaves Z100, April 20, 2015, in New York.
Ray Tamarra/GC Images/Getty Images
Taylor Swift Makes a Bright Appearance in NYC
Taylor Swift looks great as she is seen walking around Soho on April 19, 2015 in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
Ben Affleck is seen picking up some groceries in Los Angeles, April 19, 2015.
GC Images/Getty Images
January Jones
January Jones attends the premiere of 'Good Kill' during the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival at BMCC Tribeca PAC, April 19, 2015, in New York City.
Grant Lamos IV/Getty Images
Tim McGraw and Faith Hill Stun at a Movie Premiere
Singer/ actors Faith Hill and Tim McGraw attend the "Dixieland" Premiere during the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival at SVA Theater, April 19, 2015, in New York.
Cindy Ord/Getty Images
Zoe Kravitz, Ethan Hawke and January Jones
Actors Zoe Kravitz, Ethan Hawke and January Jones attend the U.S. Premiere of 'Good Kill' during the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival at BMCC Tribeca PAC, April 19, 2015, in New York.
Gilbert Carrasquillo/Getty Images
Sofia Vergara and Reese Witherspoon
Actresses Sofia Vergara and Reese Witherspoon attend the 50th Academy Of Country Music Awards at AT&amp;amp;T Stadium, April 19, 2015, in Arlington, Texas.
Rick Kern/Getty Images
Mila Kunis Stuns in a Crisp White Shirt
Actress Mila Kunis attends the Burberry "London in Los Angeles" event at Griffith Observatory, April 16, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Gregg DeGuire/Getty Images
Cara Delevingne
Model Cara Delevingne attends the Burberry "London in Los Angeles" event at Griffith Observatory, April 16, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Stefanie Keenan/Getty Images
Sofia Vergara
Sofia Vergara performs at the Film Independent at LACMA Live Read of "Major League" at Bing Theatre At LACMA, April 16, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Araya Diaz/Getty Images
Luke Hemsworth
Actor Luke Hemsworth attends the premiere of "The Water Diviner" at TCL Chinese Theatre IMAX, April 16, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Robert De Niro Preps for the Tribeca Film Festival
Robert De Niro attends the Juror Welcome Lunch - 2015 Tribeca Film Festival on April 16, 2015 in New York City.
Theo Wargo/Getty Images
Olivia Wilde
Olivia Wilde attends 2015 Tribeca Film Festival - Tribeca Talks: Master Class: ARC Adorama Rental Company The Producers at SVA Theatre 2, April 16, 2015, in New York City.
Esther Horvath/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Blake Lively
Blake Lively is seen getting ready to tape an interview to promote her new movie 'The Age of Adeline' in Los Angeles, April 13, 2015.
Michael Simon/startraksphoto.com
Reese Witherspoon Steps Out in Mile-High Shoes
Actress Reese Witherspoon is seen, April 15, 2015, in New York.
ESBP/Star Max/GC Images/Getty Images
Amber Heard
Actress Amber Heard is seen arriving to the 2015 Tiffany Blue Book dinner at ABC Kitchen on April 15, 2015 in New York.
Gilbert Carrasquillo/GC Images/Getty Images
Kelly Rutherford
Actress Kelly Rutherford attends the Opening Night premiere of "Live From New York!" during the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival at the Beacon Theatre, April 15, 2015, in New York.
Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images
Ludacris
Rapper Ludacris attends the Opening Night premiere of "Live From New York!" during the 2015 Tribeca Film Festival at the Beacon Theatre, April 15, 2015, in New York.
Jamie McCarthy/Getty Images
Judith Light Cozies Up to Julianna Margulies
Julianna Margulies and Judith Light attend the Broadway Opening Night Performance of 'It Shoulda Been You' at The Brooks Atkinson Theatre, April 14, 2015, in New York City.
Walter McBride/Getty Images
Joe Manganiello
Joe Manganiello is spotted leaving the gym after a workout, April 15, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GC Images/Getty Images
Nick Jonas is seen arriving at Charles-de-Gaulle airport, April 15, 2015, in Paris.
GC Images/Getty Images
Gwyneth Paltrow Wears Her Heart On Her Shoes
Actress Gwyneth Paltrow attends a dinner to celebrate The Victoria Beckham Collection at Fred's at Barneys, April 14, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Donato Sardella/Getty Images
Miranda Kerr is seen upon arrival at Haneda Airport, April 14, 2015, in Tokyo.
Jun Sato/GC Images/Getty Images
Eva Longoria
Actress Eva Longoria attends David And Victoria Beckham, Along With Barneys New York, Host A Dinner To Celebrate The Victoria Beckham Collection at Fred's at Barneys, April 14, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Donato Sardella/Getty Images
'How I Met Your Mother' Star Cobie Smulders Poses with Taran Killam
Cobie Smulders and Taran Killam arrive at the Los Angeles premiere of Marvel's "Avengers: Age Of Ultron" at Dolby Theatre, April 13, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Gregg DeGuire/WireImage/Getty Images
Jessica Alba
Jessica Alba picks up some coffee on her stroll through New York City, April 14, 2015.
GC Images/Getty Images
Jennie Garth is seen on the set of her Motrin 'Make It Happen Weekends' campaign in Malibu, Calif., April 13, 2015.
Michael Simon
Vanessa Williams
Vanessa Williams is spotted at the TracFone display in Walmart supporting 'Success is Calling', a new program in partnership with 'Dress for Success' to teach women phone interview skills in Secaucus, NJ, April 13, 2015.
Michael Simon
Jenny McCarthy
Jenny McCarthy hosts the launch of Strip House's 'Strip Tease' late night menu, April 13, 2015, in New York City.
Michael Simon/startraksphoto.com
Chris Hemsworth Snuggles Up to Wife Elsa Pataky
Chris Hemsworth and Elsa Pataky attend the premiere of Marvel's "Avengers: Age Of Ultron" at the Dolby Theatre, April 13, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Robyn Beck/AFP/Getty Images
Elizabeth Moss
Elizabeth Moss attends National Corporate Theatre Fund's 2015 Chairman's Awards Gala at The Pierre Hotel, April 13, 2015, in New York.
Desiree Navarro/Getty Images
Mark Ruffalo and Chris Evans
Actors Mark Ruffalo and Chris Evans attend the premiere of Marvel's "Avengers: Age Of Ultron" at Dolby Theatre, April 13, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Mark Davis/Getty Images
Brooke Shields
Actress Brooke Shields attends the 2015 Tribeca Ball at New York Academy of Art, April 13, 2015, in New York.
Gilbert Carrasquillo/Getty Images
Chrissy Teigen
Chrissy Teigen is seen on a photo shoot in Los Angeles, April 13, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Gonzalo/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Kate Winslet Stuns in Cobalt
Kate Winslet attends the UK premiere of "A Little Chaos" at ODEON Kensington, April 13, 2015, in London.
Dave M. Benett/WireImage/Getty Images
Kate Hudson Arrives at LAX Airport, April 10, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Michael Simon/startraksphoto.com
Octavia Spencer is seen exiting 'The View', April 13, 2015, in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
Cody Simpson
Cody Simpson plays a party game at the Music Lounge during the Coachella Music Festival while wearing a Call of Duty Black Ops 3 t-shirt, April 12, 2015, in Palm Springs, Calif.
Michael Simon
Jennifer Lopez Steps Out in a Little Black Dress
Actress/singer Jennifer Lopez arrives at the 2015 MTV Movie Awards at Nokia Theatre L.A. Live, April 12, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Gregg DeGuire/Getty Images
Kendall Jenner
Kendall Jenner is seen at Coachella Valley Music and Arts Festival at The Empire Polo Club, April 11, 2015, in Indio, Calif.
Light Brigade/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Sofia Vergara and Reese Witherspoon
Actors Sofia Vergara and Reese Witherspoon attend The 2015 MTV Movie Awards at Nokia Theatre L.A. Live, April 12, 2015, in Los Angeles.
MTV/MTV1415/Getty Images
Alessandra Ambrosio Goes Cowboy for Coachella
Model Alessandra Ambrosio attends Forever 21 BBQ on April 11, 2015 in La Quinta, Calif.
Stefanie Keenan/Getty Images
Liv Tyler Snuggles Up to Dave Gardner
Liv Tyler and Dave Gardner attend Ottawa Senators vs New York Rangers game at Madison Square Garden, April 9, 2015, in New York.
James Devaney/GC Images/Getty Images
Christina Milian
Christina Milian attends Christina Milian Brings We Are Pop Culture To Shiekh Shoes, April 8, 2015, in West Hollywood, Calif.
Michael Bezjian/WireImage
Jenny McCarthy Enjoys a Casual Day in NYC
Jenny McCarthy is seen leaving her SiriusXM radio show, April 8, 2015, in New York City.
Josiah Kamau/Getty Images
Uma Thurman
Uma Thurman is spotted at New York City's Serge Normant at John Frieda Salon picking up Frizz Ease products, in support of Hairraising.org, April 9, 2015, in New York.
Michael Simon
Simon Cowell
Simon Cowell arrives for the Britain's Got Talent launch at The Mayfair Hotel, April 9, 2015, in London.
GC Images/Getty Images
Miranda Kerr arrives at LAX airport, April 8, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Michael Simon/startraksphoto.com
Gwen Stefani Makes a Fashionable Exit in L.A.
Gwen Stefani is seen, April 8, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Chinchilla/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Vanessa Hudgens and Corey Cott
Vanessa Hudgens and Corey Cott attend 'Gigi' Broadway Opening Night - After Party at Tavern On The Green, April 8, 2015, in New York.
Dimitrios Kambouris/Getty Images
Ashanti stops by the Godiva store, April 8, 2015, in New York.
MPI02/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Ricky Gervais
Actor Ricky Gervais arrives for the screening of Netflix's "Derek" at Paramount Studios, April 8, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Frazer Harrison/Getty Images
'Pitch Perfect 2' Costars Brittany Snow and Anna Camp Strike a Pose
Brittany Snow and Anna Camp attend the premiere of Vertical Entertainment's "Dial a Prayer" at the Landmark Theater, April 7, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Getty Images
Ben Affleckgets some coffee while out for a stroll in Los Angeles, April 07, 2015.
GC Images/Getty Images
Jennifer Westfeldt
Jennifer Westfeldt attends "Hand To God" Broadway Opening Night at Booth Theater, April 7, 2015, in New York City.
Ben Hider/Getty Images
Hilary Swank Hits the Red Carpet in Hot Pink
Hilary Swank arrives on the red carpet at the Samsung Galaxy S 6 edge launch in New York, April 7, 2015, in New York.
Neilson Barnard/Getty Images
Freida Pinto
Freida Pinto is seen at the special screening of 'Desert Dancer' at Museum of Modern Art, April 7, 2015, in New York.
Josiah Kamau/BuzzFoto/Getty Images
Eva Longoria is seen at LAX, April 7, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Chinchilla/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Chrissy Tiegen and Jussie Smollett Match In All-Black Ensembles
Chrissy Teigen and actor Jussie Smollett speak during the "2015 Billboard Music Awards" finalists press conference, April 7, 2015, in Santa Monica, Calif.
Kevin Winter/Getty Images
Josh Gad &amp; Billy Crystal
Josh Gad and Billy Crystal attend the premiere of FX's "The Comedians" at The Broad Stage, April 6, 2015, in Santa Monica, Calif.
Alberto E. Rodriguez/Getty Images
Josh Hartnett
Josh Hartnett and girlfriend Tamsin Egerton spend some time together out strolling through the Soho neighborhood of New York City, April 6, 2015.
Josiah Kamau/Getty Images
Peyton List
Peyton List celebrates her 17th birthday and receives her first car, a new Mercedes-Benz CLA250, April 6, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Sara Jaye Weiss/StartraksPhoto
Joanna Krupa
Joanna Krupa goes on a power walk in the hills of Los Angeles with her dog and a shake from 310 Nutrition, April 6, 2015.
Michael Simon
Reese Witherspoon Enjoys a Sunny L.A. Day
Reese Witherspoon is seen in Beverly Hills on April 6, 2015 in Los Angeles, Calif.
Getty Images
Jessica Alba is seen at Craig's restaurant on April 6, 2015 in Los Angeles, Calif.
Getty Images
Michael Douglas
Actor Michael Douglas is seen walking in Midtown on April 6, 2015 in New York City.
Getty Images
Scott Eastwood and Britt Robertson
Actor Scott Eastwood and actress Britt Robertson attend the premiere of Twentieth Century Fox's "The Longest Ride" at the TCL Chinese Theatre IMAX on April 6, 2015 in Hollywood, Calif.
Michael Buckner/Getty Images
J.K. Simmons Throws Out the First Pitch for the Tigers
J.K. Simmons throws out the first pitch of the Opening Day game between the Minnesota Twins and the Detroit Tigers at Comerica Park, April 6, 2015, in Detroit.
Leon Halip/Getty Images
Arnold Schwarzenegger is seen enjoying a bike ride in sunny Los Angeles, April 04, 2015.
GC Images/Getty Images
Rob Lowe
Rob Lowe is seen arriving at LAX for a flight, April 4, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GC Images/Getty Images
Kate Hudson Enjoys a Warm L.A. Day
Kate Hudson is seen in Los Angeles, April 4, 2015.
Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Kristen Stewart seen at LAX, April 5, 2015, in Los Angeles.
GVK/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Actress Lily James is seen upon arrival at Haneda Airport, April 6, 2015, in Tokyo.
Jun Sato/GC Images/Getty Images
Heather Graham Defies Her Age at 45
Heather Graham visits at SiriusXM Studios, April 3, 2015, in New York City.
Robin Marchant/Getty Images
Rosario Dawson
Rosario Dawson attends the Premiere of Netflix's "Marvel's Daredevil" at Regal Cinemas L.A. Live, April 2, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Angela Weiss/Getty Images
Kelly Ripa Sparkles in a Silver Skirt and Plaid Top
Kelly Ripa leaves the "Late Show with David Letterman" at Ed Sullivan Theater on April 2, 2015 in New York City.
Donna Ward/Getty Images
Tom Brady
Tom Brady is seen arriving to the set for his latest UGG shoot on April 2, 2015 in Boston, Massachusetts.
GC Images/Getty Images
January Jones is seen on April 2, 2015 in Los Angeles, California.
Getty Images
Hailey Baldwin
Hailey Baldwin and Bella Hadid walk together in West Village after doing a photo shoot on April 2, 2015 in New York, New York.
Josiah Kamau/BuzzFoto via Getty Images
Elisabeth Moss Flashes a Smile
Elisabeth Moss walks into Rockefeller Center, April 2, 2015, in New York City.
GC Images/Getty Images
Katherine McPhee
Katharine McPhee attends the JustFab Apparel Launch Event at Sunset Tower, April 1, 2015, in West Hollywood, Calif.
Imeh Akpanudosen/Getty Images
Ethan Hawke seen at BBC Radio 2 studios, April 2, 2015, in London.
GC Images/Getty Images
The Rock Gives a Fist Pump and a Smile
Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson is seen, April 1, 2015, in Los Angeles.
JB Lacroix/GC Images/Getty Images
Michelle Rodriguez
Michelle Rodriguez arrives at the "Furious 7" - Los Angeles Premiere at TCL Chinese Theatre IMAX, April 1, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Steve Granitz/Getty Images
Kevin James receives a star on the Miami Walk Of Fame, April 1, 2015.
Gustavo Caballero/Getty Images
Charlize Theron Sparkles In Paris
Charlize Theron attends the 'Dark Places' Paris Premiere at Cinema Gaumont Capucine, March 31, 2015, in Paris.
Pascal Le Segretain/Getty Images
Anna Wintour &amp; Dakota Johnson
Anna Wintour, left, and Dakota Johnson attend the CHANEL Paris-Salzburg 2014/15 Metiers d'Art Collection in New York City at the Park Avenue Armory, March 31, 2015.
Stefanie Keenan/WireImage/Getty Images
Jamie Doran
'Fifty shades of Grey' actor Jamie Dornan is seen out shopping with his wife Amelia Warner, April 1, 2015, in London.
GC Images/Getty Images
Sophia Bush
Sophia Bush is looking gorgeous in a Kohl's MILLY for DesigNation collection dress, available April 23, while in Chicago, March 30, 2015.
Michael Simon
Christina Hendricks Stuns in a Red Dress
Emmy nominated actress, Christina Hendricks at the Jaguar Land Rover exclusive reception to unveil the 2016 Jaguar XF and Range Rover SVAutobiography in advance of the New York International Auto Show, at Center548, March 31, 2015, in New York City.
Neilson Barnard/Getty Images
Julianne Moore
Actress Julianne Moore attends the CHANEL Paris-Salzburg 2014/15 Metiers d'Art Collection at Park Avenue Armory, March 31, 2015, in New York.
Dimitrios Kambouris/Getty Images
Sofia Vergara is seen, March 31, 2015, in Los Angeles.
MPI99/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images/Getty Images
Rita Ora attends Tommy Hilfiger, Boutique Opening, March 31, 2015, in Paris.
Pierre Suu/GC Images/Getty Images
Pharrell Williams is seen leaving the hotel, March 31, 2015, in New York.
Charles Bladen/GC Images/Getty Images
Chrissy Teigen is seen in Soho, March 31, 2015, in New York City.
Alo Ceballos/GC Images/Getty Images
Elizabeth Banks
Actress/executive producer Elizabeth Banks arrives at the Los Angeles premiere of Hulu's "Resident Advisors" at Sherry Lansing Theatre at Paramount Studios, March 31, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Gregg DeGuire/Getty Images
Hilary Duff
Actress Hilary Duff attends the Premiere Of TV Land's "Younger" at Landmark Sunshine Cinema, March 31, 2015, in New York.
Ben Gabbe/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:03:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>AP Source: Chris Christie Ex-Ally Set to Plead Guilty to Role in New Jersey Traffic Jam Case</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/ap-source-chris-christie-ally-set-plead-guilty-30726479</Link>
        <Description>AP source: Chris Christie ex-ally set to plead guilty to role in New Jersey traffic jam case</Description>
        <MainBody>AP Source: Chris Christie Ex-Ally Set to Plead Guilty to Role in New Jersey Traffic Jam Case
NEWARK, N.J.  May 1, 2015, 9:02 AM ET
AP source: Chris Christie ex-ally set to plead guilty to role in New Jersey traffic jam case.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:00:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top-Seeded Karolina Pliskova Reaches Final of Prague Open</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Sports/wireStory/top-seeded-karolina-pliskova-reaches-final-prague-open-30723780</Link>
        <Description>Top-seeded Karolina Pliskova to face qualifier Lucie Hradecka in Prague Open final</Description>
        <MainBody>Top-Seeded Karolina Pliskova Reaches Final of Prague Open
PRAGUE  May 1, 2015, 8:59 AM ET
Top-seeded Karolina Pliskova produced an ace on her first match point Friday and advanced to the Prague Open final by beating Yanina Wickmayer of Belgium 6-4, 7-5.
It was one of 11 aces for the hard-hitting, 14th-ranked Czech.
Pliskova will face qualifier Lucie Hradecka in an all-Czech final. Hradecka beat another Czech, unseeded Katerina Siniakova, 6-2, 4-6, 6-4.
Pliskova failed to serve out the match at 5-4 but Wickmayer double-faulted to drop her serve in the following game.
In her third final of the year, Pliskova will seek her first title of 2014, and fourth overall.
Hradecka converted her first match-point with a service winner to advance to her seventh career final. She has never won a tournament.
The 18-year-old Siniakova was a set down and trailed 4-2 when she came back, winning four straight games and taking the second set on her fifth set point when Hradecka double-faulted.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:59:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fiat Chrysler US Sales Rise 6 Percent in April</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Business/wireStory/fiat-chrysler-us-sales-rise-percent-april-30725753</Link>
        <Description>Jeep brand breaks April US sales record, leads Fiat Chrysler to 6 pct. year-over-year increase</Description>
        <MainBody>Fiat Chrysler US Sales Rise 6 Percent in April
DETROIT  May 1, 2015, 8:58 AM ET
By TOM KRISHER AP Auto Writer
Led by record sales of Jeeps, Fiat Chrysler posted a 6 percent U.S. sales gain last month, a sign that Americans continued to buy cars and trucks at a brisk pace.
But the results fell a little short of analysts' predictions, also showing that auto sales growth could be slowing.
Fiat Chrysler said it sold just over 189,000 cars and trucks for its best April since 2007. The Jeep brand posted its best monthly sales at nearly 72,000, up 20 percent from a year ago.
The Cherokee compact SUV led the way with a 27 percent increase to just over 19,000, while the brand sold more than 4,200 new Renegade subcompact SUVs in their first full month at dealerships. Sales of the Ram pickup, Fiat Chrysler's top-selling vehicle, rose only 3 percent to just under 38,000, but that was still the best April ever for the trucks.
The TrueCar.com auto pricing site had expected Fiat Chrysler sales to rise 10.6 percent and Edmunds.com predicted a 7.5 percent increase.
Overall, industry analysts expect U.S. sales to rise around 6 percent when all automakers report their April results on Friday.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:59:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hollywood Rolls out Red Carpet to 'Influencer' Fans</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Health/wireStory/hollywood-rolls-red-carpet-influencer-fans-30723784</Link>
        <Description>Hollywood lets young 'influencer' fans behind the velvet curtain to help market movies</Description>
        <MainBody>Hollywood Rolls out Red Carpet to 'Influencer' Fans
LOS ANGELES  May 1, 2015, 8:58 AM ET
By RYAN NAKASHIMA AP Business Writer
Clad in his pajamas, Reid Jones often blogs about Marvel superhero movies, with starry ambitions of one day becoming an entertainment journalist.
A few weeks ago, the 16-year-old woke up to that opportunity when he was invited to conduct red carpet interviews with the stars of Marvel's "Avengers: Age of Ultron" during the Los Angeles premiere.
"It really felt like it was a dream," says Jones, who traveled with his dad from Kennesaw, Ga., to the premiere of the movie that hits theaters Friday.
Major Hollywood studios like Disney-owned Marvel are anxious to win over super fans, especially those who help build excitement online among other youngsters ahead of a movie's debut. While the fan connection has long been cultivated at conventions like Comic-Con or Disney's Star Wars Celebration, young writers like Jones  whose posts have been read nearly 11 million times  are increasingly being courted at events once reserved for traditional media outlets.
This outreach is important for marketers, who call people like Jones "influencers" because they reach an under-25 crowd of frequent moviegoers, who are not as easily reached by the traditional 30-second TV ads that advertisers typically use to reach their parents. Fading are the days when movie critics at newspapers, magazines and other publications set the tone, particularly for the big-budget superhero movies that can make or break a studio's annual revenue target.
"When you're reaching young people, you have to go to where the authorities on culture exist," says Angela Courtin, chief marketing officer for Relativity Media, the studio that has co-financed "Fast &amp; Furious" series and is releasing action comedy "Masterminds," this fall. "They're no longer in bylines of The New York Times or the Los Angeles Times. They're now on YouTube and Snapchat and Instagram and Vine."
Many of these influencers write blogs for sites like Moviepilot, which draw a large following of the younger audience marketers covet. According to Google Analytics, 37 percent of site visitors are under 25 years old, and 71 percent are under 35.
Moviepilot Inc. CEO Tobi Bauckhage says that last fall, he and his co-founders decided to change the direction of their movie fan site to take posts directly from readers, which is when usage began to take off. In March, it had 17.3 million unique U.S. visitors, more than double that of a year ago, according to comScore. In a single week in April, fan posts outnumbered editor posts 1,431 to 486.
Bauckhage attributes the growing popularity to fans like Jones, the Georgia teen who for the last year has written more than a post a day for Moviepilot. A month ago, he pored over a trailer and deduced  correctly  the hidden nature of the new character, Vision, in "Avengers: Age of Ultron." He also figured out how two distinct weapons are actually part of one giant one that will determine the universe's fate in the two-part Avengers sequel three years from now.
"People like Reid knew more about specifics than some of our editors did," says Bauckhage, who sold off the original website he founded in Germany and launched a U.S. version in May 2013. "We realized we really have to empower these kids to become creators."
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:58:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Macedonian Opposition Chief Charged Over Wiretapping Scandal</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/wireStory/macedonian-opposition-chief-charged-wiretapping-scandal-30726478</Link>
        <Description>Macedonian prosecutors charge opposition leader for alleged mass wiretapping</Description>
        <MainBody>Macedonian Opposition Chief Charged Over Wiretapping Scandal
SKOPJE, Macedonia  May 1, 2015, 8:57 AM ET
Macedonian prosecutors have filed charges against the country's main opposition leader and former intelligence officials for alleged wiretapping following a scandal that has poisoned politics in the small Balkan country for months.
Zoran Zaev is accused of "violence against the representatives of the highest state institutions." If convicted, he faces a minimum 4-year prison sentence.
The office of the prosecutor for organized crime and corruption also charged Macedonia's former intelligence chief, his wife and a former employee with espionage and unauthorized wiretapping late Thursday.
Zaev denies wrongdoing. He has accused conservative Prime Minister Nikola Gruevski of ordering the illegal wiretapping of 20,000 people, including police and judges. Gruevski rejects the allegations.
A senior judicial council will decide whether and when the five should stand trial.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:54:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Filipinos Urged to Turn off Appliances During Pacquiao Fight</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Sports/wireStory/filipinos-urged-turn-off-appliances-pacquiao-fight-30725354</Link>
        <Description>Filipinos urged to turn off appliances during Pacquiao fight to avoid power outages</Description>
        <MainBody>Filipinos Urged to Turn off Appliances During Pacquiao Fight
MANILA, Philippines  May 1, 2015, 8:53 AM ET
By OLIVER TEVES Associated Press
An officer at a Philippine electric company has urged customers to turn off major appliances to help prevent outages that have recently plagued his province so people can watch the much-awaited fight between Filipino boxer Manny Pacquiao and Floyd Mayweather .
Palawan Electric Cooperative secretary Rante Ramos said Friday shutting down refrigerators in 15,000 households alone will reduce the demand for electricity in the province enough to compensate for the expected power deficit of 2 megawatts when the fight is aired in the Philippines on Sunday.
He said air conditioners, washing machines and electric pots also consume a lot of electricity.
"If it is just for the Pacquiao fight, let us just leave electric fans and TVs on," Ramos said. "We have waited so long for this, and now that it will happen ... it is unacceptable not to have the opportunity to watch it."
The electric cooperative, which only distributes electricity, said there has been an average of 3-hour outages in Palawan because of a breakdown and maintenance shutdown of four power generators in the province.
Big power consumers such as malls, department stores and hotels have agreed to disconnect from the grid and use their own power generators from 9 a.m. to 1 p.m. on Sunday to also help reduce the load.
"This is not only for the fight," Ramos said. "We also want to teach citizens to show concern for fellow citizens, and of course to save electricity."
Ramos said he first made the suggestion in a personal Facebook post on Wednesday and it has received positive responses and has been shared by others in Palawan, the island province southwest of Manila.
Sen. Ralph Recto had served notice to energy officials as early as February to do all they can to prevent any power outages when Pacquiao fights Mayweather for what could be boxing's richest event.
Recto said they will be made "punching bags" by the people who will be deprived of watching the fight.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 21:41:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Check Out This Zebra's 'Zelfie'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Lifestyle/photos/amazing-animal-photobombs-20345462</Link>
        <Description>Amazing Animal Photobombs: Animals try to steal the limelight. </Description>
        <MainBody>
Check Out This Zebra's "Zelfie"
A visitor to a wildlife park seemed to make a new friend when a zebra stuck its head through his car window and posed for a selfie. Malte Woestefeld, a 24-year-old business administration student, was on a day trip to Zoo Safaripark in Holte-Stukenbrock, Germany, April 118, 2015, when he took the picture.
Malte Woestefeld/REX Shutterstock
Check Out This Zebra's "Zelfie"
A visitor to a wildlife park seemed to make a new friend when a zebra stuck its head through his car window and posed for a selfie. Malte Woestefeld, a 24-year-old business administration student, was on a day trip to Zoo Safaripark in Holte-Stukenbrock, Germany, April 118, 2015, when he took the picture.
Malte Woestefeld/REX Shutterstock
Sea Turtle Photobombs in the Philippines
Diovanie De Jesus and others were posing for a group photo at Apo Island in the Philippines when they were photobombed by a sea turtle surfacing to breathe.
Diovanie De Jesus
Ostrich Takes Bite Out of GoPro
An ostrich decides to take a bite out of a GoPro camera at the Amaru Zoo, in Cuenca, Ecuador on Feb. 27, 2015.
Caters News Agency
Playful Koala Gets Into the Selfie Spirit
Animals at Scotland's Edinburgh Zoo got into the selfie spirit, snapping a few pics of themselves using a small camera that activates when the animals pick it up.
Edinburgh Zoo
Diver Snaps Selfie With a Fascinated Fish
Gary Brennand is a diver from Perth, Australia, who loves to take photos with marine life. Here, a colorful fish makes its way into the frame.
Gary Brennand/Caters News
Dolphin Makes Big Splash in Couple's Wedding Photo
Alexis and Steve Espey tied the knot earlier this year by celebrating at Marineland Dolphin Adventure in St. Augustine with dolphins performing in the background of their wedding photos.
Sarah and Ben McLachlan/Caters News Agency
Lucky Swimmer Has a Whale of a Time
This is the majestic moment a group of humpback whales appear to dance with a lucky diver spotted on the horizon by Craig Parry, 35, during a trip to Vavau, Tonga.
Craig Parry/Caters News Agency
Say Cheese! Camel Smiles For Selfie
A group of friends spent several hours in the desert feeding camels before one of the animals joined the shot.
Hossam Antikka/Caters News Agency
Extremely Happy Parrotfish Photobombs Unsuspecting Diver
A parrotfish swimming near Eastern Dry Rocks at Key West in Florida, USA, caught a diver totally unaware as it dropped into the picture as the diver is busily posing for the camera. Sophia Roth, owner of Snuba of Key West, captured the image while diving in one of the areas many coral reefs.
Caters News Agency
You Have to See This Wild Selfie
Latabe the elephant took a selfie at West Midlands Safari Park in Worchester, Great Britain with a visitor's phone.
rossparry.co.uk
Robert Inman and his son Raphael with the cheeky stingray which photobombed their picture at The Deep aquarium in Hull, United Kingdom.
Emily Inman/ SWNS
See How A Squirrel Messed Up This Kids Selfie
Brian Genest took a selfie with a squirrel while visiting colleges in Tampa, Florida, but the startled squirrel decided to attack him.
Caters News Agency
A Rothschild giraffe roams the grounds at the Giraffe Manor in Nairobi, Kenya. The unique hotel in Nairobi, Kenya is known for its unique charm and offers guests an unparallelled experience with the friendly giants who are free to roam the 140-acre grounds.
Caters News Agency
Tomomi Nakazawa is seen with Gavin, the photobombing fish in the Great Barrier Reef.
Caters News Agency
Unbelievable Shark Photobomb
A shark is seen in the background of this photo taken by June Emerson on Dec. 27, 2013 on Manhattan Beach in California.
June Emerson/KABC/ABC News
Giraffe Photobombs Couple
A beluga whale photobombs newlyweds during their wedding at the Mystic Aquarium in Mystic, Conn., Oct. 5, 2013.
Weefan Photography
Amazing Animal Photobombs
Deirdre Mead and Jonathan Itskov were at Six Flags in New Jersey celebrating Mead's birthday, but had no idea they would get the picture of a lifetime as a special birthday treat. Already known for his silly behavior, Conan the giraffe is a regular culprit for photo bombing at Six Flags Adventure Land.
Deirdre Mead/Caters News
Giraffe Photobombs Couple
Flickr user Mary Cummins posted this image with caption, "I was trying to take a pic of Lyle the bunny with the wood cat. Hattie kitty jumped off the table to join us. She photobombed his photo."
Mary Cummins/Flickr
Giraffe Photobombs Couple
"Kitty Photobomb!" Flickr user Shawn B. posted this image of Sake, the Siamese cat, photobombing Boris, the black cat, at their home in Belleville, IL.
ZenLikeMe/Flickr
Amazing Animal Photobombs
A curious sloth photobombed a snapshot taken of young people with an International Student Volunteers expedition in Costa Rica.
Caters News Agency
Amazing Animal Photobombs
A still camera on a sound trigger captured this photo of an airborne frog as NASA's LADEE spacecraft lifted off from Pad 0B at Wallops Flight Facility in Virginia.
Chris Perry/NASA
Giraffe Photobombs Couple
Genevieve Morrison posted this image of a Boston terrier pit bull named Hogwarts wanting in on the action between Red Boston terrier Clementine and Michael Hogan in McKinny, Texas.
Genevieve Elaine Photography
Amazing Animal Photobombs
Just as Melissa and Jackson Brandts were about to take a vacation photo at Lake Minnewanka in Canada's Banff National Park, a squirrel jumped in front of the camera, stealing the spotlight. The photo, submitted to National Geographic's ?Your Shot? contest, has become an Internet hit.
ABC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:35:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Who's This Future Wrestler-Turned-Action Star?</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/photos/photos-famous-11334609</Link>
        <Description>See your favorite stars grow up.</Description>
        <MainBody>
Dwayne "The Rock" Johnson
Dwayne "The Rock" Johnson is seen in his senior year in 1990 at Freedom High School in Bethlehem, Pa. Right, Actor Dwayne Johnson is seen, April 21, 2015 in Las Vegas.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Dwayne "The Rock" Johnson
Dwayne "The Rock" Johnson is seen in his senior year in 1990 at Freedom High School in Bethlehem, Pa. Right, Actor Dwayne Johnson is seen, April 21, 2015 in Las Vegas.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Michelle Pfeiffer
Michelle Pfeiffer seen here in her freshman year in 1973 at Fountain Valley High School in Fountain Valley, Calif. Right, Actress Michelle Pfeiffer attends the Television Academy's 23rd Hall of Fame induction gala at Regent Beverly Wilshire Hotel, March 11, 2014, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Renee Zellweger
Renee Zellweger is seen here in eighth grade in 1983 at Katy Junior High School in Katy, Texas. Right, Renee Zellweger attends the Miu Miu show as part of the Paris Fashion Week Womenswear Fall/Winter 2015/2016, March 11, 2015, in Paris.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Kelly Clarkson
Kelly Clarkson seen here in sixth grade, 1994, at Burleson Pauline G. Hughes Middle School, in Burleson, Texas. Right, Singer Kelly Clarkson visits the SiriusXM Studios, March 5, 2015, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jack Nicholson
Jack Nicholson seen here in his senior year in 1954 at Manasquan High School in Manasquan, N.J. Right, Jack Nicholson poses at the 85th Annual Academy Awards at Dolby Theatre, Feb. 24, 2013, in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jessica Lange
Jessica Lange seen here in her senior year in 1967 at Cloquet High School in Cloquet, Minn. Right, Actress Jessica Lange arrives at the 21st Annual ELLE Women In Hollywood Awards at Four Seasons Hotel Los Angeles at Beverly Hills, Oct. 20, 2014, in Beverly Hills.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jennifer Garner
Jennifer Garner seen here in her senior year in 1990 at George Washington High School in Charleston, W. Va. Right, Actress Jennifer Garner attends the "Danny Collins" New York premiere at AMC Lincoln Square Theater, March 18, 2015, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Hugh Hefner
Hugh Hefner is seen here in his senior year, 1944 at Steinmetz High School in Chicago. Right, Hugh Hefner attends the Beverly Hills City Council and Playboy Enterprises ribbon-cutting ceremony for Beverly Hills Playboy World Headquarters, Aug. 7, 2012, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Patricia Arquette
Patricia Arquette is seen as a child. Right, Actress Patricia Arquette attends the 87th Annual Academy Awards at Hollywood &amp; Highland Center, Feb. 22, 2015, in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jamie Foxx
Jamie Foxx seen here in his senior year in 1986 at Terrell High School in Terrell, Texas. Right, Host Jamie Foxx poses in the press room during the 2015 iHeartRadio Music Awards, March 29, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Eddie Murphy
Eddie Murphy seen here during his senior year at Roosevelt High School in Roosevelt, New York. Right, Actor Eddie Murphy arrives at the 2015 Vanity Fair Oscar Party at Wallis Annenberg Center for the Performing Arts, Feb. 22, 2015 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Warren Beatty
Warren Beatty seen here during his senior year, 1955, at Washington-Lee High School in Arlington, Va. Right, Warren Beatty attends ELLE's 21st Annual Women in Hollywood Celebration at the Four Seasons Hotel, Oct. 20, 2014, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
George Clooney
George Clooney seen here during his senior year, 1979, at Augusta High School in Augusta, Ky. Right, Actor George Clooney attends SeriousFun Children's Network's New York City Gala at Avery Fisher Hall, Lincoln Center, March 2, 2015, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Steven Tyler
Steven Tyler in his freshman year at Walt Whitman Junior High School, Yonkers, New York in 1964. Right, Steven Tyler is seen on the red carpet at the Rolling Stone Party at the Venue of Scottsdale, Jan. 31, 2015.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Sarah Jessica Parker
Sarah Jessica Parker seen here in seventh grade in 1978 at Professional Children's School, New York. Right, Actress Sarah Jessica Parker attends "It's Only A Play" Broadway Re-Opening Night at The Bernard B. Jacobs Theatre, Jan. 23, 2015, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Bruce Willis
Bruce Willis in his senior year in 1973 at Penns Grove High School in Penns Grove, N.J. Right, Actor Bruce Willis attends the launch of "The Clothing Coven" at Elodie K., April 4, 2014, in West Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Adam Levine
Adam Levine is seen here in second-grade in 1987 at the Center for Early Education, West Hollywood, Calif. Right, Adam Levine arrives at the 2015 Vanity Fair Oscar Party Hosted By Graydon Carter at Wallis Annenberg Center for the Performing Arts, Feb. 22, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Carrie Underwood
Carrie Underwood seen in sixth grade in 1995 at Checotah School in Checotah, Okla. Right, Singer/songwriter Carrie Underwood attends the 2014 American Country Countdown Awards at Music City Center, Dec. 15, 2014, in Nashville, Tenn.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Eva Mendes
Eva Mendes seen here in her sophomore year in 1990 at Hoover High School in Glendale, Calif. Right, Actress Eva Mendes and New York &amp; Company launch the Eva Mendes for NY&amp;amp;C Spring 2014 collection with a pop-up shop at The Beverly Center, March 18, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Chelsea Handler
Chelsea Handler seen here in her senior year in 1993 at Livingston High School, Livingston, N.J. Right, Chelsea Handler is seen, Oct, 9, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Michael Keaton
Michael Keaton seen here in his senior year in 1969 at Montour High School, McKees Rock, Pa. Right, Michael Keaton attends the after party for the EE British Academy Film Awards at The Grosvenor House Hotel, Feb. 8, 2015, in London.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Clint Eastwood
Clint Eastwood see here in his senior year in 1949 at Oakland Technical High School in Oakland, Calif. Right, Clint Eastwood poses in the press room at the 67th Annual Directors Guild Of America Awards at the Hyatt Regency Century Plaza, Feb. 7, 2015, in Century City, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Steve Carell
Steve Carell seen here in his senior year dressed In costume for a play called "You Can't Take it With You" in 1980 at Middlesex School, Concord, Mass. Right, Actor Steve Carell attends the Outstanding Performer of The Year ceremony at the 30th Santa Barbara International Film Festival at Arlington Theatre, Feb. 6, 2015, in Santa Barbara, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Julianne Moore
Julianne Moore seen here in her junior year in 1978 at Frankfurt American High School in Frankfurt. Right, Julianne Moore attends the EE British Academy Film Awards at The Royal Opera House, Feb. 8, 2015, in London.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Meryl Streep
Meryl Streep in her freshman year in 1964 Bernards High School, Bernardsville, N.J. Right, Actress Meryl Streep attends the 15th Annual AFI Awards at Four Seasons Hotel Los Angeles at Beverly Hills, Jan. 9, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Emma Stone
Emma Stone seen here during sixth grade at Cocopah Middle School in Scottsdale, Ariz. Right, Emma Stone arrives at the 87th Academy Awards Nominee Luncheon at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, Feb. 2, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Reese Witherspoon
Reese Witherspoon seen here in first grade in 1983 at Harding Academy, Nashville, Tenn. Right, Actress Reese Witherspoon attends the 87th Annual Academy Awards Nominee Luncheon at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, Feb. 2, 2015, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
George Stephanopoulos
George Stephanopoulos seen here in his senior year 1978 at Orange High School, Pepper Pike, Ohio. Right, George Stephanopoulos attends the 24th Annual Broadcasting &amp;amp; Cable Hall Of Fame Awards at The Waldorf Astoria, Oct. 20, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Amy Robach
Amy Robach seen here in her freshman year 1988 at Brookwood High School, Snellville, Ga. Right, News anchor Amy Robach attends the United Nations 2014 Women's Entrepreneurship Day at United Nations, Nov. 19, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Barbara Hershey
Barbara Hershey seen here in her sophomore year 1964 at Hollywood High School, Hollywood, Calif. Right, Actress Barbara Hershey attends the premiere "Insidious: Chapter 2" at Universal CityWalk, Sept. 10, 2013 in Universal City, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Blythe Danner
Blythe Danner seen here in her senior year 1960 at George School, Newtown, Pa. Right, Actress Blythe Danner attends "I'll See You In My Dreams" cast party, Jan 27, 2015, in Park City, Utah.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Kerry Washington
Kerry Washington seen here in seventh grade in 1989 at Spence School, New York. Right, Actress Kerry Washington arrives at the 26th Annual PGA Awards at the Hyatt Regency Century Plaza, Jan. 24, 2015, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Oprah Winfrey
Oprah Winfrey seen here in her senior year in 1971 at East Nashville High School, Nashville, Tenn. Right, Actress Oprah Winfrey enters the "Selma" New York Premiere at the Ziegfeld Theater, Dec. 14, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Dolly Parton
Dolly Parton is seen here in her sophomore year 1962 at Sevier County High School, Sevierville, Tenn. Right, Dolly Parton speaks to the media during a press conference at Rod Laver Arena, Feb. 11, 2014, in Melbourne, Australia.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Betty White
Betty White seen here in her senior year in 1940 at Beverly Hills High School, Beverly Hills, Calif. Right, Betty White attends the 17th Annual Los Angeles Times Festival Of Books, April 22, 2012, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Nicolas Cage
Nicolas Cage seen here in his freshman year in 1979 at Beverly Hills High School, Beverly Hills, Calif. Right, Actor Nicolas Cage attends "Meet The Filmmakers" at Apple Store Soho on April 10, 2014 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Marilyn Manson
Marilyn Manson seen here in eighth grade in 1983 at Heritage Christian School, Canton, Ohio. Right, Actor/singer Marilyn Manson arrives at the season 7 premiere screening of FX's "Sons of Anarchy" at the Chinese Theatre, Sept. 6, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Mary Tyler Moore
Mary Tyler Moore seen here in her freshman year 1952 at Immaculate Heart High School in Los Angeles. Right, Mary Tyler Moore attends Broadway Barks! 14 at the Shubert Alley, July 14, 2012, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Maggie Smith
British actress Maggie Smith is seen here in this undated file photo. Right, Dame Maggie Smith is seen at Odeon Leicester Square, Oct. 15, 2012, in London.
Getty Images
Ryan Seacrest
Radio Personality Ryan Seacrest attends z100s Jingle Ball at Madison Square Garden, Dec. 12, 2014 in New York. Right, Ryan Seacrest seen here as a child.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Susan Lucci
Susan Lucci seen here in her senior year 1964 at Garden City High School, Garden City, N.Y. Right, Actress Susan Lucci, Aug. 12, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library |Getty Images
Brad Pitt
Brad Pitt seen here in his senior year in 1982 at Kickapoo High School, Springfield, Mo. Right, Actor Brad Pitt attends the premiere of "Unbroken" at TCL Chinese Theatre IMAX, Dec. 15, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Taylor Swift As a High School Sophomore
Taylor Swift is pictured in the 2006 Hendersonville High School Yearbook, from Hendersonville, Tenn. and in Los Angeles, Calif. on Dec. 5, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library|Getty Images
Britney Spears
Britney Spears seen here in 2nd Grade 1990 Park Lane Academy, McComb, Miss. Right, Britney Spears launches her collection 'The Intimate Collection' at the Ekeberg Restaurant, Sept. 26, 2014 in Oslo.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Tina Turner
Tina Turner seen here in her senior year in 1958 at Sumner High School, St. Louis. Right, Singer Tina Turner attends Armani fashion show at 798 Art Zone in this May 31, 2012 file photo in Beijing.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Scarlett Johansson
Scarlett Johansson seen here during her senior year, 2002 at the Professional Children's School in New York. Right, Scarlett Johansson attends the 2nd Annual Champions Of Rockaway Hurricane Sandy Benefit at Hudson Terrace, Nov. 18, 2014, in New York
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Goldie Hawn
Goldie Hawn seen here in her senior year 1963 at Montgomery Blair High School, Silver Springs, Md. Right, Goldie Hawn attends Forbes Women's Summit:The Entrepreneurship of Everything at 583 Park Avenue, May 15, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Seth Rogen
Actor Seth Rogen attends "Id Isn't Always Pretty: An Evening With Broad City" Panel Discussion at The Paley Center for Media, Nov. 9, 2014, in New York. Right, Seth Rogen posted this photo on Twitter with this caption: "Here's a pic of me in high school with dreadlocks wearing a Korn shirt! Goodnight!? Oct. 31, 2014.
Sethrogen/Twitter | Getty Images
Bill and Hillary Clinton
Bill and Hillary Clinton seen together in this undated photo. Right, Former President Bill Clinton and then-Secretary of State Hillary Clinton arrive for the 57th Presidential Inauguration ceremonial swearing-in of President Obama at the U.S. Capitol, Jan. 21, 2013, in Washington.
Clinton Family Historical Collection | Getty Images
Anne Hathaway
Anne Hathaway is seen here as a child. Right, Anne Hathaway is seen in Soho, Nov. 4, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Leonardo DiCaprio
Leonardo DiCaprio seen here during his junior year, 1992 at Marshall High School, Los Angeles, Calif. Right Leonardo DiCaprio attends the EE British Academy Film Awards 2014, Feb. 16, 2014 in London.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Miranda Lambert
Miranda Lambert seen here during eighth grade in 1998 at Lindale Middle School, Lindale, Texas. Right, Singer Miranda Lambert attends the 48th annual CMA Awards at the Bridgestone Arena, Nov 5, 2014 in Nashville, Tenn.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Matthew McConaughey
Matthew McConaughey seen here in his freshman year in 1985 at Longview High School, Longview, Texas. Right, Actor Matthew McConaughey attends the 'Interstellar' photocall at Palazzo Manfredi, Nov. 1, 2014, in Rome.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Kendall Jenner
Kendall Jenner first Grade 2003 Sierra Canyon School, Chatsworth, Calif. Right, Kendall Jenner poses at The National Theatre Gala dinner, Oct 7, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Natalie Portman
Natalie Portman is seen here as a child. Right, Actress Natalie Portman arrives at the Children's Hospital Los Angeles Gala Noche de Ninos at the L.A. Live Event Deck, Oct. 11, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Henry Winkler
Henry Winkler seen here during his senior year, 1963 at McBurney School in New York. Right, Henry Winkler appears at "Watch What Happens Live", Feb 11, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Bruce Jenner
Bruce Jenner senior year 1968 Newtown High School, Newtown, Conn. Television personality Bruce Jenner attends the 13th annual Michael Jordan Celebrity Invitational gala at the ARIA Resort &amp; Casino at CityCenter, April 4, 2014, in Las Vegas.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
John Mayer
John Mayer seen here in his freshman year 1992 at Fairfield High School, Fairfield, Conn. Right, Musician John Mayer attends Food Network In Concert, Sept. 20, 2014 in Chicago.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Usher
Usher seen here in his freshman year 1993 at North Springs High School, Atlanta, Ga. Right, Usher poses at the 2014 iHeartRadio Music Festival - Night 1 - Press Room at MGM Grand Garden Arena, Sept. 19, 2014, in Las Vegas.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Dale Earnhardt Jr.
Dale Earnhardt Jr. seen here in his sophomore year 1990 at Burlington High School, Burlington, Mass. Right, Dale Earnhardt Jr., driver of the #88 National Guard Chevrolet, stands in the garage area during practice, Aug. 15, 2014, in Brooklyn, Mich.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Elisabeth Shue
Elisabeth Shue seen here in her senior year in 1981 at Columbia High School, Maplewood, N.J. Right, Actress Elisabeth Shue arrives at the 'Behaving Badly' - Los Angeles Premiere at ArcLight Hollywood, July 29, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library |Getty Images
Gwen Stefani
Gwen Stefani seen here in her senior year 1987 at Loara High School in Anaheim, Calif. Right, Gwen Stefani attends the L.A.M.B. presentation during Mercedes-Benz Fashion Week Spring 2015, Sept. 5, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Kelly Ripa
Kelly Ripa is seen here as a child. Right, Super Saturday host Kelly Ripa attends QVC Presents Super Saturday LIVE! in Water Mill City, New York, July 26, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Who's This Future TV Legend?
Barbara Walters seen here in her senior year at Birch Wathen School, New York. Right, Barbara Walters is seen here in 2008.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Donna Svennevik/ABC
Amy Poehler
Amy Poehler seen here in her senior year 1989 at Burlington High School, Burlington, Mass. Right, Actress Amy Poehler attends the 66th Annual Primetime Emmy Awards at the Nokia Theatre L.A. Live, Aug. 25, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Tommy Lee Jones
Tommy Lee Jones seen here in his senior year in 1965 at St. Mark's School of Texas. Right, Tommy Lee Jones attends "The Homesman" photocall at the 67th Annual Cannes Film Festival, May 18, 2014, in Cannes, France.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Adam Sandler
Adam Sandler seen here as a kid. Right, Adam Sandler arrives at the photo call of Men, Women and Children held during the 2014 Toronto International Film Festival, Sept. 6, 2014, in Toronto.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Pink
Pink seen here in 8th Grade in 1993 at Lenape Middle School in Doylestown, Pa. Right, Pink arrives at the 56th GRAMMY Awards, Jan. 26, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Raquel Welch
Raquel Welch seen here in her senior year in 1958 at La Jolla High School, La Jolla, Calif. Right, Actress Raquel Welch arrives at the 16th Costume Designers Guild Awards at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, Feb. 22, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Beyonce
Beyonce Knowles seen here in her freshman year 1996 at Houston School for the Performing and Visual Arts, Houston. Right, Singer Beyonce Knowles attends the 2014 MTV Video Music Awards at The Forum, Aug. 24, 2014 in Inglewood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Lea Michele
Lea Michele seen here as a baby. Right, Actress Lea Michele arrives at Variety And Women In Film Annual Pre-Emmy Celebration at Gracias Madre, Aug. 23, 2014 in West Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Shania Twain
Shania Twain seen here in grade 12 in 1983 at Timmins High and Vocational Timmins, Canada. Right, Shania Twain performs at the Calgary Stampede at Scotiabank Saddledome, July 10, 2014, in Calgary, Canada.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Blake Lively
Blake Lively seen here as a child. Right, Blake Lively attends "The Captives" Premiere at the 67th Annual Cannes Film Festival, May 16, 2014, in Cannes, France.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Amy Adams
Amy Adams seen here in her senior year in 1992 at Douglas County High School, Castle Rock, Colo. Right, Actress Amy Adams attends the Metropolitan Museum of Art, May 5, 2014 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Former President Bill Clinton
Former President Bill Clinton seen here in his senior year in 1964 at Hot Springs High School, Hot Springs, Ariz. Right, Bill Clinton attends the 'Red Ribbon Celebration Concert - United in Difference' at Burgtheater, May 30, 2014, in Vienna.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Chris Pratt
Actor Chris Pratt seen here in his junior year at Lake Stevens High School in Washington State. Right, Actor Chris Pratt visits SiriusXM Studios, July 30, 2014, in New York.
Splash News | Getty Images
Halle Berry
Halle Berry seen here in 8th Grade in 1980 at Heskett Junior High School, Bedford, Ohio. Right, Actress Halle Berry attends the premiere of "Extant" at California Science Center, June 16, 2014 in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Viola Davis
Viola Davis seen here in her senior year in 1983 at Central Falls High School, Central Falls, R.I. Right, Viola Davis arrives at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, July 15, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Billy Bob Thornton
Billy Bob Thornton is seen in 12th Grade in 1973 at Malvern High School, Malvern, Ark. Right, Billy Bob Thornton attends the Television Academy's performers peer group celebrating the 66th Emmy Awards on July 28, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
Lisa Kudrow
Lisa Kudrow seen here in 9th Grade in 1978 at Portola Junior High School, Woodland Hills, Calif. Right, Lisa Kudrow arrives at the 2014 Television Critics Association Summer Press Tour, July 17, 2014 in West Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jennifer Lopez
Jennifer Lopez seen here as a child. Right, Jennifer Lopez attends the Versace show as part of Paris Fashion Week - Haute Couture Fall/Winter 2014-2015, July 6, 2014 in Paris.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
#TBT: Who's This Future Talk Show Host?
Kelly Ripa posted this photo of herself as a child to Twitter, July 17, 2014 with the caption "I've had these curves all my life. It's a curse. #throwwaybackthursday." Right, Kelly Ripa in Hollywood, Calif., March 2, 2014.
@KellyRipa/Twitter | Frazer Harrison/Getty Images
Vin Diesel
Vin Diesel seen here in his senior year 1985 at Anglo American School, New York. Right, Vin Diesel attends the Los Angeles premiere of 'Riddick' at the Westwood Village Theatre, Aug. 28, 2013 in Westwood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
The Rock
The Rock posted this photo on Instagram with this caption: "Fanny pack and lean take it to a whole other level... #90sRock #WTF #BuffLesbian," July 16, 2014. Right, Dwayne Johnson walks the red carpet ahead of a screening of Hercules at Event Cinemas George Street ,June 19, 2014, in Sydney.
therock/Instagram | Getty Images
Will Ferrell
Will Ferrell seen here in his senior year in 1986 at University High School, Irvine, Calif. Right, Actor Will Ferrell arrives at the Los Angeles Premiere "Tammy" at TCL Chinese Theatre, June 30, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jessica Simpson
Jessica Simpson seen here in her freshman year in 1995 at Richardson North Junior High School, Richardson, Texas. Right, Jessica Simpson attends Forbes Women's Summit:The Entrepreneurship of Everything at 583 Park Avenue, May 15, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Tom Hanks
Tom Hanks seen here in his sophomore year in 1972 at Skyline High School, Oakland, Calif. Right, Actor Tom Hanks attends the EE British Academy Film Awards 2014 at The Royal Opera Hous, Feb. 16, 2014, in London.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Sophia Bush seen here in her senior year in 2000 at Westridge School, Pasadena, Calif. Right, Actress Sophia Bush is seen, June 11, 2014, in Santa Monica, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Tim Howard
In high school, United States Men's National Team soccer goalie Tim Howard shared this quote in his yearbook," It will take a nation of millions to hold me back." Right, US Men's National Team Goalkeeper Tim Howard speaks with the media in Stanford, Calif. May 23, 2014.
Redit | Getty Images
Who Is This Future Playboy Playmate?
Pamela Anderson seen here in her sophomore year in 1983 at Highland Senior Secondary, Comox, British Columbia, Canada. Pamela Anderson attends the 60th Taormina Film Fest, June 16, 2014 in Taormina, Italy.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Kim Kardashian
Kim Kardashian seen here with TJ Jackson in her senior year in 1998 at Marymount School, Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Don Johnson
Don Johnson seen here in his senior year in 1967 at Wichita High School South, Wichita, Kan. Right, Don Johnson attends the ICON Awards at Montage Beverly Hills, June 5, 2014, in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library |Getty Images
Tim Howard
USA World Cup Team goalie, Tim Howard, shared an image of his younger self, left, for a "Throwback Thursday" on his Instagram account. Howard hopes to help the US team advance to the next round with a defeat against Portugal on Sunday, June 22, 2014.
timhow1/Instagram|Getty Images
Elizabeth Banks
Elizabeth Banks seen here in her senior year in 1992 at Pittsfield High School, Pittsfield, Mass. Right, Actress Elizabeth Banks attends the 2014 Vanity Fair Oscar Party hosted by Graydon Carter, March 2, 2014, in West Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Paula Abdul
Paula Abdul seen here in her senior year in 1980 at Van Nuys High School, Van Nuys, Calif. Right, Paula Abdul arrives at the 2014 Logie Awards at Crown Palladium, April 27, 2014, in Melbourne, Australia.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Natalie Portman
Natalie Portman seen here as a toddler. Right, Natalie Portman attends the 'Esprit Dior, Miss Dior' Exhibition Opening at Grand Palais, Nov. 12, 2013, in Paris.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library |Getty Images
Fergie
Fergie seen here in her senior year in 1993 at Glen A. Wilson High School, Hacienda Heights, Calif. Right, Singer Fergie Duhamel is seen, May 8, 2014, in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Peter Dinklage
Peter Dinklage before he was famous for his character in " Game of Thrones." Right, Peter Dinklage attends the "X-Men: Days Of Future Past" world premiere at Jacob Javits Center, May 10, 2014, in New York.
Reddit |Getty Images
Amanda Seyfried
Amanda Seyfried posted this on Instagram with this caption:" Happy Birthday, J #itsyourbirthdaytoday, " June 1, 2014. Right, Amanda Seyfried attends Shiseido 'Cle de Peau Beaute' Press Conference, June 2, 2014, in Tokyo.
mingey/Instagram | Getty Images
Brad Pitt
Brad Pitt seen here in his 8th grade photo in 1978 in Junior High School, Springfield, Mo. Right, Actor Brad Pitt arrives at the Los Angeles Premiere "Maleficent" at the El Capitan Theatre, May 28, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Ashton Kutcher
Ashton Kutcher seen here in his senior year in 1994 at Prom Clear Creek-Amana High School in Tiffin, Iowa. Right, Actor Ashton Kutcher attends the Human Rights Watch Voices For Justice Dinner, Nov.12, 2013 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Adam Sandler
Adam Sandler seen here during his junior year, 1983 at Manchester Central High School in Manchester, N.H. Right, Adam Sandler arrives at the "Blended" - Los Angeles Premiere at TCL Chinese Theatre, May 21, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Claire Danes
Claire Danes seen here in her senior year in 1997 at Le Lycee Francais de Los Angeles. Right, Actress Claire Danes attends the Born Free Africa Mother's Day Family Carnival at Hudson River Park Pier 45, May 11, 2014, in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Tina Fey
Tina Fey seen here in her senior year in 1988 at Upper Darby High School, Upper Darby, Pa. Right, Actress Tina Fey arrives at the Los Angeles premiere of 'Muppets Most Wanted' at the El Capitan Theatre, March 11, 2014, in Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Megan Fox
Megan Fox seen here in second-grade in 1994 at Kingston Elementary School in Kingston, Tenn. Right, Megan Fox poses at the 70th Annual Golden Globe Awards at The Beverly Hilton Hotel, Jan. 13, 2013 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Mathew Fox
Mathew Fox seen here during his senior year, 1984 at Wind River High School in Crowheart, Wyo. Right, Actor Mathew Fox poses for the movie's 'Alex Cross' photocall at St. Regis Hotel, Jan. 16, 2013 in Mexico City, Mexico.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library|Getty Images
Bethenny Frankel
Bethenny Frankel posted this image on Instagram with this caption: "In honor of prom season, here's my #promtbt - who else rocked the 80s puff sleeved prom dress look?!" May 8, 2014. Right, Bethenny Frankel, Founder of Skinnygirl Cocktails, attends the 2014 Dress For Success Something To Share Gala at the Grand Hyatt in New York, April 3, 2014 in New York.
bethennyfrankel/Instagram
Amy Poehler
Amy Poehler seen here during her senior year, 1989 at Burlington High School in Burlington, Mass. Right, Comedian Amy Poehler attends 2014 American Comedy Awards at Hammerstein Ballroom, April 26, 2014 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Do You Recognize This Emmy Winning Actor?
Bryan Cranston seen here during his senior year, 1974 at Canoga Park High School Canoga Park, Calif. Right, Actor Bryan Cranston speaks onstage at the Crackle NewFronts at Cedar Lake Studios, April 30, 2014 in New York.
Seth Poppel | Getty Images
Neil Patrick Harris
Neil Patrick Harris seen here during his senior year, 1991 at La Cueva High School, Albuquerque, N.M. Right, Neil Patrick Harris attends the 2014 Hasty Pudding Institute Of 1770 Order of the Golden Sphinx Award at The Atrium at Lincoln Center, March 10, 2014.
Seth Poppel | Getty Images
Haley Joel Osment
Haley Joel Osment at the Fifth Annual Critics' Choice Awards in Beverly Hills, Calif., Jan. 24, 2000. | Haley Joel Osment attends the Official After Party for 'In Your Eyes' starring Zoe Kazan And Nikki Reed sponsored By Bombay Sapphire Gin at China Blue, April 20, 2014, in New York.
Getty Images
Michelle Obama
First Lady Michelle Obama posted this photo of herself and her brother, Craig Robinson, on Twitter on April 10, 2014 with the caption, ""Happy #NationalSiblingsDay! #TBT #ThrowbackThursday". The pair are seen on the right at the Democratic National Convention in Charlotte, North Carolina on Sept. 5, 2012.
@FLOTUS/Twitter | Alex Wong/Getty Images
Lupita Nyong'o
Lupita Nyong'o performs in a Yale School of Drama Production in 2011. | Lupita Nyong'o poses in the press room at the 86th annual Academy Awards at Dolby Theatre, March 2, 2014 in Hollywood, Calif.
Courtesy T Charles Erickson | Getty Images
Eva Mendes
Eva Mendes seen here during her senior year, 1990 at Hoover High School, Glendale, Calif. Right, actress Eva Mendes attends Violet Grey Honors Elizabeth Taylor At She's So Violet Salon Dinner, Feb. 26, 2014 in Los Angeles, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Bruce Dern
Bruce Dern seen here during his senior year, 1954 at New Trier High School, Winnetka, Ill. Right, Bruce Dern attends the 13th annual AARP's Movies For Grownups Awards gala, Feb. 10, 2014 in Beverly Hills.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Bradley Cooper
Bradley Cooper seen here during his junior year, 1992 at Germantown Academy, Fort Washington, Pa. Right, Bradley Cooper attends the TOM FORD show, Feb. 17, 2014 in London.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Amy Adams
Amy Adams seen here during her junior year, 1991 at Douglas County High School, in Castle Rock, Colo. Right, Amy Adams at the 16th Costume Designers Guild Awards in Beverly Hills, Calif, Feb, 22, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Gisele Bundchen
Gisele Bundchen posted a wedding image, left, to her Instagram on Feb. 26, 2014 with the caption, "Happy anniversary my love. Te amo! #wedding #2009." She is seen with her husband Tom Brady in this May, 2013 file photo at an event in New York.
giseleofficial/Instagram | Larry Busacca/Getty Images
Matthew McConaughey
Matthew McConaughey seen here during his senior year, 1988 at Longview High School, Longview, Texas. Right, Matthew McConaughey arrives at the 86th Oscars Nominees Luncheon , Feb. 10, 2014 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Sandra Bullock
Sandra Bullock seen here during her freshman year, 1979 at Washington Lee High School in Arlington, Va. Right, Sandra Bullock at the 66th Annual Directors Guild Of America Awards in Century City, Calif., Jan. 25, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Jared Leto
Jared Leto seen here during his freshman year, 1986 at Flint Hill Prep in Oakton, Va. Right, Jared Leto of American rock band Thirty Seconds To Mars performs at Oslo Spektrum, Feb. 23, 2014 in Oslo.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jonah Hill
Jonah Hill seen here during his junior year, 2001 at Crossroads School, Santa Monica, Calif. Right Jonah Hill speaks onstage during the 16th Costume Designers Guild Awards, Feb. 22. 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Julia Roberts
Julia Roberts seen here during her senior year, 1985 at Campbell High School in Smyrna, Ga. Right, Julia Roberts at the 56th GRAMMY Awards at Staples Center in Los Angeles, Jan. 26, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Meryl Streep
Meryl Streep seen here during her senior year, 1967 at Bernards High School in Bernardsville, N.J. Right, Meryl Streep at the 86th Academy Awards nominee luncheon in Beverly Hills, Calif.., Feb. 10, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jennifer Lawrence
Jennifer Lawrence seen here in her 8th Grade photo in 2005 at Kammerer Middle School in Louisville, Ky. Right, Jennifer Lawrence during the 'The Hunger Games: Catching Fire' Premiere during The 8th Rome Film Festival, Nov. 14, 2013 in Rome.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library|Getty Images
June Squibb
June Squibb seen here during her senior year, 1948 Vandalia High School in Vandalia, Ill. Right, June Squibb attends the 16th Costume Designers Guild Awards in Beverly Hills, Calif., Feb. 22, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Lena Dunham
Lena Dunham is seen left with her mother, Laurie Simmons, in this undated photo posted to Instagram on Feb. 17, 2014 with the caption, "Mommy &amp;amp; Me: just floatin' through the 80s". The pair are seen right attending the Emmy's in this Sept. 22, 2013 file photo.
Lena Dunham/Instagram | Jason LaVeris/Getty Images
January Jones
A young January Jones on the left, posted to her Instagram Feb. 6, 2014. On the right, Jones is pictured attending Chloe Los Angeles fashion show and dinner hosted by Clare Waight Keller, January Jones and Lisa Love, Oct. 29, 2013.
@januaryjones/Instagram | Getty Images
Wes Welker
Wes Welker seen here during his senior year, 2000 at Heritage Hall School in Oklahoma City, Okla. Right, Denver Broncos wide receiver Wes Welker speaks at a news conference at the NFL Denver Broncos football training facility in Englewood, Colo., Jan. 15, 2014.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| AP Photo
Marshawn Lynch
Marshawn Lynch seen here during his senior year, 2004 at Oakland Technical High School in Oakland Calif. Right, Seattle Seahawks' Marshawn Lynch walks on the field at an NFL football practice, Jan. 16, 2014, in Renton, Wash.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| AP Images
Flea
Flea seen here during his sophomore year, 1978 at Fairfax High School in Los Angeles. Right, Flea attends a basketball game in Los Angeles, Nov. 12, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Anthony Kiedis
Anthony Kiedis seen here during his senior year, 1980 at Fairfax High School in Los Angeles. Right, Anthony Kiedis attends a basketball game in Los Angeles, Nov. 12, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Bruno Mars
Bruno Mars seen here during his senior year, 2003 at President Theodore Roosevelt High School, Honolulu. Right, Musician Bruno Mars accepts the Best Pop Vocal Album award during the 56th GRAMMY Awards, Jan. 26, 2014 in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Peyton and Eli Manning
Peyton, left and Eli Manning are seen as young boys. Right, Eli Manning, left and his brother Peyton laugh as they run through warm up exercises at Duke's Pascal Field House in Durham, N.C., April 11, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Raleigh News &amp; Observer/Getty Images
Steven Tyler
Steven Tyler seen here during his sophomore year at Roosevelt High School in Yonkers, N.Y. Right, Steven Tyler at the Heavan gala ,Jan. 11 2013 in Los Angeles.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Christopher Walken
Christopher Walken seen here during 7th grade, 1956 at Professional Children's School in New York. Right, Actor Christopher Walken attends the 2013 Tribeca Film Festival, April 16, 2013 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Eminem
Eminem seen here during his freshman year, 1989 at Lincoln High School in Warren, Mich. Right, Eminem is seen during the MTV EMA's 2013, Nov. 10, 2013 in Amsterdam.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Jamie Foxx
Jamie Foxx seen as a baby. Right Actor Jamie Foxx seen in New York, Sept. 26, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Stephen Colbert
Stephen Colbert seen here during his junior year, 1981 at Porter Gaud School, Charleston, SC. Right, Stephen Colbert at the Hope Awards Dinner, Dec. 11, 2013 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library/ Getty Images
Bruce Willis
At left, Bruce Willis in 1973. At right, Bruce Willis in Santa Monica, Calif., Feb. 23, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Ryan Seacrest
Ryan Seacrest seen here during his senior year, 1993 at Dunwoody High School in Dunwoody, Ga. Right, Ryan Seacrest attends Z100's Jingle Ball 2013, Dec. 13, 2013 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
George Clooney
George Clooney is seen at left as a freshman in a 1976 photo taken from the Augusta High School yearbook and at right, attending an event in Los Angeles on Nov. 9, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library | Getty Images
Phil Robertson
Phil Robertson, seen left in this 1967 yearbook photo taken during his sophomore year at the Louisiana Tech University, and at right, appearing on the television series, "Duck Dynasty".
Wikimedia | Zach Dilgard/A&amp;E/AP Photo
Amanda Seyfried
Amanda Seyfried seen here sitting on Santa's lap. Right, Amanda Seyfried seen Oct. 28, 2013 in New York
Getty Images| Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Avril Lavigne
Avril Lavigne seen here during her sophomore year, 2000 at Napanee District Secondary School in Napanee, Ontario singing at a Christmas concert. Right, Avril Lavigne performs, Dec. 16, 2013 in Duluth, Ga.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Jennifer Lopez
Jennifer Lopez seen here during her senior year, 1987 at Preston High School in Bronx, New York. Right, Jennifer Lopez at Beverly Hills Hotel, Dec. 6, 2013 in Beverly Hills, Calif.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Flashback! Relive the 1997 Kardashian-Jenner Christmas Card
As part of their tradition the Kardashian-Jenner pose for their Christmas card in 1997.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Candace Bure
Candace Bure, pictured far right and inset, posted this image of herself with other teen stars on Instagram with the caption, "Young Hollywood 1990's. No stylist or high heels. Instead: baggie clothes, pimples &amp; healthy weight. What a concept 2 show our teens today! @andreabarber @jaleelwhite."
@CandaceBure/Instagram
Kelly Osbourne
Kelly Osbourne posted a childhood photo with her father, Ozzy Osbourne, on Instagram on Dec. 3, 2013 with the caption, "Today is my Dadda's birthday! Happy birthday Dad I am so proud to be your daughter! I love you sooooo much!!!!!". The pair are seen at right attending an event in Beverly Hills, Calif. in May, 2013.
@kellyosbourne/Instagram | Kevin Winter/Getty Images
Michael Strahan has the same gap-toothed smile he had as a kid.
ABC News | Getty Images
Victoria Beckham
Victoria Beckham, nee Adams, aged eight when she was bridesmaid at the wedding is now a major fashion designer, seen right at the Glamour Women of the Year Awards in June, 2013 in London.
Rex Features | Getty Images
Josh Hutcherson
Josh Hutcherson seen here during his sophomore year, 2008 at Ryle High School, in Union, Ky. Right, during the 'The Hunger Games: Catching Fire' Premiere at the Nokia Theatre LA Live in Los Angeles , Nov. 18, 2013.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Hilary Duff
Actress Hilary Duff posted this image of herself on Twitter with this caption "#tbt there are so many things wrong with this", Nov. 7th, 2013.
HilaryDuff/Twitter|Getty Images
Taylor Swift
Before young Taylor Swift learned to form her hand in a heart shape, she flashes the peace sign; Right, during the 2013 Toronto International Film Festival, Sept. 9, 2013, in Toronto.
Andrew Orth/Coleman-Raynor | Mike Windle/Getty Images
Luke Bryan
Country singer Luke Bryan, who's stolen his fans' hearts with his hip shaking moves, is seen on the left in an undated candid yearbook photo and, right at Rockefeller Plaza on Aug. 16, 2013 in New York.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library| Getty Images
Beyonce
Singer Beyonce Knowles shared this image of her teen self as a throwback to her younger years via her Facebook page, Oct. 24, 2013.
Beyonce/Facebook|James Devaney/WireImage/Getty Images
Kanye West
A young Kanye West, left, and right, at the "Runaway" New York premiere, Oct. 21, 2010, in New York City.
Seth Poppel Archive | Michael Loccisano/Getty Images
Rumer Willis
Rumer Willis posted this old school photo to her Instagram, "Love those glasses on me #tbt #oldschool." Right, the Rumer we would recognize, Oct. 10, 2013 in Los Angeles.
ruelarue/Instaram | Imeh Akpanudosen/Getty Images
Sofia Vergara
Sofia Vergara posted this image, left, "22 years ago in Barranquilla !!!Manolo's first Holloweeeen! He was one month old," Oct. 15, 2013; Vergara attends The 2013 Los Angeles Latino International Film Festival, Oct. 14, 2013.
Sofia Vergara/whosay|JC Olivera/Getty Images
Ryan Gosling
Heartthrob Ryan Gosling, shown in the title role of Fox Kids' TV show "Young Hercules" in 1998, and at the BAM Harvey Theater for the New York premiere of the film "Only God Forgives" in New York, July 16, 2013.
FOX | Laura Cavanaugh/Getty Images
MacCaulay Culkin
MacCaulay Culkin at the American Comedy Awards in Los Angeles, in 1991. Macaulay Culkin speaks at the Robot Chicken Panel during New York Comic Con 2013 on Oct. 11, 2013 in New York City.
Getty Images
Jennifer Aniston
Jennifer Aniston during during her Freshman Year in 1984 at Rudolf Steiner School in New York. Jennifer Aniston attends the premiere for "Life Of Crime" on September 14, 2013 in Toronto.
Coleman-Rayner|Getty Images
Matt Damon
Matt Damon made his movie debut at the age of 18 in the 1988 movie, Mystic Pizza starring Julia Roberts. He only appears in one dinner scene as the younger brother of Julia Robert's boyfriend.
Youtube/Getty Images
John Travolta
At left, John Travolta in a baby picture from 1954. At right, Travolta poses next to the beach closet dedicated to him on the Promenade des Planches in Deauville, France, Sept. 6, 2013.
REX USA/SNAP/Rex | Francois Durand/Getty Images
Tom Cruise
Tom Cruise on the Glen Ridge High School wrestling team in New Jersey in 1979. At right, Cruise, now 51, in Beijing, May 9, 2013.
Coleman-Rayner | ChinaFotoPress/Getty Images
Ben Affleck
In one of his first major roles, Ben Affleck starred as Danny Coleman, a young teen who, with the assistance of his best friend, Melanie, sought happiness for his divorced mother by finding "Mr. Right", in this 1986 ABC Afterschool Special, "Wanted: The Perfect Guy."
ABC|Getty Images
Lindsay Lohan
Lindsay Lohan is seen left at her first red-carpet premiere for "The Parent Trap" in 1998 and is seen in New York City on August 5, 2013.
Steve Granitz/WireImage/Getty Images | Alo Ceballos/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Kelly Osbourne
Kelly Osbourne is shown in a 1992 photo and in Los Angeles on Aug. 24, 2013.
Dave Hogan/Hulton Archive/Getty Images | Michael Kovac/Getty Images for BeautyCon
Kim Kardashian
Kim Kardashian is shown with her father, Robert, left, in this undated photo posted on her Instagram. Kardashian is shown again, right, April 22, 2013 in New York City.
@KimKardashian/Instagram|Getty Images
Heidi Klum
Super model Heidi Klum tweeted out this childhood photo, left, with the caption, "I AM NINE," Aug. 11, 2013.
@HeidiKlum/Twitter|Getty Images
Beyonce
Beyonce, who posted this picture of herself from her younger days on her instagram, recently performed in Chicago (right) on July 17, 2013.
Beyonce/Instagram | Larry Busacca/Getty Images
Chase Crawford
Actor Chase Crawford is shown in this family photo as a young child, left, and more recently, at the Soho House, Feb. 23, 2013 in West Hollywood, Calif.
Seth Poppel Yearbook Library|Getty Images
Angelina Jolie
Left: Angelina Jolie is shown with her adoring mom Marcheline in 1975 and again, at the "WORLD WAR Z" Germany Premiere at Sony Center, June 4, 2013 in Berlin, Germany. Jolie won an Oscar award for best supporting actress in 2000 for her role in "Girl, Interrupted."
Anthony Taafe/Coleman-Rayner|Getty Images
Beyonce
Beyonce, seen in this undated photo she posted to her Instagram account and in concert on July 10, 2013.
@beyonce/Instagram | Larry Busacca/PW/WireImage/Getty Images
Reality TV star and new mom Kim Kardashian at age 6 playing soccer.
@KimKardashian|Gilbert Carrasquillo/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Jennifer Lopez
Megastar Jennifer Lopez is shown in her junior year of high school yearbook picture at Preston High School, in 1986, left, and again June 1, 2013.
Seth Poppel Yearbook Library|Getty Images
Justin Timberlake
Justin Timberlake took part in the 1995 Memphis Commercial Appeal spelling bee when he was 14-years-old.
Scripps/Splash News | George Pimentel/WireImage/Getty Images
Dita Von Teese
Dita Von Teese posted a Vine Video on her Twitter page showing pictures of her from the past. She was sporting bright blonde hair and a fierce side part in her images &lt;a href="https://vine.co/v/bYvLWrHpimd" target="external"&gt;posted HERE&lt;/a&gt; , May 29, 2013.
DitaVonTeese/Twitter/Vine
Gwyneth Paltrow in her senior year at Spence School in 1990.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Beyonce Knowles in 8th Grade at Welch Middle School in Houston, Texas.
Seth Poppel/Yearbook Library
Chelsea Handler
TV Host Chelsea Handler tweeted this photo of her younger self April 25, 2013 and right, she attends the E! 2013 Upfront at The Grand Ballroom at Manhattan Center on April 22, 2013 in New York City.
@chelseahandler/Twitter; Jennifer Graylock/Getty Images
Lena Dunham
Lena Dunham shared a photo of herself at Sandy Hollow Day Camp on Instagram on March 21, 2013, left, and Dunham as shown attending the 65th annual Writers Guild East Awards in New York, Feb. 17, 2013.
@lenadunham/Webstagram|Neilson Barnard/Getty Images
Liza Minnelli
Liza Minnelli, left, during a Children's Easter Party in Hollywood, California, 1949. Liza Minnelli poses backstage at 'Liza And Alan: One Night Only In Concert' at Town Hall, March 13, 2013, in New York City.
Archive Photos/Getty Images|Bruce Glikas/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Martha Stewart
Martha Kostyra, who later became Martha Stewart, left, is seen in a photo that appeared in the Feb. 20, 1959, Maroon and Gray Nutley (N.J.) High School school newspaper. Martha Stewart attends the Ralph Rucci Fall 2013 fashion show during Mercedes-Benz Fashion at The Theatre at Lincoln Center, Feb. 10, 2013, in New York City.
Nutley High School/AP Photo; Jemal Countess/Getty Images
Helen Mirren
Actress Helen Mirren, center, took the lead as Gretel in her 1955 Hamlet Court Junior School production of "Hansel &amp; Gretel."
Mike Floyd/Collect/Rex USA
Josh Groban
Before Josh Groban was a Grammy-nominated singer with a booming baritone voice, he was a kid growing up and rocking out in Los Angeles. Since his big break at age 17, when he sang a duet with Celine Dion, Groban has become a global pop star with over 25 million records sold and appearances on TV's "Glee" and "The Office." He released his sixth studio album, "All That Echoes," on Feb. 5, 2013.
Josh Groban; Ben Gabbe/Getty Images
Sofia Vergara
Sofia Vergara tweeted this photo of herself as a child (wearing the hat), "Haja me in Barranquilla during carnaval!" on Jan. 10, 2013, and right, Sofia is sighted in New York City on Sept. 27, 2012.
@SofiaVergara/Twitter; Jackson Lee/Star Max/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Vintage Cyndi Lauper
Cyndi Lauper was 30 when she become the '80s icon of girl power with her 1983 smash hit single, "Girls Just Wanna Have Fun." Before that, Lauper, shown (left) as a teenager, waited tables in Queens, N.Y. Since her singing career took off, Lauper has sold over 50 million records worldwide, released more than 40 singles, become a best-selling author a reality TV star and a mother.
Cyndi Lauper | Desiree Navarro/WireImage/Getty Images
Miley Cyrus
Miley Cyrus who recently turned 20 on Nov. 23, 2012, tweeted this photo of her younger self as part of Flashback Friday on Nov. 30, 2012 from her @MileyCyrus account. (Right) Miley poses backstage at the hit musical 'Chicago' on Broadway at The Ambassador Theater on Nov. 18, 2012 in New York City. The former "Hannah Montana" star currently appears on "Two and a Half Men."
@MileyCyrus/Twitter; Bruce Glikas/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Kate Moss
A 1988 photo of Kate Moss at her first professional photo shoot is going up for auction later this month in London. At 14, Moss was already exhibited the steely gaze that would become her signature look and make her a supermodel.
SWNS| Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 14:04:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Kate Middleton Goes for a Drive</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/photos/kate-middleton-duchess-cambridge-style-12598288</Link>
        <Description>The Life and Times of Kate Middleton </Description>
        <MainBody>The Life and Times of Kate Middleton
+

Kate Middleton Goes for a Drive
Kate Middleton is spotted driving a Range Rover out of Buckingham Palace in London on April 28, 2015.
MODE/AKM-GSI
Kate Middleton Goes for a Drive
Kate Middleton is spotted driving a Range Rover out of Buckingham Palace in London on April 28, 2015.
MODE/AKM-GSI
Duchess Kate Steps Out in Hot Pink
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits the Stephen Lawrence Centre in Deptford, March 27, 2015, in London.
Neil Mockford/Alex Huckle
Pregnant Kate Steps Out In Polka Dots
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits the Brookhill Children's Centre in Woolwich to find out about the work of Home Start on March 18, 2015 in London, England.
Alex Lentati-WPA Pool/Getty Images
Pregnant Kate Arrives at a St. Patrick's Day Parade
Britain's Duchess of Cambridge smiles as her husband Prince William and soldiers of the 1st Battalion Irish Guards fix shamrocks to their hats at the St. Patrick's Day Parade at Mons Barracks, Aldershot, England, March 17, 2015.
Kirsty Wigglesworth/AP Photo
Prince William Steps Out with Duchess Kate
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge leave St Paul's Cathedral after a Service of Commemoration for troops who were stationed in Afghanistan, March 13, 2015, in London.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Duchess Kate Visits 'Downton Abbey'
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge poses with cast, crew and producers of Downton Abbey during an official visit to the set of Downton Abbey at Ealing Studios, March 12, 2015, in London.
Chris Jackson/ WPA Pool/Getty Images
Pregnant Kate Wears a Wild Print
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits the Turner Contempary on March 11, 2015 in Margate, England.
Karwai Tang/WireImage/Getty Images
Kate Looks Pretty in Pink
Britain's Duchess of Cambridge arrives for the annual Commonwealth Observance at Westminster Abbey in central London, on March 9, 2015. The Observance is the biggest multi-faith celebration in the United Kingdom and takes the form of an hour long service in Westminster Abbey. The Duchess is expecting her second child in April.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Duchess Kate Shows Off Her Growing Bump
Catherine Duchess of Cambridge is seen leaving The Goring Hotel in Victoria, London, March 2, 2015.
Ben Cawthra/SIPA
Duchess Kate Shows Off Her Baby Bump in Blue
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, unveils a plaque as she visits the 'Emma Bridgewater' pottery factory, Feb. 18, 2015, in Staffordshire, England.
Oli Scarff/WPA Pool/Getty Images
Duchess Kate Shows Off Her Growing Bump in a White Coat
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge laughs as she visits the home of Ben Ainslie Racing (BAR) in Portsmouth Old Town, Feb. 12, 2015, in Portsmouth, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Pregnant Duchess Kate Bundles Up in Blue
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives to formally open the Kensington Leisure Centre, Jan. 19, 2015, in London.
Karwai Tang/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends a coffee morning at Family Friends in Kensington, Jan. 19, 2015, in London. Family Friends is a voluntary organization to help families in deprived areas of the borough of Kensington.
Geoff Pugh/ WPA Pool/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends an event hosted by The Fostering Network to celebrate the work of foster carers in providing support to vulnerable young people, Jan. 16, 2015, in London.
Lefteris Pitarakis/Getty Images
Duchess Kate Steps Out With a Smile
Britain's Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, arrives at a primary school in London, Jan. 15, 2015. The Duchess, Royal Patron of The Art Room organization, officially named The Clore Art Room at the school.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Happy 33rd Birthday, Duchess Kate!
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the St. Andrews 600th Anniversary Dinner at Metropolitan Museum of Art in this Dec. 9, 2014 file photo in New York.
Jason DeCrow/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Looks Radiant on Christmas Day
Britain's Kate Middleton, Duchess of Cambridge, attends the royal family's traditional Christmas Day Church Service at Sandringham in eastern England, Dec. 25, 2014.
Paul Ellis/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton and Prince William on Christmas Day
Britain's Prince William and Kate, Duchess of Cambridge leave after attending the British royal family's traditional Christmas Day church service at St. Mary Magdalene Church in Sandringham, England, Dec. 25, 2014.
Matt Dunham/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Learns Sign Language
Britain's Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, learning sign language as she meets with children at the newly established 23rd Poplar Beaver Scout Colony in east London on Dec. 16, 2014. The Duchess's visit supports the Scout Association's 'Better Prepared' campaign, which aims to help communities to deliver Scouting to two hundred locations across the UK where Scouting can have the biggest impact.
Ben Stansall/AFP/Getty Images
Duchess Kate Wears a Hoodie to Hang Out with Beaver Scouts
Kate Middleton shakes hands with Fynley Gooch, aged 7, after being helped to ice a cupcake while blindfolded as she promotes disability awareness while meeting with children at the 23rd Poplar Beaver Scout Colony in London on Dec. 16, 2014.
Ben Stansall/Pool/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Attends a Charity Launch in Red
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at East Anglia's Children's Hospices appeal launch at Norfolk Showground, Nov. 25, 2014, in Norwich, England.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Reveals Her Growing Baby Bump!
Britain's Kate, Duchess of Cambridge attends the Place2be Wellbeing in Schools Award at Kensington Palace, London, Nov. 19, 2014.
Paul Hackett/AP Photo
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attend the Royal Variety Performance at London Palladium, Nov. 13, 2014 in London, England.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press via Getty Images
Kate Middleton Meets with Young Athletes
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, Patron of SportsAid, meets potential young athletes at a SportsAid workshop at the GSK Human Performance Laboratory, Nov. 12, 2014, in West London.
David Parker /Getty Images
Kate Middleton Steps Out for Remembrance Sunday
The Duchess of Cambridge watched the royal family lay a wreath at a ceremony at the Cenotaph in Whitehall London, Nov. 9, 2014.
Rupert Hartley/Rex
Pregnant Kate Middleton Looks Radiant in Light Blue Coat
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits Pembroke Refinery on Nov. 8, 2014 in Pembroke, Wales.
Samir Hussein/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge visit Pembroke Refinery on Nov. 8, 2014 in Pembroke, Wales.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press via Getty Images
Kate Middleton Shows Off Her Baby Bump
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the Action on Addiction Autumn Gala evening at L'Anima on Oct. 23, 2014 in London, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Radiantly Shows Her Baby Bump
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits Pembroke Refinery on Nov. 8, 2014 in Pembroke, Wales.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press via Getty Images
Kate Middleton Shows Off Her Bump For the First Time
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge walks with museum director Michael Dixon as she leaves the Natural History Museum after she attended the Wildlife Photographer of The Year 2014 Awards Ceremony, Oct. 21, 2014 in London, England.
Stefan Wermuth/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at the Natural History Museum to attend the Wildlife Photographer of The Year 2014 Awards Ceremony, Oct. 21, 2014 in London, England.
Arthur Edwards/Getty Images
Pregnant Kate Middleton Steps Out with Prince William
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge are seen as they welcome the President of Singapore Tony Tan Keng Yam at the Royal Garden Hotel on Oct. 21, 2014 in London, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton, Prince William and Prince Harry Take in an Art Installation
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Prince Harry visit the Tower of London's Ceramic Poppy Field at The Tower of London on August 5, 2014 in London, England. Each ceramic poppy represents an allied victim of the First World War and the display is due to be completed by Armistice Day on November 11, 2014.
Stuart C. Wilson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Commemorates 100th Anniversary of WWI
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends a WW1 100 Years Commemorations Ceremony at Le Memorial Interallie on August 4, 2014 in Liege, Belgium.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Jumps in Wedges at the Commonwealth Games
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge plays the South African game of Three Tins during a visit to the Commonwealth Games Village on July 29, 2014 in Glasgow, Scotland.
Danny Lawson/Getty Images
Why Are Kate Middleton and Prince William Cringing?
Prince Harry, Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and his wife Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, react as they watch the women's field hockey match between Wales and Scotland during the 2014 Commonwealth Games in Glasgow, Scotland, on July 28, 2014.
Glyn Kirk/AFP/Getty Images
Happy Birthday Prince George!
This photo dated July 2, 2014, was taken to mark Prince George's first birthday and shows the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge and the Prince during a visit to the Sensational Butterflies exhibition at the Natural History Museum, London.
John Stillwell/PA Wire
Happy Birthday Prince George!
This photo dated Wednesday July 2, 2014, was taken to mark Prince George's first birthday and shows the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge and the Prince during a visit to the Sensational Butterflies exhibition at the Natural History Museum, London.
John Stillwell/PA Wire
What Has Kate Middleton and Prince William So Upset?
Kate Middleton and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge attend the Simone Halep v Sabine Lisicki match on centre court during day nine of the Wimbledon Championships at Wimbledon, July 2, 2014, in London.
Karwai Tang/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Goes Pretty in Pink
Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge leaves the Blessed Sacrament School in London on July 1, 2014.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Opens a Park
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge makes an official visit to Bletchley Park, June 18, 2014, in Bletchley, England.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Cheers On Prince William at Windsor Castle
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge watches as Queen Elizabeth II leads the Knights of the Garter to the Most Noble Order of the Garter Ceremony from the Galilee Porch on June 16, 2014 in Windsor, England. The Order of the Garter is the senior and oldest British Order of Chivalry, founded by Edward III in 1348.
Getty Images
Duchess Catherine Revels In Prince George's First Steps
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge is pictured with Prince George of Cambridge at the Cirencester Park Polo Club on June 15, 2014 in Cirencester, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Celebrates Queen's Birthday
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge appears on the balcony of Buckingham Palace, during the Trooping The Colour parade, in central London, Saturday, June 14, 2014.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Stuns in Champagne for Prince Philip's Birthday
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, attends a garden party at Buckingham Palace in London on June 10, 2014.
John Stillwell/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Visits the Royal Maritime Museum
Catherine Duchess of Cambridge is seen at the America's Cup event at the National Maritime Museum in London, June 10, 2014.
Rex USA
Kate Middleton Honors D-Day
Princess Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, speaks to World War II veterans in Arromanches-les-Bains, Normandy, France, June 6, 2014, during an event commemorating the 70th anniversary of the World War II Allied landings in Normandy.
Leon Neal/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Greets Her Tiniest Fans
Britain's Catherine, The Duchess of Cambridge is greeted by children during a visit to the Macrosty Park in Crieff, Scotland on May 29, 2014.
Ian MacNicol/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Steps Out In Green
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at the Portrait Gallery, April 24, 2014 in Canberra, Australia
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Goes Pretty in Pink
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge receives flowers from spectators at the Playford Civic Centre, April 23, 2014 in Adelaide, Australia.
Daniel Kalisz/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Spins Records in Australia
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge gestures after she used the DJ decks at the youth community centre, The Northern Sound System, in Elizabeth, April 23, 2014 in Adelaide, Australia.
Morne de Klerk/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Looks Glamorous in Shades of Gray
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at St Andrew's Cathedral for Easter Sunday Service on April 20, 2014 in Sydney, Australia.
Brendon Thorne/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits Taronga Zoo on April 20, 2014 in Sydney, Australia.
Samir Hussein/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge feed a tree kangaroo at Taronga Zoo on April 20, 2014 in Sydney, Australia.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge meet a Koala at Taronga Zoo on April 20, 2014 in Sydney, Australia.
Cameron Spencer/Getty Images
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits RAAF Base Amberley on April 19, 2014 in Brisbane, Australia.
Danny Martindale/Getty Images
Britain's Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge waves as she walks with Wing Commander Stephen Chappell while visiting RAAF Base Amberley near Brisbane, Australia, Saturday, April 19, 2014.
William West/AP Photo
Britain's Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge, flanked by Chief of Air Force Air Marshall Geoff Brown, left, and Commanding Officer of Number 1 Squadron, Wing Commander Stephen Chappell, makes her way into the cockpit of a RAAF Super Hornet from 1 Squadron at RAAF Base Amberley, near Brisbane, Australia, Saturday, April 19, 2014.
William West/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Runs on the Beach in Heels
Catherine, the Duchess of Cambridge, runs along the beach at Manly, on Sydney's north shore, April 18, 2014.
William West/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Meets With Surf Lifesavers
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge meets with young surf lifesavers during a surf lifesaving event on Manly Beach, April 18, 2014, in Sydney.
Jason Reed/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Rocks a Pattern Down Under
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at the Winmalee Guide Hall, April 17, 2014 in Winmalee, Australia.
Brendon Thorne/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Stuns in Yellow
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince George of Cambridge arrive at Sydney Airport on a Australian Airforce 737 aircraft, April 16, 2014 in Sydney.
Samir Hussein/Getty Images
See Kate Middleton Play Cricket in Heels
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge is seen playing cricket at Latimer Square where she attended an event to mark the 2015 Cricket World Cup, April 14, 2014 in Christchurch, New Zealand.
Danny Martindale/Getty Images
Oops! Kate Middleton Barely Avoids a Tumble
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge stumbles as she walks through the vineyard with Prince William, Duke of Cambridge visit the Amisfield Winery, April 13, 2014 in Queenstown, New Zealand.
Arthur Edwards/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Goes Nautical In Stripes
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge helms an America's Cup yacht as she races Prince William, Duke of Cambridge in Auckland Harbour, April 11, 2014, in Auckland, New Zealand.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Shines at the State Reception
Britain's Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge, smiles while attending a state reception at Government House in Wellington, New Zealand, April 10, 2014.
Hagen Hopkins/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Makes an Elegant Entrance
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends a WW1 commemorative and Flying Day at Omaka Aviation Heritage Centre April 10, 2014 in Blenheim, New Zealand.
Samir Hussein/Getty Images
Britain's Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge, holds Prince George during a visit to Plunket nurse and parents group at Government House in Wellington, New Zealand, April 9, 2014.
Marty Melville/AP Photo
Britain's Prince George plays during a visit to Plunket nurse and parents group at Government House in Wellington, New Zealand, April 9, 2014. Plunket is a national not-for-profit organization that provides care for children and families in New Zealand.
Marty Melville/AP Photo
Inside Prince George's First Royal Playdate
Britain's Prince George plays with the hair of his mother, Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge, during a visit to Plunket nurse and parents group at Government House in Wellington, New Zealand, April 9, 2014.
Marty Melville/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Channels Princess Diana in New Zealand
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge touches the leg of Prince George of Cambridge with Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge as they arrive at Wellington Airport's military terminal for the start of their tour, April 7, 2014 in Wellington, New Zealand.
Samir Hussein/Getty Images
Prince William and Kate Middleton Hit a Wedding with Prince Harry
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, Prince Harry and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attend the wedding of Lucy Meade and Charlie Budgett, March 29, 2014, in Chippenham, England.
Max Mumby/Indigo/Getty Images
The Duke and Duchess of Cambridge with their son Prince George and dog Lupo photographed at Kensington Palace, London, March 2014.
Jason Bell/Camera Press/Redux
Kate Middleton Goes Green for St. Patricks Day
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the St Patrick's Day parade at Mons Barracks, March 17, 2014 in Aldershot, England.
Getty Images
Why Kate Middleton Hung Out with Helen Mirren
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, meets actress Dame Helen Mirren as Sir David Attenborough looks on during the Dramatic Arts reception at Buckingham Palace in London, Feb. 17, 2014.
Yui Mok/WPA/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Stuns in Blue
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge leaves after opening the ICAP Art Room at Northolt High School in Ealing, London.
ZH1/ZJE/WENN.com
Kate Middleton Dazzles at a Glamorous Gala
The Duchess of Cambridge attends The Portrait Gala 2014: Collecting To Inspire at National Portrait Gallery, Feb. 11, 2014 in London, England.
Ben Pruchnie/Getty Images
Happy 32nd Birthday Kate Middleton! All Her Best Looks
Kate the Duchess of Cambridge arrives to attend a Christmas Day Service with other members of the royal family at St. Mary's church on the grounds of Sandringham Estate, the Queen's royal estate in Norfolk, England, Dec. 25, 2013.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Inside Kate Middleton's Christmas with the Queen
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrive for the Christmas Day service at Sandringham on Dec. 25, 2013 in King's Lynn, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Inside Kate Middleton's Christmas with the Queen
Queen Elizabeth II, second from right, embraces Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge as they arrive at the Christmas Day service at Sandringham on Dec. 25, 2013 in King's Lynn, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Inside Kate's Christmas with the Queen
Queen Elizabeth II, right, and Catherine, the Duchess of Cambridge arrive at the Christmas Day service at Sandringham on Dec. 25, 2013 in King's Lynn, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton and Prince William Arrive at the Palace for Christmas Lunch
Prince William and Catherine Duchess of Cambridge attend the Royal family Christmas lunch at Buckingham Palace, Dec. 18, 2013, in London.
Tim Rooke/Rex/REX USA
Kate Middleton Shows Off Her Tiny Waist in Lace
Britain's Prince William and Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, arrive at the Natural History Museum in London, to attend a screening of the film "David Attenborough's Alive 3D," Dec. 11, 2013. The Duchess of Cambridge is a patron of the museum.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Shows Off Her Tiny Waist in Lace
Britain's Prince William and Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, arrive at the Natural History Museum in London, to attend a screening of the film "David Attenborough's Alive 3D," Dec. 11, 2013.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press via Getty Images
What?s Making Kate Middleton Laugh?
Catherine, Duchess Of Cambridge, holds a frog hand puppet visits the children's hospice Shooting Star House in London, Dec. 6, 2013.
Bradley Page/Daily Mail/EPA
Kate Middleton Stuns in White
Britain's Kate the Duchess of Cambridge and her husband Prince William arrive to attend the UK premiere of the movie "Mandela: Long Walk to Freedom" at a cinema in London on Dec. 5, 2013.
Matt Dunham/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Stuns in White
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the Royal film performance of "Mandela: Long Walk To Freedom" at Odeon Leicester Square on December 5, 2013 in London. (Photo by )
Danny Martindale/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Dazzles in Diamond Tiara
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge is seen leaving Kensington Palace for the Diplomatic reception at Buckingham Palace, Dec. 3, 2013.
Jesal/Tanna/Splash News
Check Out Kate Middleton's Darker 'Do!
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the annual SportsAid dinner at Victoria Embankment Gardens, Nov. 28, 2013 in London.
Danny Martindale/Getty Images
Kate Glows at Children's Charity Function
The Duchess of Cambridge stepped out solo Thursday night for the annual SportsAid charity dinner at Victoria Embankment Gardens, Nov. 28, 2013 in London. The new mom, 31, looked stylish in a black dress by designer Alice Temperley and presented the "One-to-Watch" award to 16-year-old shooter Amber Hill.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press/Getty Images
Kate Glows At Children's Charity Function
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at Clifford Chance for a Place2Be forum at Canary Wharf, Nov. 20, 2013, in London.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Steps Out in Brown
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits the Only Connect and ex-offenders projects, Nov. 19, 2013, in London.
Ben Pruchnie/FilmMagic/Getty Images
Kate Twirls Her Ringlets During Remembrance Day
Britain's Kate, The Duchess of Cambridge, listens from a balcony during the service of remembrance at the Cenotaph in Whitehall, London, Sunday, Nov. 10, 2013. The annual remembrance service is to remember all those who have lost their lives serving in the Armed Forces.
Kirsty Wigglesworth/AP Photo
Kate Glows In Red on Poppy Day
Britain's Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, prepares to meet staff and volunteers from the Royal British Legions London Poppy Day Appeal at Kensington Palace in central London, Nov. 7, 2013.
Carl Court/AFP/Getty Images
Will and Kate Ride a Bus!
Britain's Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, ride with television personality Barbara Windsor on the 1960s Routemaster bus as they meet London Poppy Day staff and volunteers in central London, Nov. 7, 2013.
Carl Court/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Stuns at Prince George's Christening
Director of 100WHF Amanda Pullinger (L) and Chairman 100WHF Mimi Drake (R) meet Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge (R) at a gala dinner in aid of Action on Addiction hosted by the 100 Women in Hedge Funds Philanthropic Initiatives on October 24, 2013 in London, England.
Ian West/WPA Pool/Getty Images
Kate Plays Volleyball in Heels 3 Months After Giving Birth
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, holds her son Prince George of Cambridge following his Christening at Chapel Royal in St James's Palace in central London, Oct. 23, 2013.
John Stillwell/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Plays Volleyball in Heels 3 Months After Giving Birth
On the left, Britain's Prince William, right, Kate Duchess of Cambridge with their son Prince George leave the Chapel Royal in St James's Palace in London, with the Archbishop of Canterbury Justin Welby after the christening of the three month-old Prince George, Oct. 23, 2013. Prince William carries his son Prince George, as he arrives with his wife Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge.
AP Photo|Reuters
PHOTOS: Radiant Kate Steps Out Post-Birth
Britain's Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, plays volleyball during a trip to the SportsAid Athlete Workshop in the Copper Box at the Queen Elizabeth Olympic Park in east London, Oct. 17, 2013.
Carl Court/AFP/Getty Images
PHOTOS: Duke and Duchess of Cambridge out for a drive
The royal family were out in force at Crathie Kirk, Balmoral, Sept. 22, 2013. Prince William drove Catherine to the service and were followed by Prince Charles and Camilla then The Queen and Prince Philip.
Splash News
PHOTOS: Radiant Kate Steps Out Post-Birth
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attend the Tusk Conservation Awards at The Royal Society on Sept. 12, 2013 in London.
Danny E. Martindale/Getty Images
Radiant Kate Shows off Baby Boy
Kate Middleton made her first post-baby public appearance August 30, 2013 at the Ring O'Fire Anglesey Coastal Ultra Marathon in Holyhead, Wales. The Duchess of Cambridge sported a green blazer, patterned crme top, and skinny jeans, revealing how quickly the new mom has returned to her sleek and fit physique since Prince George's July 22 birth.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press via Getty Images
Radiant Kate Shows off Royal Baby Boy
Britain's Prince William and Kate, Duchess of Cambridge hold the Prince of Cambridge, July 23, 2013, as they pose for photographers outside St. Mary's Hospital exclusive Lindo Wing in London where the Duchess gave birth, July 22.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Radiant Kate Shows off Royal Baby Boy
Britain's Prince William and Kate, Duchess of Cambridge hold the Prince of Cambridge, July 23, 2013, as they pose for photographers outside St. Mary's Hospital exclusive Lindo Wing in London where the Duchess gave birt, July 22.
Lefteris Pitarakis/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Looks Radiant in Pink
Britain's Prince Harry, left, Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, center, and Prince William, on the balcony of Buckingham Palace, during the Trooping The Colour parade, in London, Saturday, June 15, 2013.Other royals including Prince Harry and the Duchess of Cambridge joined in the celebration of Queen Elizabeth's birthday Saturday.
Sang Tan/AP Photo
Pregnant Kate Pretty in Peach
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge cuts the ribbon to break the bottle of Moet &amp; Chandon Brut Imperial Champagne against the ship for the Princess Cruises naming ceremony at Ocean Terminal, June 13, 2013 in Southampton, England.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Is 'Mellow' in Yellow
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends a service marking the 60th anniversary of the Queen's coronation at Westminster Abbey, June 4, 2013 in London.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press/Getty Images
Mom-to-Be's Maternity Fashion
Prince Charles, left, Camilla, the Duchess of Cornwall and Catherine, the Duchess of Cambridge attend a Garden Party on the grounds of Buckingham Palace in London, May 22, 2013.
John Stillwell/ AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Looks Radiant in Pink
Britain's Kate, Duchess of Cambridge arrives back at Buckingham Palace in a horse drawn carriage after the Trooping The Colour parade, at the Horse Guards Parade in London, Saturday, June 15, 2013.
Sang Tan/AP Photo
New Photos: The Life and Times of Kate Middleton
Kate Middleton, The Duchess of Cambridge, visits Naomi House Children's Hospice on her 2nd wedding anniversary to Prince William to celebrate Children's Hospice Week 2013, April 29, 2013 in Winchester, England.
Barcroft Media/startraksphoto.com
Kate Middleton in Polka Dots
Duchess of Cambridge Kate Middleton joins Prince William and Prince Harry to have a magical day out with a visit to the studio where the "Harry Potter" movies were filmed, April 26, 2013.
Chris Jackson/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Is Sublime in Green Coat
Britain's Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge, in her capacity as patron of "The Art Room", arrives to attend an evening reception to celebrate the work of the charity at the National Portrait Gallery in London, April 24, 2013.
Startracks
Kate Middleton Is Sublime in Green Coat
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, right, arrives to visit The Willows Primary School, Wythenshawe to launch a new school counseling program, April 23, 2013 in Manchester, England.
Paul Ellis/WPA Pool/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Radiant in Red
Britain's Duchess of Cambridge, attends the National Review of Queen's Scouts at Windsor Castle, near London, April 21, 2013.
Olivia Harris-Pool/AP Photo
Kate Pays Tribute to Scotland
The Duchess of Cambridge, known as the Countess of Strathearn when in Scotland, smiles during a visit to Dumfries House in Ayrshire, Scotland, to attend the opening of an outdoor centre, Friday April 5, 2013.
Danny Lawson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton in Short Plaid Coat
Kate Middleton, also known as the Countess of Strathearn when in Scotland, visits The Emirates Arena in a tartan coat on April 4, 2013 in Glasgow, United Kingdom. The Emirates Arena will play host to several events at the 2014 Glasgow Commonwealth Games.
Mark Cuthbert/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Becomes a Scout
Kate Middleton bundles up around the fire at the Great Tower Scout Camp near Newby Bridge in Cumbria on March 22, 2013. The Duchess of Cambridge tried her hand at roasting pastries as an honorary member of the scouts with a red, white and blue neckerchief around her neck.
@UKScouting/Twitter
Kate Middleton's Growing Bump
The Duchess of Cambridge, right, accompanies Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip, obscured at left, to a London subway station to mark the 150th anniversary of the London Underground on March 20, 2013.
Sang Tan/AP Photo
Kate Middleton's Growing Baby Bump
Kate Middleton, Duchess of Cambridge, arrives at the Clare Foundation in London, wearing a white wool coat, March 19, 2013.
Wenn.com
Kate Bundles Up for Day at the Races
While handing out shamrocks to members of the Irish Guards on St Patrick's Day on March 17, 2013 in Aldershot, England, the Duchess of Cambridge managed to get her black suede shoe wedged in a drain. Luckily, Prince William was there for her to lean on as she freed herself.
Danny Martindale/WireImage/Getty Images
Middleton At the Races
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends Day 4 of The Cheltenham Festival at Cheltenham Racecourse on March 15, 2013 in England.
Indigo/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Bundles Up for Friend's Wedding
A pregnant Kate Middleton met with children at Humberside Fire and Rescue during an official visit to Grimsby, England March 5, 2013.
Samir Hussein/WireImage/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Attends Swiss Alps Wedding
The Duchess of Cambridge, Kate Middleton, The Duke of Cambridge, Prince William and Prince Harry attend the wedding of Mark Tomlinson and Laura Bechtolsheimer in Arosa, Switzerland, March 2, 2013.
Splash News
Kate Middleton Shows Her Baby Bump
Britain's Kate, The Duchess of Cambridge arrives at Hope House, in London, Feb. 19, 2013. As patron of Action on Addiction, the Duchess was visiting Hope House, a safe, secure place for women to recover from substance dependence.
Matt Dunham/AP Photo
Kate, Radiant in Red Viewing Her Official Portrait
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, sporting a 'Sofie Rae' dress from Whistles, smiles after viewing her newly-commissioned portrait by artist Paul Emsley at the National Portrait Gallery in central London, Jan. 11, 2013.
John Stillwell - WPA Pool/Getty Images
Kate Joins Family for Christmas Services
A newly-commissioned portrait of Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, by artist Paul Emsley hangs at the National Portrait Gallery in London, Jan. 11, 2013. While the painting reveals a more mature Middleton, art critics say it looks nothing like her.
Sang Tan/AP Photo
Kate Middleton at Christmas Services
Prince William and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, attend the Eucharist at St. Marks Church in Englefield, Berkshire, England, Dec. 25, 2012.
Jesal Parshotam/Splash
Kate Middleton's Royal Style
Winner of Sports Personality of the Year 2012, Bradley Wiggins with David Beckham (L) and and Kate Middleton, The Duchess of Cambridge (R) during the BBC Sports Personality of the Year Awards 2012 at ExCeL Arena in London, Britain, on December 16, 2012. This is the first public engagement by the Duchess after her pregnancy has been announced.
David Davie/EPA
Kate Middleton Bundles Up
Kate Middleton, the Duchess of Cambridge, plays hockey during her visit to St. Andrew's School, where she attended from 1986 to 1995, in Pangbourne, England, on Nov. 30, 2012.
Arthur Edwards/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Dazzles With New Hairdo
Kate Middleton showed off her new hairdo and bundled up in a tan coat during an official visit to The Guildhall with Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, Nov. 28, 2012 in Cambridge, England. Will and Kate arrived in their namesake city to open a new hospital.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press via Getty Images
Kate Shows Off Her Bangs
Catherine, The Duchess of Cambridge attends the official opening of The Natural History Museums's Treasures Gallery at Natural History Museum on Nov. 27, 2012 in London, England. Middleton dazzled the crowd with her gorgeous emerald-colored dress. But it was her fresh, new hairstyle that stole the show.
Mark Cuthbert/UK Press/Getty Images
Kate Atrrives at International Rugby Match
The Duchess of Cambridge was presented with a bouquet of flowers before watching a rugby match between Wales and New Zealand at the Millennium Stadium in Cardiff.
Michael Steele - WPA Pool/Getty Images
Kate Attends Rememberance Sunday
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends Remembrance Sunday at the Cenotaph on Whitehall on Nov. 11, 2012 in London. She wore a black Diane Von Furstenberg military-style coat for the occasion.
Samir Hussein/WireImage/Getty Images
Will and Kate's Late Night Out
Kate Middleton recycled a lace Alice Temperley dress for a gala dinner in support of the University of St. Andrews 600th Anniversary Campaign at Middle Temple Hall on Nov. 8, 2012, in London. The Duchess of Cambridge attended St. Andrews for college, where she met Prince William. Middleton wore the dress to the "War Horse" premiere earlier this year.
Indigo/Getty Images
Middleton Bundles Up in London
Prince William and Kate Middelton are seen leaving private members club Loulou's in London at 1 a.m. on Oct. 11, 2012. The couple was reunited for their night out in the British capital after William attended a funeral of his childhood nanny. Middleton's sister Pippa was reportedly seen catching up with the couple at the hotspot.
Xposure
Will and Kate Back in Public
Prince William and Kate Middleton spoke with the England team Oct. 9, 2012 during the official launch of The Football Association's National Football Center at St George's Park in Burton-upon-Trent, England. The Duchess bundled up in a Reiss coat as she toured the facilities and listened to her husband's speech.
Michael Regan/The FA via Getty Images
Kate Middleton Sparkles at Friend's Wedding
Prince William and Kate Middleton visited the Middle Temple in London Oct. 8, 2012. This is their first public appearance since their tour of Southeast Asia and the South Pacific last month when a French magazine released topless photos of Kate.
Chris Jackson/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Shakes and Shimmies in Tuvalu
Kate Middleton, Duchess of Cambridge, was among guests at the wedding of Thierry Kelaart and Patrick Heathcoat-Amory, at St Bartholomew's Church in Oxfordshire, England Sept. 19, 2012. Kelaart is a close friend of Middleton's sister Pippa. The Duchess wore a light blue dress by Erdem. The dress is the same one she wore in June while attending festivities to mark the Queen's Diamond Jubilee.
Ikon Pictures Ltd. I Rex USA
Kate Middleton Lets Her Hair Down
Kate Middleton shook and shimmied the night away on the island of Tuvalu Sept. 18, 2012. The Duke and Duchess of Cambridge donned traditional grass skirts at a gathering of the island chiefs. Kate also sprayed perfume on the dancers which is a sign of respect. Will and Kate are representing the Queen on their Diamond Jubilee tour through Singapore, Malaysia, the Solomon Islands and Tuvalu.
Arthur Edwards/Getty Images
Kate in Bold Island Colors
Kate Middleton and Prince William received a traditional welcome to the village of Marau before traveling to Tavanipupu Island as part of their southeast Asia tour. The Duke and Duchess of Cambridge received beaded necklaces before traveling in a war canoe to Tavanipupu. They walked barefoot as locals gave them a tour around the island.
Samir Hussein/Getty Images
Kate in Bold Island Colors
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge visit a cultural village on their Diamond Jubilee tour of the Far East, Sept. 17, 2012 in Honiara, Guadalcanal Island.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate in Bold Island Colors
Britain's William and his wife Kate, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge, leave the Cultural village in Honiara, Sept. 17, 2012.
Daniel Munoz/AP Photo
Kate in Bold Island Colors
Britain's Prince William, left, and wife Kate, the Duchess of Cambridge, right, pose for a photo in Honiara, Solomon Islands, Sept. 16, 2012.
William West-Pool/Getty Images
Kate in Bold Island Colors
Catherine, the Duchess of Cambridge, arrives with her husband Britain's Prince William at the airport in Honiara on Sept. 16, 2012.
WILLIAM WEST/AFP/GettyImages
Kate Middleton in the Rain Forest
Prince William and his wife Kate, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge arrive at Danum Valley Research Center in Danum Valley, Sabab, Malaysia, Saturday, Sept. 15, 2012.
Vincent Thian/ Pool/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Dazzzles in White
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends a tea party at the British High Commission on day 4 of Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge's Diamond Jubilee Tour of the Far East on Sept. 14, 2012 in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.
Danny Lawson - Pool/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Shines in White
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits Assyakirin Mosque on day 4 of Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge's Diamond Jubilee Tour of the Far East on Sept. 14, 2012 in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Pays Respects
Kate Middleton chose a low-cut, gold and white Alexander McQueen dress for a formal dinner in Malaysia. The Duchess of Cambridge and her husband, Prince William, dined with Malaysian King Sultan Abdul Halim Mu'adzam Shah and Queen Haminah Hamidunat at the Istana Negara Palace in Kuala Lumpur Sept. 13.
Malaysia Information Department/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Chic in Singapore
On her last day in Singapore, Kate Middleton paid her respects at a Commonwealth war graves cemetery Sept. 13. The Duchess of Cambridge wore a pale blue pleated dress and carried a Chinese parasol. With the help of her husband, Prince William, Kate laid a wreath of behalf of the Queen and Prince Philip.
Wong Maye-E/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Chic in Singapore
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends a cultural event in Queenstown on day 2 of their Diamond Jubilee tour on Sept. 12, 2012 in Singapore.
Samir Hussein/WireImage/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Chic in Singapore
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge visits Gardens by the Bay on day 2 of the Diamond Jubilee Tour of the Far East, Sept. 12, 2012 in Singapore.
Mark Large/Pool/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Chic in Singapore
Britain's Prince William and his wife Catherine, the Duchess of Cambridge, listen to speeches at a British Gala reception at the Eden Hall in Singapore, Sept. 12, 2012.
Nicolas Asfouri/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Pretty in Pink
The Duchess of Cambridge did Prabal Gurung proud when she wore one of his dresses in Singapore on Sept. 11. Gurung, a Singapore-born designer, is one of the most promising young designers working in the U.S.
Arthur Edwards/WPA/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Awards Medals
Kate Middleton wears a kimono-style pink dress as she visits Singapore Botanical Gardens on the first day of a Diamond Jubilee tour on Sept. 11, 2012. Middleton and Prince William will visit Singapore, Malaysia, the Solomon Islands and the tiny Pacific Island of Tuvalu on their nine day tour.
Danny Lawson/Getty Images
Kate Goes Sporty With Track Suit
Britain's Kate, The Duchess of Cambridge awards the gold medal to Britain's Aled Davies for winning the men's discus throw F42 at the 2012 Paralympics, Sept. 2, 2012, in London.
Matt Dunham/AP Photo
Kate Cheers On Paralympics Athletes
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge arrives at the Eton Dorney venue to watch the days rowing competitions on day 4 of the London 2012 Paralympic Games at Eton Dorney on September 2, 2012 in Windsor, England.
Matthew Lloyd/Getty Images
Kate Middleton at the Paralympics
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, claps while watching track cycling during the 2012 Paralympic Games at the Velodrome in London, Aug. 30, 2012.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton at the Paralympics
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge, and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, share a laugh as they watch track cycling during the 2012 Paralympic Games at the Velodrome in London, Aug. 30, 2012.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton at the Paralympics
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, leaves after watching a goalball game during the 2012 Paralympic Games at the Olympic Park's Copper Box in east London, Aug. 30, 2012.
Stefan Rousseau/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Recycles Dress
Kate Middleton, wearing a blue and purple Whistles dress, spends a moment with Prime Minister David Cameron, left, and his wife, Samantha, at the closing ceremony of the 2012 London Olympic Games at the Olympic Stadium Aug. 12, 2012.
John Stillwell/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Visits Olympians
Britain's Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, leaves after watching a women's hockey bronze medal match between Britain and New Zealand at the 2012 Summer Olympics, London, Aug. 10, 2012. Britain won the bronze medal.
Jae C. Hong/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Visits Olympians
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, center, talks to Team GB after their Women's Hockey bronze medal match against New Zealand on Day 14 of the London 2012 Olympic Games, Aug. 10, 2012 in London, England.
Pascal Le Segretain/Getty Images
Middleton Cheers on Brits
Prince Harry and Kate Middleton, Duchess of Cambridge visit athletes at Team GB House in the Westfield Centre on Day 13 of the London 2012 Olympic Games on Aug. 9, 2012 in London, England. Middleton and Prince Harry visited met a number of athletes, including gold medal winning rower Sophie Hosking.
John Stillwell/Getty Images
Middleton Cheers on Team
Britain's Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, applauds Britain's handball team at the end of the women's preliminary Group A handball match, Croatia vs, Great Britain, for the London 2012 Olympics Games on Aug. 5, 2012 at the Copper Box hall in London. Croatia won 37-14.
Javier Soriano/AFP/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Cheers on Olympic Cycling Team
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge applaud the gold medal victory by the Team GB Men's Team Pursuit in the Track Cycling on Aug. 3, 2012 in London, England.
John Stillwell/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Does the Wave
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge embrace after Philip Hindes, Jason Kenny and Sir Chris Hoy of Great Britain win the gold and a new world record in the Men's Team Sprint Track Cycling final during Day 6 of the London 2012 Olympic Games at Velodrome, Aug. 2, 2012 in London.
Pascal Le Segretain/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Does The Wave
Prince William and Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, join the crowd in doing the wave at a match at Wimbledon in London at the 2012 Summer Olympics, Thursday, August 2, 2012.
AP Photo/Mark Humphrey
Kate Middleton Cheers on Queen's Grandchild
Kate Middleton arrives at the Royal Academy of Arts in London for the UK creative industries reception on July 30, 2012. Middleton looked ravishing in a gray dress designed by Roksanda Ilincic. The Duchess of Cambridge greeted British Prime Minister David Cameron as she attending an event to promote the U.K.'s GREAT Campaign.
Geoff Pugh/AP Photo
Middleton Greets Olympic Torch
Kate Middleton and Prince William attend the Cross Country Phase of The Eventing at Greenwich Park, on the third day of the London 2012 Olympics. The Duchess of Cambridge wore a classic blue blazer and simple white shirt while she watched as the Queen's granddaughter Zara Phillips competed at the event.
Owen Humphreys/PA Wire/Press Association Images
Kate Middleton Cheers on Queen's Grandchild
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the Eventing Cross Country Equestrian event of the London 2012 Olympic Games at Greenwich Park on July 30, 2012.
Pascal Le Segretain/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Greets Olympic Torch
Prince William and his wife Kate, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge, and Prince Harry are joined by children from the Team Britain Ambition Program as they watch Wai Ming hand over the London 2012 Olympic Torch to John Hulse during a visit to Buckingham Palace in London, on Day 69 of the London 2012 Olympic Torch Relay, July 26, 2012.
Ian West /AP Photo
Kate Middleton Greets Olympic Torch
Torchbearer 170 passes the Olympic Flame to Torchbearer 171 in front of Buckingham Palace in the presence of the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge and Prince Harry on the torch relay leg through Westminster, July 26, 2012, in London. The opening ceremonies for the 2012 Summer Olympics were scheduled Friday, July 27, 2012.
Gareth Fuller/AP Photo
Kate Watches Wimbledon Men's Final Match
Kate Middleton visits The National Portait Gallery's "Road to 2012: Aiming High Exhibition," July 19, 2012 in London. The Duchess wore an electric blue Stella McCartney dress and an Olympic inspired necklace from her own wardrobe.
Samir Hussein/WireImage/Getty Images
Kate and Pippa Middleton at Wimbledon
Kate, Duchess of Cambridge, right, speaks with her sister Pippa Middleton as they watch Roger Federer of Switzerland face Andy Murray of Britain during the men's final match at the All England Lawn Tennis Championships at Wimbledon, England, Sunday, July 8, 2012. Kate is reportedly wearing the Joseph Vanessa dress which she previously wore when she visited Canada with Prince William.
Kirsty Wigglesworth/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Goes Retro at Wimbledon
The Duchess of Cambridge looked impeccable as always while joining the Queen and the Duke of Edinburgh for Prince William's Thistle Service. Middleton wore a pale yellow coat dress by Emilia Wickstead and carried a flash of Strathearn tartan in the shape of a folded scarf.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Goes Retro at Wimbledon
Kate Middleton and Prince William make their way to their seats in the Royal Box on Centre Court during Day 9 of the Wimbledon Lawn Tennis Championships at the All England Lawn Tennis and Croquet Club. The duchess is wearing a pleated cable-knit dress by Alexander McQueen.
Clive Rose/Getty Images
Kate Middleton and Prince William Preserved in Wax
Wax figures of the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge are pictured wearing England supporters' hats, scarves and flags in support of England's participation in the Euro 2012, at Madame Tussauds, London, Friday, June 22, 2012.
Jonathan Short/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Radiant in White
(L-R) Sophie Rhys-Jones, Countess of Wessex, Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Camilla, Duchess of Cornwall attend the annual Order of the Garter Service at St George's Chapel, Windsor Castle on June 18, 2011 in Windsor, England. The Order of the Garter is the senior and oldest British Order of Chivalry, founded by Edward III in 1348.
Paul Edwards - WPA Pool/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Atttends Polo Match
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends The Golden Metropolitan Polo Club Charity Cup polo match, in which Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Prince Harry played, at the Beaufort Polo Club on June 17, 2012 in Tetbury, England.
Indigo/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Goes Camping
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge interacts with schoolchildren at an 'Expanding Horizons' Primary School camp in Kent, on June 17, 2012 in Wrotham, England.
David Parker/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Goes Camping
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge participated in several outdoor activities at the Widehorizons Margaret McMillan House in Kent, on June 17, 2012 in Wrotham, England.
David Parker/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Tranquil in Pastels
Kate Middleton wore a silver-gray Erdem dress to celebrate the Queen's official birthday. The Duchess of Cambridge rode in a horse drawn carriage to see the Trooping The Colour at the Horse Guards Parade in London, Saturday, June 16, 2012.
Sang Tan/AP Photo
Kate Middleton Bold in Blue
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge waves from the balcony of Council House in Nottingham, central England, June 13, 2012 during a visit. Middleton dazzled in a powder blue tweed M Missoni coat dress on the latest leg of the Queen's Diamond Jubilee tour.
Rui Vieira/AFP/ Getty Images
Kate, Dreamy in Dove Grey
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attends the wedding of Emily McCorquodale and James Hutt at The Church of St. Andrew and St. Mary, Stoke Rochford on June 9, 2012 in Grantham, England. She wore a pale gray dress paired with her signature LK Bennett shoes to the nuptials of Princess Diana's niece and Prince William's cousin, Emily McCorquodale.
Indigo/Getty Images
Kate, Radiant in Red!
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge takes part in The Thames River Pageant, as part of the Diamond Jubilee, marking the 60th anniversary of the accession of Queen Elizabeth II on June 3, 2012 in London, England.
Danny Martindale/WireImage/Getty Images
Kate Pretty in Pink
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge meets guests during a garden party at Buckingham Palace on May 29, 2012 in London, England. She wore the same simple pleated dress for the Royals for the Queen's celebratory lunch at Windsor Castle two weeks ago.
Anthony Devlin - WPA Pool /Getty Images
Kate Pretty in Pink
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, Camilla, Duchess of Cornwall, Princess Royal and Prince Charles, Prince of Wales attend a garden party at Buckingham Palace on May 29, 2012 in London, England.
Anthony Devlin - WPA Pool /Getty Images
Kate Is Pretty in Pink
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince William, Duke of Cambridge during a reception in the Waterloo Chamber, before the Lunch For Sovereign Monarchs at Windsor Castle, on May 18, 2012 in Windsor, England.
Arthur Edwards/WPA Pool/Getty Images
Kate Dazzles Crowd with Teal Dress
While her husband Prince William rode horseback at a charity polo match May 13, 2012, in Berkshire, England, Duchess of Cambridge Kate Middleton displayed her long athletic legs in a short sea-green dress and high-heeled wedge shoes.
Almasi/Splash News
Kate Middleton's Shimmers in Teal
Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attended at 'Our Greatest Team Rises -BOA Olympic Concert' at the Royal Albert Hall on May 11, 2012 in London, England. She wore a teal dress by one of her favorite designers, Jenny Packham.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Will, Kate Wax Figures Unveiled
The Duchess of Cambridge dazzled crowds as she accompanied Price William on Monday night to a meeting of the Thirty Club, which consists of some of Britain's most powerful ad and media types, at the famed Claridge's hotel in London. Middleton wowed onlookers in a cream-colored gown, believed to be designed by Roland Mouret, which featured a bold slit straight up the middle.
Splash News
Will, Kate Wax Figures Unveiled
Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge attend the UK Premiere of 'African Cats' in aid of Tusk Trust at BFI Southbank on April 25, 2012 in London, England.
Mark Large/Getty Images
Kate Middleton Celebrates St. Patrick's Day
A guard faints during a St. Patrick's Day parade visit by Kate Middleton, duchess of Cambridge.
ABC News
Kate Middleton: A Princess in the Making
Kate Middleton shopped for groceries in Anglesey, North West Wales May 5, 2011. "She loaded all the shopping into her car on her own, then skipped as she ran the trolley back to the park," an told the Daily Mail.
ABC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:00:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  This Week in Pictures</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/week-pictures-30619992</Link>
        <Description>The latest news photos from around the globe.</Description>
        <MainBody>+

Performers wave Vietnamese national flags during a parade celebrating the 40th anniversary of the end of the Vietnam War which is also remembered as the "Fall of Saigon", in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, April 30, 2015.
Dita Alangkara/AP Photo
Performers wave Vietnamese national flags during a parade celebrating the 40th anniversary of the end of the Vietnam War which is also remembered as the "Fall of Saigon", in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, April 30, 2015.
Dita Alangkara/AP Photo
Royalist Terry Hutt and Margaret Tyler chat on Terry's 80th Birthday as he continues his wait for a new Royal baby at the Lindo wing, April 30, 2015, in London. Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge is expected to give birth at the Lindo wing sometime in the next couple of weeks.
Chris Jackson/Getty Images
Four-month-old baby boy Sonit Awal is held up by Nepalese Army soldiers after being rescued from the rubble of his house in Bhaktapur, Nepal, April 26, 2015, after the 7.8-magnitude earthquake shook the densely populated Kathmandu valley.
Amul Thapa/KathmanduToday.com via AP Photo
A protester is detained by New York police during a demonstration calling for social, economic and racial justice in New York City, April 29, 2015. The demonstration was being held to support Baltimore's protest against police brutality following the April 19 death of Freddie Gray in police custody.
Andrew Kelly/Reuters
Landon McKenzie, 7, walks with his father, Shawn and brother Joem during an open carry gun rally and march, April 29, 2015, in downtown Lansing, Mich.
Danielle Duval/The Jackson Citizen Patriot via AP Photo
A demonstrator wears glasses with dollar signs in Bujumbura, Burundi, April 29, 2015, as anti-government street demonstrations continue against President Pierre Nkurunziza. Some demonstrators are vowing not to leave the streets until the president, seeking a third term, withdraws his candidacy.
Jerome Delay/AP Photo
Destroyed villages sit on mountain tops near the epicenter of the massive earthquake in the Gorkha District of Nepal, April 29, 2015. Aid reached the hilly district for the first time Wednesday, four days after the quake struck.
Wally Santana/AP Photo
A victim with a broken leg from Saturday's massive earthquake, gives her details to Nepalese soldiers as she arrives by helicopter from the heavily-damaged Ranachour village at a landing zone in the town of Gorkha, Nepal, April 28, 2015.
Wally Santana/AP Photo
Boxer Manny Pacquiao, of the Philippines, holds his youngest child, Israel, as they arrive at the Delano Las Vegas hotel, April 27, 2015, in Las Vegas. Pacquiao is scheduled to fight Floyd Mayweather Jr. in a welterweight boxing match in Las Vegas on May 2.
John Locher/AP Photo
Inmates gather on the roof of the prison of the National Bolivarian Police during a riot in Caracas, Venezuela, April 27, 2015.
Carlos Garcia Rawlins/Reuters
A demonstrator jumps on a damaged police car during clashes in Baltimore, Md., April 27, 2015. Several Baltimore police officers were injured on Monday in violent clashes with young people after the funeral of Freddie Gray, who died in police custody earlier this month.
Shannon Stapleton/Reuters
A pangolin climbs out of a cage upon its release into the wild in Sibolangit, Indonesia, April 27, 2015. A police raid last week confiscated the anteater and dozens of live pangolins, along with five tons of pangolin meat, ready to be shipped abroad.
Binsar Bakkara/AP Photo
Classic dancers perform on the street during Dance Day in Pamplona, Spain, April 25, 2015.
Alvaro Barrientos/AP Photo
Damaged buildings lean to their sides in Kathmandu, Nepal, April 27, 2015. A strong 7.8 magnitude earthquake shook Nepal's capital and the densely populated Kathmandu Valley on Saturday causing extensive damage, which toppled walls and collapsed buildings.
Wally Santana/AP Photo
Nineteen new priests lay on the ground during a ceremony in which Pope Francis ordained them in St. Peter's Basilica at the Vatican, April 26, 2015.
Giorgio Onorati/AP Photo
Mourners comfort one another during the funeral for Freddie Gray at the New Shiloh Baptist Church during his funeral, April 27, 2015, in Baltimore. According to his attorney, Gray died a week after being arrested for carrying a switchblade, in the hospital from a severe spinal cord injury he received while in police custody.
Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images
A rebel fighter rides a motorbike along a road in Qarmeed camp, April 27, 2015, in Syria. A coalition of Islamist rebels seized the army base in northwestern Syria which brought the coalition closer to seizing most of the Idlib province and moving toward Latakia, the ancestral home of President Bashar al-Assad.
Abdalghne Karoof/Reuters
Former British police officer Swasie Turner abseils for charity down the fortification bastions of Valletta, Malta, April 27, 2015. Turner has wheeled himself more than 38,000 miles and raised over 1 million pounds for charity since 1997 after losing his wife to cancer, and came months after he was confined to a wheelchair when he was deliberately run down by a motorcycle while on duty as a police officer.
Darrin Zammit/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
