<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:58:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN Chief Calls for Inquiry Into Dag Hammarskjold Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/chief-calls-inquiry-mysterious-dag-hammarskjold-plane-crash/story?id=32262632</Link>
        <Description>United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon believes further investigation is necessary to uncover the truth behind a 1961 plane crash in which Dag Hammarskjold died.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN Chief Calls for Inquiry Into Mysterious Dag Hammarskjold Plane Crash
Jul 7, 2015, 3:19 AM ET
Dag Hammarskjold is seen in a 1957 file photo.
MPI/Getty Images
United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon believes further investigation is necessary to uncover the truth behind a 1961 plane crash in which Secretary-General Dag Hammarskjold and 15 others died.
Questions remain about a possible aerial attack or other interference, Ban said.
But Ban said in a letter to the U.N. General Assembly circulated Monday that an independent review of new information about the mysterious crash put to rest claims that Hammarskjold was assassinated after surviving the crash.
Editor's Picks
The Note: Notes On A Rope
Ban called for countries to disclose relevant records related to the crash.
Hammarskjold's plane, a DC-6 known as the Albertina, crashed Sept. 18, 1961, in the African bush in Northern Rhodesia , today's Zambia , during a peace mission to newly independent Congo .
Topical Press Agency/Getty Images
PHOTO: Dag Hammarskjold is seen leaving the Claridges Hotel in London in this file photo.
The crash has long been shrouded in mystery. The lone survivor reported that there were explosions aboard the plane before it hit the ground, and speculation has raged that the plane was shot down, or that Hammarskjold was the subject of an assassination plot.
Pilot error has also been thought to have ontributed to the accident.
Hammarskjold devoted his life to diplomacy and public service. He was born in 1905, the son of Swedish prime minister Hjalmar Hammarskjold, who pushed for neutrality during World War I .
After attending college and receiving a doctorate from Stockholm University, Hammarskjold served as a professor and held various government roles. He joined the United Nations in 1949, and was approved as secretary-general in 1953.
ullstein bild/Getty Images
PHOTO: Dag Hammarskjold is seen in a 1955 file photo.
His tenure was marked by his diplomatic entreaties: face-to-face communication between various heads of state, pursuing peace, seeking accord.
He probably knows more state secrets than any man alive, Parade wrote of Hammarskjold in a 1960 profile. He hides what he knows behind a cloud of diplomatic double-talk. Like a baseball umpire, he is aloof, almost icy, and does not fraternize with the players. Also, he is criticized by both sides, and respected for his integrity.
After his death, Hammarskjold was awarded a posthumous Nobel Prize , one of three people to earn the distinction. A foundation was also established in his name, and his journal was published as Markings, a collection of insights and spiritual reflections.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:17:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Person Found Decapitated in France Terror Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/terrorist-attack-reported-france-factory-dead/story?id=32044062</Link>
        <Description>One person was found decapitated and two others were injured following an apparent terrorist attack at a factory in France, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Charlie Hebdo's New Issue Sells Out Around Paris
The factory is owned by Air Products &amp; Chemicals, a Pennsylvania-based company. The company released a statement following todays attack.
"We can confirm that an incident occurred at our facility in L'Isle-d'Abeau, France this morning. Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for, the company said. Emergency services are on site and have contained the situation. The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities. Further information will be released as soon as it becomes available."
At least 17 people have been killed in terror-related violence in France this year. In January, gunmen attacked the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo . The men suspected in that attack were later killed in raids at a Kosher supermarket and print shop.
Get real-time updates as this story unfolds. To start, just "star" this story in ABC News' phone app. Download ABC News for iPhone here or ABC News for Android here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:57:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Investigation Into Apparent Terrorist Attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/apparent-terrorist-attack-france-factory-32045039</Link>
        <Description>The attack happened at a U.S.-owned facility in southern France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Apparent Terrorist Attack at France Factory
+

French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Julien Reunaud/APS-Medias/Sipa USA/AP Photo
French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Julien Reunaud/APS-Medias/Sipa USA/AP Photo
French President Francois Hollande speaks during a media conference at an EU summit in Brussels, June 26, 2015.
Geert Vanden Wijngaert/AP Photo
French security stand next to the enclosed area near the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmaze/AFP/Getty Images
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:43:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sochi Inundated by Flooding After Torrential Rains</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/sochi-russia-inundated-flooding-months-rain-falls-day/story?id=32032427</Link>
        <Description>The Olympic city of Sochi was inundated with flood waters after torrential rains.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sochi, Russia Inundated by Flooding After More Than a Month's Rain Falls in a Day
Moscow  Jun 25, 2015, 4:39 PM ET
By PATRICK REEVELL
Sochi, Russia on the Black Sea.
Getty Images
Heavy rains have flooded Sochi, the Russian city that hosted the 2014 Winter Olympics , leaving one dead and some areas under several feet of water, according to officials and reports. It is also forcing authorities to consider an evacuation, the mayor's office said.
More than a month and a halfs rain -- 100 mm, or about 4 inches -- fell in 24 hours on the seaside city, according to the Russian news agency RIA Novosti. Despite now being best-known for the Winter Olympics, the city is a popular summer resort for Russians, squeezed between the Caucasus mountains and the Black Sea .
According to the AP, a man was found dead during salvage operations Thursday. No further details were immediately available.
Sochi Airport! Hot, cool, yours! https://t.co/5FG1eo0K7b pic.twitter.com/M1b6z8aGMd
 Maria Antonova (@mashant) June 25, 2015
Pictures on social media showed Sochis airport, refurbished for the Olympics, filled with brown water, with passengers standing next to baggage carousels up to their ankles. The citys mayor has told residents to prepare for a possible evacuation and to remain indoors, warning that water spouts could form offshore.
????? ?? ????????? ????????? #???? #???????????
A video posted by @shpakovev on Jun 25, 2015 at 3:36am PDT
Sochi and its Olympic reconstruction is one of Vladimir Putin s prized achievements, with a colossal $50 billion spent on transforming the city. So far most of the sports facilities built for the Olympics have reportedly been undamaged by the floods, according to Russian media, with most of the flooding confined to residential areas.
#????? #?????? #?????????? #????#?????#????? #????????? #?????
A photo posted by alesya1502 (@alesya1502) on Jun 25, 2015 at 5:26am PDT
#????? #???? #?????????? #?????#?????? #????? #????? #?????????
A photo posted by alesya1502 (@alesya1502) on Jun 25, 2015 at 5:25am PDT
????, ????? ????????? ????#????#?????#????#?????????
A video posted by ??????? (@hibushkaaa) on Jun 25, 2015 at 3:30am PDT
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32032427.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:43:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UberPop Banned After Taxi Driver Protests Turn Ugly</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/uberpop-banned-paris-amid-taxi-driver-protests-airports/story?id=32017565</Link>
        <Description>Paris officials announced a ban on UberPop after about 2,800 taxi drivers staged a strike across France today in  protest of the  ride-hailing app.</Description>
        <MainBody>UberPop Banned in Paris Amid Taxi Driver Protests at Airports
PARIS  Jun 25, 2015, 3:39 PM ET
By HUGO LEENHARDT via Good Morning America
Taxi drivers on strike burn tires during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Marseille, France, June 25, 2015.
Jean-Paul Pelissier/Reuters
Paris officials announced a ban on UberPop after about 2,800 taxi drivers staged a strike across France today in protest of the ride-hailing app that resulted in numerous arrests and injured cops.
The taxi drivers briefly blocking access to airports and forced passengers to finish the journey by foot.
Some drivers vandalized several Uber cars, even flipping some over, and riot police were forced to intervene, arresting three taxi cab drivers, according to police officials.
Charles Platiau/Reuters
PHOTO: French taxi drivers, who are on strike, block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, June 25, 2015.
How Uber Helped a Recent Grad in Texas Plan an Epic Marriage Proposal
The demonstration was organized to protest against UberPop, the service that connects customers to drivers without professional taxi or chauffeur licenses. These drivers use their private vehicles to pick up clients, and UberPop is usually a second job for them.
Prices for the UberPop version of the Uber app are generally 30 to 50 percent cheaper than cab fares and drivers pay far less taxes.
The UberPop service had already been deemed illegal by the French government that accuses it of unfair competition, though the Uber app has not been officially banned. And today's action does not mean UberPop, and other services like it, will disappear but that police can arrest drivers in Paris and its suburbs using it, and also fine clients. But the thinking is that it will be difficult to enforce.
Michel Euler/AP Photo
PHOTO: Taxis gather at a major entrance of Paris, June 25, 2015, in Paris.
Thibaud Simphal, director of Uber France, said on French TV BFM Business that the company will challenge the "prefectoral order." "We will challenge it and see what comes out of the appeal, Uberpop can continue," Simphal said.
In the middle of the strike today, customers were taken hostage by the conflict. Musician Courtney Love , on her way to Paris from the airport, tweeted: they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
The Interior minister announced that 10 people had been arrested and seven police officers injured, in addition to the 70 cars vandalized during the day.
One of them appears to be shown in this YouTube video where a man on an overpass sends a rock crashing down on the windshield at Porte Maillot on the west side of Paris, where taxi drivers were demonstrating all day.
Also, an Uber car transporting a couple and its baby was hit by a rock on the way to the airport, breaking the rear window. "It was very scary," the passenger told French TV station iTele , but no one was injured.
Uber had warned earlier in the day that "demand will be very high today and the service could be disturbed. Good luck to all."
At Orly airport, an Uber driver reportedly ran over a cabbie who was blocking off his car, injuring him. He has been taken into custody.
Reacting to the clashes, Prime Minister Manuel Valls "condems with great severity" this "unacceptable" violence regarding today's events, he said.
Michel Euler/AP Photo
PHOTO: Striking taxi drivers stand behind an overthrown car during a taxi drivers demonstration, June 25, 2015, in Paris.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32017565.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:54:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mom and Baby Survived 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/mother-baby-rescued-surviving-days-colombian-jungle-plane/story?id=32028463</Link>
        <Description>Marie Nelly Murillo and her baby were rescued after they spent almost days stranded in the middle of a jungle following a small plane crash, the Colombia Air Force said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother and Baby Rescued After Surviving 5 Days in Colombian Jungle Following Plane Crash
Jun 25, 2015, 2:44 PM ET
The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
fac.mil.co
Copy
An 18-year-old woman and her baby miraculously survived a small plane crash in the Colombian jungle and then survived five days on coconut water before rescuers finally located them, according to officials and reports.
Colombian airmen and disaster relief agency workers discovered the mother, Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son Wednesday after five days of search and rescue efforts that immediately began when their plane was reported missing Saturday, the Colombian Air Force said today in a statement.
"It's a miracle. It is a very wild area and it was a catastrophic accident," Colombian Air Force Col. Hector Carrascal told the BBC. He added the mother's spirit must have given the baby "the strength to survive."
Nepal Earthquake: Teen Rescued After 5 Days Trapped in Rubble
Murillo, 18, suffered injuries and minor burns, but the baby was apparently unharmed, the Air Force said. They were flown in a helicopter to a hospital in Quibdo, Colombia .
The pilot of the small plane, a Cessna 303, was discovered dead on Monday before the mother and her baby were found, according to the Air Force. It was not clear what the relationship between the woman and baby and the pilot was or why they were on the plane.
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
Murillo, 18, and her son were passengers in the small plane, which was carrying fish and coconuts from the town of Nuqui to Quibdo, the the BBC reported .
A trail of clues including coconut shells discovered near the plane site and a discarded flip-flop in the jungle gave the rescue teams hope during the nearly week-long search that ended Wednesday, the BBC added.
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
Murillo wandered in the jungle carrying her child, surviving on coconut water and trying unsuccessfully to trap rodents for food, Red Cross volunteer Acisclo Renteria told The Associated Press (AP).
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
The 38-year-old rescuer said he saw the success as a blessing, the AP added.
"I thanked my little God for allowing me to save these two people," Renteria, who has been asked by Murillo to be her son's godfather, told the AP. "One thing is telling you on the phone what we experienced but it's quite another is to have lived it."
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32028463.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:24:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi F-16 Fighter Jet Crashes in Arizona</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/iraqi-16-fighter-jet-crashes-arizona-training-mission/story?id=32024137</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi pilots are being training in the U.S. to combat ISIS, officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
The F-16 fighter jet that crashed in Arizona overnight was actually owned by the Iraqi Air Force and flown by an Iraqi pilot, a U.S. Air Force official confirmed to ABC News today.
Local law enforcement has been on the scene since the crash last night near Douglas, Arizona, but Air Force officials have yet to confirmed the identity of the pilot, who they say is an Iraqi trainee. The crash caused a large grass fire and its likely the pilot did not survive, authorities said.
Officially, the Air Force is saying only that the pilots status is unknown.
Mamta Popat/The Tucson Citizen/AP
PHOTO: Smoke rises Thursday, June 25, 2015, from the site where an F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed Wednesday evening near Douglas, Ariz.
The Iraqi military is involved in a program to train Iraqi Air Force pilots in the United States before it receives the jets in Iraq. The first two of 36 jets purchased by the Iraqi government arrived at the Tucson International Airport, Arizona this December, where Iraqi pilots are training, officials said.
The F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed during a training mission at about 8 p.m. on Wednesday near Douglas, Arizona, with one person on board, the 162nd Wing of the Arizona Air National Guard said in statement.
Mamta Popat/The Tucson Citizen/AP
PHOTO: Cochise County Sheriff blocks the road on June 25, 2015, miles away from the site where an F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed near Douglas, Ariz.
The 162nd in responsible for the international training mission, which the Iraqis are depending on to combat the militant group ISIS .
Iraq has received a total of 12 brand new F-16s, all of which are currently in the U.S. The first delivery of the jets to Iraq is expected this summer.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32024137.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:40:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Space Shuttles Captured in Abandoned Hangar</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/captivating-photographs-document-soviet-space-shuttles-abandoned-kazakhstan-32001246</Link>
        <Description>Photographer documents two abandoned Soviet space shuttles.  </Description>
        <MainBody>Captivating Photographs Document Soviet Space Shuttles Abandoned in Kazakhstan
+

Russian photographer, Ralph Mirebs, traveled to Baikonur, Kazakhstan to document an abandoned hangar that resides in Kazakhstan. Inside the hangar, which has been inoperative for the last 20 years, remain two Soviet Space shuttle prototypes in decaying conditions. An aerial view of the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan is pictured.
Ralph Mirebs
Russian photographer, Ralph Mirebs, traveled to Baikonur, Kazakhstan to document an abandoned hangar that resides in Kazakhstan. Inside the hangar, which has been inoperative for the last 20 years, remain two Soviet Space shuttle prototypes in decaying conditions. An aerial view of the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan is pictured.
Ralph Mirebs
The abandoned hangar is left from the discontinued Soviet/ Russian Buran space program that was discontinued in 1993. A view of the engine from one of the shuttles found in the hangar .
Ralph Mirebs
A view inside the cargo hold
Ralph Mirebs
A prototype shuttle that was left in the abandoned hangar in Baikonur, Kazakhstan
Ralph Mirebs
A view of the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan.
Ralph Mirebs
A view inside the cockpit of one of the prototype shuttles.
Ralph Mirebs
A test model is seen in the abandoned hangar in Kazakhstan.
Ralph Mirebs
The two space shuttles found in the hangar are in bad condition -- parts of their thermal protective tiles have fallen off, windows are broken and the equipment is inoperable.
Ralph Mirebs
A view inside the cockpit of one of the prototype shuttles.
Ralph Mirebs
Exterior view of an abandoned hangar in Baikonur, Kazakhstan.
Ralph Mirebs
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:26:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China Debuts Newborn Panda Twins</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/china-debuts-newborn-panda-twins/story?id=31994921</Link>
        <Description>The twin pandas born through artificial insemination </Description>
        <MainBody>China Debuts Its Newborn Panda Twins
Jun 24, 2015, 12:26 PM ET
ABC NEWS via Good Morning America
Newborn twin female panda cubs are seen inside an incubator at the Giant Panda Research Base in Chengdu, China, June 22, 2015.
China Daily/Reuters
Visitors to a panda breeding center in China got the first, up-close view of twin pandas born just one day earlier.
The pandas were born Monday at the Chengdu Research Base of Giant Panda Breeding to their mother, 7-year-old Kelin, the Associated Press reported .
The cubs were conceived through artificial insemination, part of Chinas effort to increase the panda population. The twins mother was artificially inseminated in January, according to the AP.
China Daily /Reuters
PHOTO: A researcher feeds one of the newborn twin female panda cubs inside an incubator at the Giant Panda Research Base in Chengdu, China, June 22, 2015.
The chief administrator at Chengdu said the twins were born in good condition based on their body temperature and milk consumption.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31994921.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:59:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How the US Trains Wounded Warriors to Hunt Child Predators</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/us-government-trains-wounded-warriors-hunt-child-predators/story?id=31942508</Link>
        <Description>Soldiers have found a new way to serve their country. </Description>
        <MainBody>How the US Government Is Training Wounded Warriors to Hunt Child Predators
Jun 24, 2015, 10:43 AM ET
Sgt. Justin Gaertner, who lost both legs in Afghanistan, stands with his service dog Gunner.
Courtesy DHS and Justin Gaertner
Marine Sgt. Justin Gaertner lost both his legs in a roadside bomb explosion while serving in the Helmand province of Afghanistan on November 26, 2010. No longer able to serve his country in the U.S. military, Justin now has a new mission: Bringing to justice child sexual predators.
He took a risk and signed up for a year-long pilot program run by the Department of Homeland Security , called HERO Corps, where he and other wounded or ill warriors are being trained in the computer forensics needed to track and trap criminals involved in child exploitation.
In an interview with ABC News, Gaertner acknowledged it was a major adjustment, but said words cant really describe, how good it feels to put these guys behind bars. Its never ending ... [the] despicable things that people are doing to children."
EXCLUSIVE: Undercover DHS Tests Find Security Failures at US Airports
Last Friday, the Secretary of Homeland Security Jeh Johnson personally swore in the third class of 22 HERO Corps graduates.
In 2013, Gaernter graduated in the first HERO Corps class, also known as the Human Exploitation Rescue Operations Corps. The unit was created by the Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), a division of DHS with a long history of combating cross-border child exploitation and related cyber-crimes. The program was successful enough that it received permanent funding when the HERO Act was signed into law earlier this year.
Courtesy DHS and Justin Gaertner
PHOTO: The Homeland Security Investigations team executes a search warrant with local and federal law enforcement.
The demand for jobs like Gaertner's with Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) is astounding. Last year, ICE seized more than 5.2 million gigabytes of data related to child exploitation cases and arrested. That same year the HSI units arrested more than 2,300 child predators on criminal charges.
Justin accompanies special agents on search warrants, dissembling computers, running forensic software and scouring hard drives for illicit data that can be later used in court. He has participated first-hand in the arrest of hundreds of child predators. The raids he conducts are often done early in the morning to ensure the target it at home when it happens.
ABC News photo
PHOTO: Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, Jeh Johnson, stands with 22 graduates of the HERO Corps program at U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement headquarters in Washington D.C.
Earlier this year, Gaertner helped put away Benjamin Cuadrado for 80 years. The 40 year-old Florida man plead guilty to producing 70 sexually explicit videos of himself having sex with children who were ages two and younger.
In 2014, he helped in the conviction of Melvin Bridgers in a child sextortion case. Bridgers was found guilty of extorting 130 young girls over Facebook, using fake profiles to lure them into sending explicit photos of themselves and extorting them with those images for more sexually explicit material, threatening to share the images with their parents.
Courtesy DHS and Justin Gaertner
PHOTO: Sgt. Justin Gaertner with best friend Sgt. Gabriel Martinez, both of whom lost their legs fighting in Afghanistan.
These men and women have a natural desire to contribute, Johnson said at the recent graduation ceremony.
You want to rebuild, you want to get back into the fight. That strength and character is what we see reflected in the 22 graduates we have here today," he said.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31942508.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:59:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Huge Saw Blade Slices Truck but Not Driver  </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/huge-blade-slices-truck-driver/story?id=31970994</Link>
        <Description>A man in China is counting his lucky stars after a huge saw blade came crashing onto a highway and right into his car, and he survived. </Description>
        <MainBody>Huge Saw Blade Slices Truck but Not Driver
Jun 24, 2015, 9:01 AM ET
By CORINNE CATHCART via Good Morning America
A view of the accident site after a massive circular saw blade smashed into the front of a pickup truck on the Chongqing-Guizhou Expressway in Chongqing, China, June 17, 2015.
Imaginechina / Splash News
A man in China is counting his lucky stars after a huge saw blade came crashing onto a highway and right into his car, and he survived.
The man, identified only as Mr. Xiang, was driving on Chongqing-Guizhou Expressway in Central China when the blade of a giant circular saw blade fell of the back of a truck carrying equipment in a nearby lane, according to The Telegraph .
The blade flew into Mr. Xiang's car but he reportedly walked away unhurt. It lodged in the front of his truck as Xiang tried to keep control of the vehicle, according to the Telegraph.
"I heard a 'bang' and then I saw all the white smoke in front of me. I almost lost control of my car, Xiang told local reporters the day after the incident.
Police reportedly said that if Xiang had been driving faster or if the blade had hit at a slightly different angle, he could have been killed.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 31970994.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen Kill at Least 7 in Tunisia Beach Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-gunmen-kill-tunisia-beach-attack-32046356</Link>
        <Description>THE LATEST: British tourist describes deadly Tunisia attack: 'we thought it was firecrackers'</Description>
        <MainBody>Gunmen Kill at Least 7 in Tunisia Beach Attack
TUNIS, Tunisia  Jun 26, 2015, 8:28 AM ET
By The Associated Press
The latest news from an attack on a beach resort in Tunisia (all times local):

Tunisian state television says the number of people killed in an attack on a tourist resort is now 19 after two gunmen opened fire on beachgoers.
There have been no details on the nationalities of those killed in the resourt of Sousse on Friday, but during the holy month of Ramadan , those on the beach tend to be tourists.
Interior Ministry spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said security forces intervened immediately and killed one of the attackers, the other fled the scene.

1:20 p.m.
A British tourist close to the scene of a deadly attack on a Tunisian beach resort has described his experiences.
Gary Pine said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he told Sky News. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
He said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms, and later to gather in the lobby.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach in the coastal resort of Sousse Friday, killing at least seven people.

1 p.m.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least seven people.
Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
Aroui said the death toll could rise.
Tunisia has been battered by attacks by militants, most recently in March when two Tunisians returning from Libya killed 22 people at the national museum.

-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046356.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:38:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At Least 15 Britons Killed at Tunisia Beach Resort</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/15-britons-killed-attack-tunisia-beach-resort/story?id=32073185</Link>
        <Description>British death toll "may well rise."</Description>
        <MainBody>At Least 15 Britons Killed in Attack at Tunisia Beach Resort
Jun 27, 2015, 12:38 PM ET
By EMILY SHAPIRO via World News
A young woman lays flowers at the scene of a shooting in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Darko Vojinovic/AP Photo
Copy
At least 15 British people were among those killed when a gunman opened fire on a beach in Tunisia , Britain's foreign minister said Saturday.
Tobias Ellwood said the beachfront massacre was "the most significant terrorist attack on the British people" since suicide bombers struck the London transport network in 2005, killing 52 and wounding hundreds. The gunman killed 39 people Friday at the Hotel Imperial Marhaba in Sousse, a popular resort town on the northeast coast of Africa.
Ellwood added the number of British people killed Friday "may well rise."
The gunman hid his rifle under an umbrella before he opened fire, security official Rafik Chelli told Tunisia radio station Mosaique FM. He then entered the hotel through the pool and began firing.
The gunman was killed by police after the attack, the country's interior ministry told the Associated Press.
ISIS claimed responsibility for the attack in a statement circulated on social media.
Sousse is one of Tunisia's most popular vacation spots and draws visitors from across Europe - particularly France . The nationalities of the victims were still being determined, officials said Friday, but a security official told Mosaique FM that many of those killed were foreigners.
The hotel had 565 guests at the time of the attack, mostly from the United Kingdom and central Europe, RIU Hotels &amp; Resorts said in a statement on its website.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32073185.
Join the Discussion
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:17:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malala Calls on Leaders to Invest in Books, Not Bullets</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/malala-yousafzai-calls-world-leaders-invest-books-bullets/story?id=32262472</Link>
        <Description>Education activist Malala Yousafzai is calling on world leaders to invest in books, not bullets.</Description>
        <MainBody>Malala Yousafzai Calls on World Leaders to Invest in Books, Not Bullets
Jul 7, 2015, 12:16 AM ET
Malala Yousafzai poses with a bouquet after speaking during a media conference at the Library of Birmingham, in Birmingham, England, Oct. 10, 2014, after she was named as winner of The Nobel Peace Prize.
Rui Vieira/AP Photo
Education activist Malala Yousafzai is calling on world leaders to invest in books, not bullets.
Speaking at the Oslo Education Summit in Oslo, Norway , the 17-year-old Nobel Laureate declared that every child deserves access to 12 years of free education. The poorest girls get just three years of schooling because of a lack of will and vision by our governments, Malala said ahead of her Tuesday speech. This is unacceptable.
In a paper published by the Malala Fund called Beyond Basics, Malala calls on low- and middle-income countries to commit a minimum of 20 percent of their national budgets to education, compared to the current average of 15 percent. A new report published by the UNESCO and Education for All shows that the number of out of school children and young adolescents between the ages of 6 and 15 years is on the rise  up to 124 million in 2013, compared to 122 million in 2011.
Editor's Picks
Brutal Attacks on Schoolgirls on the Rise, UN Says
Leaders of the 21st century must deliver on their promises to invest in the future and start investing in books, education and hope, rather than in weapons, war and conflicts, Malala said. We will not stop. We will continue to speak out and raise our voices until we see every child in school.
During the World Education Forum in May, 100 countries committed to providing free primary and secondary education to all children by 2030. According to the UNESCO report, the cost of providing 12 years of free education to every child is an estimated $340 billion per year through 2030  or $39 billion more than current commitments. But Malala says that shortfall is a pittance compared to global military spending .
The shocking truth is that world leaders have the money to fully fund global education - but they are choosing to spend it on other things, like their military budgets, Malala wrote in a post on the Malala Fund blog . In fact, if the whole world stopped spending money on the military for just 8 days, we could have the $39 billion needed to provide 12 years of free, quality education to every child on the planet.
When not speaking to world leaders and advocating for education, Malala is making plans for her 18th birthday on July 12. Instead of presents, she is asking supporters to send a message to world leaders: "Post a photo of yourself holding up your favorite book and share why you choose #BooksNotBullets," she wrote. "Tell world leaders to fund the real weapon for change, education!"
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:12:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS Fighter Makes July 4 Threat, Reportedly Killed That Day</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/turnabout-isis-fighter-makes-july-threat-reportedly-killed/story?id=32259819</Link>
        <Description>ISIS-associated Twitter accounts mourn reported "martyrdom" of Brit extremist.</Description>
        <MainBody>London Attack: Man Hacked to Death in Suspected 'Terrorist Incident'
Aziz was prolific in ISISs social media outreach, allegedly luring recruits and inspiring attacks on the West online from a number of Twitter accounts.
America likes hitting people, said a Twitter account attributed to Aziz recently, but doesnt like getting hit back Oh well, every action has a reaction.
Lorenzo Vidino, Director of the Program on Extremism at the George Washington University Center for Cyber and Homeland Security, said that if Azizs death is confirmed, it would be a victory for the anti-ISIS coalition .
Obviously he is a person, definitely of interest to authorities because of the influence that he has online and the fact that he has been in contact with people in the West ready to carry out attacks, Vidino said. He was one of the key people inciting attacks in the West, calling people in the West through social media to carry out attacks.
Late today President Obama announced the U.S. is taking off the gloves when it comes to hitting ISIS targets in Syria.
Were going after ISIL [ISIS] leadership and infrastructure in Syria, the heart of [ISIS] that pumps funds and propaganda to people around the world, he said.
The President cited the attack on a Mohammed cartoon contest in Texas in May as the sort of threat the U.S. now faces. The men behind that attack were inspired by Aziz, among others.
The Telegraph reported Aziz traveled to Syria after he was convicted of stabbing a soccer fan in the eye in London. Vidino said that before he left, Aziz was a known member of the radical scene in the U.K.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:27:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian Bombers Intercepted on Independence Day</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/russian-bombers-fly-us-july-4th/story?id=32256983</Link>
        <Description>As Americans were celebrating the July 4th holiday, four Russian long-range bomb</Description>
        <MainBody>Russian Bombers Fly Near U.S. on July 4th
Jul 6, 2015, 3:16 PM ET
Tupolev Tu-95 Bear, a large, four-engine turboprop-powered strategic bomber in Voronezh region, Russia, September 20, 2014.
Oleg Kharseev/Kommersant via Getty Images
As Americans were celebrating the Fourth of July holiday, four Russian long-range bomber aircraft flew close enough to the US shores that they were intercepted by military fighter jets. The first set of two bombers flew near Alaska and just 30 minutes later a separate set flew far off the west coast of California.
According to officials at NORAD the flights stayed within international airspace and at no time did any of the Russian bombers enter or get close to entering sovereign North American boundaries.
Close Encounter Between Russian Fighter Jet and US Spy Plane
The first incident occurred at approximately 10:30 a.m. EDT on July 4, when Alaskan-based NORAD F-22 fighters intercepted and visually identified two Russian TU-95 "Bear" long-range bomber aircraft flying off the coast of the Aleutian Islands within the Air Defense Identification Zone (an area of international waters that stretches 200 miles from US coastline), officials at NORAD said in a statement to ABC News.
Then at approximately 11 a.m. EDT, NORAD F-15 fighters from the Continental NORAD Region intercepted and visually identified two additional Bear bombers flying off the central California coast, well away from U.S. sovereign airspace.
While Northcom is not saying precisely how far out the California intercept occurred, one official said it was on the outer lines of the ADIZ, meaning it could have been as far out as 200 miles. US airspace begins 12 miles from the coasts. The US asks military aircraft from other countries operating in that space to identify themselves and will make sure they've changed course away from US shores before backing away.
While intercepts of Russian aircraft off Alaska occur frequently, intercepts off California are less common. In June last year a two long-range Russian bombers flew within 50 miles of northern California.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:42:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  The Dalai Lama Turns 80 Today</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/dalai-lama-years-32256360</Link>
        <Description>The Dalai Lama Through the Years, Across the Globe</Description>
        <MainBody>The Dalai Lama Through the Years
+

The Dalai Lama greets well wishers after addressing a crowd gathered at the Stone Circles at Worthy Farm in Somerset during the Glastonbury Festival in Britain, June 28, 2015.
Dylan Martinez/Reuters
The Dalai Lama greets well wishers after addressing a crowd gathered at the Stone Circles at Worthy Farm in Somerset during the Glastonbury Festival in Britain, June 28, 2015.
Dylan Martinez/Reuters
The Dalai Lama waves, as Britain's Prince Charles watches, after planting a tree in the garden of Clarence House in London, May 22, 2008.
Alessia Pierdomenico/Reuters
His Holiness, the 14th Dalai Lama, addresses the audience after receiving an honorary degree at the University of British Columbia, April 19, 2004, in Vancouver, British Columbia. Nobel Peace Prize Laureates, His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama, Archbishop Desmond Tutu and Professor Shirin Ebadi received honorary Doctor of Law degrees from Allan McEachern, Chancellor of the University of British Columbia in a special ceremony.
Don MacKinnon/Getty Images
Tibetan spiritual leader Dalai Lama greets the audience during the inauguration of the 'Festival of Tibet,' March 12, 2000, in Bombay, India. The seven-day festival was held at two venues with several cultural programs.
Sebastian D'Souza/AFP/Getty Images
His Holiness the Dalai Lama poses with actor Richard Gere, right, Aug. 12, 1999, at the end of a press conference to discuss his visit to New York. The Dalai Lama has four days of teachings in New York culminating in a public talk in Central Park.
Henny Ray Abrams/AFP/Getty Images
Ethel Kennedy and the Dalai Lama, spiritual and temporal leader of Tibet, applaud during the Robert F. Kennedy Human Rights Award ceremonies at Georgetown University, Nov. 9, 1997, in Washington.
WIlliam Philpott/AFP/Getty Images
The Dalai Lama leads a prayer ceremony at a public park in New Delhi, July 4, 1995. The first day of a three-day celebration marking the 60th birthday of the Tibetan spiritual leader.
Raveen Dran/AFP/Getty Images
Mother Teresa of Calcutta, Nobel Peace Prize winner in 1979, right, meets with the Dalai Lama in Oxford, England, April 12, 1988. It was the first meeting between the two.
AP Photo
Dalai Lama, head of the Tibetan people, is pictured in 1969 at an unknown location.
AP Photo
The Dalai Lama, spiritual and temporal head of Tibet, and Indira Gandhi, daughter of India's Premier Jawaharlal Nehru, talk during a visit to Nehru's home in New Delhi, Sept. 4, 1959. It is the Dalai Lama's first visit to New Delhi since fleeing Tibet in March. He is living in exile at Birla House in Mussoorie, India.
AP Photo
The 14th Dalai Lama, Tenzin Gyatso, who lives in exile in India and leads the non-violent campaign of opposition to Chinese rule in Tibet, is seen in this April 14, 1959, file photo.
Keystone Features/Getty Images
His Holiness the Dalai Lama, head of state and spiritual leader of the people of Tibet, second from right, is shown with his family in Delhi, India, in 1956. From left to right are, Dalai Lama's mother; his elder sister; eldest brother Thubten J. Norbu; elder brother; Gyalo Thondup, brother; Dalai Lama; his younger sister; and his youngest brother.
AP Photo
The 17-year-old Dalai Lama of Tibet, whose country is being invaded by Chinese Communists, poses Nov. 2, 1950. The spiritual ruler sits above his crest, the thunderbolt insignias of his power and will be invested with full ruling power when he reaches 18 years of age.
AP Photo
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:36:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman Saved After Sleepwalking Into Sea</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/woman-rescued-hotel-employee-sleepwalking-sea/story?id=32250614</Link>
        <Description>Lee Searle heard the woman's cries for help around 1:30 a.m.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman Rescued by Hotel Employee After Sleepwalking into the Sea
Jul 6, 2015, 11:34 AM ET
By KAYLEE HECK via Good Morning America
Marie Lord who 'sleep-walked' half a mile and ended up walking out to sea is pictured in this undated image.
SWNS.com
A womans sleepwalking turned life-threatening when she walked straight into the sea in the middle of the night.
Marie Lord, 39, has a hotel porter to thank for saving her life after she sleepwalked into the sea in front of the Anchor Head Hotel in Somerset, U.K.
Lee Searle was three hours into his night shift two weeks ago at the seafront hotel when he heard Lord from the sand, he told ABC News today.
Passengers Rescued From Sailboat After Spending Up to 1 Week Stranded Off Florida Coast
"I heard someone cry for help and I went back outside and that's when I found her. My first thought was that this lady needs help and fast," he said.
Searle said Lord was soaking wet and he quickly brought her back to the hotel and wrapped her in blankets.
Lord left her home around 1:30 a.m. and walked a half mile to the beach, maneuvering the streets and even down steep concrete steps, according to Searle.
Im only 4 feet 10 and I have really short legs, so I dont usually go down [the stairs] without my husband or some kind of aid, she told the Telegraph.
The 39-year-old made it over all the obstacles and was woken up once she reached the water and quickly became disoriented, Searle said.
Its absolutely mind-blowing to think about what could have happened, she told the Telegraph. All I remember is seeing a flashing star and it all seemed like a dream.
Lord was transported to Weston General Hospital.
It turns out that she had the onsets of hypothermia. If she was not found, she could have died," Searle said. "It was unreal how quick it all happened."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:01:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Makes Latin America Visit About 'Most Vulnerable'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/pope-francis-makes-latin-america-visit-fragile-vulnerable/story?id=32239773</Link>
        <Description>It is Francis' first Latin America visit since he assumed the papacy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis Makes Latin America Visit About 'Most Fragile ... Most Vulnerable'
QUITO, Ecuador  Jul 5, 2015, 7:57 PM ET
Pope Francis waves to the crowd as he rides aboard the Popemobile in the streets of Quito, Ecuador, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Francis is making his first visit as pope to his Spanish-speaking neighborhood.
Dolores Ochoa/AP Photo
At the start of a weeklong visit to his native continent, Pope Francis arrived to a red carpet reception at Quito's main airport, where Ecuador's socialist president Rafael Correa greeted him on the tarmac.
But as the pope's motorcade proceeded into the city, many along the sidelines voiced their disapproval of Correa, giving him thumbs down.
For this first Latin American pope, the trip is almost a homecoming. He is not visiting his home country Argentina on this trip. Instead he will travel the Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay.
This is his first visit to Spanish speaking countries here. All three countries he is visiting are overwhelmingly Catholic and among the poorest on the continent.
Pope Brings 'Church for the Poor' to South America's Poorest
At Quito airport, Pope Francis said he feels "particular concern for our brothers and sisters who are most fragile and minorities who are most vulnerable."
The large open air masses he is scheduled to hold during his visit are expected to draw millions of people. The pope also plans to take time to visit a Bolivian prison and a slum in Paraguay, making the effort to connect with those at the margins of society.
Pope Francis took time to meet each of the 75 journalists traveling with him on the papal plane, accepting presents from some reporters and blessing rosaries and other items they brought with them.
One Bolivian reporter gave Francis locally made chocolates with his face on them. The pope beamed as he agreed to take a selfie with her.
But the trip will be physically grueling for the 78-year-old leader of the Catholic faith. He is scheduled to make nine stops in seven days, making this his longest busiest foreign trip yet.
One stop, in Bolivian capital La Paz, is at an altitude of 4,000 meters, equivalent to some of the tallest mountains in the United States.
As a young man, Pope Francis lost part of one lung due to an illness, and church officials acknowledged some concern about altitude sickness.
According to Vatican officials, the pope has expressed an interest in trying a local remedy popular among indigenous people in the Andes mountains: coca leaves.
Local residents chew them or drink them in tea to alleviate the shortness of breath and queeziness that can result from spending even a few short hours at altitude.
But coca leaves are illegal in much of the developed world, banned as a controlled substance because they are the raw ingredient of cocaine.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:19:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch Drifting Baby Rescued Out at Sea </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/drifting-baby-reportedly-rescued-sea-turkey/story?id=32220531</Link>
        <Description>A baby girl was reportedly rescued by the Turkish coast guard after she drifted out to sea.</Description>
        <MainBody>Drifting Baby Reportedly Rescued Out at Sea in Turkey
Jul 4, 2015, 10:48 AM ET
By EMILY SHAPIRO
Ten-month-old baby Melda Ilgin is seen as she drifts a kilometer out to sea on a sea buoy in Ayvacik district of Canakkale province, Turkey, July 3, 2015.
Hanife Erdinc/Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
A baby girl was reportedly rescued by the Turkish coast guard after she drifted out to sea.
The 10-month-old was in an inflatable crib when she floated about half a mile, the BBC reported .
Hanife Erdinc/Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
PHOTO: Ten-month-old baby Melda Ilgin is seen on her mother's lap after being saved by Turkish coast guard when she drifted a kilometer out to sea on a sea buoy in Ayvacik district of Canakkale province, Turkey, July 3, 2015.
The incident happened off the coast of Ayvacik, which is on the western tip of Turkey .
The girl's parents didn't realize she was gone until other beachgoers told them, the BBC reported, attributing the details to a state-run news agency.
See the dramatic rescue here, in a NotiVirales video the BBC obtained from Reuters:
The BBC did not report the girl's condition.
Hanife Erdinc/Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
PHOTO: Turkish coast guard rescue ten-month-old baby Melda Ilgin as she drifts a kilometer out to sea on a sea buoy in Ayvacik district of Canakkale province, Turkey, July 3, 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 22:18:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The 'Reel' Deal: 9-Year-Old Catches 600-Pound Fish</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/year-boy-reels-600-pound-sturgeon-video-prove/story?id=32205376</Link>
        <Description>It took nearly two hours for Kegan Rothman to reel in the sturgeon with help from his father and a fishing guide.</Description>
        <MainBody>Conservation Workers Discover 13-Foot Oarfish Washed Up on Beach
It is the most excitement Ive ever had with a fish. It was so hard to hold onto the rod. I thought the fish was going to pull me into the water, Kegan told Great River Fishing Adventures.
On his first day out on the water on vacation, Kegans rod dipped into the water and he didnt back down from the ensuing fight.
He, his father and Great River Fishing Adventures guide Ben Trainer spent the next hour and 45 minutes reeling in their catch in a nearly impossible feat," said Matthew Clive, a spokesman for Great River Fishing Adventures.
Great River Fishing Adventures
PHOTO: Kegan Rothman caught a 600-pound sturgeon in Chilliwack, British Columbia, on June 29, 2015.
Ive been a professional fishing guide on the Fraser [River] for 11 years and have fished these rivers my whole life. This is one of my largest fish I have help[ed] a client catch, Trainer told Great River Fishing Adventures.
With the size of this fish, Id bet its over 75 years old, he added.
Kegan, only 4-feet tall and from New Jersey, got the 10-foot long fish near shore, where Trainer examined it and estimated its weight to be 600 pounds.
The sturgeon was then released back into the river.
Before Mondays new personal record, Kegan said he had caught a 120-pound sailfish on vacation in Mexico .
Great River Fishing Adventures has caught and released four monster-sized sturgeons in the past five years, company officials said, noting the largest weighed in at 1,100 pounds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 01:25:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officials: Facebook, Twitter Not Reporting ISIS Messages</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/officials-facebook-twitter-reporting-isis-messages/story?id=32164079</Link>
        <Description>Civil liberties group: Bill would turn social media cos. into "secret police."</Description>
        <MainBody>A Facebook Inc. logo is displayed for a photograph in Tiskilwa, Ill., Jan. 29, 2013.
Daniel Acker/Bloomberg via Getty Images
Share
Copy
Facebook, Twitter and other social media sites would be required to report suspected terror messages to law enforcement authorities under a bill approved by the Senate Intelligence Committee, something U.S. and British law enforcement officials told ABC News they do not routinely do now.
The bill, which is headed for consideration before the whole Senate, is being applauded by U.S. counter- terrorism officials but opposed by civil liberties groups.
While Facebook says it works aggressively to ensure that we do not have terrorists or terror groups using the site, it and other social media sites are not currently required to report suspect messages to law enforcement, as they are in cases involving child pornography.
What they do now is simply terminate the account of the person who is plotting the attack, said Richard Clarke , a former White House counterterrorism official and ABC News consultant. It is very unlikely today that a social media company would turn around and call the police.
London Attack: Man Hacked to Death in Suspected 'Terrorist Incident'
U.S. officials say ISIS and other terror groups regularly use social media sites to communicate with followers and urge them to attack.
ISIS is using social media for their battlefield communications, said former British counter-terror official Michael Clarke, Director General of the Royal United Services Institute.
In the era of social media, a phenomenon like ISIL [ISIS], unlike Al Qaeda of the old days, there doesn't have to be and won't necessarily be a command-and-control relationship between somebody who instigates an incident and ISIL as an organization," U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter told reporters today. "They are self-radicalized, self-organized people on social media. Are we concerned about that? Absolutely, we're concerned about it."
Under the proposed Senate legislation (language below), social media sites would have a duty to report any information it learns about terrorist activity.
The issue first emerged two years ago in the wake of the brutal beheading of a British soldier, Lee Rigby, on the streets of London.
Authorities say they later learned that the attackers had communicated about their intentions on a social media site reported to be Facebook.
Lets kill a soldier, was one of the messages, according to a British investigation.
Officials say their accounts were closed but authorities were not notified before the attack.
If they are saying things, like, I want to go out and behead a soldier, then that ought to alert the system, said Hazel Blears a former leading member of the Intelligence and Security Committee of Parliament who was part of an investigation into the failure of social media to disclose what it knew.
There is certainly, in my view, a moral responsibility, Blears told ABC News.
Facebook did not respond directly to criticism from authorities, but in Rigbys case said that the company was horrified by what happened. A spokesperson said, Facebooks policies are clear  we do not allow terrorists content on the site and take steps to prevent people from using our service for these purposes. The spokesperson also pointed to a statement on their Community Standards page, which says, "We work with law enforcement when we believe there is a genuine risk of physical harm or direct threats to public safety."
A U.S. Senate aide said the proposed Senate bill only requires social media sites to report information they are made aware of and does not require the specific monitoring of any particular user. Facebook previously said that it relies on its users to report misuse of its service.
Still, some civil liberties groups say the legislation creates a dangerous precedent.
In this American democracy, we dont want our social media providers to be acting as essentially secret police, said Nate Cardozo, a Staff Attorney at the Electronic Frontier Foundation. There is a first amendment right to talk about terrorism Discussing controversial political, religious, social events of our time is absolutely protected speech. And requiring social media providers to rat out their customers for engaging in their first amendment right to debate important topics is not something that is constitutional.
Cardozo disagreed that in the Rigby case, law enforcement should have seen the Facebook messages because they didnt represent a true threat.
A spokesperson for Twitter did not respond to requests for comment on this report.
Below is the updated language in the Intelligence Authorization Act related to social networks, as approved by the Senate Intelligence Committee and obtained by ABC News:
SEC. 603. REQUIREMENT TO REPORT TERRORIST ACTIVITIES AND THE UNLAWFUL DISTRIBUTION OF INFORMATION RELATING TO EXPLOSIVES.
(a) DUTY TO REPORT.Whoever, while engaged in providing an electronic communication service or a remote computing service to the public through a facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce, obtains actual knowledge of any terrorist activity, including the facts or circumstances described in subsection (c) shall, as soon as reasonably possible, provide to the appropriate authorities the facts or circumstances of the alleged terrorist activities.
(b) ATTORNEY GENERAL DETERMINATION.The Attorney General shall determine the appropriate authorities under subsection (a).
(c) FACTS OR CIRCUMSTANCES.The facts or circumstances described in this subsection, include any facts or circumstances from which there is an apparent violation of section 842(p) of title 18, United States Code, that involves distribution of information relating to explosives, destructive devices, and weapons of mass destruction.
(d) PROTECTION OF PRIVACY.Nothing in this section may be construed to require an electronic communication service provider or a remote computing service provider (1) to monitor any user, subscriber, or customer of that provider; or (2) to monitor the content of any communication of any person described in paragraph (1).
This report was updated July 2, 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:37:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mali Extremist Traded for French Hostage Killed in Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/mali-extremist-traded-french-hostage-killed-attack-32258396</Link>
        <Description>Military operation kills Islamic extremist who had been exchanged for French hostage</Description>
        <MainBody>Mali Extremist Traded for French Hostage Killed in Attack
BAMAKO, Mali  Jul 6, 2015, 3:37 PM ET
A Malian special forces spokesman says an Islamic extremist who was released last year in exchange for the freedom of a French hostage in Mali has been killed.
Modibo Nama Traore said Monday that French special forces killed Mohamed Ali Ag Wadossene in an early Sunday morning operation in the Tigharghar mountains in north Mali's Kidal region. A dozen others were arrested, he said.
An official with the French special forces, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not permitted to speak to the press, confirmed the operation.
Ag Wadossene was among the al-Qaida in the Islamic Maghreb members who kidnapped Philippe Verdon and Serge Lazarevic in northern Mali in 2011. Ag Wadossene was captured, and then released in December 2014 for the freedom of French hostage Lazarevic.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:49:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank Refuses to Increase Credit for Greece</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/greece-awaits-european-central-bank-decision-liquidity-32080639</Link>
        <Description>ECB refuses to increase credit lifeline for Greek banks after referendum call by PM Tsipras</Description>
        <MainBody>European Central Bank Refuses to Increase Credit for Greece
ATHENS, Greece  Jun 28, 2015, 9:48 AM ET
By ELENA BECATOROS and DAVID McHUGH Associated Press
The European Central Bank refused to increase emergency credit to Greek banks on Sunday, a day after the government threw Greece's bailout negotiations into turmoil by calling a referendum on creditors' financial proposals.
The central bank's decision  seen treading a narrow middle ground that could keep the bailout talks going  left Greece's banks under increasing pressure since they are seeing deposits drain away.
Anxious Greeks lining up at ATMs all weekend, worried about the possibility of financial controls being imposed to stop banks from hemorrhaging funds. Those fears are driven by the fact Greece's international bailout runs out Tuesday and it needs the last tranche of those funds to pay some $1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to the International Monetary Fund on the same day.
The developments have thrown Greece's financial future and its continued membership in the 19-nation shared euro currency into question.
The ECB said it could reconsider its decision on credit levels.
"We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of member states in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies," ECB chief Mario Draghi said.
Yannis Stournaras, governor of the Bank of Greece, said the bank would "take all measures necessary to ensure financial stability for Greek citizens in these difficult circumstances."
The Greek finance ministry said the country's financial stability council, the Systemic Risk Board, would meet Sunday afternoon to discuss the situation. The board is a seven-member body that includes the finance minister, the central bank governor and the heads of the Greek banks association, the capital markets commission and the financial stability fund.
Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis meanwhile, tweeted that the government "opposes the very concept" of capital controls within a monetary union. He also suggested that his country might not pay the money it owes to the IMF on Tuesday.
Varoufakis refused to reply to a direct question Sunday on the IMF payment. Instead, he told BBC radio that the ECB should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014, an idea he called "a very sensible transfer."
"We are owed money by one part of the troika and we owe money to another part of the troika? Why don't they sort themselves out and transfer money from one pocket ... to the other?" Varoufakis said.
Greek Prime Minister Alexia Tsipras' move for a national vote next Sunday on the creditors' financial proposals startled and angered Greece's European partners, who said they would not accept an extension of the current bailout, which expires Tuesday. Parliament approved the referendum call in a majority vote early Sunday.
France's prime minister, meanwhile, urged all in Europe to do everything they could to keep Greece in the eurozone.
"We don't know  none of us  the consequences of an exit from the euro zone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the euro zone," French Prime Minister Manuel Valls told France's i-Tele TV.
"But doing everything, that means respecting Greece and democracy, but it's also about respecting European rules. So Greece needs to come back to the negotiating table."

McHugh reported from Frankfurt. Geir Moulson in Berlin, Jamey Keaten in Paris and Demetris Nellas in Athens contributed.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080639.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Correction: Palestinians-Rainbow Flag Story</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/correction-palestinians-rainbow-flag-story-32258071</Link>
        <Description>Correction: Palestinians-Rainbow Flag story</Description>
        <MainBody>Correction: Palestinians-Rainbow Flag Story
RAMALLAH, West Bank  Jul 6, 2015, 3:25 PM ET
In a story June 30 about Palestinian protesters whitewashing a gay pride rainbow flag, The Associated Press reported erroneously that homosexual acts are banned by law in the West Bank and Gaza Strip. While homosexuality is largely taboo in Palestinian society, there are no laws specifically banning homosexual acts.
A corrected version of the story is below:
Angry protesters whitewash rainbow flag on West Bank barrier
Angry protesters whitewash Palestinian artist's painting of rainbow flag on West Bank barrier
By MOHAMMED DARAGHMEH
Associated Press
RAMALLAH, West Bank (AP)  Palestinian protesters whitewashed a rainbow flag of gay rights that was painted by a Palestinian artist on six slabs of the West Bank separation barrier.
The artist, Khaled Jarrar, said Tuesday his art was meant as a reminder that Palestinians live under Israeli occupation, at a time when gay rights are in the news after the U.S. allowed same-sex weddings.
But protesters perceived the painting as support for homosexuality, a taboo subject in Palestinian society, where gays are not tolerated.
The artwork ignited angry responses among Palestinians, and activists whitewashed the flag on Monday night, just a few hours after it was painted on the best known section of Israel's graffiti-covered barrier, next to a portrait of Yasser Arafat and other Palestinian leaders.
Jarrar, 39, who has exhibited in Europe and the United States, told The Associated Press that the destruction "reflects the absence of tolerance, and freedoms in the Palestinian society."
"People don't accept different thinking in our society," he said, adding he drew the rainbow flag on the barrier to put a spotlight on Palestinian issues.
Mohammed, who only gave his first name for fear of repercussions, said he helped whitewash the flag because "we cannot promote gay rights."
Mohammed al-Amleh, a 46-year-old lawyer, also approved of the action, saying that "it would be shameful to have the flag of gays in our refugee camp."
Gay Palestinians tend to be secretive about their social lives and some have crossed into Israel to live safely.
There are no laws on the books in either the West Bank or the Gaza Strip that specifically ban homosexual acts.
Israel, meanwhile, has emerged as one of the world's most gay-friendly travel destinations recently, in sharp contrast to most of the rest of the Middle East , where gay culture is not tolerated and gays are persecuted and even killed. Earlier this month, over 100,000 people attended a gay pride parade in Tel Aviv.
In Israel, gays serve openly in Israel's military and parliament, and many popular artists and entertainers are gay.
Gays cannot marry in Israel, primarily because there is no civil marriage of any kind  all Jewish weddings must be conducted through the Jewish rabbinate, which considers homosexuality a sin and a violation of Jewish law. But the state recognizes same-sex couples who marry abroad.
Across most of the rest of the Middle East, however, gay and lesbian relationships are taboo. The pervasiveness of religion in everyday life, along with strict cultural norms, plays a major factor in that.
Same-sex relations are punishable by death in Iran, Mauritania, Saudi Arabia , Sudan and Yemen.

Associated Press writer Ian Deitch contributed to this report from Jerusalem.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:16:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Day of Extremist Violence Across Nigeria Kills More Than 60</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bombs-mosque-restaurant-central-nigerian-city-kill-15-32242854</Link>
        <Description>Extremist attacks on mosques, church, restaurant across Nigeria leave more than 60 people dead</Description>
        <MainBody>Day of Extremist Violence Across Nigeria Kills More Than 60
JOS, Nigeria  Jul 6, 2015, 3:15 PM ET
By AHMED MOHAMMED and MICHELLE FAUL Associated Press
People gather at the site of suicide bomb attack at Redeem Christian church in Potiskum, Nigeria, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Witnesses say a woman suicide bomber blew up in the midst of a crowded evangelical Christian church service on Sunday and killed... View Full Caption AP
People gather at the site of suicide bomb attack at Redeem Christian church in Potiskum, Nigeria, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Witnesses say a woman suicide bomber blew up in the midst of a crowded evangelical Christian church service on Sunday and killed at least five people, the latest in a string of bombings and shooting attacks blamed on the Islamic extremist group Boko Haram that has killed some 200 people in the past week. (AP Photo/Adamu Adamu) Close AP
A day of extremist violence against both Muslims and Christians in Nigeria killed more than 60 people, including worshippers in a mosque who came to hear a cleric known for preaching peaceful coexistence of all faiths.
Militants from Boko Haram were blamed for the bombings Sunday night at a crowded mosque and a posh Muslim restaurant in the central city of Jos; a suicide bombing earlier at an evangelical Christian church in the northeastern city of Potiskum, and attacks in several northeastern villages where dozens of churches and about 300 homes were torched.
President Muhammadu Buhari condemned the attacks and said the government will defend Nigerians' right to worship freely.
It was the latest spasm of violence by Boko Haram extremists who have killed about 300 people in the past week  apparently after an order by the self-proclaimed Islamic State group for more mayhem during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. Earlier this year, Boko Haram became an affiliate of the Islamic State group.
The deadliest attack came on Wednesday when more than 140 people were killed  mostly men and boys mowed down by gunfire as they prayed in mosques in the northeastern town of Kukawa.
Burials were held Monday for 51 people killed by the two bombings a day earlier in Jos, said Muslim community lawyer Ahmed Garba.
Another 67 people were wounded, according to Abdussalam Mohammed, the National Emergency Management Agency coordinator.
The explosion at the Yantaya Mosque came as cleric Sani Yahaya was addressing the worshippers, survivors said. Yahaya is the national chairman of the Jama'atu Izalatul Bidia organization, which preaches that all religions should peacefully coexist.
Garba said gunmen also opened fire on the mosque from three directions.
Survivor Danladi Sani said he saw a man dressed in white take aim at Yahaya, and then blow himself up. Yahaya was unharmed, Sani added.
"He is a great Islamic scholar who has spoken out against Boko Haram, and that is why we believe he was the target," Sani told The Associated Press.
Another bomb exploded at Shagalinku, a restaurant often patronized by state governors and other top politicians for its specialties popular with Muslims, witnesses said.
Sabi'u Bako was picking up a takeout meal when he heard a massive explosion as he walked away with friends.
"The restaurant was destroyed, and we saw many people covered in blood," he said. "We can't believe that we escaped."
Jos is a hotspot for violent religious confrontations because it is located in the center of the country where Nigeria's majority Muslim north meets the mainly Christian south. The city has been targeted by bombs claimed by Boko Haram extremists that have killed hundreds.
Earlier Sunday, a female suicide bomber struck a crowded service of the Redeemed Christian Church of God in Potiskum, killing six people, witnesses said.
Elsewhere in the northeast, extremists killed nine people and burned down 32 churches and about 300 homes in several villages, said Stephen Apagu, chairman of a self-defense group in Borno state's Askira-Uba local government area. He said the militia killed three militants.
The villages had been attacked three days earlier and 29 people killed.
The United States condemned the recent attacks and said it continues to provide counterterrorism assistance to Nigeria to "combat the threat posed by Boko Haram," said a statement Monday from State Department spokesman John Kirby.
Boko Haram took over a large swath of northeastern Nigeria last year. A multinational force from Nigeria and its neighbors forced the militants out of many towns, but bombings and village attacks have increased in recent weeks.
Meanwhile, Nigeria's military freed 180 detainees who had been held for up to two years, accused of being Boko Haram members. Those freed Monday included women with babies and toddlers.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:18:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Refugee Response Exposes Divisions, Meagre Ambitions</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/eu-leaders-agree-relocate-40000-migrants-32042300</Link>
        <Description>EU refugee deal exposes divisions, meagre ambitions, limits to solidarity with Greece, Italy</Description>
        <MainBody>EU Refugee Response Exposes Divisions, Meagre Ambitions
BRUSSELS  Jun 26, 2015, 8:16 AM ET
By LORNE COOK Associated Press
The European Union decided Friday to share 40,000 of the refugees landing in Italy and Greece but foot-dragging and verbal sniping over the move exposed deep divisions about how to deal with Europe's massive migrant influx.
While the size of the challenge is daunting, the EU's response has been underwhelming. More than 114,000 migrants fleeing wars or poverty have been plucked from the Mediterranean so far this year as they try to cross in unseaworthy smugglers' boats. Some 2,600 have died or are missing along the route, according to the International Organization for Migration.
"It is  to tell the disturbing truth  a very modest effort," European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker said Friday after EU leaders agreed at a summit to decide by late July on how to distribute the refugees.
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi agreed.
"It's not a big number," he said. "For Italy it's a small help, but there's still a lot of work to do."
Greece and Italy have been swamped by the arrivals, while Hungary and Bulgaria are also under pressure from thousands of migrants traveling over land. Things are likely to get worse amid the summer high season for migrant crossings.
Radical action is being taken around Europe in response. Hungary has pledged to build a fence to keep out the torrent of migrants crossing its border with Serbia. France and Italy have been at loggerheads over the movement of migrants along their common border. Police have dismantled migrant camps in northern France, from where people are hoping to cross into Britain.
Greece and Italy have been accused of not properly screening arrivals and allowing them to move deeper into the 28-nation EU.
In an effort to ease some of their burden, Juncker's team has tried to force northern EU countries to share the burden, but any notion of mandatory migrant quotas for each nation was rejected at the summit.
Belgian Prime Minister Charles Michel called Friday's decision "saddening and disappointing."
"There is a lack of ambition, a lack of will," he said. "It wasn't a sense of solidarity that dominated around that table."
With some 60 million refugees in the world, this effort from a wealthy, half-a-billion-strong bloc appears paltry when countries like Lebanon, Jordan and Turkey are hosting hundreds of thousands of people displaced by conflict.
Even the decision to share 40,000 Syrians and Eritreans arriving over the next two years  and a separate move to resettle 20,000 refugees from outside Europe  only came after an emotional appeal from Italy.
"If you don't agree with 40,000 refugees you don't deserve to be called Europe," Renzi was quoted as saying to the leaders as the debate dragged into the night.
"If this is your idea of Europe, you can keep it. Either there is solidarity or don't waste our time," he said, according to an EU diplomat, who asked not to be identified because the discussions were not public.
The emergency plan was launched in response to the deaths of hundreds of migrants in the Mediterranean earlier this year. At a hastily organized summit, ships, planes and other equipment were pledged to help rescue those trying to come. But as the media spotlight faded, so has the EU's commitment to its partners.
Ultimately, around a dozen EU nations oppose the obligatory quota plan. A further 12 that would support it want the method for sharing out the refugees reassessed.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:41:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Minister: 3 Irish Among Dead in Tunisia Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-tunisia-puts-1000-extra-police-tourist-sites-32080204</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Minister: Authorities confirm Irish couple among 38 dead in Tunisia beach attack</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Minister: 3 Irish Among Dead in Tunisia Attack
TUNIS, Tunisia  Jun 28, 2015, 9:40 AM ET
A young woman lays flowers at the scene of a shooting in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The morning after a lone gunman killed at tens of people at a beach resort in Tunisia, busloads of tourists are heading to the nearby Enfidha-Hammamet airport hoping to return to their home countries. (AP Photo/Darko Vojinovic)
The Associated Press
The latest developments on the attack that killed 38 tourists on a beach in Tunisia :

2:30 p.m.
Ireland's foreign affairs minister says an Irish couple missing since Friday's gun attack at a Tunisian beach resort is among the dead.
Charlie Flanagan didn't confirm the pair's names, but they were identified locally as Laurence and Martina Hayes, both reportedly in their 50s.
Sunday's announcement brings the number of Irish victims to three.
An Irish mother-of-two, Lorna Carty, was earlier confirmed as a victim of Friday's attack on the Sousse beach resort in Tunisia.
A total of 38 tourists were killed when a student armed with a Kalashnikov and grenades opened fire at the resort in Sousse.

1:50 p.m.
Britain's home secretary says the number of Britons confirmed killed in the Tunisia beach resort attack is expected to rise.
Theresa May told reporters that the confirmed figure remained at 15, but "we should expect that that number is going to rise."
The Britons were among the 38 people killed at the Sousse resort Friday, and authorities are still working to determine the identities of all the dead.
Tunisian authorities have said victims were from Britain, Germany, Ireland, Belgium and Portugal, and no Tunisians were killed.

1:40 p.m.
The owner of a Tunisian resort hotel insists there was no security breakdown during an attack by a gunman with alleged ties to the extremist Islamic State group who killed at least 38 tourists in Soussa, because "unfortunately the hotel security (guards) are not armed.
Zohra Idriss of Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba says it has five or six guards on the sandy beach.
"How can they defend themselves against someone who has a Kalashnikov and who is killing them?" Idriss said. "They tried to beat him with chairs, with the vases of flowers but it was impossible. It was all very, very quick."

12:05 p.m.
A major German tour operator says around 250 of its customers have chosen to return early from their vacations in Tunisia after the attack on tourists but most people visiting the country  around 3,500  are staying on.
After Friday's attack on a beach in Sousse, tour operator TUI offered free cancelations or re-bookings for customers who had reserved vacations in Tunisia through Sept. 15. It said it had received about 500 calls by Sunday from people taking up that offer, and that Spain's Canary Islands, Turkey and Egypt topped the list of alternative destinations that their customers chose.
One German has been confirmed dead and another injured in the attack Friday on a beach resort. Thirty-eight people were killed in Tunisia's worst terrorist attack.

10:10 a.m.
Britain's Foreign Office has updated its travel advice to Tunisia, urging vigilance and warning that further terrorist attacks in the North African nation's tourist resorts are possible.
The ministry is warning Sunday against all travel to Tunisia's militarized southern zone, all travel anywhere within 5 kilometers (3 miles) of Tunisia's border with Libya and all travel to the country's Chaambi Mountain national park area.
It also advised against all but essential travel to much of Tunisia's south and along its western border with Algeria .
The ministry says possible attacks could stem from "individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:16:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS Claims Blast at Shiite Mosque in Kuwait's Capital</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bomb-strikes-shiite-mosque-kuwait-32044671</Link>
        <Description>IS claims blast Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers</Description>
        <MainBody>IS Claims Blast at Shiite Mosque in Kuwait's Capital
KUWAIT CITY  Jun 26, 2015, 8:23 AM ET
By HUSSAIN AL-QATARI Associated Press
The Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claims the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt.
The attack was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group calling itself the Najd Province, the same group that claimed responsibility for a pair of attacks on two Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32044671.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:45:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Young Soccer Player, Blogger Among Those Killed in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/young-soccer-player-blogger-killed-tunisia-32082082</Link>
        <Description>British families, friends mourn loss of loved ones in Tunisia beach attack</Description>
        <MainBody>Young Soccer Player, Blogger Among Those Killed in Tunisia
LONDON  Jun 28, 2015, 9:28 AM ET
By SYLVIA HUI Associated Press
Three men from the same British family, a recently engaged lifestyle blogger and a couple whose children launched a desperate social media campaign to find them were among those feared killed in the Tunisian beach attack.
Britain's government says at least 15 Britons were among the 38 killed when a university student opened fire Friday at the Sousse beach resort. Officials haven't officially confirmed the names of the victims, but families and friends have released details of those killed to British media. Other families were still fearing the worst Sunday.
Tunisian authorities have said other victims include people from Germany, Ireland, Belgium and Portugal .
Here is a look at some of those believed killed:

Joel Richards, a 19-year-old student and active soccer player, was reportedly killed along with his uncle, Adrian Evans, as well as his grandfather, 78-year-old Charles Evans. All three were keen soccer fans who were holidaying together at the beach.
"A young, talented referee with the world at his feet. He was highly thought of and will be sadly missed," Ian Murphy of the Birmingham County Football Association said of Richards. "He was such a talented lad," he added to Sky News.
Another Birmingham-based club, James Connolly's GFC, said Richards was an "exceptionally talented footballer" who represented his club and county on numerous occasions.
Joel's 16-year-old brother, Owen, who was also at the beach, reportedly fled the scene, surviving a bullet wound to his shoulder.
A local council paid tribute to Adrian Evans, 49, described as a popular and long-serving employee who managed gas services.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

Faul reported from Lagos, Nigeria. Associated Press writer Haruna Umar in Maiduguri, Nigeria, contributed to this report.

<<<<<<< HEAD
This version has been corrected to show that only the mosque bombing in Jos was a suicide attack.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:54:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands Evacuate as Wildfires Burn in West Canada</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/thousands-evacuate-wildfires-burn-west-canada-32256815</Link>
        <Description>Thousands forced to evacuate as more than 200 wildfires burn across west Canada province</Description>
        <MainBody>Thousands Evacuate as Wildfires Burn in West Canada
VANCOUVER, British Columbia  Jul 6, 2015, 2:53 PM ET
More than 200 forest fires are burning across western Canada , causing a heavy gray haze to settle over the Pacific coast and forcing the evacuation of thousands of residents.
Authorities issued air quality advisories across British Columbia on Monday as an unrelenting heat wave that began in early June sent temperatures soaring to record highs. More than 20 fires were sparked on Sunday alone, according to officials.
People with medical conditions, as well as the elderly and the very young were urged to remain indoors and limit strenuous activity.
A 61-year-old logger died Sunday while helping forestry crews battle a wildfire near Sechelt, north of Vancouver.
Local authorities have imposed a province-wide ban on open burning.
=======
Like others, 23-year-old Conor Fulford turned to social media for help when he became increasingly worried about his missing mother Sue Davey, 44.
Fulford, who thought he may have seen his mother on television as she was being taken away on a stretcher, repeatedly tweeted pleas for information.
So did Ross Nayler, whose father, 42-year-old Scott Chaulkley, was on holiday in Tunisia together with Davey.
"I'm checking Twitter and all the other social media just for anything really, just for any update," Nayler told ITV News.
But by Saturday night, both sons learned the truth. Fulford wrote: "Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight." He added: "Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight. Rest easy."
Severn Trent Water, where Davey and Chaulkley worked, paid tribute to the pair Sunday. "Sue and Scott had a passion to help others however they could, they cared enormously for all those they worked with and were totally committed to our customers and our company," the company said in a statement.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32082082.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:16:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thailand Junta Cancels Human Rights Report Launch on Vietnam</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/thailand-cancels-rights-groups-report-launch-vietnam-32041944</Link>
        <Description>Thai junta forces rights group to cancel public launch of report on Vietnam's ethnic minority</Description>
        <MainBody>Thailand Junta Cancels Human Rights Report Launch on Vietnam
BANGKOK  Jun 26, 2015, 8:15 AM ET
By THANYARAT DOKSONE Associated Press
Thailand's military government on Friday forced a human rights group to cancel the public launch of its report on the Vietnamese government's persecution of an ethnic minority, saying it could affect national security and bilateral relations.
The report by the New York-based Human Rights Watch describes persecution of Montagnard Christians in Vietnam's Central Highlands, whose religious practices have been described by the government as "evil."
Thai police said in a statement Friday the scheduled event at the Foreign Correspondents Club of Thailand could "have an impact on the country's security or could affect the friendship and cooperation between Thailand and Vietnam."
It is the third event in one month that has been canceled at the venue. Two previous seminars involved topics about human rights situation in Thailand and the country's harsh law protecting its monarchy.
More than a dozen plainclothes and uniformed police officers were waiting outside the club, along with a police truck parked nearby. The club said it received a written order from police, issued on behalf of the ruling junta, to cancel the news conference where the report was to be launched.
The human rights report was available on the group's website. An electronic version was also sent to journalists by email.
The cancellation of the event is "very disappointing" and is "another affirmation that human rights organizations can no longer report, not only about situation in Thailand, but situations in neighboring countries in Southeast Asia," said Sunai Phasuk, Human Rights Watch's senior researcher in Asia.
"Thailand is now going to be known as the defender of human rights violators in (Southeast Asia), which added more damage to Thailand's already tarnished international reputation under the military rule," he added.
Thai authorities have cracked down on critics and dissents since the military seized power from a civilian government in last May's coup.
The Thailand section on Human Rights Watch's website was briefly blocked by the government.
In its report, Human Rights Watch called for the Vietnamese government to "end abusive policies and practices" that have forced hundreds of Montagnards to flee the country.
It said the Montagnards' beliefs and faith practices, such as De Ga Protestantism and Ha Mon Catholicism, are suppressed by the government on the grounds that they are not religions at all. It said the Montagnards have been subjected to intimidation, arbitrary arrests and mistreatment in custody.
There was no immediate response from the Vietnamese government on the report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32041944.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:50:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Flags From Many Nations Seen During Pope Visit</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-thousands-await-pope-ecuadorean-port-city-32247967</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Flags from many countries seen at Mass celebrated by pope in Guayaquil, Ecuador</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Flags From Many Nations Seen During Pope Visit
QUITO, Ecuador  Jul 6, 2015, 2:50 PM ET
By The Associated Press
Here are the latest developments from Pope Francis' trip to South America:

1:30 p.m.
Flags of more than half a dozen countries can be seen waving in the air at a Mass that Pope Francis is celebrating in Guayaquil, a humid port city that is Ecuador's largest.
The variety of flags include: Ecuador, Mexico, Peru , the United States, Argentina , Colombia, Brazil, Chile and Puerto Rico.
"I didn't want to miss the opportunity to see Francis," said Norma Peralta, from neighboring Peru. "It took me about 10 hours driving to get here. It's cheaper than going to the Vatican."
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:12:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Russian PM Yevgeny Primakov Dies at 85</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/russian-pm-yevgeny-primakov-dies-85-32043554</Link>
        <Description>Yevgeny Primakov, former Russian premier, foreign minister dies at 85</Description>
        <MainBody>Former Russian PM Yevgeny Primakov Dies at 85
MOSCOW  Jun 26, 2015, 8:11 AM ET
By JIM HEINTZ Associated Press
Former Russian Prime Minister Yevgeny Primakov, whose career included desperate but unsuccessful diplomatic efforts to avert wars in Iraq and NATO's bombing of Yugoslavia, has died. He was 85.
President Vladimir Putin on Friday offered condolences to Primakov's family, Putin's spokesman Dmitry Peskov said. He added that the president saw Primakov as "a statesman, an academic and a politician who has left a very big heritage" and that he always wanted to hear Primakov's view on global issues.
The cause of death wasn't immediately known.
With his slow, rumbling speaking manner, hooded eyes and a face whose default expression was a sly smile, Primakov, a seasoned political scholar and Middle East expert, looked like the embodiment of an insider operative for a country full of opaque intrigues.
Primakov began his career on a classic Soviet path. Trained as an Orientalist, he worked as a journalist for a decade-and-a-half in the Middle East for Soviet radio and the Communist Party newspaper Pravda, positions widely seen to be covers for espionage work.
He later moved through an assortment of senior academic positions and joined the political scene in 1989, when he became chairman of one of the chambers of the Soviet parliament, helping spearhead Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev's political reforms.
As the international drumbeat for war against Iraq increased in 1990, Gorbachev sent Primakov as an envoy to Iraq, drawing on his deep knowledge of the Middle East. He was said by some to be the outsider whom Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein knew best and trusted the most.
Gorbachev in a statement praised Primakov for "defending the country's interests with both resolve and flexibility."
In 1991, Primakov was named head of Russia's foreign intelligence service and held the job for five years before becoming foreign minister. As Russia's top diplomat, he was regarded as a firm but pragmatic supporter of Russian interests as the country agonized over its loss of superpower status. He worked hard to dilute the United States' perceived unilateral dominance of world affairs.
After being appointed prime minister in 1998 following Russia's bruising financial crisis, Primakov tried to prevent the NATO air war against Yugoslavia over the Kosovo crisis. He was heading to the United States on official visit in March 1999 when he learned that Washington decided to launch the air raids, and ordered his pilots to turn the plane back while it was already halfway over the Atlantic, a bold move that helped bolster his popularity at home.
Primakov lost the premier's job in May 1999 while the NATO bombing campaign was still going on. By many accounts, President Boris Yeltsin feared Primakov's rising influence and popularity.
Primakov was widely seen as a top contender to succeed Yeltsin, but sensationalist criticism of him and his alleged poor health on television controlled by supporters of Putin deflated his aspirations. By the time Putin became acting president when Yeltsin stepped down in the closing hours of 1999, Primakov's chances of election had vanished.
Putin nonetheless continued to tap Primakov's expertise in tackling global crises. He made Primakov Russia's top envoy to Iraq to try to stave off the brewing war in 2003. Primakov also was among those who tried to mediate with Chechen terrorists who seized a Moscow theater and hundreds of hostages in 2002.
Primakov also continued to wield considerable influence as the chairman of the Chamber of Industry and Commerce, a Russian business advocacy group, a post he held from 2001 to 2011.
Primakov is survived by his wife, his daughter and grandchildren. Funeral arrangements were not immediately known.

Vladimir Isachenkov contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32043554.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:17:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Greek Minister Hints No Payment Tuesday to IMF</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-greece-ecb-giving-emergency-32080338</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Minister suggests Greece may not pay $1.6 billion euros it owes Tuesday to IMF</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Greek Minister Hints No Payment Tuesday to IMF
ATHENS, Greece  Jun 28, 2015, 9:16 AM ET
The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations (all times local):
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

1:05 p.m.
Pope Francis is focusing his homily on the family while celebrating Mass at a large park in Ecuador's coastal city of Guayaquil.
Francis gave the example of a mother and her children, saying she loves all of them equally.
"The family is also a small church, a domestic church," said Francis. "With life, it channels tenderness and divine mercy."
Hundreds of thousands listened to the pope at Semanes Park while standing in the hot sun and using handkerchiefs to wipe sweat from their brows.

12:06 p.m.
Hundreds of thousands of faithful cheered Pope Francis as he arrived at the Semanes Park in Guayaquil. The pope planned to celebrate Mass at the park in the Ecuadorean coastal city, the country's largest with 2.35 million residents.
Riding in the popemobile, Francis waved to the crowds. People waved handkerchiefs and Vatican flags.
The port city is known for its heat and humidity, at noon was already 86 degree Fahrenheit (30 degrees Celsius).

11:05 a.m.
Pope Francis has arrived at the Divine Mercy shrine in the Ecuadorean coastal city of Guayaquil. Upon arrival to the shrine, the outstretched hand of a young child nearly poked Francis in the eye. The pope smiled as he continued walking.
Francis then spent a minute praying at the shrine beneath a large painting of Jesus. The pope told the crowd he would pray for them.
"And I won't charge you a thing," he joked. "All I ask is that you pray for me. Will you promise me that?"
After visiting the shrine, the pope plans to celebrate Mass at a park with more than 1 million people.

10:43 a.m.
A self-proclaimed "Mr. Nobody" soon will be sharing the spotlight with one of the world's most famous people.
It's been 30 years since the Rev. Francisco Cortes last spoke with Pope Francis, who at that time was the Rev. Jorge Mario Bergoglio.
Cortes, known as Padre Paquito, must have made quite an impression on Bergoglio, who in Argentina was in charge of the Jesuit order that the men share.
Cortes, who is 91 years old and a Spaniard by birth, was to spend five minutes with the pope on Monday. They will meet in a small room adorned by flowers and religious paintings after Francis celebrates an outdoor Mass in the Ecuadorean coastal city of Guayaquil.
"I don't know why he set the meeting. We haven't even corresponded," Cortes told The Associated Press in an interview. "I'm really just a Mr. Nobody."

10:03 a.m.
A handful of altar boys took selfie photos with Pope Francis upon his arrival in Guayaquil, a port city in Ecuador where the pope plans to celebrate Mass with up to 1 million people. The altar boys were waiting on the tarmac and approached the pontiff when he descended from his plane.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco </title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/walter-reed-medical-center-lockdown-president-obama-remarks-32260211</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis Draws Millions In Ecuador, U.S. Women Win The World Cup</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Breaking news authorities respond to a report of being single gunshot and a half of the country. The national military medical center everyone is and shelter. Plays Ellen come in or out facility they didn't find anything. That in mind computer aided and kind of weapon directly have to stand stand by for us. President Obama it out Bayer visit to the Pentagon with a briefing on the department's effort in combating eyes. Coalitions now hit sisal more than 5000 airstrikes take it out thousands of fighting positions. Us believe this bomb factories. It's like. Case under way palladium down there working in the years. Illegal immigrant now charged with murder how is convicted felon. Deported five times before the balance of retreat and Francisco this is a relationship problem we can talk all day long about a broken immigration system but law enforcement. Can work together informally to at least stop people like mr. saint Kitts. A sea of humanity celebrating mass but we'll break it into Ecuador today this. His first visit to the Spanish speaking country that is home positive he's visiting Ecuador Bolivia Perez. Last night in each round that Japan might just to midfielder partly Lloyd was the star scoring three goals in the first. Sixteen minutes featured at. Everything we believed and we excuse game plan and we got it done. He loved puppy you will love this sixteen adorable puppies from three different letters in one basket the best shot a little boy. Sleeping with all of them kind of like canine constantly.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: Sen. Tom Cotton: Military Action Against Iran Must Remain an Option
Now Playing: Baby Charlotte Elizabeth Diana Ready for Royal Christening
Now Playing: Greek Citizens Left Penniless by Economic Crisis
Now Playing: Texas Woman Goes Missing During Caribbean Snorkeling Trip
Now Playing: Beatles' Ringo Starr Gets His Personal Story Told in 'Ringo - With a Little Help'
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: 'Britain's Schindler,' Who Saved Over 650 Jewish Children During Holocaust, Dies
Now Playing: Pilots Fired After Video Captures Model in Cockpit
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32260211,"title":"Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco ","duration":"1:57","description":"Pope Francis Draws Millions In Ecuador, U.S. Women Win The World Cup","url":"/International/video/walter-reed-medical-center-lockdown-president-obama-remarks-32260211","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:39:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/million-celebrate-mass-pope-francis-ecuador-32255553</Link>
        <Description>This is the first big event of the pope's 3-nation tour of South America. Pontiff will preach the importance of protecting the needy and the environment.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
I'm doing these. A sea of humanity celebrating mass with Pope Francis in Ecuador today the pocket visiting the port city. Of quiet keel on the first leg of his ninety pilgrimage to Latin America this is his second trip to his home continent since becoming hunted. In 2013. Hello everyone analyst at her in New York Pope Francis. Is bringing a message of hope and compassion at ABC's David Wright isn't going keel and filed this report. I Elizabeth from wire act healing Ecuador where we'll France's that is that is celebrated an open air mass. Eagles. Eyewitness. It's either now or ligaments in his Latin America stands to help Francis is of course the first post has. Collected from the new world and business. His first visit to the Spanish speaking countries at his home continent he's visiting Ecuador Bolivia and Paraguay. This open air mass movements of the first big event details what Reagan tradition and normally the pope's visit us. President of the country with his visiting birthday itineraries but today he elected to come here and celebrates. With these folks and afterwards he's going to have. A private lunch with an old friend a brief yet seen since 1985. Jesuits and he knew him when he was the leader graduates and arts. Tina. Brings with surprise that blueprint is remembered him he's here and return. Firemen. Now at age 91 I believe. I. How much greater excitement. People are welcoming home native son he's not from Ecuador many. And flexes and that these people here are delighted Elizabeth. When beginning ABC's David Wright thank you for that in my head back live to the math in quiet keel. Williams. Yeah those who that he was soon. I mean did he has of heat on them and I hook people unless he Lewis and it is. It's here knows him knows these foods obesity. Yes. Yeah. These Louis king of yes we shouldn't and is okay. Well. An innocent. You know New Year's best. To stand out from beneath the vehicle. He it and when you have he has. He heals photos he as he. And you've been watching Pope Francis celebrating mass and quiet keel Ecuador an estimated one million people are there many spent the night outdoors. Others walked for miles just to attend that service now this is the pope's. Source trip to Ecuador will also travel to Bolivia and Paraguay talking about the importance of protecting that he be. And the environment. Of course you can keep up with this story in real time by downloading the ABC news dampened starring this story or exclusive update on the go. I'm Elizabeth her in New York. Low sodium this commodity so bailout Prodi. It is still on the ground some.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
The pope offered to host a peace summit at the Vatican.
Now Playing: Pope Francis Heads to Jerusalem
Now Playing: Historic Deal Reached in Iran Nuke Talks; Unprecedented Drought in California; Pope Told to Lay Off Pasta
Now Playing: More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
Now Playing: North Carolina's Shark Threat: 7th Victim Attacked
Now Playing: Toxic Train Accident Forces 5,000 Residents Out of Maryville, TN
Now Playing: Obama Embraces Campaign Mode in Overtime Push
Now Playing: Shooting Scare at Washington, D.C. Navy Yard
Now Playing: New Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: US and Cuba to Normalize Diplomatic Relations
Now Playing: 100+ Killed in Military Cargo Plane Crash in Indonesia
Now Playing: Gene Palmer, Guard Charged in NY Prison Escape, Appears in Court
Now Playing: NBC to Donald Trump: 'You're Fired!'
Now Playing: Manhunt Continues for Surviving Escapee
Now Playing: Manhunt Continues for David Sweat, Public Reacts to SCOTUS Decision
Now Playing: Supreme Court Ends Same-Sex Marriage Ban
Now Playing: Reaction to Supreme Court Ruling on Obamacare
Now Playing: Hillary Clinton on Racism in America
Now Playing: President Obama Uses the N-word in Race Discussion
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: Charleston Shooting: One-on-One With the Florist Whose 911 Call Led to Dylann Roof's Arrest
Now Playing: Dylann Roof's Emotional Bond Hearing; Shooting Victims' Families Share Powerful Statements
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32255553,"title":"More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador","duration":"7:35","description":"This is the first big event of the pope's 3-nation tour of South America. Pontiff will preach the importance of protecting the needy and the environment.","url":"/International/video/million-celebrate-mass-pope-francis-ecuador-32255553","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 22:53:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/world-awaits-results-greek-debt-referendum-32236051</Link>
        <Description>ABC News' Devin Dwyer reports the latest news on the vote in Greece and the afternoon's other top stories.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Good afternoon I'm Devin Dwyer ABC news headquarters in New York with a digital report this Sunday afternoon we begin in Greece where the polls have now closed in that crucial. Nationwide vote on whether to accept EU bailout package the country they are divided on terms of that plan many early polls predicting that a no vote is winning. That Greece is actually rejecting Europe's bailout package of course millions of Greeks waiting for the first official results. To come in later today and back your home firefighters are extra alert in parched California this holiday weekend residents there have been warned about fireworks. But someone in Sacramento didn't get the message and sparked a huge house fire. ABC's campus Gibson is there with the story in Los Angeles. It's. Shocking dimple of the dangers posed by fireworks that's your health yes. When Mike. A Sacramento neighborhood engulf in flames after fourth of July festivities got out of hand setting a tree on fire the flames spreading to two nearby home. When did you guys noted they definitely know. I. Looked tense. Holiday weekend across several western states fire crews feared the combination of epic drought conditions and explosive fireworks could spell trouble. We are in an extreme drought. Water restrictions so the vegetation is even drier than it has been in past years because he can't water as much as he have in the past. As overnight those conditions leading to a 320 acre wildfire in a Bay Area suburb more than a hundred residents urged to leave their home. Bakersfield California a special task force in forcing a 15100 dollar fine to make sure an incident like this grass fires started by an illegal M eighty fireworks. Doesn't happen in the city again anybody caught with illegal fireworks will receive already wildfires are burning in eight western states more than a dozen of them considered large fires. This 1 in eastern Washington State's sparked. By fireworks. The way it raced past us. Was it was have two incredible. Can this Gibson ABC news. This is a California and our thanks to Kenneth Gibson for that now the frightening holiday nightmare at that beach house in North Carolina medical choppers responding to the scene Saturday night. Right after a deck full of people suddenly collapsed emergency crews say 23 people were injured. At least three of them in critical condition today building inspectors are on the scene now. Trying to pinpoint exactly why that deck buckled as a family there was taking a group picture. And finally this afternoon soccer fans gearing up for the ultimate rematch in the women's World Cup final in Vancouver tonight. That's team USA vs Japan back in 2011 of course team USA lost the championship to Japan and a heartbreaker. Coming up short in that penalty kick shoot out work today. They're going in with good momentum and have that opportunity to win the first women's World Cup title since 1999. While ABC news is monitoring these developments around the clock to get updates on these stories star them on the ABC news phone apps. Tom yum that's will have a complete wrap up later tonight right here world news for now I'm given Byron York have a great day.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: Sen. Tom Cotton: Military Action Against Iran Must Remain an Option
Now Playing: Baby Charlotte Elizabeth Diana Ready for Royal Christening
Now Playing: Greek Citizens Left Penniless by Economic Crisis
Now Playing: Texas Woman Goes Missing During Caribbean Snorkeling Trip
Now Playing: Beatles' Ringo Starr Gets His Personal Story Told in 'Ringo - With a Little Help'
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: 'Britain's Schindler,' Who Saved Over 650 Jewish Children During Holocaust, Dies
Now Playing: Pilots Fired After Video Captures Model in Cockpit
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32236051,"title":"The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum","duration":"3:15","description":"ABC News' Devin Dwyer reports the latest news on the vote in Greece and the afternoon's other top stories.","url":"/International/video/world-awaits-results-greek-debt-referendum-32236051","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 16:17:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/queen-elizabeth-joins-moment-of-silence-for-tunisia-terror-attack-victims-32202817</Link>
        <Description>The Queen and the Duke of Edinburgh were visiting Glasgow when they paused to honor the victims of last week's attack.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Importantly. Four. Fully. Well you're wrong. You know do people. When. You most.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: Sen. Tom Cotton: Military Action Against Iran Must Remain an Option
Now Playing: Baby Charlotte Elizabeth Diana Ready for Royal Christening
Now Playing: Greek Citizens Left Penniless by Economic Crisis
Now Playing: Texas Woman Goes Missing During Caribbean Snorkeling Trip
Now Playing: Beatles' Ringo Starr Gets His Personal Story Told in 'Ringo - With a Little Help'
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: 'Britain's Schindler,' Who Saved Over 650 Jewish Children During Holocaust, Dies
Now Playing: Pilots Fired After Video Captures Model in Cockpit
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32202817,"title":"Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims","duration":"1:48","description":"The Queen and the Duke of Edinburgh were visiting Glasgow when they paused to honor the victims of last week's attack.","url":"/International/video/queen-elizabeth-joins-moment-of-silence-for-tunisia-terror-attack-victims-32202817","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jul 03 03:51:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/false-alarm-puts-washington-navy-yards-lockdown-freight-32196150</Link>
        <Description>No threat found after reports of active shooter at Washington Navy Yards; Freight train car carrying toxic chemicals catches fire forces thousands to evacuate; "Maria" retiring from Sesame Street after 44 years.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Dramatic scene today the Washington media are just actors. 30 AM on yeah police response after. It's been active shooter on the grounds thing GDR went on lockdown and police told to shelter in place officials found no threat. But 10 AM police vehicles were moving out of the area. We are grateful at this point that we had found no heat or evidence at shooting or beating the victim. We're making more workers eligible for overtime that you learn. As one the single most important we can take to help. As many as five million Americans including 80000 folks right here in Wisconsin in the overtime protections they deserved. Freight train carrying toxic chemicals. Catching fire in Maryville Tennessee forcing thousands from their homes one CSX. Car caught fire in the middle of the night on a trip to Georgia just one car involved but the chemical burning used to make plastics is toxic so in a two mile area firefighters are going door to door telling people to move away. A ferry overturned in the Philippines today nearly 200 people on board at least 36 people aren't yet to death others are missing. Officials say the Americans are on 100 plus survivors many were saved by local fisherman swam to safety. Can major airlines are beginning to turn over information to government investigators looking into whether they're colluding to keep air fares high by limiting the number of seats available. United delta. American and southwest. Control 80% of the US market but they deny working together insisting. They compete to keep seats fault. Maria one of the most recognizable characters on Sesame Street. Has announced that she will not be returning next season the actress who played her for 44. Years is retiring. Sonia months on I was also an award winning writer on the show. Why should watch. Harlem. Yeah. Yeah. Underneath his isn't funny about it really exciting. Wallace and rods fly. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
The Washington Navy Yard is "all clear" after being placed on lockdown this morning, officials said.
Now Playing: No Threats at Washington Navy Yard After Lockdown
Now Playing: Washington Navy Yard on Lockdown After Reports of Active Shooter
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: Sen. Tom Cotton: Military Action Against Iran Must Remain an Option
Now Playing: Baby Charlotte Elizabeth Diana Ready for Royal Christening
Now Playing: Greek Citizens Left Penniless by Economic Crisis
Now Playing: Texas Woman Goes Missing During Caribbean Snorkeling Trip
Now Playing: Beatles' Ringo Starr Gets His Personal Story Told in 'Ringo - With a Little Help'
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: 'Britain's Schindler,' Who Saved Over 650 Jewish Children During Holocaust, Dies
Now Playing: Pilots Fired After Video Captures Model in Cockpit
=======
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:17:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait Names Saudi Man as Suicide Bomber in Mosque Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/kuwait-saudi-citizen-deadly-suicide-bombing-32080439</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait names Saudi citizen as bomber in deadly Shiite mosque attack, says he flew in at dawn</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait Names Saudi Man as Suicide Bomber in Mosque Attack
KUWAIT CITY  Jun 28, 2015, 9:16 AM ET
By HUSSAIN AL-QATARI Associated Press
Kuwaiti authorities on Sunday identified the suicide bomber behind an attack on a Shiite mosque that killed 27 people as a Saudi citizen who flew into the Gulf nation just hours before blowing himself up.
Police have begun making arrests in connection with Friday's bombing, which took place at one of Kuwait's oldest Shiite mosques during midday prayers. An affiliate of the Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for the blast in the normally peaceful oil-rich nation.
The Interior Ministry named the bomber as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa and said he was born in 1992, making him 22 or 23 years old. It said in a statement carried by the official Kuwait News Agency that he arrived on a flight to Kuwait International Airport at dawn Friday.
Authorities also said they arrested a 25-year-old from Kuwait's "bidoon" community, identified as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, who they say drove the car that brought the bomber to the mosque.
The bidoon community is made up of descendants of desert nomads and others considered stateless by the government. They have long claimed the government deprives them of citizenship and rights.
A Kuwaiti man who housed the driver was also taken into custody. The Interior Ministry described him as a follower of a "fundamentalist and deviant ideology."
The government-linked Al-Jarida newspaper reported that at least seven suspects had been detained in connection with the attack, which has drawn condemnation from Sunni groups in Kuwait and leaders from across the Middle East .
Officials say 227 people were wounded in the attack.
A local affiliate of the Islamic State group calling itself the Najd Province has claimed responsibility for the bombing. The IS group considers Shiites to be heretics and is fighting Iranian-backed Shiite militias in Iraq and Syria .
More than a third of Kuwait's 1.2 million citizens are believed to be Shiite.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080439.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading, Explosion at Factory in France; Suspects Captured</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/beheaded-attack-explosion-french-gas-factory-32044065</Link>
        <Description>France: Several in custody after attack on French gas factory leaves 1 beheaded, 2 wounded</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading, Explosion at Factory in France; Suspects Captured
SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France  Jun 26, 2015, 8:07 AM ET
By LORI HINNANT and LAURENT CIPRIANI Associated Press
An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande , speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack. He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo , a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32044065.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:51:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moldovans Choose Between Russia, Europe in Local Elections</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/moldova-chooses-russia-europe-local-elections-32079459</Link>
        <Description>Moldovans hold local vote seen as a test whether country will move closer to Europe or Russia</Description>
        <MainBody>Moldovans Choose Between Russia, Europe in Local Elections
CHISINAU, Moldova  Jun 28, 2015, 8:49 AM ET
By CORNELIU RUSNAC Associated Press
Moldovans voted Sunday in local election runoffs being seen as a test of whether the former Soviet republic moves closer to the European Union or to neighboring Russia.
The key post is for the next mayor of Chisinau, the capital, where pro-European incumbent Dorin Chirtoaca faces pro-Russian challenger Zinaida Greceanai, a former prime minister of the Communist Party. A low turnout in the city of one million will benefit the 59-year-old Greceanai.
"I hope we will clarify things.... and build something that is certain, definitive, irreversible, for the future of Chisinau and Moldova ," Chirtoaca said after voting.
"Residents have a great desire to see deeds and not just statements," said Greceanai.
Runoffs were being held in 458 towns in this country of 4 million and result were expected late Sunday. Some 348 seats were already decided in the first round.
Renato Usatii, a pro-Russian businessman, won outright on June 14 in Moldova's second-largest city, Balti, and pro-Russian businessman Ilan Shor won in the eastern town of Orhei.
Moldova, which declared independence in 1991 after the Soviet Union broke up, is located between Romania and Ukraine. Last year, it signed an association agreement with the 28-nation EU, angering Russia, which then banned some of its fruits and vegetables, hurting the largely agricultural nation.
Moldova's currency has lost 20 percent of its value this year against the euro.
Moldova is one of the poorest nations in Europe with an average monthly salary of $250. Some 600,000 Moldovans work abroad and send remittances home, which make up 30 percent of the country's Gross Domestic Product.
Moldovan officials, meanwhile, have been investigating the disappearance of $1.5 billion from state-owned and private banks before the parliamentary election last November, and Shor is being investigated in that probe.

Alison Mutler in Bucharest, Romania contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32079459.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:04:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Journalist Jailed in Zimbabwe for Starting Newspaper</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/journalist-jailed-zimbabwe-starting-newspaper-32046319</Link>
        <Description>Zimbabwe jails journalist for starting newspaper without government permission</Description>
        <MainBody>Journalist Jailed in Zimbabwe for Starting Newspaper
HARARE, Zimbabwe  Jun 26, 2015, 8:03 AM ET
The attorney for a Zimbabwe journalist says his client was convicted of publishing a newspaper in a southern town without government permission and sentenced to eight months in prison.
Several newspapers and radio stations have already been closed under Zimbabwe's harsh media laws and dozens of journalists have been arrested over the past 15 years.
Defense lawyer Martin Mureri said his client Patrick Chitongo was only putting together a dummy version of the paper to apply for a license. They plan to appeal the conviction.
Although several privately owned newspapers are in circulation, the government is the largest media owner, running over a dozen national and community newspapers as well as enjoying television monopoly.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046319.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:37:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds Still in Hospital After Fire at Taiwan Music Party</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/hundreds-hospital-fire-taiwan-music-party-32080438</Link>
        <Description>Fire sparked by an accidental explosion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds Still in Hospital After Fire at Taiwan Music Party
TAIPEI, Taiwan  Jun 28, 2015, 8:37 AM ET
By RALPH JENNINGS Associated Press
Rescue workers tend to injured people at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City on June 27, 2015.
STR/AFP/Getty Images
More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.
The fire late Saturday was sparked by an accidental explosion of a colored theatrical powder thrown from the stage in front of about 1,000 people, the local fire agency and media said. The powder for the one-time event called "Color Play Asia" ignited along the ground, mainly burning people's lower bodies, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
The exact cause of the fire was still being investigated, but Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo banned public activities that use the colored powder.
A total of 519 people were injured by the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, according to a statement from the city government's health bureau. It said that 419 remained hospitalized on Sunday afternoon, about half of whom were seriously injured, including 184 in intensive care. Apart from Taiwanese, the victims were four people from Hong Kong , two from the Chinese mainland and one each from Macau, Japan, Malaysia and Singapore. The nationalities of three other foreigners were not given.
President Ma Ying-jeou visited burns victims at a hospital in Taipei on Sunday afternoon and said authorities would do their best to ensure victims receive "the best medical care" and find out who was responsible for the "tragic incident."
Taiwan's Central News Agency said that police were questioning two park workers who had launched the powder as well as the party's on-site organizer and two technicians. They may face charges of professional negligence causing serious injuries and endangering the public, it said.

AP writer Louise Watt in Beijing contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080438.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:01:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>With Nuke Talks in Final Stretch, Foreign Ministers Join In</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/nuke-talks-final-stretch-foreign-ministers-join-32046292</Link>
        <Description>With only days to June 30 target date for Iran nuclear deal, foreign ministers join in</Description>
        <MainBody>With Nuke Talks in Final Stretch, Foreign Ministers Join In
VIENNA  Jun 26, 2015, 8:00 AM ET
FILE - In this Saturday, Feb. 3, 2007 file photo, an Iranian technician works at the Uranium Conversion Facility just outside the city of Isfahan 255 miles (410 kilometers) south of the capital Tehran, Iran. State TV says the Guardian Council, Iran's... View Full Caption The Associated Press
FILE - In this Saturday, Feb. 3, 2007 file photo, an Iranian technician works at the Uranium Conversion Facility just outside the city of Isfahan 255 miles (410 kilometers) south of the capital Tehran, Iran. State TV says the Guardian Council, Iran's constitutional watchdog, ratified a bill Wednesday, June 24, 2015, banning access to military sites and scientists as Tehran and world powers approach a deadline for reaching a comprehensive nuclear deal. The bill would allow for international inspections of Iranian nuclear sites within the framework of the Nuclear Non-proliferation Treaty. (AP Photo/Vahid Salemi, File) Close The Associated Press
The foreign ministers of Iran , the United States and France are joining Iran nuclear talks, as they try to overcome disputes ahead of a June 30 target date for a deal.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius are expected to arrive in Vienna on Saturday. U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry is due to arrive just before midnight Friday according to their travel schedules.
Foreign ministers from Russia , China, Britain and Germany have not formally announced dates of arrival. But they are also expected to join over the next few days to try and bridge stubborn differences on the limits Tehran must accept on its nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046292.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:32:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank Maintains Emergency Credit to Greek Banks at Current Level</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/european-central-bank-maintains-emergency-credit-greek-banks-32081113</Link>
        <Description>European Central Bank maintains emergency credit to Greek banks at current level</Description>
        <MainBody>European Central Bank Maintains Emergency Credit to Greek Banks at Current Level
FRANKFURT, Germany  Jun 28, 2015, 8:31 AM ET
European Central Bank maintains emergency credit to Greek banks at current level.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32081113.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:59:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Interior Ministry: Gunmen Kill at Least 7 People in Attack on 2 Hotels on Tunisian Coast</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/interior-ministry-gunmen-kill-people-attack-hotels-tunisa-32046191</Link>
        <Description>Interior Ministry: Gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 hotels on Tunisian coast</Description>
        <MainBody>Interior Ministry: Gunmen Kill at Least 7 People in Attack on 2 Hotels on Tunisian Coast
TUNIS, Tunisia  Jun 26, 2015, 7:59 AM ET
Interior Ministry: Gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 hotels on Tunisian coast.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046191.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:06:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan Official: IS Group Present in at Least 3 Provinces</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/afghan-official-group-present-provinces-32080978</Link>
        <Description>Afghan official: Islamic State group now present in 3 provinces</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan Official: IS Group Present in at Least 3 Provinces
KABUL, Afghanistan  Jun 28, 2015, 8:06 AM ET
An Afghan official says the Islamic State group now has a presence in three provinces but that the government is determined to drive it out.
Zafar Hashimi, the Afghan president's deputy spokesman, said Sunday that the group  which controls large areas of Iraq and Syria  is active in the eastern Nangarhar, western Farah and southern Helmand provinces.
Hashimi says security forces have launched successful operations against the IS group but gave no further details.
The Taliban , which have been at war with the government for nearly 14 years and are also active in the three provinces, have warned the IS group to stay out of the country. Both groups want Islamic rule but the Taliban do not recognize the IS group's self-styled caliphate.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080978.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:47:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/scotus-rules-favor-aca-foods-overcharging-customers-french-32035096</Link>
        <Description>The Supreme Court rules in favor of Affordable Care Act; Whole Foods found to be overcharging customers by exaggerating weight; French Alpine paraglider lands inside a moving cable car.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Because of this law and because of today's decision to millions of Americans. Who I hear from every single day we'll continue to receive the tax credits. We have given about eight in ten people who buy insurance on the new marketplace Schwartz of the health care plan would cost less than a hundred dollars a month. Arraignment today renewed our prisons are now taking charges tied to Shawshank style break out a written update. Officials saying corrections officer Jean Pollard admitted to passing then my backpack. To date context. Even gave him special classes as areas of the president. Never knew there GI. Where officials are banning over and similar services in an around Paris. That comes after protesters from angry taxi driver and got ugly throwing eggs at cars he. And blocking off access to the airport many writers. Forced to walk to catch their flights. Taxi drivers upset because over drivers don't have to pay the same taxes. Are to compete with Hoover's prices up. Murphy store chain whole foods with stores in 42 state. Under scrutiny after New York consumer affairs says there investigators from around the worst case of grocery mislabeling. They've ever seen investigator citing he's examples of a package of chicken tenders overpriced by nearly five dollars. His vegetable platter six dollars more than it should be credible. Video a couple of guys jump off a mountain in France terror gliding toward that cable car right there one of them flies. Way forward. Right inside. His buddies catch in the ovals all back up but they grab and I can save you had some experience that if there are easier ways let's get to write it. I doubt they are a number of up to the screen door and watch the cat has she leaves airing out the big that they are so shocking that this package falls off the porch. Maginnis has your head is usually it's scary cat but she hasn't seen their sins. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Millionaire Funds Rescue Missions to Save Migrants: Part 1
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32035096,"title":"SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car","duration":"2:10","description":"The Supreme Court rules in favor of Affordable Care Act; Whole Foods found to be overcharging customers by exaggerating weight; French Alpine paraglider lands inside a moving cable car.","url":"/International/video/scotus-rules-favor-aca-foods-overcharging-customers-french-32035096","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mother-baby-survive-days-jungle-plane-crash-32031301</Link>
        <Description>Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Also there and get a mother at a baby rescued days after their small plane goes down and a jungle the air force swooping in to help the to the crash happening over the weekend in Colombia. And search crews springing into action the first survey first found the body of the product and yesterday the mother and child were spotted. The mother had just minor injuries the baby fortunately was not hurt.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:23:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus Carrying British Children Crashes in Belgium; 1 Dead</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bus-carrying-british-schoolchildren-crashes-belgium-32080641</Link>
        <Description>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; 1 adult killed, others injured</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus Carrying British Children Crashes in Belgium; 1 Dead
BRUSSELS  Jun 28, 2015, 8:05 AM ET
Fire and rescue vehicles line a highway as they attend to a bus which crashed on a motorway in Middlekerke, Belgium on Sunday, June 28, 2015. The bus, carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, injuring the driver and some of the children and killing one of the adults accompanying them.
Geert Vanden Wijngaert/AP PHOTO
A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, killing one adult chaperone and injuring the driver and some of the children, officials said.
Belgian highway authorities said the vehicle apparently went out of control, struck a bridge pillar on the E40 highway, then shot off the road. The bus was carrying around 40 passengers, including 34 British children from 11 to 13 years old, authorities said.
The Belgian federal prosecutor's office said all of the children survived the accident, but an adult passenger had been killed. The bus driver was also seriously injured.
Three adults and some of the children were sent to a local hospital for treatment. Others were transported to a center in the coastal city of Middelkerke.
British authorities said they were aware of the crash and working with Belgian authorities to help the U.K. citizens.
The E-40 highway, a major thoroughfare that links Belgium 's North Sea coast to the capital city of Brussels, was closed to traffic following the crash.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080641.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:58:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/day-terror-attacks-shock-world-32052524</Link>
        <Description>Attacks across three continents spurred concerns over spreading jihadist influence.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Okay. I I'm. And. We're.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32031301,"title":"Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash","duration":"0:21","description":"Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.","url":"/International/video/mother-baby-survive-days-jungle-plane-crash-32031301","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:27:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bomber-apologizes-court-funeral-proceedings-begin-sc-32007812</Link>
        <Description>Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev speaks in court during sentencing; Funeral proceedings begin for victims of South Carolina shootings; Governor Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Boston Marathon bomber killed Arthur Bryant spoke in court for the first time today it is we'll send. I think he stated he was sorry for the irreparable damage that he costs and all of the suffering. That he caused and he left no doubt about his guilt I didn't do it's our night instead hold. Bad. His words were genuine. They were heart cells. And I hope that they were as honest as the statements that you received were from victims' survivors. Reaffirmed. The United States government. Make concessions for just. Cost us. I from the celebrated pastor and state senator being honored as the remains of the reverend Clementi asking me lying in proposing Columbia. A horse drawn carriage carrying the coffin to the steps of the state house there a public viewing taking place throughout the afternoon. And on Friday president Obama's scheduled to deliver the eulogy the lakes states. Hundreds of camps are second homes throughout the area. Continue to check these camps and secure them. We're out of time law enforcement officials in upstate New York giving an update on their church or she would date killers. Describing the rugged terrain surrounding a hunting camp where those men are last believed to beats. Another Republican throwing his hat into the presidential ring today the big announcement from Louisiana governor Bobby Jindal. Making him the thirteenth major GOP yeah. I'm conservative governance shrinking the size of government. Smart management this is this is the details and it's been a guy who's worked in the Health and Human Services Department served in congress briefly and has an idea driven governor. Management leadership those are the qualities will talk about. Finally a lot of people love going to outdoor festival during the summer the one drawback. Port of bodies except of course if you report a body has looked at this point. I mariachi band inside. I they had. That's infineon and let's mariachi band marching out of the port of hiding and that they don't have a whole lot marching bands that part. The looks on people's faces apple. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32007812,"title":"Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid","duration":"2:17","description":"Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev speaks in court during sentencing; Funeral proceedings begin for victims of South Carolina shootings; Governor Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid.","url":"/International/video/boston-bomber-apologizes-court-funeral-proceedings-begin-sc-32007812","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:24:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy,  Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Tsarnaev: 'Sorry for the Lives I Have Taken'
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
=======
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32196150,"title":"False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street","duration":"2:31","description":"No threat found after reports of active shooter at Washington Navy Yards; Freight train car carrying toxic chemicals catches fire forces thousands to evacuate; \"Maria\" retiring from Sesame Street after 44 years.","url":"/International/video/false-alarm-puts-washington-navy-yards-lockdown-freight-32196150","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 01:04:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/pres-obama-announces-embassy-openings-cuba-dozens-killed-32166853</Link>
        <Description>President Obama announces embassy openings in Cuba; Dozens killed in suicide bomber attack in Sinai desert; Hillary Clinton releases thousands of emails.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Or years ago. The height of the Cold War the United States closed its embassy in Havana. Today I can announcing the United States has agreed to formally reestablishing. Diplomatic relations with the republic of Cubans. Had. Full confidence. You know law enforcement and they fled every bit of resources that that's there. And out of quest to find out the origins. Fire we will rebuild that is the message from Louisville official authority still trying to determine whether it was the result of arson. Work out like. Miles from the Gaza border ice is launching multiple attacks on military targets in that at least sixty soldiers killed by suicide bomber. This fighting is still ongoing and raging all day right in the northeastern part of the Sinai Peninsula against the border. Gaza and is. My overs match at Hillary Clinton emails released nearly. Thousand messages written by or tomb of the then secretary of state in 2009. Many of the emails are pretty routine is shedding some light on the inner workings of a large government department but one key revelation that the White House apparently didn't know that Clinton had a special nongovernment email accounts. Yeah. That is an actress model in the cockpit of a commuter jetliner as it taxis to the runway in Argentina who. Watched as the pilots ask her if she wants to help increase the speed she puts her hand on the throttle. As the pilots put on the power for take off the next day the pilots were fired from the Argentinean airline. The model banned for five years from that airline field. Listening to this nineties sitcom I pulled up to the house about seven Hillary and I yelled to the candy young homes and smell you later. Unsure where the Fresh Prince of Bel Air. Wow I. It's. Your bag proving he can wrap your local corporate rate why rendition of fame the freshly printed in Atlantic names on. We think that Will Smith would probably prove.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
World News Now pays homage to bubble wrap.
Now Playing: Bubble Wrap Appreciation Day
Now Playing: Steve Jobs Immortalized in Bubble Wrap Art
Now Playing: Law Enforcement on Heightened Alert Ahead of July 4th
Now Playing: Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: Iran Hostage Crisis Survivor Protests Obama Nuclear Deal
Now Playing: A Year of Sleepless Nights for Boy Who Survived Deadly Beach Attack
Now Playing: ISIS in Mosul 1 Year Later
Now Playing: Meet the 8 Young Musicians of NYC's Harmony Program As They Take the Stage with the NY Philharmonic
Now Playing: Inside the Horse Barns at Belmont Park
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: How Music Helps Get One Girl Into One of NYC's Top Public Schools
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: Music Helps Change the Life of a Boy From an Underserved Community
Now Playing: The American Dream: Music Helps An Immigrant Mother's Wishes Come True for Her Daughter
Now Playing: Retaliation for Military Sexual Assault Reporting Rampant
Now Playing: Wildlife Parkgoers Defy Rules After Lion Kills American
Now Playing: First Look Inside the Dizzying Heights of the New World Trade Center
Now Playing: Watch: Texas Flash Flooding, May 2015
Now Playing: Here's The Military-Style Gear President Obama Banned Local Police From Using
Now Playing: Biker Gang Shootout Leaves 9 Dead in Texas
Now Playing: Moscow's Subway Is An Underground Palace
Now Playing: How 5 Possible White House Hopefuls Answered the Iraq Question
Now Playing: Mexican Girl Describes Being Taken From Family, Sent to Texas in Case of Mistaken Identity
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32166853,"title":"Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released","duration":"2:16","description":"President Obama announces embassy openings in Cuba; Dozens killed in suicide bomber attack in Sinai desert; Hillary Clinton releases thousands of emails.","url":"/International/video/pres-obama-announces-embassy-openings-cuba-dozens-killed-32166853","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jul 02 00:51:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies,  U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day,  Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/obama-announces-reopening-us-cuba-embassies-us-naval-32166805</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 7.1.15</Description>
        <MainBody>President Obama announces the formal reestablishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries for the first time in more than 50 years.
Now Playing: US and Cuba to Normalize Diplomatic Relations
Now Playing: US, Cuba Enter 'New Chapter' With Embassies Reopening
Now Playing: Oops! Umbrella Closes on President Obama's Head
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: C-130 Plane Crashes In Medan Indonesia, Gov. Chris Christie Announces Presidential Bid, President Obama Meets With Brazilian President
Now Playing: Obama Signs Fast-Track Trade Bill, NBC Cuts Ties With Trump, Wimbledon Begins
Now Playing: 3rd Suspect in Boston ISIS Terror Arrested; House Rejects Obama's Trade Bill; Boeing Shows Off New Dreamliner
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 6/9/15
Now Playing: Colorado Tornado Damage, American Pharoah Practice Run, Hong Kong MERS Screening
Now Playing: Sen. Graham Enters Presidential Race, Caitlyn Jenner Revealed, Nadal Wears $775k Watch At The French Open
Now Playing: FIFA Executives Indicted, Memphis Remembers B.B. King, US and Iraqi Forces Train Together
Now Playing: Hillary Breaks Her Silence With Reporters, Fatal Flooding In Columbia, 'Blue Alert Act' signed
Now Playing: Amtrak Derailment Debris Cleaned Up, Mississippi Officer Remembered, Search for Missing US Marines Helicopter
Now Playing: Deadly Amtrak Crash in Philadelphia, Nepal Earthquake Aftermath, Indy 500 Car Flips During Practice
Now Playing: Second Earthquake Strikes Nepal, Arkansas Tornado Victims Cleanup, 'Jetman' Soars Above Dubai
Now Playing: Attorney General Announces Baltimore Investigation, NYPD Officer Mourned, Obama at Nike Headquarters
Now Playing: Oklahoma Tornado Aftermath, Quake Victims Remembered In Nepal, Air Force Football Meets Obama
Now Playing: Philadelphia Honors Fallen Officers, Sir Elton John Fights For HIVAIDS Funding, SpaceX Tests Astronaut Abort System
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: Freddie Gray's Death Ruled A Homicide, Gov. Christie Ally Pleads Guilty To 'Bridgegate', Yemen Airstrike Aftermath
Now Playing: Bernie Sanders Announces Presidential Candidacy , Quake Survivors Rescued, Vietnam Celebrates The 'Fall Of Saigon'
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32166805,"title":"Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon","duration":"0:43","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 7.1.15","url":"/International/video/obama-announces-reopening-us-cuba-embassies-us-naval-32166805","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 22:26:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  'British Schindler' Saved Hundreds Of Kids During the Holocaust</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/sir-nicholas-winton-saved-hundreds-of-kids-during-the-holocaust-32161888</Link>
        <Description>Sir Nicholas Winton organized the rescued of 669 children from Nazi-occupied Czechoslovakia in 1939.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for 'British Schindler' Saved Hundreds Of Kids During the Holocaust
Finally tonight our person of the week we've all heard about Schindler's List tonight Winston's list. Seventy years ago he saved hundreds of children from the Nazis. Now tens of thousands of children are signing up to get this modest 99 year old the Nobel Peace Prize here's nick watt. I don't think anybody really anticipate that the real. Cost and those. But what the cast him as the him. This is Winston's list the names of 669. Jewish children who owe him their lives. In the fall of 1938 Hitler's troops marched into textbook market. Refugees. Fled deprived. Revealed who's with some things removed it was hopeful. Wynton canceled a planned ski vacation to Switzerland and went instead to the Czech capital he has a plan. Corwin had to do was to find out whether it was possible. And but I found out that it won't fall through. He charger trains raised money spent the children in most danger forged papers and the hardest hospital found families England to take the children and the Germans had Winston under surveillance but didn't stop them. We would get rid of those people and to warm can compute revoked. So I mean you leave now that the pushed up book Wilson's station who opened the pilgrim on the croatians. V reducing was just ten years old when she and her elder sister. Boarded one of Winston's trains. Geico fifteen deaths saying flew. Chugging. Along you know and that can. We're coming out of and I eat he formed. Its fifth who rich. Thanks for corporal. Her parents died at the Bergen belts and concentration camp. The day Hitler invaded Poland in September 1939. 251. Children were boarding Winston's sixth train at rock station Europe's borders closed. It never left. They had to get tough but today and go back. I only found. One college and pet food. Who survived. And your cousins your birth on the and my cousins that go from that chain and you know they won't. All of them hands. Did you feel about that it is time. Was was not feeling about it now with. Review article. That was my fields of could be done. He nano Wynton story is told in track classrooms last year one school even changed its Ney and. He didn't only say. 669. UK might generations. Because. We've had children and grandchildren. You know today live there is about seven cannabis and I. Vieira has three children and three grandchildren. Regret to prime. Interest from Joseph about Cuomo confirmed in group has come of it. And so we choose sir Nicholas went and he's a roads were forgotten for fifty years until his wife discovered a scrapbook in their attic.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: More than 1 Million Celebrate Mass With Pope Francis in Ecuador
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: Int'l Hotspot: Dozens of Egyptian Soldiers Killed by ISIS Suicide Bombers
Now Playing: Pres. Obama Announces Embassy Openings in Cuba; Dozens Killed in ISIS Sinai Attack; Hillary Clinton Emails Released
Now Playing: 'British Schindler' Saved Hundreds Of Kids During the Holocaust
Now Playing: Obama Announces Reopening of U.S. and Cuba Embassies, U.S. Naval Academy Induction Day, Serena Williams Advances At Wimbledon
Now Playing: Day in Pictures: 5/04/15
Now Playing: Gen. Dunford Nominated Joint Chiefs Of Staff, Huckabee Announces 2016 Bid, Cinco De Mayo
Now Playing: Philadelphia Amtrak Train Crashes, Killing 7; North Korean Official Executed for Falling Asleep; Prince Harry Does a Haka
Now Playing: 7.3 Earthquake Rocks Nepal; Obama Presidential Library to Be in Chicago; Tom Brady to Appeal NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Colleagues of Slain Putin Critic Boris Nemtsov Publish Ukraine Report
Now Playing: Royal Notice of Newborn's Arrival Placed on Easel
Now Playing: Prince William Takes George to Hospital to See Newborn Sister
Now Playing: Mexican Girl Describes Being Taken From Family, Sent to Texas in Case of Mistaken Identity
Now Playing: Moscow's Subway Is An Underground Palace
Now Playing: May 4, 1979: Margaret Thatcher Becomes Prime Minister #TBT
Now Playing: X-Ray Scan Uncovers Boy Smuggled in a Suitcase
=======
Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Millionaire Funds Rescue Missions to Save Migrants: Part 1
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32006748,"title":"Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms","duration":"0:42","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.","url":"/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 01:02:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/anti-confederate-flag-protest-columbia-sc-tornado-cleanup-31979425</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.23.15</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Tom Brady 'Deflategate' Appeal
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
=======
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32161888,"title":"'British Schindler' Saved Hundreds Of Kids During the Holocaust","duration":"3:15","description":"Sir Nicholas Winton organized the rescued of 669 children from Nazi-occupied Czechoslovakia in 1939.","url":"/International/video/sir-nicholas-winton-saved-hundreds-of-kids-during-the-holocaust-32161888","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 22:04:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Int'l Hotspot: Dozens of Egyptian Soldiers Killed by ISIS Suicide Bombers</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/intl-hotspot-dozens-egyptian-soldiers-killed-isis-suicide-32159860</Link>
        <Description>ISIS suicide bombers targeted multiple Egyptian military checkpoints throughout the Sinai Peninsula in attacks that killed at least 60 soldiers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Int'l Hotspot: Dozens of Egyptian Soldiers Killed by ISIS Suicide Bombers
New terror miles from the Gaza border ice is launching multiple attacks on military targets in Egypt. At least sixty soldiers killed by suicide bombers at checkpoints threw out the Sinai Peninsula the terror group now warning of deadly attack surrounding the Muslim holiday. Robert now. Right now international hot spot Egypt. Pac man is in New York this afternoon the White House National Security Council releasing a statement in support of Egypt following these attacks saying in part. The United States strongly condemns the terrorist attacks against Egyptian security forces. In north Sinai this morning which killed dozens of Egyptian person Allen injured many others the United States stands resolutely with Egypt a bit the spate of terrorist attacks. Have afflicted the country. Following this story for a ABC's Alex mark pot in Beirut Alex. Hello to you and dozens of soldiers killed in multiple attacks what do we know about how these attacks were carried out. That's right time fact that fighting is still ongoing it's been raging all day right in the northeastern part of the Sinai Peninsula against the border. Gaza and Israel as you mentioned the latest reports that we're getting are around sixty to seventy soldiers dead. Scores more militant as scores more of militants dead on top of that these numbers have not yet been confirms. By the Egyptian army but these are reports that are sourcing. A medical sources bear in the Sinai Peninsula that's fighting started around 6 o'clock in the morning. When these militants attacked the town of chickens who waited. And this was. I'm. This it's this attack was quickly claimed by a group called Sinai Peninsula which it is an affiliate of ices in the Sinai Peninsula you speak I'll answer atomic decent solely swore allegiance. Two ice is back in November and this is one of the deadliest it's not the deadliest terrorist attack in modern engines and history. And it comes just two days after Egypt's top prosecuted at public prosecutor. Was assassinated in his upscale neighborhood. In Cairo has been not there hasn't been any claim responsibility yet. Sport that attacked the assumption is it was also carried out by miss about Egypt is buried our turn. Do we know what ideas might have focused on the Sinai Peninsula. Well this is the place bets militants have been Terry audit tax years more than 700. Egyptian security forces have been killed by Islamist militants. Among them from this group Sinai Peninsula. In the past two years there are a lot of military targets there. In the Sinai and there has been a fierce crackdown by the government. Of president's SEC against these islamists after he came to power he took power seized power is safe. In Millard military tools from the is Liz is Louis president Mohamed Morse. It had warned of deadly attacks particular are wrapped particularly around Ramadan with Egypt prepared for an attack like this. You are right this is the holy month of Ramadan and and prices both for and had calls for expanded attacks in the region around the world's. And we've seen a couple of these. Attacks take place over the past few days in places like seizure were almost forty. People were killed on that beach at a mosque in Kuwait. Where a suicide bomber went in and and and blue glow didn't look at suicide vest at the height of Friday prayers. Com now it's it's part is it's hard to call these all. Ice is attacks we don't notes what extent ice is proper in Iraq Syria. Has. Has ordered these attacks as sanction them. But it goes to show that the reach of crisis is expanding and that people are willing to take matters into their own ante up lone gunman. You have groups that are acting by themselves and then ices as a whole claims that attack. This is the second attack of the week in Egypt who was targeted and Monday's bombing. Now is the public prosecutor. Name of guy named Eric disembarked. That was one of the highest level political assassinations. In decades. And she was someone who had helps the CC regime clamp down. On the islamists since easy came to power exactly two years ago and that's what we should actually note is that. Years ago right now there are these mass protests and Kyra that ended on July 3 when the military men and chicks. Morse the out. And since then. Hundreds of Islam isn't being chilled and rounded up arrested put on trial sentenced to death. By the CC regime and its judiciary. And so that's. One and that's the main reason that we're seeing this massive backlash all these attacks by as well as. Alex this attack also following three others last week in France Kuwait and two knees you what is the sense now on the ground in terms. Fear and and what may be next. Well the senses. That this is something that's just going to continue I mean crisis is we know it's you know it got its name because it's in Iraq and Syria but frankly it's it's spreading. Like cancer throughout the regional affiliates are up in in Libya and Egypt all across our North Africa and beyond and so this is something. Better that will continue. An and answers certainly could grow. Because it's Ramadan and we could see more attacks decree on Friday you know witches witches believe that it. The May Day and increase our calendar. And and so we expect more these attacks I mean this is something. That has picked up in case something has been picked up and scale it's it's it's up in terms of the geography. And anger Saudi Arabia for example which is the place we rarely see any sort of attacks in the past few weeks there have been two attacks. By ice militants it again it's Shiite mosques and this is something to it that they'll just. And Alex is there a sense of outrage among some Muslims that these attacks are happening during this holiest times. Absolutely. This was expected but there certainly is outraged at the same time this is something that this region has come to grout is is is grappling and and world regardless of whether or not it's Ramadan. This is something that you know people all across regional firm. You're Lebanon's it to Syrian and ends Egypt are trying to figure out. Out to deal but in the meantime. This is a group and that it is only growing in terms of it its ability to carry edit and willingness to carry out attacks. As we know now with some of the bodies are being flown back up particularly apt from Tunisia to the United Kingdom in terms of victims of that attack. What are some of they reactions that you have been seeing. On the ground there in the Middle East to these most recent spate of attacks. All apps that outraged and I think we should just someone in Egypt for example this is no Tunisia is often held up as an example. Or is often called the only success story and the Arab Spring gave managed to do. Transitioned to a democratic governments and I was actually in Tunisia two months ago are right at three months ago. When there is the attack on the national museum. And there is this sense of outrage there that something like this would disrupt the relative peace that they've had that you know that they're on the right track. And you can see it in those scenes from Tunisia on the beach. They were all these other Sunnis and shouting at the gunman creating this human chain to block him from carrying out more tax there is a great story a construction worker on the roof growing tiles at. At the young at the gunman so there certainly is a sense of outraged. By everyday Muslims all across the Middle East in Tunisia and beyond. I'm Alex thank you so much for joining us ABC's mark pot in Beirut. Also joining us now ABC news counterterrorism contributor John Cohen John reports cities attacks were well coordinated and happened. Simultaneously. What does that say about ice this strategy is this something we've seen out high they use in the past. It good afternoon in time. Top crisis is trying to project a global presence and they're doing it through various strategies. One they're trying to pull territories Syria and Iraq. They're gaining territory humans through insurgent army techniques they're trying to govern its territories the building affiliations with. Other extremist organizations and countries like Saudi Arabia. Tunisia Libya. Kuwait in each out and date through these affiliations are trying to show people that they can cost problems in these countries as well. Process seeking to inspire. People around the world particularly in Europe and unites states and Canada to act independently carry out attacks on their behalf. They you all of this together in a coordinated synchronized way because they are trying to show that they are global organization with global reach. And last week's attack in France Kuwait and Tunisia now Egypt are certainly evidence that in part. That is in fact coming true how our US counterterrorism officials working to prevent a possible life is attacked here in the United States especially leading up to this holiday weekend. Well this is an area big concern for US law enforcement. You've seen the FBI much more aggressive of late and looking at people who they believe may be inspired by the axis ideology and taking law enforcement action against those people you see quite a bit of intelligence being shared the private sector state and local law enforcement. And ask state local law enforcement looks to provide security around these fourth of July events. You'll see stepped up efforts to in screening of people coming to these events and undercover. Officers being in it in with the crowd. And critical infrastructure protection activities around key targets. The area concerned there's a lot of security in place. It's already in place a tremendous increase as V don't into the weekend. Com and I would remind you that crisis has specifically I. Asked this thing out for attacks. I during the month Ramadan. Arbitrary and as you talk about her hair and there's real concern that somebody on their independently low heat that and action in the United States. I need these news contributor John Colin thank you for being with us. And you can keep up with this story in real time I downloading the ABC news app and starring this story for exclusive updates on the go. This is an international hot spot on ABC news digital anti Hernandez in New York thanks for action.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: Sen. Tom Cotton: Military Action Against Iran Must Remain an Option
Now Playing: Baby Charlotte Elizabeth Diana Ready for Royal Christening
Now Playing: Greek Citizens Left Penniless by Economic Crisis
Now Playing: Texas Woman Goes Missing During Caribbean Snorkeling Trip
Now Playing: Beatles' Ringo Starr Gets His Personal Story Told in 'Ringo - With a Little Help'
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: 'Britain's Schindler,' Who Saved Over 650 Jewish Children During Holocaust, Dies
Now Playing: Pilots Fired After Video Captures Model in Cockpit
=======
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31979425,"title":"Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension","duration":"0:40","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.23.15","url":"/International/video/anti-confederate-flag-protest-columbia-sc-tornado-cleanup-31979425","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 22:13:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/giant-basking-shark-caught-australia-31974124</Link>
        <Description>The shark, just under 21 feet long, was caught off the west coast of Victoria, Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
=======
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32159860,"title":"Int'l Hotspot: Dozens of Egyptian Soldiers Killed by ISIS Suicide Bombers","duration":"10:47","description":"ISIS suicide bombers targeted multiple Egyptian military checkpoints throughout the Sinai Peninsula in attacks that killed at least 60 soldiers.","url":"/International/video/intl-hotspot-dozens-egyptian-soldiers-killed-isis-suicide-32159860","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed Jul 01 01:45:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Christie Announces 2016 Bid; Obama Holds Bilateral Meeting with Brazil's Rousseff; Team USA Faces Germany in World Cup Semi-Finals</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/christie-announces-2016-bid-obama-holds-bilateral-meeting-32138533</Link>
        <Description>NJ Governor Chris Christie announces 2016 presidential bid; President Obama holds bilateral meeting with Brazil's President Rousseff; Team USA to face Germany in World Cup Semi-Finals.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Christie Announces 2016 Bid; Obama Holds Bilateral Meeting with Brazil's Rousseff; Team USA Faces Germany in World Cup Semi-Finals
Horrifying scene in Indonesia and military cargo plane carrying more than a hundred people crashing into local channel and that countries. Third largest city this C 130 prominent just minutes after they. You have strained. And decision making. And authority back in the Oval Office and that is why today I am proud to announce my candidacy for the Republican nomination. All out at the upstate New York prison where those two convicted killers pulled off dramatic escape the manhunt is over but so many questions remain under investigation in. How I was man broke out in anger remains help others. Three executives at that facility including the superintendent and tools it's his deputies have been put on paid administrative leave it along with nine correction officers now in prison guards. Obama meeting with Brazilian president until month Lucent and the two leaders announcing today new partnerships on several fronts economically environmentally. Vowing to address climate change among other things. The outline of a neighborhood but we acknowledge the homes at least twenty into the ground by this fast moving wildfire that exploded under high winds. And scorching. Triple digit temperatures like a war song. Never seen anything like it. He went game gearing up for the World Cup semifinals. Tiki none powerhouse stay number one seed. Tonight police say German authentic scored twenty goals so far more than any other week. Our weird world record Korea a stunt driver popped his car up onto two wheels and drove a mild. As fast as he could it to them two minutes and ten seconds new record. About thirty miles an hour when he came back down over those tires needed to be replaced. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: Team USA Facing Off Against Germany
Now Playing: Extended Deadline for Iran Nuclear Negotiations Nears
Now Playing: Walter Reed Medical Center On Lockdown, President Obama Remarks On ISIL, Confession To Murder In San Francisco
Now Playing: Inside Princess Charlotte's Royal Christening
Now Playing: Team USA Beats Japan in Women's World Cup Final
Now Playing: What Does Greek Debt Crisis Mean for US Economy?
Now Playing: Greeks Vote No on International Bailout
Now Playing: The World Awaits Results of Greek Debt Referendum
Now Playing: Iran Nuclear Talks Near Deadline
Now Playing: Women's World Cup Final Preview
Now Playing: Greece's Economic Fate Goes to the Ballot Box
Now Playing: Sen. Tom Cotton: Military Action Against Iran Must Remain an Option
Now Playing: Baby Charlotte Elizabeth Diana Ready for Royal Christening
Now Playing: Greek Citizens Left Penniless by Economic Crisis
Now Playing: Texas Woman Goes Missing During Caribbean Snorkeling Trip
Now Playing: Beatles' Ringo Starr Gets His Personal Story Told in 'Ringo - With a Little Help'
Now Playing: Queen Elizabeth Joins Moment of Silence for Tunisia Terror Attack Victims
Now Playing: False Alarm Puts Washington Navy Yards on Lockdown; Freight Train Carrying Toxic Chemicals Burns; 'Maria' Retiring from Sesame Street
Now Playing: 'Britain's Schindler,' Who Saved Over 650 Jewish Children During Holocaust, Dies
Now Playing: Pilots Fired After Video Captures Model in Cockpit
=======
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31974124,"title":"Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia","duration":"1:44","description":"The shark, just under 21 feet long, was caught off the west coast of Victoria, Australia.","url":"/International/video/giant-basking-shark-caught-australia-31974124","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 00:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176</Link>
        <Description>Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
And yeah. In New York fertility aid killer on the rise DNA evidence found at a campground where they are hiding out positively link Richard Matt and David sweat or we don't know obviously is how old you. An idea that they lived. In the way it's supposed to escape that jeers realist it's time to minutes to plant in the capital. South Carolina governor Eliot and pound cake along for support line. I stayed out. It's not just a matter. Did not being polite to stray. And public and that's not good measure of whether racism still exists or continent. President was discussing racism with the comedian mark Merritt for his WTF podcast and he was making a point about how our political record. And talents in this country scenes whitewashed fact that. The reasons why that we're being used in the first place has somehow been scrubbed clean because we start seeing that word pop. A grim discovery on a mountain in New Mexico searchers have located the body of the former White House chef Walter shine in a river near a trail where he'd gone hiking more than a week ago that shot but who cook for about the clintons and bushes had just recently moved. Two New Mexico. Forty million Americans in the capital dangerous storms including. Possible tornadoes target in Chicago and Detroit while much of the south is under water. I think there are busy in Southern California he wondered in the shade in the backyard for bed and Johnson won't happen cooling off we'll present them. We'll.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Update on Escaped Prisoners
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
=======
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32138533,"title":"Christie Announces 2016 Bid; Obama Holds Bilateral Meeting with Brazil's Rousseff; Team USA Faces Germany in World Cup Semi-Finals","duration":"2:00","description":"NJ Governor Chris Christie announces 2016 presidential bid; President Obama holds bilateral meeting with Brazil's President Rousseff; Team USA to face Germany in World Cup Semi-Finals.","url":"/International/video/christie-announces-2016-bid-obama-holds-bilateral-meeting-32138533","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:15:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 7/6/15:  Legal Motion: Bill Cosby Said in 2005 Deposition He Got Quaaludes to Give to Women</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-7615-legal-motion-bill-cosby-2005-deposition-32262939</Link>
        <Description>ESPN Magazine's Body Issue 2015: Behind the Scenes; Inside Joan Rivers' $28 Million NYC Penthouse</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 7/6/15:  Legal Motion: Bill Cosby Said in 2005 Deposition He Got Quaaludes to Give to Women
17:12 07/06/15 NR
=======
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:24:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy,  Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Tsarnaev: 'Sorry for the Lives I Have Taken'
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31951176,"title":"Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'","duration":"1:43","description":"Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.","url":"/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 23:20:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165</Link>
        <Description>Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Zero. That's emergency landing knees and that bully and Bloomberg. There. Oh. Now. I hope what. And running in regard him running new wave group. You know addicted to video now Mike is a quick. I.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: 10 Ducklings Rescued From Storm Drain
Now Playing: Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Now Playing: Coast Guard Rescues Endangered Turtle
Now Playing: Police Release Surveillance Video in Maryland Graffiti Spree
Now Playing: Eight-Foot Gator Makes Trapper Feel the Miami Heat
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Moment Homeless Man Attacks Teen in Target
Now Playing: Restaurant Employees Take Down Man Accused of Bomb Threat
Now Playing: Man's Rescue From Sinking Truck Caught on Tape
Now Playing: NY Toddler Survives Being Hit By Out-Of-Control Car
Now Playing: Dozens Push Double-Decker Bus Off Trapped Cyclist
Now Playing: Boaters' Frightful Near-Collision With Airplane Caught on Video
Now Playing: Man Crashes SUV Into Store to Steal Beer
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Mount Everest Avalanche
Now Playing: Train Plummets Off Tracks in Dramatic Video
Now Playing: Man's 'Crazy' Encounter With Tornado Caught on Video
Now Playing: Nanny Cam Captures Powerful Home Boiler Explosion
Now Playing: Girl Attacked at McDonald's Caught on Video
Now Playing: Store Clerk Fights Off, Shoots Robber
Now Playing: Pilots Escape Mid-Air Collision at Air Show
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31948165,"title":"Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead","duration":"0:45","description":"Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.","url":"/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 19:06:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/international-hotspot-explosion-rocks-afghanistan-parliament-31942098</Link>
        <Description>Taliban launches bold attack against lawmakers in Kabul. Security forces kill seven gunmen.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
I've let alone and I'm. It is and the terrifying moment a suicide bomber in a car blew himself up outside the Afghan parliament today. Lawmakers screaming and running for cover right now. Hot spot Kabul Afghanistan. Hello. We are it's how about took credit for the attack came hours after the militant groups he's controlled the second district in the northern part of Afghanistan. BB BBC's David line isn't cobbled with the latest. This was how the bomb fell inside the Afghan parliament. If that panics at the speaker of the writings he Brahimi. Members of parliament and officials try to find their way out and there was pandemonium in the surrounding corridors. Windows at the back of parliament with shafted in the last. Full tree when they heard sounds of gunfire coming from the other side of the building. And this was the scene outside in the road a line of can't set alight by the huge explosion. Newly trained Afghan special forces quickly arrived to take up position. The Taliban gunmen were repulsed by police in the parliament and sought refuge in a building under construction. You can see puffs of concrete chipped away it's the police attacked positions. Firing when tone for about an hour into all the gunmen were killed. As the clearing up when tone the questions were beginning as to how the Taliban go this close to a century of Afghan power. They said they carried out the attack on the day that the new defense minister was to be introduced in parliament. A passing taxi was damaged. Its drive at two of them leaders said his hand was singed by the explosion. With two passengers were injured. And outside this is the crater of the poem he blew open the seats of Afghan democracy and a reminder of the Taliban's continuing ability to disrupt this country. This Kabul attack and Taliban and balances in Helmand in the southwest. And elsewhere in the country. Put pressure on Afghan government forces just at a time when peace talks between the Taliban and the government built mold possible and for many years. David going BBC news Kabul. And you can keep up with this story in real time by downloading the ABC news that had started this story for exclusive updates ago. Anti Hernandez a New York you've been watching the international hot spot.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Sat Jun 20 19:41:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/red-devils-parachutist-tangles-teammate-mid-air-31912318</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of onlookers at the Whitehaven Airshow in the United Kingdom held their breath during the stunt.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
=======
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32006748,"title":"Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms","duration":"0:42","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.","url":"/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:12:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 07/06/15: USA Women's Soccer Team Dominates Japan in World Cup Final</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-070615-usa-womens-soccer-team-dominates-japan-32253320</Link>
        <Description>Greeks Decision to Stand Behind PM Tsipras Could Impact US Markets; San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 07/06/15: USA Womens Soccer Team Dominates Japan in World Cup Final
01:01:13 07/06/15 NR
Greeks Decision to Stand Behind PM Tsipras Could Impact US Markets; San Francisco Shooter States He Chose City for Sanctuary Policies
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:38:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 07/06/15:  Shooter Scare at Walter Reed Medical Center</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-070615-shooter-scare-walter-reed-medical-center-32262422</Link>
        <Description>49 wildfires burn in eight states; the battle over the confederate flag at South Carolina Statehouse.</Description>
        <MainBody>WN 07/06/15:  Shooter Scare at Walter Reed Medical Center
17:14 07/06/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jul 05 22:35:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 07/05/15: Donald Trump's Impact on the 2016 Campaign Trail</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-070515-donald-trumps-impact-2016-campaign-trail-32234897</Link>
        <Description>Guests: Rick Perry, Yanis Varoufakis, Bob Goodlatte, Tom Cole, Bill Kristol, Joaquin Castro, Anne Gearan</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 07/05/15: Donald Trumps Impact on the 2016 Campaign Trail
48:52 07/05/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 09:03:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20: Bruce Jenner: The Interview - Encore Presentation</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-bruce-jenner-interview-encore-presentation-32235522</Link>
        <Description>Bruce Jenner shares an exclusive and wide-ranging conversation with Diane Sawyer.</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 07/04/15: Bruce Jenner: The Interview - Encore Presentation
01:20:00 07/04/15 NR
=======
        <date>Tue Jun 23 00:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176</Link>
        <Description>Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
And yeah. In New York fertility aid killer on the rise DNA evidence found at a campground where they are hiding out positively link Richard Matt and David sweat or we don't know obviously is how old you. An idea that they lived. In the way it's supposed to escape that jeers realist it's time to minutes to plant in the capital. South Carolina governor Eliot and pound cake along for support line. I stayed out. It's not just a matter. Did not being polite to stray. And public and that's not good measure of whether racism still exists or continent. President was discussing racism with the comedian mark Merritt for his WTF podcast and he was making a point about how our political record. And talents in this country scenes whitewashed fact that. The reasons why that we're being used in the first place has somehow been scrubbed clean because we start seeing that word pop. A grim discovery on a mountain in New Mexico searchers have located the body of the former White House chef Walter shine in a river near a trail where he'd gone hiking more than a week ago that shot but who cook for about the clintons and bushes had just recently moved. Two New Mexico. Forty million Americans in the capital dangerous storms including. Possible tornadoes target in Chicago and Detroit while much of the south is under water. I think there are busy in Southern California he wondered in the shade in the backyard for bed and Johnson won't happen cooling off we'll present them. We'll.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Update on Escaped Prisoners
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
<<<<<<< HEAD
Now Playing: An Inside Look at the UN's Race to Save Refugees Around the World
Now Playing: Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air
Now Playing: Judge Sets SC Shooter Bond at $1Million; California Fire Blazes On Close to Big Bear; Tiger Woods Loses His Grip
Now Playing: U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch Sworn In; Study Finds Water Resources Depleting Worldwide; Woman in Bali Gets Phone Stolen by Selfie Monkey
Now Playing: Lynch Sworn In As Attorney General, Trump Hits The Campaign Trail, McIlroy Practices For The U.S. Open
Now Playing: Putin Unveils Massive Military Expo with Weapons and 'Trendy' Clothing
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31912318,"title":"Red Devils Parachutist Tangles With Teammate in Mid-Air","duration":"2:31","description":"Thousands of onlookers at the Whitehaven Airshow in the United Kingdom held their breath during the stunt.","url":"/International/video/red-devils-parachutist-tangles-teammate-mid-air-31912318","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:02:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 06/25/15:  After Charleston Shooting, Signs of Change in Race Conversation</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-062515-charleston-shooting-signs-change-race-conversation-32043184</Link>
        <Description>'Magic Mike XXL' Cast on New Film, Getting Their Stripper Physiques; Trump's Comments on Mexican Immigrants Spark Controversy</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 06/25/15:  After Charleston Shooting, Signs of Change in Race Conversation
17:41 06/25/15 NR
'Magic Mike XXL' Cast on New Film, Getting Their Stripper Physiques; Trump's Comments on Mexican Immigrants Spark Controversy
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:24:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 06/25/15: Obamacare Gets a Major Supreme Court Victory</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-062515-obamacare-major-supreme-court-victory-32041131</Link>
        <Description>Authorities Investigating 2 Possible Arsons on Southern Churches; The CEO of Takata Apologizes Publicly for the First Time</Description>
        <MainBody>WN 06/25/15: Obamacare Gets a Major Supreme Court Victory
20:02 06/25/15 NR
Authorities Investigating 2 Possible Arsons on Southern Churches; The CEO of Takata Apologizes Publicly for the First Time
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:39:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 06/25/15: Boston Bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev Apologizes</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-062515-boston-bomber-dzhokhar-tsarnaev-apologizes-32025449</Link>
        <Description>Corrections Officer Charged in NY Prison Escape; Sibling Spies Watching in Ways That Parents Can't</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 06/25/15: Boston Bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev Apologizes
01:01:35 06/25/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 23:10:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20 06/19/15:  'The Wolfpack'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-061915-wolfpack-31908232</Link>
        <Description>'Wolfpack' Brothers Grew Up Locked in NYC Apartment for Years; Chance Encounter With Filmmaker Changes 'Wolfpack' Brothers' Lives; Brothers Meet Grandma For First Time at 'Wolfpack' Family Reunion</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 06/19/15: 'The Wolfpack'
40:42 06/19/15 NR
'Wolfpack' Brothers Grew Up Locked in NYC Apartment for Years; Chance Encounter With Filmmaker Changes 'Wolfpack' Brothers' Lives; Brothers Meet Grandma For First Time at 'Wolfpack' Family Reunion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
=======
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31951176,"title":"Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'","duration":"1:43","description":"Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.","url":"/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 23:20:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165</Link>
        <Description>Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Zero. That's emergency landing knees and that bully and Bloomberg. There. Oh. Now. I hope what. And running in regard him running new wave group. You know addicted to video now Mike is a quick. I.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: 10 Ducklings Rescued From Storm Drain
Now Playing: Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Now Playing: Coast Guard Rescues Endangered Turtle
Now Playing: Police Release Surveillance Video in Maryland Graffiti Spree
Now Playing: Eight-Foot Gator Makes Trapper Feel the Miami Heat
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Moment Homeless Man Attacks Teen in Target
Now Playing: Restaurant Employees Take Down Man Accused of Bomb Threat
Now Playing: Man's Rescue From Sinking Truck Caught on Tape
Now Playing: NY Toddler Survives Being Hit By Out-Of-Control Car
Now Playing: Dozens Push Double-Decker Bus Off Trapped Cyclist
Now Playing: Boaters' Frightful Near-Collision With Airplane Caught on Video
Now Playing: Man Crashes SUV Into Store to Steal Beer
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Mount Everest Avalanche
Now Playing: Train Plummets Off Tracks in Dramatic Video
Now Playing: Man's 'Crazy' Encounter With Tornado Caught on Video
Now Playing: Nanny Cam Captures Powerful Home Boiler Explosion
Now Playing: Girl Attacked at McDonald's Caught on Video
Now Playing: Store Clerk Fights Off, Shoots Robber
Now Playing: Pilots Escape Mid-Air Collision at Air Show
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31948165,"title":"Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead","duration":"0:45","description":"Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.","url":"/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:40:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 06/27/15: Controversy Over Confederate Flag Begins To Boil</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-062715-controversy-confederate-flag-begins-boil-32078829</Link>
        <Description>1,200 Officers Searching for Escaped Prisoner; The Resistance Against Same-Sex Marriage Already Underway. </Description>
        <MainBody>WN 06/27/15: Controversy Over Confederate Flag Begins To Boil
16:48 06/27/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:24:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20 06/26/15:  'Reversal of Fortune'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-062615-reversal-fortune-32068348</Link>
        <Description>Video Shows Vanderbilt Football Player Carrying Date Into Dorm; Vanderbilt Football Player Makes Stunning Admission at Trial for Rape; Vanderbilt Rape Trial Juror's Secret Leads to Mistrial</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 06/26/15: 'Reversal of Fortune'
40:09 06/26/15 NR
Video Shows Vanderbilt Football Player Carrying Date Into Dorm; Vanderbilt Football Player Makes Stunning Admission at Trial for Rape; Vanderbilt Rape Trial Juror's Secret Leads to Mistrial
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:10:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 06/27/15: Gay Rights Triumph in Supreme Court Ruling</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-062715-gay-rights-triumph-supreme-court-ruling-32072212</Link>
        <Description>Richard Matt Killed by Border Agents in New York; Quasi Modo Crowned World's Ugliest Dog</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 06/27/15: Gay Rights Triumph in Supreme Court Ruling
28:30 06/27/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:06:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 06/26/15:  Escaped Convicted Murderers: 1 Dead, 1 Still on the Run</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-062615-escaped-convicted-murderers-dead-run-32069194</Link>
        <Description>One of the World's Best Rock Climbers Attempts Redwood Tree Climb; A Country Comes Together After Charleston, Same-Sex Marriage Decision</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 06/26/15:  Escaped Convicted Murderers: 1 Dead, 1 Still on the Run
18:30 06/26/15 NR
One of the World's Best Rock Climbers Attempts Redwood Tree Climb; Celebrations Over Same-Sex Marriage Decision Spread Across the Country
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:45:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  What Would You Do? 06/26/15</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WhatWouldYouDo/video/062615--32066122</Link>
        <Description>Season 10, Episode 5</Description>
        <MainBody>What Would You Do? 06/26/15
40:46 06/26/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <date>Sun Jun 21 22:31:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 06/21/15: Inside the Tragic Shooting In Charleston, South Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-062115-inside-tragic-shooting-charleston-south-carolina-31927284</Link>
        <Description>Guests: Rick Santorum, Carl Anderson, Bakari Sellers, Steve Inskeep, Sara Fagen, Maria Cardona</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 06/21/15: Inside the Tragic Shooting In Charleston, South Carolina
46:09 06/21/15 NR
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
