<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="abcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:38:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At Least 15 Britons Killed at Tunisia Beach Resort</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/15-britons-killed-attack-tunisia-beach-resort/story?id=32073185</Link>
        <Description>British death toll "may well rise."</Description>
        <MainBody>At Least 15 Britons Killed in Attack at Tunisia Beach Resort
Jun 27, 2015, 12:38 PM ET
By EMILY SHAPIRO via World News
A young woman lays flowers at the scene of a shooting in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Darko Vojinovic/AP Photo
Copy
At least 15 British people were among those killed when a gunman opened fire on a beach in Tunisia , Britain's foreign minister said Saturday.
Tobias Ellwood said the beachfront massacre was "the most significant terrorist attack on the British people" since suicide bombers struck the London transport network in 2005, killing 52 and wounding hundreds. The gunman killed 39 people Friday at the Hotel Imperial Marhaba in Sousse, a popular resort town on the northeast coast of Africa.
Ellwood added the number of British people killed Friday "may well rise."
The gunman hid his rifle under an umbrella before he opened fire, security official Rafik Chelli told Tunisia radio station Mosaique FM. He then entered the hotel through the pool and began firing.
The gunman was killed by police after the attack, the country's interior ministry told the Associated Press.
ISIS claimed responsibility for the attack in a statement circulated on social media.
Sousse is one of Tunisia's most popular vacation spots and draws visitors from across Europe - particularly France . The nationalities of the victims were still being determined, officials said Friday, but a security official told Mosaique FM that many of those killed were foreigners.
The hotel had 565 guests at the time of the attack, mostly from the United Kingdom and central Europe, RIU Hotels &amp; Resorts said in a statement on its website.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32073185.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 16:13:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About the Iran Nuclear Negotiations</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/iran-nuclear-negotiations/story?id=32035825</Link>
        <Description>Negotiations are underway with Iran over the nuclear compromise.</Description>
        <MainBody>Everything You Need to Know About the Iran Nuclear Negotiations
Jun 27, 2015, 6:00 AM ET
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif shakes hands on January 14, 2015 with US State Secretary John Kerry in Geneva.
Rick Wilking/AFP/Getty Images
A Brief History
This deal has been in the works since November 2013. That's when Iran and the so-called P5+1 (U.S., U.K., France , Russia , China and Germany ) agreed on a Joint Plan of Action, an interim agreement that paved the way for talks by temporarily halting Iran's nuclear enrichment program and subjecting it to daily inspections in exchange for the loosening of some economic sanctions. In November 2014, Secretary Kerry announced an extension of the deadline for an interim agreement until March 31. And on April 2, after eight straight days of high-level diplomatic talks, an interim deal was reached.
What Was The Interim Deal?
A U.S. fact sheet provided at the time said Iran's nuclear breakout time -- the time it would take the country to build a bomb -- would be shifted from 2-3 months to a year. It said Irans deep buried nuclear facility will be converted from a nuclear site into a peaceful physics and technology center. No fissile material would remain there. Iran agreed not to enrich uranium over 3.67 percent (20 percent is considered weapons grade) for the next 15 years and to dilute or sell its existing stockpile of enriched uranium, reducing that stockpile by a total of 98 percent. Upon verification of these steps many United Nations and European financial sanctions would be lifted. Other sanctions, including those approved by Congress, will be lifted in a phased approach. A final agreement would have to be reached by June 30.
John Kerry in 'Good Condition' After Surgery on Broken Leg
How Close Are They To A Final Deal?
As Kerry put it last Thursday, "Im hopeful, but Im not declaring optimism." Despite televised comments this week where the Irans supreme leader, Ayatollah Khomeini, appeared to pull away from the most basic principles of the interim agreement, State Department officials insist that behind closed doors those matters are resolved. They say at this point its a very technical discussion. On Wednesday, Kerry dismissed the Ayatollahs comments as bluster made for domestic political consumption. He also said plainly that if those were Irans actual negotiating terms there would be no deal. At this point completion of a deal hinges on a few very difficult stumbling blocks.
What Are The Stumbling Blocks?
The negotiations are intensely focused right now on the pace and scope of sanctions relief for the Iranians. All that the West wants is to stop Irans pathway to a bomb; and all Iran wants is economic relief. What the Iranians care about most is lifting the United Nations sanctions. Those sanctions prevent Iran from doing business with the US, but also from most of the industrialized world. Publicly the Iranians are saying they will not allow inspection of military sites. But for the U.S. that is a non-starter; and officials say indeed the Iranians will concede this point. The negotiating parties are stuck on which sanctions to lift and when, and by what verification process. Also critical in this debate is the issue of snapping back sanctions.
What Is Snap Back?
The U.S. wants to make sure it can snap UN sanctions back into place if something goes wrong. The problem is that they dont want the U.N. Security Council (of which China and Russia are members) to be able to influence that process. So they are trying to develop a new mechanism, independent of the Security Council, to snap sanctions back into place if needed. At the same time, the Iranians want some measure of snap back too. They want to be able to ramp up nuclear production again if they feel the terms of the agreement are violated, just the same as the US would be able to do. Snap back essentially serves as a mutual deterrent and a mechanism used to make sure each side keeps up its end of the bargain.
Could The Deadline Slide Back?
Its very possible the deadline could slide back yet again, but likely by only a matter of days. The State Department has held firm in public statements that it is focused on getting a deal done by June 30, but other foreign ministers involved in the talks, as well as U.S. officials who have spoken privately, acknowledge the real possibility that the date could move beyond that.
What Would A Final Deal Look Like?
Similar to the interim deal, officials say nothing is going to be signed on the dotted line. You wont see that photo op with Secretary Kerry and Foreign Minister Zarif seated at a table, signing a leather bound document and shaking hands for the cameras. But there will be a document, perhaps as long as a 100 pages, a state department official said, detailing the agreement. Its never been about signatures," one official said. "Its always been about actions and verification.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32035825.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:01:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS Claims Responsibility for Tunisia Attack That Killed 39</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/tunisia-attack-gunman-kills-beach-resort-officials/story?id=32046785</Link>
        <Description>Some 39 were killed and 39 injured when a gunman opened fire at a Tunisian beach resort.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
A gunman opened fire on beachgoers at a hotel in Tunisia today, killing at least 39 people and injuring at least 39, officials said.
The attack took place at the Hotel Imperial Marhaba in Sousse, a popular resort town on the northeast coast of Africa.
The gunman, who acted alone, was killed by police after the attack, the country's Interior Ministry told the Associated Press. The gunman was not known to authorities, security official Rafik Chelli told Tunisia radio station Mosaique FM.
ISIS claimed responsibility for the attack in a statement circulated on social media today.
Terrorist Attacks Rock Three Countries
Chelli said the gunman hid his Kalashnikov rifle under an umbrella before he opened fire. The gunman then entered the Hotel Imperial through the pool and shot at people, Chelli told Mosaique FM.
Sousse is one of Tunisia's most popular vacation spots and draws visitors from across Europe - particularly France. The nationalities of the victims are still being determined, officials said, but a security official confirmed to Mosaique FM that many victims were foreigners. At least five victims were British, according to the U.K. Foreign Office.
The hotel had 565 guests at the time of the attack, mostly from the United Kingdom and central Europe, RIU Hotels &amp; Resorts said in a statement on its website, but the hotel has not confirmed nationalities of the victims.
Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
PHOTO: The bodies of people are seen after an armed attack on a tourist hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, left at least 27 people dead, including foreigners, and injured six others , on June 26, 2015.
RIU Hotels said 9 of its guests and 4 of its employees were hospitalized, all with non-life-threatening injuries.
A woman staying in an adjacent hotel told Irish radio program RT Radio: "As I was running towards the hotel, the waiters and security on the beach started saying, 'Run, run, run.' And we just ran to our room."
Tunisia has been on high-alert since March, when Islamist militant gunmen attacked a museum, killing 22 foreign tourists.
The attack in Tunisia is one of three alleged terrorist attacks today: in Kuwait, at least 16 were killed in an attack on a Shiite mosque, and in France, a man was believed to have been decapitated at an American-owned energy factory.
Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
PHOTO: Security measures are taken after an armed attack on a tourist hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, left at least 27 people dead, including foreigners, and injured six others , on June 26, 2015.
The White House said in a statement: "The United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait, and Tunisia today. Our thoughts and prayers are with the victims of these heinous attacks, their loved ones, and the people of all three countries. As the President has discussed with his French, Kuwaiti, and Tunisian counterparts in recent weeks, we are resolute and united in our shared effort to fight the scourge of terrorism.
We stand with these nations as they respond to attacks on their soil today, and we have been in contact with appropriate counterparts in all three countries to offer any necessary support. Terrorism has no place in any society, and the United States will continue to work closely with our international partners to combat terrorist actors and counter violent extremism around the globe."
Get real-time updates as this story unfolds. To start, just "star" this story in ABC News' phone app. Download ABC News for iPhone here or ABC News for Android here .
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32046785.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 01:55:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi Pilot Identified in Arizona F-16 Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/arizona-16-fighter-jet-crash-iraqi-pilot-identified/story?id=32062379</Link>
        <Description>The fighter jet crashed during a training mission on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow @JustinFishelABC
In this May 15, 2015, file photo, a boneyard crew tows an F-16 Fighting Falcon aircraft prior at Davis-Monthan Air Force Base in Tucson, Ariz. Military officials confirm a single F-16 Fighting Falcon aircraft crashed Wednesday night, June 24, 2015, about 5 miles east of Douglas Municipal Airport.
Matt York/AP Photo
The Iraqi pilot who was killed when his F-16 fighter jet crashed in Arizona during a night time training mission Wednesday has been identified as Brigadier General Rasid Mohammed Sadiq, a U.S. official said today.
"Today is a is a sad day for this brave heros family, his colleagues and friends, the Iraqi people, and their American allies," U.S. Ambassador to Iraq Stuart Jones said in a statement.
How the US Government Is Training Wounded Warriors to Hunt Child Predators
The F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed during a training mission at about 8 p.m. on Wednesday near Douglas, Arizona, with one person on board, according the 162nd Wing of the Arizona Air National Guard. The cause of the crash is still under investigation, authorities said.
The Iraqi military purchased 36 F-16's from the U.S., a number of which Iraqi pilot are being trained on in Arizona, officials said. None of the aircraft have been delivered to Iraq yet, but the first shipment is expected this summer.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32062379.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:18:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Person Found Decapitated in France Terror Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/france-terror-attack-decapitated-head-suspects-boss-found/story?id=32044062</Link>
        <Description>The man who is believed to have decapitated his boss and caused an explosion at an American-owned factory in France was let in because he regularly made deliveries.</Description>
        <MainBody>Victims of the Charlie Hebdo Massacre
A nearby camera recorded the vehicle accelerating toward a covered hangar at 9:35 a.m. and an explosion was heard a minute later.
Firefighters who were practicing nearby arrived at the scene quickly but did not find the suspect until about 10 a.m. when he was in a second hangar where there were gas canisters, acetone and liquid air, Molins said.
The decapitated body was found in the front seat of the truck along with a knife that is now being analyzed. The head of the victim was found pitched on a fence surrounding the factory with two flags with a Muslim profession of faith written across them.
The investigation into the attack is ongoing and among the primary questions for police are when and where the body was decapitated, including whether it was after death.
Laurent Cipriani/AP Photo
PHOTO: Police officers investigate next to the enclosed area near the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
The suspect did not identify himself to the firefighters but the employees were able to identify him, Molins said.
He has since been identified as Yassine Salhi and was taken into custody, French Minister of Interior Bernard Cazeneuve said earlier today. The suspect has no criminal record but was the subject of a Fiche S designation  for security of the state  in 2006 because of suspected radicalization, Cazeneuve said. That status was not renewed in 2008.
Cazeneuve said Salhi is originally from Saint-Priest, Lyon, which is about 12 miles away from Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the site of the factory.
The victims name has not been released but Molins said he was the 54-year-old owner of the transportation company where Salhi has worked since March.
In addition to Salhi, three others have been arrested in connection to the case: his wife of 10 years, his sister and another associate. Their names have not been publicly released.
Philippe Desmaze/AFP/Getty Images
PHOTO: French security stand next to the enclosed area near the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
French President Francois Hollande said here were inscriptions on the body.
"It is a terrorist attack, there is no doubt about that, Hollande said from Brussels, where he is attending an EU summit.
The attack took place on the grounds of a factory owned by Pennsylvania-based Air Products &amp; Chemicals, which produces industrial gases and says its the worlds leading supplier of helium.
"We can confirm that an incident occurred at our facility in L'Isle-d'Abeau, France this morning. Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for, the company said. Emergency services are on site and have contained the situation. The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities. Further information will be released as soon as it becomes available."
At least 17 people have been killed in terror-related violence in France this year. In January, gunmen attacked the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo. The men suspected in that attack were later killed in raids at a Kosher supermarket and print shop.
Last September, in a 42-minute video address, ISIS spokesman Abu Muhammad al-Adnani urged Muslims around the globe to target, specifically, the "spiteful and filthy" French.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
PHOTO: French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
A senior U.S. intelligence official told ABC News that the timing of today's attack is not necessarily tied to the Muslim religious period of Ramadan.
"It is fair to say that there has been a heightened awareness in general for the homeland, but have not seen it tied to Ramadan," the official said. "Overseas, ISIL has referenced Ramadan, however."
White House press secretary Josh Earnest released a statement today about the three attacks.
"The United States condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in France, Kuwait, and Tunisia today. Our thoughts and prayers are with the victims of these heinous attacks, their loved ones, and the people of all three countries," the statement read.
"As the President has discussed with his French, Kuwaiti, and Tunisian counterparts in recent weeks, we are resolute and united in our shared effort to fight the scourge of terrorism.
ABC News' Joseph Simonetti and The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Get real-time updates as this story unfolds. To start, just "star" this story in ABC News' phone app. Download ABC News for iPhone here or ABC News for Android here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:17:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Photos:  Terrorist Attacks Rock Three Countries</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/photos/apparent-terrorist-attack-france-factory-32045039</Link>
        <Description>Separate attacks in Kuwait, France and Tunisia leave dozens dead. </Description>
        <MainBody>Terrorist Attacks Rock Three Countries
+

The bodies of people are seen after an armed attack on a tourist hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, left at least 27 people dead, including foreigners, and injured six others , on June 26, 2015.
Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
The bodies of people are seen after an armed attack on a tourist hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, left at least 27 people dead, including foreigners, and injured six others , on June 26, 2015.
Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
Tunisian police officers stay in the lobby of an hotel where a terrorist attack took place in the coastal town of Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015. An attack that killed at least 28 people at a Tunisian beach resort was one of three deadly attacks from Europe to the Middle East.
Leila Khemissi/AP Photo
A body lays on a stretcher near a Tunisian beach, Sousse, June 26, 2015. An attack that killed at least 28 people occurred at a Tunisian beach resort, one of three deadly attacks from Europe to the Middle East.
Jawhara FM via AP Photo
A body lies on a street in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
EPA
Security measures are taken after an armed attack on a tourist hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, left at least 27 people dead, including foreigners, and injured six others , on June 26, 2015.
Anadolu Agency/Getty Images
An injured man is helped following a blast at Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City, Kuwait, June 26, 2015.
EPA
Kuwaiti worshippers react following a blast at Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, Kuwait City, Kuwait, June 26, 2015.
EPA
Kuwaiti men and a security member inspect the scene outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was attacked during Friday prayers, June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
AFP/Getty Images
Kuwaiti men accompany a man with blood-stained clothes at the site of the attack at the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque during Friday prayers, June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
AFP/Getty Images
Kuwaiti man reacts following an attack at the Imam Sadiq Mosque in the Sawaber area of Kuwait City on June 26, 2015.
Getty Images
People gather outside the Imam Sadiq Mosque following an attack in Kuwait city, June 26, 2015.
Noufal Ibrahim/Newscom
French police and firefighters secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Julien Reunaud/APS-Medias/Sipa USA/AP Photo
French security stand next to the enclosed area near the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmaze/AFP/Getty Images
French President Francois Hollande speaks during a media conference at an EU summit in Brussels, June 26, 2015.
Geert Vanden Wijngaert/AP Photo
French police and firefighters gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, June 26, 2015.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:43:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sochi Inundated by Flooding After Torrential Rains</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/sochi-russia-inundated-flooding-months-rain-falls-day/story?id=32032427</Link>
        <Description>The Olympic city of Sochi was inundated with flood waters after torrential rains.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sochi, Russia Inundated by Flooding After More Than a Month's Rain Falls in a Day
Moscow  Jun 25, 2015, 4:39 PM ET
By PATRICK REEVELL
Sochi, Russia on the Black Sea.
Getty Images
Heavy rains have flooded Sochi, the Russian city that hosted the 2014 Winter Olympics , leaving one dead and some areas under several feet of water, according to officials and reports. It is also forcing authorities to consider an evacuation, the mayor's office said.
More than a month and a halfs rain -- 100 mm, or about 4 inches -- fell in 24 hours on the seaside city, according to the Russian news agency RIA Novosti. Despite now being best-known for the Winter Olympics, the city is a popular summer resort for Russians, squeezed between the Caucasus mountains and the Black Sea .
According to the AP, a man was found dead during salvage operations Thursday. No further details were immediately available.
Sochi Airport! Hot, cool, yours! https://t.co/5FG1eo0K7b pic.twitter.com/M1b6z8aGMd
 Maria Antonova (@mashant) June 25, 2015
Pictures on social media showed Sochis airport, refurbished for the Olympics, filled with brown water, with passengers standing next to baggage carousels up to their ankles. The citys mayor has told residents to prepare for a possible evacuation and to remain indoors, warning that water spouts could form offshore.
????? ?? ????????? ????????? #???? #???????????
A video posted by @shpakovev on Jun 25, 2015 at 3:36am PDT
Sochi and its Olympic reconstruction is one of Vladimir Putin s prized achievements, with a colossal $50 billion spent on transforming the city. So far most of the sports facilities built for the Olympics have reportedly been undamaged by the floods, according to Russian media, with most of the flooding confined to residential areas.
#????? #?????? #?????????? #????#?????#????? #????????? #?????
A photo posted by alesya1502 (@alesya1502) on Jun 25, 2015 at 5:26am PDT
#????? #???? #?????????? #?????#?????? #????? #????? #?????????
A photo posted by alesya1502 (@alesya1502) on Jun 25, 2015 at 5:25am PDT
????, ????? ????????? ????#????#?????#????#?????????
A video posted by ??????? (@hibushkaaa) on Jun 25, 2015 at 3:30am PDT
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32032427.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:43:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UberPop Banned After Taxi Driver Protests Turn Ugly</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/uberpop-banned-paris-amid-taxi-driver-protests-airports/story?id=32017565</Link>
        <Description>Paris officials announced a ban on UberPop after about 2,800 taxi drivers staged a strike across France today in  protest of the  ride-hailing app.</Description>
        <MainBody>UberPop Banned in Paris Amid Taxi Driver Protests at Airports
PARIS  Jun 25, 2015, 3:39 PM ET
By HUGO LEENHARDT via Good Morning America
Taxi drivers on strike burn tires during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Marseille, France, June 25, 2015.
Jean-Paul Pelissier/Reuters
Paris officials announced a ban on UberPop after about 2,800 taxi drivers staged a strike across France today in protest of the ride-hailing app that resulted in numerous arrests and injured cops.
The taxi drivers briefly blocking access to airports and forced passengers to finish the journey by foot.
Some drivers vandalized several Uber cars, even flipping some over, and riot police were forced to intervene, arresting three taxi cab drivers, according to police officials.
Charles Platiau/Reuters
PHOTO: French taxi drivers, who are on strike, block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, June 25, 2015.
How Uber Helped a Recent Grad in Texas Plan an Epic Marriage Proposal
The demonstration was organized to protest against UberPop, the service that connects customers to drivers without professional taxi or chauffeur licenses. These drivers use their private vehicles to pick up clients, and UberPop is usually a second job for them.
Prices for the UberPop version of the Uber app are generally 30 to 50 percent cheaper than cab fares and drivers pay far less taxes.
The UberPop service had already been deemed illegal by the French government that accuses it of unfair competition, though the Uber app has not been officially banned. And today's action does not mean UberPop, and other services like it, will disappear but that police can arrest drivers in Paris and its suburbs using it, and also fine clients. But the thinking is that it will be difficult to enforce.
Michel Euler/AP Photo
PHOTO: Taxis gather at a major entrance of Paris, June 25, 2015, in Paris.
Thibaud Simphal, director of Uber France, said on French TV BFM Business that the company will challenge the "prefectoral order." "We will challenge it and see what comes out of the appeal, Uberpop can continue," Simphal said.
In the middle of the strike today, customers were taken hostage by the conflict. Musician Courtney Love , on her way to Paris from the airport, tweeted: they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
The Interior minister announced that 10 people had been arrested and seven police officers injured, in addition to the 70 cars vandalized during the day.
One of them appears to be shown in this YouTube video where a man on an overpass sends a rock crashing down on the windshield at Porte Maillot on the west side of Paris, where taxi drivers were demonstrating all day.
Also, an Uber car transporting a couple and its baby was hit by a rock on the way to the airport, breaking the rear window. "It was very scary," the passenger told French TV station iTele , but no one was injured.
Uber had warned earlier in the day that "demand will be very high today and the service could be disturbed. Good luck to all."
At Orly airport, an Uber driver reportedly ran over a cabbie who was blocking off his car, injuring him. He has been taken into custody.
Reacting to the clashes, Prime Minister Manuel Valls "condems with great severity" this "unacceptable" violence regarding today's events, he said.
Michel Euler/AP Photo
PHOTO: Striking taxi drivers stand behind an overthrown car during a taxi drivers demonstration, June 25, 2015, in Paris.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32017565.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:54:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mom and Baby Survived 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/mother-baby-rescued-surviving-days-colombian-jungle-plane/story?id=32028463</Link>
        <Description>Marie Nelly Murillo and her baby were rescued after they spent almost days stranded in the middle of a jungle following a small plane crash, the Colombia Air Force said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother and Baby Rescued After Surviving 5 Days in Colombian Jungle Following Plane Crash
Jun 25, 2015, 2:44 PM ET
The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
fac.mil.co
Copy
An 18-year-old woman and her baby miraculously survived a small plane crash in the Colombian jungle and then survived five days on coconut water before rescuers finally located them, according to officials and reports.
Colombian airmen and disaster relief agency workers discovered the mother, Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son Wednesday after five days of search and rescue efforts that immediately began when their plane was reported missing Saturday, the Colombian Air Force said today in a statement.
"It's a miracle. It is a very wild area and it was a catastrophic accident," Colombian Air Force Col. Hector Carrascal told the BBC. He added the mother's spirit must have given the baby "the strength to survive."
Nepal Earthquake: Teen Rescued After 5 Days Trapped in Rubble
Murillo, 18, suffered injuries and minor burns, but the baby was apparently unharmed, the Air Force said. They were flown in a helicopter to a hospital in Quibdo, Colombia .
The pilot of the small plane, a Cessna 303, was discovered dead on Monday before the mother and her baby were found, according to the Air Force. It was not clear what the relationship between the woman and baby and the pilot was or why they were on the plane.
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
Murillo, 18, and her son were passengers in the small plane, which was carrying fish and coconuts from the town of Nuqui to Quibdo, the the BBC reported .
A trail of clues including coconut shells discovered near the plane site and a discarded flip-flop in the jungle gave the rescue teams hope during the nearly week-long search that ended Wednesday, the BBC added.
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
Murillo wandered in the jungle carrying her child, surviving on coconut water and trying unsuccessfully to trap rodents for food, Red Cross volunteer Acisclo Renteria told The Associated Press (AP).
fac.mil.co
PHOTO: The Colombian Air Force rescued Marie Nelly Murillo and her one-year-old son on June 25, 2015 from a jungle where they were stranded for five days after a plane crash.
The 38-year-old rescuer said he saw the success as a blessing, the AP added.
"I thanked my little God for allowing me to save these two people," Renteria, who has been asked by Murillo to be her son's godfather, told the AP. "One thing is telling you on the phone what we experienced but it's quite another is to have lived it."
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32028463.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 00:10:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi F-16 Fighter Jet Crashes in Arizona</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/iraqi-16-fighter-jet-crashes-arizona-training-mission/story?id=32024137</Link>
        <Description>Iraqi pilots are being training in the U.S. to combat ISIS, officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy
The F-16 fighter jet that crashed in Arizona overnight was actually owned by the Iraqi Air Force and flown by an Iraqi pilot, a U.S. Air Force official confirmed to ABC News today.
Local law enforcement has been on the scene since the crash last night near Douglas, Arizona, but Air Force officials have yet to confirmed the identity of the pilot, who they say is an Iraqi trainee. The crash caused a large grass fire and its likely the pilot did not survive, authorities said.
Officially, the Air Force is saying only that the pilots status is unknown.
Mamta Popat/The Tucson Citizen/AP
PHOTO: Smoke rises Thursday, June 25, 2015, from the site where an F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed Wednesday evening near Douglas, Ariz.
The Iraqi military is involved in a program to train Iraqi Air Force pilots in the United States before it receives the jets in Iraq. The first two of 36 jets purchased by the Iraqi government arrived at the Tucson International Airport, Arizona this December, where Iraqi pilots are training, officials said.
The F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed during a training mission at about 8 p.m. on Wednesday near Douglas, Arizona, with one person on board, the 162nd Wing of the Arizona Air National Guard said in statement.
Mamta Popat/The Tucson Citizen/AP
PHOTO: Cochise County Sheriff blocks the road on June 25, 2015, miles away from the site where an F-16 Fighting Falcon crashed near Douglas, Ariz.
The 162nd in responsible for the international training mission, which the Iraqis are depending on to combat the militant group ISIS .
Iraq has received a total of 12 brand new F-16s, all of which are currently in the U.S. The first delivery of the jets to Iraq is expected this summer.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32024137.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:49:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank Refuses to Increase Credit for Greece</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/greece-awaits-european-central-bank-decision-liquidity-32080639</Link>
        <Description>ECB refuses to increase credit lifeline for Greek banks after referendum call by PM Tsipras</Description>
        <MainBody>European Central Bank Refuses to Increase Credit for Greece
ATHENS, Greece  Jun 28, 2015, 9:48 AM ET
By ELENA BECATOROS and DAVID McHUGH Associated Press
The European Central Bank refused to increase emergency credit to Greek banks on Sunday, a day after the government threw Greece's bailout negotiations into turmoil by calling a referendum on creditors' financial proposals.
The central bank's decision  seen treading a narrow middle ground that could keep the bailout talks going  left Greece's banks under increasing pressure since they are seeing deposits drain away.
Anxious Greeks lining up at ATMs all weekend, worried about the possibility of financial controls being imposed to stop banks from hemorrhaging funds. Those fears are driven by the fact Greece's international bailout runs out Tuesday and it needs the last tranche of those funds to pay some $1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to the International Monetary Fund on the same day.
The developments have thrown Greece's financial future and its continued membership in the 19-nation shared euro currency into question.
The ECB said it could reconsider its decision on credit levels.
"We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of member states in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies," ECB chief Mario Draghi said.
Yannis Stournaras, governor of the Bank of Greece, said the bank would "take all measures necessary to ensure financial stability for Greek citizens in these difficult circumstances."
The Greek finance ministry said the country's financial stability council, the Systemic Risk Board, would meet Sunday afternoon to discuss the situation. The board is a seven-member body that includes the finance minister, the central bank governor and the heads of the Greek banks association, the capital markets commission and the financial stability fund.
Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis meanwhile, tweeted that the government "opposes the very concept" of capital controls within a monetary union. He also suggested that his country might not pay the money it owes to the IMF on Tuesday.
Varoufakis refused to reply to a direct question Sunday on the IMF payment. Instead, he told BBC radio that the ECB should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014, an idea he called "a very sensible transfer."
"We are owed money by one part of the troika and we owe money to another part of the troika? Why don't they sort themselves out and transfer money from one pocket ... to the other?" Varoufakis said.
Greek Prime Minister Alexia Tsipras' move for a national vote next Sunday on the creditors' financial proposals startled and angered Greece's European partners, who said they would not accept an extension of the current bailout, which expires Tuesday. Parliament approved the referendum call in a majority vote early Sunday.
France's prime minister, meanwhile, urged all in Europe to do everything they could to keep Greece in the eurozone.
"We don't know  none of us  the consequences of an exit from the euro zone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the euro zone," French Prime Minister Manuel Valls told France's i-Tele TV.
"But doing everything, that means respecting Greece and democracy, but it's also about respecting European rules. So Greece needs to come back to the negotiating table."

McHugh reported from Frankfurt. Geir Moulson in Berlin, Jamey Keaten in Paris and Demetris Nellas in Athens contributed.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080639.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:41:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Minister: 3 Irish Among Dead in Tunisia Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-tunisia-puts-1000-extra-police-tourist-sites-32080204</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Minister: Authorities confirm Irish couple among 38 dead in Tunisia beach attack</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Minister: 3 Irish Among Dead in Tunisia Attack
TUNIS, Tunisia  Jun 28, 2015, 9:40 AM ET
A young woman lays flowers at the scene of a shooting in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The morning after a lone gunman killed at tens of people at a beach resort in Tunisia, busloads of tourists are heading to the nearby Enfidha-Hammamet airport hoping to return to their home countries. (AP Photo/Darko Vojinovic)
The Associated Press
The latest developments on the attack that killed 38 tourists on a beach in Tunisia :

2:30 p.m.
Ireland's foreign affairs minister says an Irish couple missing since Friday's gun attack at a Tunisian beach resort is among the dead.
Charlie Flanagan didn't confirm the pair's names, but they were identified locally as Laurence and Martina Hayes, both reportedly in their 50s.
Sunday's announcement brings the number of Irish victims to three.
An Irish mother-of-two, Lorna Carty, was earlier confirmed as a victim of Friday's attack on the Sousse beach resort in Tunisia.
A total of 38 tourists were killed when a student armed with a Kalashnikov and grenades opened fire at the resort in Sousse.

1:50 p.m.
Britain's home secretary says the number of Britons confirmed killed in the Tunisia beach resort attack is expected to rise.
Theresa May told reporters that the confirmed figure remained at 15, but "we should expect that that number is going to rise."
The Britons were among the 38 people killed at the Sousse resort Friday, and authorities are still working to determine the identities of all the dead.
Tunisian authorities have said victims were from Britain, Germany, Ireland, Belgium and Portugal, and no Tunisians were killed.

1:40 p.m.
The owner of a Tunisian resort hotel insists there was no security breakdown during an attack by a gunman with alleged ties to the extremist Islamic State group who killed at least 38 tourists in Soussa, because "unfortunately the hotel security (guards) are not armed.
Zohra Idriss of Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba says it has five or six guards on the sandy beach.
"How can they defend themselves against someone who has a Kalashnikov and who is killing them?" Idriss said. "They tried to beat him with chairs, with the vases of flowers but it was impossible. It was all very, very quick."

12:05 p.m.
A major German tour operator says around 250 of its customers have chosen to return early from their vacations in Tunisia after the attack on tourists but most people visiting the country  around 3,500  are staying on.
After Friday's attack on a beach in Sousse, tour operator TUI offered free cancelations or re-bookings for customers who had reserved vacations in Tunisia through Sept. 15. It said it had received about 500 calls by Sunday from people taking up that offer, and that Spain's Canary Islands, Turkey and Egypt topped the list of alternative destinations that their customers chose.
One German has been confirmed dead and another injured in the attack Friday on a beach resort. Thirty-eight people were killed in Tunisia's worst terrorist attack.

10:10 a.m.
Britain's Foreign Office has updated its travel advice to Tunisia, urging vigilance and warning that further terrorist attacks in the North African nation's tourist resorts are possible.
The ministry is warning Sunday against all travel to Tunisia's militarized southern zone, all travel anywhere within 5 kilometers (3 miles) of Tunisia's border with Libya and all travel to the country's Chaambi Mountain national park area.
It also advised against all but essential travel to much of Tunisia's south and along its western border with Algeria .
The ministry says possible attacks could stem from "individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:45:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Young Soccer Player, Blogger Among Those Killed in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/young-soccer-player-blogger-killed-tunisia-32082082</Link>
        <Description>British families, friends mourn loss of loved ones in Tunisia beach attack</Description>
        <MainBody>Young Soccer Player, Blogger Among Those Killed in Tunisia
LONDON  Jun 28, 2015, 9:28 AM ET
By SYLVIA HUI Associated Press
Three men from the same British family, a recently engaged lifestyle blogger and a couple whose children launched a desperate social media campaign to find them were among those feared killed in the Tunisian beach attack.
Britain's government says at least 15 Britons were among the 38 killed when a university student opened fire Friday at the Sousse beach resort. Officials haven't officially confirmed the names of the victims, but families and friends have released details of those killed to British media. Other families were still fearing the worst Sunday.
Tunisian authorities have said other victims include people from Germany, Ireland, Belgium and Portugal .
Here is a look at some of those believed killed:

Joel Richards, a 19-year-old student and active soccer player, was reportedly killed along with his uncle, Adrian Evans, as well as his grandfather, 78-year-old Charles Evans. All three were keen soccer fans who were holidaying together at the beach.
"A young, talented referee with the world at his feet. He was highly thought of and will be sadly missed," Ian Murphy of the Birmingham County Football Association said of Richards. "He was such a talented lad," he added to Sky News.
Another Birmingham-based club, James Connolly's GFC, said Richards was an "exceptionally talented footballer" who represented his club and county on numerous occasions.
Joel's 16-year-old brother, Owen, who was also at the beach, reportedly fled the scene, surviving a bullet wound to his shoulder.
A local council paid tribute to Adrian Evans, 49, described as a popular and long-serving employee who managed gas services.

Carly Lovett, 24, was a budding lifestyle blogger on holiday with her fiance Liam Moore.
Lovett, a University of Lincoln graduate and a photographer, had just recently launched a blog sharing her love for beauty products.
The university's school of film and media confirmed Lovett graduated in 2013, and tweeted it was saddened to hear news reports about her.
As friends and fellow bloggers paid tribute to her on social media, a poignant message Lovett wrote on Wednesday is still on Twitter: "Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing..."
Her fiance was reportedly traveling home.

Like others, 23-year-old Conor Fulford turned to social media for help when he became increasingly worried about his missing mother Sue Davey, 44.
Fulford, who thought he may have seen his mother on television as she was being taken away on a stretcher, repeatedly tweeted pleas for information.
So did Ross Nayler, whose father, 42-year-old Scott Chaulkley, was on holiday in Tunisia together with Davey.
"I'm checking Twitter and all the other social media just for anything really, just for any update," Nayler told ITV News.
But by Saturday night, both sons learned the truth. Fulford wrote: "Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight." He added: "Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight. Rest easy."
Severn Trent Water, where Davey and Chaulkley worked, paid tribute to the pair Sunday. "Sue and Scott had a passion to help others however they could, they cared enormously for all those they worked with and were totally committed to our customers and our company," the company said in a statement.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32082082.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:17:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Greek Minister Hints No Payment Tuesday to IMF</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-greece-ecb-giving-emergency-32080338</Link>
        <Description>The Latest: Minister suggests Greece may not pay $1.6 billion euros it owes Tuesday to IMF</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Greek Minister Hints No Payment Tuesday to IMF
ATHENS, Greece  Jun 28, 2015, 9:16 AM ET
The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations (all times local):

4:10 p.m.
Greece's finance minister is suggesting that his country might not pay the 1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis refused to reply to a direct question Sunday on the payment. Instead, he told BBC radio that the European Central Bank should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014. Varoufakis calls that idea "a very sensible transfer."
Asked directly, for the second time, whether Greece will pay up Tuesday, Varoufakis replies: "We are owed money by one part of the troika and we owe money to another part of the troika? Why don't they sort themselves out and transfer money from one pocket ... to the other?"

3:35 p.m.
The European Central Bank has announced it is maintaining emergency credit to Greek banks at its current level.
The decision keeps a key financial lifeline open but does not provide further credit to Greece's banks, which are seeing deposits drain away as anxious Greeks withdraw savings.
The ECB said it was working closely with the Bank of Greece to maintain financial stability and added it could reconsider the decision on credit levels.
ECB head Mario Draghi said "we continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies."

3:20 p.m.
France's prime minister is urging Greece and other nations to do whatever they can to keep Greece in the 19-nation bloc that uses the euro currency.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said Sunday that "we don't know  none of us  the consequences of an exit from the eurozone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the eurozone." He was speaking on France's i-Tele TV.
Valls added that "means respecting Greece and democracy, but it's also about respecting European rules. So Greece needs to come back to the negotiating table."
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' call for a national referendum on creditors' demands has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil.

2:35 p.m.
Germany's Foreign Ministry is advising travelers to Greece to ensure they have enough cash on them before they depart.
An updated version of the ministry's travel advice issued Sunday noted that people seeking to withdraw cash in Greece could face "significant waits" and possible shortages at cash machines.
Worried Greeks were lining up at ATM machines on Sunday, the day after the Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for a referendum on creditors' financial proposals in return for rescue loans and creditors refused to extend Greece's international bailout beyond Tuesday.
While some machines in Greece were running out of cash, others were being replenished. Another top Greek financial official urged Greeks on Sunday to remain calm and not withdraw all their savings.

The European Central Bank faces a major decision.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:17:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait Names Saudi Man as Suicide Bomber in Mosque Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/kuwait-saudi-citizen-deadly-suicide-bombing-32080439</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait names Saudi citizen as bomber in deadly Shiite mosque attack, says he flew in at dawn</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait Names Saudi Man as Suicide Bomber in Mosque Attack
KUWAIT CITY  Jun 28, 2015, 9:16 AM ET
By HUSSAIN AL-QATARI Associated Press
Kuwaiti authorities on Sunday identified the suicide bomber behind an attack on a Shiite mosque that killed 27 people as a Saudi citizen who flew into the Gulf nation just hours before blowing himself up.
Police have begun making arrests in connection with Friday's bombing, which took place at one of Kuwait's oldest Shiite mosques during midday prayers. An affiliate of the Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for the blast in the normally peaceful oil-rich nation.
The Interior Ministry named the bomber as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa and said he was born in 1992, making him 22 or 23 years old. It said in a statement carried by the official Kuwait News Agency that he arrived on a flight to Kuwait International Airport at dawn Friday.
Authorities also said they arrested a 25-year-old from Kuwait's "bidoon" community, identified as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, who they say drove the car that brought the bomber to the mosque.
The bidoon community is made up of descendants of desert nomads and others considered stateless by the government. They have long claimed the government deprives them of citizenship and rights.
A Kuwaiti man who housed the driver was also taken into custody. The Interior Ministry described him as a follower of a "fundamentalist and deviant ideology."
The government-linked Al-Jarida newspaper reported that at least seven suspects had been detained in connection with the attack, which has drawn condemnation from Sunni groups in Kuwait and leaders from across the Middle East .
Officials say 227 people were wounded in the attack.
A local affiliate of the Islamic State group calling itself the Najd Province has claimed responsibility for the bombing. The IS group considers Shiites to be heretics and is fighting Iranian-backed Shiite militias in Iraq and Syria .
More than a third of Kuwait's 1.2 million citizens are believed to be Shiite.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080439.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:51:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moldovans Choose Between Russia, Europe in Local Elections</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/moldova-chooses-russia-europe-local-elections-32079459</Link>
        <Description>Moldovans hold local vote seen as a test whether country will move closer to Europe or Russia</Description>
        <MainBody>Moldovans Choose Between Russia, Europe in Local Elections
CHISINAU, Moldova  Jun 28, 2015, 8:49 AM ET
By CORNELIU RUSNAC Associated Press
Moldovans voted Sunday in local election runoffs being seen as a test of whether the former Soviet republic moves closer to the European Union or to neighboring Russia.
The key post is for the next mayor of Chisinau, the capital, where pro-European incumbent Dorin Chirtoaca faces pro-Russian challenger Zinaida Greceanai, a former prime minister of the Communist Party. A low turnout in the city of one million will benefit the 59-year-old Greceanai.
"I hope we will clarify things.... and build something that is certain, definitive, irreversible, for the future of Chisinau and Moldova ," Chirtoaca said after voting.
"Residents have a great desire to see deeds and not just statements," said Greceanai.
Runoffs were being held in 458 towns in this country of 4 million and result were expected late Sunday. Some 348 seats were already decided in the first round.
Renato Usatii, a pro-Russian businessman, won outright on June 14 in Moldova's second-largest city, Balti, and pro-Russian businessman Ilan Shor won in the eastern town of Orhei.
Moldova, which declared independence in 1991 after the Soviet Union broke up, is located between Romania and Ukraine. Last year, it signed an association agreement with the 28-nation EU, angering Russia, which then banned some of its fruits and vegetables, hurting the largely agricultural nation.
Moldova's currency has lost 20 percent of its value this year against the euro.
Moldova is one of the poorest nations in Europe with an average monthly salary of $250. Some 600,000 Moldovans work abroad and send remittances home, which make up 30 percent of the country's Gross Domestic Product.
Moldovan officials, meanwhile, have been investigating the disappearance of $1.5 billion from state-owned and private banks before the parliamentary election last November, and Shor is being investigated in that probe.

Alison Mutler in Bucharest, Romania contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32079459.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:37:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds Still in Hospital After Fire at Taiwan Music Party</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/hundreds-hospital-fire-taiwan-music-party-32080438</Link>
        <Description>Fire sparked by an accidental explosion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds Still in Hospital After Fire at Taiwan Music Party
TAIPEI, Taiwan  Jun 28, 2015, 8:37 AM ET
By RALPH JENNINGS Associated Press
Rescue workers tend to injured people at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City on June 27, 2015.
STR/AFP/Getty Images
More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.
The fire late Saturday was sparked by an accidental explosion of a colored theatrical powder thrown from the stage in front of about 1,000 people, the local fire agency and media said. The powder for the one-time event called "Color Play Asia" ignited along the ground, mainly burning people's lower bodies, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
The exact cause of the fire was still being investigated, but Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo banned public activities that use the colored powder.
A total of 519 people were injured by the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, according to a statement from the city government's health bureau. It said that 419 remained hospitalized on Sunday afternoon, about half of whom were seriously injured, including 184 in intensive care. Apart from Taiwanese, the victims were four people from Hong Kong , two from the Chinese mainland and one each from Macau, Japan, Malaysia and Singapore. The nationalities of three other foreigners were not given.
President Ma Ying-jeou visited burns victims at a hospital in Taipei on Sunday afternoon and said authorities would do their best to ensure victims receive "the best medical care" and find out who was responsible for the "tragic incident."
Taiwan's Central News Agency said that police were questioning two park workers who had launched the powder as well as the party's on-site organizer and two technicians. They may face charges of professional negligence causing serious injuries and endangering the public, it said.

AP writer Louise Watt in Beijing contributed to this report.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080438.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:32:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank Maintains Emergency Credit to Greek Banks at Current Level</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/european-central-bank-maintains-emergency-credit-greek-banks-32081113</Link>
        <Description>European Central Bank maintains emergency credit to Greek banks at current level</Description>
        <MainBody>European Central Bank Maintains Emergency Credit to Greek Banks at Current Level
FRANKFURT, Germany  Jun 28, 2015, 8:31 AM ET
European Central Bank maintains emergency credit to Greek banks at current level.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32081113.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:06:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan Official: IS Group Present in at Least 3 Provinces</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/afghan-official-group-present-provinces-32080978</Link>
        <Description>Afghan official: Islamic State group now present in 3 provinces</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan Official: IS Group Present in at Least 3 Provinces
KABUL, Afghanistan  Jun 28, 2015, 8:06 AM ET
An Afghan official says the Islamic State group now has a presence in three provinces but that the government is determined to drive it out.
Zafar Hashimi, the Afghan president's deputy spokesman, said Sunday that the group  which controls large areas of Iraq and Syria  is active in the eastern Nangarhar, western Farah and southern Helmand provinces.
Hashimi says security forces have launched successful operations against the IS group but gave no further details.
The Taliban , which have been at war with the government for nearly 14 years and are also active in the three provinces, have warned the IS group to stay out of the country. Both groups want Islamic rule but the Taliban do not recognize the IS group's self-styled caliphate.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080978.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:23:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus Carrying British Children Crashes in Belgium; 1 Dead</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bus-carrying-british-schoolchildren-crashes-belgium-32080641</Link>
        <Description>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; 1 adult killed, others injured</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus Carrying British Children Crashes in Belgium; 1 Dead
BRUSSELS  Jun 28, 2015, 8:05 AM ET
Fire and rescue vehicles line a highway as they attend to a bus which crashed on a motorway in Middlekerke, Belgium on Sunday, June 28, 2015. The bus, carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, injuring the driver and some of the children and killing one of the adults accompanying them.
Geert Vanden Wijngaert/AP PHOTO
A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, killing one adult chaperone and injuring the driver and some of the children, officials said.
Belgian highway authorities said the vehicle apparently went out of control, struck a bridge pillar on the E40 highway, then shot off the road. The bus was carrying around 40 passengers, including 34 British children from 11 to 13 years old, authorities said.
The Belgian federal prosecutor's office said all of the children survived the accident, but an adult passenger had been killed. The bus driver was also seriously injured.
Three adults and some of the children were sent to a local hospital for treatment. Others were transported to a center in the coastal city of Middelkerke.
British authorities said they were aware of the crash and working with Belgian authorities to help the U.K. citizens.
The E-40 highway, a major thoroughfare that links Belgium 's North Sea coast to the capital city of Brussels, was closed to traffic following the crash.
-- This embed didnt make it to copy for story id = 32080641.
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:58:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/day-terror-attacks-shock-world-32052524</Link>
        <Description>Attacks across three continents spurred concerns over spreading jihadist influence.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Okay. I I'm. And. We're.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32052524,"title":"Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World","duration":"1:37","description":"Attacks across three continents spurred concerns over spreading jihadist influence.","url":"/International/video/day-terror-attacks-shock-world-32052524","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:03:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/israel-avoid-civilians-deadly-attack-32048883</Link>
        <Description>A recent Israeli military investigation called the incident a "tragic accident," claiming the target of the attack was a Hamas "compound," and mistook the young boys for militants.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Israeli military accuses Hamas of endangering civilians by launching attacks from crowded areas.
Now Playing: Benjamin Netanyahu: Hamas Committing 'Double War Crime'
Now Playing: Possible Images of Hamas Rockets Launched From School
Now Playing: Deadliest Day in Gaza as Airstrikes Kill More Than 100 People
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: ISIS in Mosul 1 Year Later
Now Playing: Meet the 8 Young Musicians of NYC's Harmony Program As They Take the Stage with the NY Philharmonic
Now Playing: Inside the Horse Barns at Belmont Park
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: How Music Helps Get One Girl Into One of NYC's Top Public Schools
Now Playing: A Day in the Life: Music Helps Change the Life of a Boy From an Underserved Community
Now Playing: The American Dream: Music Helps An Immigrant Mother's Wishes Come True for Her Daughter
Now Playing: Retaliation for Military Sexual Assault Reporting Rampant
Now Playing: Wildlife Parkgoers Defy Rules After Lion Kills American
Now Playing: First Look Inside the Dizzying Heights of the New World Trade Center
Now Playing: Watch: Texas Flash Flooding, May 2015
Now Playing: Here's The Military-Style Gear President Obama Banned Local Police From Using
Now Playing: Biker Gang Shootout Leaves 9 Dead in Texas
Now Playing: Moscow's Subway Is An Underground Palace
Now Playing: How 5 Possible White House Hopefuls Answered the Iraq Question
Now Playing: Mexican Girl Describes Being Taken From Family, Sent to Texas in Case of Mistaken Identity
Now Playing: Amtrak Crash: Demonstrating Positive Train Control
Now Playing: Watch Jeb Bush's Evolution on Iraq: 5 Answers in 4 Days
Now Playing: Blind Runner and Guide Survive Cancer, Find Friendship
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32048883,"title":"UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack","duration":"4:41","description":"A recent Israeli military investigation called the incident a \"tragic accident,\" claiming the target of the attack was a Hamas \"compound,\" and mistook the young boys for militants.","url":"/International/video/israel-avoid-civilians-deadly-attack-32048883","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:47:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/scotus-rules-favor-aca-foods-overcharging-customers-french-32035096</Link>
        <Description>The Supreme Court rules in favor of Affordable Care Act; Whole Foods found to be overcharging customers by exaggerating weight; French Alpine paraglider lands inside a moving cable car.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Because of this law and because of today's decision to millions of Americans. Who I hear from every single day we'll continue to receive the tax credits. We have given about eight in ten people who buy insurance on the new marketplace Schwartz of the health care plan would cost less than a hundred dollars a month. Arraignment today renewed our prisons are now taking charges tied to Shawshank style break out a written update. Officials saying corrections officer Jean Pollard admitted to passing then my backpack. To date context. Even gave him special classes as areas of the president. Never knew there GI. Where officials are banning over and similar services in an around Paris. That comes after protesters from angry taxi driver and got ugly throwing eggs at cars he. And blocking off access to the airport many writers. Forced to walk to catch their flights. Taxi drivers upset because over drivers don't have to pay the same taxes. Are to compete with Hoover's prices up. Murphy store chain whole foods with stores in 42 state. Under scrutiny after New York consumer affairs says there investigators from around the worst case of grocery mislabeling. They've ever seen investigator citing he's examples of a package of chicken tenders overpriced by nearly five dollars. His vegetable platter six dollars more than it should be credible. Video a couple of guys jump off a mountain in France terror gliding toward that cable car right there one of them flies. Way forward. Right inside. His buddies catch in the ovals all back up but they grab and I can save you had some experience that if there are easier ways let's get to write it. I doubt they are a number of up to the screen door and watch the cat has she leaves airing out the big that they are so shocking that this package falls off the porch. Maginnis has your head is usually it's scary cat but she hasn't seen their sins. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Millionaire Funds Rescue Missions to Save Migrants: Part 1
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32035096,"title":"SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car","duration":"2:10","description":"The Supreme Court rules in favor of Affordable Care Act; Whole Foods found to be overcharging customers by exaggerating weight; French Alpine paraglider lands inside a moving cable car.","url":"/International/video/scotus-rules-favor-aca-foods-overcharging-customers-french-32035096","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mother-baby-survive-days-jungle-plane-crash-32031301</Link>
        <Description>Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Also there and get a mother at a baby rescued days after their small plane goes down and a jungle the air force swooping in to help the to the crash happening over the weekend in Colombia. And search crews springing into action the first survey first found the body of the product and yesterday the mother and child were spotted. The mother had just minor injuries the baby fortunately was not hurt.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32031301,"title":"Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash","duration":"0:21","description":"Marie Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old child lived on coconut water until rescuers located them in the Colombian jungle.","url":"/International/video/mother-baby-survive-days-jungle-plane-crash-32031301","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:27:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bomber-apologizes-court-funeral-proceedings-begin-sc-32007812</Link>
        <Description>Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev speaks in court during sentencing; Funeral proceedings begin for victims of South Carolina shootings; Governor Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Boston Marathon bomber killed Arthur Bryant spoke in court for the first time today it is we'll send. I think he stated he was sorry for the irreparable damage that he costs and all of the suffering. That he caused and he left no doubt about his guilt I didn't do it's our night instead hold. Bad. His words were genuine. They were heart cells. And I hope that they were as honest as the statements that you received were from victims' survivors. Reaffirmed. The United States government. Make concessions for just. Cost us. I from the celebrated pastor and state senator being honored as the remains of the reverend Clementi asking me lying in proposing Columbia. A horse drawn carriage carrying the coffin to the steps of the state house there a public viewing taking place throughout the afternoon. And on Friday president Obama's scheduled to deliver the eulogy the lakes states. Hundreds of camps are second homes throughout the area. Continue to check these camps and secure them. We're out of time law enforcement officials in upstate New York giving an update on their church or she would date killers. Describing the rugged terrain surrounding a hunting camp where those men are last believed to beats. Another Republican throwing his hat into the presidential ring today the big announcement from Louisiana governor Bobby Jindal. Making him the thirteenth major GOP yeah. I'm conservative governance shrinking the size of government. Smart management this is this is the details and it's been a guy who's worked in the Health and Human Services Department served in congress briefly and has an idea driven governor. Management leadership those are the qualities will talk about. Finally a lot of people love going to outdoor festival during the summer the one drawback. Port of bodies except of course if you report a body has looked at this point. I mariachi band inside. I they had. That's infineon and let's mariachi band marching out of the port of hiding and that they don't have a whole lot marching bands that part. The looks on people's faces apple. Yeah.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32007812,"title":"Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid","duration":"2:17","description":"Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev speaks in court during sentencing; Funeral proceedings begin for victims of South Carolina shootings; Governor Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid.","url":"/International/video/boston-bomber-apologizes-court-funeral-proceedings-begin-sc-32007812","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:24:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy,  Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Tsarnaev: 'Sorry for the Lives I Have Taken'
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":32006748,"title":"Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms","duration":"0:42","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.24.15.","url":"/International/video/boston-bombing-survivor-walks-past-demonstrators-obama-announces-32006748","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 01:02:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/anti-confederate-flag-protest-columbia-sc-tornado-cleanup-31979425</Link>
        <Description>News photographs taken around the world on 6.23.15</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Tom Brady 'Deflategate' Appeal
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31979425,"title":"Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension","duration":"0:40","description":"News photographs taken around the world on 6.23.15","url":"/International/video/anti-confederate-flag-protest-columbia-sc-tornado-cleanup-31979425","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 22:13:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/giant-basking-shark-caught-australia-31974124</Link>
        <Description>The shark, just under 21 feet long, was caught off the west coast of Victoria, Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Transcript for Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
--
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31974124,"title":"Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia","duration":"1:44","description":"The shark, just under 21 feet long, was caught off the west coast of Victoria, Australia.","url":"/International/video/giant-basking-shark-caught-australia-31974124","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 00:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176</Link>
        <Description>Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related Videos
Video Transcript
Transcript for Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
And yeah. In New York fertility aid killer on the rise DNA evidence found at a campground where they are hiding out positively link Richard Matt and David sweat or we don't know obviously is how old you. An idea that they lived. In the way it's supposed to escape that jeers realist it's time to minutes to plant in the capital. South Carolina governor Eliot and pound cake along for support line. I stayed out. It's not just a matter. Did not being polite to stray. And public and that's not good measure of whether racism still exists or continent. President was discussing racism with the comedian mark Merritt for his WTF podcast and he was making a point about how our political record. And talents in this country scenes whitewashed fact that. The reasons why that we're being used in the first place has somehow been scrubbed clean because we start seeing that word pop. A grim discovery on a mountain in New Mexico searchers have located the body of the former White House chef Walter shine in a river near a trail where he'd gone hiking more than a week ago that shot but who cook for about the clintons and bushes had just recently moved. Two New Mexico. Forty million Americans in the capital dangerous storms including. Possible tornadoes target in Chicago and Detroit while much of the south is under water. I think there are busy in Southern California he wondered in the shade in the backyard for bed and Johnson won't happen cooling off we'll present them. We'll.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: Update on Escaped Prisoners
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for 2 Terror Attacks
Now Playing: Three Terror Attacks Around the World in One Day
Now Playing: Department of Homeland Security on High Alert
Now Playing: Day of Terror: Three Attacks Shock the World
Now Playing: ISIS Claims Responsibility for Mosque Bombing in Kuwait
Now Playing: Deadly Terror Attack at American Factory in France
Now Playing: UN Says Israel Did Too Little to Avoid Civilians in Deadly Attack
Now Playing: Man Decapitated in Gruesome Terror Attack in France
Now Playing: Daring Man Pulls Off Amazing Paragliding Stunt
Now Playing: SCOTUS Rules in Favor of ACA; Whole Foods Overcharging Customers; French Alpine Paraglider Lands Inside Cable Car
Now Playing: Mother and Baby Survive 5 Days in Jungle After Plane Crash
Now Playing: Boston Bomber Apologizes in Court; Funeral Proceedings Begin for S.C. Shooting Victims; Gov. Bobby Jindal Announces 2016 Presidential Bid
Now Playing: Boston Bombing Survivor Walks Past Demonstrators, Obama Announces Change to U.S. Hostage Policy, Atlanta Hawks Debut New Uniforms
Now Playing: Anti-Confederate Flag Protest in Columbia, SC, Tornado Cleanup In Illinois, Tom Brady Appeals NFL Suspension
Now Playing: Mysterious Face Discovered Etched on Canadian Cliff
Now Playing: Meet Blind Dog and His Canine Best Friend Who 'Acts as His Eyes'
Now Playing: Giant Basking Shark Caught in Australia
Now Playing: Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'
Now Playing: International HotSpot: Explosion Rocks Afghanistan Parliament
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31951176,"title":"Escaped Killers' DNA Found In Upstate New York Cabin, South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley Calls For The Removal Of The Confederate Flag From Capital Grounds, Obama Uses The 'N-Word'","duration":"1:43","description":"Former White House executive chef found dead in New Mexico, Rough weather sweeps across the south.","url":"/International/video/escaped-killers-dna-found-upstate-york-cabin-south-31951176","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 23:20:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Watch:  Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165</Link>
        <Description>Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Zero. That's emergency landing knees and that bully and Bloomberg. There. Oh. Now. I hope what. And running in regard him running new wave group. You know addicted to video now Mike is a quick. I.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
Now Playing: 10 Ducklings Rescued From Storm Drain
Now Playing: Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead
Now Playing: Coast Guard Rescues Endangered Turtle
Now Playing: Police Release Surveillance Video in Maryland Graffiti Spree
Now Playing: Eight-Foot Gator Makes Trapper Feel the Miami Heat
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Moment Homeless Man Attacks Teen in Target
Now Playing: Restaurant Employees Take Down Man Accused of Bomb Threat
Now Playing: Man's Rescue From Sinking Truck Caught on Tape
Now Playing: NY Toddler Survives Being Hit By Out-Of-Control Car
Now Playing: Dozens Push Double-Decker Bus Off Trapped Cyclist
Now Playing: Boaters' Frightful Near-Collision With Airplane Caught on Video
Now Playing: Man Crashes SUV Into Store to Steal Beer
Now Playing: Dramatic Video Shows Mount Everest Avalanche
Now Playing: Train Plummets Off Tracks in Dramatic Video
Now Playing: Man's 'Crazy' Encounter With Tornado Caught on Video
Now Playing: Nanny Cam Captures Powerful Home Boiler Explosion
Now Playing: Girl Attacked at McDonald's Caught on Video
Now Playing: Store Clerk Fights Off, Shoots Robber
Now Playing: Pilots Escape Mid-Air Collision at Air Show
Now Playing: {{itm.title}}
{"id":31948165,"title":"Mid-Air Plane Collision Leaves 2 People Dead","duration":"0:45","description":"Video shows the pilot of the second plane making an emergency landing after the fatal collision over Fort McMurray in Alberta, Canada.","url":"/International/video/mid-air-plane-collision-leaves-people-dead-31948165","section":"International","mediaType":"Default"}
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:40:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  WN 06/27/15: Controversy Over Confederate Flag Begins To Boil</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WNT/video/wn-062715-controversy-confederate-flag-begins-boil-32078829</Link>
        <Description>1,200 Officers Searching for Escaped Prisoner; The Resistance Against Same-Sex Marriage Already Underway. </Description>
        <MainBody>WN 06/27/15: Controversy Over Confederate Flag Begins To Boil
16:48 06/27/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:24:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  20/20 06/26/15:  'Reversal of Fortune'</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/2020/video/2020-062615-reversal-fortune-32068348</Link>
        <Description>Video Shows Vanderbilt Football Player Carrying Date Into Dorm; Vanderbilt Football Player Makes Stunning Admission at Trial for Rape; Vanderbilt Rape Trial Juror's Secret Leads to Mistrial</Description>
        <MainBody>20/20 06/26/15: 'Reversal of Fortune'
40:09 06/26/15 NR
Video Shows Vanderbilt Football Player Carrying Date Into Dorm; Vanderbilt Football Player Makes Stunning Admission at Trial for Rape; Vanderbilt Rape Trial Juror's Secret Leads to Mistrial
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:10:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  GMA 06/27/15: Gay Rights Triumph in Supreme Court Ruling</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/gma-062715-gay-rights-triumph-supreme-court-ruling-32072212</Link>
        <Description>Richard Matt Killed by Border Agents in New York; Quasi Modo Crowned World's Ugliest Dog</Description>
        <MainBody>GMA 06/27/15: Gay Rights Triumph in Supreme Court Ruling
28:30 06/27/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:06:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  Nightline 06/26/15:  Escaped Convicted Murderers: 1 Dead, 1 Still on the Run</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/Nightline/video/nightline-062615-escaped-convicted-murderers-dead-run-32069194</Link>
        <Description>One of the World's Best Rock Climbers Attempts Redwood Tree Climb; A Country Comes Together After Charleston, Same-Sex Marriage Decision</Description>
        <MainBody>Nightline 06/26/15:  Escaped Convicted Murderers: 1 Dead, 1 Still on the Run
18:30 06/26/15 NR
One of the World's Best Rock Climbers Attempts Redwood Tree Climb; Celebrations Over Same-Sex Marriage Decision Spread Across the Country
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:45:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  What Would You Do? 06/26/15</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/WhatWouldYouDo/video/062615--32066122</Link>
        <Description>Season 10, Episode 5</Description>
        <MainBody>What Would You Do? 06/26/15
40:46 06/26/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 22:31:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Full Episode:  This Week 06/21/15: Inside the Tragic Shooting In Charleston, South Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://abcnews.go.com/ThisWeek/video/week-062115-inside-tragic-shooting-charleston-south-carolina-31927284</Link>
        <Description>Guests: Rick Santorum, Carl Anderson, Bakari Sellers, Steve Inskeep, Sara Fagen, Maria Cardona</Description>
        <MainBody>This Week 06/21/15: Inside the Tragic Shooting In Charleston, South Carolina
46:09 06/21/15 NR
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
