<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="AP">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany's oldest remaining nuclear plant shuts down</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-06-28-EU--Germany-Nuclear%20Shutdown/id-e1aebc41bf9d4a52a5acf11b424ea039</Link>
        <Description>BERLIN (AP) — Germany's oldest remaining nuclear reactor has been shut down, part of a move initiated four years ago to switch off all its nuclear plants by the end of 2022.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait names Saudi man as suicide bomber in mosque attack</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-06-28-ML--Kuwait/id-287422857cb44e988130a70dd91acccb</Link>
        <Description>KUWAIT CITY (AP) — Kuwaiti authorities on Sunday identified the suicide bomber behind an attack on a Shiite mosque that killed 27 people as a Saudi citizen who flew into the Gulf nation just hours before blowing himself up.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank refuses to increase credit for Greece</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-06-28-EU--Greece-Bailout/id-c3fd00debb70468285201c193ced215e</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — The European Central Bank refused to increase emergency credit to Greek banks on Sunday, a day after the government threw Greece's bailout negotiations into turmoil by calling a referendum on creditors' financial proposals.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Greek minister hints no payment Tuesday to IMF</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-06-28-EU--Greece%20Bailout-The%20Latest/id-75de8d8d41f14684819ddb9ed2b1fc7e</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations (all times local):</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds still in hospital after fire at Taiwan music party</title>
        <Link>http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/cae69a7523db45408eeb2b3a98c0c9c5/Article_2015-06-28-AS--Taiwan-Fire/id-7200c3f228984d0eb9cc4942b293c0f3</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) — More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yahoo
Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou, center, speaks to a victim injured in an accidental explosion during a music concert, as he visits a local hospital in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Sunday, June 28, 2015. A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park. The cause of the fire is being investigated. (Central News Agency via AP)
Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou, center, speaks to a victim injured in an accidental explosion during a music concert, as he visits a local hospital in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Sunday, June 28, 2015. A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park. The cause of the fire is being investigated. (Central News Agency via AP)
Police investigators inspect the stage area after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, early Sunday, June 28, 2015. A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a Saturday night party at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 500 people, authorities said Sunday. (AP Photo) TAIWAN OUT
In this screen grab taken from ETTV, ambulances arrive after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The New Taipei City fire department says 200 people were injured in an accidental explosion of colored theatrical powder Saturday night near a performance stage where about 1,000 people were gathered for party. (ETTV via AP)
In this screen grab taken from ETTV, an injured concert spectator is treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The New Taipei City fire department says 200 people were injured in an accidental explosion of colored theatrical powder Saturday night near a performance stage where about 1,000 people were gathered for party. (ETTV via AP)
In this screen grab taken from ETTV, injured concert spectators are treated after an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The New Taipei City fire department says 200 people were injured in an accidental explosion of colored theatrical powder Saturday night near a performance stage where about 1,000 people were gathered for party. (ETTV via AP)
.   .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
