<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:44:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter denies scandal responsibility</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32923104#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Fifa president Sepp Blatter says he cannot be held responsible for the current corruption scandal but vows to work to earn back trust.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fifa corruption crisis: Sepp Blatter denies responsibility
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Fifa president Sepp Blatter has condemned the "action of individuals" for bringing "shame and humiliation" on football in a corruption scandal.
But he said that although many held him "ultimately responsible" for the football community, he could "not monitor everyone all of the time".
He was speaking at the opening of Fifa's congress, a day after seven top officials were held in a US inquiry.
Mr Blatter has faced calls to quit but is seeking re-election on Friday .
Many of Fifa's major sponsors have expressed concern over twin corruption investigations by both the US and Swiss authorities.
'Dragged through the mud'
Speaking at the opening ceremony of the Fifa congress in Zurich, Mr Blatter said the events of the week had "cast a long shadow over football".
In his first public appearance since the scandal broke, he said: "The actions of individuals bring shame and humiliation on football and demand action and change from us all.
Analysis: BBC's Imogen Foulkes in Zurich
An astonishing speech from Sepp Blatter: 17 years as Fifa president but when it comes to corruption he cannot "monitor everyone all the time".
He did say the allegations had brought "shame and humiliation" (words, cynics might say, that are not normally in his vocabulary) to football, but he did not mention the fact that a great many people, from David Cameron to Uefa boss Michel Platini have called on him to resign.
Instead he addressed the future, secure in his own personal conviction that he has a future in Fifa. It was time to change, "for football, for the world, for peace". Then he swept out again, to the strains of the Fifa anthem. On Friday, he stands for re-election. And he's likely to win.
Football fans' reactions
"We cannot allow the reputation of football and Fifa to be dragged through the mud and it has to stop here and now.
"Many people hold me ultimately responsible for the... global football community... I cannot monitor everyone all of the time. If people want to do wrong they will also try to hide it."
But he added: "It must fall to me to bear the responsibility for the reputation and well-being of our organisation and to find a way forward to fix things."
Mr Blatter admitted the "next few months will not be easy - I am sure bad news will follow" but that with Friday's vote, "we have the opportunity to begin on what will be a long and difficult road to rebuilding trust".
Mr Blatter had faced calls to resign, including from UK PM David Cameron and the head of European football's governing body Uefa, Michel Platini.
Mr Platini had earlier taken part in an emergency meeting with other Fifa confederation heads and Mr Blatter.
Mr Platini said he had asked Mr Blatter "as a friend" to resign, saying: "I have had enough - enough is enough, too much is too much."
The president refused, and the other confederations agreed with him that Friday's vote, in which Mr Blatter is seeking a fifth term, should go ahead.
The current and former Fifa executives indicted include Rafael Esquivel, Nicolas Leoz, Jeffrey Webb, Jack Warner, Eduardo Li, Eugenio Figueredo and Jose Maria Marin
Uefa will back Jordan's Prince Ali bin al-Hussein , Mr Blatter's only challenger.
Mr Platini said that if Mr Blatter won, Uefa could hold an extraordinary meeting in Berlin at the time of the Champions League final.
When asked if this could include withdrawing from Fifa competitions, Mr Platini said: "We will raise all possibilities."
Britain's David Gill said he would not take up his post on Fifa's executive committee if Mr Blatter were re-elected.
Swiss investigation
Some of the 14 people indicted on Wednesday in the US investigation are accused of receiving bribes to influence the outcome of bids to stage football tournaments, such as the 2010 World Cup in South Africa and the 2016 Copa America in the US.
Fifa on Wednesday provisionally banned from football-related activity 11 of the 14 people charged in the US. On Thursday it added another, Aaron Davidson.
Fifa's major sponsors Coca-Cola, Visa, Adidas, McDonald's, Hyundai Motor and Budweiser are pressing Fifa to take immediate action to restore its reputation.
Swiss prosecutors plan to interview 10 Fifa executive committee members as part of a separate investigation into the bidding process for the World Cup tournaments in 2018 in Russia and 2022 in Qatar.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:43:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syria Islamists 'seize Idlib city'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32924268#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Islamist rebel coalition has seized one of the last cities in western Idlib province held by the Syrian government, activists say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian Islamist rebels 'seize Ariha in Idlib province'
28 May 2015
From the section Middle East
Fighters from Ahrar al Sham and other Islamist affiliates claimed one of the last government strongholds in Idlib on Thursday
An Islamist coalition that includes Syria's al-Qaeda affiliate al-Nusra Front has taken over one of the last government strongholds in western Idlib province, activists say.
The Jaish al-Fateh, or Conquest Army, took control of the city of Ariha after a "lightning offensive", the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said.
However, the Syrian army said intense fighting was still going on there.
Ariha's fall would leave most of Idlib, bordering Turkey, in rebel hands.
Since late March, rebels have claimed a number of cities in the province, including Idlib and Jisr al-Shughour.
As well as bordering Turkey, Idlib is also next to Latakia province, a government stronghold and President Bashar al-Assad's heartland.
Al-Nusra Front and allied rebel groups took control of the northern city of Idlib in March
Meanwhile, the head of the al-Nusra Front said the group had been ordered by al-Qaeda's overall leader, Ayman al-Zawahiri, not to use Syria to launch attacks on the West.
In an interview with Al Jazeera , Abu Mohammed al-Julani said al-Nusra Front was focused on capturing Damascus and toppling President Assad.
He also promised to protect Syrian minorities that disavowed Mr Assad.
The hour-long interview with Julani, broadcast on Wednesday night, was his second with Qatar-based Al Jazeera since 2013, when al-Nusra Front split from what is now Islamic State (IS).
"We are only here to accomplish one mission, to fight the regime and its agents on the ground, including Hezbollah and others," he stressed, referring to the Lebanese Shia Islamist movement that is fighting alongside government forces."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:35:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US charges Chinese in testing scam</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32921737#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The US Department of Justice has charged 15 Chinese nationals with developing a scheme to have imposters take university entrance exams.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese nationals accused of taking SATs for others
28 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
US officials say the suspects posed as students to take college entrance exams
The US Department of Justice has charged 15 Chinese nationals with developing a scheme to have imposters take university entrance exams.
Prosecutors said suspects used fake passports to trick administrators into allowing people other than legitimate test takers to sit the exams.
The scheme took place between 2011 and 2015 mostly in western Pennsylvania, authorities said.
Those charged could face up to 20 years in prison if convicted.
The defendants, both male and female, range in age from 19 to 26, and are currently living in several cities - including Blacksburg, Virginia, and Boston, Massachusetts - where major universities are located, the Reuters news agency reported.
The counterfeit test takers sat for the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT) - a major university entrance exam in the US - as well as the Test of English as a Foreign Language (Toefl) and the Graduate Record Examination (GRE), the Justice Department said.
The SAT is a major university entrance exam in the US
The scheme's beneficiaries "fraudulently obtained admissions to American institutions of higher education," said US Attorney for the Western District of Pennsylvania David Hickton.
The prosecutor said that the students also cheated student visa requirements by using counterfeit Chinese passports.
The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette reported that 24-year-old Siyuan Zhao, who resides in Massachusetts, has been detained. Han Tong, 24, of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, who is considered the primary defendant, and 10 others will receive an order to appear in court.
The newspaper reports that three others are currently in China, and their names have been redacted from court documents.
Special Agent in Charge John Kelleghan for Homeland Security Investigations of Philadelphia said: "These students were not only cheating their way into the university, they were also cheating their way through our nation's immigration system".
The defendants could face up to 20 years in prison, a fine of $250,000 (163,000) or both for each of the wire and mail fraud counts they face.  Additionally, they face five years on top that for the conspiracy charges.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:05:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most-wanted Nazi 'unfit for trial'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32924225#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former SS lieutenant Gerhard Sommer, at the top of a most-wanted list of Nazis, has been declared unfit for trial by prosecutors in Germany.</Description>
        <MainBody>Most-wanted German Nazi Sommer 'unfit for trial'
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Ten ex-Nazi officers were found guilty of the 1944 Sant'Anna massacre of 560 civilians
Former SS lieutenant Gerhard Sommer, at the top of a most-wanted list of Nazis, has been declared unfit for trial by prosecutors in Germany.
They said he had severe dementia.
Sommer, 93, was one of 10 ex-Nazi officers found guilty in absentia in Italy of one of the country's worst civilian wartime massacres.
He was convicted for his role in the murders of 560 civilians in the Tuscan village of Sant'Anna di Stazzema in August 1944.
The Nazis, who were retreating in northern Italy ahead of Allied troops, surrounded the village early on 12 August and in the space of a few hours murdered men, women and 119 children.
Sommer was serving at the time in an SS Panzer division. He now lives in a nursing home in Hamburg-Volksdorf and tops the Simon Wiesenthal Center's list of most-wanted Nazi criminals.
German President Joachim Gauck (R) visited Sant'Anna di Stazzema in 2013
Hamburg lawyer Gabriele Heinecke, who has campaigned on behalf of the victims' families to put him on trial, said she was unhappy with the way specialists had reached the conclusion that Sommer was suffering from dementia.
When asked by Berlin website Tageszeitung if she thought dementia could be faked, Ms Heinecke said: "Of course. In matters of pensions it's something that happens every day."
The decision to drop the trial comes as Oskar Groening, another 93-year-old former Nazi, described as "The Bookkeeper of Auschwitz" is being tried in Germany on at least 300,000 counts of accessory to murder.
For years, attempts have been made to put Sommer on trial in Germany, and prosecutors in Hamburg said if he had been deemed fit he would "with high probability have been charged with 342 cases of murder, committed cruelly and on base motives".
In 2012, the case was dropped for lack of evidence after a 10-year investigation, but it was eventually re-opened in August last year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:22:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tajik special ops chief 'joins IS'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32917311#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tajikistan's special forces chief appears in a video claiming to have joined Islamic State forces in Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tajikistan special forces chief Gulmurod Khalimov 'joins IS'
28 May 2015
From the section Asia
Gulmurod Khalimov has been missing since the beginning of May
Tajikistan's special forces chief has appeared in a video claiming to have joined Islamic State forces in Syria.
Gulmurod Khalimov is seen in the footage dressed in black and holding a gun. He went missing in early May.
He says he joined IS in protest at Tajikistan's policy towards religion, which he says is anti-Islamic.
Hundreds of Central Asians are thought have left for Syria, but this is the first known case of such a high profile officer joining the militants.
The authorities in Tajikistan have refused to comment on his whereabouts since his disappearance, reports the BBC's Abdujalil Abdurasulov in Almaty.
'Slaughter'
Khalimov used to fight extremists at home and was one of the best trained officers in the country, our correspondent says.
In the video, which is believed to have been recorded in a Syrian camp, he says he plans to return to Tajikistan and "bring slaughter".
He voices his disillusionment with the Tajik police and talks about the hardship of thousands of Tajik working migrants in Russia.
Analysis: Khayrullo Fayz, BBC Central Asian Service
Tajikistan has been stable since the end of the civil war which followed independence
The news of a high profile Tajik commander joining IS is bound to have shocked Tajikistan's authoritarian government. YouTube - where Gulmurod Khalimov's video could be seen - was blocked almost immediately. So far no officials have been available for comment.
It's an unprecedented case for Tajikistan.
Khalimov did not belong to the thousands of Muslims in the country routinely targeted by a government intent on fighting what it sees as extremism, but was part of the very security establishment meant to counter such threats.
Many in Tajikistan are puzzled by the speed of his departure; after all he was still working in the country in April. With Central Asian militants now battling Afghan security forces just across the border in Afghanistan, the authorities in Dushanbe will be extremely concerned about the wider implications.
Khalimov's position and profile are significant enough to potentially influence other members of the security forces.
There are no official figures for the number of Tajik citizens fighting alongside Islamic State, but in January sources in the security services were quoted saying they range from 200 to 500.
Central Asian fighters have also formed their own groups such as Sabri Jamaat and Imam Bukhari Jamaat, the BBC's Abdujalil Abdurasulov says.
Many of these militants have reportedly been seen in major battles in Syrian cities, including Aleppo, Kobane and lately in Palmyra.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bangkok talks on Asia migrant crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32925815#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A regional conference is due to begin in the Thai capital Bangkok to discuss solutions to the South-East Asia migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Asia migrants: Bangkok meeting to debate crisis
28 May 2015
From the section Asia
Indonesia has agreed to give some migrants temporary shelter
A regional conference is due to get under way in the Thai capital Bangkok to discuss possible solutions to the South-East Asia migrant crisis.
The talks will include member states from the Association of South-East Asian Nations (Asean) as well as representatives from the US and the UN.
Bangladesh and Myanmar have seen an exodus of people fleeing south by boat to Thailand, Indonesia and Malaysia.
Thousands are thought to be stranded at sea in abandoned boats.
Most are economic migrants from Bangladesh and Rohingya Muslims fleeing persecution in Myanmar - also known as Burma.
Friday's talks includes representatives from 17 countries affected by "irregular migration in the Indian Ocean" - Australia, Bangladesh, Cambodia, India, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, the Philippines, Vietnam, Thailand, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, Sri Lanka, Pakistan, Afghanistan and Iran.
The US, Japan and Switzerland have sent observers and there are officials from the UN refugee agency, the UN Office on Drugs and Crime and the International Organization for Migration.
However, correspondents say many of those attending are not ministerial-level and the talks are unlikely to produce a binding agreement or even a plan of action.
Myanmar, which denies the Rohingya citizenship, making them effectively stateless, has played down any hopes of an agreement.
"We are going there only to discuss the regional crisis which all of the Asean countries are facing," Htein Lin, head of Myanmar's delegation, told Reuters news agency.
The crisis began earlier this year when Thailand cracked down on overland migrant routes, forcing people smugglers to use sea routes instead.
Most countries are unwilling take in the migrants, fearing that by accepting them they will encourage more to make the journey.
Malaysia and Indonesia have agreed to stop towing boats out to sea and to give temporary shelter to those who have landed. Thailand has only said it will stop rejecting the boats.
Asia's migrant crisis
Rohingya Muslims mainly live in Myanmar, where they have faced decades of persecution.
Rights groups say migrants feel they have "no choice" but to leave, paying people smugglers to help them.
The UN estimates more than 120,000 Rohingyas have fled in the past three years.
Traffickers usually take the migrants by sea to Thailand then overland to Malaysia.
But Thailand recently began cracking down on the migrant routes, meaning traffickers are using sea routes instead.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:51:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU withdraws Burundi poll observers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32923214#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The European Union suspends its election monitoring mission in Burundi amid political unrest over the president's third-term bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi elections: EU withdraws poll observers
28 May 2015
From the section Africa
Protests against the third term bid have been going on for weeks
The European Union has suspended its election monitoring mission in Burundi where President Pierre Nkurunziza is seeking a third term next month.
The decision was taken because of restrictions on the media, excessive force against demonstrators and a climate of intimidation, it said.
It comes as the Catholic Church said it would no longer help organise the elections amid the political unrest.
Earlier this month, the president survived a coup attempt.
Rights groups say at least 20 people have died in protests since Mr Nkurunziza announced on 25 April that he would seek a third term.
The UN says about 70,000 people have fled to neighbouring countries fearing political violence.
EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said her team had been on the ground for more than a month.
They reported that "the election process continues to be seriously marred by restrictions on independent media, excessive use of force against demonstrators, a climate of intimidation for opposition parties and civil society and lack of confidence in the election authorities", she said in a statement .
The EU has already said it is withholding more than $2m (1.3m) of funding for the elections.
Correspondents say the statement by the Catholic Church, which is hugely influential in Burundi, is another blow for Mr Nkurunziza.
Mr Nkurunziza has been in power since 2005
Many of the country's 18 provincial electoral commissions are headed by priests, who the Catholic Church committee have asked to stand down.
Bishop Gervais Bashimiyubusa said in a statement read on Catholic radio that the church could not "endorse an election riddled with shortcomings", the AFP news agency reports.
He did not call for a boycott of the elections, but stressed that nobody should go to the polls "by threat or intimidation, or because they have been bought in one way or another".
Parliamentary elections are scheduled for 5 June and the presidential poll for 26 June.
The president's critics say his bid for a third term contravenes the constitution, which requires him to step down after two terms.
But Burundi's Constitutional Court ruled that Mr Nkurunziza's first term does not count because he was elected by parliament and not voters.
Burundi: Key facts
The country is facing its worst turmoil since the 12-year civil war ended in 2005
10.4m population
50 years - life expectancy for a man
2nd poorest country in the world
85% are Hutu, 14% Tutsi
300,000 died in civil war
UN, World Bank, CIA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:27:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ecuador seizes illegal shark fins</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32926068#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Police in Ecuador have seized around 200,000 shark fins which were to be illegally exported to Asia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ecuador seizes huge illegal shark fin haul
29 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Officials estimate 50,000 sharks were killed
Police in Ecuador have seized around 200,000 sharks fins which were about to be illegally exported to Asia.
The fins - often used to make soup - were discovered after raids on nine locations in the port city of Manta.
Six people, including a Chinese national, have been arrested on charges of damaging wildlife.
Interior Minister Jose Serrano said at least 50,000 sharks had been killed by the traffickers.
He said the authorities had "dealt a major blow to an international network that trafficked shark fins".
"We must end these criminal networks that are only interested in their own economic interests and are destroying the eco-system."
Shark fishing is prohibited in Ecuador and they cannot be sold unless they have been accidentally caught in fishing nets.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:59:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS 'kills 20 men at Palmyra site'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32920614#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State militants killed 20 men at the ancient theatre at the Unesco World Heritage site of Palmyra, central Syria, a monitoring group says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Palmyra: IS 'kills 20 men' at ancient theatre
28 May 2015
From the section Middle East
The men were said to have been shot dead inside the ancient theatre, pictured here in 2008
Islamic State (IS) militants have killed 20 men at the ancient theatre inside the Unesco World Heritage site of Palmyra, central Syria, a monitoring group says.
Residents were rounded up and forced to watch the men being shot, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says.
About 240 people - mostly soldiers - have now been killed by IS since it overran the town last week, it adds.
It comes amid fears IS may destroy the 2,000-year-old Roman-era ruins.
IS militants have already destroyed ancient sites in Iraq that pre-date Islam - most recently the ancient city of Nimrud, one of Iraq's greatest archaeological treasures.
'New images'
Since the town's takeover, IS has also taken control of a military airbase and a notorious prison nearby.
There have so far been no reports of damage at the site in the town of Palmyra, known locally as Tadmur. Last week IS militants locked the doors to the museum at the site and placed guards at its doors, Syrian officials said.
Footage published online by a jihadist media outlet belonging to IS purportedly showed the ruins "undamaged", Reuters reports. While there has been no independent verification of the images, residents on the ground say the ruins remain unharmed, the news agency adds.
A video released by IS earlier this week alleged to show the ruins in Palmyra unharmed
Other images released by jihadist media outlet "Welayat Homs" allegedly showed the IS flag hoisted above Tadmur's notorious prison
Images said to be from inside one of the prison cells were also released
Syrian officials said they had moved hundreds of Palmyra's statues to safety prior to the IS takeover but could not transfer large monuments.
The 20 men who were shot dead on Wednesday were accused by IS of fighting alongside Syrian pro-government troops, who fled the town in the face of the IS onslaught last week.
Soon after the town's capture last week, witnesses said IS militants went door-to-door looking for government soldiers and made announcements via a large mosque calling on residents to hand them over.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, which tracks developments on the ground in Syria based on witness reports, said nearly 70 women and children were among the 240 people killed in the town. There are fears that another 600 prisoners the militants are holding may suffer a similar fate.
There are also concerns that a rare species of bird, the northern bald ibis, may become extinct in Syria because of the town's capture.
About a third of the town's 200,000 residents were able to flee before IS arrived, the UN told the BBC last week. But it said it had received reports that Syrian forces based in Palmyra had prevented many others from leaving.
The ancient ruins are situated in a strategically important area on the road between the Syrian capital, Damascus, and the contested eastern city of Deir al-Zour.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:08:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin makes troop deaths state secret</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32913929#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>President Vladimir Putin declares Russian troop losses in peacetime a state secret as the Kremlin continues to deny sending troops to Ukraine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin declares Russian troop deaths in peacetime a secret
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Vladimir Putin attended a military parade to mark Victory Day earlier this month
Russian President Vladimir Putin has signed a decree to make losses of Russian troops in peacetime a secret.
The amendment bans information about the deaths of Russian forces "during special operations" in peacetime.
The Kremlin has consistently denied sending regular troops and armour to help rebels in eastern Ukraine.
But a new report from the US says Russia has been using training camps near the border as "launching points of Russia's war in Ukraine".
The study by the Atlantic Council , published on Thursday, claims to have tracked Russian involvement in the conflict using photographs, videos and satellite images posted online.
President Putin's move to ban information about peacetime military deaths comes amid fears of a fresh offensive by Russian-backed separatists.
Men wearing military uniforms ride atop a troop transporter during exercises at Kuzminsky military training ground in the Rostov region
Reuters reporters said they had observed this week Russia's army massing troops and weaponry - including mobile rocket launchers, tanks and artillery - at a makeshift base in Kuzminsky, near the border with Ukraine.
The news agency said many of the vehicles had number plates and identifying marks removed, while servicemen had taken insignia off their fatigues - similar to some unidentified forces seen in eastern Ukraine.
A ceasefire agreement was signed in Minsk in February, but heavy fighting has continued in some areas since then.
'Secretly buried'
Before the amendment was signed by Mr Putin on Wednesday, the loss of troops was a state secret only in wartime.
The decree gives no details of what is meant by "special operations".
For months there have been reports of secret burials of Russian soldiers killed in Ukraine.
Earlier this month, Russian blogger Ruslan Leviyev said he had found three graves of Russian  officers killed by shelling in eastern Ukraine on 5 May.
Meanwhile the authors of the Atlantic Council report - including British weapons analyst Eliot Higgins - say satellite images have confirmed the movement of Russian troops and camp build-ups along the Ukrainian border.
They say Russian training camps are being used as "the staging ground" for military equipment and soldiers to be transported into Ukraine.
The most recent photograph analysed in the Atlantic Council report was taken in February.
Captured soldiers
The Kremlin has denied Western accusations that its forces are directly involved in combat, insisting that any Russians serving with the rebels are "volunteers".
Russian reporters 'attacked at secret soldier burials'
On Wednesday Russia's ambassador in Ukraine visited two men, who were captured by Kiev and accused of being elite Russian soldiers operating in the Luhansk region.
The Kremlin had demanded access to Aleksandr Aleksandrov and Yevgeny Yerofeyev, complaining that their situation was being exploited as propaganda.
The pair were charged by Kiev with involvement in "terrorist activity", after apparently confirming in video statements that they were active Russian servicemen.
Moscow said they were not serving "at the moment they were detained".
But Ukraine's President Petro Poroshenko told the BBC that the soldiers were proof that his country was engaged in a "real war" with Russia, rather than pro-Russian separatists.
He said Ukrainians should prepare for a Russian offensive in the coming months.
Nato Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg has called for an end to snap exercises by Russia close to the Ukrainian border, and demanded Russia be "more transparent when it comes to their military activities".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:16:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Zuma not liable for home upgrades</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32921715#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>South African President Jacob Zuma will not have to repay state money spent to upgrade his private home in Nkandla, the police minister says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Zuma 'will not have to repay' money spent on residence
28 May 2015
From the section Africa
Mr Zuma has previously said that he did not request the upgrades to the property
President Jacob Zuma will not have to repay state money spent to upgrade his private home in Nkandla, South Africa's police minister has said.
Nathi Nhleko said that the upgrades, including a pool costing almost 4m rand ($328,000; 215,000) were in fact security features.
Last year an independent inquiry found the president had "unduly benefited" from the upgrades.
The president has been heavily criticised over the issue.
In February the Nkandla controversy prompted chaotic scenes in parliament as leftist MPs scuffled with security.
They had been interrupting a key annual speech by Mr Zuma and demanding answers over the row.
A report last year by South Africa's anti-corruption watchdog found Mr Zuma had "unduly benefitted" from the renovations and recommended he pay back some of the money.
However Mr Zuma has maintained he would only pay money back if ordered to do so by Mr Nhleko, the police minister.
At a news conference Mr Nhleko justified his decision not to make Mr Zuma pay back any of the money by saying the upgrades were security features.
For example, Mr Nhleko explained the pool was in fact intended for use in fighting fires, and he even had a video of four policemen demonstrating how this security feature worked.
A chicken run, a cow enclosure, an amphitheatre and visitors centre were also all classed as security features by Mr Nhleko.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:21:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Concern over Mers spread in S Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32919416#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Concern is growing in South Korea over the spread of the Mers virus after a man defied quarantine to travel to China.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mers virus: Concern growing in South Korea
28 May 2015
From the section Asia
Seven people have been confirmed with the virus in South Korea
Concern is growing in South Korea over the spread of the Mers virus after a man defied quarantine to travel to China.
Seven people have been infected with the disease so far in South Korea, said the country's health ministry.
Chinese officials said they had traced the son of a patient who had refused voluntary quarantine.
Cases of the virus, for which there is no known cure, have been confirmed in more than 20 countries.
Two new cases of Mers (Middle East Respiratory Syndrome) in South Korea were confirmed on Thursday.
The health ministry said that all of them had been linked to a man who returned from the Middle East - where Mers is more common.
Dozens of people are now in quarantine.
'Deeply sorry'
Meanwhile, Chinese officials said they had identified and isolated a South Korean man who had ignored quarantine restrictions to fly to China through Hong Kong.
Local media said that health workers had contacted 35 people who came into close contact with him.
His father was diagnosed with the virus earlier in May.
"We should have checked more actively and broadly on family-related issues. We are deeply sorry about that," said Yang Byung-kook, director of the Korea Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.
What is Mers?
Acronym for Middle East Respiratory Syndrome
A type of coronavirus which causes respiratory infections
First death recorded in 2012 in Saudi Arabia
Camels are suspected to be the primary source of infection for humans
Mers was first identified in humans in 2012 and is a type of virus from the same family as Sars (severe acute respiratory syndrome).
Sars killed almost 800 people in an outbreak that began in 2002.
There is no cure or vaccine for Mers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:47:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swiss cheese hole origins solved</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32920200#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Scientists say they have discovered why Swiss cheese has holes in it: apparently, it is all down to how dirty buckets are when the milk is collected.</Description>
        <MainBody>Swiss cheese hole mystery solved: It's all down to dirt
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Hole again: and it is all thanks to tiny flecks of hay, say Swiss scientists
Scientists say they have discovered why Swiss cheese has holes in it: apparently, it is all down to how dirty buckets are when the milk is collected.
Contrary to what cartoons have suggested over the years, the holes are not made by mice eating their way through the cheese.
And nor are they produced by carbon dioxide released by bacteria, as popular scientific belief held.
Instead, a Swiss laboratory says they are created by flecks of hay.
Agroscope, a government agricultural institute, said "microscopically small hay particles" would fall in to buckets collecting milk, and develop into bigger holes as the cheese matures.
The process affects only some Swiss cheeses, such as Emmental and Appenzell.
Agroscope said the findings explained why fewer holes had been appearing in Swiss cheeses over the last 15 years, since more modern milking methods made it less likely for hay to fall into containers.
Scientists reached their conclusions after adding small amounts of hay dust to milk and making it into cheese over 130 days.
The research has not been peer reviewed.
The theory that bacteria caused the holes has been around since 1917, after findings were published by an American scientist, William Clark .
The cheese industry calls holes in cheese "eyes". Any cheese without eyes is known as blind.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:54:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's Mysore crowns new maharaja</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-32911649#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A 23-year-old graduate from the University of Massachusetts is crowned the new maharaja of Mysore, titular head of the 600-year-old Wadiyar dynasty.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's Mysore crowns new maharaja Yaduveer Wadiyar
By Imran Qureshi BBC Hindi, Bangalore
28 May 2015
From the section India
A 23-year-old economics graduate from the University of Massachusetts has been crowned the new maharaja of Mysore, titular head of the 600-year-old Wadiyar dynasty in southern India.
Yaduveer Krishnadatta Chamaraja Wadiyar was anointed at an elaborate ceremony lasting nearly two hours.
It was conducted by more than 40 priests across 15 temples spread across the Mysore Palace grounds.
He succeeds his grand uncle Srikantadatta Narasimharaja Wadiyar.
Srikantadatta Wadiyar, who died in December 2013, was childless and did not name an heir, but his widow Pramodadevi Wadiyar adopted Yaduveer Gopalraj Urs, a relative, at a ceremony in February.
After his coronation , the maharaja became known by his full title, Yaduveer Krishnadatta Chamaraja Wadiyar.
"It was quite a spectacle. This was enormous and certainly beyond expectations," Michael Ludgrove, curator of the Royal House of Mysore, told BBC Hindi following Thursday's ceremony.
"All sections of society were here, including the representatives of the people," he added.
The crowning ceremony was attended by more than 1,000 guests from India and abroad, including former Indian prime minister HD Deve Gowda and Karnataka state Chief Minister K Siddaramaiah.
Mr Ludgrove says he has met the new maharaja just once but is quite impressed by him. "He is a man of the times. He is full of enthusiasm and potential."
The new maharaja will now become the custodian of more than 1,500 acres of land spread across Mysore, Bangalore, Hassan, Channapatna and other places in the southern state of Karnataka.
But, he will also be inheriting a legal battle with the Karnataka government, which wants to take over the palace properties.
He is also likely to face a legal challenge from one of the late maharajah's nephews, Kantharaj Urs, who is upset that he was not chosen as successor.
The dispute over the inheritance is because the Wodeyar kings have never had children - legend has it that the dynasty has suffered from a 17th Century curse .
Mr Ludgrove, who worked with the former maharaja for nearly three decades, says the Mysore royals are very similar to the British royalty.
"They are the constant. These are traditions which continue and they bring all people together. Something that is rarely seen," he says.
Historian Nanjaraj Urs says some of the members of Wadiyar dynasty had contributed greatly to the development of the state, but the crowning ceremony now is a "farce".
"The real maharajas had an intimate relationship with the people. There was affection and it is that emotional attachment which makes this family popular.
"But now it is just a function in a traditional family. You can call the ceremony by any name but all of it is within the family."
India's royalty lost their official powers when the nation gained independence in 1947 but the modern-day maharajas are still wealthy and influential.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:27:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Gay Head lighthouse moves inland</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32921654#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Gay Head Lighthouse in Martha's Vineyard, Massachusetts, its being moved inland on Thursday to avoid falling into the Atlantic Ocean.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gay Head Lighthouse in US moves inland to avoid ocean fall
28 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The Gay Head Lighthouse in Massachusetts is being moved to avoid falling into the sea.
A US lighthouse will begin a journey inland on Thursday to avoid falling down an eroding cliff side.
The $3m (2m) effort will move the 400-tonne Gay Head Lighthouse in Martha's Vineyard, Massachusetts.
The 160-year-old structure helped mariners navigate foggy coastlines during the peak of the whaling trade in the region in the 1800s.
The historic lighthouse should arrive at its destination farther away from the Atlantic Ocean by Saturday.
As it stands now, it is only 46ft (14 metres) from the edge of a cliff.
Workers have been preparing the historic lighthouse for its move.
Gay Head Lighthouse is a popular tourist destination for holidays, on the western side of Martha's Vineyard.
The lighthouse has been hoisted off the ground to prepare for the move.
The lighthouse will be passed along steel beams and rollers by hydraulic jacks, which will move it 129 feet (39 meters) southeast of its current location.
Strong ocean waves have distorted nearby Gay Head cliffs
Within two years, the lighthouse would have been too near to the edge to move safely.
The call to move it has become more urgent in recent years due to landslides, strong ocean waves and groundwater, eroding the surrounding Gay Head cliffs.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:38:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pataki launches US presidential bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32921735#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former New York Governor George Pataki has entered contest for the Republican presidential nomination.</Description>
        <MainBody>Former New York Governor George Pataki launches campaign
28 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Mr Pataki was the governor of New York from 1995 to 2006
Former New York Governor George Pataki has entered contest for the Republican presidential nomination.
Mr Pataki, who served as governor from 1995 to 2006, is positioning himself as a moderate in a heavily conservative field.
He joins seven other Republicans who have announced their campaigns, and several others who are expected to announce in the coming weeks.
After leaving the governor's office, he served as a UN delegate.
Mr Pataki launched a fundraising "super-Pac" earlier this year - a standard move for a politician considering running for America's highest office.
But his campaign was officially kicked off in a video posted to his website on Thursday morning.
In the video, titled George Pataki For President, he played up his role as a Republican governor in a state dominated by Democrats.
"Washington has grown too big, too powerful, too expensive and too intrusive," he said. "This is exactly what the founding fathers feared...It is time to stand up, protect our freedom and take back this government".
Mr Pataki with President Bush and other leaders on the fifth anniversary of the Sept 11 attacks
Amid thumping music, the campaign video pointed to his leadership during the attacks of 11 September 2001, and stressed that he would be a unifying candidate.
Since leaving elected office in the middle of the last decade, Mr Pataki has struck a moderate tone in the news media.
Analysis: Anthony Zurcher, BBC Washington
Could a former Republican governor from a large state who hasn't held public office in more than eight years have a shot at winning the Republican presidential nomination in 2016?
If the man's last name is Bush, the answer is yes. If it's Pataki, the odds are significantly longer.
So why does Jeb Bush of Florida consistently sit near the top of polls and dominate campaign fundraising, while George Pataki - the man who, along with Mayor Rudy Giuliani, became the face of New York's response to the September 11 attacks - barely move the needle?
There's the name, of course. But it's also likely the fact that Mr Pataki is part of a dying breed of Northeast Republican moderates who blend fiscal conservatism with social positions closer to those of the political left. He's in favour of same-sex marriage, supports legalised abortions and backs robust environmental regulation, for instance.
Once upon a time candidates with these kinds of views were a force in the Republican Party. Those days are long past, however.
In recent months, he has criticised so-called Religious Freedom bills that many conservative Republicans support.
He has also been critical of of Republican lawmakers who wrote to Iranian leaders while the Obama Administration was negotiating Iran's nuclear programme. He called their actions "inappropriate".
Mr Pataki made his first public appearance as a candidate later on Thursday when he spoke in Exeter, New Hampshire.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:19:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latin Americans open Fifa enquiries</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32925887#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Brazil begins investigations into possible Fifa corruption there, as an Argentine judge issues warrants for three businessmen wanted by the US.</Description>
        <MainBody>Latin Americans open their own Fifa enquiries
29 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
The CBF's headquarters is named Jose Maria Marin, who was arrested in Switzerland on Wednesday
Brazil's federal police has begun investigations into possible Fifa corruption in the country.
Justice Minister Eduardo Cardozo said they were looking at possible tax evasion and money laundering within Brazil.
Costa Rica has opened an enquiry into US accusations against Eduardo Li, head of Costa Rica's football association.
In Argentina, a judge has issued warrants for three local businessmen wanted by the US.
Brazil's President Dilma Rousseff said football in her country "will only benefit" from the US corruption investigation of Fifa and other top officials of the sport.
In the meantime, the Brazilian Football Confederation has removed the name of Jose Maria Marin from the facade of its Rio de Janeiro headquarters after the former president was arrested in Switzerland on corruption charges.
A Congressional enquiry into corruption in the CBF may also be on the agenda.
On Wednesday, the Brazilian senator and former football player Romario made a formal application for an enquiry to be opened.
Mr Marin, who faces extradition to the US, was head of the CBF from 2012 to April 2015 and headed the local committee for the organisation of the 2014 World Cup.
Up to his arrest, he was part of a Fifa committee organizing the Olympic football tournaments.
Front pages of newspapers in the Paraguayan capital, Asuncion with pictures of Nicolas Leoz,, the former president of South America's football confederation. Mr Leoz fell ill and was hospitalized in Paraguay on Wednesday as US authorities sought his extradition.
In Costa Rica, prosecutors have opened an investigation into the president of the country's football federation, Eduardo Li, who was also detained on Wednesday.
The arrest of Mr Li was met with surprise in Costa Rica. He had become a national hero after the national team's unexpected run to the quarter-finals of the World Cup in Brazil in 2014.
A spokesman for Costa Rica's public prosecutor said: "The investigation opened today aims to determine whether the hypothesis of the US Department of Justice probe related to a case of money laundering and corruption involving Eduardo Li can be corroborated."
Costa Rica's tax office said it had also opened an investigation into Mr Li's various business interests in the country.
Argentina support
In Argentina, the football association - AFA - issued a statement in support of the US led investigation into Fifa.
"The Argentine Football Association states that it supports and joins the investigations on Fifa and Conmebol representatives and members, sharing the football world's concerns as regard transparency in our beloved sport."
A judge issued arrest warrants for three businessmen accused of conspiring to win and keep lucrative media rights contracts from regional football federations in return for millions of dollars in bribes.
The warrants were issued a day after the US Justice Department had requested them.
The head of the Argentine Cabinet, Anibal Fernandez, said the country's tax authority would pursue any money owed it and that bribery should be investigated in Argentina "no matter the cost".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:04:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Neruda death probe inconclusive</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32925398#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>New tests on the remains of the Chilean poet Pablo Neruda say they have found no conclusive evidence he was poisoned.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chilean poet Pablo Neruda death probe inconclusive
28 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Pablo Neruda (L) was interviewed in London in 1965 by the BBC's Latin American service
Spanish scientists investigating the death of the world famous left-wing Chilean poet, Pablo Neruda, in 1973 say they have found no conclusive evidence that he was poisoned.
The Chilean government reopened an investigation in January with new tests on his remains for protein traces caused by poisoning.
The investigators said they had found proteins explained by natural causes including advanced prostate cancer.
Tests in 2013 uncovered nothing.
The source of a third protein was not immediately clear but it was probably caused by an infection or the posthumous manipulation of the remains, the investigators said.
A final round of DNA testing is still expected to take place.
Pablo Neruda is presumed to have died of cancer days after the military coup in 1973.
His driver has alleged that agents of General Augusto Pinochet, who was leading the military coup, had taken advantage of Mr Neruda's illness to inject poison in his stomach as he lay in hospital.
Pablo Neruda, a Nobel laureate,  was famed for his passionate love poems and his outspoken communist views.
His supporters and family are divided on whether researchers should continue the tests or whether his remains should be returned to his grave near his coastal home of Isla Negra.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:06:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>SA denies organising World Cup bribe</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32912917#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>South African officials dismiss US allegations that a $10m (6.5m) bribe was organised for top Fifa officials in order to host the 2010 World Cup.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Africa denies Fifa was paid World Cup bribe
28 May 2015
From the section Africa
South African officials have dismissed allegations by US investigators that a $10m (6.5m) bribe was organised for Fifa officials to host the 2010 World Cup.
There had been a "clean audit report" at the end of the World Cup, a government minister said.
A football official added that the bid was run by "men of integrity", including the late Nelson Mandela.
South Africa was the first African nation to host the World Cup.
Fifa, the world football governing body, chose it ahead of Morocco.
'Don't panic'
The South African government promised to pay $10m to former Fifa vice-president Jack Warner and his co-conspirators in exchange for winning the right to host the tournament, an FBI indictment alleges.
South Africa is the only African country to have hosted the World Cup
The indictment later states that the South Africans "were unable to arrange for the payment to be made directly from government funds" so instead the $10m was sent through Fifa using funds that would otherwise have gone to South Africa to support the World Cup.
In the South African government's first response to the allegation, Jeff Radebe, a minister in the president's office, said that leading accounting firm Ernest &amp; Young had given South Africa a "clean audit report" at the end of the World Cup.
Nelson Mandela played a key role in the bid
Sports Minister Fikile Mbalula said South Africa would ask the US for the indictment through diplomatic channels in order "to establish the basis on which the allegations are being made as this has a potential of tarnishing the name and people of our country globally and put into question the competence of our nation in organising mega events".
The South Africa Football Association (Safa) said the allegation was "baseless" and "untested".
"No need to press any panic button regarding the Fifa 2010 World Cup. Terrible thumb-sucking from individual making those wild allegations," its spokesman Dominic Chimhavi said in a tweet .
Mr Warner said on Wednesday that he was innocent of any charges.
He handed himself over to police in his home nation of Trinidad and Tobago and spent the night in prison after delays in processing his $395,000 bail.
Fifa announced a provisional ban from football-related activity on 11 of the 14 people who were charged by the US authorities of racketeering, fraud and money laundering.
But it said the election on Friday - in which Fifa president Sepp Blatter is seeking a fifth term - would go ahead.
Mr Blatter, who has not been named in the investigations, issued a statement on the US case, saying: "Such misconduct has no place in football and we will ensure that those who engage in it are put out of the game."
Swiss prosecutors have also opened a separate investigation into the bidding process for the World Cup tournaments in 2018 in Russia and 2022 in Qatar.
Swiss police said they would question 10 Fifa executive committee members who participated in the votes that selected Russia and Qatar in December 2010.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:59:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top Angolan journalist sentenced</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32924487#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A renowned Angolan journalist is given a six-month suspended jail sentence for falsely linking military generals to the "blood diamond" trade.</Description>
        <MainBody>Angola's Morais sentenced over diamond book
28 May 2015
From the section Africa
Rafael Marques de Morais has won a freedom of expression award
A renowned Angolan journalist has been given a six-month suspended jail sentence for falsely linking military generals to the "blood diamond" trade.
Prosecutors pushed for his conviction, despite his legal team saying last week that a deal had been reached with the generals to drop the case.
A rights group said he had been sentenced after an "absurd process".
Rafael Marques de Morais is a long-standing critic of President Jose Eduardo dos Santos' 35-year rule.
He spent 43 days in prison, including 11 in solitary confinement, in 1999 after he published the article, The Lipstick of the Dictatorship, in a private Angolan newspaper.
The latest case against Mr Morais came after he wrote a book, Blood Diamonds: Torture and Corruption in Angola.
'Appalled'
He accused seven generals of being linked to murder, torture and land grabs in Angola's lucrative diamond fields.
The generals denied the allegation, and sued Mr Morais.
Last week, his legal team said he had agreed not to republish the book, in exchange for the charges being dropped.
Campaign group Index on Censorship said on its website that it was "appalled to hear that Rafael has been sentenced after an absurd process".
"This is a clear violation of rights to free expression, to a free press and to a fair trial," its chief executive Jodie Ginsberg said.
In March, Index on Censorship gave Mr Morais a freedom of expression award for his work as a journalist and human rights activist in Angola.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu May 28 10:26:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rinehart loses family trust battle</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-australia-32911028#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Australia's richest person, mining magnate Gina Rinehart, loses control of the family trust to her daughter, after a long-running legal battle.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia's Gina Rinehart loses control of family trust to daughter
28 May 2015
From the section Australia
The court found Bianca Rinehart better suited to administer the trust than any of the other alternatives
Australia's richest person, mining magnate Gina Rinehart, has lost control of the family trust to her daughter, after a long-running legal battle.
The New South Wales Supreme Court gave Bianca Rinehart control of the trust. It was set up by her grandfather and is worth more than A$4bn ($3.1bn; 2bn).
Mrs Rinehart's children John Hancock and Bianca Rinehart launched the legal action against their mother in 2011.
They said she had acted "deceitfully" in her dealings with the trust.
Their sister, Hope Rinehart Welker, launched the suit with them but later dropped out. A fourth child, Ginia, has sided with their mother, saying that the case filed by her siblings was "motivated entirely by greed".
Justice Paul Brereton found that Bianca, 38, was better suited than any of the alternatives to administer the trust under the circumstances. He ordered Mrs Rinehart to hand over trust documents to Bianca.
The feud began after Mrs Rinehart changed the vesting date of the trust from 2011 to 2068
Justice Brereton said it had become clear that Gina Rinehart had "gone to extraordinary lengths" to maintain control directly or indirectly of the trust.
He said it was reasonable inference that she would try to influence any trustee who tried to move against her interest.
Mrs Rinehart has a net value of $12.2bn, according to Forbes, making her the richest person in Australia. She heads up Hancock Prospecting - an iron ore trader.
In 2014 the company finalised a deal worth $7.2bn to develop Roy Hill - one the world's largest iron-ore mines.
The feud in the family began after Mrs Rinehart changed the vesting date of the Hope Margaret Hancock Trust from 2011 to 2068.
The trust contains part ownership of Hancock Prospecting and would make each of Mrs Rinehart's children billionaires.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:11:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan plane hijackers hanged</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32911257#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Three Pakistani insurgents are hanged by the authorities, 17 years after they hijacked a passenger plane and tried to fly it to India.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan hangs Baloch insurgents behind 1998 plane hijacking
28 May 2015
From the section Asia
Two of the hijackers were pictured being taken away by police after they stormed the plane
Pakistan has hanged three Baloch insurgents, 17 years after they hijacked a passenger plane with 30 people on board.
The men were executed at jails in Karachi and Hyderabad.
They hijacked a Pakistan International Airlines flight in May 1998 and ordered the pilot to fly to India but the plane was diverted and stormed by troops.
Pakistan has put at least 130 people to death since lifting a moratorium on executions in December.
The men - Shabbir Rind, Shahsawar Baloch and Sabir Rind - were members of the left-wing Baloch Students' Organisation (BSO), who were demanding more resources, such as gas and electricity, for their region.
Death sentence
They were sentenced to be executed in October 1998 but remained on death row until a moratorium on executions was lifted after the Peshawar school massacre.
Four other men were hanged on Thursday at jails across the country. They were convicted in murder cases and were not linked to the hijackers.
PIA flight 554 took off from Turbat, in the south of Balochistan, and was heading for Karachi when the attackers boarded during a stop-over in Gwadar.
They commandeered the Fokker shortly after take-off, and demanded the captain fly directly to Delhi.
He told them there was not enough fuel, but agreed to bring the plane as far as Bhuj, an airstrip in Gujrat, India.
Instead, he landed in Hyderabad where security forces were waiting.
Executions around the world
Thousands of people protest against the death penalty every year
According to Amnesty International , Pakistan has executed 139 people since December 2014 - 132 were carried out this year
Figures for executions in other countries in 2015 are not yet available
By the end of 2014, the countries with the highest number of reported executions were: Iran: 289, Saudi Arabia: 90, Iraq: 61, USA: 35, and Sudan: 23
In 2013 the numbers were: Iran: 369, Iraq: 169, Saudi Arabia: 79, Somalia: 68, USA: 39
China and North Korea refuse to divulge information on the number of executions that take place within their borders
BBC Urdu's Riaz Sohail in Karachi reports that in order to let the hijackers think they were in India, authorities banned the use of loudspeakers in mosques around the airport.
Troops then stormed the plane and overpowered the hijackers. Passengers and crew were unharmed.
The hijacking on 24 May came just four days before Pakistan carried out nuclear tests in Balochistan, which the BSO opposed.
The province is one of the most underdeveloped regions in the country and has become the site of a long-running conflict between separatists and security forces.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:55:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eight 'exploited' L'Oreal heiress</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32923006#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A French court hands down jail sentences and fines to eight people found guilty of exploiting billionaire Liliane Bettencourt.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bettencourt case: Eight guilty of exploiting L'Oreal heiress
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Mrs Bettencourt, pictured here in 2011, is now under the guardianship of her family
A French court has found eight people guilty of exploiting 92-year-old L'Oreal heiress Liliane Bettencourt, one of the world's richest people.
Among those convicted was photographer Francois-Marie Banier, given three years in prison and ordered to pay 158 million ($170 million) in damages.
But a former ally of ex-President Nicolas Sarkozy was acquitted.
The verdict brings to an end a long-running case that began with a feud between Mrs Bettencourt and daughter.
In 2007, Francoise Bettencourt-Meyers filed charges against Banier, who had become a close companion of her mother.
Photographer Francois-Marie Banier was given jail time and a vast fine
Francoise Bettencourt-Meyers was in court to hear the verdict
Mrs Bettencourt had lavished the photographer with gifts worth hundreds of millions of dollars, including artworks by Picasso and Matisse.
She even made him her sole heir - although this was later revoked.
At the time Mrs Bettencourt said she was a free woman, and her daughter would just have to accept it.
Ms Bettencourt-Meyers said her mother, who medical records later revealed suffers from dementia and Alzheimer's disease, was being exploited by Banier.
The court agreed. The president of the hearing in Bourdeaux said Banier had "a real moral and psychological hold" on Mrs Bettencourt.
Among those sentenced was Patrice de Maistre, Mrs Bettencourt's wealth manager
Mrs Bettencourt's father Eugene Schueller founded cosmetics giant L'Oreal
Patrice de Maistre and Pascal Wilhelm, who oversaw her estimated $40.1 bn (26.1 bn) fortune, were given fines and 18-month jail sentences.
But Eric Woerth, who served as campaign treasurer during Nicolas Sarkozy's successful bid for the presidency in 2007, was cleared of taking donations from her.
Mr Sarkozy was placed under criminal investigation for allegedly receiving illegal funding from Mrs Bettencourt but this was dropped in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:48:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PM urges EU 'flexibility' on reforms</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-32909896#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>David Cameron tells his fellow European leaders they need to be "flexible and imaginative" as he demands reforms to the EU.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU referendum: David Cameron pushes leaders on reforms
28 May 2015
From the section UK Politics
comments
Mr Cameron met French President Francois Hollande
David Cameron has told his fellow European leaders they need to be "flexible and imaginative" as he demands reforms to the EU.
The PM was speaking alongside French President Francois Hollande during a tour of his European counterparts.
Mr Cameron wants to renegotiate the UK's relationship with Brussels ahead of an in/out referendum by 2017.
Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said the PM would warn that the UK could exit the EU unless reforms were agreed.
During talks with Mr Hollande, Mr Cameron said "the status quo is not good enough".
"I believe there are changes we can make that will not just benefit Britain, but the rest of Europe too," he added.
The PM will hold talks with German Chancellor Angela Merkel and Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz on Friday.
'Clear requirements'
He has not set out in full detail the reforms he is pushing for, but they will include tougher rules to prevent migrants claiming benefits.
He also wants safeguards to protect the City of London in the event of closer eurozone integration and an exemption for Britain from the EU drive for "ever closer union".
The prime minister also held talks with his Dutch counterpart, Mark Rutte
Earlier, arriving in The Hague for talks with Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte, Mr Cameron said they would focus on growth, jobs and a "pro-enterprise agenda" as well as "my plans for European reform".
Speaking on BBC Radio 4's Today programme, Mr Hammond played down talk of the referendum being held before 2017, the date by which it has been promised.
He also said the UK government had received legal advice saying changes to EU treaties would be needed to secure Mr Cameron's reforms - something that has so far been resisted by other EU leaders.
The foreign secretary said: "We have a clear set of requirements. The prime minister is very clear in dealing with European Union counterparts - that if we are not able to deliver on those big areas of concern that the British people have we will not win the referendum.
"And we expect our European Union partners to engage with us in delivering a package that will enable the British people to decide that they think Britain's future is best delivered inside the European Union."
Asked if that meant the government would still recommend Britain stay in the EU even if it was not able to secure major reforms, Mr Hammond said:  "If our partners do not agree with us - do not work with us to deliver that package - then we rule nothing out."
Mr Hammond said the talks process had just begun but the UK expected to secure a "substantive package of reforms" over the summer and into the winter months.
Referendum question
He said he wanted to negotiate reforms as quickly as possible but the timeline would depend on the "mechanism" set up for the negotiations.
He said "I don't think we've ruled out" having a referendum on a new deal next year but "what matters is getting it right rather than doing it quickly," adding that the government is "in the hands of our counterparts in the European Union".
French MP Christophe Premat, a member of President Hollande's Socialist Party, said the UK's referendum could not be used "as a threat".
He told BBC Radio 4's The World At One: "We respect that a referendum will be held in Great Britain, that's the destiny of the people in the UK. That's correct.
"But, at the same time, we can't use the referendum as a threat in order to have more space in the renegotiation. The method should be approached in another way."
The EU referendum bill, which has been published and was earlier presented to the Commons, contains details of the question and the commitment to staging the vote by the end of 2017.
Downing Street wants voters to be asked the question: "Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union?"
The Electoral Commission suggested this form of words - which would make those campaigning to stay in the EU the Yes campaign - in 2013.
A spokesman said: "We will consider the contents of the Bill when it is published and will make our views known as it progresses through Parliament to ensure voters' interests are put first."
EU referendum in focus
David Cameron is starting renegotiation of the terms of Britain's EU membership ahead of a referendum. Here is some further reading on what it all means:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:45:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Ten killed' by Baghdad car bombs</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32925959#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 10 people die in twin bomb attacks outside central Baghdad hotels, say Iraqi police</Description>
        <MainBody>'Ten killed' by Baghdad car bombs
28 May 2015
From the section Middle East
At least 30 people were reportedly injured in the blasts
At least 10 people have died after two car bomb attacks outside central Baghdad hotels, say Iraqi police.
The explosions happened just before midnight local time (21:00 GMT). The first hit the Babylon Hotel, near the Tigris river, and the second struck the Ishtar, formerly the Sheraton Hotel.
The Reuters news agency said at least 30 people were injured in the blasts.
A night-time curfew lasting 12 years was lifted in Baghdad in February.
The BBC's Orla Guerin, in Baghdad, tweeted that gunfire was also heard .
Police said they were trying to defuse a third car bomb they found in the Babylon Hotel car park.
The two hotels are regularly busy on Thursday nights and had been renovated in recent years.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:03:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Nusra 'told not to attack West'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32913509#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Al-Qaeda has ordered its affiliate in Syria not to use the country to launch attacks on the West, the leader of al-Nusra Front says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Al-Qaeda 'orders Syria's Al-Nusra Front not to attack West'
28 May 2015
From the section Middle East
The interview with Abu Mohammed al-Julani was his second with Al Jazeera since 2013
Al-Qaeda's affiliate in Syria has been ordered by the jihadist network not to use the country to launch attacks on the West, the group's leader has said.
In an interview with Al Jazeera , Abu Mohammed al-Julani said al-Nusra Front was focused on capturing Damascus and toppling President Bashar al-Assad.
He also promised to protect Syrian minorities that disavowed Mr Assad.
A rebel alliance including al-Nusra has been making gains in north-western Syria, capturing the city of Idlib.
Rebel fighters are now advancing on the Mediterranean coastal province of Latakia, a stronghold of the president and his heterodox Shia Muslim Alawite sect.
'One mission'
The hour-long interview with Julani broadcast on Wednesday night was his second with Qatar-based Al Jazeera since 2013, when al-Nusra Front split from what is now Islamic State (IS).
It was not clear where it was filmed and Julani's face was not shown. He sat on an ornate chair opposite the interviewer, Ahmed Mansour, with his back to the camera.
Al-Nusra Front and allied rebel groups took control of the northern city of Idlib in March
Julani said al-Nusra had been instructed by the overall leader of al-Qaeda, Ayman al-Zawahiri, to avoiding launching attacks abroad that might jeopardise its operations in Syria.
"We are only here to accomplish one mission, to fight the regime and its agents on the ground, including Hezbollah and others," he stressed, referring to the Lebanese Shia Islamist movement that is fighting alongside government forces.
"Al-Nusra Front doesn't have any plans or directives to target the West. We received clear orders not to use Syria as a launching pad to attack the US or Europe in order to not sabotage the true mission against the regime. Maybe al-Qaeda does that, but not here in Syria."
The al-Nusra leader also denied claims by the US that it had a secret cell called the " Khorasan Group " that was tasked with plotting attacks outside Syria.
"There is nothing called Khorasan group. The Americans came up with it to deceive the public. They claim that this secret group was set up to target the Americans but this is not right."
US cruise missiles struck alleged Khorasan Group bases in north-western Syria in September
The US-led coalition against Islamic State, to which al-Nusra is violently opposed, has bombed several bases that US officials say were used by the Khorasan group.
"Our options are open when it comes to targeting the Americans if they will continue their attacks against us in Syria. Everyone has the right to defend themselves," Julani warned.
A US intelligence official told the New York Times that Julani's claims were "self-serving propaganda".
Julani also vowed that al-Nusra would not harm members of Syria's Christian and Druze minorities who did not fight against it, and that Alawites would be safe if they "drop their weapons, disavow Assad, do not send their men to fight for him and return to Islam".
"The battle does not end in Qardaha, the Alawite village and the birthplace of the Assad clan," he explained. "Our war is not a matter of revenge against the Alawites despite the fact that in Islam, they are considered to be heretics."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:50:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cameron and Merkel in EU reform talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-32925582#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>David Cameron will try to persuade German Chancellor Angela Merkel to back him over EU reforms as the two leaders hold face-to-face talks.</Description>
        <MainBody>David Cameron and Angela Merkel in EU reform talks
29 May 2015
From the section UK Politics
David Cameron will hold talks with Angela Merkel later
David Cameron will try to persuade German Chancellor Angela Merkel to back him over EU reforms as the two leaders hold face-to-face talks later.
The PM is on a whistle-stop tour of Europe trying to gather support for changes he wants before holding the UK's EU membership referendum.
He urged his fellow EU leaders to be "flexible and imaginative".
But one of Germany's most senior businessmen said Europe should refuse to negotiate with him.
Volker Treier, who is deputy chief executive of Germany's chamber of commerce and industry, told the BBC the German business world was "astonished" the UK was holding a referendum at all.
'Carefully thought-out'
Asked how far Ms Merkel should go in accommodating Britain's requests, he said: "Our recommendation is not to deal under such circumstances."
Mr Cameron has not set out in full detail the reforms he is pushing for, but they will include tougher rules to prevent migrants claiming benefits.
He also wants safeguards to protect the City of London in the event of closer eurozone integration and an exemption for Britain from the EU drive for "ever closer union".
Securing the backing of Ms Merkel, who leads Europe's largest economy, will be crucial to his chances of negotiation success.
She has previously said she wanted the UK in a "strong and successful Europe" while stressing the importance of the free movement principle, which has seen a rise in the number of EU migrants coming to the UK.
Mr Cameron has met French President Francois Hollande
The prime minister also held talks with his Dutch counterpart, Mark Rutte
BBC Europe editor Katya Adler said Mr Cameron's four-country tour - taking in the Netherlands and France on Thursday, followed by Poland and Germany on Friday - was "carefully thought-out".
The Netherlands and Germany were seen as "open to reforming the single market", she said, while France was "trickier" and Poland seen as a "rising star".
Ahead of formal negotiations "tone is as important as content", she said, adding: "As he travels around Europe he will find an appetite for reform - but David Cameron's trickiest trick will be to persuade leaders that his way is the right way."
During his talks with the French President, Francois Hollande, Mr Cameron said: "The status quo is not good enough".
"I believe there are changes we can make that will not just benefit Britain, but the rest of Europe too," he added.
Mr Cameron's tour coincided with the publication of his government's EU Referendum Bill, which contains details of the question and the commitment to staging the vote by the end of 2017.
Downing Street wants voters to be asked the question: "Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union?"
The Electoral Commission suggested this form of words - which would make those campaigning to stay in the EU the Yes campaign - in 2013.
Labour is backing the bill, meaning it is likely to speed through the House of Commons.
EU referendum in focus
David Cameron is starting renegotiation of the terms of Britain's EU membership ahead of a referendum. Here is some further reading on what it all means:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:03:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jail terms under 'legal highs' law</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-32919712#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A new "blanket ban" on so-called legal highs will carry prison sentences of up to seven years, the government says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jail terms under 'legal highs' law
29 May 2015
From the section UK Politics
Legal highs can be smoked, snorted or swallowed
A new "blanket ban" on so-called legal highs will carry prison sentences of up to seven years, the government says.
Ministers are to publish draft laws they say are a "landmark" in prohibiting the substances' production, distribution, sale and supply.
Legal highs, officially called new psychoactive substances, have been linked to a number of deaths.
Ministers said young people who took them were "taking exceptional risks with their health".
A blanket ban on legal highs, which are often sold online or on the high street, was in the Conservative Party's election manifesto and featured in the Queen's Speech.
Labour also promised to ban their sale and distribution in its manifesto .
'Fundamental change'
The Psychoactive Substances Bill applied to "any substance intended for human consumption that is capable of producing a psychoactive effect", the government said.
Alcohol, tobacco and caffeine will be excluded, and there are also exemptions for food and medical products, while controlled drugs will continue to be regulated by existing laws.
The new restrictions will also extend to the sale of nitrous oxide - also known as laughing gas or "hippy crack" - for human use.
There is currently no blanket ban on the sale of legal highs, also known as new psychoactive substances
Legal highs are psychoactive drugs that contain various chemical ingredients, some of which are illegal while others are not
They produce similar effects to illegal drugs like cocaine, cannabis and ecstasy
They are sold in a variety of forms, including powder, pills, liquids, capsules, perforated tabs and smoking mixtures
The substances are often sold in "head shops" alongside drug paraphernalia
What are legal highs?
The government said the "legitimate sale" of nitrous oxide, which is also used for food processing, medicinal and industrial purposes, would not be affected.
Home Office minister Mike Penning said the measures would "fundamentally change the way we tackle new psychoactive substances".
'Cat and mouse'
They would end the "game of cat and mouse" whereby new drugs appeared on the market more quickly than the government could identify and ban them, he said.
He added: "The blanket ban will give police and other law enforcement agencies greater powers to tackle the reckless trade in psychoactive substances, instead of having to take a substance-by-substance approach."
Legal highs are not controlled under the Misuse of Drugs Act, although individual substances, such as mephedrone, have been outlawed.
The government's proposals would apply throughout the United Kingdom, and would include powers to seize and destroy legal highs and to search people, premises and vehicles.
Civil measures - including prohibition notices and prohibition orders - will also be possible.
Commander Simon Bray, of the National Police Chiefs' Council, said: "A blanket ban on new psychoactive substances will make it simpler for law enforcement to deal with those drugs which are potentially unsafe but which may not yet be controlled."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:13:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Honda, Fiat and BMW in airbag recall</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32925357#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Three major carmakers have expanded recalls of vehicles with faulty Takata airbags.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fiat Chrysler, Honda and BMW expand airbag recall
28 May 2015
From the section Business
Three big carmakers have expanded recalls of vehicles with faulty airbags.
The move from Fiat Chrysler, Honda and BMW comes after Takata Corp, the Japanese airbag maker last week said the number of vehicles affected was 53 million globally.
Of that figure, 34 million are in the US, making it the country's largest ever recall of cars.
The faulty airbags, when exposed to too much moisture, can explode.
Regulators have linked the problem to six deaths worldwide, all in Honda vehicles.
Honda has called back about 690,000 cars in the US and Japan.
Since 2008, Honda has recalled about 20 million vehicles around the world with Takata air bag parts.
Fiat Chrysler announced an expansion of its recalls of vehicles with Takata air bags to about 5.22 million worldwide, involving models from 2003 to 2011. About 4.5 million of those vehicles are in the US.
Most of the vehicles have been involved in previous recalls and are from the 2003 to 2011 model years, the car maker said.
BMW in North America is recalling 20 models from 2002 to 2006 that contain Takata driver-side front air bags. Regulators said the air bag module will be replaced.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:49:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ireland votes through Aer Lingus deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32925347#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Republic of Ireland's parliament has approved the sale of the nation's 25% stake in Aer Lingus to British Airways owner, IAG.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ireland's parliament clears Aer Lingus stake sale
28 May 2015
From the section Business
The Republic of Ireland's parliament has approved the sale of a stake in Aer Lingus to British Airways owner, IAG.
Irish lawmakers voted by 74 votes to 51 in favour of the deal.
Some MPS had expressed concern about the sale of the 25% stake, fearing that services between Irish airports and London's Heathrow could be cut.
However on Tuesday , after months of negotiation, the government and IAG announced an agreement under which IAG promised to maintain routes.
Under the deal IAG agreed to a legally binding commitment to maintain current services between Heathrow and Dublin, Cork and Shannon for at least seven years.
Also, Aer Lingus will operate its international passenger services under the Aer Lingus brand and its head office will remain in the Republic of Ireland.
In order to take complete control of Aer Lingus, IAG still needs to reach an agreement with the remaining big shareholder, Ryanair.
Ryanair, which holds a 29.8% stake, says it will consider a bid when it receives a formal offer.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:51:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chip maker Avago buys rival Broadcom</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32919602#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Avago Technologies, one of the world's biggest manufacturers of semiconductors, is buying its California-based rival Broadcom for $37bn.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chip manufacturer Avago buys rival Broadcom for $37bn
28 May 2015
From the section Business
Avago Technologies, one of the world's biggest manufacturers of semiconductors, is buying its California-based rival Broadcom for $37bn (24bn).
Between them, the two firms employ more than 20,000 staff worldwide with combined annual sales of 15bn (10bn).
Avago, based in both the US and Singapore, said the deal was a "landmark" transaction.
It is using a combination of cash and shares to pay for Broadcom.
"The combination of Avago and Broadcom creates a global diversified leader in wired and wireless communication semiconductors," said Hock Tan, Avago's chief executive.
Broadcom makes semiconductors for set-top boxes, mobile phones and network equipment, and its chips are used in smartphones made by Apple and Samsung.
Avago has been expanding rapidly.  Broadcom is the sixth company to be bought by Avago since the start of 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:00:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifa to vote on Blatter v Prince Ali</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/32925307</Link>
        <Description>The vote to elect Fifa's president takes place on Friday as Prince Ali bin al-Hussein challenges current chief Sepp Blatter.</Description>
        <MainBody>print
Fifa election: Sepp Blatter and Prince Ali are presidential candidates
Fifa's 209 member associations will vote to elect a new president on Friday with the crisis engulfing football's governing body hanging over it.
Jordanian Prince Ali bin al-Hussein, 39, is standing against 79-year-old Swiss Sepp Blatter, who has been president since of Fifa since 1998.
The vote takes place after bribery and racketeering charges were laid against top Fifa officials by US prosecutors.
Blatter resisted calls to resign led by Uefa president Michel Platini.
Instead Blatter, who is seeking a fifth term of office at world football's governing body, promised to restore trust in Fifa and "find a way to fix things".
Opening a meeting of Fifa's annual congress in Zurich on Thursday on the eve of the presidential election, he said: "These are unprecedented and difficult times for Fifa.
"It must fall to me to uphold responsibility for the well-being of the organisation."
Blatter has condemned the "action of individuals" for bringing "shame and humiliation" on football in the corruption scandal.
But he said that although many held him "ultimately responsible" for the football community, he could "not monitor everyone all of the time".
Swiss authorities have launched a second investigation into the awarding of the 2018 and 2022 World Cups to Russia and Qatar respectively.
How does the voting work?
Before the voting is opened, the candidates will have the opportunity to speak for 15 minutes to present their programme.
Each of Fifa's 209 member national associations gets one vote - so the likes of footballing minnows American Samoa have just as much of a say as nations such as England.
It is a paper vote rather than an electronic one and the member associations cast their votes by secret ballot, in alphabetical order.
Sepp Blatter: "I cannot monitor everyone all of the time... those who are corrupt in football are in a minority"
In the first round, a candidate needs to get two-thirds of the vote to be declared the winner - if the vote is closer than that, a second round of voting is held, where a simple majority is enough.
So the winning candidate would need 105 votes in the second round, if every member casts a valid vote, to win.
Fifa's secretary general Jerome Valcke, assisted by a number of scrutineers, will be charge of the conduct distribution and counting of the ballot papers.
Fifa's rules point out that if it receives more ballot papers than there are members, the election will be declared void and re-run.
Is it possible to abstain?
Yes - and six members did so during the last Fifa presidential election in 2011 - one of them was England's Football Association (FA).
It did so after Blatter's only rival, Mohammed bin Hammam, pulled out days before the election after being suspended over bribery allegations.
Blatter was re-elected after receiving 186 of the 203 votes cast.
The last four Fifa presidential elections
2011: Blatter was unopposed because his rival Mohamed Bin Hammam, president of the Asian Football Federation, pulled out after being suspended over bribery allegations.
2007: No other candidate was put forward to challenge Blatter.
2002: Blatter saw off the challenge of Issa Hayatou, president of the African confederation Caf.
1998: The Swiss succeeded Joao Havelange and won a bitter election against former Uefa president Lennart Johansson.
What happened to the other candidates?
Originally there were five potential candidates to stand against Blatter in the election.
Ex-Tottenham and Newcastle midfielder David Ginola, backed by a betting company, announced in January his intention to stand.
But the 48-year-old Frenchman withdrew two weeks later having failed to secure the backing of five football associations, a requirement for standing in the election.
Ginola's compatriot and former diplomat Jerome Champagne, who worked for Fifa for 11 years as an executive before leaving in 2010, revealed last September he planned to challenge Blatter.
Prince Ali will stand against Sepp Blatter, who is seeking a fifth term in office
Champagne, 56, failed to win enough support in his bid to unseat Blatter and pulled out at the beginning of February.
Former Portugal midfielder Luis Figo, 42, joined the race in January and secured enough support to stand as a legitimate candidate against Blatter.
Like Figo, Royal Dutch Football Association (KNVB) president Michael van Praag, 67, was also a viable candidate for the election after he gained the necessary support of five national associations.
However, both Figo and Van Praag pulled out of the running on the same day last week as to not split the anti-Blatter vote, which left Prince Ali as the only rival.
We know about Blatter, but who is Prince Ali?
Prince Ali, the son of the late King Hussein and the late Queen Alia, attended Sandhurst military academy in England before joining his country's armed forces.
Prince Ali of Jordan: The man taking on Sepp Blatter
He is the brother-in-law of leading racehorse owner Sheikh Mohammed, the ruler of Dubai. Prince Ali successfully championed the lifting of Fifa's ban on the hijab - the veil worn by Muslims - in women's football.
Prince Ali is head of the West Asian Football Federation and was one of a number of officials who called for the publication of ethics investigator Michael Garcia's report into allegations of corruption surrounding the 2018 and 2022 World Cup bids.
Prince Ali said: "It is time to shift the focus away from administrative controversy and back to sport. The headlines should be about football, not about Fifa."
How will the election unfold?
Blatter has been publicly backed by the football confederations of Asia (AFC) and Africa (Caf), which means that most of their member nations are expected to vote for him.
FA chairman Greg Dyke: ''Fifa have got to be rid of Blatter''
Prince Ali is the favoured candidate of European confederation Uefa, so he is likely to pick up most of the European votes. Platini believes "45 or 46" from 54 European members could back him.
It is not quite so clear where the votes from the North American (Concacaf) and South American (Conmebol) confederations will go.
In the past these regions have been loyal to Blatter but there are suggestions that at least some of their member nations will back Prince Ali, especially in light of the recent scandals. Prince Ali himself is said to believe he has the support of 60 nations outside Europe.
FA chairman Greg Dyke has already called on Blatter to go while Football Association of Ireland chief executive John Delaney says the president should step down for "the good of the game".
Scottish FA chief executive Stewart Regan claims Prince Ali is the "only credible candidate", while Football Association of Wales chief executive Jonathan Ford says "change is needed in Fifa" ahead of the vote.
The bookmakers currently make Blatter the 1/2 favourite, with Ali's chances rated at 13/8.
What happens if Blatter wins?
Good question.
The BBC has learned that Uefa could call for an extraordinary general meeting of Fifa's congress if Blatter is victorious.
If 20% of members agree with the motion, the meeting would have to be held within three months - and a motion of no confidence would almost certainly be put forward.
Uefa head Michel Platini: "Blatter will convince the majority to vote for him but he has already lost, Fifa has already lost"
Uefa did not want the vote to go ahead because it risked turning it into "a farce", although they decided not to boycott the congress.
That is not to say a wholesale Uefa boycott of Fifa or its tournaments could not happen further down the line. "All of these things have been discussed," Stewart Regan told BBC Radio Scotland.
FA vice-chairman David Gill also says he will resign from Fifa's executive committee if Blatter is re-elected.
It seems unlikely that either Russia or Qatar will be stripped of the World Cups, though.
Despite Fifa's numerous attempts to prove the bidding process was fair, rumours persist that not everything was above board - and the Swiss investigation into the bidding process has only added to those suspicions.
However, Fifa is adamant there will be no re-run of the bidding process, and that position would be unlikely to change should Blatter stay in power.
He has powerful allies in this regard. Russian president Vladimir Putin is a supporter of Blatter and has accused the US of overstepping its authority, suggesting the arrests were part of an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from his country.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:00:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murray tested but into third round</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/32917423</Link>
        <Description>Andy Murray beats Portugal's Joao Sousa in four sets to secure his place in the French Open third round.</Description>
        <MainBody>Andy Murray reaches French Open third round with Joao Sousa win
By Piers Newbery BBC Sport at Roland Garros
French Open
Venue: Roland Garros, Paris Dates: 24 May - 7 June
Coverage: Live text and BBC Radio 5 live sports extra commentaries on every Andy Murray match and other key matches.
Murray wins 12th clay-court match in a row
Last Briton left in singles draws
Wins in two hours and 30 minutes
Receives two time violations on his serve
Andy Murray was given a stern test by Joao Sousa before securing his place in the French Open third round.
The Briton, seeded third, won 6-2 4-6 6-4 6-1 to set up a match with Australia's Nick Kyrgios.
Murray began and ended the contest in fine form, but showed his frustration as Portugal's Sousa fought back in the second and third sets.
Fellow British number one Heather Watson lost 6-2 6-4 to American Sloane Stephens on Court Seven.
That leaves Murray as the only remaining Briton in the singles at Roland Garros.
Murray at the French Open
The British number one has twice reached the semi-finals. He first got there in 2011 and again in 2014 but lost to Rafael Nadal on both occasions. The Spaniard is a potential semi-final opponent this year.
The Scot has now taken his clay-court record in 2015 to 12-0.
However, his first meeting with Sousa on clay proved a far tougher challenge than his five straight-sets wins over the Portuguese on hard courts.
"For a lot of the match I played very well," Murray told BBC Sport.
"I didn't really help myself in the second set. I served badly, which made it difficult.
"Then at the end of that second set he was able to dictate a lot of the points, and he played very well at the beginning of the third set and had some chances there as well.
"I was happy with the way I was able to turn it around and make some adjustments out there on the court, which turned the match in my favour."
Another regulation victory appeared likely when he powered through the first set, dropping just three points on serve.
That area of his game began to falter as the skies darkened in the second set, a first-serve percentage of just 36% allowing Sousa to tee off with his forehand especially.
Murray was given a time violation on his way to dropping serve at 3-5 and, after reclaiming the break immediately in an intense game - screaming "Let's Go!" - he let his serve slip once more to hand over the set.
He was now up against an opponent, and a crowd, that was buzzing with expectancy, and Sousa had two chances to break early in the third, only to fire a return long and watch as an ace flew past him.
A second time violation, which led to the loss of a first serve, did nothing to brighten Murray's mood.
"Probably I was playing too slow and I didn't argue at all with the umpire," he explained.
"It was just on the second one, I was up at the line in good time but they were still playing the highlight of the point before, so I didn't serve when that was going on.
"I tried to speed up after that and I think I did a good job of that."
Murray was becoming increasingly mired in a battle, urging himself to "calm down, calm down", but as the threat of a storm overhead passed, so Murray's mind cleared.
A blistering backhand winner down the line gave him a break point at 3-3 and a heavy forehand into the corner clinched a lead he would not relinquish.
Murray served out the set and broke at the start of the fourth, before whipping a cross-court forehand winner for 3-0 that brought coach Amelie Mauresmo to her feet in the stands.
The two-time semi-finalist closed out the match in a similar vein to how he had started, breaking again to wrap up victory in two hours and 30 minutes.
Murray was bemused to be interviewed by a kilt-wearing Fabrice Santoro at the end of his match
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:46:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McIlroy posts nightmare opening 80</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/golf/32915865</Link>
        <Description>Rory McIlroy faces a battle to make the cut at the Irish Open after slumping to a first-round nine-over-par 80 at Royal County Down.</Description>
        <MainBody>Irish Open: Rory McIlroy makes nightmare start at County Down
Dubai Duty Free Irish Open first round leaders
-4 P Harrington (Ire), M Kieffer (Ger); -3 S Hansen (Den); -2 D Willett (Eng), S Kjeldsen (Den), E Grillo (Arg); -1 L Donald (Eng), M Ford (Eng), R Karlberg (Swe), C Wood (Eng), A Levy (Fra), T Fisher Jnr (SA), A Hansen (Den) Selected others: Par R Fowler (USA), E Els (SA); +4 S Garcia (Spa); +9 R McIlroy (NI)
Rory McIlroy faces an uphill battle to make the cut at the Irish Open after carding a nightmare nine-over-par 80 in the first round at Royal County Down.
McIlroy, 26, posted five bogeys in his first nine holes and dropped a further four shots in his second nine.
The world number one has missed the cut at the last two Irish Open tournaments.
Ireland's Padraig Harrington, the 2007 winner, shares the lead with Maximilian Kieffer of Germany on four under par with Soren Hansen one shot behind.
England's Danny Willett, Argentinian Emiliano Grillo and Dane Soren Kjeldsen are two off the pace after carding rounds of 69 at the Newcastle links course.
English trio Luke Donald, Matt Ford and Chris Wood are among seven players nicely placed on one under.
Starting at the 10th, world number one McIlroy, who pledged to donate his prize money this week to his charitable foundation, the official tournament host, strayed occasionally off the tee, was repeatedly erratic with his iron play and struggled with the putter throughout.
The Northern Irishman has won two of his last four tournaments, the WGC-Cadillac Match Play and Wells Fargo tournament at Quail Hollow, but missed the cut at last week's PGA Championship at Wentworth.
Fascinating facts
The Irish Open has been staged at Royal County Down on three occasions, most recently back in 1939.
Royal County Down hosted the Senior British Open on three consecutive years, from 2000 to 2002.
Only one player from Northern Ireland has ever won the Irish Open - Fred Daly at Portmarnock in 1946.
Rickie Fowler was a member of the United States team which won the 2007 Walker Cup at Royal County Down. Rory McIlroy was part of the European team.
"I was caught between trying to play two ways. My poor iron play led to missed greens and I left myself a lot of eight to 12 foot putts for par, pretty much all of which I missed," said McIlroy after his round.
McIlroy's playing partner, American world number nine Rickie Fowler, is in contention near the top of the leaderboard on level par, but the third member of the illustrious group, Germany's Martin Kaymer, has a lot of ground to make up on eight over.
Fowler was making his first appearance since securing the second PGA Tour win of his career in The Players Championship earlier this month.
Graeme McDowell was two under after 15 holes but the former US Open winner bogeyed the final three holes of his round, the seventh, eighth and ninth, to drop back to one over.
The third of the host nation's recent major winners, European Ryder Cup captain Darren Clarke, lies well back on four over, but his compatriot Michael Hoey fared better on level par.
Spaniard Miguel Angel Jimenez is one over, while Lee Westwood registered a three-over-74 in the windy conditions in front of a sell-out 20,000 crowd at the seaside links.
Ernie Els, playing in the Irish Open for the first time since 1998, had a level-par round, but 1999 tournament winner Sergio Garcia is down the pack on four over.
Germany's Maximilian Kieffer shares the lead with Padraig Harrington after the first round of the 2015 Irish Open
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Thu May 28 11:09:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BB King honoured with procession</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32912756#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Blues artist BB King has been honoured with a street procession in Memphis a fortnight after his death at the age of 89.</Description>
        <MainBody>BB King honoured with Memphis street procession
28 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
'Lucille', one of BB King's beloved guitars, was carried before his hearse
Thousands have lined the streets of Memphis, Tennessee to pay tribute to blues artist BB King, who died earlier this month.
At an event on Wednesday, a Dixieland jazz band walked ahead of a black hearse down Beale Street - a street synonymous with American blues music.
It is where the young King was nicknamed the Beale Street Blues Boy - a moniker later shortened to BB.
King died on 14 May. US authorities are investigating claims he was poisoned.
His daughters have alleged the musician was given "foreign substances to induce his premature death" by his business manager Laverne Toney and personal assistant Myron Johnson.
Beale Street is considered the birthplace of the Memphis blues
Lawyers for King's estate have said the claims are unfounded and disrespectful.
The coroner initially said he had died of a series of small strokes connected to his Type 2 diabetes, although a further autopsy has now been carried out, with results expected in eight weeks.
At the street procession honouring King's memory, the Memphis-based Mighty Souls Brass Band played the song When the Saints Go Marching In.
Singer Ruby Wilson, the 'Queen of Beale Street', performed at the memorial
Drummer Rodd Bland - the son of the late blues singer Bobby 'Blue' Bland - carried one of King's signature Lucille guitars.
Artists including singer Ruby Wilson, Bobby Rush and the Ghost Town Blues Band all performed tributes on stage.
"Such a beautiful day," Memphis native Gary Daly told the Associated Press. "It's a great tribute to a wonderful contributor to the world of music.
A banner hung up on BB King's Blues Club was covered with warm wishes from fans
"It's been really amazing to see the people of Memphis coming out, having a great time together, celebrating a wonderful, loving man."
King's body is being taken to Indianola, Mississippi, which King considered his hometown, for his funeral on Saturday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:54:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top Gear car plate complaints rejected</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32914817#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC Trust rejects complaints over Top Gear's Patagonia special, in which a car number plate appeared to refer to the Falklands conflict.</Description>
        <MainBody>Top Gear car plate complaints rejected by BBC Trust
28 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
The crew fled Argentina following protests over the plates
The BBC Trust has rejected complaints over Top Gear's Patagonia special, in which a car number plate which appeared to refer to the 1982 Falklands war.
The production team fled Argentina following protests over the use of the registration number H982 FKL.
Complainants doubted that the number plate was randomly allocated. Their concerns were rejected by the BBC but were passed to the trust on appeal.
It found there was no evidence of "a deliberate reference" to the war.
The initial complaints, received prior to the programme's broadcast, said the connection with the Falklands War would have been clear to the producers and the plates should have been changed.
Two complainants also wanted the BBC to apologise to Argentina for any offence. They said the decision to air the programme as a Christmas special was particularly offensive.
A response from the BBC Complaints Management and Editorial Standards Adviser included a blog written by the executive producer of Top Gear Andy Willman, denying allegations the number plate had been deliberately chosen by the production team.
The complaints were subsequently investigated by the controller of entertainment commissioning who said: "To date, there is nothing that we have seen or read since the team returned which supports the view that the number plates in question were deliberately employed, which is in-keeping with what production staff and the presenters have said."
As such, the complaints were not upheld before being escalated to the BBC Trust, which is the corporation's governing body.
Reviewing the appeals, the trust's Head of Editorial Standards said they did not have a reasonable prospect of success and proposed not to put them before trustees.
This decision was rejected by the complainants, who asked for a review.
Regarding the complaint about the lack of a BBC apology, trustees said "in the absence of any evidence that the choice of number plate was deliberate it was a matter for the Executive as to whether they wished to apologise."
They agreed the BBC had been open about its investigation into the complaints and that amounted to an explanation of why the BBC would not be apologising.
Trustees said they did not consider that it was appropriate or proportionate to take this matter on appeal because the complaint did not raise a matter of substance and therefore was not a matter in which the Trust would get involved.
The Top Gear special saw presenter Jeremy Clarkson and co-stars Richard Hammond and James May drive the famous Patagonian highway - Route 40 - to the southern city of Ushuaia.
All three have now left the programme, following Clarkson's altercation with a producer, which prompted the BBC not to renew his contract.
Producer Andy Willman has also stepped down.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:05:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tracy Morgan settles crash lawsuit</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32911831#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Comedian and 30 Rock actor Tracy Morgan settles his legal action against Walmart over the car crash which left him seriously injured and killed his friend.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tracy Morgan settles Walmart crash lawsuit
28 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Morgan starred in US sitcom 30 Rock and Saturday Night Live
Comic and 30 Rock star Tracy Morgan has settled his legal case against Walmart over a crash which left him seriously injured, and killed his friend.
A Walmart truck crashed in to the back of Morgan's limo in June 2014, with prosecutors alleging the driver had not slept for more than 24 hours.
Comedian James McNair, known as Jimmy Mack, was killed in the crash.
Morgan's lawyer, Benedict Morelli, said Walmart "took full responsibility for the accident".
All sides had worked hard to reach the undisclosed agreement, he added.
Morgan said Walmart "did right by me and my family, and for my associates and their families".
"I am grateful that the case was resolved amicably.''
Driver Kevin Roper has pleaded not guilty to death by auto
A representative for supermarket giant Walmart also called it an "amicable settlement".
Traumatic head injury
Morgan, 46,  was left in a critical condition following the crash, suffering a traumatic head injury, a broken leg, nose and ribs.
In March, his lawyer said the star had not yet been able to get back to work but was "working very hard to get better, physically, emotionally and mentally."
The comedian, who rose to fame on Saturday Night Live, will give his first interview since the crash to NBC's Today on Monday, 1 June.
Morgan will be interviewed by Matt Lauer live in the Rockefeller Center - which was the setting for 30 Rock - and will be joined by his lawyer Benedict Morelli.
Walmart had previously reached an agreement with the family of James McNair, 62, who grew up with Morgan in New York.
Their driver, Kevin Roper of Jonesboro, Georgia, has pleaded not guilty to death by auto and assault and is currently on bail.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:02:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Putin shows his support for Blatter</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32911702#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has accused the US of trying to block Sepp Blatter from being re-elected as Fifa president.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Fifa corruption: Vladimir Putin expresses support for Blatter
28 May 2015 Last updated at 13:02 BST
Russian President Vladimir Putin has said he supports a fifth term for Sepp Blatter as Fifa president and has accused the US of trying to block his re-election.
Mr Blatter was not among the 14 people charged by the US authorities on Wednesday with racketeering, fraud and money laundering.
Mr Putin said: "One thing is clear - this has nothing to do with the United States.  These employees are not American citizens and if something did happen, then it didn't happen on the territory of the United States."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Thu May 28 07:11:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Macau's casinos gamble on growth</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32908834#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Macau's biggest casinos plan to invest $25bn in hotels and casinos over the next two years, despite a plunge in gambling revenues.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Macau's casinos gamble on new customers
28 May 2015 Last updated at 05:11 BST
Macau's biggest casinos plan to invest $25bn (16bn) in hotels and casinos over the next two years, despite a plunge in gambling revenues.
The Chinese territory has seen a big fall in business from mainland China following a crackdown by authorities on lavish spending.
Gaming firms hope the new facilities will broaden Macau's appeal and attract holidaymakers and families.
Juliana Liu has more from Macau.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:37:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Why brave treacherous Bay of Bengal?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32922210#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC's Justin Rowlatt travelled to Teknaf on the southern coast of Bangladesh, from where hundreds of migrants begin the perilous journey across the Bay of Bengal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Why Bangladeshi migrants brave treacherous Bay of Bengal
28 May 2015 Last updated at 18:37 BST
An international summit to discuss the migrant crisis in south east Asia begins in Thailand on Friday.
25,000 people are estimated to have set sail from the Bay of Bengal in the first three months of this year alone.
They are hoping to reach Malaysia, and about half of them come from Bangladesh.
The BBC's Justin Rowlatt travelled to Teknaf on the southern coast of Bangladesh, and discovered that treacherous seas are far from the only concern facing those desperate enough to risk the journey.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Thu May 28 02:00:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Police recruits get tough in Ukraine</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32879599#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>David Stern visited the police academy in Ukraine where new police officers are being trained as part of a major programme of reforms to the service.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Ukraine police receive Western-style training
28 May 2015 Last updated at 00:00 BST
Ukraine is introducing major reforms to its police force, in the hopes of rooting out corruption and overhauling what is still a very Soviet institution.
Instructors from the US are teaching the latest western methods to a group of recruits in Kiev, the capital, which is serving as a test case.
A quarter of the recruits are women, something completely new in Ukraine.
Many people are watching closely how well the programme does, as an indication of the strength of the country's reforms, following last year's pro-western revolution.
The BBC's David Stern visited the police academy where the new police officers are being trained.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Thu May 28 05:39:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: South Sudan faces food shortage</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32911043#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The UN warns that more people are at risk of hunger in South Sudan than at any time since it became independent four years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
South Sudan faces 'worst levels of food insecurity'
28 May 2015 Last updated at 03:39 BST
There has been a warning that more people are at risk of hunger in South Sudan than at any time since it became independent four years ago.
The UN World Food Programme says about 40% of the population will require help in the next few months.
Saskia O'Donoghue reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:50:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: 'Diblings' - the siblings created through donors</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-32914087#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Being a 'dibling' - a child biologically connected through egg or sperm donation, can lead to a large family of half brothers and sisters, as the Victoria Derbyshire programme finds out.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
'Diblings': The siblings created from the same donor
28 May 2015 Last updated at 11:50 BST
'Diblings' - or donor-conceived siblings - are children who are biologically connected through donated eggs or sperm.
One-year-old Sam has travelled with his parents from the United States to meet his two-year-old half brother Iori in London.
They are part of a network of twelve children whose parents all used sperm from the same donor.
Watch Victoria Derbyshire weekdays from 09:15-11:00 BST on BBC Two, the BBC News Channel, and online.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Thu May 28 07:35:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Palestinians want Israel football ban</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32911101#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Palestinian Football Association is asking Fifa to suspend Israel from world football, just as it once suspended apartheid South Africa and Slobodan Milosevic's Yugoslavia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Palestinians push for Israel football suspension
28 May 2015 Last updated at 05:35 BST
The Palestinian Football Association is asking Fifa to suspend Israel from world football, just as it once suspended apartheid South Africa and Slobodan Milosevic's Yugoslavia.
The PFA says the Israeli FA has violated rules relating to racism, players' free movement and where clubs are based.
Suspension would mean Israeli teams would not be able to take part in the Champions League and Euro 2016.
Kevin Connolly reports from Jerusalem.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Thu May 28 02:00:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Street workout to get SA children fit</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32901214#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>South African street workout competitor Smith Mangena is taking the sport back to the townships to keep young people healthy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Street workout to get South African children fit
28 May 2015 Last updated at 00:00 BST
Muscle-ups, front lever, and the human flag are exercises that you will rarely see in the gym.
They are extreme body weight only movements performed by competitors in the growing sport of street workout.
The sport can be practised anywhere, at any time and for free.
Smith Mangena, from Soweto in South Africa, was the first African to compete in the world championships.
He is now taking the sport back into the townships to help keep young people healthy in a nation with one of the highest obesity rates in the world.
Video journalist: Christian Parkinson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:03:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Are more people on the move?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-32912867#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Are more people on the move than ever before?</Description>
        <MainBody>Migration: Are more people on the move than ever before?
By Paul Adams BBC News
28 May 2015
From the section World
From the Mediterranean to the Andaman, it's been a season of despair, the faces of migrants haunting television screens and dominating headlines.
Harrowing stories have emerged of death, starvation and abuse at the hands of people smugglers. And from the world's new and continuing conflict zones, there have been new mass movements, across borders and within states.
Half a million Yemenis have been internally displaced since March. One hundred thousand Burundians have fled into neighbouring countries since April.
The statistics can be numbing - 7.6 million Syrians, homeless inside their own country, now make up a fifth of all internally displaced people (IDPs) in the world.
Are more people on the move than ever before?
Today's map of the world is a complex spider's web of movement. Our map only represents the larger recent trends.
But it helps to explain why, in 2013, there were 232 million "international migrants" in the world (defined by the UN as people who have lived a year or longer outside their country of birth).
This figure includes refugees, asylum seekers and economic migrants - anyone who has crossed a border, legally or illegally, to escape disaster or persecution or simply to pursue a better life.
And it's almost certainly an under-estimate.
Where do international migrants live?
Half of all international migrants live in just 10 countries. The largest number (46 million) reside in the United States. By 2013, the US was host to 13 million people born in Mexico, but the fastest growth was among recent arrivals from China (2.2m) and India (2.1m).
Russia's second place is a result of Moscow's strong ties to former states of the Soviet Union, particularly Ukraine and Kazakhstan.
In Europe, Germany and France host some of the largest migrant populations (from Turkey and Algeria respectively), while vast numbers of migrant workers from southern Asia still live and work in Saudi Arabia and the Gulf.
In the UAE, international migrants make up a staggering 84% of the population.
Deadly crisis in the Mediterranean
Dramatic scenes from the Mediterranean have captured headlines for the past two years.
Before the fall of the Libyan dictator, Muammar Gaddafi, numbers of migrants making the perilous crossing were actually declining.
Oil-rich Libya offered employment opportunities and Gaddafi was persuaded by the EU to limit onward movement.
But the year of his violent ouster, 2011, saw a sudden spike, and Libya's descent into chaos since 2012 has had a dramatic effect.
In 2014, more than 170,000 migrants arrived in Italy, the largest influx into one country in EU history.
Perilous routes through Africa to Europe
The spider's web is at its most complex here. Some of these journeys are epic, with sub-Saharan and West African migrants crossing two perilous seas, one of sand and one of water, before arriving in Europe.
These journeys can take weeks or years to complete, with young men from Gambia, Senegal and Nigeria passing through several countries and relying heavily on people smugglers.
Among the largest groups crossing from Libya this year: thousands of Eritreans fleeing long-term conscription, as well as large numbers of Somalis and Nigerians.
In the eastern Mediterranean, huge numbers of Syrians cross from Turkey to Greece, accompanied by Afghans and Iraqis.
Syria: A displaced nation
Syria's civil war has now uprooted half the country's pre-war population. More than four million Syrians are refugees in neighbouring countries, with a much larger number internally displaced.
Syria is the main country of origin of asylum seekers in the industrialised world. This huge, growing exodus is one big reason why the number of forcibly displaced people in the world is now higher than it's been at any time since World War Two.
It also helps to explain why, when it comes to housing refugees, the burden falls more and more heavily on developing countries (86%, up from 70% a decade ago).
In the hands of people smugglers
Graphic scenes of the suffering experienced by refugees afloat in the Andaman Sea have drawn international attention to another desperate story of people smuggling and human deprivation.
The numbers are smaller than the Mediterranean, but the issues are similar.
Friday's meeting in Bangkok will attempt to grapple with this latest migrant crisis, but hopes are not high for any kind of action plan.
Journeys north through Mexico
The Mexico-Texas border remains the world's largest migration corridor. Mexicans are still the largest single group apprehended by US border officials but last year, for the first time, they were outnumbered by the combined total of other Central Americans.
Mexican migration has dropped, thanks to Mexico's improved economic circumstances, but worsening security situations have prompted large numbers of Hondurans, Salvadoreans and Guatemalans to journey north along a series of well-travelled routes.
The recent arrivals have included tens of thousands of unaccompanied children.
Growing global population
The share of international migrants in the world population has remained constant in recent years, hovering around 3%.
But as the world's population expands rapidly, so too does the raw number of people living outside their place of birth.
There are even more internal migrants: the figure of 740m is almost certainly a conservative estimate. It's hard to keep track of the millions of Chinese peasants who continue to converge on urban centres every year.
Thousands of people are forced from their homes each year by natural disasters, this woman is in a makeshift camp after the recent earthquake in Nepal
And the numbers of internal migrants fluctuate wildly: it's thought half a million Iraqis were displaced in a matter of weeks in June 2014.
Then there are natural disasters, which displace an average of more than 27m people every year.
Global migration fuels political debate, tests alliances and resources and keeps legions of statisticians very busy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:21:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Great Barrier Reef status at risk</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-australia-32911084#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Australia holds its breath as Unesco decides status</Description>
        <MainBody>Unesco reconsidering Great Barrier Reef heritage status
By Saffron Howden Sydney, Australia
28 May 2015
From the section Australia
The world's largest coral reef system is the blessed with breathtaking beauty
Australia faces a dent to its reputation and a potentially devastating blow to its tourism industry should one of the country's most iconic natural wonders, the Great Barrier Reef, be listed as "in danger" by the United Nations.
Tony Fontes loves diving the waters around Queensland's Whitsunday Islands.
In a career spanning three decades, the diving operator has introduced countless others to the magical underworld that is the Great Barrier Reef.
But he has also watched its decline.
Divers like Tony Fontes have witnessed a noticeable decline in the reef's health
The waters are now milkier and the coral quality poorer. Increasing attacks by crown-of-thorns starfish have left swathes of reef brown and lifeless.
"There'll always be reef but it's not what it once was," he told the BBC.
Like many others, he is waiting to hear if the reef - which gained World Heritage status in 1981 - will be listed as "in danger" by UN cultural agency Unesco.
The reef is one of more than 1,000 sites on Unesco's World Heritage List considered to be of such outstanding value that the world has an obligation to look after them.
Danger point
Unesco believes the Australian site is worth saving because it contains the world's largest collection of coral reefs, along with 1,500 species of fish and 4,000 types of molluscs.
But it is worried that threats to the reef's health - from overdevelopment, pollution and climate change - have reached a dangerous point.
The reef system has lost 50% of its coral in the past 30 years.
* The Great Barrier Reef  includes 3,000 coral reefs and 600 islands
* It is the world's largest marine park
* It receives about two million tourists each year.
* The region contributes A$6bn ($4.6bn; 3bn) a year to the Australian economy
In pictures: Great Barrier Reef
Late on Friday, Unesco will receive a draft recommendation about whether to place the reef on its "in danger" list.  A final decision will be made at a Unesco World Heritage Committee meeting in Germany in late June.
Few expect the international body to take this step - in part because of a flurry of activity by the Australian and Queensland governments to tighten development regulations along the Queensland coast, as well as heavy diplomatic lobbying by the Federal government.
An "in danger" listing would prove problematic for plans to open more coal mines in Queensland and proposals for more coal ports along its coast.
But environmentalists and scientists remain concerned about the reef's long-term fate.
Damage to tourism
Climate change, pollution, coastal development, fishing and dredging for shipping channels have wrought significant damage on the 348,000-sq km World Heritage Site, which stretches from the tip of Queensland to the city of Bundaberg.
There is no question the reef is in danger, says World Wildlife Fund Australia (WWF) marine programme manager, Richard Leck.
"If we'd lost 50% of the Taj Mahal, we wouldn't even question whether it was in danger," he told the BBC, referring to the loss of coral cover.
Coral bleaching, invasive starfish and pollution are damaging the reef system
But WWF does not want the reef's heritage status changed.
"We know the impact that will have on Australia's international standing," says Mr Leck.
He says it would deliver a heavy blow to tourism and the coastal communities who rely on it.
Government promises
Submissions to a 2014 Australian parliamentary inquiry into the reef back that view.
As the Whitsunday Charter Boat Industry Association explained: "It has taken a long time to build the brand that is the World Heritage Great Barrier Reef, and making the wrong decision could ruin that reputation."
State and federal governments have taken note of Unesco's scrutiny.
The Queensland government has pledged to forbid new dredge spoil - the sand, silt and rock dug out of the sea floor to create deeper ports - from being dumped in reef waters or on nearby wetlands.
There are also government plans to reduce pollution from fertilisers and pesticides used in coastal farming.
The Abbot Point port near the Reef will service a giant new coal mine in Queensland
Just this week, the Queensland Government announced it would introduce laws limiting port development adjacent to the reef.
The federal government is so worried about a potential listing that officials from its Environment Department have spent A$100,000 travelling overseas to lobby World Heritage Committee members.
Officials have visited 19 of the 21 member countries of the World Heritage Committee in recent months in a bid to avoid a highly embarrassing "in danger" listing.
A spokesperson for Federal Environment Minister Greg Hunt  told the BBC the government makes "absolutely no apology" for defending the reef's reputation.
The government says also that more than A$2bn will be spent on the reef over the next decade.
"This is a significant investment and it's on top of the A$2.6bn we're spending to tackle climate change - one of the major long term threats to the reef," said the spokesperson.
Fish kills
Still, concerns remain that the flurry of government reports, plans and promises generated over the past few years will not be enough if the watchful eye of Unesco moves on.
Some Australians are concerned about the expansion of coal ports near the Reef
And a lot of damage has already been done.
A 2012 study by the Australian Institute of Marine Sciences found the reef had lost half of its coral cover in less than 30 years.
A year before, there were reports of large-scale disease among fish and crabs in Gladstone harbour, one of the four major ports inside the world heritage area.
Simon Whittingham, from Gladstone Fish Markets, told the 2014 parliamentary committee that turtles, dolphins and dugongs were washing up dead.
Dugong habitats are at risk from overdevelopment and boat traffic, among other things
"Fish kills were occurring throughout the harbour. Something was terribly wrong," he said.
But as politicians, scientists, and conservationists debate the reef's future and Australia awaits the World Heritage Committee's decision, the reef itself continues to quietly divulge its secrets.
Three years ago, the Catlin Seaview Survey photographed a large crop of coral 125m under water that had never been seen before.
"We don't even know when the deeper reef formed," survey executive director Richard Vevers says.
"There's a lot of the Great Barrier Reef that has never been explored," he adds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:46:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How gang violence is spreading fear in El Salvador</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32913749#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Gang violence on the rise again in El Salvador</Description>
        <MainBody>How gang violence is spreading fear in El Salvador
By Katy Watson BBC News, San Salvador
29 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
All of the skeletons at San Salvador's Institute of Legal Medicine belong to victims of violence
Dr Oscar Quijano picks up a bone and excitedly explains how, just by looking at its texture, he knows how old the person was when they died.
Every day, he says, is a learning curve.
The forensic anthropology department of San Salvador's Institute of Legal Medicine feels like a history museum.
Laid out neatly on the tables are skeletons, each bone labelled and placed in position.
But these bones I am being shown do not tell me about El Salvador's history - they tell me more about what is happening right now.
Violent deaths
Some of these skeletons are no more than a year old.
Dr Quijano says the bones are either handed in after people stumble across them, or they are given to police by criminal gangs as part of a sort of plea bargain.
Each one of them belongs to someone who died in a violent manner.
One skull had to be carefully pieced together because the victim had her face smashed in.
Another skull has several bullet holes.
Many of the skulls bear bullet holes
Dr Quijano takes me to one table and picks up some vertebrae, pointing out that this victim was dismembered - most probably alive.
"Each different group or clique kills people in a different way," he tells me.
"Dismembering or strangling. Or a blow to the head. They all have their own execution style."
Crumbling truce
Dr Quijano says his team is struggling under all the work they are being given.
Many bodies are still awaiting identification in the morgue in San Salvador
In recent months, more and more bones have been brought to him to investigate.
El Salvador is on track to become one of the most violent countries in the world, and much of that violence is down to the country's biggest gangs.
The Mara Salvatrucha and the 18th Street Gang both trace their origins to Los Angeles, where they were founded by Central American immigrants.
Gang graffiti shows who controls the neighbourhood
After many of their members were deported back to their home countries, they now control entire neighbourhoods in El Salvador.
In 2012, El Salvador's main gangs agreed a truce which initially reduced murder rates by 40%.
But the truce has all but crumbled and killings have now soared.
March was the deadliest month in a decade and there has been little let-up since.
'Hard life'
The family of Pedro Valladares Martinez knows this too well.
Pedro Valladares Martinez (in the picture) was killed while working as a bus driver
Last month, the father of five was at work as a bus driver when he was shot in the head.
Just a few days earlier, Mr Valladares had told his wife Margarita that his job was getting too dangerous.
He said he wanted to find something else.
"He came home at eight in the evening, he had dinner and watched a bit of sport on the TV," she tells me.
"When it finished, he called our five children over and said please behave, we live in such a violent place, even just looking at somebody you can get into trouble you might not think it, but life is hard."
'No truce'
Critics say that the truce only served to expand the power of the gangs.
President Salvador Sanchez Ceren, who took office in June, has not recognised the truce and is opposed to negotiations with gang members as a way of tackling crime.
President Sanchez Ceren has ruled out negotiating with the gangs
But with homicide rates on the rise, many Salvadoreans fear the country may be facing another civil war.
They argue that gang warfare has replaced the guerrilla warfare and death squads which wracked the country from 1980 to 1992, when Marxist rebels of the Farabundo Marti National Liberation Front (FMLN) fought the government.
"Today, the problem El Salvador is facing is no longer an issue that's just between gangs," explains Raul Mijango, a former FMLN leader who helped broker the truce between the gangs three years ago.
Raul Mijango helped negotiate the truce between the gangs
"Now, what you have is a problem between gangs and the state."
With 70,000 active members and more than four times as many people in some way connected to or dependent on the gangs, this is not a problem the government can ignore, he argues.
"Around 11% of Salvadoreans are involved in the violence that this country faces, so you can't try and resolve a problem of this size just through clamping down on them."
Failed strategy
Police are increasingly becoming the target of attacks.
An anti-gang police force has been created, but murder rates have not gone down
A new anti-gang force has been created but so far it has not been able to reverse the upward trend of homicides.
So is a new truce the answer?
Deputy National Police Commissioner Howard Augusto Cotto says the iron-fist tactic has not worked in El Salvador, but negotiating with gangs is "a difficult subject".
"It's a strategy that cannot provide results," he argues.
Mr Cotto argues that negotiations with groups that have an ideology or a political vision have been successful.
Deputy Police Commissioner Howard Augusto Cotto thinks prevention would be best
"But here we're talking about a criminal activity," he says.
The police chief says there needs to be another solution, one that prevents crime in the first place.
But resources here are tight. And these gangs have just as much - if not more - firepower than the authorities they are fighting.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:26:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A symbol of holding out</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32900601#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tiny buildings that stand in the way of big developments</Description>
        <MainBody>Spiegelhalter's: The ultimate symbol of holding out
By Justin Parkinson BBC News Magazine
28 May 2015
From the section Magazine
The former Spiegelhalter jewellers in 2009
A shabby old shop that became an architectural landmark has evaded the bulldozer for a second time - almost 90 years after its first escape. Spiegelhalter's is the British equivalent of the Chinese "nail house".
It's a popular theme in movies and television. A plucky home or business-owner refuses repeated offers from a bullying property developer.
In China, it's now a frequent occurrence. Images circulate of lone buildings surrounded by rubble or where the developers have gone ahead and built around them. They are known as "nail houses" because they refuse to be hammered down.
Some owners go to extraordinary lengths to keep their properties intact, even as skyscrapers and shopping centres rise above them and roads are planned to run through them.
A nail house sits in the middle of a road under construction in Nanning, China
A partially demolished nail house in Rui'an, China
But they have their precursors in "holdout" buildings in the US and an extraordinary example from London.
Its tatty 19th Century frontage is dwarfed by the neoclassical superstore that stands either side of it. It might be small, but what's left of the Spiegelhalter jewellery and clock shop is a symbol of defiance.
The shop in east London's Mile End Road survived an attempted demolition in the 1920s - thanks to its owners' stubbornness. The Spiegelhalters' neighbouring business, Wickham's Department Store, had grown until it owned several buildings on either side.
It made an offer to buy out the Spiegelhalters - in business in Mile End Road since the early 19th Century, having migrated from Bavaria - and knock down their shop. The plan was to build grander premises, complete with columns and a tower, with the explicit aim of rivalling Selfridges, the famous West End department store.
But the Spiegelhalters, who had already moved from 75 to 81 Mile End Road in 1892 to accommodate an earlier stage of the Wickham's expansion, resisted this time. No offer would budge them, meaning the department store had to be built around their shop. This made the store asymmetrical, as its "central" tower had to be moved to the side.
Now nine decades later, the little shop in the middle of a grand new development has again escaped destruction.
Spiegelhalter and Sons in about 1900
More than 2,700 people signed a petition to keep what remains of the frontage , described by the famous architecture critic Ian Nairn in the 1960s  as "one of the best visual jokes in London". The developers have listened and, instead of going, the first floor of the Spiegelhalter shop will now form an archway over the entrance to an office and accommodation complex.
"It's important we keep individual buildings in place, so people don't feel a sense of dislocation," says Harriet Harriss, principal lecturer in architecture at Oxford Brookes University. "Much of modern development in London and elsewhere looks the same. It could be anywhere. It would have been ironic if Spiegelhalter's, a building that Hitler couldn't destroy during the Blitz, was removed forever now."
The incongruous Spiegelhalter shop became a landmark. In his 1966 book Nairn's London , regarded as a classic of topographical writing, Ian Nairn described it as "a perennial triumph for the little man, the blokes who won't conform. May he stay there till the bomb falls."
"It's at the level of the pedestrian facade where buildings are the most distinct," says Harriss, "showing regional differences and telling us stories about the way places have changed. If we get rid of that, we lose a lot of our cultural heritage."
The Wickhams eventually sold up, as department stores became less viable. The Spiegelhalters held on until 1982, their building becoming an off-licence after they left.
Since the 1990s, both sites have been in common ownership. Tesco Metro and a Sports Direct rent the ground floor of the old department store's premises. The Spiegelhalter shop, of which only the first-floor facade remains, is no longer in use.
Before and after - excavators tear down a five-storey apartment block in the middle of a newly-built road in Wenling, in eastern China
Plans have been submitted to Tower Hamlets Council to renovate the Wickham's building. But a petition, backed by English Heritage, the Twentieth Century Society and the Victorian Society, protested against proposals to remove the remainder of the Spiegelhalter shop to allow a tall, glass-fronted atrium.
Following the campaign, architect Buckley Gray Yeoman says it will change the plans so that the Spiegelhalters' frontage will remain, forming an archway above the main entrance. Director Matt Yeoman has said the company wants to listen to concerns , rather than behave in an "arrogant" manner. However, he added that it made the project a "slightly missed opportunity to create something more interesting".
The council says it is "keen to retain the heritage of the building" and is "working closely with the applicant to explore how to do so". "We hope that amended plans will be submitted in the near future," a spokeswoman adds, "and if so these will be published for further consultation with the local community."
"It's important that developers listen to what the public is saying, rather than making it a David-versus-Goliath contest," says Joe O'Donnell of the Victorian Society. He thinks the preservation campaign "evokes the spirit" of what the Spiegelhalters did in the 1920s. "Keeping the frontage is no hindrance to the architects' design, while it preserves a valued part of the streetscape."
In other parts of the world, where rampant redevelopment has meant the displacement of families and businesses on a bigger scale, some strain to achieve the same as the Spiegelhalters did in the 1920s.
A three-storey nail house in the middle of a road in Luoyang, China...
And one surrounded by tower blocks in downtown Shanghai
China provides stunning examples of holdouts . One house was left standing on a mound of earth in Chongqing for three years until it was demolished. Another remained standing in the middle of a shopping mall in Changsha. And one stayed in place despite being in the path of a road in Zhejiang province.
Chinese developers are said to call such properties "nail houses" , as they liken them to stubborn nails that can't easily be hammered into wood. People in the country have had stronger property ownership protections since 2007 , increasing the potential for conflict.
A nail house sits on top of a mound next to a construction site in Yibin, China
Chinese workers build around a grave mound 10 meters high, at a construction site in a village in Taiyuan
Most attempts to prevent demolitions fail but the nail houses have become a "powerful symbol of resistance", according to The Atlantic , some of their owners carrying on the fight for years and gaining widespread media coverage. Councils are said to cut access to utilities to encourage owners to leave, or even to demolish homes when they are out for the day.
There have been several prominent cases in the US. In 2006, octogenarian Edith Macefield became famous for refusing to sell her Seattle bungalow for $1m (650,000) to make way for a development. So it had to be built around her home. But she died in 2008 and it was recently put on sale.
Passers-by have taken to attaching balloons to the fence in front of the building . This is a reference to the 2009 Disney film Up, in which pensioner and widower Carl Fredricksen resists the developers.
The house formerly owned by Edith Macefield in Seattle
In Up, a pensioner escapes developers by tying balloons to his house and floating off
The corner of the block housing Macy's department store in New York has been a holdout for more than 100 years, the shop's owners never being able to buy the five-storey building there. Macy's sometimes rents advertising space on its front to hide the anomaly.
Macy's has covered its corner building with a giant shopping bag
The Spiegelhalter facade looks set for a prouder future.
"It's rather sweet," says historian Ellen Leslie. "It's a real one-off." But she warns against a movement towards "facadism", arguing that it's important to maintain buildings in their entirety. "You don't want to keep just the front and have a load of glass and steel at the back. That's not what our heritage is all about, and developers should be made aware of that. But, as hardly anything of Spiegelhalters' remains anyway, the decision here is good news."
It remains a talking point, just as Nairn would have wanted.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:53:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pilgrimage to the mountains</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32888643#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The festival that brings thousands to the Andes</Description>
        <MainBody>Pilgrimage to the mountains
29 May 2015 Last updated at 01:53
Photographer Timothy Allen climbs high into the Peruvian Andes for Qoyllur Rit'i - the Snow Star Festival.
Every year, a week before the Christian feast of Corpus Christi, tens of thousands of pilgrims climb high into the Peruvian Andes where the Sinakara Valley hosts Qoyllur Rit'i - the Snow Star Festival. Held under a full moon, the Catholic celebrations are infused with pre-Christian traditions. (Image 1/20) (Photography by Timothy Allen)
The pilgrims tend to come from rural communities and include dancers and musicians. The Catholic side of the festival dates from the late 1700s, when an image of Jesus is said to have appeared on a boulder after the death of a young shepherd boy. The pre-Christian elements are partly based on reverence for the Pleiades star constellation, which disappears and reappears in the Southern Hemisphere at this time of the year and is linked to hopes of an abundant harvest. (Image 2/20)
The main camp, known as the Sanctuary, is in the upper region of the Sinakara Valley. It is 4,700m above sea level and many pilgrims prepare for the change in altitude by drinking coca tea or chewing coca leaves. Above the valley sit sacred glaciers on Mount Qullqip'unqu. (Image 3/20)
The route up to the Sanctuary is dotted with crosses where Christian pilgrims show reverence by lighting candles and saying prayers. (Image 4/20)
The use of whips at Qoyllur Rit'i is common. Elders give out ceremonial punishment to young pilgrims who break the strict rules of the religious festival. Groups also take part in ritualistic whip fights. (Image 5/20)
The masked machulas represent the nawpa machus - the mythical first inhabitants of the Andes. Speaking in squeaky, high-pitched voices, their split personalities swing between playing the role of jesters and policemen - joking with pilgrims one minute then reprimanding those who forget to follow festival rules the next. (Image 6/20)
When the pilgrims arrive at the Sanctuary, a huge tented village springs up, with food stalls and restaurants. Even fresh fish is available, carried up to the site live in barrels of water on the backs of donkeys. (Image 7/20)
At the Sanctuary, pilgrims can visit the unorthodox Albacitas market where they can buy piles of fake money or miniature replicas of things they would like to manifest in real life. (Image 8/20)
Divided into so called "nations", the groups that come to the Sinakara Valley are invited by the Brotherhood of the Lord of Qoyllur Rit'i, a volunteer body that organises the event and imposes strict rules for attendees - alcohol is banned. (Image 9/20)
For the Christian participants of Qoyllur Rit'i, the highlight comes when the crosses are carried up even higher to the sacred glaciers above the valley. This is done by a group dressed as Ukukus - mythical half-man-half-bear characters. (Image 10/20)
The Ukukus dress in dark woollen clothes and masks. Regulars are quick to point out the decline in the size of the glaciers in recent decades, and say the ice has receded considerably. (Image 11/20)
In days gone by, Ukukus wore football boots to stop them slipping on the ice but nowadays professional climbers with ropes and crampons assist them. (Image 12/20)
Crosses are placed in the glacier and left overnight, traditionally surrounded by a candlelit shrine. But in recent years, as a nod to the receding glaciers, large candles have been banned. (Image 13/20)
After leaving their crosses in the ice, groups of Ukukus descend to the base of the glacier to spend the night together huddled around candles. (Image 14/20)
Dawn breaks and the Ukukus climb back up to retrieve their crosses. In procession, they then head back to the waiting crowds in the valley. Pilgrims used to cut chunks of ice from the glacier to use in church fonts as holy water but the practice has been banned because of the shrinking glacial mass. (Image 15/20)
At first light, the arrival of the crosses back at the Sanctuary is cause for great celebration. Pilgrims must then prepare themselves for a day-long procession to Tayancani. (Image 16/20)
After a morning mass, the procession leaves the Sanctuary and makes its way for seven hours or so, past lagoons and through valleys, until it reaches the small settlement of Yanacocha. Most groups rest there for three or four hours until nightfall. (Image 17/20)
The journey from Yanacocha to the church in the village of Tayancani must be undertaken in the dark. The light from the pilgrims' torches snakes through the mountains for eight hours under the stars. (Image 18/20)
Just before dawn, the pilgrims stop outside Tayancani and wait for the first rays of sunlight to break over the horizon - a sun-greeting ceremony is performed by those who celebrate old Incan spiritual beliefs. (Image 19/20)
In its colourful, eclectic, contemporary incarnation, today's Qoyllur Rit'i festival honours not only Jesus, but also the mountain gods (or apus) that South Americans worshipped long before Christianity's arrival on the continent. These photos were taken in 2014 - this year's festival will be held at the beginning of June. (Image 20/20) (Photography by Timothy Allen - all images subject to copyright)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:00:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bangladeshi boat migrants doomed from the start</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32918219#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Migrants knowingly boarding ships to Thai prison camps</Description>
        <MainBody>Justin Rowlatt South Asia correspondent
28 May 2015
From the section Asia
Thousands of Rohingya Muslims have boarded rickety boats in search of a better life
Over the last couple of weeks, the world has woken up to the horrific trade in human beings being conducted in the seas of South East Asia.
What we haven't heard so much about is how these journeys begin.
We travelled to southern Bangladesh, where many of the migrants set off on their perilous voyages.
What we have discovered brings a shocking new dimension to this story that speaks of the terrible desperation that is driving this vast movement of people.
We met one of the people smugglers on what Bangladeshis proudly boast is the world's longest beach - a vast stretch of sand that runs for more than 120km along the southern coast.
Let's call him Kamrul Rahman.
He appeared to be in his early 30s.  He said he used to be a fisherman and started in the people smuggling racket greedy for money after his business went belly up.
The migrants leave on fishing boats, similar to these, before being transferred to larger trawlers
They are packed into the vessels with little food or water
The smuggler told the BBC that prison camps were part of their business model
As the surf crashed down on the beach beside us, he calmly explained in chilling detail how the business worked.
He said the prison camps were an essential part of the business model and all the migrants knew about them.
It seems they are part of what amounts to a sinister and hideously cynical marketing trick the people smugglers have evolved: they offer the voyage for virtually no upfront cost.
Before they leave from here, we tell them if they don't pay they will be put in a prison
Kamrul Rahman, Human trafficker
He said the deal was straightforward and understood by everyone involved. You only pay the main charge - about 1,500 ($2,300) when you arrive in southern Thailand.
I was amazed. "So the migrants know they will be held in camp before they get to Malaysia?" I asked.
"Before they leave from here we tell them if they don't pay they will be put in a prison. You won't get any rice and you will die of hunger", he told me, without any sign of emotion.
"If you pay, you will be able to start for Malaysia with honour."
We spoke to many migrants and relatives of migrants in southern Bangladesh.
They all confirmed his account. Without exception, they said they knew migrants would be held in Thailand until full payment was made.
The majority of the migrants are male, but entire families have decided to travel too
What this suggests is that for the most part this phenomenon isn't strictly human trafficking - where people are bought and sold against their will - but rather a perverted business transaction to which most of the migrants and their families are actually party.
The so-called "ransoms" migrants who have been rescued from the camps in Thailand say their captors are actually part of the deal they sign up to when they make the journey.
Take a moment now to think about what that tells us about the people who make these journeys.
They are so desperate for a better life that they are willing to go with the people smugglers even though they know that they may end up starving to death in a jungle prison camp.
Stina Ljungdell, the UN refugee agency representative in Bangladesh, agrees that many migrants do know what they are getting into.
'Risky and selfish hope'
If you think about it objectively, it makes a kind of sick business sense for both the smugglers and their customers.
The migrants are assured that they only pay the full cost if they actually arrive in Thailand - cash on delivery, if you like.
Meanwhile, the smugglers have leverage to guarantee that they get paid.
The model has the added advantage, from the perspective of the smugglers at least, of making the decision to attempt the trip much easier.
Rohingya villagers desperately await news of their migrant relatives
It seems many young men, and it is predominantly young men who seem to make the journey, are lured in the risky and selfish hope that their family will find a way raise the money once they arrive in Thailand.
But other migrants make the decision to leave together with their families, judging that it is the only way to lift them out of poverty.
We were told that a successful migrant can send as much as 30,000 taka (260/$400) back to his family each month.
But many, many migrants don't make it.
Within minutes of arriving in an unofficial camp for Rohingya refugees further up the coast, I was surrounded by parents showing me pictures of their missing sons (and occasionally daughters).
Some said their sons had left for Malaysia without telling them. Many others, however, said they had sent them off in the hope that they would send money back for the family.
According to the smuggler, one in five of the migrants he takes don't make it to Malaysia.
Many die before they even reach the camps, he told me.
"Some die because of the suffering, some die because of of tension, some die thinking about how to escape from the situation and some people die of hunger after they run out of food.
"All people have to die", he said, "that is fate."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
