<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:59:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France pushes for Greek bailout deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33421521#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>France says it will do everything it can to help Greece reach a deal over its debt and remain within the eurozone, ahead of an emergency summit.</Description>
        <MainBody>What does Europe make of 'no' vote?
New demands
European finance ministers and officials gathered in Brussels told reporters they wanted to hear new proposals from Greece's new finance minister, Euclid Tsakalotos, ahead of a full summit of eurozone leaders later.
Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said as he arrived: "The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek government has an interest in coming up with serious and credible solutions soon."
European Economic Affairs Commissioner Pierre Moscovici added: "On Sunday the Greeks gave their voice but there are also 18 other countries with a voice."
Peter Kazimir, finance minister of Slovakia - one of the countries with the highest exposure to Greek debt - said he was "sceptical" that a deal would be found, adding that debt relief was a "red line for my country".
What are the scenarios for Greece?
Mr Tsipras met Greek political party leaders on Monday to agree demands to reach a "socially fair and economically viable deal". According to Greek media, the demands include:
Securing liquidity for Greece's financial system
Credible reforms with reduced recessionary impacts
Strong programme for growth
Restructuring of Greek debt - that could mean writing some off and rescheduling repayments.
'No taboo'
In his comments on Tuesday, Mr Valls said the eurozone could not "take the risk of Greece leaving" - for economic as well as political reasons.
"There is no taboo subject when it comes to [Greek] debt," he told French radio.
Germany, which takes a tougher line, has warned against any unconditional write-off of Greece's debt, amid fears it would destroy the single currency.
Germany and France - two of Greece's major creditors - differ over how much they should bend to help Greece reach a deal
German economy minister and vice chancellor Sigmar Gabriel said: "The other 18 member states of the euro can't just go along with an unconditional haircut [debt write-off]."
The differences between the French and German stances on Greece reflect a fissure running through the EU, say correspondents.
Several eurozone countries - including Malta, Slovakia and Estonia - are owed significantly more by Greece as a percentage of GDP than Germany or France.
Analysis: Chris Morris, BBC News, Athens
With pressure growing on the Greek banking system, the eurozone summit will have to give a pretty clear signal that it thinks progress can be made.
But the two most important leaders in the eurozone, Angela Merkel and Francois Hollande, appear to be struggling to find a common position on Greece in the wake of Sunday's "No" vote.
Broadly speaking, some countries - led by France - are pushing for a deal that will give Greece some breathing space to stay in the eurozone.
Others - led by Germany - are under greater political pressure at home, and wonder whether such a deal is possible.
It all leaves Greece in the most precarious position it has experienced in five years of wrenching economic crisis. The best that can be said is that it could go either way.
Meanwhile, the ECB said it would keep emergency cash support for Greek banks, which are running out of funds and on the verge of collapse, at the same frozen level - refusing requests for additional support.
It told the banks to lodge more collateral - or assets - with the Bank of Greece, reducing the amount of spare cash the banks have.
Capital controls have been imposed, with people unable to withdraw more than 60 a day from cash machines.
On Tuesday, Western Union said it was reactivating its Direct to Bank service to Greece, allowing funds to be transferred into bank accounts there from 31 countries.
The European Commission - one of the "troika" of creditors along with the IMF and the ECB - wants Athens to raise taxes and slash welfare spending to meet its debt obligations.
Greece's Syriza-led left-wing government, which was elected in January on an anti-austerity platform, said creditors had tried to use fear to put pressure on Greeks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:15:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French kill hostage-swap militant</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33429046#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>French special forces kill a militant Islamist in Mali who was said to have been freed in exchange for the release of French citizen Serge Lazarevic.</Description>
        <MainBody>French troops kill AQIM's Ali Ag Wadossene in Mali
7 July 2015
From the section Africa
Mr Lazarevic was France's last remaining hostage when he was released
French special forces have killed a militant Islamist in Mali who was said to have been freed in exchange for the release of French Serge Lazarevic.
Ali Ag Wadossene, a senior member of al-Qaeda in the Islamic Maghreb (AQIM), was killed in northern Kidal city, a French army statement said.
Two other militants were captured in the operation, it added.
France sent troops to Mali in January 2013 to prevent the militants from over-running the capital, Bamako.
Latest African news updates
Mr Lazarevic was abducted by AQIM in 2011 and freed last December.
Mr Wadossene and another militant, Heiba Ag Acherif, were jailed in Mali for allegedly being involved in his abduction.
Mali's government confirmed at the time that Mr Wadossene was one of four militants who had been freed in return for Mr Lazarevic's release.
Mr Lazarevic said he had been abducted in Mali while on a business trip.
Mali is a former French colony, and is a major producer of cotton and gold.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:17:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby gave woman drugs before sex</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33421101#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>US comedian Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 to obtaining sedatives with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with, court documents say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill Cosby admitted he gave woman drugs before sex
7 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The comedian is best known as Dr Cliff Huxtable on The Cosby Show in 1984-92
US comedian Bill Cosby admitted he obtained sedatives with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with, court papers from 2005 show.
The unsealed files, obtained by the Associated Press news agency, show Mr Cosby made the admission in a sex abuse civil case brought by a woman.
That case was settled for an undisclosed sum in 2006.
Mr Cosby, now 77, is facing a series of sexual assault accusations dating back decades. He has denied the claims.
Mr Cosby has never been criminally charged.
The documents came to light after the AP went to court to compel the release of the documents.  Mr Cosby's lawyers tried to stop the release of the papers, arguing it would embarrass their client and reveal personal information.
'I gave her Quaaludes. Then we have sex'
In his 2005 testimony, Mr Cosby admitted that he obtained Quaaludes in the 1970s, with the intent of giving it to women he wanted to have sex with.
The case was brought by Andrea Constand, a former employee of Temple University - the Philadelphia college with which Mr Cosby was once closely associated.
Mr Cosby admitted in 2005 that he intended to give drugs to women he wished to sleep with
The comedian said he had given the sedatives to at least one woman and "other people".
Later in the deposition, he said: "I meet Ms T (another woman whose name was redacted to preserve her anonymity) in Las Vegas. She meets me back stage. I give her Quaaludes. We then have sex."
His lawyers said that at least two of those accusing the comedian had knowingly taken the sedative.
In his deposition Mr Cosby said he had sex with "Ms T" after giving her Quaaludes
Mr Cosby also admitted to offering money to Ms Constand, and other women who had made allegations, in the form of educational trusts.
Testifying later in the case, Mr Cosby said that he had given Ms Constand one and a half pills of the over-the-counter antihistamine drug Benadryl.
Mr Cosby has yet to comment on his released testimony.
Timeline of allegations against Bill Cosby
2002: Lachele Covington, a 20-year-old actress, reportedly files a police report saying she had been inappropriately touched. No further action was taken.
2005: Andrea Constand sues Mr Cosby for sexual assault. The case is eventually settled out of court in 2006.
2014: Over the year, dozens of women make public accusations that Mr Cosby sexually assaulted them. Live shows are cancelled across the country amid protests
November 2014: TV network NBC scraps plans for a new show with the comedian following allegations by TV presenter Janice Dickinson that he had assaulted her in 1982. Repeats of the Cosby Show are also pulled from cable TV
December 2014: Judy Huth sues Mr Cosby for molesting her in 1974 when she was 15 years old. Mr Cosby counter-sues, claiming she is trying to extort money from him
May 2015: Mr Cosby speaks publicly about the allegations for the first time. "I can't speak; I just don't want to argue; I don't talk about it," he told ABC News.
Best known as Dr Cliff Huxtable on The Cosby Show in 1984-92, the comedian is facing a number of allegations dating back to the 1960s.
Most of the claims of sexual assault are barred by statutes of limitations. They restrict the length of time in which legal actions can be taken after an alleged crime has been committed.
The accusations, which Mr Cosby has described as "fantastical" and "uncorroborated", have led to some of his stand-up shows being called off and the cancellation of some TV projects.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:16:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant dies on Channel Tunnel train</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-33422109#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A migrant dies on a freight train heading for Britain, resulting in delays for cross-channel passengers and freight services.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant dies on Channel Tunnel train trying to reach UK
7 July 2015
From the section England
Cross-Channel passengers and freight services are facing delays following the incident at 05:00 BST
A migrant who is believed to have jumped onto a freight train heading for Britain has died, Eurotunnel has said.
The Channel Tunnel operator tweeted that the shuttle had been stopped following the incident on the French side at about 05:00 BST.
The death comes days after about 150 migrants tried to storm the Channel Tunnel terminal in France.
Passengers and freight services are facing delays with Eurotunnel advising some customers to rearrange travel.
'Jump injuries'
John Keef from Eurotunnel said: "Migrants were seen onboard a truck shuttle approaching the tunnel at about half-past-five this morning.
"We brought the shuttle to a controlled stop [and] cut the electrical power overhead.
"Police conducted a search at the end of which they found a migrant dead from injuries sustained probably from trying to jump on to the shuttle."
It is the second migrant fatality in as many weeks following the reported death of an Eritrean while trying to get on a train at Coquelles last month.
Operation Stack, where lorries are parked on the M20 and non-freight traffic diverted off the motorway, was re-introduced from 13:00 BST according to Kent Police.
Signs warn about the risk of death on rail tracks ahead of the Channel Tunnel in France
A Eurotunnel spokesman said: "Services are partly suspended, and the disruption is principally affecting freight services.
"Passenger services are running with slight delays."
He added: "We are working very hard to restore full services as soon as possible."
According to reports, there is already congestion on the approach road to the UK terminal in Folkestone and at the Port of Dover.
Highways England tweeted : "#M20 eastbound, delays approaching J11a @LeShuttle terminal. Delays on #A20 btwn Roundhill tunnel and @Port_of_Dover. Caused by hvy traffic."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:52:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bomb blast in Nigeria 'kills 25'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33425734#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 25 people have been killed in a bomb attack in northern Nigeria's Zaria city, a senior government official says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria's Boko Haram crisis: Zaria bomb 'kills 25'
7 July 2015
From the section Africa
Nigeria's soldiers have been fighting the insurgents since 2009
A bomb attack has killed at least 25 people and wounded 32 others in northern Nigeria's Zaria city, the state governor has said.
A suspected suicide bomber targeted civil servants at a government building in the city, witnesses said.
Emergency workers have rushed to the scene to help evacuate the wounded.
Militant Islamist group Boko Haram, which often targets northern Nigeria, has stepped up attacks since President Muhammudu Buhari took office in May.
The group has not yet commented on the latest attack.
It came a day after police chief Solomon Arase announced new measures to curb the rise in bombings. They include:
banning street trading and hawking in the capital, Abuja
strengthening security at all mosques and churches countrywide.
Latest African news updates
Witnesses in Zaria said people including primary school teachers had been queuing up seeking employment under Mr Buhari's administration when the bomb detonated in Zaria's Sabon Gari district.
"We call on our citizens to be vigilant and avoid crowded places like markets, mosques, churches and motor parks in the next few weeks," Kaduna state governor Nasir El-Rufa'i said on his Twitter account .
Mr El-Rufa'i said the government was working with the security agencies to end the wave of militant attacks in the country.
Buhari blamed
More than 200 people were killed in attacks blamed on Boko Haram last week.
On Sunday two bombings in Jos, Plateau state, left at least 44 people dead.
Men held on suspicion of being affiliated to Boko Haram line up to be released by the Nigerian military in Maiduguri
On Monday, a young girl believed to be just 13 was killed when explosives strapped to her body detonated near a mosque in Kano city, the biggest in northern Nigeria.
Some analysts link the upsurge in bombings to Mr Buhari's decision to remove military checkpoints countrywide on the grounds that internal security was the responsibility of police, reports the BBC's Bashir Sa'ad  Abdullahi from Abuja.
Plateau state governor Simon Lalong has called on Mr Buhari to reverse his decision, saying checkpoints made it more difficult for militants to move around.
Meanwhile, military spokesman Colonel Sani Usman told the BBC that 100 men, 24 women and dozens of children accused of links to Boko Haram had been freed.
Some has spent months in custody but investigations revealed that they were innocent, Col Usman added.
Regional forces have been battling Boko Haram in north-eastern Nigeria, and have recaptured all major cities and towns from the group.
Boko Haram at a glance
Founded in 2002, initially focused on opposing Western-style education - Boko Haram means "Western education is forbidden" in the Hausa language
Launched military operations in 2009
Pledged allegiance to Islamic State, calling itself West African Province
Thousands killed, mostly in north-eastern Nigeria, hundreds abducted, including at least 200 schoolgirls
Seized vast area in north-east, where it declared caliphate in 2014
Regional force retaken most territory
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Madrid to drop Franco street names</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33425995#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The new left-wing council in the Spanish capital Madrid plans to remove all names relating to Gen Franco's dictatorship from streets and plazas.</Description>
        <MainBody>Spanish dictator Franco names to go from Madrid streets
7 July 2015
From the section Europe
Gen Franco's dictatorship came to an end in 1975
The new left-wing council in the Spanish capital Madrid has said it plans to remove all names relating to Gen Francisco Franco's dictatorship in streets and squares.
Many streets were renamed under a 2007 "historical memory" law on replacing symbols of Franco's 1939-75 rule.
But some 167 streets are still named after regime figures.
Spain's new left-wing mayor, Manuela Carmena, was an anti-Franco lawyer in the later years of the dictatorship.
She took over in Madrid after years of centre-right Popular Party rule. Her predecessor, Ana Botella, was among 38 mayors accused by a human rights lawyer earlier this year of dragging their feet removing symbols of Franco's rule.
Franco had the Arco de la Victoria erected as a tribute to his Nationalist army's victory over Republicans
Although the Madrid council spokeswoman admitted there was "no concrete plan" to start changing street names, she said it would be carried out in co-ordination with local districts and civil society groups.
Among the streets highlighted by Spanish media are the street of the Fallen of the Blue Division, a unit that served with the Nazis during World War Two, and Arriba Espana square, which refers to Spain's old fascist Falange party.
Several vestiges of Franco's dictatorship remain on historic buildings in Madrid, including a victory arch at one of the entrances to the city, several defence buildings and the El Pardo and Santa Cruz palaces.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:00:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WHO 'unfit for health emergencies'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-33422635#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Ebola crisis proves the World Health Organization (WHO) lacks the "capacity and culture" to deal with global health emergencies, says a damning independent report, commissioned by the WHO itself.</Description>
        <MainBody>WHO 'unfit for health emergencies'
By Michelle Roberts Health editor, BBC News online
7 July 2015
From the section Health
The Ebola crisis proves the World Health Organization (WHO) lacks the "capacity and culture" to deal with global health emergencies, says a damning independent report, commissioned by the WHO itself.
The review panel says WHO was too slow to act to get on top of the deadly virus which has now killed more than 11,000 people in West Africa.
And it calls for an urgent overhaul of the organisation.
WHO says it has plans for reform.
It has already admitted that it waited too long to declare Ebola a public health emergency of international concern.
Inaction
The disease began spreading in December 2013, but it took until August 2014 for WHO to sound the alarm. By that point, more than 1,000 people had died of the virus.
The death toll now stands at more than 11,000.
According to the report, WHO lacked a culture of rapid decision-making.
In the early stages of the Ebola crisis, messages were sent about the seriousness of the situation but these "either did not reach senior leaders or senior leaders did not recognise their significance".
"There seems to have been a hope that the crisis could be managed by good diplomacy rather than by scaling up emergency action," the report says.
WHO was also criticised for failing to keep governments and the public up to speed about the extent and severity of the outbreak.
But the review praised WHO for playing a critical role in pushing forward work to find new treatments and cures for Ebola.
And it said WHO should be given the job of leading future health emergency responses - be that for Ebola or an outbreak of pandemic flu, for example.
It suggests an immediate contribution from all member countries towards a $100 million special outbreak response fund, and says WHO should establish a Centre for Emergency Preparedness and Response.
The panel's head, Dame Barbara Stocking, former chief executive of the charity Oxfam, said the WHO must now be made fit for the task.
"To me, coming from somewhere like Oxfam which is an emergency culture, you are very much, if you like, on the front foot. You are always trying to prevent a situation coming through or grab it when it starts and really get it under control very fast and those are some of the internal changes that have to be made at WHO."
The WHO said it was "already moving forward on some of the panel's recommendations including the development of the global health emergency workforce and the contingency fund to ensure the necessary resources are available to mount an initial response".
Dr Jeremy Farrar, Director of the Wellcome Trust, said: "The recommendations outlined by the independent panel should give WHO the mandate it needs to lead the global response to future health crises. The proposal to establish a WHO Centre for Emergency Preparedness and Response is encouraging.
"It's essential that this new body is accountable and can show leadership in the face of emerging health threats, with the authority and independence to act quickly when needed. The support of the global community is also crucial if we are to avert another catastrophe on the scale of Ebola."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:50:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Women's World Cup breaks TV records</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33422820#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A record 25.4 million TV viewers in the US watched the Women's World Cup final, the country's biggest ever audience for a football game.</Description>
        <MainBody>Women's World Cup breaks TV records
7 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
USA are the first nation to win three Women's World Cups
The Women's World Cup final has become the most-watched football game ever in the United States.
Sunday's match, in which the US beat Japan 5-2, was seen by a record 25.4 million viewers, according to Nielsen ratings data.
It shatters the previous record, set during the 2014 Brazil World Cup, when 18.2 million tuned in to see the USA play Portugal.
The audience peaked at 30.9 million between 01:30 and 01:45 BST.
Viewers saw Carli Lloyd score an incredible 13-minute hat-trick, as the United States trounced Japan to win their third Women's World Cup title, following victories in 1991 and 1999.
The latter was seen by 18 million viewers, the previous highest audience for a women's match.
Sunday's game, which was held in Vancouver, beat big-brand shows like Big Brother on CBS and Celebrity Family Feud on ABC; while broadcaster Fox Sports saw 14.6 million people stick around for its post-match analysis.
In the UK, conversely, the culmination of the tournament saw a steep drop in audience figures. Just 500,000 viewers - or 13% of the total television audience - stayed up to watch the final.
Four days earlier, England's quarter-final match was seen by an average audience of 1.7 million, with a 32% share of the audience.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:23:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Karate Kid producer Weintraub dies</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33421099#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Jerry Weintraub, the Hollywood producer of the Karate Kid and Ocean's Eleven films, dies in California aged 77.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jerry Weintraub, Karate Kid producer, dies aged 77
7 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Weintraub had a successful career that spanned more than five decades
Jerry Weintraub, the Hollywood producer of the Karate Kid and Ocean's Eleven films, has died at the age of 77.
According to his publicist, he died of heart failure on Monday at his home in Santa Barbara, California.
Weintraub started his career in the music industry, promoting tours for Elvis Presley and Frank Sinatra, before moving into film production.
Ocean's Eleven star Clooney and former US President George HW Bush are among those who have paid tribute.
"In the coming days there will be tributes," said Clooney in a statement. "We'll laugh at his great stories, and applaud his accomplishments.
"And in the years to come, the stories and accomplishments will get better with age, just as Jerry would have wanted it. But not today. Today our friend died."
The producer made three Ocean's films with (l to r) Brad Pitt, George Clooney and Matt Damon
"Jerry was an American original, who earned his success by the sheer force of his instinct, drive, and larger-than-life personality," said Bush.
"He had a passion for life. And throughout the ups and downs of his prolific career it was clear just how much he loved show business."
"So sad at loss of Jerry Weintraub, you were 1 of a kind, my friend," tweeted Ralph Macchio , who starred in the first three Karate Kid films.
The actor, now 53, described the producer as being the "last of a breed," adding: "So glad I got to be 'that kid.'''
Others to tweet tributes include actress Goldie Hawn , who described Weintraub as "a friend [and] a powerhouse of light that graced our lives with spirit and joy."
"So sad and shocked that a creative spirit like Jerry Weintraub's could EVER be silenced," tweeted Rob Lowe, who worked with the producer on Emmy and Golden Globe-winning TV movie Behind the Candelabra.
The producer's most recent credits include HBO comedy series The Brink and a new version of the Tarzan story, due out next year.
The New York-born producer worked in artist management and concert promotion before turning to movies
Jerome Charles Weintraub, a native New Yorker, was born in Brooklyn in 1937 and raised in the Bronx. As a teenager he served in the Air Force as a radio operator.
He went on to work in the mailroom at MCA Records and rose through the ranks before leaving to form his own management company.
Moving into films, he quickly enjoyed success as the executive producer of Robert Altman's 1975 film Nashville.
Yet not all his films were hits, Weintraub suffering a notable flop in 1998 with the film version of TV show The Avengers.
"The secret to my success is the people that I associate myself with and work with,'' Weintraub said in 2010. ''I work with the greatest artists and I respect them."
He is survived by his four children and his longtime partner, Susan Ekins.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:17:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabab raid kills Kenya workers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33421902#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 14 people are killed in a gun attack by Islamist group al-Shabab near Kenya's border with Somalia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kenya: Al-Shabab kills quarry workers in Mandera gun attack
7 July 2015
From the section Africa
Kenya Red Cross are flying some of the casualties to the capital
At least 14 people have been killed and several others wounded in a gun attack near a military camp at the Kenyan border with Somalia.
It is believed the victims were workers from a local quarry in Mandera county in the north-east of the country.
Residents told the BBC they had heard two explosions, followed by heavy gunfire in the middle of a night.
Militia group al-Shabab, which operates out of Somalia, has confirmed to the BBC it carried out the attack.
Mandera County Commissioner Alex Ole Nkoyo told AFP that people were sleeping when the gunmen struck.
"They just came and hurled explosives in the houses," he said.
Kenya Red Cross said it was sending an aircraft to the scene to fly the injured to hospitals in Nairobi.
Constant threat
In December 2014 al-Shabab killed 36 quarry workers in Mandera town.
On that occasion they attacked while the workers were sleeping and shot the non-Muslims dead after separating them from Muslims.
Their deadliest assault to date happened at a university in the Kenyan town of Garissa in April, when four gunmen killed 148 people.
In 2013, at least 67 people died in a gun attack on the Westgate mall in the capital Nairobi.
Analysis: Tomi Oladipo, BBC Africa Security correspondent
People from other parts of Kenya working in the north-east have threatened to leave the area following frequent al-Shabab attacks.
The Islamist group has carried out numerous attacks near the long porous border with Somalia.
This latest incident is likely to put the spotlight on the Kenyan authorities again over their handling of the security situation.
Just two weeks ago the government lifted a night-time curfew in the area after Muslim clerics said it impeded prayers during the month of Ramadan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:32:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Single bank boss who spurns luxury</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33414351#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Kenya's single bank boss intrigues the press when he turns down a free house to live in a religious community.</Description>
        <MainBody>Patrick Njoroge: Kenyan bank boss who doesn't want luxury house
7 July 2015
From the section Africa
Kenya's new central bank governor rejected the grand house that comes with his prestigious job. The BBC's Abdinoor Maalim writes this is a rare move which has created a lot of interest in the single 54-year-old, who is a member of the Catholic group Opus Dei.
Kenyans are enthralled by the new central bank governor. And it is not because they are wondering what he is going to do about the Kenyan shilling weakening against other currencies.
Patrick Njoroge seems to be from a different planet altogether.
His "refusal to take his turn to eat is surprising" says business columnist Otieno Otieno in the Daily Nation . While Victor Nyakachunga writes in the Standard "many were challenged" by him opting for the simple life.
Kenyans are used to senior government officials leading lavish lifestyles.
It is an issue which has provoked protest, not least when parliamentarians awarded themselves a pay rise of 319,000 shillings ($3,200; 2,100) a month, less than two months after being sworn in in 2013.
Mr Njoroge's predecessors in the central bank lived in the luxurious Muthaiga Estate in Nairobi.
They drove Range Rovers or Mercedes Benz accompanied by security cars.
The house is famous for its beautiful gardens which are used to host parties.
It is near the residences of the US and UK foreign envoys and Kenya's former President Mwai Kibaki.
The Central bank governor's abode is in the same neighbourhood as former President Mwai Kibaki
Mr Njoroge has dismissed these perks, preferring to live in a communal house in Nairobi's Loresho estate.
He went to live with his fellow members of an organisation of the Roman Catholic church called Opus Dei.
The organisation, which means "work of God" in Latin, teaches that ordinary life is a path to sanctity.
It is widely credited with developing his humble stance.
The Opus Dei website says members aim at "humility, justice, integrity, and solidarity" and to work "hard and well, honestly and fairly".
"In God's eyes, what matters is the love people put into their work, not its success in terms of money or fame," it adds.
What is Opus Dei?
A branch of the Catholic Church founded in 1928
Has a reputation for secrecy
Featured in the Dan Brown bestseller The Da Vinci Code where a member whips himself until he bleeds
Self-flagellation is an expression of remorse for sins
The Opus Dei website says members do perform penance and sacrifice but "not like the distorted and exaggerated depiction in The Da Vinci Code"
Offered a wife
When he was being vetted by MPs for the governor position, he surprised the committee by revealing he didn't own any property in Kenya.
That is despite commanding a presumably large salary in his previous job as an advisor to the International Monetary Fund's (IMF) Deputy Managing Director.
"I don't have a single asset here in Kenya," he said.
"It doesn't mean that this how it will be forever. I subscribe to being very deliberate about that. This is my economic model and maybe years after retirement, I would want to invest in other things," he said.
But it is not the only element of the banker's private life which has caused a stir.
He is also single.
MPs were so intrigued by Mr Njoroge's marital status that he was asked about it during the vetting process - a move BBC Trending reports was mocked online.
The MPs gave him a rare offer. When they found out he was single they requested to get him a wife.
"I am single by choice - it's not because there's a problem or shortage," he replied.
Kenya's CTV asked focused on Mr Njoroge marital status
His character has attracted offers of marriage and admiration on Twitter.
"And then, that new #CBKGovernor just made me re evaluate my life goals..man is so humble and content." tweeted an inspired Anthony Mbugua .
His colleagues are equally taken by him.
"Totally devoid of ego and instinctively averse to self-advertisement," is how a senior treasury official and long-serving central banker described him.
Kenyans hope his austere nature means he will keep their luxury-loving politicians in check and safeguard their economic future.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:00:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fraser a 'blatant racist' - Kyrgios</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/33421964</Link>
        <Description>Nick Kyrgios calls Australian Olympic swimming great Dawn Fraser a "blatant racist" after comments on his Wimbledon exit.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wimbledon 2015: Nick Kyrgios calls Dawn Fraser a 'blatant racist'
Wimbledon 2015
Dates: Until Sunday 12 July
Play: Centre Court and Court One 13:00 BST
BBC coverage: TV, radio and online with up to 15 live streams. Read More: TV and radio schedules.
Nick Kyrgios says Australian Olympic swimming great Dawn Fraser is a "blatant racist" after she said players should "go back to where their parents came from" if they cannot behave.
Australian Kyrgios, who has a Greek father and Malaysian mother, appeared to stop trying during his defeat by Richard Gasquet at Wimbledon.
The 20-year-old was also given a code violation for bad language.
Fraser later "unreservedly" apologised for her comments.
In her initial interview on Australian television, Fraser, who won the 100m freestyle at three successive Olympic Games from 1956 to 1964, said: "It's absolutely disgusting.
"I am so shocked to think that he went out there to play and he tanked, he did all that tanking, that's terrible."
Kyrgios was involved in a running battle with the umpire in his defeat by Gasquet
The 77-year-old was also discussing fellow Australian Bernard Tomic, who was born in Germany and has a Croatian father and Bosnian mother, during her interview.
Tomic, 22, accused Tennis Australia of abandoning him after he had hip surgery last year and will not be chosen for his country's Davis Cup tie against Kazakhstan in Darwin later this month.
Fraser added: "They should be setting a better example for the younger generation of this country, a great country of ours.
"If they don't like it, go back to where their fathers or their parents came from. We don't need them here in this country if they act like that."
Kyrgios was beaten 7-5 6-1 6-7 (7-9) 7-6 (8-6) by Gasquet and was booed when he appeared to stop trying in the second set after being given a code violation for bad language.
He repeatedly clashed with British umpire James Keothavong, including an altercation over how long the 26th seed was taking to change his socks between games.
Kyrgios linked to Fraser's interview on his Facebook page and responded: "Throwing a racket, brat. Debating the rules, disrespectful. Frustrated when competing, spoilt. Showing emotion, arrogant. Blatant racist, Australian legend."
Fraser apologises unreservedly
Fraser denied her comments were racist before later issuing an apology.
"Australians have a rich sporting heritage made up of individuals from a variety of different countries of origin," she said.
"My intended message, which was not delivered as articulately as it could have been, was on a purely sporting level rather than meant as an attack on Nick's ethnicity.
"Nick's representing Australia and I want to see him representing Australian tennis in the best possible light. "
McEnroe on Kyrgios: "He should have admitted he tapped out and lost it for that period of time"
'I'll give you the racquet'
In his post-match news conference, Kyrgios clashed with journalists and denied that he stopped trying in the second set.
"Do you want to try and return Richard Gasquet's serve?" he said.
"I'll give you the racquet and we'll see how many times you can return his serve also. He served too good."
He added: "Of course I tried. He hits a serve past me as an ace, that's too good. I did move."
'He's going to wish he didn't do it'
BBC Sport pundit John McEnroe was famed for his temper during his playing career but believes the 'tanking' incident was "completely unprofessional".
5 of the best from Gasquet v Kyrgios
"The pressure got to him," McEnroe told Wimbledon 2Day. "A lot of this is overblown, but you can't condone what he did.
"I'm a big defender of Nick Kyrgios, I think he's going to be a great player and he's going to learn. He should have admitted he tapped out and lost it for that period of time.
"He's going to wish he didn't do it and realise he made an ass out of himself."
He added: "I believe he should be himself, he's the kind of fresh face we need plus he can play."
'He's different off court'
British number one and 2013 Wimbledon winner Andy Murray had some sympathy for the pressure Kyrgios is under.
"I don't think people always appreciate how difficult it is to grow up under the spotlight, how difficult it is to have loads of people expecting you to be perfect from a young age," said Murray.
"I like Nick. I've spoken to him away from the court. He's quite different to how he is on it."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:08:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Zambian writer to share prize money</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33424103#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Zambian writer Namwali Serpell promises to split the winnings for this year's Caine Prize for African Writing, regarded as Africa's leading literary award, with all the runners up.</Description>
        <MainBody>Zambian writer Namwali Serpell to share Caine prize money
7 July 2015
From the section Africa
Namwali Serpell has promised to split her winnings with the four other runners up
US-based Zambian writer Namwali Serpell has promised to share her winnings in the Caine Prize for African Writing with the runners up.
She received the 10,000 ($15,600) prize for her short story The Sack.
The judges described it as "innovative, stylistically stunning, haunting and enigmatic".
Ms Serpell was among five writers short-listed for the prize, regarded as Africa's leading literary award.
Two South Africans and two Nigerians were also shortlisted for the prize - Masande Ntshanga for Space, FT Kola for A Party for the Colonel, Elnathan John for Flying and Segun Afolabi for The Folded Leaf.
Ms Serpell told BBC Newsday that the promise to share the winnings was "an act of mutiny".
"I wanted to change the structure of the prize.
"It is very awkward to be placed into this position of competition with other writers that you respect immensely and you feel yourself put into a sort of American idol or race-horse situation when actually, you all want to support each other."
The chair of judges, Zoe Wicomb, awarded the prize at a dinner held at the Bodleian Library at Oxford University in the UK.
The short story "yields fresh meaning with every reading," she said.
In The Sack, two men who live together their whole lives love one woman but don't know which one of them she loves.
"One of the men has a series of backwards moving dreams about his own death and he becomes very paranoid about the other man," Ms Serpell said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:51:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miss Universe defends keeping crown</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33421449#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The reigning Miss Universe defends keeping her crown despite a row between the pageant owner Donald Trump and her home country Colombia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Miss Universe defends keeping crown despite Trump row
7 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Paulina Vega, 22, won the 2014 Miss Universe pageant last January in Miami
The reigning Miss Universe says she will not give up her crown, despite her home country Colombia withdrawing its bid to host the competition.
Paulina Vega had come under pressure to quit after her country's condemnation of the pageant owner, Donald Trump.
Mr Trump caused a furore last month after he said Mexican immigrants who came to the US brought drugs and crime.
Ms Vega called Mr Trump's comments "unjust and hurtful", but said she would continue as Miss Universe.
"The fact that I am not giving up my crown doesn't mean I am changing my stance about everything I said," Ms Vega told local radio on Monday, adding that the Miss Universe organisation did meaningful social work.
"I have kept doing my job as Miss Universe all these days. The work continues as always despite all this craziness going on," she added.
Boycott
Mr Trump had attacked Ms Vega for keeping her crown, saying: "Miss Universe, Paulina Vega, criticised me for telling the truth about illegal immigration, but then said she would keep the crown - hypocrite."
While announcing his candidacy for the US presidency last month, Mr Trump had accused Mexico of sending rapists and other criminals to the United States.
He also pledged to build a "great wall" on the US border with Mexico and insisted it would be paid for by Mexicans.
He later insisted he was criticising US lawmakers, not Mexican people.
Following Mr Trump's remarks, several TV networks across the Americas said they would no longer air Miss Universe, including the Spanish language network, Univision and NBC.
Mexico also announced that it would not send a contestant to the pageant.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:13:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ten dead and dozens shot in Chicago</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33414256#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Ten people are killed, including a 7-year-old boy, in a series of shootings during a violent US holiday weekend in Chicago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chicago boy, 7, among victims as gun violence sweeps city
6 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Amari Brown, 7, was shot and killed in the Humboldt Park section of the city
Gun violence in Chicago at the weekend left 10 people dead, including a 7-year-old boy, and more than 50 wounded.
Amari Brown was shot in the chest by a gunman who was targeting his father, a known gang member, according to police.
Police chief Garry McCarthy said the boy's father should not have been on the streets, telling reporters: "If [he] is in custody, his son is alive".
Despite the multiple shootings since Thursday, the number of incidents was lower than in the same period in 2014.
Last year, 16 people were shot dead and more than 80 others were injured, according to the Chicago Tribune.
The worst period at the weekend came between 21:00 on Saturday and 05:00 on Sunday, when 30 people were shot as residents celebrated Independence Day.
Among the other incidents, a 17-year-old was shot dead as he played basketball and a 19-year-old was injured as rival gangs fought near Navy Pier after the fireworks display there.
Chicago's police chief said the city needed to do more to punish those behind the violence
The shootings happened despite a 30% increase in the number of police officers on patrol in the city over the weekend, Mr McCarthy said.
He said police in the city recovered one illegal gun per hour across the city. "We must stem the flow of guns into the city," he said.
The police force is doing "everything we can to fight this" but the city needs to "repair a broken system", Mr McCarthy said, adding: "Criminals don't feel the repercussions of the justice system."
Chicago has struggled to turn the tide of gun violence for several years and is one of the most deadly in the US.
In 2014, there were 406 homicides across the city - although this was a 3% decrease from 2013, when there were 419 gun-related deaths.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:37:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian 'bombed divorce lawyer'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33414260#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man in Winnipeg, Canada, is charged with attempted murder after sending bombs to law firms that represented him or his ex-wife in the past.</Description>
        <MainBody>Canadian charged over bombs sent to Winnipeg law firms
6 July 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Police said Guido Amsel was targeting lawyers that have represented his ex-wife
Police in Canada have charged a man for sending explosive devices to several businesses in the city of Winnipeg and warned that more could be discovered.
Guido Amsel, 49, targeted law firms that represented him or his ex-wife in a lengthy legal battle, police said .
One bomb exploded at an office last Friday, severely injuring a woman.
Two more explosive devices were found at law firms over the weekend in the city, but they were detonated by police, and no one was injured.
Mr Amsel has been charged with two counts of attempted murder, one count of aggravated assault and a number of offences related to possessing explosives.
Maria Mitousis, the 38-year-old injured by the first bomb, represented Mr Amsel's ex-wife during their divorce and a later case.
She is reported to be in a stable condition at a local hospital but suffered several serious injuries to her upper body.
Friends and family of the lawyer set up a fundraising page to help pay for her medical expenses and have so far raised more than $25,000 (16,000).
They said Ms Mitousis faced "a long road to recovery".
Police said more packages may be delivered to other lawyers or justice officials linked to Mr Amsel and urged "extreme caution" over unusual packages.
Winnipeg city hall was evacuated on Monday after reports of a suspicious package but it was given the all clear after police investigated. There was also a similar false alarm at a Canada Post building.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:27:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope draws huge crowds in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33380260#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of thousands of people gather in the Ecuadorean city of Guayaquil to see Pope Francis celebrate mass.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis draws millions in tour of Ecuador
6 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Hundreds of thousands of people gathered in the Ecuadorean port city of Guayaquil on Monday to greet Pope Francis.
The Pope waved to the crowds from his custom car ahead of an open-air mass in the city's Samanes Park.
He arrived in Ecuador on Sunday for the first leg of his three-country trip to Latin America, which will also take him to Bolivia and Paraguay.
It is his second visit to the region since becoming pontiff in 2013.
City officials said a million visitors had travelled to Guayaquil to see the Pope.
Up to a million people reportedly gathered in Guayaquil to see Pope Francis
People from all sections of society greeted Pope Francis upon his arrival in the capital Quito
Many gathered in front of the Vatican Embassy in Quito on Monday
Looking relaxed, Pope Francis smiled as the crowds in Guayaquil cheered him and snapped selfies.
Before his procession he visited the city's Divine Mercy shrine, where he reacted with good humour to nearly being poked in the eye by a young boy.
He spent a minute praying at the shrine and told the crowd he would pray for them.
A Vatican official estimated that half a million people had lined the streets of the Ecuadorean capital, Quito, on Sunday, to see the Pope.
Many also gathered in front of the Vatican Embassy in Quito, where he stayed the night.
He joined them for a prayer and, according to some of those present, said: "I am going to give you a blessing so that you go home and rest and let the neighbours get some sleep."
After landing in Quito, the Pope thanked God "for having allowed me to return to Latin America".
Peripheries
His 2013 visit to Brazil drew huge crowds of young Catholics attending the Catholic Youth Conference. A Mass on Copacabana beach was estimated to have been attended by three million people.
The papal mass was rapturously received in the city of Guayaquil
Pope Francis was making his second visit to Latin America since becoming Pontiff in 2013
But this time the Pope chose some of the smaller and poorer countries of the region for his visit, a move which the Vatican said reflected his interest in the "peripheries".
Pope Francis is the first leader of the Roman Catholic Church to come from South America, but on this occasion he will not be visiting his home country of Argentina.
The Vatican said that he would focus on the issue of poverty and inequality.
"Progress and development must ensure a better future for all," he said in a speech on the Quito airport runway after he was welcomed by Ecuadorean President Rafael Correa.
In 2007, before becoming Pope, he told a gathering of Latin American bishops that they were living in the most unequal part of the world.
Coca leaves
On Wednesday Pope Francis will travel to Bolivia.
He has requested to chew coca leaves while in Bolivia, according to Culture Minister Marko Machicao.
Children in Bolivia are already excited over the Pope's impending visit
Coca, the raw ingredient for cocaine, has been used in the Andes for thousands of years to combat altitude sickness and as a mild stimulant.
In September the Pope will travel to Cuba ahead of a trip to the US.
The pontiff is credited with helping to bring about last December's diplomatic thaw between the two countries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:33:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brazil introduces caesarean rules</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33421376#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>New rules aimed at reducing Brazil's high number of caesarean births come into force.</Description>
        <MainBody>Brazil introduces new caesarean birth rules
7 July 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
The caesarean rate in Brazil is more than 50%
New rules have come into force in Brazil aimed at reducing the country's high number of caesarean births.
Eighty-five per cent of all births in Brazilian private hospitals are caesareans and in public hospitals the figure is 45%.
The new rules oblige doctors to inform women about the risks and ask them to sign a consent form before performing a caesarean.
Doctors will also have to justify why a caesarean was necessary.
They will have to fill in a complete record of how the labour and birth developed and explain their actions.
Each pregnant woman will now be assigned medical notes which record the history of her pregnancy, which she can take with her if she changes doctors.
The new rules are designed to reduce unnecessary surgical procedures, and ensure pregnant women are aware of the risks associated with caesareans.
However, experts say that a scarcity of maternity beds and wards equipped to deal with natural births means that for many women in Brazil, caesarean birth is seen as the best option.
"The best way to guarantee yourself a bed in a good hospital is to book a caesarean," Pedro Octavio de Britto Pereira, an obstetrician and professor at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, said in an interview with BBC Brasil last year.
'Uncivilised and primitive'
Women who want to give birth naturally in a private hospital have reported finding all the beds are reserved for scheduled deliveries.
There have been numerous reports of women going into labour without a caesarean scheduled and being forced to travel from hospital to hospital in search of a bed.
Researchers say many women also see caesareans as more civilised and modern, and natural birth as primitive, ugly and inconvenient.
In Brazil's body-conscious culture, where there is little information given about childbirth, there is also huge concern that  natural birth can make women sexually unattractive.
Many doctors prefer caesareans too, as they can plan the time of a birth, and feel more protected from litigation.
Gynaecologist Renato Sa told BBC Brasil: "Doctors are responsible for what happens and in a situation of risk they chose a caesarean, because if there is a death or complication they will be asked why they didn't do this. Doctors are afraid of natural childbirth."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:26:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Twin Nigeria blasts kill scores</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33406537#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Two bomb attacks - on a restaurant and a mosque - in the central Nigerian city of Jos have left at least 44 people dead, the authorities say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria's Boko Haram crisis: Jos blasts kill scores
7 July 2015
From the section Africa
Dozens of people were injured in the Jos bombings
Two bomb attacks on the central Nigerian city of Jos have left at least 44 people dead, the authorities say.
A restaurant and a mosque were targeted on Sunday night.
No group has said it carried out the attack, but militant group Boko Haram has attacked Jos before, even though it is not in north-east Nigeria where the Islamists normally operate.
The blasts are the latest in a series of deadly attacks in recent days which have seen more than 200 people killed.
The attacks came shortly after the Ramadan fast was broken, with both sites full of people.
Of the 44 dead, 23 were killed at the restaurant and 21 at the mosque, Nigeria's National Emergency Management Agency (Nema) says.
The bomb at the Shagalinku restaurant came as people were breaking the Ramadan fast
There are also 47 people being treated for injuries, but emergency officials are still gathering information, so the figures may rise.
The blast at the restaurant was caused by a bomb that had been planted, whereas the mosque was attacked by a suicide bomber and that explosion was preceded by gunfire, the BBC's Ishaq Khalid reports.
Eyewitness Akaria Ahammed said: "When they started shooting people, people started running helter-skelter for their lives.
"Unfortunately those that stood up were shot."
Hospital staff attended to injured people in Jos throughout Monday
Our correspondent says that many believe that the mosque's imam, who was preaching at the time, may have been the target.
Sheikh Muhammad Sani Yahya Jingir, who survived the attack, is known for preaching against Boko Haram and has written a book which criticises the group called Boko Halal (Western education is permitted - Boko Haram means Western education is forbidden).
He has survived a previous assassination attempt at his home and is seen as one of the most influential clerics in Nigeria.
Speaking on Monday, Sheikh Jingir said the bombing was "not an attack on an individual, it is an attack on all of us".
Meanwhile the Nigerian military told the BBC it had freed more than 180 people who had been detained on suspicion of being Boko Haram members.
The former suspects had been freed after being screened by the military to ensure their innocence, officials said.
Correspondents say Nigeria's treatment of Boko Haram suspects has been an extremely contentious issue.
Amnesty International says that thousands have died in detention in the past four years - something the military denies.
However, Nigeria's President Muhammadu Buhari has promised to investigate the rights group's claims.
Why the upsurge in attacks? Will Ross, BBC News, Nigeria
It is not unusual for there to be a heightened risk of jihadist attacks during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan.
Boko Haram may be trying to deepen its ties with the jihadists fighting in Iraq and Syria who had called for "a month of disasters for the infidels".
Many of the recent attacks have been by suicide bombers - often young women.
Where the bombs are being made and where the bombers are being brainwashed is unclear but the Nigerian intelligence and security services need to do far more to stop the bloodshed.
Once again the range of targets is alarming and on this latest bloody Sunday a church and a mosque were bombed within hours of each other.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:53:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moroccan women in court over dress</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33410759#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Two women go on trial in Morocco on charges of "gross indecency" for wearing skirts.</Description>
        <MainBody>Moroccan women in Inezgane court over dress
6 July 2015
From the section Africa
People protested outside the court ahead of the court case
Two women have gone on trial in Morocco on charges of "gross indecency" for wearing skirts.
The two were arrested in Inezgane last month, after a market trader drew attention to what they were wearing and a crowd gathered round, reports say.
An internet petition calling the arrest an attack on personal freedom has attracted thousands of signatures.
There was controversy in May when a Jennifer Lopez performance in Morocco was considered "sexually suggestive".
There have been a number of demonstrations over the case in Morocco, with protesters saying that women should be free to wear what they want.
Activists also gathered at the court house on Monday to support the detainees.
The two women, 23 and 29, are being tried under an article in the penal code which says that anyone found guilty of committing an act of "public obscenity" can be jailed for up to two years.
The judge will give a verdict on 13 July.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:47:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two suicide attacks hit Kabul</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33424578#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A Nato convoy and an Afghan intelligence agency office are targeted in two suicide attacks hours apart in the Afghan capital Kabul.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan conflict: Two suicide attacks hit Kabul hours apart
7 July 2015
From the section Asia
A Nato land cruiser was hit in the first suicide attack in the Shah Shahid area of Kabul
A Nato convoy and an Afghan intelligence agency office have been targeted in two suicide attacks hours apart in the Afghan capital Kabul.
In the first attack a car bomb hit a land cruiser carrying foreign forces. Nato said there were no fatalities.
In the second attack, two people tried to storm an intelligence office in the Eighth Precinct after a third man blew himself up on a bomb-laden motorbike.
A guard was killed and another person injured. Two gunmen were also killed.
The Taliban and another militant group, Hezb-e-Islami, have said they carried out the first attack, in the Shah Shahid area of the city.
Taliban and other insurgents have stepped up attacks on Afghan and foreign forces this year
The violence comes as diplomatic sources confirmed the presence of Afghanistan's deputy foreign minister for political affairs, Hikmat Karzai, in the Pakistani capital Islamabad at the same time as a Taliban delegation from Qatar.
If a meeting takes place, it would be a pre-talk discussion similar to those already held in Beijing, Urumqi and Oslo , says BBC Kabul bureau chief Waheed Massoud.
The Taliban has stepped up its campaign of violence in recent months, taking advantage of the warmer weather of spring and summer. It has been making military gains, especially in northern Afghanistan.
Last week, a suicide bomber struck a convoy of Nato troops close to the US embassy, killing one civilian and injuring 22.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:08:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India woman 'set on fire by police'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33422227#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Indian woman dies after alleging that she was set on fire by two policemen inside a police station when she refused to pay a bribe.</Description>
        <MainBody>India woman 'set on fire by police' in Uttar Pradesh
7 July 2015
From the section India
Senior police official Abdul Hameed (right) said they had begun an investigation
A woman in the northern Indian state of Uttar Pradesh has died after alleging that she was set on fire by two policemen inside a police station after she refused to pay a bribe.
Neetu Dwivedi, 40, told a magistrate before her death that the policemen asked her for 100,000 rupees ($1,578).
She had gone to the police station to free her husband, who had been detained for questioning in a crime.
The accused policemen deny the charge and say she tried to immolate herself.
The policemen have been suspended and Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Akhilesh Yadav has ordered an inquiry into the case.
The incident took place on Monday in Barabanki town, senior police official Abdul Hameed told BBC Hindi.
Mrs Dwivedi, who sustained 80% burns, was admitted to hospital in the state capital, Lucknow, where she died on Tuesday morning.
In her dying declaration before a magistrate and reporters, she alleged that she was abused and humiliated by her attackers when she refused to pay the bribe.
Mrs Dwivedi's son, who is a journalist with a Hindi newspaper, has said he wants justice as his "mother will only rest in peace when the guilty are punished".
The incident comes barely a month after journalist Jagendra Singh was set on fire allegedly by some policemen in the state's Shahjahanpur district.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:09:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ceremonies commemorate 7/7 victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33407554#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A minute's silence is observed as ceremonies take place in memory of the 52 people killed in the London bombings of 7 July 2005.</Description>
        <MainBody>15 changes to anti-terror planning since 2005
Silences were held across the London transport network and flowers were laid at the sites of the four explosions.
The prime minister said the day of the attacks was "one of those days where everybody remembers exactly where they were when they heard the news".
Carmen Macovie and her friend Sarah were among those caught in the blast at Tavistock Square.
They met afterwards in one of the assistance centres set up to help those affected - and found they "finished each other's sentences" about the way they felt about what they experienced.
Ms Macovie said: "I can still remember every moment of that day, except where I was sitting on the bus. I remember standing there after it happened thinking, 'What happened to my bus?' It still feels like yesterday.
"The next day the picture of me standing on the bus was on the front of every paper.
"The most amazing things was the way Londoners reacted after it happened - with tolerance and togetherness. It's an amazing city."
Thirteen people were killed in the Tavistock Square bus blast
'Walk together'
Commuters were urged to "walk together" by finishing their morning bus or Underground commute one stop early and travelling the last few minutes by foot.
Adrian Luscombe, one of those taking part, tweeted : "A commuter today as I was 10 years ago. It could have been me. As fresh in memory as if it was yesterday."
Later, the Duke of Cambridge will join victims' families, survivors and ambulance and fire brigade employees who were working 10 years ago, for a service at the Hyde Park memorial, where there will be songs, recitals and a reading.
A unique grief
By Peter Hunt, BBC correspondent at Hyde Park
This was a simple, short almost stark ceremony.
There were no readings, no music.
In silence, wreaths - more than a dozen of them - were placed on the memorial stone at the time when, 10 years ago, three of the four homemade rucksack bombs exploded underground with such devastating consequences.
The 7 July Memorial, which consists of 52 stainless steel pillars, was designed to symbolise the random nature of the loss of life.
Tessa Jowell, a minister at the time of the attacks, has spoken of how each column represents a unique person, a unique grief.
The memorial events are very much about that grief; about the enduring sense of loss suffered by the bereaved; and about the unfulfilled futures of the 52 who were murdered.
Read more from Peter
The bombers began their journey to London from Luton
The bombings were carried out by Mohammad Sidique Khan, 30, Shehzad Tanweer, 22, Hasib Hussain, 18, and Germaine Lindsay, 19. The group had links to al-Qaeda in Pakistan and Afghanistan.
The UK's most senior counter-terrorism officer, Metropolitan Police Assistant Commissioner Mark Rowley, said the rise of Islamic State militants in Syria and Iraq meant the UK was now facing a "very different" threat.
"We've seen another step change in terrorism in the way it works and connects across the world in the last couple of years," he said.
The UK's terror threat level was raised from "substantial" to "severe" in August 2014 in response to conflicts in Iraq and Syria.
The victims
A total of 52 people lost their lives when four suicide bombers attacked central London 10 years ago. Here are their stories.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:18:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hungary MPs aim to restrict migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33421093#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hungarian MPs pass legislation to give the government the power to close the borders to all migrants and build a border fence.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hungary MPs approve border fence and anti-migrant law
7 July 2015
From the section Europe
There has been a sharp rise in the number of migrants trying to enter Hungary
Hungary's parliament has passed new legislation tightening asylum rules, and backed plans to erect a border fence to keep out migrants.
The new law allows the detention of migrants in temporary camps, the speeding up of asylum assessments and limiting the possibility for appeal.
The move was criticised by the UN and human rights groups.
Hungary has seen a rise in the number of migrants and asylum seekers in 2015, most of them entering from Serbia.
The government says about 72,000 migrants have entered the country so far this year, compared with 43,000 people in 2014.
The hope is that only "several dozen, or at most a few hundred" asylum seekers will be accepted in future, a senior government source told the BBC's Nick Thorpe.
'Devastating implications'
The new legislation was passed easily in a 151-41 vote on Monday, with the backing of the governing Fidesz party and the far-right Jobbik party.
"Hungary is confronted with the biggest surge of migrants in its history, its capacities are overloaded by 130%," said Interior Minister Sandor Pinter.
Government spokesman Zoltan Kovacs told the BBC that from now on the Hungarian authorities would regard Serbia, Macedonia, Bulgaria and Greece as "safe" countries.
In practice this means that almost all asylum seekers who reach Hungary - a landlocked country - overland will be rejected, Nick Thorpe reports from Budapest.
He adds that most will not even get a chance to apply, because they would be stopped by the border fence, construction of which is expected to begin immediately.
According to Mr Kovacs, Hungary will handle each asylum application on its own merits, albeit in a fast-track procedure, and will comply with the 1951 UN Convention on Refugees.
The fence is to run the length of the 175km (109-mile) border with Serbia.
The UN and human rights groups have criticised Hungary's immigration proposals.
The regional representative of the UN High Commissioner for Refugees warned that the legislation would have devastating implications for thousands of people seeking safety in Hungary.
Refugees from the wars in Syria, Iraq, Afghanistan and Democratic Republic of Congo could see their applications rejected automatically, our correspondent says.
"Eighty per cent of these people are fleeing war and conflict," said the UNHCR's Babar Baloch. "This is a refugee crisis, but it's being wrongly described as a migrant crisis by the politicians here."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:51:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Push for Iran deal as deadline nears</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33424502#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>World powers and Iran will continue to work towards a nuclear deal even though they are likely to miss Tuesday's deadline, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks: Deal 'within reach' as deadline nears
7 July 2015
From the section Middle East
Representatives from both sides said a comprehensive deal was closer than ever before
World powers and Iran will continue to work towards a comprehensive nuclear deal even though they are likely to miss Tuesday's deadline, officials say.
Negotiations took place late into the night in the Austrian capital, Vienna, with foreign ministers grappling to resolve outstanding differences.
However, US officials said the midnight (22:00 GMT) deadline might slip and that an agreement was not yet assured.
The talks have intensified since the previous deadline was missed last week.
The so-called P5+1 - the US, UK, France, China and Russia plus Germany - want Iran to scale back its sensitive nuclear activities to ensure that it cannot build a nuclear weapon.
Iran, which wants crippling international sanctions lifted, has always insisted that its nuclear work is peaceful.
'Within reach'
Representatives from both sides said a deal was closer than ever before as they arrived at Vienna's Palais Coburg hotel on Monday. China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi told reporters: "The comprehensive agreement is within reach."
Progress has been made - one Iranian newspaper reported that there was agreement on the main body of the accord and four of the five annexes. But several sticking points remain, including limits on nuclear research and development and guidelines for inspections.
Tehran is also demanding that the UN ban on the import and export of conventional arms and ballistic missiles be lifted as part of any deal, a senior Iranian official said on Monday.
The text of a new UN Security Council resolution is being drafted, but the US and its European allies oppose lifting the arms embargo because Iran has been accused of fomenting unrest in the Middle East. Russia and China have expressed support.
US Secretary of State John Kerry wants an agreement finalised by Wednesday at the latest so that it can be submitted to the US Congress for approval by Thursday. If a deal is presented later, the review period will double from 30 days to 60.
Journalists are gathered outside the Palais Coburg hotel, awaiting a breakthrough
White House spokesman Josh Earnest said it was "certainly possible" that Tuesday's deadline might slip, while state department spokesman John Kirby insisted that Tuesday was merely "an extension of basically seven days of the parameters" of the framework accord agreed in Lausanne in April.
But he added: "Everybody is still, I think, rowing on the oars here to try to get a deal done. But it's got to be the right deal."
An Iranian official told reporters: "If we pass 9 July, this may not be the end of the world."
Officials from the global nuclear watchdog, the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) meanwhile held "intense discussions" with officials in Tehran about the possible military dimensions of Iran's nuclear programme.
The IAEA has said Iran has failed to give a satisfactory explanation of its research at a military site into detonators that could be used to trigger a nuclear weapon or explained studies that could help calculate the explosive yield of one.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:09:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US 'intensifying' anti-IS campaign</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33418021#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The US-led coalition fighting Islamic State is "intensifying" its campaign against the group's base in northern Syria, President Barack Obama says.</Description>
        <MainBody>US campaign against Islamic State in Syria 'intensifying'
7 July 2015
From the section Middle East
US fighter jets have been leading air strikes against Islamic State in Syria and Iraq
The US-led coalition fighting the Islamic State group is "intensifying" its campaign in northern Syria, President Barack Obama says.
Speaking at the Pentagon, Mr Obama said the US would not send additional troops to Syria but would increase support for the country's moderate opposition.
He added that "an effective partner on the ground" was needed to defeat IS.
It comes as IS militants were reported to have regained control of the town Ain Issa from Kurdish-led forces.
Mr Obama's remarks followed some of the heaviest bombing of IS since coalition strikes began in September last year.
The bombing targeted Raqqa, IS's de facto capital in Syria.
"We're intensifying our efforts against Isil's base in Syria," said Mr Obama, using another name for the militant group.
"Our air strikes will continue to target the oil and gas facilities that fund so much of their operations.
"When we have an effective partner on the ground, Isil can be pushed back," he added.
However, he warned that the campaign against the group would "not be quick".
The Popular Protection Units (YPG) celebrated seizing Ain Issa just two weeks ago
Earlier on Monday, IS militants reportedly regained control of a town near their northern Syrian stronghold of Raqqa from Kurdish-led forces.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a UK-based monitoring group, said jihadists overran Ain Issa - 50km (30 miles) from Raqqa - and nearby villages.
But a spokesman for the Kurdish Popular Protection Units (YPG), which seized the town from IS two weeks ago, said it was still resisting the IS assault.
YPG fighters and allied Syrian rebels had only seized Ain Issa from IS two weeks ago.
The jihadist group had suffered a series of defeats in areas along the Turkish border, since being forced to withdraw from the town of Kobane in January.
However, in recent weeks, IS has launched several deadly counter-attacks against the Kurds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:18:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sunday trading laws could be relaxed</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33421315#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Shops in England and Wales could be allowed to open for longer on Sundays, under plans to be unveiled by Chancellor George Osborne.</Description>
        <MainBody>Budget to propose longer Sunday trading hours
7 July 2015
From the section UK Politics
comments
Shops in England and Wales could be allowed to open for longer on Sundays, under plans to be unveiled by Chancellor George Osborne.
The proposal expected in Wednesday's Budget could give elected mayors and councils powers to relax laws locally if it might boost economic activity.
Current laws allows smaller shops to open all day, but restrict those over 280 sq m (3,000 sq ft) to six hours.
The Association of Convenience Stores said some small shops could struggle.
The Treasury pointed to research by the New West End Company - which represents more than 600 businesses in London - that suggested two extra hours of Sunday trading could create nearly 3,000 jobs in the capital.
It said such a move would also generate more than 200m a year in additional sales in London.
Olympic Games trial
The proposal comes after larger stores and supermarkets were allowed to open for longer on Sundays during the 2012 London Olympic and Paralympic Games.
Mr Osborne said decisions on similar relaxations of the law should be taken at a local level - if officials think longer opening hours would boost economies.
The chancellor said there was a "growing appetite" for shopping on a Sunday.
"There is some evidence that transactions for Sunday shopping are actually growing faster than those for Saturday.
"The rise of online shopping, which people can do round the clock, also means more retailers want to be able to compete by opening for longer at the weekend.
"But this won't be right for every area, so I want to devolve the power to make this decision to mayors and local authorities," he added.
Analysis by Robin Brant, BBC political correspondent
Ms Soubry said the only thing to look forward to on Sundays used to be 'Sing Something Simple' on the radio
Anna Soubry is on a mission to cheer up Sundays and her solution is shopping.
The small business minister has been out promoting the case for extending opening hours and sharing her recollection of what the seventh day used to be like 'Chez Soubry'.
It was the most "miserable" day of the week and as far as she is concerned it was a myth that families came together on the day of rest.
Yes, she knows some people like to go to church and switch off but she thinks more flexible retail options will brighten up Sundays.
There are also the new jobs and flexibility it will bring too for people who work funny hours, like her, she says.
It is not the answer to everything, though.
She told me food shopping in a supermarket can be "depressing", and that seemed to apply to any day of the week.
Small Business Minister Anna Soubry told the BBC the government would consult on the proposal first.
But she said she thought it was a good idea, telling Radio 4's Today programme it was "about giving local authorities the ability to determine what they do in their local area".
She said: "I want to listen to what the unions have to say and obviously I'm concerned if they say it will put pressure on workers.
"But I don't think they are right, actually. This is all about devolving power down to local authorities who are more than capable of being able to make a decision that suits their area."
Ms Soubry also warned against "harking back to a world that probably didn't exist... we are of that generation where Sunday, truthfully, was the most miserable day of the week".
"The only thing to look forward to was Sing Something Simple on the radio. Goodness me, if that didn't sum up a miserable Sunday."
Sunday shopping law across the UK
In England and Wales, the Sunday trading law applies to shops over 280 sq m. They can open on Sundays but only for six consecutive hours between 10:00 and 18:00, and must close on Easter Sunday and on Christmas Day.
In Northern Ireland a 1997 law "removed the restrictions on the goods which may be sold in shops on Sunday", allowed small shops (under 280 sq m) to trade any time on Sunday and allowed big shops to trade for a maximum of five hours between 13:00 and 18:00.
In Scotland there are no restrictions and shops often open for long hours on Sundays.
Trading hours for retailers
High Street shops have been coming under growing pressure from online retailers, which now account for 11% of retail sales overall - rising to 17% in the month before Christmas of last year.
A review of the 1994 Sunday Trading Act by the then Labour government in 2006 resulted in no change to the law.
The Bishop of St Albans, the Right Reverend Alan Smith - who speaks for the Church of England on the economy in the House of Lords - criticised the proposals.
He told BBC Radio 4's The World at One programme it was important to "balance the rights of those who want to go shopping with those who find themselves having to work on Sunday when they don't want to".
"We have to make some quite big decisions.. about what sort of society we have," he added.
Bishop Smith said giving local authorities the power to set hours for their areas was "a recipe for disaster", because people visiting different parts of the country "won't know where they stand".
But Conservative MP Philip Davies. the vice chairman of the all-party parliamentary group on retail, said Sunday was the most convenient day of the week for some people to go shopping.
He said the current law was "absurd" because smaller branches of Tesco and Sainsbury's were able to open later but larger stores' hours were restricted.
George Osborne will unveil the government's new Budget on Wednesday
Welcoming the chancellor's proposal, Adrian Pepper, from the Open Sundays campaign group, said restricting Sunday opening hours "makes no sense".
"The current Sunday trading laws do not preserve any valuable cultural aspects of our way of life. They just make life more inconvenient," he said.
However, Association of Convenience Stores chief executive James Lowman said giving local authorities responsibility for setting Sunday trading hours could lead to "inconsistency and confusion" for businesses and shoppers.
Mr Lowman said the same amount of trade would be spread over more hours and would shift from small shops to larger stores.
"The short period of time that small stores are open while large stores are shut is a crucial advantage for convenience stores, most of which are owned by small businesses.
"Liberalising Sunday trading hours would make some small stores unviable," he added.
John Hannett, secretary general of shopworkers' union USDAW, said the announcement was disappointing, and the union would campaign against the move.
He told the Today programme it would not bring further economic benefits to the country, but would put more pressure on employees.
'Definitively rejected'
Meanwhile, campaign group Keep Sundays Special accused the government of a U-turn over Sunday trading hours.
Its spokesman, Michael Trend, said it received a letter on behalf of David Cameron in April which stated that there were "no plans" to relax the current laws.
He said Sundays should be a time for family, friends and community, arguing that the plans should be "definitively rejected".
Labour leader contender Andy Burnham said he would oppose any relaxation in the current laws.
He said in a tweet that Sundays were the only day shop workers could spend time with family.
Green Party leader Natalie Bennett also signalled her opposition to the move, tweeting that the move would be bad for small businesses, people and communities.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:41:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HSBC sacks staff over mock IS video</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33424034#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>HSBC sacks employees who made an "abhorrent" video in which they pretended to be Islamic State militants carrying out a beheading.</Description>
        <MainBody>HSBC sacks staff over mock Islamic State video
7 July 2015
From the section UK
HSBC has sacked employees who made an "abhorrent" video in which they pretended to be Islamic State militants carrying out a beheading.
The video was posted online and shows a man dressed in an orange jumpsuit, while five other men in black stand around him - one holding a fake knife.
The Sun said the employees were members of the bank's legal division in Birmingham on a team building exercise.
The bank said it did not tolerate "inappropriate behaviour".
"As soon as the Sun brought this video to our attention we took the decision to sack the individuals involved," the bank said.
"This is an abhorrent video and HSBC would like to apologise for any offence caused."
The bank did not specify how many people had been sacked.
'Shocking behaviour'
The newspaper has posted an eight-second clip of the video on its website in which one man shouts "Allahu Akbar" - Arabic for "God is great" - while others laugh.
It said the employees created the video while on a visit to Teamworks Karting in Birmingham.
Teamworks Karting has released a statement which described their actions as "shocking behaviour".
It said: "The abhorrent video was filmed without our knowledge, during a private party booked by one of our corporate clients and we would not wish this to reflect negatively on Teamworks.
"We have lodged a complaint with HSBC and understand that the individuals involved have since been sacked."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:15:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Libor trader says managers knew</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33426974#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A trader accused of manipulating the Libor rate has told a court that senior managers knew what he was doing.</Description>
        <MainBody>Libor trader tells court managers knew what he was doing
By Mark Broad BBC News, Southwark Crown Court
7 July 2015
From the section Business
Tom Hayes denied that what he was doing was "clandestine"
A trader accused of manipulating the Libor rate has told a court that senior managers knew what he was doing.
Tom Hayes is the first trader to be tried by a jury for his part in the manipulation of the key interest rate.
"I acted with complete transparency...  My managers knew, my manager's manager knew. In some cases the CEO [chief executive] was aware of it," he said.
The former UBS and Citigroup trader denies eight counts of conspiracy to defraud over the period 2006-2010.
'Hunger'
Mr Hayes denied that what he was doing was "clandestine" and said that he made no attempts to "cover his tracks".
The 35-year-old said that he did not believe that at the time that what he was doing as a Libor trader was "wrong".
He said he was motivated by his determination to make as much money as possible for his bank.
"Greed was the wrong word, hunger is a better word.
"I was hungry to do the best job I could do - because of the performance metric, because that is how you are judged," he told the jury at Southwark Crown Court.
$300m
Mr Hayes also said that others bankers at UBS seemed to be fixing the Libor rate for commercial gain before he arrived at the bank.
He said that a group of senior managers at UBS discussed manipulating the Libor rate and that "nobody batted an eye lid".
Mr Hayes told the court that he was frustrated by the pay he was getting at UBS
He said he had calculated that he had  made $300m for UBS over three years and that the bank had not paid him what he felt he was owed for his success.
He said that very little of his profit for the bank actually came from Libor trading.
'Frozen with fear'
During his time at Citi Bank in August 2010, Mr Hayes was called into meeting with lawyers who were looking into the Libor market.
Mr Hayes said that he could not work out what he rules he might have broken.
'I could not work out what I had or had not done wrong. They could not tell me what rule I had broken.'
Mr Hayes also told the court that he gave interviews to the Serious Fraud Office in 2013 cataloguing his actions as a Libor trader in order to prevent him being extradited to the US where he was being charged by the Department of Justice.
He said that he was "frozen with fear" and  "petrified" when he learned that he was to be charged by the US Authorities.
Mr Hayes is the first person in the global investigation to stand trial for allegedly rigging the rate.
Mr Hayes's trading activities were based around movements in the Libor rate - an interest rate used by banks around the world to set the price of financial products worth trillions of pounds.
The trial continues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:55:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watchdog probe into RSA's Irish unit</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33427323#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The UK accounting watchdog is to investigate the conduct of individuals working for the Irish unit of RSA Insurance in the run-up to its bailout by its UK parent.</Description>
        <MainBody>Watchdog probe into RSA's Irish unit
7 July 2015
From the section Business
The UK accounting watchdog is to investigate the conduct of individuals working for the Irish unit of RSA Insurance in the run-up to its bailout by its UK parent company.
The Financial Reporting Council (FRC) said the probe was related to "financial irregularities" at the insurer.
It did not identify individuals or say if they still worked at the business.
RSA Insurance was forced to inject 200m into its Irish unit in 2013.
The company subsequently tapped shareholders for cash through a rights issue to help bolster its finances.
Compensation
RSA's Irish unit was bailed out weeks after the resignation of its chief executive Philip Smith and after the insurer informed the market about the accounting irregularities.
Mr Smith was initially suspended after an investigation was launched into issues in the Irish unit's claims and finance functions identified during a internal routine audit.
Last month, he won a 1.25m compensation payment for a constructive dismissal.
RSA is appealing against the award.
RSA Group's chief executive, Simon Lee, also resigned in the wake of the crisis at the Irish unit. He was eventually replaced by former Royal Bank of Scotland boss Stephen Hester
The FRC said the investigation would cover 2012 "and relevant prior periods as a result of the identification of issues within the claims and accounting functions announced by RSA Insurance Group at the end of 2013".
RSA said the FRC's investigation was not into the company itself but into individuals who were members of accounting, auditing or actuarial professional bodies.
It said in a statement: "We understand that the investigation will therefore cover members of these professions who were employed by RSA at the  time. RSA Group will of course assist with these inquiries if requested to do so."
The FRC said it would co-operate with the Irish authorities as necessary.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:57:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oil and gas boosts UK industry</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33422015#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A rise in oil and gas output boosted UK industrial production in May, but manufacturing output fell for the second month in a row.</Description>
        <MainBody>Oil and gas output boosts UK industrial production
7 July 2015
From the section Business
A rise in oil and gas output boosted UK industrial production in May, official figures show, but manufacturing output continued to fall.
Industrial production rose 0.4% in May, helped by a 7.3% rise in oil and gas output and higher mining output.
However, manufacturing continued to lag behind, falling by 0.6% last month after a fall of 0.4% in April.
Manufacturers have struggled against the strength of the pound and weak demand in European markets.
The numbers suggested "a persistent weakness" developing in manufacturing, said UBS economist David Tinsley.
"The last few months' readings of manufacturing output have been soft, and surveys such as the PMI are also suggesting slower growth," he added.
Compared with a year earlier, industrial output rose by 2.1%, the strongest annual growth since April of last year, and manufacturing was up 1.0%.
George Osborne is expected to announce more help for manufacturers in his Budget announcement on Wednesday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:42:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mayweather stripped of WBO title</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/boxing/33418239</Link>
        <Description>Five-weight world champion Floyd Mayweather is stripped of the WBO welterweight belt he won from Manny Pacquiao.</Description>
        <MainBody>The May contest between Floyd Mayweather (left) and Manny Pacquiao was billed as the "fight of the century"
7 July 2015 Last updated at 06:42
print
Floyd Mayweather stripped of WBO title won from Pacquiao
Five-weight world champion Floyd Mayweather has been stripped of the WBO welterweight belt won from Manny Pacquiao in May.
The 38-year-old failed to pay the WBO a $200,000 (128,000) fee to administer the fight by the 3 July deadline.
Mayweather had been expected to relinquish the title by now, saying he planned to do so following his points victory over Pacquiao.
Fellow American Timothy Bradley will now become the full belt holder.
After Mayweather defeated Pacquiao, he had declared he would vacate all his titles in order to give younger fighters the chance to win belts.
"The WBO World Championship Committee is allowed no other alternative but to cease to recognize Mr Floyd Mayweather Jr as the WBO welterweight champion of the world and vacate his title." said a statement on wboboxing.com.
Mayweather, who still holds the WBA and WBC belts at welterweight, has until 20 July to appeal against the decision.
He is expected to stage one more fight in Las Vegas on 12 September, although he has yet to name the opponent.
The WBO created a vacant interim welterweight belt for the 27 June fight between Bradley and Jessie Vargas.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:19:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Djokovic through to quarter-finals</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/33430920</Link>
        <Description>Defending champion Novak Djokovic is into the quarter-finals at Wimbledon after coming back from two sets down to beat Kevin Anderson.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wimbledon 2015: Novak Djokovic beats Kevin Anderson
By Chris Bevan BBC Sport at Wimbledon
Wimbledon 2015
Play: 11:30 BST outside courts; 13:00 Centre Court and Court One
BBC coverage: Live across TV, radio and online with up to 15 live streams
Defending champion Novak Djokovic is into the quarter-finals at Wimbledon after completing his comeback from two sets down to beat Kevin Anderson.
Djokovic had levelled at two sets all when bad light stopped play on Monday.
He struggled to find his rhythm when play resumed on Tuesday after a delay because of rain.
But the world number one and top seed finally got to grips with the big-serving South African to win 6-7 (6-8) 6-7 (6-8) 6-1 6-4 7-5.
More to follow.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:11:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Batsman struck by cricket ball dies</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/cricket/33425867</Link>
        <Description>A cricketer dies after being struck on the chest by a ball while batting during a local league match in Surrey.</Description>
        <MainBody>The British Tamil Cricket League has cancelled all third division matches scheduled for 12 July
7 July 2015 Last updated at 14:11
print
Bavalan Pathmanathan dies after being struck in chest by ball
A cricketer has died after being struck on the chest by a ball during a local league match in Surrey.
Bavalan Pathmanathan, 24, was batting for Manipay Parish Sports Club in the British Tamil League on Sunday at Long Ditton recreation grounds.
An air ambulance was called but he later died of his injuries.
In November, Australia batsman Phillip Hughes died two days after being struck on the top of the neck by a ball during a domestic match in Sydney.
Pathmanathan's team-mate Rukshan, who was also batting at the time, told the Colombo Mirror: "When he received the hit I asked from the other end if he is alright. He gave a thumb-up and nodded to indicate he was alright, while pressing his chest.
"He took a couple of steps behind the stumps and collapsed.
"He was such a talented and composed cricketer and a darling friend of all of us. Every one of us is going through terrible pain as a result of this terrible loss."
A statement on Manipay Parish Sports Club's Facebook page said they were "totally shocked by his death at this young age".
Surrey chief executive Richard Gould added: "Everyone at the club has been deeply saddened to learn of Bavalan's death and would like to extend their sympathies to his family, friends and everyone who knew him from within the community of cricket."
A report by the Federation of International Cricketers' Associations (Fica) found last month that cricketers are as much at risk from lightning strikes, mental illness and terrorism as they are of being seriously injured by the ball.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Radio 3 host slams Proms 'snobs'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33425935#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Critics of an upcoming BBC Prom that will celebrate the dance sounds of Ibiza are branded "snobs and scaremongers" by Radio 3 presenter Suzy Klein.</Description>
        <MainBody>Radio 3 presenter slams Proms 'snobs'
7 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Klein is a regular presenter of Radio 3's daily afternoon music show In Tune
Critics of an upcoming BBC Prom that will celebrate the dance sounds of Ibiza have been branded "snobs and scaremongers" by a Radio 3 presenter.
Writing in the Radio Times , Suzy Klein said suggestions the BBC was "teetering worryingly at the top of a slippery slope" were "a load of old cobblers".
"Electronic dance music is dazzling in its primal energy," the presenter of Radio 3's In Tune programme continued.
"Great music festivals must embrace great music, in its many guises."
The late-night Prom on 29 July will see Radio 1 presenter Pete Tong celebrate 20 years of the Ibiza dance scene in a concert with Jules Buckley and the Heritage Orchestra.
This year's Proms season also includes a BBC Radio 1Extra Prom on 12 August featuring leading hip-hop and grime artists from Britain's urban music scene.
Klein promised that the latter concert would be "mind-blowing" and could hardly be seen as "the tip of the iceberg for Proms armageddon".
"I love dancing to an addictive club anthem as much as I adore listening... to a Brahms symphony," the broadcaster wrote. "Who says you're not allowed to enjoy all of it?"
The 2015 BBC Proms season runs from 17 July to 12 September and will comprise 92 concerts in total, mainly at London's Royal Albert Hall.
Klein is a regular presenter of Radio 3's daily afternoon music show and will be one of the presenters of the BBC's Proms coverage.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:16:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>James Naughtie to leave Today show</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33423245#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Presenter James Naughtie is to leave Radio 4's Today programme and take on a new role as a special correspondent from early next year.</Description>
        <MainBody>James Naughtie to leave Radio 4 Today programme
7 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Naughtie will take on a new role as BBC News Book Editor
Presenter James Naughtie is to leave Radio 4's Today programme and take on a new role as a special correspondent from early next year.
The veteran journalist has presented Radio 4's flagship breakfast news programme for more than 21 years.
He is also being appointed BBC News Books Editor and will present a book review on Radio 4 on Saturday mornings.
BBC director general Tony Hall called Naughtie "the emotional heart of Today for a generation".
Naughtie joined Today in 1994 following the death of Brian Redhead, having spent six years as presenter of The World at One.
He has anchored every election results programme for BBC Radio since 1997 and has worked on every US presidential election since 1988.
Last year, he become a chief reporter in the BBC's coverage of the independence referendum in Scotland.
Naughtie has presented Radio 4's Bookclub since 1998
In recent years, he has written and presented radio documentaries including a 60-part story of classical music, The Making of Music.
His new role as Books Editor comes as a result of presenting Radio 4's monthly Bookclub since it began in 1998.
The 63-year-old said: "It was exciting to discover that the BBC and I had the same idea about what I should do next. I'm thrilled to be moving from one dream job to another, and working with the programmes across Radio 4 - including Today - that I love and have known for so long.
He added: "After 21 years, I can turn off that 3am alarm at last".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:25:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BBC boss defends licence fee deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33422814#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>BBC director general Tony Hall defends the corporation's decision to take on the cost of free TV licences for people over the age of 75.</Description>
        <MainBody>BBC director general defends licence fee deal
7 July 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Lord Hall said he was first approached about taking on the cost of free licence fees last week
The BBC's director general has defended the corporation's decision to take on the cost of free TV licences for people over the age of 75.
"It gives us financial stability and the ability to plan for the future," Tony Hall told BBC Radio 4's Today.
He rejected comments by former culture secretary Ben Bradshaw that the deal effectively made the BBC "a branch of the department of work and pensions".
But he acknowledged misgivings over the process that led to the arrangement.
"There are issues to do with the independence of the BBC which will be examined at the charter review," said Lord Hall.
There has been criticism from the chair of the BBC Trust, Rona Fairhead, and former director general Lord Birt, that the deal was struck behind closed doors.
"We are disappointed that [the public] have not been given any say in the major decisions about the BBC's future funding," said Fairhead in an open letter to chancellor George Osborne.
Lord Birt said the government had set "a very dangerous precedent" by failing to consult the public, and suggested the BBC's independence had been compromised.
"I think the process should be looked at," Lord Hall told Today presenter John Humphrys , "This is the second time this has happened. It is the government's decision to come at it this way."
The new deal was unexpectedly announced in the House of Commons by culture secretary John Whittingdale on Monday, in response to an urgent question tabled by Labour MP Chris Bryant, following newspaper reports of the settlement.
In return for the BBC's agreement to shoulder the 650m cost of free TV licences, the government promised to allow the 145.50 fee to increase in line with inflation and close a loophole that made it possible to watch on-demand television without a licence.
Ministers said the move would be phased in from 2018-19. At the same time, the BBC's commitment to fund rural broadband will be decreased.
Lord Hall said "the government's decision has been more than matched by the deal coming back to the BBC."
But Mr Bryant, the shadow culture secretary, described the agreement as a "shabby little deal" and said Labour would oppose the government's plans if they amounted to a "smash and grab raid" on the BBC.
BBC funding
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:03:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: One killed in US ice cave collapse</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33426707#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Authorities in the US have reported one person dead and several others injured after part of an ice cave collapse in Washington.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
One killed in US ice cave collapse
7 July 2015 Last updated at 11:03 BST
Authorities in the US have reported one person dead and several others injured after part of an ice cave collapsed at the Big Four ice caves in Washington state.
The area is a popular with hikers, and attracts thousands of visitors in the summer months.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:28:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Spain bull runners describe injuries</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33426708#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Some of those taking part in the annual running of the bulls in Pamplona have been describing their experience.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Pamplona bull run: Runners describe injuries
7 July 2015 Last updated at 12:28 BST
Some of those taking part in the annual running of the bulls in Pamplona have been describing their experience.
Several people were injured in the event which forms part of the San Fermin festival - an eight-day celebration of the town's patron saint.
On Saturday an anti-bull running protest was held outside the Pamplona bullring.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:34:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Anti-IS campaign 'will not be quick'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33420749#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>US President Barack Obama says there is progress in the campaign against Islamic State militants, but emphasises that ''it will not be quick''.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Obama: Campaign against IS militants 'will not be quick'
7 July 2015 Last updated at 00:34 BST
President Barack Obama says there has been progress in the campaign against Islamic State militants, but has emphasised ''it will not be quick''.
Speaking at a Pentagon briefing, the US president said that the task was largely up to local forces on the ground - but that losses in Syria and Iraq proved that the militants could be defeated.
''Our coalition has now hit Isil [Islamic State] with more than 5,000 airstrikes, we've taken out thousands of fighting positions, tanks, vehicles, bomb factories and training camps,'' he said.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:07:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Pope Francis celebrates Mass in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33420750#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of thousands of people gather in the Ecuadorean port city of Guayaquil to greet Pope Francis as he arrives to celebrate an open-air mass.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Pope Francis celebrates Mass in Ecuador on his Latin America tour
7 July 2015 Last updated at 03:07 BST
Hundreds of thousands of people have gathered in the Ecuadorean port city of Guayaquil to greet Pope Francis.
The pontiff waved to the crowds from his custom car ahead of an open-air mass in the city's Samanes Park, where his sermon focussed on the importance of family as ''the first school for children''.
Ben Bland reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:24:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Five banking headaches facing Greeks</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33415799#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Ros Atkins explains the banking restrictions and the impact are they having on everyday life in Greece.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Greek crisis: Five banking issues causing headaches in Greece
6 July 2015 Last updated at 20:24 BST
Eurozone finance ministers say they expect to hear new proposals from Greece after the country voted to reject the terms of a bailout.
Greek banks have remained closed and the Greek people are only able to withdraw 60 euros each from cash machines per day.
Ros Atkins explains the banking restrictions and the impact they are having on everyday life in Greece.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:43:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Anniversary of Asia's biggest war</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-33420751#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Commemorations are taking place to mark the 70th anniversary of the end of the Second Sino-Japanese War in 1945 - the biggest war in Asia in the 20th Century.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Marking 70 years since Second Sino-Japanese War
7 July 2015 Last updated at 02:43 BST
Commemorations are taking place to mark the 70th anniversary of the end of the Second Sino-Japanese War in 1945 - the biggest war in Asia in the 20th Century.
The war later merged into the Second World War and changed the history of China and the world - but little is known outside the region about it.
Cindy Sui reports from Taipei.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:00:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Driver survives massive Nascar crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33416452#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Nascar driver Austin Dillon survived a massive last-lap crash on Monday that saw his car hurdled upside down into protective fencing.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Driver survives horrific Nascar crash
6 July 2015 Last updated at 19:00 BST
It was the last lap of the Nascar Sprint Cup Series in Daytona Beach, Florida when Austin Dillon's car went hurdling through the air.
The incident occurred shortly before 02:41 localtime (07:41 BST) on Monday, and saw Mr Dillon's car fly upside down into a protective fence before falling back to the track.
Once on the track, the upside down vehicle was smashed again by an oncoming vehicle.
Crews raced to car and quickly signalled that Mr Dillon was unhurt. Several fans were treated for minor injuries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:03:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Lesbos migrant camp strewn with rubbish</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33420008#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Record-breaking numbers of migrants are arriving on the Greek island of Lesbos overwhelming local authorities</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Island of Lesbos struggles to cope with migrant influx
6 July 2015 Last updated at 23:03 BST
Police on the Greek island of Lesbos are reporting a big increase in the number of migrants.
They say 1,600 arrived on Saturday breaking all previous records. Many are believed to be fleeing the conflict in Syria.
The island's only detention facility is overwhelmed and a makeshift camp set up on an abandoned race track is also unable to cope.
Anna Holligan reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:14:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The children scarred by war</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33424229#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The children scarred by the Gaza-Israel war, one year on</Description>
        <MainBody>Lyse Doucet Chief international correspondent
7 July 2015
From the section Middle East
A wasteland of rubble still bears testament to last summer's conflict between Israel and Gaza. But there are deeper scars - damage that can't be seen and may never heal.
A week after the fighting began, Syed's life was shattered on the day the 12-year-old, his 11-year-old brother Mohamed, and their six cousins went to Gaza's beach to play football.
It was the natural playground for young boys from a family of fishermen which has lived off the sea for generations.
"We didn't know that beach was dangerous," says Syed - his eyes still, round, sad pools, as he remembers 16 July, one of the most harrowing days of the war.
By the end of that day, Mohamed and three of his cousins were dead. An Israeli investigation said its air force mistook the children for Hamas fighters when a pilot fired twice at a "compound" next to the beach.
Syed and the three other boys who survived still show small scars on their legs and disturbing signs of being severely traumatised.
"For the son I lost, my tears will never dry," says his mother. But she fears she lost two sons last summer. "Those left behind are lost like those who died," she laments, as she looks across their small one-bedroom home at Syed, who stares blankly into the distance.
Syed finds it hard to sleep, and too tough to go to school because it reminds him of his brother. Even the sea, which had been a constant reference point in his life, no longer feels safe. "I never used to get scared, but now I do," he tells me as we ride in a speed boat close to the shore and he fiddles nervously with the cords on his life jacket.
Abdulrahman lost his father and 17 other family members in the conflict
His cousins struggle with even darker emotions. One tried to jump from a window after an angry altercation with his father. Another almost pushed a girl under a bus. They all live with nightmares, and battle just to get through each day.
Find out more
Children of the Gaza War will be broadcast on BBC Two on Wednesday 8 July at 21:00.
You can catch up later via BBC iPlayer.
By the end of the 51-day conflict, 551 Gazan children had lost their lives. Many more lost loved ones. The UN estimates that nearly 400,000 children need counselling. Syed has had some sessions at Gaza's community mental health programme - they help, but it's not enough. Therapy doesn't stand much chance as long as children are acutely aware that the conflict isn't over. They've already lived through three wars in six years.
Aid agencies say none of the nearly 20,000 homes destroyed in the fighting have been rebuilt, and more than 100,000 people remain displaced.
On the Israeli side of the border, children also live with distressing reminders of last summer's fighting, which also killed a young Israeli boy in the kibbutz of Nahal Oz.
"It's so not fair," protests 10-year-old Michal whose home in Nahal Oz lies only about a mile from Gaza. "We can't just keep running away, because it's our home and we need to live here.
"It's not because of us, it's not because of Gaza kids," she says, her eyes narrowing behind bright pink sunglasses.
A few miles away, the southern Israeli town of Sderot, sometimes referred to as the "bomb shelter capital of the world", has been the target of rockets fired from Gaza for 14 years.
Eilon was born the year missiles started landing, and speaks of a childhood "where I didn't grow up as a normal child". He's lived through two rocket attacks in his own neighbourhood in recent years.
His nightmares after last year's war led him to see a trauma counsellor. Months after a ceasefire was agreed, he still kept sleeping in the bomb-proof bedroom that's built in every Israeli home.
The first time he and his 10-year-old sister Agam summon up enough courage to climb the highest ridge in Sderot, they look at neighbouring Gaza through binoculars.
"Wow, look at the destruction there. It saddens me because there are innocent people there who were killed, but on the other hand there are people there that didn't care about us," remarks Eilon.
"They are the homes of people who want to kill us," adds Agam.
Israel says its 2014 campaign, Operation Protective Edge, was launched to stop rocket attacks from Gaza and destroy a vast network of tunnels, some of which extended into Israeli communities. Hamas, which controls most of Gaza, said it was fighting against Israeli air strikes and incursions, and trying to ease severe restrictions on its crossings with both Israel and Egypt.
But civilians, including children, paid a heavy price. A recent UN investigation said both Israeli forces and Palestinian militant groups violated international humanitarian law. Their actions, it said, may have amounted to war crimes.
A report released this week by Save the Children, A Living Nightmare , says the vast majority of children in the hardest-hit area still experience nightmares and bed wetting.
Twelve-year-old Samar's home in a block of flats is one of many places that lie in ruins just next to the border. "I never imagined it would be this bad," she gasps, as she and her siblings wander through the hollowed rooms of their devastated apartment for the first time since it was destroyed in the fighting.
"We had dreams of growing up here with our father," she says as she tries to find her balance on a mound of dust and concrete.  Then she collapses in tears.
Samar and her family took shelter in a UN school, but her father died, and her mother was seriously injured when Israeli missiles struck the building.
Israel says its forces only targeted infrastructure used by Hamas to attack Israel. But it has been accused of insufficient regard for civilian lives, while Hamas and other Palestinian militant groups are blamed for firing missiles from residential areas.
Twelve-year-old Abdulrahman, the son of a Hamas fighter, lost 17 members of his family. Fifteen homes in his neighbourhood were destroyed. "If they besiege us, we will hit them with more rockets," he declares with a manly defiance, but a child's sadness to see his small world reduced to piles of rubble.
Every child I meet in Gaza and southern Israel finds a different way to cope with memories of a summer they struggle to forget.
But every child said, ever so matter-of-factly, that another war was coming. And every child still hoped that, somehow, it wouldn't.
"Is it right that children around the world live and play in comfort and safety while we live with death and destruction?" pleads Abdulrahman.
Children of the Gaza War is on BBC Two on Wednesday 8 July at 21:00 BST. It is on BBC World News on 11 July at  09:10 and 21:10 GMT and on 12 July at 02:10 and 15:10 GMT. You can catch up later via BBC iPlayer .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:39:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Would Calais migrants really be better off in the UK?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33268521#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Is the UK better than France for migrants?</Description>
        <MainBody>Would Calais migrants really be better off in the UK?
By Justin Parkinson BBC News Magazine
7 July 2015
From the section Magazine
Around 3,000 migrants are camped around Calais in northern France. Many of them think life will be better in the UK than France - or many other EU countries - but are they right?
Scenes of immigrants trying to storm the Channel Tunnel, or climbing aboard lorries, show how desperate those who have fled to Europe are to get to the UK from France. On Tuesday a migrant died on a freight shuttle through the tunnel.
Many want to claim asylum in the UK. Others want to enter the country incognito to remain as illegal workers. But what do migrants say is drawing them to the UK - and is the risk of prolonging their journey really worth it?
Benefits
"I heard good news about England. They give you a house and some money to spend and live. And then they give them the opportunity to study, to have a good life."
Hamzei, from Afghanistan
Both France and the UK offer cost-of-living benefits, for food, clothing, toiletries and so on, for those awaiting an asylum decision.
In the UK the system is known as Section 95 support, and is given to those unable to feed themselves. Its entitlements are 72.52 a week for a married couple or a couple in a civil partnership. Lone parents over 18 get 43.94 and single people of this age 36.95. Those aged 16 to 18 get 39.80 and under-16s get 52.96.
The French system is more simple. As of January this year, the allowance for adults was 11.45 euros (8.13) a day. This equates to 80.15 euros (56.82) a week.
This is higher than any adult rate in the UK. However, the French state provides no money for children. So, those with children would be better off in the UK.
People can look for work in the UK if their asylum claims have taken more than a year to process. This can only happen in areas of work where there's a shortage of personnel. They can also work in France after a year waiting and are subject to a labour market test along similar lines to that in the UK.
Housing
"In England I can get a house very quickly. England is a very good place to have a good life."
Fadi, from Syria
In the UK, asylum seekers will be given accommodation , either in a flat, house, hostel or bed and breakfast. "You can't choose where you live," is the government's advice. "It's unlikely you'll get to live in London or south-east England."
In France, asylum seekers awaiting decisions are also entitled to accommodation. But, according to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, the authorities "claim there are not enough places and priority should be given to families with small children".
For those given refugee status and renting properties afterwards, costs can be substantially higher in the UK than France. According to the comparison website Expatistan , accommodation is 25% cheaper in Paris than London.
Average rents for central London were 2,561 per month in the first quarter of this year, according to the estate agent Countrywide. In south-east England they were 1,097, expensive for someone not on a medium-to-high income.
Healthcare and education
"I speak the language and I respect the education system in England. It's a civilised country."
Alaa, from Syria
In the UK, asylum seekers can get free National Health Service healthcare, enabling them to see a doctor or access hospital treatment. They also receive free prescriptions, dental care, eyesight tests and help paying for glasses.
Asylum seekers in France have access to healthcare thanks to the universal healthcare insurance system, as long as their incomes are proved to be low.
Illegal migrants in the UK, including failed asylum seekers liable to removal, illegal entrants and people who have overstayed their visas, will be chargeable for NHS hospital care, with exemptions for some groups, such as victims of violence. Treatment in accident and emergency departments and at GP surgeries remains free for all.
Children aged five to 17 of asylum-seekers in the UK must attend school. This is free, while children may be eligible for free school meals.
Similarly in France, children aged six to 16 are subject to compulsory education .
Illegal work
"Britain says, 'We don't want immigrants,' but does nothing to prevent the black economy."
Philippe Mignonet, Deputy Mayor of Calais
The main aim of those entering the country but not seeking asylum is presumed to be economic - they want to find work.
A 2009 study carried out for London Mayor Boris Johnson estimated that the UK had 618,000 "irregular" residents, with London accounting for about 70% of this. The campaign group Migration Watch says a figure of 1.1 million is "more plausible".
The size of black economies is hard to gauge, making the demand for unregistered, untaxed workers difficult to know. But it's thought those of France and the UK are very similar. In 2013, the management consultancy firm AT Kearney estimated that the black economy was the equivalent of 10% of GDP in both countries.
But the OECD, in 2012, put the UK's "non-observed economy" at 2.3% of GDP . That of France was 6.7%, arguably implying more opportunity for illegal workers there.
Despite this, the OECD estimated in 2011 that the use of illegal immigrants represented 1% of total employment in the UK - higher than the 0.75% in France.
It would be hard for a migrant to make an informed judgement of work prospects in the two countries based on these figures.
Existing communities
"I want to go to England because I have relatives and my father in England."
Abdul, from Pakistan
The European Union states that, among the factors drawing people to specific countries are "historical ties between countries of origin and destination (former colonies for instance), a certain knowledge of the language used in the host country, the presence of established ethnic communities".
The popularity of the UK among asylum-seekers from Pakistan, a member of the Commonwealth, could be explained in this way. The number of people in the UK identifying as Pakistani increased by about 0.4 million between 2001 and 2011, when they accounted for 2% of the population, according to censuses.
The Democratic Republic of Congo, contributing the largest number of asylum seekers in France last year, is a former Belgian colony. As a result, the official language is French.
A 2012 study found that the "likely higher proficiency" in English among migrants made them more likely to choose an English-speaking country. For instance, English is widely understood in Eritrea , one of the main countries producing asylum seekers at the moment.
The economy
What about the situation that awaits those who are eventually granted refugee status?
According to the EU's own figures, the unemployment rate in France in May was 10.3%.
In the UK it was 5.5% for the period from February to April, according to the Office for National Statistics.
The figures are not directly comparable, but it is clear that there is a better likelihood of getting work in the UK once settled. However, recent figures show the French economy growing faster than the UK's.
Likelihood of gaining refugee status
"EU member states have a shared responsibility to welcome asylum seekers in a dignified manner, ensuring they are treated fairly and that their case is examined to uniform standards so that, no matter where an applicant applies, the outcome will be similar."
European Union
Those choosing to claim asylum once they reach the UK have a better chance of this being granted than in France.
Last year, 38.8% of UK decisions ended in a grant of asylum or an alternative form of protection. For France the rate was 21.7%.
But, while the rate of approval differed between France and the UK, the overall number of people allowed to stay was 10,050 in the UK, for France it was 14,905, because France had more than twice as many applicants.
The top five countries of origin for UK asylum seekers in 2014 were Pakistan, Eritrea, Iran, Syria and Albania. For France, they were the Democratic Republic of Congo, Russia, Bangladesh, Albania and Syria.
In 2013, Matthieu Tardis, of France Terre D'Asile,  which provides legal and social services to asylum-seekers and refugees, said the country's government did not consider many of the applications to come from those from "'good' countries, for example countries ravaged by war like Syria or Afghanistan". This, he added, helped to explain the lower rate of approval.
There was a wide variance between acceptance rates for asylum-seekers within the UK. Last year, of Eritrean applicants 87% were granted asylum , but just 20% of Pakistanis.
Detection
"There are no ID cards. They can easily find work outside the formal economy, which is not really controlled."
Natacha Bouchart, Mayor of Calais
It is reported that some illegal migrants want to come to the UK because there is no national system of identity cards and police cannot stop people in the street to ask for their papers. This would make it easier to go about their business, as detection is difficult.
In 2008, the Labour government started to introduce biometric compulsory identity cards for foreign nationals from outside the European Economic Area (EEA). The Conservative-Liberal Democrat coalition of 2010 to 2015 did not scrap this .
UK Immigration Enforcement officers arrested 139 suspected immigration offenders at locations including London, Durham, Manchester, Wales and Somerset in a single day in 2013 following raids.
The 2014 Immigration Act introduced a requirement for private landlords to check whether new tenants have the right to rent in the UK, or face a fine of up to 3,000. A pilot scheme in the West Midlands is due to be extended across England in the autumn.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:08:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>An ugly statue of a beautiful queen</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-trending-33411219#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Egyptians lambast 'tasteless' new Nefertiti statue</Description>
        <MainBody>Egyptians lambast 'ugly' new Nefertiti statue
BBC Trending What's popular and why
7 July 2015
Linkedin
On the right: the famous bust of Nefertiti in the Neues museum in Berlin. On the left: the replica that sparked an outcry in Egypt. Facebook user Wael Saad commented: 'This is how Egyptian art has evolved over the years'
The unveiling of an ugly copy of a famously beautiful bust of Queen Nefertiti caused Egyptians to mock the authorities as well as the current state of art in the country.
Queen Nefertiti ruled Egypt alongside her husband in the 14th century BCE, and her beauty is legendary - her name in fact translates as "a beautiful woman has arrived." Our modern picture of the ancient queen has been largely shaped by a bust unearthed in 1912 which currently sits in a museum in Berlin - its ownership is the subject of frequent debate between Egypt and Germany .
To Egyptians, Nefertiti remains a proud symbol of their country's impressive history and beauty. So when the authorities wanted to commission a statue at the entrance of the city of Samalut, they thought of the ancient queen.
Unfortunately, the replica that resulted bore so little resemblance to the legendary beauty that many began to despair for the state of Egyptian art. In simple terms, it was just plain ugly.
"This is an insult to Nefertiti and to every Egyptian," tweeted one Egyptian woman. Another wrote: "It should be named 'ugly tasteless artless statue'... not Nefertiti."
Many Egyptians feeling offended by the failed attempt to replicate the iconic bust directed their anger at the sculptors: "If you don't know how to make statues don't go and do something so unfair to the beautiful Nefertiti," tweeted one man. "Not only are you distorting the present but also the past... I ask that the original bust not be returned from Germany, at least there she's got her dignity," another wrote .
Thousands of other Egyptians are using the hashtag "Nefertiti" in Arabic, comparing the replica to the original bust, often using sarcastic captions:
Translation: "Nefertiti before and after marriage"
A number of people even compared the statue to Frankenstein's monster:
Translation: Spot the difference
The massive bust has now been removed following the public outcry and will be replaced with a statue of a peace dove, according to local media reports . 
Next story: Lionesses welcomed home with 'patronising' and 'sexist' message
A tweet from an account run by the Football Association was quickly deleted on Monday after immediately running into controversy - although the organisation behind England's national football team says the message was taken out of context. READ MORE
You can follow BBC Trending on Twitter @BBCtrending , and find us on Facebook .  All our stories are at bbc.com/trending .
Latest Tweets
From BBC Trending @BBCtrending
In remembrance of #sevenseven : Individual tributes to all those who died ten years ago from @bbcnews https://t.co/CRfmdt8sjP
1 hour ago
#walktogether http://t.co/OBmRmUWtcl 10 images being shared on the anniversary of the 7/7 attacks http://t.co/Ak5jPx5CnN
1 hour ago
'You look disgusting!' http://t.co/wKZUxQgbHf Why this beauty blogger is shaming her bullies @mypaleskinblog http://t.co/a0lbaCCWax
2 hours ago
Content from Twitter. Learn more about content from Twitter.
Subscribe to our podcast
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:22:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The company bosses who pray</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33405579#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Is there a place for religion in the workplace?</Description>
        <MainBody>Firm faith: The company bosses who pray
By Katie Hope Business reporter, BBC News
6 July 2015
From the section Business
Saying prayers with colleagues would feel a bit uncomfortable, too intimate an activity in the workplace for many people.
Yet at Chinese real estate giant Tiantai Group, known as Tentimes Group in English, that is exactly what they do in the boardroom before making important decisions.
Three-quarters of the firm's eight-strong senior management team are Christians and founder and chairman Wang Ruoxiong, who himself became a Christian seven years ago, says that when the company has to make difficult decisions, it turns to the Bible for guidance.
In fact, he goes as far to say that it's not him but God running the firm.
"He controls everything. I am merely a housekeeper of Jesus, assisting him in taking care of the company," he says.
Wang Ruoxiong believes that Christian values have helped his firm to succeed
'Universal values'
Mr Wang admits that Christian beliefs alone have not driven the firm's success, acknowledging that employees' technical skills such as marketing and sales capability have also played a big part.
But he believes that following Christian values have helped to make the firm more effective.
He says that employees feel cared for, helping them to perform better, and that treating the company's suppliers more fairly has created stronger relationships with them, for example.
He also believes his approach is unique, which he says will help the company to survive despite increasing competition.
"When the senior managers at the top are willing to use the values in their own work and life, the values are passed down. Eventually they become the shared values of the common employees of the entire company.
"At that time, the company becomes truly irreplaceable," he says.
Gavin Oldham says he is careful not to "flash the brand" at work
Nonetheless meeting a company boss who is so open about his religion at work is rare. While organisations themselves must make allowances for their staff to be able to practise their religious faith, providing prayer rooms for example, those at the top normally keep their beliefs private. Typically they're wary of being seen as promoting their own faith to those below them.
Gavin Oldham, executive chairman of retail stockbroker The Share Centre, is an elective lay member of the General Synod - the highest governing body of the Church of England - a fact he states openly on his firm's website biography and his Twitter account.
But while he never hides the fact that he is a Christian, he says he is careful not to "flash the brand" at work.
"It can't be overt. There's such a huge range of backgrounds. It may be that people have no faith. You have to respect others," he tells the BBC.
But he says his faith does guide his business life as well as his personal life - particularly, he says, his belief in God's unconditional love, which he tries to apply in his own life.
He says the belief of "love your neighbour as yourself" provides a structure for when he's making difficult business decisions and ensures a consistency which he believes ultimately has helped him to make better judgements at work.
"It's not even necessary to chart them down as Christian values, they are universal values," he says.
'All you need is love'
It's a view shared by Whole Foods Market co chief executive Walter Robb, who says that while "spirituality" is often a charged word for people, it could just as easily be replaced with "love".
While for many, "love" at work may seem equally inappropriate, Mr Robb believes that a softer approach from those at the top, emphasising that the firm is part of a larger world with wider responsibilities, can be very powerful.
He recalls recently holding his granddaughter for the first time, reminding him of holding his own children when they were young, as an explanation for the feeling.
"That depth of feeling in your heart, your capacity to bring that to your work as a leader, your capacity to develop that capability in the organisation and to celebrate it, to reward it, to acknowledge it, to model it.
"Those sorts of things are part of creating a wider vessel and not a narrower vessel. And to the extent that that's spiritual, then I think that's a good thing."
Chen Feng, chairman of Chinese conglomerate HNA, whose empire spreads from aviation to real estate and financial services, draws on Buddhist teachings to help underpin his company's culture, but emphasises that religion alone isn't enough to create a successful company.
"Incentives and profits must also be given so that people are guided to the right way of life for themselves and the right way of development for the company.
"Buddhism is my thing. People have to solve their problems on their own. We cannot simply use one culture for all. We need to use all good cultures, and integrate them with modern management methods," he says.
This feature is based on interviews by leadership expert Steve Tappin for the BBC's CEO Guru series, produced by Neil Koenig.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:28:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Narendra Modi app is 'like Tinder for good governance'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33240085#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Why the Indian PM's new app includes a videogame</Description>
        <MainBody>Narendra Modi app is 'like Tinder for good governance'
7 July 2015
From the section India
Technology writer Krish Raghav reviews the Narendra Modi mobile app, unveiled by the Indian prime minister in June.
There is a lot of swiping in the new app, also called Narendra Modi (Google Play Store, free).
You swipe up to reveal new instructions. Swipe down to refresh the app's feed. Swipe left to approve of his government's new schemes, and swipe right to find new schemes to approve by swiping left.
It is like Tinder (the international dating app) for good governance, except all you can do is approve, and share your approval.
Often, you're not even sure what you're approving. The first question in the app's "Poll" section just asks: "Which of the following government initiatives do you think has had the most." The most what?
It does not matter.
All that matters is that you approve of the question, and tell your 900 Facebook friends, like I did, that you strongly believe that the Swachh Bharat Abhiyan (Clean India campaign) has "had the most".
The app has a quiet desperation to it, a weakly repetitive insistence that you share, share, share. You cannot even read your daily Modi news without logging in via Facebook, Twitter, Google+ or your Narendra Modi account (presumably the app's target demographic), and the little green "Share" button is the only consistent element in the app's otherwise confused design ethos.
Gaming approval
When I first loaded up the Narendra Modi App, I was expecting this:
A simple Modi-centric aggregator, built to amplify the well-oiled social media machine his campaign pioneered. Grafted to that, a one-stop shop for Modi news and updates, culled from his many productive online channels.  You can listen to old episodes of the PM's weekly radio show, or read all the (positive) media coverage he is receiving. I was expecting all that.
What I was not expecting was a videogame.
"Earn points and win badges" is one of the first things the app tells you about itself. "Badges come with recognition and increased responsibility."
Okay.
"Earn them all and establish yourself as a true changemaker."
This is where things get both clever and insidious. The app "gamifies" your approval of the government's policies - giving you the incremental opiate buzz of points ticking upwards and badges awarded. As a gamer, this opened some kind of ancient competitive gristle in my mind. I had 10 points, the app told me. Get 80, and I'd be awarded the "Pro Active" badge.
Challenge accepted, Mr Modi.
There are two ways to earn "points" - approve of the government's policies (by "Liking" posts) and share them (by posting articles from the app on your own feeds). I got right into it. I answered the aforementioned poll question for five points. I Liked a post about Mr Modi attending a World Yoga Day rally for two points. I shared his lecture at the Dhaka University earlier in June for two points.
Episodes from Mr Modi's life are written with breathless reverence
And that was it. Nothing left to approve. "Stay tuned!" the app said cheerfully. "Contribute by [showing] support towards various policies." I was stuck at 19 points, 61 short of that "Pro Active" badge. Desperate for policies to approve.
I consoled myself by reading some of the app's other content - episodes from Mr Modi's life, written with breathless reverence. I learnt that he was a "Man of Organisation", who had "mastered the Art of Governance".
I pored over Charts and Infographics (literally, because you can't zoom into them) flanking articles about the government policies, written like press releases. The app has a decent reading interface with a thoughtful layout that lets you filter for photos, charts or embedded videos.
With nothing else to do, and no apparent way to earn my badge, I stumbled upon the "Give Feedback" section of the app. I remembered its insistence that I "contribute" in whatever way I could, and I considered writing a thoughtful critique of the videogame component, and how its points economy was fundamentally broken.
But I couldn't be bothered. After all, I couldn't even get my "Pro Active" badge.
So how much would I give this app? Two stars.
Krish Raghav is a comic book artist, policy analyst and podcaster. He tweets @krishraghav
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:00:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>7/7 anniversary: Is the UK safer now?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-33415475#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A decade on from the 7/7 attacks, are Londoners safer?</Description>
        <MainBody>The Syria factor
Islamic State extremists are believed to be encouraging British jihadists to commit attacks on their return
Almost the entire UK government apparatus underestimated both the appeal and the threat now emanating from the Syria-based terror group that calls itself Islamic State (IS).
Latest estimates put the number of foreign fighters flocking to join the group, or live under its control, in excess of 20,000. That is more than the number who went to Afghanistan to train in al-Qaeda camps when the Taliban were in charge for five years.
Official estimates put the number of Britons who have gone to Syria to join IS at 700, with around half that number returning to the UK. Real figures are probably higher.
Not all those who return need to be watched. Some come back disillusioned, some come back traumatised and need counselling.
But counter-terrorism officials believe there are concerted efforts by IS leaders in Syria to persuade Britons to carry out attacks in the UK, in some cases urging followers who have not even travelled to the Middle East.
The sheer numbers getting drawn to IS, for a whole range of reasons, means that the 'Syria factor' places an enormous workload on those trying to head off the next plot.
"Since 7/7 lots of different places have started to emerge as a source of a potential threat," says Aimen Deen, a former member of al-Qaeda who now works for a Middle East-based consultancy.
"Be this in Yemen, be this in North Africa, be this in Somalia or more recently in Syria and Iraq, where we can see that there are different groups and networks that are trying to launch attacks."
Multiplication of ways of attack
So-called "lone wolf" attacks such as that seen in Tunisia are among those most feared by the authorities
Al-Qaeda's primary modus operandi was big, co-ordinated, centrally planned attacks using synchronised suicide bombings. 9/11, 7/7, the Madrid and Bali bombings were all examples of this.
So too would have been the 2006 liquid bomb airline plot, if it had not been intercepted in time. That threat has not gone away.
There are still jihadist planners in Yemen, Syria and Pakistan who would like to execute just such a big, signature attack on a list of Western countries, of which Britain, the US, France and Denmark are at the top.
One of the most serious threats the UK has been rehearsing for, ever since the Mumbai siege of 2008, is a "marauding attack" by heavily-armed gunmen targeting defenceless citizens in a crowded city centre.
Plots are harder to detect right now because they moved from being centralised plots, organised by cells overseas into plots that are basically carried out by lone wolves, who are recruited in isolation and who are not in touch with other cells
Aimen Deen, Former jihadist
Powerful, automatic weapons are much harder to obtain in Britain than they are on the continent but that may not always be the case.
Most of today's would-be jihadist attackers are interested in a much simpler, cruder approach, one with minimal communications that can be intercepted, with as small as possible a circle of people in the know.
MI5 are believed to have between 2,000-3,000 people "on their radar", meaning people who are known to have extremist views or be in contact with extremists, but who have not necessarily committed a criminal offence.
Trying to second guess when someone's extremist views are going to translate into action, like the killers of Lee Rigby in Woolwich, is an ongoing challenge for the police and spooks.
They point out that "being on the radar" is not the same as "being under the microscope" and that to watch all those people all the time would require a network of informants akin to the Stasi in the former East Germany.
"Plots are harder to detect right now because they moved from being centralised plots, organised by cells overseas into plots that are basically carried out by lone wolves, who are recruited in isolation and who are not in touch with other cells," says Aimen Deen.
"Therefore when they decide to take action it is difficult to detect them in advance so it became harder and harder for security agencies."
Encryption
Deciphering encrypted messages can be a laborious process
Back in 2005 international terrorists communicated mainly by email or mobile phone.
Today the choice of methods at their disposal has ballooned, from easily encrypted messages to those hidden in online games. GCHQ has enormous and controversial powers to tap into communications but its operatives have to know what they are looking for.
Often, says one expert, it is not so much a case of looking for a needle in a haystack as looking for a certain type of needle in a haystack made up of needles.
Decrypting terrorist communications, once they are zeroed in on, is labour intensive as they can pass through dozens of stages of encryption using multiple nodes around the world.
Sometimes it can prove a false alert and sometimes the trail can reach a dead end, as plotters switch seamlessly to a different means of communication.
Threat level
Britain is currently at a national terror threat state of "severe", the second highest in a ranking of five.
Officially this means a terrorist attack of some sort is thought "highly likely", ranging from a single jihadist with a machete on the High Street to a 7/7-style attack.
This assessment is based on the intelligence being fed into a unit called JTAC, the Joint Terrorism Analysis Centre, but it is far from complete.
MI5 and the police have stopped a very large number of plots since the 7/7 bombings but they also missed the 21/7 plot two weeks later - it failed because the bombs did not work - and the Woolwich attack of 2013.
Although today Britain has an almost negligible military presence in Iraq and Afghanistan (one of the main reasons given by jihadists for their targeting a decade ago), the threat has still multiplied and morphed.
How long will it last?
"Well it started a generation ago," says former jihadist Aimen Deen. "There is no reason to believe that it won't last another generation or possibly even two".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
