<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:41:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly attack on Tunisia beach</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33287978#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 people are killed in an attack on a beach near two tourist hotels in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse, the interior ministry says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack on Sousse beach 'kills 27'
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
Tunisian TV ran footage from one hotel close to the attack
At least 27 people have been killed, including foreigners, in an attack on a beach near two tourist hotels in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse, according to the interior ministry.
Officials say one gunman has been shot dead and another is being pursued.
Sousse is a popular tourist destination.
Tunisia has been on high alert since March when militants killed 22 people, mainly foreign tourists, in an attack on a museum in the capital Tunis.
The interior ministry told the BBC "a terrorist attack" was ongoing.
Tunisia attacks: Live updates
A British man on holiday told the BBC that he heard the attack on a neighbouring hotel and saw a man with a pistol from his room, but did not know whether this was an attacker or a member of the security forces.
The holidaymaker said he and other guests had been told to take shelter in the hotel's staff quarters and have been told to wait for the all-clear.
One image circulating on social media appeared to show a man lying face down in the sand with what looks like blood around his head.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:11:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man decapitated in French attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33284937#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>One man has been decapitated and several people hurt in a suspected Islamist attack on a factory near the French city of Lyon.</Description>
        <MainBody>France attack: Man decapitated in attack near Lyon
26 June 2015
From the section Europe
The site belongs to Air Products, a US-based firm
A man has been decapitated and several others injured at a factory in France in what President Francois Hollande has called a terrorist attack.
Two men drove into the Air Products gas factory near Lyon, officials said, before several explosions were heard.
One of the suspects, who was investigated by police in 2006, has been arrested.
The dead man was found with Arabic inscriptions on him and an Islamist flag was found near the site.
Live updates: France beheading attack
At a press conference from Brussels, Mr Hollande confirmed that two attackers had targeted the chemicals factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, crashing into it in a car.
"We have no doubt that the attack was to blow up the building. It bears the hallmarks of a terrorist attack," he said.
Referring to the terrorist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January, he said: "We all remember what happened before in our country. There is therefore a lot of emotion."
Mr Hollande said he would leave the EU summit in Brussels this afternoon and return to France.
Speaking from the scene, France's Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said the suspect in custody has been under investigation between 2006 and 2008.
Mr Cazeneuve said the identity of the suspect was yet to be confirmed but that he was thought to be Yacine Sali.
"This person was under investigation for radicalisation but this investigation was not renewed in 2008. He had no police record," Mr Cazeneuve said.
Officials said the suspect in custody has been known to police since 2006
According to France's Dauphine Libere newspaper, a second suspect has been arrested at his home in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier.
He is believed to be the man seen driving back and forth past the factory before the attack occurred at around 10:00 local time (08:00 GMT), the newspaper said.
A spokesman for Air Products said: "We can confirm that an incident occurred at our facility in L'Isle-d'Abeau, France this morning.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for."
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls has ordered that security be stepped up at sensitive sites around Lyon.
Alain Juppe, the mayor of Bordeaux, took to Twitter to condemn the attack.
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," he said, adding that France "must make every effort to protect its citizens".
Are you in Isere? Did you witness the factory attack? Please email your story to haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk .
If you would be happy to speak further to a BBC journalist, please include a contact telephone number.
You can message us on WhatsApp 07525 900971.
Send your pictures and videos to yourpics@bbc.co.uk or text them to 61124 (UK) or +44 7624 800 100 (international). Or you can upload here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:56:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS 'kills 120 civilians' in Kobane</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33285699#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State militants have killed more than 120 civilians since launching a fresh attack on the Syrian border town of Kobane, activists say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria crisis: Islamic State 'kills 120 civilians' in Kobane
26 June 2015
From the section Middle East
Many of the wounded were taken across the border into the Turkish town of Suruc
Islamic State (IS) militants have killed more than 120 civilians since launching a fresh attack on the Syrian border town of Kobane, activists say.
IS "fired at everything that moved" after entering on Thursday, said the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
A separate IS attack on the north-eastern city of Hassakeh has displaced 60,000 people, the UN says.
Kobane became a symbol of Kurdish resistance in January after an IS siege lasting several months was repelled.
IS launched an apparent two-pronged offensive on Thursday after Kurdish fighters from the Popular Protection Units (YPG) cut off one of the militants' major supply routes near Raqqa.
Raqqa is the de facto capital of the IS "caliphate", whose creation IS announced a year ago after it captured large swathes of northern and western Iraq and parts of Syria.
'Women and children'
"According to medical sources and Kobane residents, 120 civilians were executed by IS in their homes or killed by the group's rockets or snipers," said Rami Abdel Rahman, who heads the UK-based Observatory.
He said women and children were among the bodies found inside houses and on the streets of the town, which is close to the border with Turkey.
He described it as one of the biggest massacres by the group in the country since its offensive began last summer.
The militants took the town by surprise when they launched their attack on Thursday, five months after IS was removed by Kurdish fighters backed by US-led coalition strikes.
The attack at dawn on Thursday began when militants detonated a car bomb, followed by two more bombings.
Women and children were said to be among the civilians killed in the latest attack
Reports said some of the militants may have hidden themselves among returning refugees and disguised themselves by wearing Kurdish militia uniforms.
In a nearby village, IS reportedly shot dead at least 20 civilians, including women and children.
Activists say clashes between some IS militants and the Kurdish YPG forces are continuing in the town.
Separately on Friday, the UN said an estimated 50,000 people had been displaced within the city of Hassakeh after another IS offensive there. Another 10,000 have fled northwards towards a town near the Turkish border, it added.
Hassakeh, about 270km (180 miles) east of Kobane, has been under the control of both government forces and Kurdish fighters, and IS militants have been trying to capture it for months.
Overall, in four years of armed conflict in Syria, more than 200,000 people have lost their lives and more than 11 million others have been forced from their homes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:13:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait mosque hit by suicide blast</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33287136#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber targets a Shia mosque in Kuwait City during Friday prayers, killing a number of people, officials and eyewitnesses say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait Shia mosque hit by suicide blast
26 June 2015
From the section Middle East
The mosque was packed at the time of the attack
At least four people have been killed in a suicide bomb attack on a Shia mosque in the Kuwaiti capital.
Many people were injured, and unconfirmed reports put the death toll much higher.
The blast hit during Friday prayers at the Imam Sadiq Mosque in al-Sawaber, a busy area to the east of Kuwait City.
An Islamic State- (IS) affiliated group said it was behind the attack. IS has carried out similar recent attacks in neighbouring Saudi Arabia and Yemen.
An Islamic State-affiliated group said it was behind the bombing
The governor of Kuwait City, Thabet al-Muhanna, told Reuters four people had died in the suicide attack. However, the AFP news agency said at least 13 people were killed. At least eight people were reportedly wounded.
A Kuwaiti MP, who saw the attack, said the mosque was packed with some 2,000 people when there was a loud explosion, Reuters news agency reported.
Footage posted online said to be from the scene of the attack showed men, some in blood-splattered clothing, walking around a smoke-filled room with rubble on the floor.
Al-Jazeera also reported that the Kuwaiti emir was heading to the scene of the blast.
Sunni-ruled Kuwait has a large Shia minority, which IS considers to be heretics.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:20:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU agrees to relocate migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33276443#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders holding late-night talks on the Mediterranean migrant crisis agree to relocate 40,000 of those who have arrived in Greece and Italy.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU leaders agree to relocate 40,000 migrants
26 June 2015
From the section Europe
EU leaders holding late-night talks in Brussels have agreed to relocate tens of thousands of migrants who have arrived in Italy and Greece.
Summit chairman Donald Tusk said 40,000 would be relocated to other EU states over the next two years.
However, there will be no mandatory quotas for each country.
The Greek debt crisis was also on the summit's agenda. Greece and its international creditors remain deadlocked after talks on Thursday.
Earlier, Mr Tusk called on EU member states to share the burden of the boat loads of illegal migrants who have crossed the Mediterranean.
'Modest' plan
New figures from the UN refugee agency UNHCR show that 63,000 migrants have arrived in Greece by sea this year and 62,000 in Italy.
"Leaders agreed that 40,000 persons in need will be relocated from Greece and Italy to other states over the next two years," Mr Tusk told reporters. "Interior ministers will finalise the scheme by the end of July."
Leaders also agreed to resettle another 20,000 refugees who are currently outside the EU. French President Francois Hollande said he expected most of them to be Syrians and Iraqis, AP reported.
Migration into Europe
migrants crossed into Europe so far this year
149% increase from 2014
63,000 migrants reached Greece by sea
62,000 migrants reached Italy by sea
10,000 on Hungary/Serbia border in May
Source: UN/Frontex
Details of where the refugees will go has yet to be decided.
The scheme was made voluntary after some nations in eastern Europe refused to accept set quotas. The UK also opted out of the scheme, using one of its exemptions as agreed in the EU Lisbon treaty .
Hungary, which has seen thousands of migrants cross its border by land, and Bulgaria, one of the EU's poorest countries, have also both been granted exemptions.
This angered Italy's Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, who called the plan "modest".
Italy has sought more help from its EU partners to handle the thousands of migrants arriving by sea, many of whom are fleeing war and poverty in countries such as Syria, Eritrea, Somalia and Nigeria.
More than three million people who fled the Syrian civil war are being housed in neighbouring countries - far more than the EU has taken in.
The migrant crisis has been high on the agenda for the EU summit, which opened on Thursday.
The final day of the summit on Friday is due to focus on security issues, namely the Ukraine crisis and tensions with Russia.
EU summit: Greece and migrants to dominate agenda
The relationship between Alexis Tsipras, Italian PM Matteo Renzi and Germany's Angela Merkel appeared jovial at the EU summit despite the deadlock
Meanwhile, the impasse in the Greek debt talks threatened to overshadow the summit, with two hours of unscheduled talks on Thursday.
Only once agreement on economic reforms is reached between Greece and its creditors - the European Commission, the European Central Bank (ECB) and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) - will the final 7.2bn tranche of bailout funds be released to Greece.
Counting down to the default deadline
Fri 26 June: Final day of EU summit, although Greece is not expected to be high on the agenda
Sat 27 June: Greece meets Eurogroup creditors in Brussels in effort to reach a deal or face default on a 1.6bn (1.1bn) IMF loan
Sun 28 June: Absolute final deadline for a deal, says Austrian Finance Minister Hans Joerg Schelling
Mon 29 June: Day on which any agreed deal must be approved by Greece's parliament. German legislators also have to sign it off before funds can released for Greece to start repaying its IMF loan
Tue 30 June: Greece's current bailout expires and it should have paid back the IMF loan. This may prompt the ECB to reconsider its support for Greek banks
Wed 1 July: Day on which country would be in arrears with the IMF if it misses Tuesday's deadline. If so, it would be hard for the ECB to continue any support it is still giving to Greek banks
EU President Donald Tusk said European leaders are pushing for a weekend deadline for a deal to be reached, tweeting : "Another Eurosummit is not foreseen. Leaders expect the Eurogroup to conclude this process at their meeting on Saturday."
Cash-strapped Greece must make a 1.6bn (1.1bn) IMF debt repayment by Tuesday or face default and a possible exit from the euro.
On Thursday, a meeting of eurozone finance ministers also broke up without progress on the issue.
It was the fourth time in a week that the Eurogroup had met in an attempt to prevent a Greek debt default. They will meet again on Saturday.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel said that meeting would be "decisive" in finding a solution.
IMF head Christine Lagarde said lenders had been presented with a counter-proposal by the Greek parties "at the last hour" on Thursday and needed more time to assess it, Reuters reported.
Also during Thursday's talks, UK Prime Minister David Cameron outlined his plans to renegotiate the terms of Britain's membership of the EU.
Mr Tusk said EU leaders should consider British concerns but "only in a way that is safe for all of Europe".
Greek debt talks - main sticking points
Greece has refused to accept cuts to pension payments or public sector wages
The IMF is pushing for deeper spending cuts, not just more tax rises
A key point of friction is a special benefit paid to some low-income pensioners, which creditors want scrapped
Creditors also want a wider VAT base; Greece says it will not allow extra VAT on medicines or electricity bills, and has also resisted calls for VAT hikes on hotels and restaurants
Athens wants a concrete commitment to debt relief, something its creditors are not offering
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:14:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China 'top suspect' in US cyber hack</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-33281269#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The head of US intelligence says that China is the "leading suspect" in a huge data breach of US government personnel files.</Description>
        <MainBody>US spy chief James Clapper says China lead suspect in cyber hack
26 June 2015
From the section China
James Clapper is the highest ranking US official to publicly implicate China
China is the "leading suspect" in the massive hack of a US government agency holding the personnel records of millions of Americans, US intelligence chief James Clapper has said.
He is the highest-ranking US official to publicly implicate Beijing since news of the data breach emerged.
China always dismissed suggestions that it was behind the hacking.
The statement comes after three days of high-level talks in which China and the US agreed to a "code of conduct".
"China remains the leading suspects," said Mr Clapper at a conference in Washington DC, but "the US government continues to investigate" he added, according to his office.
Background to a "massive" hack in five points
On 5 June the US Office of Personnel Management (OPM) said more than four million employees, retirees, contractors and job applicants may have had their personal data compromised
Some reports have put the number at 14 million or higher - this remains unconfirmed
The OPM first became aware of the breach in April
Members of the Senate Intelligence Committee said the hackers were believed to be in China
It's not the first attempt: In March 2014 hackers breached OPM networks - an intrusion blamed on China - but the attempt was blocked
China military unit 'behind prolific hacking'
At the Washington talks where cyber security was a top priority, US Secretary of State John Kerry said there was a need to work with China to develop a "code of conduct" on state behaviour in cyberspace - Chinese representatives had agreed with these conclusions.
"It's something that we agreed needs to be addressed and hopefully it can be addressed soon," State Department spokesman John Kirby said on Thursday.
China has said any suggestion that it was behind the hacking is "irresponsible and unscientific".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:25:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India monsoon rains cause havoc</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33281474#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Authorities in India's Gujarat state say incessant monsoon rains have caused widespread damage to public and private properties.</Description>
        <MainBody>India floods: Monsoon rains cause havoc in Gujarat
26 June 2015
From the section India
Many people are still stranded in the worst-affected Amreli district
Authorities in India's Gujarat state say incessant monsoon rains have caused widespread damage to public and private properties.
Air force helicopters have been dropping food in affected areas after more than 70 people were reported to have died in flood-related incidents.
More than 10,000 people have been moved to higher ground, including 1,000 who were airlifted to safety.
India regularly witnesses severe floods during the monsoon season.
Heavy rains have triggered house collapses in the worst-affected Saurashtra region with some reports saying these are the worst floods in 90 years.
The coastal district of Amreli is the worst affected, where more than 600 villages have been affected.
Farmers are among the worst hit with crops over a large area damaged, Gujarat Health Minister Nitin Patel told BBC Hindi's Ankur Jain in Ahmedabad.
Rescue and relief work is on, he added.
Indian air force has been carrying on rescue operations in Amreli district
Rains have caused widespread damage to public and private properties
The defence ministry said on Thursday that air force helicopters carried out 23 sorties to drop food packets to those stranded.
There have been reports of lions coming out of their habitat in the Gir forest in Junagadh - the only home to Asiatic lions - which has also been hit by rains.
Meanwhile, flood warnings have been issued in Indian-administered Kashmir state where floods killed about 300 people last year.
The Jhelum river in the state's main city of Srinagar was flowing above the danger mark, reports said.
In the northern state of Uttarakhand, authorities have halted pilgrimage to Kedarnath and other Hindu holy sites due to heavy rains.
India receives 80% of its annual rainfall during the monsoon season, which runs between June and September.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:37:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Militants storm Somalia military base</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33282778#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 30 people are killed as al-Shabab gunmen attack a military base used by African Union peacekeepers in southern Somalia, witnesses say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Somalia attack: Al-Shabab 'kills 30' at AU military base
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
Al-Shabab has said it carried out the attack
At least 30 people have been killed after gunmen attacked an African Union military base in southern Somalia, witnesses say.
A suicide car bomber drove into the main gates of the base in Leego, along the main road connecting the capital, Mogadishu and the city of Baidoa.
The militant Islamist group al-Shabab says its fighters have taken control of the base but this is not confirmed.
Al-Shabab is battling Somalia's government for control of the country.
The base is manned by Burundian soldiers from the African Union Mission in Somalia (Amisom), which has more than 20,000 troops in the country.
Amisom confirmed on its Twitter account that an attack was ongoing, but has not given any details on casualties.
Leego residents have seen militants burning vehicles, carrying off weapons and removing the bodies of their fighters killed in the attack, reports the BBC's Mohamed Moalimu from Mogadishu.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:41:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese shares tumble more than 7%</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281146#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mainland Chinese shares see sharp losses as investors begin to worry about another wave of new listings absorbing liquidity in the market.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese shares tumble more than 7% amid Asian losses
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Mainland Chinese shares plunged on Friday as investors began to show concern about another wave of new listings absorbing liquidity in the market.
The Shanghai Composite closed down 7.4% at 4,192.87 points.
However, shares of Guotai Junan Securities - China's third-largest brokerage - jumped 44% on its debut after raising $4.8bn (3bn).
It was the country's biggest initial public offering since 2010.
In Hong Kong, the Hang Seng index closed down 1.8% at 26,663.87, with investor sentiment hit by the share fall on the mainland.
Sentiment was also hit by a crackdown on margin trading and concerns over whether the government would continue to ease policy in order to boost growth in a slowing economy.
Regulators have been cracking down on illegal margin financing and urging brokerages to tighten rules.
However, Bernard Aw, market strategist at trading firm IG, said the "correction" in the market was healthy in the longer term and was also what the central bank wanted to see.
"It is probably not a bad idea to repeat my view that China's leaders still view a strong capital market as beneficial for the Chinese economy. More importantly, a stable bull market is desired," he said in a note.
Japan data weighs
Shares in Japan ended lower after government data showed a mixed picture of the world's third-largest economy, which seems to be struggling to gain momentum.
Household spending rose 4.8% in May from a year ago to mark the first annual increase in more than a year, a sign that consumers are finally spending again after last year's sales tax rise.
But core consumer prices rose 0.1%, still well below the central bank's target of 2%.
The Nikkei 225 index ended down 0.3% at 20,706.15.
The unemployment rate was unchanged at 3.3% in May from April, in line with expectations.
Marcel Thieliant, Japan economist at Capital Economics, said Friday's data cast doubt on the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) upbeat view on the economy and consumer spending.
"With increasing signs that the economic recovery is faltering, we think the BOJ will have to step up the pace of easing before too long, perhaps as soon as October," he said.
Takeover talk
In Australia, the benchmark S&amp;P/ASX 200 closed down 1.6% at 5,544.60.
Shares of supermarket giant Woolworths rose 3.9% after reports that US private equity firm KKR would bid to take over the struggling retailer.
South Korean shares were bucking the trend, with the Kospi closing up 0.2% to 2,090.26.
The benchmark index ended four straight weeks of losses this week.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:57:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nigeria death sentences for blasphemy</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33283261#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Islamic court sentences nine people to death after finding them guilty of blasphemy in the northern Nigerian city of Kano.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria court in Kano sentences nine people to death for blasphemy
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
An Islamic court has sentenced nine people to death for insulting the Prophet Muhammad in the northern Nigerian city of Kano.
The accused, who were all Muslims, had pleaded guilty, the head of Kano's religious police, Aminu Ibrahim Daurawa, told the BBC.
The trial was speedily done in secret after a section of the court was burnt down by angry protesters last month.
It is not known if they will appeal against the sentence.
The alleged offence was committed last month at a religious gathering in honour of Sheikh Ibrahim Niasse, the Senegalese founder of the Tijaniya sect, which has a large following across West Africa.
The nine, eight man and a woman, were reported to have said that "Niasse was bigger than Prophet Muhammad", triggering unrest.
The venue was burnt to the ground by an angry mob and the nine were arrested,
"There has been consensus among Muslims scholars that insulting the prophet carries a death sentence," Mr Daurawa told the BBC Hausa service.
"We quickly put them on trial to avoid bloodshed because people were very angry and trying to take law into their hands," he added.
Kano has a predominately Muslim population and Islamic courts operate alongside secular courts.
BBC Kano reporter Yusuf Yakasai said people celebrated in some parts of the city when news of the judgement emerged.
Tijaniya at a glance
The Sufi sect of Tijaniya was founded in Algeria in 1784 by Ahmad ibn Muhammad al-Tijani.
It spread all over the world, with large following in north and west Africa. It also has followers in South Africa, Indonesia and other parts of the world.
There are other Sufi sects in Islam but Tijaniya is the largest.
They have three main daily practices: Asking the forgiveness of God; sending prayers to the Prophet Muhammad and affirming the Oneness of Allah.
Senegalese-born Sheikh Ibrahim Niasse was credited with reviving the sect in the 20th Century. People travel from across the continent to visit his shrine.
They have several factions including the Haqiqa (Realist) group, whose leaders were convicted accused of blasphemy in Kano.
Several states in predominantly Muslims northern Nigeria have introduced Sharia law after the country returned to civilian rule in 1999.
This is the first time a death sentence has been handed down for blasphemy in northern Nigeria.
The sentence has been delivered for other offences such as adultery but none has been carried out.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:46:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Indonesia seeks to quieten mosques</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33285910#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Indonesia sets up a team to investigate complaints that places of worship are too noisy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Indonesia seeks to quieten noisy mosques during Ramadan
26 June 2015
Mosques are particularly active now during the holy month of Ramadan
Indonesia has set up a team to investigate complaints that its mosques are too noisy.
Hussein Abdullah, vice president of the country's mosque council, told the BBC the team gathered samples of noise from places of worship in about 10 cities.
They found loudspeaker volumes set too high, the call to prayer broadcast at different times and sermons at hours there shouldn't be any, he said.
There are approximately 800,000 mosques in the country.
They become particularly active during the holy month of Ramadan, which began in mid-June.
Mr Abdullah said part of the problem was that mosques were competing with one another at such loud volumes that "Muslims couldn't focus on what was being broadcast".
He said the authorities would appeal to mosques to ensure they were only heard in their immediate area and not beyond.
"They should agree on the time and duration. Say for the morning there's a prayer for 5 to 7 minutes, then the call to prayer. That's enough. Don't broadcast a prayer loudly from 4 o'clock in the morning," he said.
The new team would complement a previous initiative, which saw around 100 groups of technicians deployed across the country to help fine-tune mosque loudspeakers and give advice on how best to arrange speakers to reduce noise, the AFP news agency reported.
"This is not to limit the freedom to pray. We just want to manage the noise, so the sound that comes out of mosques is more harmonious and soothing and people can pray better," Mr Abdullah said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:32:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baseball welcomes first gay player</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33279560#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Baseball's first openly gay professional, a 23-year-old pitcher, takes the mound in a small league in California.</Description>
        <MainBody>Baseball welcomes first openly gay professional player
26 June 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Conroy has been out since he was 16
Baseball has welcomed its first openly gay professional player, in a minor-league game in California.
Pitcher Sean Conroy, 23, took the mound for the Sonoma Stompers after agreeing to come out publicly in time for the team stadium's gay pride night.
The team is part of the independent Pacific Association of Baseball Clubs.
Several baseball players have disclosed their sexual orientation while in retirement but Conroy is thought to be the first active player to do so.
New Yorker Conroy joined The Stompers from college in May and had already told his team-mates and coaching staff he was gay, said general manager Theo Fightmaster.
"His goal has always been to be the first openly gay baseball player so he was very much in favour of telling the story, of carrying that torch," he said.
Major League Baseball historian John Thorn said he thought Conroy was the first active professional to come out.
Both Glenn Burke (Oakland Athletics and LA Dodgers) and Billy Bean (Detroit Tigers, LA Dodgers and San Diego Padres) did so after they retired.
Conroy, right, gets a handshake from catcher Isaac Wenrich
Conroy told his family he was gay when he was 16 and he said it was important to be honest with his new team-mates, especially when conversation turns to girlfriends.
"Instead of getting the different looks or questions when I didn't join them, I'd rather tell you the truth and let you know who I am and have real conversations instead of the fake ones," he said.
Some Stompers will wear rainbow-themed socks or symbols to mark the occasion, the club has said.
Other gay players in US sports
Football: Robbie Rogers scored his first goal for LA Galaxy this week
Basketball: Jason Collins played 13 seasons in the NBA
American football: Michael Sam was drafted by the St Louis Rams, now plays in Canada
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:32:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TV dumps Trump over Mexico remarks</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33279933#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A Spanish-language US television network cuts ties with businessman Donald Trump because of disparaging remarks he made about Mexicans.</Description>
        <MainBody>Univision dumps Donald Trump over Mexico remarks
25 June 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Donald Trump with Miss Connecticut Erin Brady in 2013
US television network Univision says it is cutting ties with businessman Donald Trump and ending coverage of the Miss USA beauty pageant, which he co-owns.
The network, one of the largest US Spanish-language broadcasters, said it follows the hotel tycoon's disparaging remarks made about Mexicans.
Mr Trump said Mexicans brought drugs and crime to the US, during his announcement last week to seek the Republican presidential nomination.
He is now threatening a lawsuit.
In his speech last week, Mr Trump said of Mexico: "They're bringing drugs, they're bringing crime, they're rapists, and some I assume are good people, but I speak to border guards and they tell us what we are getting."
In announcing the breakup, Univision said that his words were "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" and said it would not air the Miss USA pageant on 12 July. The company also said it would be severing all business ties with the celebrity businessman.
Mr Trump has said his remarks were a criticism of US lawmakers, not the Mexican people or their government. He has also said that if Univision follows through with its decision it would be in breach of a contract that "has no termination rights".
"We intend to pursue all legal rights and remedies available to Mr Trump pursuant to the terms of the licence agreement as well as a defamation case against Univision," lawyer Michael Cohen said.
Mr Trump also accused the Mexican government of pressuring the network into "laying down".
"They want to silence Donald Trump. And Donald Trump can't be silenced," Mr Trump said in reference to himself.
"Of course I have a signed contract: five years, they have to pay me almost $15m [9.5m]," he said in an interview with the Fox News television network.
Univision has not commented on these remarks.
Singer J Balvin has withdrawn from both broadcasts
Cristian de la Fuente, one of the two co-hosts who pulled out of the programme, said: "It's a shame that such an important institution as Miss USA is now in the hands of a clown."
While English-language television network NBC has the primary broadcast rights to the spectacle, Univision was - for the first time - going to simultaneously air the event in Spanish.
Colombian singer J Balvin was set to give a performance that would air on both broadcasts, but has withdrawn from the event.
NBC plans to air the programme despite Univision pulling out.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:26:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Indians mock Bobby Jindal on Twitter</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33272125#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Louisiana Republican Governor Bobby Jindal's US presidential campaign launch becomes the subject of online mockery.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bobby Jindal presidential bid sparks Twitter mockery
25 June 2015
From the section India
Louisiana Governor Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the 2016 Presidential nomination during a rally at the Pontchartrain Center
Louisiana Governor Bobby Jindal's announcement that he is entering the Republican presidential race has become the subject of online mockery.
Mr Jindal launched his campaign with a call for a uniform US identity, saying he disliked Americans being identified by origin, ethnicity or wealth.
The hashtag #BobbyJindalisSoWhite began trending on Twitter after the launch.
The tweets poked fun at Mr Jindal's speech and alleged attempts to distance himself from his Indian heritage.
"We are not Indian-Americans, African-Americans, Irish-Americans, rich Americans, or poor Americans. We are all Americans," he told supporters.
Also a subject of ridicule was the fact that Mr Jindal railed against allowing "people to immigrate to this country so that they can use our freedoms to undermine our freedoms".
He added it was incumbent on migrants entering the United States to be "ready and willing to embrace our values, learn English, and roll up your sleeves and get to work".
The presidential hopeful had begun his speech with the words: "Forty-four years ago, a young couple who had never been on an airplane before left their home on the other side of the world to come to a place called America."
Indians online were not amused by the remarks.
The original hashtag #bobbyjindalissowhite was started by Indian-American comedian Hari Kondabolu , with a series of tweets. Following the success of the tag he said it was the most "satisfying thing" he had ever done.
Others chimed in, like Aasif Mandvi from the Daily Show.
The hashtag was also picked up in India, where it was among the country's top trends for much of the day.
Analysis: Anthony Zurcher, BBC News, Louisiana
Gopinath Gopalam, a healthcare professional from Baton Rouge, travelled to New Orleans to watch Bobby Jindal make his presidential announcement on Wednesday. Although Gopalam hails from India, he says the governor's Indian ancestry is of little importance to him. What matters, he says, is what his success says about the US.
"It's an open economy, open community," he says. "Anybody can come here and have the skill and ability they can rise to the top."
The focus on Mr Jindal's ethnicity in recent media coverage has angered many conservatives. In particular, they point to a Washington Post article that featured a quote from a Louisiana University professor who said "there's not much Indian left in Bobby Jindal".
"For years, liberals have attacked Governor Jindal for not being brown or Indian enough for their liking," Mr Jindal's office said in a statement. "Governor Jindal is proud of his heritage. He believes we need to stop fixating on race and hyphenated Americans."
Mr Jindal, who was born Piyush, told CBS news that he changed his name to Bobby after a character in US sitcom The Brady Bunch.
He also converted to Catholicism from Hinduism while he was at school.
A report in the Washington Post said many Indian-Americans who were among his first supporters are now disillusioned with what they see as efforts by Mr Jindal to distance himself from his roots.
"So what if he's Republican? So what if he's Christian? I don't care about those things, But you can't forget about your heritage. You can't forget about your roots," one of his first donors Suresh C. Gupta was quoted as saying.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:02:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Supreme Court preserves Obamacare</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33269991#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court has handed President Barack Obama a major victory by upholding a key portion of his landmark healthcare law.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obamacare subsidies preserved in US Supreme Court ruling
25 June 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The US Supreme Court has upheld a key portion of President Barack Obama's healthcare law, preserving health insurance for millions of Americans.
In a 6-3 decision, the justices said that tax subsidies that make health insurance affordable for low-income individuals can continue.
The ruling preserves the law known as Obamacare, which Mr Obama considers a major part of his presidential legacy.
Republicans have vowed to continue fighting the law.
"We've got more work to do, but what we're not going to do is unravel what has now been woven into the fabric of America," Mr Obama said.
The case, known as King v Burwell, was the second major challenge the law has faced in the US's highest court.
Unlike in many other western countries, the US does not have a single-payer healthcare system. Private companies, rather than the US government, provide health insurance for US citizens.
The decision sparked celebrations outside the court in Washington
The enactment of the Affordable Care Act (ACA) - one of Mr Obama's most significant and controversial domestic achievements - in 2010 mandated that every American had to purchase private insurance. It provided the subsidies to allow many to do so.
In 2012, the mandate portion of the law was challenged in the court. The justices ruled to preserve it.
In that decision, as in the decision on Thursday, Chief Justice John Roberts surprised observers by siding with his liberal colleagues in support of the law.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," Chief Justice John Roberts wrote in the opinion.
Justice Anthony Kennedy dissented in 2012, but sided with the majority on Thursday.
Had the court made the opposite decision, an estimated 8.7 million people in the US would have been at risk of losing the aid that makes healthcare affordable.
Analysis - Jon Sopel, BBC North America editor
The stakes could not have been higher.
People's health (crucially important) and Obama's legacy (less important, but for him and those around him fairly vital) were at stake.
Well a politically finely balanced Supreme Court has given an emphatic, overwhelming vote in favour of the president by 6-3.
I bet "No-drama Obama" is high-fiving anyone and everyone in the White House - that is how big it is.
Obama defies lame-duck expectations
Demonstrators gathered outside the court as early on Thursday morning.
Reading updates on their mobile phones, the crowd became jubilant when they learned mid-morning that the court had ruled in their favour. Some began dancing, while others chanted "If you're covered and you know it clap your hands."
"This is a big sigh of relief for millions across the country," said Ron Pollack of Families USA, a health-care advocacy organisation. "The ACA is not just the law of the land, it will remain the law of the land".
"Today is a good day for healthcare in America," said activist Benton Strong. "I hope this is the end of the line."
Demonstrators opposing the subsidies did not have a large visible presence.
Demonstrators added tape that read "still covered" to their signs after the decision was announced
Media staff sprinted with the news from the court to colleagues outside
Justice Antonin Scalia wrote in his dissent that the Supreme Court is setting a precedent of favouring some laws over others.
"We should start calling this law Scotuscare" Justice Scalia wrote, referring to the court's acronym. "Today's interpretation is not merely unnatural; it is unheard of."
Congressional Republicans have voted more than 50 times to undo the law.
House Speaker John Boehner said that they will continue their "efforts to repeal the law and replace it with patient-centred solutions that meet the needs of seniors, small business owners, and middle-class families".
Following the enactment of the ACA in 2010, states were given the option of establishing their own healthcare exchanges - online marketplaces for citizens to buy health coverage.
Citizens in states that refused to establish exchanges could shop for coverage on a federal exchange.
Rep Steve Scalise described the ACA as a "dismal failure" and vowed to continue fighting it
In the court, opponents argued that a phrase included in the law, "established by the state," meant the federal government could only provide subsidies to people in states that set up their own exchanges.
However, most Americans receiving subsidies purchase healthcare through the federal exchange, after many states decided not to set up their own marketplaces. Only 13 states and Washington DC have set up their own exchanges.
The Obama administration argued that was a too-narrow reading of the law, which spans nearly 1,000 pages, and the rest of the legislation makes clear subsidies are intended for those who meet income requirements, regardless of which exchange insurance was purchased from.
Obamacare by the numbers
citizens in 37 states depend on federal subsidies to make healthcare affordable
only 13 states and Washington, DC have established their own exchanges
over 10m people have purchased coverage through one of the new exchanges - federal or state
on average, the federal government provides a $272 (173) monthly subsidy
Source: Reuters
The upholding of the law cements President Obama's biggest legislative victory. Limiting the subsidies could have unravelled Mr Obama's signature healthcare reforms.
Republican Congressional leader Steve Scalise said he was disappointed with the ruling and would work to have the law "repealed and replaced," echoing near-universal Republican sentiment.
"It does not change the fact that Obamacare has been a dismal failure for millions of Americans who have lost the good healthcare that they liked, and are paying more for the plans that they have," Mr Scalise said in statement.
Meet the Supremes
the US Supreme Court is one of the oldest constitutional review courts in the world
their decisions can overturn federal or state laws, if the justices find they are unconstitutional
its powers have ended segregation in schools, legalised interracial marriage and once effectively chose a president
there are nine justices nominated by the president and confirmed by the Senate, each with life tenure
it is currently one third female, with one Hispanic justice and one African-American
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:42:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds mourn Charleston dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33258820#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The first of the funerals for victims of the Charleston church shooting are held in the South Carolina city.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds mourn Charleston shooting victims
25 June 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Ethel Lance's grandson Brandon Risher touches his grandmother's casket
The first of the funerals for victims of the Charleston church shooting have been held in the South Carolina city.
The services for Ethel Lee Lance took place after a viewing at a Baptist church in North Charleston.
Ms Lance, 70, worked for the church for 30 years and was a mother of five.
The funeral for Sharonda-Coleman Singleton, 45 took place at another Baptist church. She was a speech therapist, pastor and high school track coach, as well as a mother of three.
Their funerals were the first two of nine, with five more to take place on Friday and Saturday. The families of two of those who died have not yet released details.
The nine worshippers were shot dead at a bible study group at an African-American church last week.
Ethel Lance worked for the church for 30 years
Reverend Jesse Jackson, Mayor of Charleston Joe Riley and South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley and US representative Mark Sanford were in attendance at Lance's funeral.
"She can be a symbol for love," said Lance's grandson Brandon Risher. "Hate is powerful but love is more powerful."
Security was high at the funeral, with police standing guard and checking bags as hundreds of people filed in.
Members of Mother Emanuel church stood and said: "Sister Lance, we are here! Mother Emanuel, we are here!"
Reverend Jesse Jackson and Reverend Al Sharpton were present at Ethel Lance's funeral
Funeral attendees released doves at Lance's funeral
At Singleton's funeral, hundreds of mourners filed past the casket at Mt Moriah Missionary Baptist Church. Police officers surrounded the church and surrounding roads.
On Friday, President Barack Obama will give the eulogy at a service for Rev Clementa Pinckney, 41, who was the pastor at the Emanuel AME church. Vice-President Joe Biden will also attend the service.
Both Mr Obama and Mr Biden were friends of Mr Pinckney, who was also a state senator in South Carolina.
His remains were taken to South Carolina's State House in Columbia on Wednesday, where his coffin will lie in state until Friday's service.
Clementa Pinckney's remains were carried by horse drawn carriage to government buildings
Sharonda Coleman-Singleton and her son Chris
Footage emerged on Tuesday of suspect Dylann Roof being arrested by police officers in Charleston. He appeared to surrender without incident.
Mr Roof has been charged with the murder of those who died at the Emanuel AME church.
The victims
Left to right top: Cynthia Hurd, Clementa Pinckney, Sharonda Coleman-Singleton, Tywanza Sanders. Left to right bottom: Ethel Lance, Depayne Middleton-Doctor, Susie Jackson, Daniel Simmons Sr
Cynthia Hurd, 54
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:59:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brazil senators travel to Venezuela</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33280591#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Brazilian senators are in Venezuela to try to promote dialogue, a week after a rival Brazilian team was allegedly attacked by government supporters.</Description>
        <MainBody>New Brazil delegation travel to Venezuela after 'bus attack'
25 June 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Senator Requiao met Lilian Tintori, the wife of jailed opposition politician Leopoldo Lopez
A group of Brazilian senators has travelled to Venezuela to try to promote dialogue between the country's government and opposition.
More than 40 people have been killed since last year in street protests.
Most of the senators in the delegation are close to Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff and support Venezuela's socialist President Nicolas Maduro.
Last week, a delegation of opposition Brazilian senators said their bus came under attack in Caracas.
The group, which included former presidential candidate Aecio Neves, said it had to flee the country after landing in Caracas because their bus was stoned by government supporters.
The Venezuelan authorities have denied involvement in any violence.
The Brazilian government delegation arrived in Caracas on Thursday and said it would talk to all sides.
"Brazil has a duty to identify and promote conditions for dialogue and the reduction of aggression, which has been a feature in Venezuela's democratic process," said Senator Roberto Requiao, who is leading the mission.
'Against the arrest'
The senators later met Lilian Tintori and Mitzy Capriles, the wives of jailed opposition politicians Leopoldo Lopez and Antonio Ledezma.
They have also met former presidential candidate Henrique Capriles and will hold talk with government officials.
"In Brazil we are in principle against the arrest of anyone taking part in the political process," said Mr Requiao, who is leading the delegation.
But the senators are not planning to visit Mr Lopez or Mr Ledezma, who were arrested last year after being accused of inciting violence during anti-government protests.
The visit comes at a crucial time in Venezuelan politics. Earlier this week, the government announced that parliamentary elections would be held on 6 December.
Delays in setting a date had drawn criticism from the opposition.
The United Socialist Party of Venezuela (PSUV) of President Nicolas Maduro currently holds a majority of seats.
Venezuela is facing a major economic crisis, which the opposition blames on 16 years of mistaken left-wing policies.
The government accuses the opposition of sabotaging the economy and inciting violence to topple President Maduro.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:16:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother and baby survive plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33265943#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A young mother and her baby son have been found alive five days after their plane crashed in the jungle of western Colombia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother and baby survive Colombia jungle plane crash
26 June 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Ms Murillo suffered some injuries and burns but she is recovering well
A young mother and her baby have been found alive five days after their plane crashed in the jungle of western Colombia.
A Colombian Air Force chief described their survival as "a miracle".
Maria Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old son were found by rescuers near to where their small Cessna plane crashed in Choco province.
Ms Murillo had some injuries and burns while her baby appeared to be in good health.
Contact lost
The twin-engine Cessna, which was carrying fish and coconuts, had been flying from the town of Nuqui on the Pacific coast to Quibdo, the capital of Choco.
Stories of miraculous plane crash survivals
Baby Yudier Moreno was held by a rescuer on the flight back to Quibdo
It disappeared from the radar of the civil aviation authorities 20 minutes into the flight. A search plane eventually found the wreckage in the Alto Baudo region.
The reason for the crash is not known. The pilot of the Cessna was found dead in the cockpit.
Glimmer of hope
There was no trace of Ms Murillo or her baby, Yudier Moreno, which the passenger list said had been on board.
But according to Col Hector Carrascal of the Colombian Air Force, rescuers took hope when they noticed that the cabin door was ajar.
Search and rescue aircraft found the wreck of the plane. The cause of the crash is unclear
"It could have opened on impact, but it could have been opened from the inside," he said.
"We didn't have a clue what had happened to them: they could be lost in the jungle trying to survive or they could have died already."
Part of the search party searched the area on foot, while others flew in a helicopter using a loudspeaker to shout Ms Murillo's name and urge her to return to the crash site.
But for two days their search yielded no results.
'Miracle'
Finally, on Wednesday, they located Ms Murillo about 500m from the site of the crash in a ravine on the banks of a river.
Ms Murillo and her baby were taken by helicopter to a hospital in Quibdo
"It's a miracle," Col Carrascal said. Of the baby, who is unharmed, he said: "His mother's spirit must have given him strength to survive."
The pair were airlifted to a hospital in Quibdo. BBC Mundo's Natalio Cosoy has spoken to Ms Murillo's elder brother, Carlos.
Mr Murillo said she had managed to open the cabin door and run into the jungle as fire was spreading in the cabin.
"It was then she remembered she had a baby and went back from him," said Carlos Murillo. She sustained burns to her face, an arm and a leg.
Afraid the plane might explode, she walked into the jungle along the bank of a small river.
She was able to survive by drinking coconut water from the coconuts the plane had been carrying, her brother said. She used big leaves to collect and drink rain water.
Ms Murillo eventually heard the calls over loudspeaker from the rescue helicopter which prompted her to make her way back to the crash site.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:33:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ghana 'ball boy' receives $100,000</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33276668</Link>
        <Description>A role defined as 'ball boy' earned a Ghana staff member $100,000 at the World Cup while a drummer was paid over $5,000.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ghana striker Asamoah Gyan was one of 23 players to receive the same fee as Ghana's "equipment officer"
25 June 2015 Last updated at 18:33
print
Ghana 'ball boy' receives same fee as players at 2014 World Cup
Consider a world in which the England kit man is paid as big an appearance fee as Wayne Rooney, Joe Hart or Raheem Sterling.
Tough to imagine? Not so if you worked for Ghana's Football Association at the 2014 World Cup where their "equipment officer" earned $100,000 (64,000).
In a 396-page report which investigates the Black Stars' first-round exit in Brazil, payment for a role also defined as "ball boy" is highlighted.
Ismail Hamidu was the lucky recipient of a sum equal to that earned by individual players, doctors, coaches and manager James Kwesi Appiah.
The report also found a fee of $5,263 (3,345) was paid to Ghana's official drummer.
His beat was not enough to help the team beat Portugal in their final group fixture to reach the second round, a match which followed the country's FA flying $3m out to South America to settle a pay dispute with players.
Two sentences in the Dzamefe Report that perhaps sum up the frustrations and difficulties of Ghana's World Cup campaign are:
The government's decision to pay $100,000 to each of their 23 players "reduced the tension"
"The players however insisted on being paid in cash and this reignited the tension"
The report aims to unpick myriad financial issues surrounding Ghana's World Cup campaign, including some payments which could not be verified or accounted for.
The African side received $8m (5m) for their group-stage exit, but spent almost $4m more than that on their campaign from the beginning of qualifying.
The Dzamefe Report took four months to compile this year and aims to highlight Ghana's shortcomings at the Brazil World Cup
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:42:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Marikana deaths: SA police blamed</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33278083#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A South African commission recommends a criminal investigation into police accused over the 2012 deaths of 34 striking workers at the Marikana mine.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Africa police accused over Marikana mine deaths
25 June 2015
From the section Africa
A South African commission has recommended a criminal investigation into police over the deaths of 34 miners during a strike in 2012.
President Jacob Zuma said the inquiry concluded the police had a "defective plan" to end the strike at the Marikana mine and were wrong to proceed with it.
Police have always claimed self-defence over the shooting of the workers during a protest over wages.
Mr Zuma called it a "horrendous tragedy that has no place in a democracy".
"We should, as a nation, learn from this painful episode. We should use it to build a more united, peaceful and cohesive society," he said.
Criminally liable?
The killings were the worst violence in South Africa since the end of apartheid 20 years ago, and led to intense scrutiny over the roles of the police, mining companies, unions and the government.
The miners had been striking for a number of days, and 10 other people had already died at the site - including non-striking miners, security guards and two police officers - before the events of 16 August.
Reading out the findings of the inquiry, Mr Zuma said that the police had planned to encircle the strikers with barbed wire in the morning and allow them out after disarming them.
But as the number of strikers grew later in the day, they implemented a "tactical option" which the commission said was "defective in a number of respects".
The miners had been protesting over wages and conditions
The commission concluded the police should have appreciated that the situation was such that "it would have been impossible to disarm and disperse the strikers without significant bloodshed".
Police were accused of allowing the situation to get out of control.
In its conclusions, the commission said a full investigation should be launched to determine whether any officers are criminally liable. It also called for an inquiry into whether police chief Riah Phiyega was fit to hold office.
The report also criticised the delay in getting medical attention to the injured, which it said contributed to the death of at least one of the workers.
It recommended that a panel of experts should be set up to revise policing methods and investigate new tactics for crowd control that do not involve "weapons capable of automatic fire".
Analysis: Milton Nkosi, BBC News, Johannesburg
Judging by what President Zuma said when he released the report, there will be many disappointed people in South Africa tonight.
It seems that the person who will carry the can of the first massacre by the state since the end of apartheid will be police chief Riah Phiyega.
President Zuma said that his deputy Cyril Ramaphosa, who was a shareholder at Lonmin at the time of the killings, has been exonerated.
This will certainly not go down well with opposition parties, who have been a thorn in his side over the controversial security upgrades at the president's home in Nkandla.
Mr Zuma can expect an even noisier national assembly flowing directly from his address to the nation tonight.
Marikana deaths: A case for murder?
Both the mining unions and Lonmin, the mine's owners, were criticised for not doing enough to resolve the original dispute, which was over pay and accommodation.
But the commission did exonerate two government ministers and Cyril Ramaphosa, who was a non-executive director at Lonmin at the time and is now South Africa's deputy president.
It said the accusation that Mr Ramaphosa had put pressure on the police to take action against the strikers was "groundless".
The killings were the worst violence in South Africa since the end of apartheid
Lonmin has called the findings of the commission a "vital step in the healing process".
The commission, headed by retired judge Ian Farlam, has spent nearly three years investigating the shooting and the issues surrounding it.
No-one has been charged or held responsible for the killings. A lawyer, acting for the injured miners, said that they were looking into instituting civil claims.
Some of the lawyers for the dead miners' families have also made accusations of a cover-up, describing the killings as revenge by the police for earlier deaths at the mine.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:47:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thailand halts human rights event</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33286290#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Human Rights Watch cancels an event in Bangkok that was to launch a report into alleged abuses in Vietnam, after Thai authorities intervene.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thailand halts Human Rights Watch event on Vietnam
26 June 2015
From the section Asia
Sunai Phasuk (left), HRW senior researcher in Asia, speaks to police at the event
Thailand's military-run government has forced Human Rights Watch (HRW) to cancel an event in Bangkok to launch a report into alleged abuses in Vietnam.
Thai officials said the event, which was halted minutes before it was due to start, could have affected relations between the two countries.
The HRW report focuses on the treatment of a Christian group in Vietnam.
The group said the Thai response showed how freedom of speech had been eroded since the army seized power last year.
Thai police said the event at the Foreign Correspondents Club of Thailand could "have an impact on the country's security or could affect the friendship and cooperation between Thailand and Vietnam".
It is the third human rights event at the venue that has been halted by authorities in the past month.
The HRW report describes what it says is the persecution of Montagnard Christians in Vietnam's central highlands. Their religious practices have been described by the Vietnamese government as "evil".
Sunai Phasuk, Human Rights Watch's senior researcher in Asia, said the decision to cancel the report's launch was "very disappointing".
"Thailand is now going to be known as the defender of human rights violators in [Southeast Asia], which adds more damage to Thailand's already tarnished international reputation under the military rule," he added.
Thai authorities have launched a crackdown on critics since the military seized power from a civilian government in May 2014.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:40:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan pursues party funding claim</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33280074#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Pakistan says it will pursue more information from the British government over claims a major political party was funded by the Indian government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan asks UK over claims India funded MQM party
25 June 2015
From the section Asia
The MQM has a loyal support base among the Mohajir community
Pakistan says it will pursue more information from the British government over claims that the MQM party was funded by Indian's government.
MQM officials told UK investigators they had received money from the Indian government, the BBC has learned.
A Pakistani official also told the BBC that India has trained hundreds of MQM militants over the past 10 years.
Indian authorities say the claims made to the BBC are "completely baseless". The MQM also denies them.
Party spokesman Saif Muhammad Ali told BBC Urdu that the MQM had never received any funding or training from India. He said authorities in Pakistan were running a campaign against the party.
Chaudhry Nisar Ali Khan, Pakistan's interior minister, said on Thursday he would write to the British government on Friday.
He said they had a duty to "extend as much help as possible" to Pakistan on the investigation.
With 24 members in the National Assembly, the Muttahida Quami Movement (MQM) has long been a dominant force in the politics of Pakistan's largest city, Karachi.
British authorities investigating the MQM for alleged money laundering held formal recorded interviews with senior MQM officials .
They told investigators the party was receiving Indian funding, the BBC was told. UK authorities also found a list of weapons in an MQM property.
A Pakistani official told the BBC that India has trained hundreds of MQM militants in explosives, weapons and sabotage over the past 10 years in camps in north and north-east India.
Before 2005-2006, the training was given to a small number of mid-ranking members of the MQM, the official said.
More recently, greater numbers of more junior party members have been trained, the BBC was told.
The arrest of Altaf Hussain prompted unrest in Karachi
The claims follow the statement of a senior Karachi police officer in April that two arrested MQM militants said they had been trained in India.
Asked about the claims of Indian funding and training of the MQM, the Indian High Commission in London said: "Shortcomings of governance cannot be rationalised by blaming neighbours."
The UK authorities started investigating the MQM in 2010 when a senior party leader, Imran Farooq, was stabbed to death outside his home in north London.
In the course of those inquiries, the police found around 500,000 ($787,350) in the MQM's London offices and in the home of Mr Hussain.
That prompted a second investigation into possible money laundering.
Who is Altaf Hussain?
Born in Karachi in 1953 to a middle-class family; studied pharmacy at university.
Formed MQM party in 1984 to represent Mohajirs - descendants of Urdu-speaking Muslims who migrated from India to Pakistan.
Requested political asylum in UK in 1992, later gained British citizenship; continues to run MQM from north London.
British investigators then found a list itemising weapons, including mortars, grenades and bomb-making equipment in an MQM property, according to Pakistani media reports that the BBC believes to be credible.
The list included prices for the weapons. Asked about the list, the MQM made no response.
The MQM insists it is a peaceful, secular party representing the interests of the middle classes in Pakistan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:50:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece crisis deepens amid deadlock</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33265923#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Greece and its international creditors remain in deadlock over its debt crisis despite a series of top-level meetings.</Description>
        <MainBody>The relationship between Alexis Tsipras, Italian PM Matteo Renzi and Germany's Angela Merkel appeared jovial at the EU summit despite the deadlock
Greece's Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis attended the Eurogroup meeting to put forward Athens' own ideas
After the meeting of finance ministers broke up without agreement, Eurogroup head Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it was not too late for Greece to accept the proposals of its international lenders.
It was the fourth time that the finance ministers had met in a week in an attempt to prevent a Greek debt default. They will meet again on Saturday.
An EU diplomat told the BBC that the Eurogroup had to make a decision then - yes or no.
The Greek government has criticised the international creditors for rejecting its own ideas, which were initially welcomed.
IMF head Christine Lagarde said the lenders had been presented with a counter-proposal by the Greek parties "at the last hour" on Thursday and needed more time to assess it, according to Reuters.
The IMF has been particularly strong in refusing to accept Greece's proposals put forward earlier this week.
Correspondents say the Greek plan included far more tax rises and far fewer spending cuts than creditors had suggested.
Why the IMF is worried - by Andrew Walker, BBC economics correspondent
Throughout the Greek crisis, the IMF has been concerned that the programme should add up. That means that specific actions should be able to achieve whatever targets are agreed for the Greek government's borrowing needs.
In the current impasse, one concern is that the Greek proposals include too much emphasis on tax rather than spending.
The IMF worry is that might aggravate the economy's weakness. For the long term the IMF's concern is that Greece should ultimately have a sustainable debt burden and has been telling the eurozone that it should be thinking about debt relief.
Like the other players in this crisis, the IMF has politics to contend with: IMF member countries (Brazil has been a notable example) who have in the past been unhappy about the organisation's financial support for Greece.
Greece's PM Tsipras held talks on Thursday morning with IMF leader Christine Lagarde and European Central Bank head Mario Draghi as well as Jean-Claude Juncker, the president of the European Commission, and Eurogroup leader Mr Dijsselbloem.
Technical experts met several hours earlier to continue deliberations. However, no deal was struck.
If an agreement is reached, it will have to be endorsed by Greece's parliament, with some critics at home accusing the prime minister of reneging on his party's campaign pledge to end austerity.
Greek debt talks - main sticking points
Greece has refused to accept cuts to pension payments or public sector wages
The IMF is pushing for deeper spending cuts, not just more tax rises
A key point of friction is a special benefit paid to some low-income pensioners, which creditors want scrapped
Creditors also want a wider VAT base; Greece says it will not allow extra VAT on medicines or electricity bills, and has also resisted calls for VAT hikes on hotels and restaurants
Athens wants a concrete commitment to debt relief, something its creditors are not offering
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:21:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France cracks down on Uber service</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33267581#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>France's interior minister orders the closure of the low-cost car-sharing service UberPOP after a day of protests by taxi drivers.</Description>
        <MainBody>France cracks down on Uber service after protests
26 June 2015
From the section Europe
France's interior minister has ordered a ban on the low-cost car-sharing service UberPOP after a day of nationwide protests by taxi drivers.
Bernard Cazeneuve said the service was "illegal" and ordered police and prosecutors to enforce its closure.
His announcement followed a day of sometimes violent protests by French taxi drivers, who say the US-based firm Uber is stealing their livelihoods.
US rock singer Courtney Love Cobain was caught up in the unrest.
She tweeted her frustration, saying her taxi had been ambushed as she left the airport.
The musician shared an image of the window of her car spattered with egg, and thanking two motorcyclists she said rescued her.
Windows smashed
Uber officials have insisted they will continue their activities until France's highest court rules on the service - an attitude Mr Cazeneuve called "cynical and arrogant".
Key highways around Paris were blocked and tyres were burned during the day-long strike. Barriers also appeared around Marseille and Aix-en-Provence in southeast France.
Some cars were overturned and others had their windows smashed with bats.
Riot police responded to protests in Paris after French taxi drivers overturned cars and set fire to tyres in protest against taxi app Uber
Aeroports de Paris, the operator of the French capital's Charles de Gaulle (CDG) and Orly airports, warned passengers to travel by train, saying "access by road is completely blocked".
Some travellers walked along the side of the motorway to reach the airport.
Taxi drivers also blocked access to Marseille and Aix train stations and protested on the main access to Marseilles-Provence airport.
France's taxi drivers - who have to pay thousands of euros for a licence - say they are being unfairly undercut by UberPOP.
"Many taxis drivers are infuriated," Abdelkader Morghad, a representative of the FTI taxi union, told Bloomberg.
He said a law that forbids unlicensed drivers to carry paying passengers should be implemented.
France's licensed drivers have lost between 30% and 40% of their income over two years because of the growth of UberPOP, Mr Morghad said.
UberPOP is a car-sharing service offered by Uber, which brings together customers and private drivers at prices lower than those charged by both traditional taxi firms and even other Uber services.
UberPOP differs because it allows non-professional drivers to register their car and transport other passengers.
It has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and the service continues to operate, AFP news agency reports.
Mr Cazeneuve said on Thursday that he had ordered police in Paris to issue a decree banning UberPOP and said any cars defying the order would be seized.
Uber spokesman Thomas Meister said the firm had contested the law under which UberPOP has been ruled illegal, and accused the interior minister of overriding the normal legal process.
"The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is legal or illegal," he was quoted by Reuters news agency as saying.
The nationwide protests saw violence in Marseille as well as Paris
San Francisco-based Uber says it has a million users in France, including 250,000 for UberPOP. Uber also operates a luxury service which is not banned.
Uber has faced similar teething problems in cities all over the world, with traditional taxi drivers protesting against being undercut by the unlicensed company.
But licensed taxi drivers have been criticised for being slow to adopt the app-based geolocation technology behind Uber's success.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:29:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama warned over Iran concessions</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33269405#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former advisers to US President Barack Obama express concern at the emerging deal between world powers and Iran over its nuclear programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks: Obama warned over concessions
25 June 2015
From the section Middle East
John Kerry and Mohammad Javad Zarif are due to join the negotiations in Vienna on Friday
Former senior advisers to US President Barack Obama have expressed concern at the emerging deal between world powers and Iran over its nuclear programme.
In an open letter , the security and foreign policy experts say it "falls short of meeting the administration's own standard of a 'good' agreement".
They call for fewer concessions on international nuclear inspections and on research and development activities.
The publication of the letter comes as the deadline for a final accord nears.
US Secretary of State John Kerry and his Iranian counterpart Mohammad Javad Zarif are to fly to the Austrian capital Vienna on Friday to join the negotiations, which may need to continue beyond 30 June.
The so-called P5+1 - the US, UK, France, China and Russia plus Germany - wants to limit Iran's sensitive nuclear activities to ensure that it could not build a nuclear weapon quickly.
Iran, which wants sanctions lifted in exchange, insists its nuclear work is peaceful.
'Tracks with US position'
The open letter published by the Washington Institute for Near East Policy on Thursday is signed by a bipartisan group of US diplomats, legislators, policymakers and experts who have met regularly over the past three years to discuss Iran.
They include:
Dennis Ross, who advised President Obama on Iran
Former CIA director David Petraeus
Robert Einhorn, a former member of the US negotiating team with Iran
James Cartwright, a former vice-chairman of the US military's Joint Chiefs of Staff
Gary Samore, a former Obama adviser on nuclear policy
Stephen Hadley, who was a national security adviser to President George W Bush
Iran insists its nuclear work is solely for peaceful purposes
"Most of us would have preferred a stronger agreement," the letter says.
"The agreement will not prevent Iran from having a nuclear weapons capability. It will not require the dismantling of Iran's nuclear infrastructure," it adds.
"It will however reduce that infrastructure for the next 10 to 15 years. And it will impose a transparency, inspection, and consequences regime with the goal of deterring and dissuading Iran from actually building a nuclear weapon."
The letter calls on Mr Obama to insist that Iran provide information about nuclear weapons research Western powers suspect it has carried out, and allow inspectors from the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) access to military sites.
The president is also urged to establish strict limits on the research and development of centrifuges used to enrich uranium to preclude the "rapid technical upgrade and expansion" of Iran's enrichment capacity at the end of any deal. Enriched uranium can be used to make fuel for both nuclear energy and weapons.
A senior Obama administration official said it had received the letter and that it "in large part tacks with the US negotiating position inside the negotiating room".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 15:53:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Diplomat convoy hit by Somalia bomb</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33257724#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The United Arab Emirates' ambassador to Somalia narrowly escapes an al-Shabab suicide attack that kills 12 people in Mogadishu, reports say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Somalia attack: Al-Shabab targets diplomat in Mogadishu
24 June 2015
From the section Africa
The UAE ambassador survived as he was in a bulletproof vehicle
A military vehicle escorting a United Arab Emirates' diplomatic convoy was hit by a car bomb in Somalia's capital, killing at least 12 people, police say.
The UAE ambassador survived the suicide attack as he was riding in a bullet-proof land cruiser vehicle, the BBC's Mohamed Moalimu reports from Mogadishu.
The militant Islamist group al-Shabab says it carried out the attack, to target "a foreign enemy".
Al-Shabab is battling Somalia's government for control of the country.
On Sunday morning, a suicide car bomber and gunmen attacked a training centre for the national intelligence agency .
The militants have vowed to intensify attacks during the Muslim fasting month of Ramadan, which began on Wednesday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:53:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PM 'delighted' after EU reform talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-33281019#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>David Cameron says he is delighted the process of "reform and renegotiation" of the UK's EU membership is under way, following a summit in Brussels.</Description>
        <MainBody>David Cameron 'delighted' EU renegotiation under way
26 June 2015
From the section UK Politics
David Cameron says he is delighted the process of "reform and renegotiation" of the UK's membership of the EU is "properly under way".
The PM was speaking in the early hours after formally setting out his aims to EU counterparts in Brussels.
He addressed EU leaders for 10 minutes at a summit dominated by the migrant crisis and Greek debt , although his exact speech was not reported.
The European Council's Donald Tusk said there was a will to help the UK.
Follow the latest developments on our live page
However Mr Tusk, who is overseeing the membership negotiations, added that basic values, such as freedom of movement to live and work within the EU, "were not for sale".
Detailed discussions would now begin in earnest, he added, with EU leaders next considering the matter in December.
'Safe for all'
Mr Cameron, who wants to reform the UK's membership of the EU before holding an in/out referendum of the British public by the end of 2017, tweeted that "significant progress" had been made in Brussels.
The prime minister, who is under pressure from his Conservative backbenchers to deliver a far-reaching and lasting deal, has not set out in full detail what he wants but his key demands include:
An opt-out on the core EU aim of "ever closer union"
The sovereignty of national parliaments to be boosted, so groups of them can block proposed EU legislation
Safeguard the City of London and other financial centres outside the eurozone
Curb EU immigration by cutting benefits
Make the EU more streamlined and competitive
To get what it wants the UK believes it will need to rewrite treaties agreed by all 28 EU members.
Downing Street has said the prime minister remains committed to "proper, full-on treaty change" but it has acknowledged this is unlikely by the end of 2017 since it would trigger referendums in other EU countries as well.
The government is understood to be seeking "legally-binding" guarantees by the time of the referendum that EU treaties would be changed at some point in the future.
Analysis
By Ben Wright, BBC political correspondent
It was during the night's long, acrimonious discussion about Europe's migrant crisis that David Cameron was given time to set out his case. The prime minister's remarks to fellow EU leaders were brief and will not have been a surprise.
He had spoken to each of them in the weeks leading up to this summit - explaining why Britain will have an in/out referendum by the end of 2017 and sketching out his aims.
He has also made it clear Britain could leave the EU if he doesn't get a meaningful deal. For Britain, for Europe, this summit has marked a significant moment - and the start of official renegotiation talks between London and Brussels.
The prime minister of Malta said David Cameron "had worked the crowd well" over recent weeks. Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi was broadly supportive too, but said EU leaders had some different ideas to those proposed by Mr Cameron.
There remains a big question mark over exactly what the prime minister will be asking for.
Aspirations such as new powers for national parliaments, a British exemption from "ever closer union" and efforts to curb EU migration to Britain through welfare changes will be controversial.
What does David Cameron want?
The BBC's Europe editor Katya Adler said EU leaders accepted treaty change would be needed further down the line to reflect closer integration within the eurozone.
"The idea is to use that to get in the British changes as well but that cannot happen before 2017," she said.
Estonian prime minister Taavi Roivas told the BBC that treaty change could not be ruled out but a process which required a referendum in every country could pose some "difficulties".
"First of all we have to agree what we want to achieve and then we will talk the legal aspects, whether it is treaty change or secondary legislation," he told Radio 4's Today.
While the principle of freedom of movement could not be circumscribed in any way, he said EU leaders should be willing to listen to all the UK's ideas, including on benefit restrictions.
"I wouldn't draw any red lines just yet. My country men are coming to Britain only to work and to study and are not travelling for benefits so if Britain has this serious concern, we should be open for this discussion."
'Sensible'
UKIP leader Nigel Farage said the prime minister was "accepting the inevitable" that there would be no treaty change.
He said there would be "nothing really fundamental in Britain's renegotiation of its membership".
Former Conservative Home Office minister Damian Green, a pro-European MP, said it was "perfectly sensible for the prime minister to leave his options open" to get the results he wanted.
But Labour's shadow foreign secretary Hilary Benn said Mr Cameron was "signalling retreat while pretending that all he ever wanted was a post-dated cheque".
Mr Benn said Mr Cameron had "made a mess" and "should have known what the position of other countries would be".
Tory MP Steve Baker, co-founder of Conservatives for Britain, said he and colleagues were "more concerned" about the "substance" of any new relationship between the UK and the EU "rather than the mechanism" which will deliver it.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:22:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Network Rail 'too big', says Branson</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281468#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Network Rail is too big and should be broken up into regional units, Sir Richard Branson tells the BBC.</Description>
        <MainBody>Network Rail 'too big', says Sir Richard Branson
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Network Rail is too big and should be broken up into regional units, Sir Richard Branson has told the BBC.
Many of the delays that passengers on Virgin Rail suffer are down to Network Rail, he said.
"Network Rail is far too big a company," he said. "I think that companies that kind of size should be broken up into small units."
Network Rail said decisions on its future would be taken by the government.
Investment delays
Sir Richard added that "ideally" the train operators should manage the track they use.
"We get enormously frustrated that people say will say that Virgin Rail has delays, but 90% of those delays are down to Network Rail," he told the BBC.
"If we were running the track underneath, because we've got our trains running on that track we'd make absolutely certain that track was fixed and running well, because we value our reputation."
When asked if a break-up of Network Rail was likely, he said: "I don't know; I've thrown that idea out before. Maybe right now it's an option that might be considered."
A spokesman for Network Rail described Sir Richard's figures as "incorrect", adding: "Over the last year (to 30 May), infrastructure faults were responsible for around a third (36%) of delays to Virgin Trains services."
On Thursday, the government said it would delay or cut back a number of modernisation projects planned for Network Rail.
Transport Secretary Patrick McLoughlin said rising costs and missed targets made an existing 38.5bn investment plan untenable,
Mr McLoughlin said Network Rail should have foreseen the improvements would cost more and take longer.
Network Rail said the plan, which was launched last year as the "largest modernisation of the railways since Victorian times", was too ambitious.
Under the changes, the government said electrification work on the Midland main line and on the Trans-Pennine route between Leeds and Manchester would be "paused".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:14:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hong Kong rejects Jetstar local bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281154#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hong Kong authorities reject an application by Qantas-backed Australian budget carrier Jetstar to set up local operations on the island.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hong Kong rejects Jetstar bid to start local airline
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Hong Kong has refused an application by Jetstar to set up local operations there
Hong Kong authorities have rejected an application by Qantas-backed Australian budget carrier Jetstar to set up a local airline, after nearly two years of deliberation.
The regulator said the bid did not comply with the laws of having its principal place of business in the Chinese territory.
The city's other carriers had also objected, it said.
Qantas said it would reconsider basing the low-cost carrier in Hong Kong.
The carrier is a three-way joint venture between Qantas Airways, China Eastern Airlines and Hong Kong investment firm Shun Tak Holdings.
"Jetstar Hong Kong cannot make its decisions independently from that of the two foreign shareholders," said the Air Transport Licensing Authority when handing down its decision.
It also said the city's other carriers, including Cathay Pacific and Dragon Airlines, had objected to Jetstar's application.
'Disappointing' decision
Qantas chief executive Alan Joyce said the decision was disappointing for shareholders as well as "for the travellers that Jetstar Hong Kong planned to serve".
"It's the travelling public who have lost out, because the message from this decision is that Hong Kong appears closed to fresh aviation investment even when it is majority locally-owned and controlled," he said in a statement on Friday.
He added that Hong Kong was going in the opposite direction of other aviation markets in Asia that were "opening up".
"Given the importance of aviation to global commerce, shutting the door to new competition can only serve the vested interests already installed in that market."
The airline, along with its partners, said it had not yet decided on whether to appeal the decision.
The joint venture was valued at $10m Australian dollars ($7.7m; 4.9m), according to Qantas.
Shares of Qantas were down 1.4% in Sydney in reaction to the news.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:39:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesco's sales decline in UK slows</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281464#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tesco reports a slower rate of decline in sales at its UK stores as it tries to stem the flow of customers switching to discount chains.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tesco's sales decline in UK slows
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Tesco has reported a slower rate of decline in sales at its UK stores as it tries to stem the flow of customers switching to discount chains.
UK sales fell 1.3% for the three months to the end of May, compared with a 4% decline a year earlier.
The result beat analysts' forecasts of a fall of 1.6%-3%, and was better than the 1.7% fall reported in the fourth quarter of the last financial year.
Tesco chief Dave Lewis said it was a "step in the right direction".
"We are fixing the fundamentals of shopping to win back customers and relying less on short-term couponing," he said.
Shares in Tesco were up 3.4% in morning trade.
Including its international businesses, sales across the Tesco group dropped 1.3% in the quarter compared with a 3.4% dip a year ago.
Mr Lewis, who took the helm in September, is trying to revive the fortunes of Britain's largest supermarket after it reported the worst loss in its history in April.
Tesco reported a full-year pre-tax loss of 6.4bn, one of the largest in UK corporate history. About  4.7bn of the losses were the result of the fall in property value of its UK stores, 43 of which it said would close.
Analysis: Kamal Ahmed, BBC business editor
To understand why Tesco is slowly turning the corner, it is worth looking at the rather mundane world of the humble ham sandwich.
Tesco now offers 30% fewer sandwich lines after it realised that the wide range it was selling meant that customers often could not buy their favourite, simple sandwich, like, say, one with ham in it.
So, it reduced the range and increased the supply of the top sellers. Customers were happier that they could buy what they wanted and the number of transactions increased.
Read Kamal's blog in full
The trading update from Tesco comes ahead of an annual meeting of shareholders later.
Tim Bush of pension advisers Pirc told the BBC's Today programme that investors are likely to question payoffs for Tesco's former chief executive and finance director Philip Clarke and Laurie McIlwee, who shared 2.2m in severance pay after the supermarket said it was "contractually committed" to make the payments.
The pair, who left the firm last year, were awarded 1,217,000 and 970,880 respectively.
The payments were initially suspended while Tesco investigated last year's 263m accounting scandal.
"Things have stopped getting worse but they haven't yet started getting better," said Mr Bush.
Tesco said data from researcher Kantar Worldpanel had also shown that 180,000 more customers shopped at the supermarket in the 12 weeks to 24 May.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:07:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woolworths shares up on bid rumours</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281314#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Shares in Australia's biggest supermarket chain Woolworths rise as much as 5% on rumours it could be facing a takeover bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woolworths shares up 5% on takeover rumours
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Woolworths is Australia's largest supermarket chain but faces stiff competition from discount rivals
Shares in Australia's biggest supermarket chain Woolworths have risen as much as 5% in Sydney on media reports of a possible takeover.
The Australian newspaper reported fresh rumours that US private equity giant KKR had a bid that could be "almost ready" for consideration.
It would be one of the biggest deal in Australia's corporate history, the newspaper said.
The news comes amid turbulent times for the supermarket chain.
Woolworths' media team made no comment in relation to the takeover rumours, while KKR's media team in Australia was unavailable for comment.
Woolworths is Australia's largest supermarket chain but faces stiff competition from discount rivals
Turbulent times
Earlier this month, Woolworths announced that its chief executive, Grant O'Brien, was stepping down after nearly four years.
The firm also said it had plans to cut about 1,200 jobs. The changes are aimed at cutting millions of dollars in costs and improving sales after Woolworths' first-half profits fell.
The retail giant has been up against rivals such as Coles and Aldi and it has been trying to win more customers with improved stores and competitive pricing.
Woolworths recently cut its profit guidance for the year to June 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:15:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fifa chief Blatter 'did not resign'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33284185</Link>
        <Description>Sepp Blatter says he has not resigned from his post as president of football's world governing body, says a Swiss newspaper.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sepp Blatter: Fifa president says he did not resign
Sepp Blatter says he has not resigned as Fifa president.
The 79-year-old Swiss was thought to have ended his 17-year reign on 2 June amid claims of corruption in world football's governing body.
But, according to Swiss newspaper Blick, Blatter told a party at a Fifa museum: "I did not resign. I put myself and my office in the hands of the Fifa congress."
Blatter is thought to be considering standing for re-election as president.
Two criminal investigations into alleged Fifa corruption began in the week that Blatter was elected for a fifth term in charge.
Four days after being voted president, Blatter - who is reportedly under investigation in the United States - said: "While I have a mandate from the membership of Fifa, I do not feel that I have a mandate from the entire world of football.
Blatter resigns as Fifa president
"Therefore, I have decided to lay down my mandate at an extraordinary elective congress. I will continue to exercise my functions as Fifa president until that election."
However Blatter did not use the words 'resign' or 'resignation'.
Meanwhile, Blatter may not attend the final of the Women's World Cup in Canada because of the twin investigations into Fifa by American and Swiss authorities.
He would normally present the trophy to the winning team, but Fifa will not confirm whether Blatter or secretary general Jerome Valcke will attend.
A Fifa spokesperson said: "In terms of the Fifa president and the Fifa secretary general, their future travel plans will be confirmed in due course."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:54:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murray faces Kukushkin in round one</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/33284508</Link>
        <Description>Britain's Andy Murray faces world number 58 Mikhail Kukushkin of Kazakhstan in the first round of Wimbledon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Andy Murray's Wimbledon begins against Mikhail Kukushkin
Wimbledon 2015
Venue: All England Club Dates: 29 June to 12 July
Coverage: Live on BBC TV, HD, Radio and Red Button with up to 15 live match streams on Connected TVs, desktop, tablets, mobiles and sport app.
Britain's Andy Murray will begin his Wimbledon campaign against world number 58 Mikhail Kukushkin of Kazakhstan.
The 2013 champion is in the opposite half to top seed Novak Djokovic, who takes on German Philipp Kohlschreiber - ranked 33rd in the world.
Third seed Murray, 28, could face Rafael Nadal in the quarter-finals and Roger Federer in the semi-finals should he progress that far.
British women's number one Heather Watson plays 32nd seed Caroline Garcia.
Watson's compatriot Laura Robson, who returned from injury last week, will begin her first Grand Slam since the 2014 Australian Open against Russia's world number 101 Evgeniya Rodina .
Men's draw highlights
Djokovic (1) (Ser) v Kohlschreiber (Ger)
Wawrinka (4) (Sui) v Sousa (Por)
Bolelli (Ita) v Nishikori (5) (Jpn)
Bellucci (Brz) v Nadal (10) (Spa)
Kukushkin (Kaz) v Murray (3) (GB)
Dzumhur (Bih) v Federer (2) (Sui)
Players' selfies: Murray in a chopper
Top seed Serena Williams starts against Russia's Margarita Gasparyan.
British number two Johanna Konta, who reached t he quarter-finals at Eastbourne this week, will face fourth seed and 2004 Wimbledon champion Maria Sharapova.
Reigning champion Djokovic, 28, will open on Centre Court on Monday against Kohlschreiber, who reached the quarter-finals in 2012.
Wimbledon 2015: An alternative look at the All England Club
The Serb, who has played no competitive grass-court tennis before Wimbledon, is in the same half of the draw as Swiss fourth seed Stan Wawrinka, who beat him in the final of the French Open earlier this month.
Scot Murray, whose first-round match will be on Tuesday, has won his two previous meetings against Kukushkin, both of which were on Australian hard courts in 2012.
The world number three looked in impressive form when he beat Kevin Anderson on Sunday to secure a fourth Queen's Club title.
With Nadal only seeded 10th, Murray could face the two-time winner as early as the quarter-finals, should both men reach that point.
Nadal could face eighth seed and fellow Spaniard David Ferrer, who starts against Britain's 110th-ranked wildcard James Ward, in the fourth round.
Women's draw highlights
S Williams (1) (US) v Gasparyan (Rus)
Sharapova (4) (Rus) v Konta (GB)
Wozniacki (5) (Den) v Zheng (Chn)
Cepelova v Halep (3) (Rom)
Bertens (Ned) v Kvitova (2) (Cze)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:35:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bhamara creates history in NBA draft</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/basketball/33287175</Link>
        <Description>Teenager Satam Singh Bhamara makes history as the first Indian-born player to be selected in the NBA draft.</Description>
        <MainBody>India's Satam Singh Bhamara creates NBA draft history
Satnam Singh Bhamara has made history as the first India-born selection in the NBA draft.
The 19-year-old 7ft 2in centre, who comes from a small Punjab village, was the 52nd overall pick to the Dallas Mavericks.
The draft gives NBA teams the chance to sign up the best college and young international talent.
Fellow teenager Karl-Anthony Towns was chosen by the Minnesota Timberwolves with the first pick.
Towns, 19, averaged 10.3 points, 6.7 rebounds and 2.3 blocked shots a game last season for the University of Kentucky.
But New York Knicks fans were unhappy with their team's selection Kristaps Porzingis, booing the announcement of the Latvian's acquisition as fourth choice.
"These people don't know me, might think I'm soft, European, a bust," said the 19-year-old, who is aiming to become the third Latvian to play in the NBA. "I'm different. It's my passion that sets me apart."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:29:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Harry Potter play to open next year</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33283158#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>JK Rowling announces the play Harry Potter and the Cursed Child will open in London's West End next year.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Potter and the Cursed Child to open in 2016
26 June 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
JK Rowling is the author of the seven Potter novels and three companion books
JK Rowling has announced her Harry Potter stage play will open in London's West End next year.
Called Harry Potter and the Cursed Child, it will tell the "untold part" of the boy wizard's story, including the story of the lives of his murdered parents.
However, the author said on Twitter the play was "not a prequel".
It will run at the Palace Theatre in the summer of 2016, with tickets on sale this autumn.
Rowling said she chose to make the announcement on Friday because it was "a very special day" - the 18th anniversary of when her debut book, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, was first published in the UK.
But she was tight-lipped about the plot of the play, saying she did not "want to say too much more, because I don't want to spoil what I know will be a real treat for fans".
She added: "To answer one inevitable (and reasonable!) question - why isn't Cursed Child a new novel? I am confident that when audiences see the play they will agree that it was the only proper medium for the story."
The play was first announced in December 2013, after the author said she had "received countless approaches" over the years "about turning Harry Potter into a theatrical production".
Although the new story has not been written by Rowling, it is a collaboration between herself and writer Jack Thorne - who previously adapted Let The Right One In for the stage and won a Bafta for his work on Channel 4's This is England '88 - and John Tiffany, who will also direct the play.
It will be produced by Sonia Friedman and Colin Callender, and British singer Imogen Heap will provide the music.
Analysis - Tim Masters, entertainment correspondent
The plot details might still be hazy, but there's little doubt Harry Potter and the Cursed Child will have a magical effect at the West End box office.
It will be at the 1,400-seat Palace Theatre, which was home to theatrical blockbuster Les Miserables for a record 19 years.
JK Rowling's success needs no introduction, but the new Harry Potter play reunites the creative dream team behind the stage adaptation of supernatural love story Let The Right One In.
When it comes to West End hits, producer Sonia Friedman has a golden touch.  Her biggest successes include Book of Mormon and Sunny Afternoon, while her musical Bend It Like Beckham kicked off to rave reviews this week.
When it opens in summer 2016 the play is likely to spark the kind of Potter-mania that surrounded the release of the books and films.
And it won't end there. The stage show will be closely followed by the Potter film spin-off Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them in November 2016.
Eddie Redmayne will star in a movie adaptation of Rowling's Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them
"Jack, John and Sonia Friedman are a dream team," Rowling said.
"It has been a huge pleasure to share with them (and soon, with you!) this untold part of Harry's story."
Producers originally said the play would explore "the previously untold story of Harry's early years as an orphan and outcast".
"Featuring some of our favourite characters from the Harry Potter books, this new work will offer a unique insight into the heart and mind of the now legendary young wizard," they said.
The Daily Mail's Baz Bamigboye claimed The Cursed Child would "delve into what happened to Harry's parents before they were killed by Lord Voldemort, forcing an infant Harry to be raised in miserable circumstances by his mother's sister, Petunia, her horrid husband Vernon and their spoiled son Dudley".
Rowling's seven Harry Potter best-sellers were adapted into eight blockbuster films starring Daniel Radcliffe as the boy wizard.
The author is making her screenwriting debut on Potter spin-off film Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them, starring Eddie Redmayne, due in cinemas next November.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:42:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Street artist wanted by police</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33286110#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An arrest warrant is issued for street artist Shepard Fairey, best known for his "Hope" image of Barack Obama.</Description>
        <MainBody>Arrest warrant issued for street artist Shepard Fairey
26 June 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Fairey faces a prison sentence for malicious damage
Street artist Shepard Fairey is wanted by police in Detroit after they say he tagged buildings across the city.
An arrest warrant has been issued for the designer, best known for creating the "Hope" image of President Obama during his 2008 election campaign.
Just because he is a well-known artist does not take away the fact that he is also a vandal
Detroit police sergeant Rebecca McKay
He was commissioned to paint a huge, 18-storey mural in Detroit last month but police say he used his down time to plaster buildings with posters.
The warrant accuses him of two counts of malicious destruction of property.
Each is punishable by a prison sentence and a $10,000 (6,347) fine.
"When you're in Detroit, we welcome your work, Shepard Fairey, your commissioned work, not your Wild West work," Detroit police sergeant Rebecca McKay said.
"Just because he is a well-known artist does not take away the fact that he is also a vandal," she added.
However, Fairey laughed off the charges, calling them "hilarious".
The artist, who has been arrested 17 times in his 20-year career, told the Independent he did not know what the warrant would amount to.
"Sometimes it's a day or two in jail. Normally the charges get downgraded. Most of the arrests aren't for serious stuff," he said.
The Detroit mural took five days to complete
Fairey's commissioned work was the largest mural of his career - a 184ft by 60ft stencil on the side of an office block, which took  more than 300 cans of spray paint to complete.
It featured many of his recurring motifs - lotus leaves, a peace sign, the scales of justice and a stylised image of the late wrestler and Princess Bride star Andre The Giant.
But Fairey had told local newspaper The Detroit Free Press he intended to tag buildings during his visit.
"I still do stuff on the street without permission. I'll be doing stuff on the street when I'm in Detroit," Fairey said.
Fairey's portrait of Barack Obama became a symbol of the 2008 presidential election
The artist's murals can be seen in Philadelphia, New York and Paris (pictured)
Police say that between 16 and 22 May, Fairey pasted nine posters, including some with the face of Andre the Giant on buildings around the city, causing damage totalling $9,105.54 (5,779.20).
Detroit is trying to shed its reputation as a haven for illegal street artists. Last summer, Mayor Mike Duggan formed a quality-of-life task force targeting graffiti and building code violations. The team has since apprehended about a dozen people suspected of vandalism.
"Whether it's appealing to the eye or not, it is a crime," Ms McKay said. "He is well aware of the law, and instead of respecting the city of Detroit he took us two steps back."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:18:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Avengers star Patrick Macnee dies</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33279566#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Actor Patrick Macnee, star of The Avengers TV series, dies in California at the age of 93.</Description>
        <MainBody>Avengers star Patrick Macnee dies
26 June 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Actor Patrick Macnee, star of The Avengers TV series, has died in California at the age of 93.
The Briton, best known for playing John Steed in the 1960s television spy show, died at home with his family at his bedside, his son Rupert said.
Macnee, who served in the Royal Navy during World War Two, also played roles in theatre, appearing on Broadway.
Avengers co-star Dame Diana Rigg paid tribute, saying: "Patrick was a very dear man and I owe him a great deal".
A statement on Mcnee's website read : "Wherever he went, he left behind a trove of memories."
He died peacefully at his home in California's Rancho Mirage on Thursday, Rupert said.
Patrick Macnee reprised his John Steed role for The New Avengers TV series, starring alongside Joanna Lumley and Gareth Hunt
James Bond ally
Born in London, Macnee grew up in Berkshire and was educated at Summerfields Preparatory School and Eton.
At the age of 11, he acted in Henry V opposite a young Sir Christopher Lee. He first appeared in the West End while still in his teens.
He played a number of minor roles - including one in Laurence Olivier's 1948 film version of Hamlet - before rising to fame in the original Avengers series between 1961 and 1969.
The series developed a cult following around the world, with Macnee portraying the quintessentially English and mysterious super-spy John Steed.
Steed was known for his dress sense, always donning a bowler hat and carrying an umbrella, which was used as a secret weapon. He never used a gun.
Macnee, centre, pictured with Lumley and Hunt in 1995
His co-stars during the initial run included Honor Blackman, Diana Rigg and Linda Thorson.
Macnee returned when that series was reprised as The New Avengers in the 1970s, appearing alongside Joanna Lumley's Purdey and Gareth Hunt's Mike Gambit.
Later, he starred on Broadway in Anthony Shaffer's Sleuth, touring internationally with that play and several other productions.
He also appeared in the 1985 James Bond film A View to a Kill, playing an ally of Roger Moore's Bond character, and made a cameo appearance as the head of a record company in This is Spinal Tap.
Sir Roger tweeted: "So very sad to hear Pat Macnee has left us.
"We were mates from 1950s and I have so many happy memories of working with him. A true gent."
Thorson, who played assistant Tara King, remembered Macnee as "a paradox".
"He was the best-dressed man on television and a nudist in real life," she told BBC Radio 4's Today programme.
"He was always upbeat. He had great stories and great detail and wonderful energy," she continued. "Patrick [had] a very happy and long life and the most wonderful children who took the greatest of care of him, in the last decade in particular."
Macnee also featured as a guest star in dozens of British, American and Australian TV productions; and made a cameo in Oasis's video for Don't Look Back In Anger.
He scored a top 10 hit of his own in 1990, with Kinky Boots - a novelty song recorded with Avengers co-star Honor Blackman - which was championed by Radio 1's then-breakfast DJ Simon Mayo.
'Ahead of their time'
In a 2014 interview with The Lady magazine, Macnee said he believed The Avengers was a success because it "did something different and did it better."
He told the magazine : "It was beautifully written, the ideas were very good, way ahead of their time and they incorporated fantasies for people who dreamed of doing exciting things."
Macnee and wife Katherine Woodville, who also appeared in The Avengers
Macnee with fellow actor Richard Burton in 1973
Macnee had two children, son Rupert and daughter Jennifer, and one grandson.
He was married three times, including to actress Katherine Woodville, with whom he acted in The Avengers.
He had been a US citizen since 1959, according to the AP news agency.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:05:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Bridge across Ukraine's front line</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33255770#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tom Burridge visits the bridge in Luhansk that connects rebel-held territory with the rest of the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Ukraine crisis: The bridge out of rebel territory
26 June 2015 Last updated at 00:05 BST
The Ukrainian authorities are increasing restrictions in and out of rebel-held territory in eastern Ukraine.
In recent weeks, goods and people have been stuck on either side of the conflict's front line.
And with the war appearing to have reached a stalemate, some politicians in Ukraine are calling for rebel territory to be completely shut off from the rest of the country.
Tom Burridge went to meet people in the rebel-controlled part of the Luhansk region in eastern Ukraine, who risk their lives to cross.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:49:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: 1,000 dead in Pakistan heatwave</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33281167#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Local media reports in Pakistan say that the death toll from the country's heatwave has passed 1,000.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Death toll in Sindh over 1,000 after Pakistan heatwave
26 June 2015 Last updated at 01:49 BST
The death toll Pakistan's heatwave has passed 1,000, local media say.
Officials have been criticised for not doing enough to tackle the crisis.
Catharina Moh reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:41:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: White Horse Village: 'Divided families'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-33280405#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>For a decade, our China Editor Carrie Gracie has followed the fortunes of one rural community being transformed into a city.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
How much pressure can a migrant marriage take?'
26 June 2015 Last updated at 04:41 BST
Urbanisation is one of the most important stories of modern China.
For a decade, our China Editor Carrie Gracie has followed the fortunes of one rural community being transformed into a city.
The last report in her series explains how the marriage of a migrant worker has been affected.
Read more about Xiao Zhang and how she was liberated by the transformation of White Horse Village.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:46:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Sir David tells Obama how to save planet</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33280621#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The distinguished broadcaster and naturalist, Sir David Attenborough, has been on a visit to the White House at the personal invitation of President Obama.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Barack Obama interviews Sir David Attenborough at the White House
25 June 2015 Last updated at 22:46 BST
The distinguished broadcaster and naturalist, Sir David Attenborough, has been on a visit to the White House at the personal invitation of US President Obama.
The president, who is said to be a great admirer of Sir David's work, wanted to discuss the future of the natural world.
David Sillito reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:00:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Greek voices from the underground</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33280401#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC spent an evening in Thessaloniki, tracking down three diverse voice of Greece's youth and asked them about their hopes and expectations for the talks in Brussels.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Greek debt crisis: Voices from the underground
26 June 2015 Last updated at 05:00 BST
While a lot of attention this week has been paid to Greece's pensioners and super rich, it is also an anxious time for young people.
Unemployment among the under 25s is around 50%, almost double the EU average.
The BBC spent an evening in Thessaloniki, tracking down three diverse voices of Greece's youth and asking them about their hopes and expectations for the talks in Brussels.
Video Journalist: Howard Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:08:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Queen visits Brandenburg Gate</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33285229#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Queen Elizabeth II visits Berlin's Brandenburg Gate during her state visit to Germany.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Queen visits Berlin's Brandenburg Gate on Germany trip
26 June 2015 Last updated at 11:08 BST
Queen Elizabeth II has visited Berlin's Brandenburg Gate during her state visit to Germany.
Crowds had been waiting for hours to catch a glimpse of the British monarch, as Jenny Hill reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:08:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Ethiopia opens space observatory</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33281235#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Ethiopia has begun operating the first space observatory in East Africa in an effort to promote astronomy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Ethiopia opens first space observatory in East Africa
26 June 2015 Last updated at 07:08 BST
Ethiopia has begun operating the first space observatory in East Africa in an effort to promote astronomy.
Two telescopes have recently been unveiled on the outskirts of the capital Addis Ababa.
EmmanuelIgunza reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:09:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Formula E's electrifying final races</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-33281931#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The final round of the first world championship for electric racing cars is due to take place in London.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Formula E: Electric racing car season finishes in London
26 June 2015 Last updated at 12:09 BST
The final round of the first world championship for electric racing cars takes place in London on Saturday and Sunday.
The final two races of the inaugural Formula E series will take place around Battersea Park, on the banks of the Thames.
The series is aimed at boosting the image of electric cars and promoting their improving technology.
Theo Leggett reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:51:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lebanon pivotal to Iran's reach across Middle East</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33281739#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Lebanon pivotal to Iran's reach across Middle East</Description>
        <MainBody>Lebanon pivotal to Iran's reach across Middle East
By Kevin Connolly BBC Middle East correspondent, Beirut
26 June 2015
From the section Middle East
The Baalbek festival takes place against a backdrop of turmoil and war just across the border
On the road to Baalbek, in the hot afternoons of Ramadan, the Bekaa Valley shimmers in the midsummer sun.
The soaring columns of the ruined temples of Baalbek are one of the glories of the ancient world - but there are few tourists around these days to admire them.
Lebanon's own civil war petered out 15 years ago, leaving tensions smouldering below the surface of daily life. Syria's is raging uncontrollably just a few kilometres up the road.
The town is cradled by snow-capped mountains and surrounded by emerald fields under sapphire skies - but the bewitching quality of the landscape isn't enough to attract visitors in the numbers that Baalbek's economy needs.
Tourists are understandably risk-averse, and the proximity to Syria is enough to deter all but the bravest.
So, not for the first time, Baalbek is hoping that its cultural festival will bring the visitors flooding back. It has worked before.
In the dreary years after the Second World War, the Baalbek festival - held against the spectacular backdrop of the ruined temples - was a sign that better and brighter days lay ahead.
Now, after it was suspended in recent years because of the fighting in Syria, the festival is to open again this summer.
Pragmatic course
It is a fact of political life in this part of the Bekaa Valley that a decision of this magnitude requires the consent of Hezbollah - the powerful Lebanese militia founded and funded by Iran.
Its local dominance indeed may also be a factor in keeping visitors away.
Hezbollah, of course, is heavily committed to the fighting in Syria where it is the most disciplined and effective element in the coalition struggling to keep Bashar al-Assad in power.
But even as it is engaged in a vicious civil war with strong sectarian overtones on the Syrian side of the border, it has demonstrated in Lebanon a pragmatic ability to coexist with rival communities in the context of a demographic patchwork which is rather similar to Syria's.
No-one should be under illusions about the nature of that coexistence, of course - most Lebanese assume, for example, that Hezbollah was behind the car bomb that killed the powerful Sunni politician Rafik Hariri in February 2005.
But optimists believe it shows that Hezbollah's sponsor Iran is prepared - to some extent at least - to be flexible and pragmatic about the way it exercises influence in the Middle East.
Hassan Hamad from the Baalbek Municipality told me: "The moderate social policy that Hezbollah follows here helps to keep Lebanon safe from terrorism and from the Syrian war.
"They recognise that Lebanon is Lebanon - it isn't Iran and it isn't Europe."
New 'Cold War'
Now, this all matters because an old order is disintegrating in the Middle East - the order imposed by France and Great Britain on the ruins of the Turkish Empire which collapsed here at the end of the First World War.
The US-led Western Alliance is still a player in the battle for influence now raging but the real struggle is between Shia Islam under Iranian leadership  and a grouping of Sunni powers led by Saudi Arabia.
Shia Iran and regional Sunni powers view each other with deep suspicion
In Yemen, Iraq and Syria, their proxies fight each other - you could draw a modern comparison with the Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union or perhaps more accurately with the division of Europe in Catholic and Protestant camps in the 16th and 17th Centuries.
To some extent, Iran's modern leaders are reviving an ancient Persian appetite for influence in the Arab world. In Beirut, political commentator Charmine Narwani told me that West does not work hard enough to understand the changing Middle East from Iran's point of view.
She says there is resentment in Tehran that the country is always portrayed as a destabilising force with dangerous nuclear ambitions, and points out that Iran is in the frontline of a battle with Sunni extremism which is hostile to the West as well as to Shia Islam.
"Iran is probably Ground Zero - a centre for the fightback against Islamic State and al-Qaeda and Sunni extremists in the region," she said.
"The only boots on the ground fighting this fight in earnest are backed, funded and supported by Iran."
That analysis may underplay the role that the Kurds are playing in fighting Islamic State in Iraq but it does help to explain why everyone in the Middle East is talking about Iran.
State-with-a-state
The US-led Western powers are currently seeking a political deal with Iran in which the lifting of crippling economic sanctions could be traded for some sort of verifiable cap on Iranian nuclear ambitions.
But even as those long negotiations approach what will probably prove to be a protracted end-game, the underlying attitude towards Iran remains one of suspicion.
That is partly, of course, because Iran is a revisionist power which feels it has the right to export revolution.
But it is partly because of the way in which Hezbollah - so pragmatic in Lebanon - has emerged as the cutting edge of Iranian power on a wider stage.
In that role, it has been blamed by the West for bomb attacks against Jewish and Israeli targets as far afield as Bulgaria and Argentina.
Hezbollah, which began as a force against Israel, has grown into a major social, political and military movement
And within Lebanon, Hezbollah may offer a glimpse of how Iran sees the future of the Middle East.
What was created as a vehicle to fight Israeli forces of occupation in Lebanon in the 1980s has grown into a powerful state-within-a-state.
Equipped and funded by Iran, it comfortably outguns the Lebanese Army and has perhaps 25,000 fighters under arms.
The movement has social and political responsibilities, too, in its own areas like southern Lebanon but Iran does not seem to aspire to a Hezbollah takeover of the whole country - partly, at least, because it does not need to.
Nothing can happen in Lebanon unless Hezbollah agrees to it and for now it enjoys many of the advantages of being a state - like possession of a powerful army - without the problems that would come from responsibility for Sunni, Christian or Druze regions.
Strategic vision
It is possible that Iran may hope to create other similar non-state Shia entities elsewhere in the Middle East, especially if old multi-confessional nation-states like Syria and Iraq turn out to have reached the limit of their viability.
It does help to explain why Hezbollah is so important to Iran.
I have heard it argued that Iran's involvement is not really about using Hezbollah to maintain President Assad in power - it is more about keeping Mr Assad in office to maintain the land-bridge through which it supplies Hezbollah in southern Lebanon.
Iran is heavily involved in supporting Syria's regime in the war, seeing Damascus as a critical gateway to Lebanon
At a turbulent time in the Middle East, when it feels like influence is up for grabs, Iran has a strategic vision and it brings to it a sense of purpose and energy which other regional players appear to struggle to match.
So when Baalbek holds its festival this summer, it may feel as it has felt before, like a sign of better days to come in the Middle East.
But make no mistake - this is a time of profound upheaval based on deep rivalries between regional powers like Iran and the Gulf monarchies.
And the changes that will flow from that upheaval are far from over.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:19:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tennis's reluctant transgender pioneer</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33062241#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The 1970s transgender pioneer who fought to play and won</Description>
        <MainBody>By Sara Lentati BBC World Service
26 June 2015
From the section Magazine
Renee Richards made history when she walked out on to the centre court of the Forest Hills stadium to play in the 1977 US Open. She was the first transgender woman to play in a professional tennis tournament.
"I had a very good and full life as Dick but I had this other side of me that kept emerging and that kept pushing back, until finally it just wasn't possible to submerge Renee any more and Renee won out," Richards says.
Born Richard Raskind, tennis was a huge part of her life from an early age. She was captain of the men's tennis team at Yale University and later, while serving in the Navy as a medic, won the All Navy Tennis Championship.
She forged a career as a successful eye surgeon, and at a time when the major tennis tournaments were only open to amateurs - professionals were only allowed to compete from 1968 - she took part in the US Open several times as a man.
"I was just another young doctor, married and with a child, practising medicine and having a great life," Richards says.
Renee Richards at her home in New York  Reuters
Find out more
Renee Richards spoke to Sporting Witness on the BBC World Service
But she says it always felt like there were two personalities competing inside her.
As a child, she used to dress up in her sister's clothes. "It gave me some relief and I felt good doing that... Recently Bruce Jenner [Caitlyn Jenner], who's a very famous athlete, is beginning a transition and talked about the same thing. I gave myself the name Renee, which actually means 'reborn' - I didn't even know that."
Richards had gender reassignment in 1975 at the age of 40 and moved to California to start a new life. But when she started competing in tennis tournaments her 6ft 2in (1.88m) frame and trademark left-hand serve began to attract attention - and after she won the La Jolla Tennis Tournament in July 1976 a journalist reported that she had previously competed as a man.
"My world kind of blew up on me when people found out who I was," she says.
Richard Raskind playing tennis in 1972  AP
Her critics said it was unfair for her to play in women's competitions because she would have an unfair advantage in terms of strength.
But it's more complex than that, says Richards. "Of course the men are stronger and they do hit the ball harder but there are other variables too. Serena Williams sometimes gets her serve up greater than 120mph and some of the men don't serve as hard as 120mph."
Controversy raged over whether Richards should be allowed to play. The US Open was just a few weeks away, but for the first time in its 95-year history a chromosome test was made a prerequisite for female entrants.
"I never had any intention of playing in the US Open... but when they said, 'You're not allowed to play,' that changed everything. I said, 'You can't tell me what I can or cannot do - I'm a woman and if I want to play in the US Open as a woman I'm going to do it,'" she says.
Richards was invited by a friend to compete in the South Orange Open in New Jersey, which took place just before the US Open, but more than 20 women players boycotted the event in protest. She reached the semi-final. Then she set about suing the United States Tennis Association for gender discrimination - and found the odds firmly stacked against her.
"The Tennis Association and the people on the other side had top New York lawyers. They brought in witness after witness that said I shouldn't be able to play and it was a big case. Then on my side, my lawyer Mike Rosen, he only had one witness for me," says Richards.
Billie Jean King won 39 Grand Slam titles and founded the Women's Tennis Association in 1973  Getty Images
But that witness proved crucial - she was one of the greatest players in the history of the women's game, a former world number one who was still playing on the circuit.
"My lawyer handed over an affidavit from Billie Jean King that said she had met me, that I was a woman, that I was entitled to play, and that I couldn't be denied. And that was it. We won.
"It was very dramatic, and we all went out and got drunk after we got the verdict," says Richards.
The court victory prompted her to turn professional, but she then faced a struggle to get other players to accept her.
"I had death threats, I had people that hated me, I had people that told me I was immoral, and people told me I was awful. There were some players who would walk off the court when I played them or they wouldn't play me at all.
"There was a lot of objection in the beginning and then finally they realised I was OK and I wasn't going to take everybody's money away and gradually a lot of those that had been against me ended up being very good friends of mine.
Renee Richards playing in July 1977  Getty Images
"I was 43 years old and embarking on a professional career playing against Chrissie Evert, Tracy Austin, and Andrea Jaeger, and they're all 19 and 20 years old. So I had a pretty good disadvantage in terms of age but I said, 'I'm going to do it for a little while and see how I like it,'" says Richards.
In the first round of the women's singles at the 1977 US Open Richards faced that year's Wimbledon champion, Virginia Wade.
"I was on centre court in the stadium at Forest Hills and Virginia Wade had been used to that situation her whole life and I hadn't been. No matter how much good tennis I had played as an amateur there's nothing that compares to playing as a pro in the US Open on centre court.
"I remember she beat me pretty easily in the first set, 6-1. We had a very close second set as I got going and she finally won it 6-4, and that was it.
It was in the women's doubles at the same 1977 Grand Slam that Richards would achieve her best result.
"In the doubles nobody gave my partner Betty Ann Stuart and I much of a chance because nobody had ever heard of us. We won the first round and the second and then all of a sudden we're in the finals of the US Open doubles. We played Martina Navratilova and Betty Stove and we lost to them 7-6 in the second set.
"We stood up there on the podium at Forest Hills on that beautiful Indian summer day, and the band was playing, and they were presenting the prizes. I turned to my partner Betty Ann after we received the silver bowl for being the runners up and I said under my breath, 'Next year we'll be back here for the gold bowl.'"
Renee Richards and Betty Ann Stuart playing in the 1977 women's double final at the US Open  AP
As it happened, Stuart did not return, and although Richards returned with another partner the following year they were knocked out in the second round.
Richards continued to play in the US and Latin America until retiring in 1981. Despite being banned from tournaments in Europe she briefly reached 20th position in the Women's Tennis Association world rankings.
"I never beat any of the first five women in the world. I didn't beat Martina, I didn't beat Chrissie Evert, but I did have wins over some of the players in the second five. So I was up there but I wasn't at the very top," she says.
After retiring Richards remained in tennis and coached Martina Navratilova to victory in all of the four Grand Slam tournaments. Afterwards she resumed her career as an eye surgeon and now, aged 80, she is planning on retiring later this year.
She is the only player in history to play top-level tennis in both the men's and women's competitions. Initially, Richards says she was overwhelmed by the thousands of people who would try to catch a glimpse of her at tournaments.
"I was not set out for that. I mean I wouldn't say I was reclusive, because I wasn't - I was captain of every team I was on - but I was a quiet person and I lived a private life and now all of a sudden everybody in the world knows who I am.
"I became a public figure, a reluctant pioneer, for all of the disenfranchised groups in the world, no matter whether they were transgender, gay or lesbian."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:20:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why bankers believe Greece will do a deal with its creditors</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33283005#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Why bankers think Greece and the EU will eventually agree</Description>
        <MainBody>From the section Business
comments
It is going to be 24 hours from hell for Greek bankers (and of course for the Greek people).
Senior bank executives tell me they have more than enough cash in their branches to meet whatever demand for withdrawals there may be today - and in fact they believe that the rate of withdrawals by worried customers will remain at a lower level than at the beginning of the week.
"We're OK" says one.
And what about next week? "There is going to be a deal [between the Greek government and its creditors]. That is certain".
His certainty is not based on the increasingly sceptical and wary tone of statements and comments from ministers and officials in Brussels, crucible of the negotiations.
It stems from financial logic. If there were to be no deal, the consequences for the Greek banking system would be cataclysmic - and the knock-on to the Greek economy would be dire.
Bankers have been warned by the Bank of Greece, the Greek central bank, that no deal means the probable end of emergency liquidity assistance, or the loans they receive both to finance withdrawals by worried investors and to fund vital short-term loans to the Greek government.
if you woke up tomorrow to be told that there was no way of getting money out of your bank, you will understand why this is not a prospect any rational minister or banker would wish to contemplate
So it also means, they've been told (as if they needed telling), that the Greek government would have to impose capital controls - or severe limits on cash withdrawals - were the liquidity tap to be turned off.
However there would be several days of bank holidays, or branch and ATM closures, before customers were permitted to withdraw any money under the circumstances of capital controls - because legislation would need to pass through the parliament to impose such controls.
If you conduct a thought experiment about what it would mean if you woke up tomorrow to be told that there was no way of getting money out of your bank, you will understand why this is not a prospect any rational minister or banker would wish to contemplate.
Apart from the short-term blow to confidence and economic activity, the current drought of lending by banks would turn into a nuclear winter.
Greek businessmen tell me it is hard enough - and ludicrously expensive - for them to finance investment and exports right now. In the circumstances of capital controls, many Greek companies would collapse, because the banks would no longer have the capacity to provide any credit at all - pending the recapitalisation, or resurrection, of the banking system.
The point is that Greek banks not only have a liquidity problem, a chronic problem borrowing and taking in deposits. Their solvency would also be in question - because something like a third of all their loans are classed as "non-performing" (borrowers are struggling to keep up the payments) and because around a half of their capital resources are tax-refund claims (so-called deferred tax assets) on a government seen to be close to defaulting on its obligations.
So in the unlikely event that you have missed the point, today's talks in Brussels are not just about whether Greece can make its 1.5bn-euro payment to the IMF next week. It is about whether the Greek banking system can be maintained as a going concern.
But don't however conclude please that the Greek government has everything to lose and its creditors - eurozone governments, the ECB and the IMF - will be immune from harm if it all goes spectacularly wrong.
The damage to the eurozone, and indeed to the wider European Union, would be potentially devastating.
Here are just a few illustrations.
The hard and painful reality of the Greek banking system in turmoil would lead, inevitably, to capital shifting from banks in economies perceived to be weaker - Portugal, Spain and Italy, inter alia - to the stronger north, especially Germany.
This would increase the cost and decrease the availability of finance in those weaker economies, and stymie their nascent recoveries. It would also widen the damaging economic inequality between the eurozone's flourishing north and its struggling south.
The only beneficiary, arguably, of Greek anomie would be a Russia under President Putin looking for new allies
Second, there would probably be colossal losses for the European Central Bank and therefore for eurozone taxpayers.
Having provided, directly and via the Bank of Greece, something like 120bn euros of loans to Greek banks, the ECB has in effect financed around 100bn euros of capital flight from Greek banks. Of this an estimated 45bn euros is cash under mattresses and buried in gardens, with the rest moved to overseas banks.
All of that cash and exported money represents hard "promises to pay" by the European Central Bank. By contrast the collateral it has received for its loans from the Greek government would be of questionable value.
The reputational damage to the European Central Bank, were it to incur severe losses, could imperil its primary responsibility - namely to maintain confidence in the euro as a store of value.
Without a deal, would the protests in Greece turn to riots?
And finally, if you get back to that thought experiment of what it would mean for an entire banking system to be closed for days and impaired for months, it would be naive to expect anything but fury from Greek people. Recriminations would fly against their own government and - inevitably - against Germany and the rest of the eurozone.
Diplomats working in Athens have told me of their anxiety that there would probably be riots. There is a risk of political extremists seizing this bleak day.
Social breakdown in Greece, the cradle of civilisation, would be more than embarrassing for the European Union. If the EU means anything, it means a collective endeavour to provide peace and stability in Europe.
The only beneficiary, arguably, of Greek anomie would be a Russia under President Putin looking for new allies.
So just maybe Greek bankers are right when they tell me that agreement will imminently be reached between Greece and its creditors - because the alternative is nightmarishly unthinkable.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:49:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Africa frustration at Marikana deaths inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33281413#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>S Africa politicians escape blame for Marikana deaths</Description>
        <MainBody>South Africa frustration at Marikana deaths inquiry
By Milton Nkosi BBC News, Johannesburg
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
A total of 44 people died during the strike, including 34 in one police operation
President Jacob Zuma's release of the 600-page Marikana report has sparked yet another national conversation about the rule of law in South Africa.
This follows hot on the heels of the Omar al-Bashir controversy , and the trials of Oscar Pistorius and Shrien Dewani .
Was the report a whitewash? Ferial Haffajee, editor of the weekend newspaper City Press, tweeted : "Sticking my neck out: I don't think 'whitewash' sticks."
Many South Africans took to social media to condemn the report, especially its recommendations.
They wanted to see a huge political figure, such as Deputy President Cyril Ramaphosa, take responsibility for his actions.
At the time, Mr Ramaphosa was a shareholder in Lonmin, the owner of the Marikana mine.
But President Zuma was reading the commission's recommendations. These were not his findings.
Some South Africans wanted to see Cyril Ramaphosa (left, pictured with Jacob Zuma) found guilty
Reports of this nature appear to be simple but they are full of legalese. A lot of the conclusions are left to interpretation or suggest another investigation.
One can sympathise with the people who lost loved ones three years ago and are utterly frustrated by the idea of yet another inquiry.
If an investigation is launched by prosecutors, the trial might drag for a very long time, meaning victims and relatives may never find closure.
While the report apportions some fault to the unions who took part in the wildcat wage strike, much of the blame is aimed squarely at the police .
Police Chief Riah Phiyega seems to be the highest-ranking person likely to take the hit.
Some of her junior staff are vulnerable too, such as the regional police chief of the North West province, Lieutenant-General Zukiswa Mbombo.
President Zuma called the deaths at Marikana "horrendous tragedy"
Just before police opened fire on the miners, Lt Gen Mbombo told the media: "Today is D-Day: we are ending this matter".
Last month, she announced she was retiring.
There does not seem to be any politician who is going to take responsibility for the killings of the 44.
There is no way President Zuma could afford to let his trusted deputy Cyril Ramaphosa shoulder some of the blame because that would jeopardise the current leadership succession plan.
If Mr Ramaphosa had to go to prison for sending emails asking the police minister to intervene at the mine during the violent wage strike, there would be a gaping hole in the post-Zuma ANC leadership line-up.
Once the dust settles, we will see whether the police chief will voluntarily step down or if she leaves the man who appointed her no choice but to fire her.
The sad part of this saga is that there are no talks of reparations for the miners who died and most of them were breadwinners.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:22:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can game theory explain the Greek debt crisis?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33254857#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Can a game explain the crisis facing Greece?</Description>
        <MainBody>Can game theory explain the Greek debt crisis?
26 June 2015
From the section Magazine
The Greek finance minister is an expert in game theory. Could this help predict how the Eurozone negotiations will turn out, asks Marcus Miller, professor of economics at the University of Warwick.
Game theory is what its name implies. It's the use of games to study behaviour and decision-making.
The most famous game of all is the Prisoner's Dilemma. Imagine two prisoners have to choose between confessing and staying silent. If they both stay silent, they both go to jail for one year. If one confesses and the other stays silent, the first goes free and the second gets 20 years. If both confess, they both get five years.
Neither can communicate with the other. So, rationally, what should each do? Sadly for the prisoners - but not the jailer - the answer is for both to confess.
Now, take the situation facing the Greek government, which needs a deal with its eurozone partners within days to secure to avoid defaulting on its debts. Will it have the same unfortunate outcome as the Prisoners' Dilemma?
Yanis Varoufakis, the Greek finance minister, spent his academic career (which included teaching posts at the University of Essex and the University of East Anglia) studying game theory.
In February 2015, he denied that he was "busily devising bluffs, stratagems and outside options" using game theory to "improve upon a weak hand".
Nevertheless, game theory should apply in situations like this where the outcomes for each player depend on the actions of both. The world being an uncertain place, random chance may also play a role - game theory takes account of this, too.
The Greek finance minister Yanis Varoufakis is an expert on game theory
So how might Varoufakis have visualised negotiations with the rest of the eurozone panning out?
He may well have drawn a decision-tree like that shown below, with Greece and the eurozone partners as key players. He would also include random outside factors, referred to in game theory jargon as "nature", which may also affect the outcome.
The outcomes, known as payoffs, of each player when the game ends are shown in brackets - so (1, 0) would be a good payoff for Greece and a bad one for the eurozone, whereas (1,1) would be good for both and (0,0) would be bad for everyone.
So what does the decision tree imply?
Imagine Greece moves first to avoid default by putting a plan on the table. This plan involves new taxes on the wealthy and changes to pensions - avoiding spending cuts and and having some of its debts written off in exchange. If this plan is accepted by the rest of the eurozone, then Greece is content. Let's give its payoff a score of 1.
To work out how the rest of the eurozone will respond, one has to see what they stand to gain by accepting Greece's plan, or by rejecting it.
If the eurozone accepted this deal, the monetary union would remain intact, but it would have to ease its strict rules on fiscal policy and take a loss on holdings of Greek debt. Let's give the eurozone payoff a score of . So the overall payoff is (1,  ).
What if the eurozone rejected the deal? Then Greece, unable to pay its creditors on time, would be in what is called "technical default".
What follows next is not at all clear. Let's look at two possibilities.
First there could be "Grexit" - Greece alone leaves the eurozone but the other members live happily ever after.
Second, Greek departure leads to the collapse of the eurozone.
The first scenario is likely to be pretty bad for Greece but not for the eurozone - a payoff of (0,1). The second is bad for everyone - the payoff is (0,0).
The truth, of course, is that no one really knows which of these will transpire - here is where nature throws the dice. If the two prospects are equally likely, the expected payoffs look pretty bad for both players.
So what is the bottom line? Faced with the messy prospect of letting Greece slide into default - and the significant risks of chaos that this entails - it looks better for eurozone partners to avert default and accept the Greek plan - or a watered-down version of it - after all.
This is better for Greece too - so unlike the Prisoner's Dilemma both players avoid the bad stuff.
This may be what has been concluded - if so, there will be a settlement with no technical default at the end of the month. But a lot depends on how well the agreed plan works. If it is a botched job, the drama may be repeated. Such is the game of life.
More from the Magazine
Game theory can be described as the mathematical study of decision-making, of conflict and strategy in social situations. It helps explain how we interact in key decision-making processes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:03:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Luxury consumer goods thrive in Iran</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33224168#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>High-end designer goods proving big business in Iran</Description>
        <MainBody>Why a luxury-shopping revolution is coming to Iran
By Amir Paivar &amp; Camelia Sadeghzadeh BBC Persian
26 June 2015
From the section Middle East
From the roadside billboards advertising Rolex and Louis Vuitton, to the glitzy shopping centres that have sprung up across Tehran, it's clear that big brands are becoming big business in Iran.
After decades of austerity following the Islamic Revolution , middle-class Iranians have developed a taste for high-end designer goods, and for Tehran's young rich, shopping has become the new religion.
"Exposure to foreign trends through travelling, the internet and satellite television has created a desire for branded products," says Bahar, a 30-year-old fashion blogger.
"Showing off is a big part of the story. By spending huge amounts of money on big brands, well-off Iranians want to show they've made it."
Living the high life
One group of super-rich young Tehranis have taken showing off to new levels with their own Instagram site - Rich Kids of Tehran , where without any perceptible sense of irony, they post pictures of their designer clothes and designer lifestyles.
When the site first appeared last year it prompted fury and resentment among poorer Iranians and the conservatives who dominate Iran's political and legal institutions.
But the Rich Kids seem undeterred by the controversy.
The Rich Kids of Tehran's Instagram feed features high-end vehicles
Recent postings include pictures of Tehran Fashion Week and a question about where people are going on holiday this year - the responses range from Italy and Istanbul to Japan and Dubai.
Because luxury brands are still the preserve of the rich, they don't yet show up in the Iranian Customs Authority's list of top 100 imports.
But there is an indication of the potential for growth in the most recent figures for cosmetics imports.
In the year to March 2015, cosmetics made up 0.1% of the country's $52bn (32.8bn) total imports - many of them big name brands snapped up by increasingly image-conscious consumers.
Mall envy
Iranians shop at the main old bazaar in Tehran
In big cities all across Iran, traditional bazaars now face fierce competition from American-style urban shopping centres where big name Western brands are on conspicuous display.
But although these luxury shopping centres look exactly the same as retail outlets anywhere in the world, the designer goods on display have actually been brought in by third-party importers via Turkey and the Gulf States.
The outlets that sell them have no connection to the big brand manufacturers.
Big Western fashion brands are not banned from doing business in Iran.
But international banking sanctions in place against Iran over its nuclear programme make it very difficult for them to get their profits out.
To date Spanish clothing retailer Mango, Italian fashion boutique Benetton, and luxury women's designer Escada, are among the very few Western companies to open shops in Iran.
Strict Islamic dress code in Iran also applies to advertising, so companies either have to show women fully covered, or just show the clothes on their own
The backdoor way in which foreign brands are imported into Iran means they are more expensive than they would be abroad, but so far this doesn't seem to be deterring the shoppers.
Mariam, an office worker who earns the equivalent of just $17,000 a year, has just blown more than a month's salary on a new Burberry bag.
She bought it online from an Iranian website that offers clothes and accessories from big brands and Western High Street retailers.
The site takes payments via local credit cards, and offers a free home-delivery service.
In the vanguard: Luxury retailers in Iran
Luciano Benetton
Benetton was the brainchild of Italian Luciano Benetton, who launched the company back in 1963 with his sister and two brothers.
Benetton now has about 5,000 stores, employing more than 10,000 people.
Mango was founded in Barcelona, Spain, launched on the web in 2005, opening its first shop in 2000.
Mango now has 2,731 stores in 105 countries.
Escada was founded in 1978 by Margaretha and Wolfgang Ley in Munich, Germany.
Escada has shops in 80 countries worldwide.
Mariam told BBC Persian she would rather pay more for good-quality brand names than cheaper but inferior, locally made equivalents.
But she concedes that status also plays a big role in how she decides to spend her money.
"There's a lot of pressure on middle-class people to go out wearing designer clothes or an expensive watch," she says. "Personally I feel more confident when I'm wearing brands."
'Untapped market'
Fashion houses like Burberry currently have no control over this so-called "grey market" of their brand names in Iran.
But that is clearly something which could change.
Despite years of sanctions, the International Monetary Fund puts Iran's per capita GDP (gross domestic product) at $16,500.
That means Iranian consumers on average have more money to spend than their counterparts in emerging markets like Brazil, China, India and South Africa.
With the prospect of banking sanctions being lifted if a nuclear deal is finally reached, the big brands are waking up to the potential of a barely tapped market which could offer big dividends in the future.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:21:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ECB 'to maintain Greek funding limit'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33304674#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The European Central Bank says it will maintain its emergency funding of Greek banks at the level agreed on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek debt: ECB 'to maintain funding limit'
28 June 2015
From the section Europe
Greek banks are reliant on emergency support from the ECB
The European Central Bank says it will maintain its emergency funding of Greek banks at the level agreed on Friday.
The ECB said that it stood ready to review the decision on its Emergency Liquidity Assistance (ELA) and would work closely with the Bank of Greece.
BBC economics editor Robert Peston says the ECB is not providing any additional aid to Greece, which will lead to huge pressure for capital controls.
Greek banks depend on ELA, and cutting it could push Greece out of the euro.
An ECB spokesman told the BBC: "Greece still has access to the ELA."
The ECB statement quotes Bank of Greece Governor Yannis Stournaras as saying: "The Bank of Greece, as a member of the eurosystem, will take all measures necessary to ensure financial stability for Greek citizens in these difficult circumstances."
The statement comes after eurozone finance minsters on Saturday refused a Greek request to extend Greece's current bailout.
The bailout expires on Tuesday, the same day that Greece has to make a payment of  1.5bn (1.1bn) to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) that it risks defaulting on.
Greece and its creditors had been locked in negotiations over a new bailout on Friday when the Greek government called a surprise referendum for 5 July over whether to accept the terms it was being offered. It has described the international offer as "not viable".
It then asked for an extension of its current deal until after the vote was completed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:53:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Organisers held over Taiwan inferno</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33302902#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The organisers of a party at a water park in Taiwan are questioned after 516 people were injured when a fire suddenly erupted among the crowds.</Description>
        <MainBody>Organisers questioned over Taiwan water park inferno
28 June 2015
From the section Asia
Organisers of a party at an amusement park in Taiwan have been detained for questioning after a fire tore through crowds at a party.
More than 500 people were injured in the incident, when a coloured powder apparently ignited after being discharged from the stage onto the audience.
Footage showed people panicking and screaming, and inflatable water toys used as stretchers.
Some 182 injured are in intensive care.
Figures are not yet available, but officials said many of the victims appear to in their 20s or younger.
Some of them breathed in the powder, causing respiratory problems.
The water park outside the capital Taipei has been closed, and so-called colour parties have been banned while the investigation into what caused the inferno proceeds.
Skin 'gone'
Event manager Lu Chung-chi and several staff members were detained by police and are being questioned by prosecutors.
Mr Lu was pictured in the Taiwan News with handcuffs on and his hands in a prayer position. The news site said he had apologised for what had happened and pledged to take responsibility for it.
Investigators were collecting evidence from the concert arena on Sunday morning
The blaze began so quickly that many partygoers had no time to escape
Many of those injured were initially tended by fellow partygoers
A trolley was used to rush one young man with leg burns to an ambulance
Footage of the incident shows a party in full swing when fire suddenly erupts.
It was "hell", a male student who sustained minor injuries said, according to AFP news agency.
"There was blood everywhere, including in the pool where lots of the injured were soaking themselves for relief from the pain."
His girlfriend added: "I saw lots of people whose skin was gone."
The fire was quickly brought under control.
The fire department said the powder ,used to create a party atmosphere, may have ignited due to the heat of the lights on the stage, or from sparks from machinery.
The substance is also used in other countries. It is made of dried corn and can be highly flammable, says the BBC's Cindy Sui in Taipei.
The 519 victims were sent to 41 hospitals, and 413 are still in hospital, say municipal authorities.
Soaring temperatures
Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou has been visiting some of the victims in hospital
The incident occurred about 20:30 (12:30 GMT) on Saturday.  More than 1,000 people were near the stage at the time.
Many people flocked to water parks on Saturday as temperatures reached 36.6C (98F) in Taipei and as high as 38C in other parts of Taiwan.
Taiwan has suffered a series of deadly fires in the past couple of years due partly to poor enforcement of building and fire safety codes and illegal construction, our correspondent says.
A fire earlier this year killed six firefighters, prompting orders to rectify illegally constructed buildings and upgrade firefighters' equipment and training.
Were you at the party? Have you been affected by the fire? You can share your experiences by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk .
Or WhatsApp us on +44 7525 900971.
Or comment here:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:56:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran talks 'to go beyond deadline'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33304417#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Iranian nuclear talks are set to continue beyond Tuesday's deadline, a senior US official says, with Iran's foreign minister preparing to go home for consultations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks 'to go beyond 30 June deadline' - US
28 June 2015
From the section Middle East
Iranian nuclear talks are set to go on beyond Tuesday's formal deadline for a deal, a senior US official says.
The admission came as Iran's Foreign Minister Mohammed Javad Zarif prepared to fly back to Tehran from Vienna, Austria, where talks are taking place.
Observers said Mr Zarif probably needed to seek guidance over a stumbling block in negotiations - how much access Tehran will grant to nuclear monitors.
Seven countries are taking part in the talks.
The negotiations aim to see limits placed on Tehran's nuclear programme in exchange for international sanctions on Iran.
The so-called P5+1 - the US, UK, France, China and Russia plus Germany - want to limit Iran's sensitive nuclear activities to ensure that it could not build a nuclear weapon quickly.
The negotiators were a few days late agreeing a framework agreement, which was reached in early April, and it now appears likely that Tuesday's deadline for a comprehensive deal may also not be respected.
But the US official - who spoke on condition of anonymity - insisted there would be no long-term extension, tweeted the BBC's state department correspondent Barbara Plett .
As well as the details of the proposed UN monitoring regime on Tehran's activities, disagreements are also reported to exist over the timing of sanctions relief.
US negotiators are being closely watched by critics both at home and in Israel - including Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, whose country is understood to have the Middle East's only nuclear arsenal.
On Sunday he decried "this bad agreement, which is becoming worse by the day".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:31:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisians march against beach attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33302564#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Marchers in the Tunisian town of Sousse condemn the killing of 38 people, mostly tourists, by a militant on a nearby beach.</Description>
        <MainBody>One Belgian and one German have so far been identified among the dead, the Tunisian health ministry said. One citizen of the Irish Republic is also confirmed dead. There were also thought to be Tunisians  killed in the attack.
At least 36 people were injured, some seriously.
Hundreds of people attended a rally in the Tunisian resort to denounce Friday's attack
Tourists do the peace sign from inside a bus as demonstrators take part in a rally
Tourists can be seen preparing to leave at Monastir airport near Sousse
An image published on sites associated with Islamic State purported to show the Tunisia gunman
Many of the tourists in hotels targeted in the attack have left the country or are waiting for specially arranged flights, but correspondents noted a few were back by the hotel pool on Saturday, vowing they would continue their holidays as scheduled.
Tunisia's economy relies on tourism, and there are fears that the recent attacks will deal a major blow to the industry.
Security officials said the attacker, who posed as a swimmer but was carrying a rifle under a parasol, started shooting on the beach before entering the Hotel Imperial Marhaba, continuing to shoot.
Officials later identified the gunman as 23-year-old student Seifeddine Rezgui. They said they had no inkling of what he had been planning.
The country has recently seen militant Islamists gain strength since the overthrow of long-serving ruler Zine al-Abidine Ben Ali in in 2011.
Tunisia's tourism industry
the number of tourist arrivals to Tunisia in 2014
15.2% the total contribution of travel and tourism to Tunisia's GDP
473,000 the number of jobs supported by travel and tourism (13.8% of total employment)
Source: Tunisia Tourism Ministry, World Travel and Tourism Council
Getty Images
Have you taken part in the protests? You can share your experiences by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk . Please leave a contact number if you are happy to speak to a BBC journalist.
Or WhatsApp us on+44 7525 900971.
Or comment here:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:07:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait mosque bomber 'was a Saudi'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33303795#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait says the attacker who carried out Friday's suicide bombing at a Shia mosque has been identified as a Saudi citizen.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait Shia mosque attack: Bomber 'was Saudi'
28 June 2015
From the section Middle East
Kuwait state media released an image of the alleged bomber, who authorities said had been identified as Saudi citizen Fahd Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Qaba'a
Kuwait says the attacker who carried out Friday's suicide bombing at a Shia mosque was a Saudi citizen.
The interior ministry named the bomber as Fahd Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Qaba'a, according to state media.
The ministry said he flew into Kuwait on Friday just hours before he detonated explosives at the mosque, killing at least 27 people.
The Islamic State group - which regards Shia Muslims as heretics - says it was behind the attack.
Last month, an IS branch in Saudi Arabia carried out bombings on consecutive Fridays on Shia mosques there.
These attacks have brought home the growing threat posed by the jihadists to the Gulf, says the BBC's Arab affairs editor Sebastian Usher.
Arrests
More than 200 people were injured in Friday's bombing at Imam Sadiq Mosque in Kuwait City - the bloodiest ever attack on Shia Muslims in the country's recent history.
Kuwaiti officials said the Saudi suspect was in Kuwait illegally.
Several people have been arrested in connection with the attack - including both the owner and driver of the car in which the bomber arrived at the mosque.
They have also arrested the owner of a house which the bomber is said to have visited - the interior ministry saying initial investigations showed he was a supporter of "extremist and deviant ideology".
Security has been stepped in Kuwait since Friday's bloodshed
Often at odds, Gulf states have united in confronting IS, our correspondent says.
All have joined the US-led coalition against the group in Syria and Iraq, although they have kept their participation low key.
IS is clearly hoping to stoke further tension between Sunnis and Shias in the Gulf, our correspondent adds.
Kuwait has one of the biggest Shia communities in the region, but any sectarian friction has so far been less visible than in Saudi Arabia or Bahrain.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 17:29:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman pulls down Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33297625#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A black woman removes the controversial Confederate flag from the flagpole in the grounds of the South Carolina State House in Columbia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag at South Carolina State House pulled down
27 June 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
A black woman has climbed the flagpole in the grounds of the South Carolina State House and removed its controversial Confederate flag.
Bree Newsome climbed the 30ft (9m) steel pole just after dawn on Saturday despite police telling her to come down, Associated Press reported.
Ms Newsome and a man were later arrested and the flag returned.
There have been calls for it to be removed since nine people were killed in a racist attack in Charleston.
Shooting suspect Dylann Roof had been pictured with the Civil War era saltire - seen by some as a symbol of slavery and racism - on a number of occasions.
There has been a social media campaign to remove the flag
Since the pictures emerged there has been pressure to remove the flag from the memorial in front of the South Carolina State House in Columbia.
It was first flown in 1962 in protest at the growing civil rights movement and has been a source of rancour and controversy in the state ever since.
The hashtag #TakeItDown has been trending on Twitter in the US.
Bree Newsome was taken into custody and the flag reinstated
White House spokesman Eric Schultz has said President Obama believes the Confederate flag "belongs in a museum".
Ms Newsome describes herself on Twitter as a filmmaker, singer, songwriter and freedom fighter.
A rally by flag supporters was scheduled for later on Saturday.
An impromptu Ride for Pride event took place in Brandon in Florida on Friday.
There have been rallies to support the use of the flag
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:00:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French beheading suspect sent selfie</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33301733#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man suspected of an attack on a factory in France sent a selfie where he posed with the severed head of his boss, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>France beheading attack: Suspect sent selfie with head
27 June 2015
From the section Europe
A photo of beheading victim Herve Cornara was released by friends
The man suspected of an attack on a factory in France sent a selfie where he posed with the severed head of his boss, security sources say.
Yassin Salhi, 35, reportedly sent the photo to a Canadian mobile phone number via the WhatsApp messaging service after Friday's attack near Lyon.
His boss Herve Cornara's head was found alongside Islamic flags.
The suspect is accused of ramming a vehicle into an area containing flammable liquids, causing a blast.
Police have so far not found any motive or possible foreign connection, prosecutors say.
In response to the attack, President Francois Hollande held a security meeting with ministers on Saturday.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls cut short a visit to Latin America to return to France which is on its highest state of alert after the attack in the small town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier some 40km (25 miles) from Lyon.
Yassin Salhi had been investigated in the past about his alleged links with Islamist militants.
Officials and residents of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier gathered outside the town hall on Saturday morning to observe a minute's silence.
'Suspect speaking'
Investigators are still trying to establish the identity of the recipient of the selfie.
A general view of the Air Products factory
They were unable to immediately confirm media reports that it was an unspecified person now in Syria, AP news agency reports.
The agency quoted the Paris prosecutor's office as saying the suspect had begun speaking to investigators after initially keeping silent.
Mr Salhi was arrested at the Air Products factory on Friday morning.
Anti-terror police searched the apartment of the father-of-three in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, taking his wife and sister into custody.
It is alleged he was waved through the gates of the factory because he was a regular delivery driver.
The severed head of Mr Cornara was found placed on factory railings. It is unclear when he died.
'Heated arguments'
President Hollande said: "We have no doubt that the attack was to blow up the building. It bears the hallmarks of a terrorist attack."
US-owned Air Products makes gases and chemicals and has employees in 50 countries around the world.
Chief Executive Seifi Ghasemi said: "I believe I speak for all of our Air Products family around the world in expressing our deepest sympathies to the family of the victim of this unspeakable act."
The home of the suspect, who was known to police, has been searched
There has been a heavy police presence outside the factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier
According to a report in the French newspaper Le Figaro (in French) , a friend of Herve Cornara witnessed heated arguments between the delivery firm boss and his employee "several times".
Mr Cornara, 54, is said to have been a well-known figure in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone. He led a tenants' association and campaigned for better amenities in the area.
"He fought with local authorities when the heating wasn't working," another friend recalled, speaking to AFP news agency. "He got involved in the campaign to save the post office."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:07:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brazil 1-1 Paraguay (3-4 pens)</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33085894</Link>
        <Description>Paraguay beat Brazil on penalties in the Copa America to set up a semi-final against Argentina.</Description>
        <MainBody>Derlis Gonzlez (Paraguay) wins a free kick on the right wing.
89:34
Hand ball by Everton Ribeiro (Brazil).
88:44
Corner,  Brazil. Conceded by Victor Cceres.
88:14
Corner,  Brazil. Conceded by Pablo Aguilar.
86:44 Substitution
Substitution Substitution, Brazil. Everton Ribeiro replaces Robinho.
86:22
Dani Alves (Brazil) wins a free kick in the defensive half.
86:22
Foul by scar Romero (Paraguay).
85:17
Filipe Luis (Brazil) wins a free kick in the defensive half.
85:17
Foul by Derlis Gonzlez (Paraguay).
83:54
Elas (Brazil) wins a free kick in the defensive half.
83:54
Foul by Ral Bobadilla (Paraguay).
83:23 Substitution
Substitution Substitution, Paraguay. scar Romero replaces dgar Bentez.
82:50
Attempt missed. Dani Alves (Brazil) right footed shot from outside the box misses to the left from a direct free kick.
81:45
Elas (Brazil) wins a free kick in the attacking half.
81:45
Foul by Ral Bobadilla (Paraguay).
81:36
Attempt saved. Philippe Coutinho (Brazil) right footed shot from the left side of the box is saved in the bottom right corner.
81:01
Miranda (Brazil) wins a free kick in the defensive half.
81:01
Foul by Ral Bobadilla (Paraguay).
80:35 Booking
Booking Osvaldo Martnez (Paraguay) is shown the yellow card.
80:30
Hand ball by Robinho (Brazil).
79:35
Corner,  Paraguay. Conceded by Jefferson.
79:34
Attempt saved. Derlis Gonzlez (Paraguay) right footed shot from the right side of the box is saved in the centre of the goal. Assisted by Roque Santa Cruz with a headed pass.
78:42
Philippe Coutinho (Brazil) wins a free kick in the attacking half.
78:42
Foul by Osvaldo Martnez (Paraguay).
76:57
Corner,  Brazil. Conceded by Paulo Da Silva.
76:42
Attempt blocked. Bruno Valdez (Paraguay) right footed shot from outside the box is blocked. Assisted by Derlis Gonzlez.
76:12 Substitution
Substitution Substitution, Paraguay. Osvaldo Martnez replaces Eduardo Aranda.
75:32 Booking
Booking Philippe Coutinho (Brazil) is shown the yellow card for a bad foul.
75:26
Foul by Philippe Coutinho (Brazil).
75:26
Pablo Aguilar (Paraguay) wins a free kick in the defensive half.
74:36
Attempt saved. Bruno Valdez (Paraguay) header from the centre of the box is saved in the top centre of the goal. Assisted by Derlis Gonzlez with a cross.
73:25 Substitution
Substitution Substitution, Paraguay. Ral Bobadilla replaces Nelson Valdez.
71:09 Goal scored
Goal! Goal!  Brazil 1, Paraguay 1. Derlis Gonzlez (Paraguay) converts the penalty with a right footed shot to the bottom left corner.
69:27
Penalty conceded by Thiago Silva (Brazil) with a hand ball in the penalty area.
68:50 Substitution
Substitution Substitution, Brazil. Diego Tardelli replaces Roberto Firmino.
66:56
Offside, Paraguay. dgar Bentez tries a through ball, but Roque Santa Cruz is caught offside.
61:47
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:03:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armenia suspends power price hike</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33301689#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The president of Armenia suspends an increase in electricity prices, but protesters who have held days of demonstrations remain on the streets.</Description>
        <MainBody>Armenia protests: Electricity price hike suspended
27 June 2015
From the section Europe
The president of Armenia has suspended an increase in electricity prices that led to more than a week of protests.
Serzh Sargsyan said that the government would temporarily cover the cost of the electricity price rise pending a review.
Protesters have been blocking the main avenue in the capital, Yerevan.
They remained on the streets on Saturday, saying the president's concession fell short of their demand for the price hike to be reversed.
The BBC's Rayhan Demytrie reports from Yerevan that the protest area has been surrounded by the police, and buses and water canons have been brought close to where the demonstration is being held.
Protests began a few days after a 17 June decision by the state utilities commission to increase electricity tariffs from the beginning of August by more than 16%.
In the early hours of Tuesday, the situation escalated when police used water cannon to disperse the crowd. There have been round-the-clock demonstrations , referred to on social media under the hashtag #ElectricYerevan.
Analysts say the protests are partly fuelled by anger over years of alleged corruption and unaccountability within the Armenian government, and big business monopolised by Russian oligarchs with ties to the Kremlin.
Armenia still has close links with Russia. The former Soviet nation hosts a Russian military base and a Russian company runs its power distribution network.
The electricity network is wholly owned by Inter-RAO, a large Russian energy company whose chairman Igor Sechin is a close friend of President Vladimir Putin.
Mr Sargsyan's announcement of the price hike suspension followed a meeting with Russian Transport Minister Maxim Sokolov.
Russia agreed to loan Armenia $200m (127m) to help modernise its military, and to allow a Russian soldier accused of killing seven members of an Armenian family to be tried locally.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:58:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Argentina in Falklands asset ruling</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33301540#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A judge in Argentina orders the seizure of assets of firms drilling for oil around the Falklands, but it is unclear how it can be enforced.</Description>
        <MainBody>Argentina judge orders asset seizure of Falklands oil firms
27 June 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Rhetoric on the islands is likely to step up during the campaign for October's presidential elections
A federal judge in Argentina has ordered the seizure of assets of five companies drilling for oil in the Falkland Islands.
Tierra del Fuego judge Lilian Herraez ordered the authorities to seize boats and other assets worth $156m.
Argentina claims sovereignty of the islands, which it calls the Malvinas.
The oil companies named in the case are not based in Argentina and it is not clear how the measure will be implemented.
Drilling for oil in the territorial waters around the Falklands began in 2010 despite opposition from Buenos Aires.
'Bordering on stupidity'
Judge Herraez says the new ruling will take steps to try to seize the companies' assets abroad.
The five companies mentioned are: Premier Oil Plc, Rockhopper Exploration Plc, Falkland Oil and Gas Ltd, Noble Energy Inc and Edison International Spa.
Three of the companies are British-based, one is American, based in Texas, and one is French-owned, based in Italy.
Britain and Argentina went to war over the Falklands in 1982.
Argentina occupied the South Atlantic archipelago for 74 days, before British forces regained control.
During the conflict, 255 British and about 650 Argentine servicemen were killed, along with three Falklands civilians.
Argentina accuses Britain of colonialism, saying the islands lie some 700km (450 miles) off its coast.
Britain has held the Falklands for 180 years and says the wishes of its 3,000 residents should be respected.
The vast majority of them want the islands to remain a British overseas territory.
"They want to remain British and that view should be respected by everybody, including by Argentina," said David Cameron after a 2013 referendum in which the islanders gave almost unanimous support for the status quo.
Argentine President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner said at the time that Britain was "arrogant" and "bordering on stupidity" for refusing to negotiate on the future of the islands.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:07:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gay marriage legalised across US</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33290341#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The US Supreme Court rules that same-sex marriage is a legal right - a decision President Obama hails as a "victory for America".</Description>
        <MainBody>US Supreme Court rules gay marriage is legal nationwide
27 June 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The US Supreme Court has ruled that same-sex marriage is a legal right across the United States.
It means the 14 states with bans on same-sex marriage will no longer be able to enforce them.
Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote that the plaintiffs asked "for equal dignity in the eyes of the law. The Constitution grants them that right."
The ruling brings to an end more than a decade of bitter legal battles.
Same-sex couples in several affected states including Georgia, Michigan, Ohio and Texas rushed to wed on Friday.
However officials in other states, including Mississippi and Louisiana, said marriages had to wait until procedural issues were addressed.
President Barack Obama said the ruling was a "victory for America".
"When all Americans are treated as equal, we are all more free " he said.
However, Christian conservatives condemned the decision.
Former Arkansas governor and presidential candidate Mike Huckabee called it "an out-of-control act of unconstitutional, judicial tyranny".
And Kellie Fiedorek, a lawyer for an anti-gay marriage advocacy group, said the decision "ignored the voices of thousands of Americans".
Greg Abbott, the governor of Texas, a state where marriages licences will now be issued to same-sex couples, said the justices "have imposed on the entire country their personal views on an issue that the Constitution and the Court's previous decisions reserve to the people of the states".
At the scene - Paul Blake, BBC News
Loud cheers erupted outside the court after the ruling was announced, and there were tears, hugs, and cheers of "USA USA USA!".
A sea of rainbow flags overwhelmed the few anti-gay marriage activists who reacted in disbelief, and the demonstration seemed to turn into a street party.
A tour bus drove past honking as hundreds cheered the decision.
One of the demonstrators, Jordan Monaghan, called his mother from his mobile phone amid the celebrations.
"Hey mom, I'm at the Supreme Court. Your son can have a husband now," Mr Monaghan said.
Jordan Monaghan told his mum: "Your son can have a husband now."
Minutes after the ruling, couples in one of the states that had a ban, Georgia, lined up in hope of being wed.
In Texas, Yasmin Menchaca and her partner Catherine Andrews told the BBC that they are "trying to round up our parents" in order to get married on Friday.
The two have been together for six years, and had attempted to marry in Washington state - but decided to wait because of the financial burden of flying their parents across the country.
On social media, Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton merely tweeted the word "proud" and the White House changed its Twitter avatar into the rainbow colours.
The case considered by the court concerned Jim Obergefell, an Ohio resident who was not recognised as the legal widower of his late husband, John Arthur.
"It's my hope that gay marriage will soon be a thing of the past, and from this day forward it will simply be 'marriage,'" an emotional Mr Obergefell said outside the court.
Couples in some parts of Texas were able to get married
States affected:
Alabama, Arkansas, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Michigan, Mississippi, most of Missouri, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, South Dakota, Tennessee and Texas.
The first state to allow same-sex marriage was Massachusetts, which granted the right in 2004.
In recent years, a wave of legal rulings and a dramatic shift in public opinion have expanded gay marriage in the US.
In 2012, the high court struck down a federal anti same-sex marriage law.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:45:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>England Women 2-1 Canada Women</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33085911</Link>
        <Description>England knock out hosts Canada to reach the Women's World Cup semi-final and book a date with defending champions Japan.</Description>
        <MainBody>England Women v Canada Women
England Women 2
Women's World Cup 2015 highlights: England 2-1 Canada
28 June 2015 Last updated at 02:45
By Alistair Magowan BBC Sport in Vancouver
England face Japan (coverage from 23:40 BST, 1 July)
Two early goals put Lionesses through
England reached a World Cup semi-final for the first time in their history as victory over hosts Canada set up a tie with reigning champions Japan.
Women's World Cup Catch-Up: Lionesses make history in Canada
The Lionesses made a dream start with two goals in three minutes as Jodie Taylor, making her first World Cup start nine weeks after knee surgery, capitalised on Lauren Sesselmann's blunder.
Lucy Bronze then headed in Fara Williams' free-kick to double the advantage.
Taylor tearful after 'amazing' England win
England goalkeeper Karen Bardsley continued her mixed World Cup when she gifted Christine Sinclair a goal three minutes before the break.
But in a second half in which Mark Sampson's side became disjointed, England held on for a famous win that sparked joyous celebrations at the final whistle.
England had already broken new ground by winning their first World Cup knockout game in the last 16, when they beat Norway.
Women's World Cup 2015: Jodie Taylor capitalises to give England lead
But the result means Welshman Sampson has guided a senior England side, men's or women's, to a World Cup semi-final for the first time since 1990.
As in their final group game win over Colombia, England started fast and then dug deep to keep Canada out as they matched the victory they inflicted over John Herdman's side in this year's Cyprus Cup.
Although they did not reach the heights of their second-round win over Norway, they will now travel to Edmonton to face a team they beat in the group stages of the last World Cup before Japan went on to lift the trophy.
Women's World Cup 2015: Lucy Bronze heads England 2-0 up
England's preparations were disrupted shortly before the game when vice-captain Jordan Nobbs posted an update on social media to say her World Cup was over because of a hamstring injury - although the Football Association denied the story was true.
But it had little effect on England, as 29-year-old Taylor showed signs of her growing status  just 10 months after making her debut by robbing Sesselmann and drilling low past hosts' goalkeeper Erin McLeod for her first World Cup goal.
The nightmare continued for Canada when England won a free-kick deep in Canadian territory.
Williams picked out Bronze at the back post, and the right-back managed to loop her header over McLeod and in off the crossbar.
Women's World Cup 2015: Karen Bardsley error gives Canada lifeline
England's goals came against the run of play - Melissa Tancredi guilty of being wasteful for Canada - and Katie Chapman almost added to England's tally when her header clipped the top of the crossbar.
Sinclair was then presented with a chance to get Canada back in the match when Bardsley, who was also at fault when she conceded late on against Mexico, could not gather Ashley Lawrence's centre and Canada's record goalscorer converted from close range.
Bardsley's game came to a premature end when she departed five minutes into the second half with what looked like a swollen eye and was replaced by Siobhan Chamberlain.
Women's World Cup 2015: Canada's John Herdman apologies to nation
But it did not disrupt England.
Taylor was denied a second when McLeod brilliantly tipped her curling effort wide.
With the game becoming scrappy, it felt like another England mistake might lead to a Canada equaliser.
But after Sophie Schmidt fired over seven minutes from the end, the Lionesses remained resolute and roared wildly as the hosts were eliminated in front of 54,027 fans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:14:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sao Paulo bans sale of foie gras</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33296884#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Legislation approved in Brazil's largest city, Sao Paulo, bans the production and sale of foie gras</Description>
        <MainBody>Brazil: Foie gras banned in Sao Paulo restaurants
27 June 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Most of the foie gras produced in the world comes from France
Legislators in Brazil's largest city, Sao Paulo, have banned the production and sale of foie gras, a delicacy made from the fatty liver of force-fed ducks and geese.
City councillors said animals go through a great deal of suffering for the production of the pate.
Animal rights campaigners have hailed the move, but some of Sao Paulo's best-known chefs have voiced concern.
Foie gras, originally a French delicacy, is produced worldwide.
Several countries, including Britain, Germany, Italy and Argentina, have banned its production. But the sale of the pate is still allowed in most of them.
The Sao Paulo city council has set a fine of 5,000 reais (1,000) for restaurants and bars that break the new law - which will take effect in 45 days.
"Foie gras is an appetiser for the wealthy," said the law's author, city councillor Laercio Benko.
"It does not benefit human health and to make it, the birds are submitted to a lot of suffering,'' said Mr Benko.
However Sao Paulo-based chef Alex Atala told the UOL news portal: "How can a city regulate what a person eats? Where will it all end?''
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:16:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother and baby survive plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-33265943#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A young mother and her baby son have been found alive five days after their plane crashed in the jungle of western Colombia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother and baby survive Colombia jungle plane crash
26 June 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Ms Murillo suffered some injuries and burns but she is recovering well
A young mother and her baby have been found alive five days after their plane crashed in the jungle of western Colombia.
A Colombian Air Force chief described their survival as "a miracle".
Maria Nelly Murillo, 18, and her one-year-old son were found by rescuers near to where their small Cessna plane crashed in Choco province.
Ms Murillo had some injuries and burns while her baby appeared to be in good health.
Contact lost
The twin-engine Cessna, which was carrying fish and coconuts, had been flying from the town of Nuqui on the Pacific coast to Quibdo, the capital of Choco.
Stories of miraculous plane crash survivals
Baby Yudier Moreno was held by a rescuer on the flight back to Quibdo
It disappeared from the radar of the civil aviation authorities 20 minutes into the flight. A search plane eventually found the wreckage in the Alto Baudo region.
The reason for the crash is not known. The pilot of the Cessna was found dead in the cockpit.
Glimmer of hope
There was no trace of Ms Murillo or her baby, Yudier Moreno, which the passenger list said had been on board.
But according to Col Hector Carrascal of the Colombian Air Force, rescuers took hope when they noticed that the cabin door was ajar.
Search and rescue aircraft found the wreck of the plane. The cause of the crash is unclear
"It could have opened on impact, but it could have been opened from the inside," he said.
"We didn't have a clue what had happened to them: they could be lost in the jungle trying to survive or they could have died already."
Part of the search party searched the area on foot, while others flew in a helicopter using a loudspeaker to shout Ms Murillo's name and urge her to return to the crash site.
But for two days their search yielded no results.
'Miracle'
Finally, on Wednesday, they located Ms Murillo about 500m from the site of the crash in a ravine on the banks of a river.
Ms Murillo and her baby were taken by helicopter to a hospital in Quibdo
"It's a miracle," Col Carrascal said. Of the baby, who is unharmed, he said: "His mother's spirit must have given him strength to survive."
The pair were airlifted to a hospital in Quibdo. BBC Mundo's Natalio Cosoy has spoken to Ms Murillo's elder brother, Carlos.
Mr Murillo said she had managed to open the cabin door and run into the jungle as fire was spreading in the cabin.
"It was then she remembered she had a baby and went back from him," said Carlos Murillo. She sustained burns to her face, an arm and a leg.
Afraid the plane might explode, she walked into the jungle along the bank of a small river.
She was able to survive by drinking coconut water from the coconuts the plane had been carrying, her brother said. She used big leaves to collect and drink rain water.
Ms Murillo eventually heard the calls over loudspeaker from the rescue helicopter which prompted her to make her way back to the crash site.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:37:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Militants storm Somalia military base</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33282778#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>At least 30 people are killed as al-Shabab gunmen attack a military base used by African Union peacekeepers in southern Somalia, witnesses say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Somalia attack: Al-Shabab 'kills 30' at AU military base
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
Al-Shabab has said it carried out the attack
At least 30 people have been killed after gunmen attacked an African Union military base in southern Somalia, witnesses say.
A suicide car bomber drove into the main gates of the base in Leego, along the main road connecting the capital, Mogadishu and the city of Baidoa.
The militant Islamist group al-Shabab says its fighters have taken control of the base but this is not confirmed.
Al-Shabab is battling Somalia's government for control of the country.
The base is manned by Burundian soldiers from the African Union Mission in Somalia (Amisom), which has more than 20,000 troops in the country.
Amisom confirmed on its Twitter account that an attack was ongoing, but has not given any details on casualties.
Leego residents have seen militants burning vehicles, carrying off weapons and removing the bodies of their fighters killed in the attack, reports the BBC's Mohamed Moalimu from Mogadishu.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:57:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nigeria death sentences for blasphemy</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33283261#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Islamic court sentences nine people to death after finding them guilty of blasphemy in the northern Nigerian city of Kano.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria court in Kano sentences nine people to death for blasphemy
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
An Islamic court has sentenced nine people to death for insulting the Prophet Muhammad in the northern Nigerian city of Kano.
The accused, who were all Muslims, had pleaded guilty, the head of Kano's religious police, Aminu Ibrahim Daurawa, told the BBC.
The trial was speedily done in secret after a section of the court was burnt down by angry protesters last month.
It is not known if they will appeal against the sentence.
The alleged offence was committed last month at a religious gathering in honour of Sheikh Ibrahim Niasse, the Senegalese founder of the Tijaniya sect, which has a large following across West Africa.
The nine, eight man and a woman, were reported to have said that "Niasse was bigger than Prophet Muhammad", triggering unrest.
The venue was burnt to the ground by an angry mob and the nine were arrested,
"There has been consensus among Muslims scholars that insulting the prophet carries a death sentence," Mr Daurawa told the BBC Hausa service.
"We quickly put them on trial to avoid bloodshed because people were very angry and trying to take law into their hands," he added.
Kano has a predominately Muslim population and Islamic courts operate alongside secular courts.
BBC Kano reporter Yusuf Yakasai said people celebrated in some parts of the city when news of the judgement emerged.
Tijaniya at a glance
The Sufi sect of Tijaniya was founded in Algeria in 1784 by Ahmad ibn Muhammad al-Tijani.
It spread all over the world, with large following in north and west Africa. It also has followers in South Africa, Indonesia and other parts of the world.
There are other Sufi sects in Islam but Tijaniya is the largest.
They have three main daily practices: Asking the forgiveness of God; sending prayers to the Prophet Muhammad and affirming the Oneness of Allah.
Senegalese-born Sheikh Ibrahim Niasse was credited with reviving the sect in the 20th Century. People travel from across the continent to visit his shrine.
They have several factions including the Haqiqa (Realist) group, whose leaders were convicted accused of blasphemy in Kano.
Several states in predominantly Muslims northern Nigeria have introduced Sharia law after the country returned to civilian rule in 1999.
This is the first time a death sentence has been handed down for blasphemy in northern Nigeria.
The sentence has been delivered for other offences such as adultery but none has been carried out.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:23:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds hurt in Taiwan park blast</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33300970#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>More than 500 people are injured when a fire tears through crowds at a party at a water park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan Formosa Water Park explosion injures hundreds
28 June 2015
From the section Asia
More than 500 people were injured when fire ripped through crowds at a party at an amusement park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei.
Saturday's incident at the Formosa Water Park is believed to have happened when a coloured powder ignited after being discharged onto the crowd.
Footage showed people panicking and screaming. Inflatable water toys were shown being used as stretchers.
Some 190 people are seriously hurt - 182 are in intensive care.
Some of them breathed in the powder, causing respiratory problems.
Local media said organisers of the Color Play Asia event had been taken in for questioning by prosecutors.
Skin 'gone'
Footage of the incident shows a party in full swing when suddenly fire erupts.
It was "hell", a male student who sustained minor injuries said, according to AFP news agency.
"There was blood everywhere, including in the pool where lots of the injured were soaking themselves for relief from the pain."
His girlfriend added: "I saw lots of people whose skin was gone."
The incident occurred during a concert
A trolley was used to rush one young man with leg burns to an ambulance
The fire was quickly brought under control, but the cause of the incident is still under investigation.
The authorities believe something that caught fire caused the coloured powder spray or dust - used to create a party atmosphere - to explode.
The substance is also used in other countries. It is made of dried corn and can be highly flammable, our correspondent says.
The 519 victims were sent to 41 hospitals, and 413 are still in hospital, say municipal authorities.
The incident occurred about 20:30 (12:30 GMT).  More than 1,000 people were near the stage at the time.
The fire department said: "Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage".
Soaring temperatures
Many people flocked to water parks on Saturday as temperatures reached 36.6C (98F) in Taipei and as high as 38C in other parts of Taiwan, says the BBC's Cindy Sui in Taipei.
New Taipei City's mayor, Eric Chu, ordered an immediate shutdown of the water park pending an investigation.
Taiwan has suffered a series of deadly fires in the past couple of years due partly to poor enforcement of building and fire safety codes and illegal construction, our correspondent adds.
A fire earlier this year killed six firefighters, prompting orders to rectify illegally constructed buildings and upgrade firefighters' equipment and training.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:03:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sri Lankan parliament dissolved</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33292592#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Sri Lankan President Maithripala Sirisena dissolves parliament, paving the way for an early general election.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sri Lanka's president dissolves parliament
26 June 2015
From the section Asia
Maithripala Sirisena dissolved parliament with effect from midnight
Sri Lankan President Maithripala Sirisena has dissolved parliament, paving the way for an early general election.
"The president signed a gazette notification dissolving parliament with effect from midnight today," government spokesman Rajitha Senaratne said.
The general election was not scheduled for another 10 months.
Mr Sirisena defeated incumbent Mahinda Rajapaksa in presidential elections held in January.
The president's decision to dissolve parliament came shortly after a spokesman for the United National Party (UNP) said it had formally requested him to do so.
The UNP was the main party behind Mr Sirisena's presidential bid and its leader, Ranil Wickremesingha, is the country's prime minister.
Sri Lankan law dictates that elections be held between 52 and 66 days after the dissolution.
Government sources told the BBC that the election will be held on 17 August.
Sri Lankan election Commissioner Mahinda Deshapriya is scheduled to hold a news conference on Saturday where he will announce the dates.
The dissolution of parliament ends the term of the coalition government that was appointed for a 100-day period after the presidential election result. However, it exceeded that time limit as it sought to implement key constitutional reforms.
Former President Rajapaksa is expected to use the elections to stage a political comeback.  He has previously announced that he intends to be the new prime minister.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:10:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NI driver dies in Belgium bus crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33303121#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A bus driver from Northern Ireland is killed after a coach carrying 34 children from an Essex school crashes in Belgium.</Description>
        <MainBody>NI driver killed in Belgium school trip bus crash
28 June 2015
From the section Northern Ireland
A bus driver from Northern Ireland has been killed in a coach crash in Belgium.
He was on a bus carrying 34 school children from an Essex school in the UK.
Another driver, also from Northern Ireland, has been seriously injured.
A pupil from Brentwood School who was on the bus suffered a head injury and is in intensive care. It is understood that three pupils and two teachers are in hospital.
The bus company, Richmond Coaches, is from Lisburn, County Antrim.
The bus overturned on the A18 (E40) at Middelkerke, West Flanders at 09:45 local time (08:45 BST).
Eyewitnesses said it crashed into a motorway bridge pillar.
West Flanders traffic police confirmed that one person is dead and one is injured.
A rescue worker carries students' backpacks from the bus
Thirty-one children and three teachers walked away from the crash.
The children from Brentwood School were all aged from 11 to 13 years old.
Ian Davies, the school's head teacher said: "There are three children in hospital. We don't know the full extent of their injuries.
"I know that one boy has a head injury which is being monitored very carefully.
"I have spoken to the lead teacher on the trip. He is in hospital, I think he broke his collar bone, but seemed in as good a shape as could be expected."
A spokesman from Richmond Coaches of Ballinderry Road, Lisburn, confirmed that one of its vehicles had been involved in the crash.
He said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved and they were cooperating fully with the authorities.
Janna Rommel-Opstaele, the mayor of the nearby coastal town of Middelkerke, told press agency Reuters that the bus driver had been killed and another seriously injured.
"Some of the children with light injuries have been taken to hospital and local medical centres," she said.
A spokesman for the Foreign and Commonwealth Office said they were aware of the crash and were working with  the Belgian authorities to establish details.
Have you been affected by this incident? You can email haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk with your experiences.
If you are willing to speak further to a BBC journalist, please include a contact phone number.
Email your pictures to yourpics@bbc.co.uk , upload them here , tweet them to @BBC_HaveYourSay or text 61124. If you are outside the UK, send them to the international number +44 7624 800 100.
Or WhatsApp us on +44 7525 900971
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 16:51:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kurds 'drive IS from border town'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33299306#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State militants are reportedly driven out of the Syrian border town of Kobane but are said to have massacred more than 200 civilians.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria Islamic State: Kurds 'claim control over Kobane'
27 June 2015
From the section Middle East
Smoke could still be seen over Kobane on Saturday, from Turkish territory
Islamic State (IS) militants have been driven out of the town of Kobane, on the Turkish border, Kurdish forces and activists say.
IS launched a surprise assault on the long-contested town on Thursday, reportedly massacring civilians, including women and children.
The UK-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights says 206 bodies were found, most with bullet wounds.
Kurdish forces broke an IS siege of Kobane only in January.
Meanwhile, fighting is reportedly continuing in the Syrian city of Hassakeh, about 270km (180 miles) further east, which was also attacked by IS on Thursday.
Troops loyal to Syrian President Bashar al-Assad and their allies are tackling the militants after fighting which, according to UN figures, saw some 60,000 people flee.
Overall, in four years of armed conflict in Syria, more than 200,000 people have lost their lives and more than 11 million others - nearly half the population - have been forced from their homes.
'Last stand'
Smoke could still be seen rising over Kobane on Saturday.
Redur Xelil, spokesman for the Syrian Kurdish YPG militia, told Reuters news agency that around eight IS members had escaped north towards the Turkish border.
"There are still search operations in neighbourhoods where they might be hiding," he added. "The town is quiet now."
An activist in Kobane, Mustafa Bali, told AP news agency by telephone that Kobane had been "completely cleared".
"Kurdish forces are now combing the town looking for fighters who may have gone into hiding," he added.
As the civilian death toll rose during searches on Saturday, local journalist Rudi Mohammad Amin told AFP news agency more people were still unaccounted for.
The militants, he said, had made their last stand in an apparently unoccupied boys' secondary school.
"The YPG detonated explosives outside of the school, then stormed it," he said. "This military operation was carried out after ensuring that there were no civilians left in the school."
Unconfirmed reports say Kurdish civilians began returning to the town from across the border in Turkey on Saturday.
Civilians could be seen heading back towards Kobane
Erdogan warning
IS launched its two-pronged offensive after the YPG cut off one of its major supply routes near the city of Raqqa.
The city is the de facto capital of the IS "caliphate", declared a year ago after the group captured large swathes of northern and western Iraq and parts of Syria.
Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has pledged never to allow Kurds to establish their own state in northern Syria.
"I say to the international community that whatever price must be paid, we will never allow the establishment of a new state on our southern frontier in the north of Syria," he said at a dinner on Friday night.
The Turkish leader also rejected accusations that Turkey had colluded with IS in its attack on Kobane this week. "It is a big lie to accuse Turkey of having link with a terrorist organisation," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:29:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama warned over Iran concessions</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33269405#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Former advisers to US President Barack Obama express concern at the emerging deal between world powers and Iran over its nuclear programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks: Obama warned over concessions
25 June 2015
From the section Middle East
John Kerry and Mohammad Javad Zarif are due to join the negotiations in Vienna on Friday
Former senior advisers to US President Barack Obama have expressed concern at the emerging deal between world powers and Iran over its nuclear programme.
In an open letter , the security and foreign policy experts say it "falls short of meeting the administration's own standard of a 'good' agreement".
They call for fewer concessions on international nuclear inspections and on research and development activities.
The publication of the letter comes as the deadline for a final accord nears.
US Secretary of State John Kerry and his Iranian counterpart Mohammad Javad Zarif are to fly to the Austrian capital Vienna on Friday to join the negotiations, which may need to continue beyond 30 June.
The so-called P5+1 - the US, UK, France, China and Russia plus Germany - wants to limit Iran's sensitive nuclear activities to ensure that it could not build a nuclear weapon quickly.
Iran, which wants sanctions lifted in exchange, insists its nuclear work is peaceful.
'Tracks with US position'
The open letter published by the Washington Institute for Near East Policy on Thursday is signed by a bipartisan group of US diplomats, legislators, policymakers and experts who have met regularly over the past three years to discuss Iran.
They include:
Dennis Ross, who advised President Obama on Iran
Former CIA director David Petraeus
Robert Einhorn, a former member of the US negotiating team with Iran
James Cartwright, a former vice-chairman of the US military's Joint Chiefs of Staff
Gary Samore, a former Obama adviser on nuclear policy
Stephen Hadley, who was a national security adviser to President George W Bush
Iran insists its nuclear work is solely for peaceful purposes
"Most of us would have preferred a stronger agreement," the letter says.
"The agreement will not prevent Iran from having a nuclear weapons capability. It will not require the dismantling of Iran's nuclear infrastructure," it adds.
"It will however reduce that infrastructure for the next 10 to 15 years. And it will impose a transparency, inspection, and consequences regime with the goal of deterring and dissuading Iran from actually building a nuclear weapon."
The letter calls on Mr Obama to insist that Iran provide information about nuclear weapons research Western powers suspect it has carried out, and allow inspectors from the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) access to military sites.
The president is also urged to establish strict limits on the research and development of centrifuges used to enrich uranium to preclude the "rapid technical upgrade and expansion" of Iran's enrichment capacity at the end of any deal. Enriched uranium can be used to make fuel for both nuclear energy and weapons.
A senior Obama administration official said it had received the letter and that it "in large part tacks with the US negotiating position inside the negotiating room".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 15:53:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Diplomat convoy hit by Somalia bomb</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33257724#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The United Arab Emirates' ambassador to Somalia narrowly escapes an al-Shabab suicide attack that kills 12 people in Mogadishu, reports say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Somalia attack: Al-Shabab targets diplomat in Mogadishu
24 June 2015
From the section Africa
The UAE ambassador survived as he was in a bulletproof vehicle
A military vehicle escorting a United Arab Emirates' diplomatic convoy was hit by a car bomb in Somalia's capital, killing at least 12 people, police say.
The UAE ambassador survived the suicide attack as he was riding in a bullet-proof land cruiser vehicle, the BBC's Mohamed Moalimu reports from Mogadishu.
The militant Islamist group al-Shabab says it carried out the attack, to target "a foreign enemy".
Al-Shabab is battling Somalia's government for control of the country.
On Sunday morning, a suicide car bomber and gunmen attacked a training centre for the national intelligence agency .
The militants have vowed to intensify attacks during the Muslim fasting month of Ramadan, which began on Wednesday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:05:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flags at half-mast for Tunisia dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33304310#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Downing Street's flags will be flown at half-mast, as officials fear the British death toll from the Tunisian beach attack could be in the mid to high 20s.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack: No 10 flags to be flown at half-mast
28 June 2015
From the section UK
The beach area where the attack happened reopened on Sunday
Downing Street's flags will be flown at half-mast in memory of the British victims of the Tunisian beach attack.
Officials fear the UK death toll from Friday's gun attack is likely to be in the mid to high 20s, out of a total of 38 victims.
Relatives of others still missing are anxiously awaiting any news of their loved ones.
Daniel Welch, who has not heard from his grandfather John since the attack, said "we can only expect the worst".
Simon Boon is another Briton desperately seeking information.
He says he saw his sister Allison Heathcote on news channels being stretchered off the beach on a sunbed, but had very little information from the Foreign Office, and had to rely on news websites and phoning hospitals in Sousse to find out what happened.
She had received two gunshot wounds, had undergone surgery and was now critical, he said.
"My brother-in-law - we still have no information. Originally the Foreign Office said he was with his wife but no hospitals have any records," he said.
"Nearly 48 hours on, we're none the wiser."
The Foreign Office flag was lowered to half-mast in memory of the victims of Friday's gun attack
A total of 38 people were killed in the attack at a beach resort in Sousse on Friday, and an unspecified number have been injured.
Other countries affected by the shooting carried out by 23-year-old Seifeddine Rezgui, who had links with Islamic State, include Belgium, Germany and Ukraine. Three people from Ireland were also killed.
The Foreign Office has updated its travel advice to warn that further terrorist attacks in Tunisia are possible, and urged people to be vigilant.
'Won't have had phones'
Speaking after she chaired a meeting of the government's emergency Cobra committee, Home Secretary Theresa May said Foreign Office staff were working round the clock in Tunisia and a 24-hour crisis centre was up and running in the UK.
She added that she had seen no evidence to indicate the beach was targeted because of the high number of British holidaymakers.
Armed police are now patrolling the beach where the gun attack took place
The home secretary suggested officials were having difficulty identifying the British victims as many were not carrying identification.
Ms May said many would not have had passports with them on the beach and some victims were being moved between hospitals in the country.
"What's important is that the information is absolutely 100% correct when it is given to a family," she told  BBC One's Andrew Marr Show.
"If you can imagine, because of the circumstances of the attack, people won't have had documents with them, they won't necessarily have had phones."
No British victims have been officially identified but the names of some have been confirmed by friends and family :
Carly Lovett, 24, a beauty blogger and photographer from Gainsborough in Lincolnshire who was first to be named
Sue Davey and her partner Scott Chalkley, both in their 40s, whose deaths were confirmed by their respective sons
Adrian Evans, his father, 78-year-old Patrick Evans and nephew Joel Richards, 19, from Wednesbury.
Bruce Wilkinson, 72, from Goole in Yorkshire
Lisa Burbidge, in her 60s, from Whickham, Gateshead
Claire Windass, 54, from Hull, was on the beach with her husband, who survived.
Carly Lovett, Adrian Evans and Joel Richards, left to right
Sue Davey and Scott Chalkley
Mr Welch, from Swindon in Wiltshire, says he is at a "bit of a loss" about his grandfather John Welch, 74, and his partner Eileen Swannack, 70.
He said the hardest thing was "not knowing".
John Welch and his partner Eileen Swannack
The family of Denis and Elaine Thwaites, from Blackpool, Lancashire, are appealing for information about their whereabouts.
The retired couple, aged 70 and 69, arrived in Sousse on Wednesday and had been staying at the Marhaba.
Their son-in-law Danny Clifford said news the family had received telling them Mr and Mrs Thwaites were in hospital was proved to be misinformation. "We are absolutely frantic," he added.
Denis and Elaine Thwaites
The beach area at Sousse where the attack took place has now reopened.
Rezgui, a Tunisian student who was not previously known to the authorities, began his attack on tourists at noon on Friday. He had been posing as a swimmer but carrying a rifle under a parasol.
Rezgui shot at people on the beach near the Imperial Marhaba and Bellevue hotels. He then entered one of the hotel lobbies, where explosives were also detonated.
He then walked through the streets of Sousse where he was reportedly chased by local Tunisians, firing shots at them.
It has also been reported that local builders threw rubble down at him from rooftops as he passed by in the street. The attack eventually ended when he was shot dead by police.
His parents, sister and close friends have been detained by the Tunisian authorities.
Were you in Sousse in Tunisia when the attacks happened? Do you have friends or family affected? Please share your stories.
You can share your experiences by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk . If you are happy to speak to a BBC journalist, please leave a contact number.
Or WhatsApp us on+44 7525 900971.
Or you can comment here:
Required field
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:01:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man charged with child stabbings</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-hampshire-33304117#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man is charged with attempted murder after two children are stabbed in Havant.</Description>
        <MainBody>Attempted murder charge over Havant child stabbings
28 June 2015
The attack happened close to the junction of Eastleigh Road and Southleigh Road
A man has been charged with the attempted murder of two children who were stabbed.
The boys, aged 12 and 13, were seriously injured in the attack in Havant, Hampshire, on Friday and remain in hospital.
Richard Michael Walsh, 43, of no fixed address, has been charged with two counts of attempted murder and one count of assault.
He will appear before magistrates in Portsmouth on Monday, police said.
The attack happened shortly before 15:00 BST at the junction of Southleigh Road and Eastleigh Road.
Hampshire Constabulary said both boys were in a serious but stable condition at Southampton General Hospital.
Police continued searching the area on Saturday
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:14:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hong Kong rejects Jetstar local bid</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281154#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hong Kong authorities reject an application by Qantas-backed Australian budget carrier Jetstar to set up local operations on the island.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hong Kong rejects Jetstar bid to start local airline
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Hong Kong has refused an application by Jetstar to set up local operations there
Hong Kong authorities have rejected an application by Qantas-backed Australian budget carrier Jetstar to set up a local airline, after nearly two years of deliberation.
The regulator said the bid did not comply with the laws of having its principal place of business in the Chinese territory.
The city's other carriers had also objected, it said.
Qantas said it would reconsider basing the low-cost carrier in Hong Kong.
The carrier is a three-way joint venture between Qantas Airways, China Eastern Airlines and Hong Kong investment firm Shun Tak Holdings.
"Jetstar Hong Kong cannot make its decisions independently from that of the two foreign shareholders," said the Air Transport Licensing Authority when handing down its decision.
It also said the city's other carriers, including Cathay Pacific and Dragon Airlines, had objected to Jetstar's application.
'Disappointing' decision
Qantas chief executive Alan Joyce said the decision was disappointing for shareholders as well as "for the travellers that Jetstar Hong Kong planned to serve".
"It's the travelling public who have lost out, because the message from this decision is that Hong Kong appears closed to fresh aviation investment even when it is majority locally-owned and controlled," he said in a statement on Friday.
He added that Hong Kong was going in the opposite direction of other aviation markets in Asia that were "opening up".
"Given the importance of aviation to global commerce, shutting the door to new competition can only serve the vested interests already installed in that market."
The airline, along with its partners, said it had not yet decided on whether to appeal the decision.
The joint venture was valued at $10m Australian dollars ($7.7m; 4.9m), according to Qantas.
Shares of Qantas were down 1.4% in Sydney in reaction to the news.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:05:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesco's sales decline in UK slows</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281464#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Tesco reports a slower rate of decline in sales at its UK stores as it tries to stem the flow of customers switching to discount chains.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tesco's sales decline in UK slows
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Tesco has reported a slower rate of decline in sales at its UK stores as it tries to stem the flow of customers switching to discount chains.
UK sales fell 1.3% for the three months to the end of May, compared with a 4% decline a year earlier.
The result beat analysts' forecasts of a fall of 1.6%-3%, and was better than the 1.7% fall reported in the fourth quarter of the last financial year.
Tesco chief Dave Lewis said it was a "step in the right direction".
"We are fixing the fundamentals of shopping to win back customers and relying less on short-term couponing," he said.
Shares in Tesco , the UK's largest supermarket chain, closed up 2.7% at 223.65p.
Including its international businesses, sales across the Tesco group dropped 1.3% in the quarter compared with a 3.4% dip a year ago.
Mr Lewis, who took the helm in September, is trying to revive the fortunes of Britain's largest supermarket after it reported the worst loss in its history in April.
Tesco reported a full-year pre-tax loss of 6.4bn, one of the largest in UK corporate history. About  4.7bn of the losses were the result of the fall in property value of its UK stores, 43 of which it said would close.
Analysis: Kamal Ahmed, BBC business editor
To understand why Tesco is slowly turning the corner, it is worth looking at the rather mundane world of the humble ham sandwich.
Tesco now offers 30% fewer sandwich lines after it realised that the wide range it was selling meant that customers often could not buy their favourite, simple sandwich, like, say, one with ham in it.
So, it reduced the range and increased the supply of the top sellers. Customers were happier that they could buy what they wanted and the number of transactions increased.
Read Kamal's blog in full
The trading update from Tesco comes ahead of an annual meeting of shareholders later.
Tim Bush of pension advisers Pirc told the BBC's Today programme that investors are likely to question payoffs for Tesco's former chief executive and finance director Philip Clarke and Laurie McIlwee, who shared 2.2m in severance pay after the supermarket said it was "contractually committed" to make the payments.
The pair, who left the firm last year, were awarded 1,217,000 and 970,880 respectively.
The payments were initially suspended while Tesco investigated last year's 263m accounting scandal.
"Things have stopped getting worse but they haven't yet started getting better," said Mr Bush.
Tesco said data from researcher Kantar Worldpanel had also shown that 180,000 more customers shopped at the supermarket in the 12 weeks to 24 May.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:07:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woolworths shares up on bid rumours</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-33281314#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Shares in Australia's biggest supermarket chain Woolworths rise as much as 5% on rumours it could be facing a takeover bid.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woolworths shares up 5% on takeover rumours
26 June 2015
From the section Business
Woolworths is Australia's largest supermarket chain but faces stiff competition from discount rivals
Shares in Australia's biggest supermarket chain Woolworths have risen as much as 5% in Sydney on media reports of a possible takeover.
The Australian newspaper reported fresh rumours that US private equity giant KKR had a bid that could be "almost ready" for consideration.
It would be one of the biggest deal in Australia's corporate history, the newspaper said.
The news comes amid turbulent times for the supermarket chain.
Woolworths' media team made no comment in relation to the takeover rumours, while KKR's media team in Australia was unavailable for comment.
Woolworths is Australia's largest supermarket chain but faces stiff competition from discount rivals
Turbulent times
Earlier this month, Woolworths announced that its chief executive, Grant O'Brien, was stepping down after nearly four years.
The firm also said it had plans to cut about 1,200 jobs. The changes are aimed at cutting millions of dollars in costs and improving sales after Woolworths' first-half profits fell.
The retail giant has been up against rivals such as Coles and Aldi and it has been trying to win more customers with improved stores and competitive pricing.
Woolworths recently cut its profit guidance for the year to June 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:16:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'England into 1966 and 1990 club'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33302568</Link>
        <Description>England's women have matched the men of 1966 and 1990 by reaching a World Cup semi-final, says boss Mark Sampson.</Description>
        <MainBody>England join 1966 &amp; 1990 club by reaching semis - Sampson
Women's World Cup semi-final
Date: Thursday, 2 July. Kick-off: 00:00 BST. Coverage: Live on BBC One, BBC Radio 5 live and BBC Sport website from 23:40 BST on 1 July
England's women have matched their male counterparts from 1966 and 1990 by reaching the semi-finals of the Women's World Cup, says manager Mark Sampson.
Women's World Cup Catch-Up: Lionesses make history in Canada
Sampson's side beat hosts Canada 2-1 to progress to the last four of the tournament for the first time.
The men's team of 1966 won the World Cup, while the 1990 side were beaten at the semi-final stage.
"They are history-makers again, the third ever England team to get to a semi-final," said Sampson.
"We now join the 1966 and the 1990 club, and I'm very proud of the whole group."
'We have reached new levels'
Sampson described the atmosphere as like a "cauldron" against host nation Canada at the BC Place Stadium in Vancouver.
His side took the lead through a Jodie Taylor shot and Lucy Bronze header as they scored two goals in three minutes.
England goalkeeper Karen Bardsley's fumble allowed Christine Sinclair to pull one back for Canada but they failed to engineer an equaliser as a resolute England stood firm.
"What a show of resilience and character from the team," added Sampson.
"They have shown a desire I've never seen from an England team before to hang on in there and get us through to the next round.
"We didn't play much football and Canada were outstanding. But this team just won't give in. We had to get to levels we have never been to before."
'Bring them on'
Taylor tearful after 'amazing' England win
England will now play holders Japan in the semi-final in a game that will be live on BBC One from 23:40 BST on Wednesday, 1 July.
"We got ourselves through and I could not be prouder," said Sampson. "Every player ran through brick walls for this team. I don't know where this team found their energy.
"It was a do-or-die game. Canada gave everything, England gave everything and we came out on top."
Japan are the reigning champions, beating the USA in the final in 2011, although England did beat them in a group game in that tournament in Germany.
"Bring them on," said Sampson.
England had 37.3% possession against Canada but still came out on top
'History-making game'
England captain Steph Houghton hopes the win will help the women's game in England.
"It was 55,000 people inside the stadium against 23 players and staff," she said. "We fought for the shirt to the very end.
"It is a massive thing for English football. The women's game is changing and we knew this was a history-making game.
"We want to inspire a nation, inspire young girls to go and play football. We hope they were allowed to stay up and watch us!"
'Can't believe it ended like this'
Canada manager John Herdman is English and was tipped to take the England job before Mark Sampson was appointed 18 months ago.
Women's World Cup 2015: Canada's John Herdman apologies to nation
"We've given you our best but it just wasn't good enough," he told Canadians in an emotional on-pitch interview. "We wanted to go all the way.
"We are absolutely gutted. We made mistakes, they caught us on a set-play and an error. I don't think anyone hid from the responsibility.
"I want to thank everyone who supported us. I can't believe it ended like this."
Reaction to England's win
William, Duke of Cambridge and president of the Football Association: I'm thrilled. This team is making history and I can't wait to see them in action against Japan. The Lionesses are doing their country proud."
England men's captain Wayne Rooney: "England women doing the country proud. Huge congratulations on reaching the semi-finals."
The last England team to reach a World Cup semi-final was Sir Bobby Robson's squad of 1990
Actor Danny Dyer: "Desire....... gentleman.... it's called Belief &amp; Desire. Love it."
Former England forward Sue Smith: "We call Mark Sampson the tinkerman and all of his tactics have been spot on. England need to keep believing.
"There is no reason why they can't go on and beat Japan. Yes, they are a fantastic team and play unbelievable football but so can England now."
Former England captain Faye White: "Who said that England were the weakest team left in the competition at the quarter-final stage???? Err I think not!"
Karen Carney tweeted a picture from the England dressing room after the win over Canada
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:40:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter told to stand by resignation</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/33303066</Link>
        <Description>Sepp Blatter is urged to stick by his decision to quit as Fifa president amid rumours he is considering re-election.</Description>
        <MainBody>print
Sepp Blatter urged to stand by Fifa resignation decision
Sepp Blatter has been urged to stick by his decision to quit as president of world football's governing body, Fifa.
Blatter announced on 2 June that he would step down at an extraordinary congress between December and March.
However, on Thursday the 79-year-old said he had not resigned and was thought to be considering re-election.
"The times of flirting with the power are definitely gone," said Domenico Scala, the independent chairman of Fifa's audit and compliance committee.
"I call on all concerned - including Mr Blatter - to endorse in the interest of the reforms unequivocally the announced changing of the guard at the top of Fifa."
Two criminal investigations into alleged Fifa corruption began in the week that Blatter was elected for a fifth term, with seven Fifa officials arrested on charges of receiving bribes.
Four days after his re-election, Blatter - who is reportedly under investigation in the United States - said: "While I have a mandate from the membership of Fifa, I do not feel that I have a mandate from the entire world of football.
"Therefore, I have decided to lay down my mandate at an extraordinary elective congress. I will continue to exercise my functions as Fifa president until that election."
However, Blatter did not use the words 'resign' or 'resignation'. He did add, however, that the election would be for his "successor" and said: "I shall not be a candidate."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:12:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Injured Ferrer out of Wimbledon</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/tennis/33304720</Link>
        <Description>Eighth seed David Ferrer pulls out of Wimbledon with an elbow injury, giving Britain's James Ward a new opponent.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wimbledon 2015: David Ferrer withdraws with elbow injury
Wimbledon 2015
Venue: All England Club Dates: 29 June - 12 July
Play: From 11:30 on outside courts and 13:00 on Centre Court and Court One
BBC coverage: across BBC TV, radio and online starts on 29 June with 153 hours of tennis scheduled and up to 15 live streams available.
Read more: BBC coverage bigger than ever and TV and radio schedules.
Eighth seed David Ferrer has pulled out of Wimbledon with an elbow injury.
He was set to play Britain's James Ward, 28, in the first round, but will be replaced by a lucky loser from qualifying, Italy's Luca Vanni.
World number seven Ferrer, 33, reached the quarter-finals at SW19 in 2013.
His exit opens up the draw for Rafael Nadal, who could have faced his fellow Spaniard in the fourth round, with a potential quarter-final against Britain's Andy Murray for the winner.
Wimbledon begins on Monday, with defending men's champion Novak Djokovic opening play on Centre Court against Germany's Philipp Kohlschreiber at 13:00 BST.
More from BBC Sport's Wimbledon coverage
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:26:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dalai Lama praises Glastonbury 'joy'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33303900#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Dalai Lama appears at the Glastonbury Festival, praising it as "a festival of people, not governments or politicians".</Description>
        <MainBody>Dalai Lama praises Glastonbury 'joy'
By Ian Youngs Entertainment reporter, Glastonbury festival
28 June 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
The Dalai Lama has made an appearance at the Glastonbury Festival, praising it as "a festival of people, not governments or politicians".
The exiled Tibetan spiritual leader gave a talk in the Peace Garden, where the crowd sang happy birthday in advance of his 80th birthday on 6 July.
He arrived using a Glastonbury t-shirt to cover his head as rain soaked the festival site.
"I see old and young, everybody full of joy," he said.
The Dalai Lama used a festival t-shirt to shelter from the rain
"While you are here, enjoy the joyfulness here. But you should remember on this same planet are human beings being killed by human beings."
He mentioned conflicts in Iraq, Syria and Nigeria as he delivered a message of peace and respect.
He is also expected to appear on the festival's Pyramid stage later.
If he does, he will join a Sunday line-up that also features The Who, Alt-J and Patti Smith.
Irish singer Hozier kicked off proceedings, drawing a huge crowd hoping to hear his signature hit, Take Me To Church.
Other artists due to play on Sunday include The Chemical Brothers, Ryan Adams and Charli XCX; while Lionel Richie takes the mid-afternoon "legends" slot on the main stage - following in the footsteps of the likes of Johnny Cash and Dolly Parton.
The main stage was headlined by US rapper Kanye West on Saturday, to a mixed response .
He appeared alone under a vast, mobile lighting rig consisting of hundreds of bright white lights; playing hits including Stronger, Power, Gold Digger and, appropriately, All Of The Lights.
At the end of the set, he declared himself "the greatest living rock star on the planet," prompting much derision on social media.
"I really do think he's a rock star," pop star Charli XCX told the BBC. "I liked his minimal approach and when you watch that set, it's hit after hit after hit."
One person who missed West's performance was festival founder Michael Eavis.
"I'm not a fan of that kind of music," he said. "Although I chose Jay-Z originally of course."
Jay-Z was the festival's first hip-hop headliner in 2008. But since then, Eavis has handed over responsibility for the line-up to his daughter Emily.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:37:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crosby: Joni Mitchell unable to speak</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33303234#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Musician David Crosby says his friend Joni Mitchell is still unable to speak after being found unconscious in her home two months ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>David Crosby: Joni Mitchell unable to speak after aneurysm
28 June 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Mitchell is known for songs like Big Yellow Taxi and Case of You
Joni Mitchell is still unable to speak after being found unconscious in her home in March, according to her friend David Crosby.
Crosby said the singer-songwriter had suffered a brain aneurysm and faced a long struggle.
"She is home, she is in care, she is recovering," he told Huffington Post . "How much she's going to come back, and when, I don't know."
We're all holding our breath and thinking of goodbye
David Crosby, Singer-songwriter
There has been no official confirmation of Mitchell's condition.
The 71-year-old was found unconscious in her Los Angeles home on 31 March and taken to hospital.
A statement released on her website several days later said the singer was "resting comfortably" and continued to "improve and get stronger each day".
Her representatives later denied Mitchell was in a coma , saying "she's alert, and she has her full senses".
Crosby produced Mitchell's debut album, Song to a Seagull
"She took a terrible hit," said Crosby on Saturday. "She had an aneurysm, and nobody found her for a while. And she's going to have to struggle back from it the way you struggle back from a traumatic brain injury.
"To my knowledge, she is not speaking yet."
Crosby and Mitchell dated in 1967, when he was still a member of the Byrds. They have remained close friends ever since.
"She's a tough girl and very smart," he said. "I love her. She's probably the best of us  probably the greatest living singer-songwriter.
"[But] I think we're all holding our breath and thinking of goodbye, you know? And hoping it's gonna turn out ok."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:32:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swift and friends leave mark on park</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-33303397#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Taylor Swift is joined on stage by Cara Delevigne, Serena Williams and Kendall Jenner as she wraps up her UK tour.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taylor Swift and friends leave their mark on Hyde Park
By Neil Smith Entertainment reporter
28 June 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Swift (centre) was joined onstage by Cara Delevingne, Kendall Jenner, Martha Hunt. Karlie Kloss, Serena Williams and GiGi Hadid
The star's 18-song set lasted almost two hours
Taylor Swift signed off the UK leg of her world tour in style with an open-air show featuring one of Britain's top models.
Cara Delevigne waved a Union Jack flag as she joined the singer on stage before a 65,000-strong crowd at London's Hyde Park.
Tennis champion Serena Williams and model Kendall Jenner also appeared in a catwalk-themed section of Swift's set.
The pop star said she would "remember this night for the rest of [her] life".
"I remember seven years ago when I played my first UK show," she said. "King's College [in London] had sold out and there were a few hundred people.
"I was surprised that a few hundred people would come to see me perform and now I'm looking at 65,000 people in Hyde Park.
"This is one of those nights where I'm aware I'm going to be taking mental snapshots so I can remember this night for the rest of my life," the singer continued.
The speech was one of several extended confessionals from a performer whose closeness to her fans became literal during a section where a giant rotating bridge suspended her above the heads of her adoring acolytes.
Swift played guitar and keyboards while travelling above her audience
Swift's fans - nicknamed "Swifties" - were caught on the hop on Saturday when their idol began her gig 15 minutes earlier than scheduled.
Wearing a green sequinned jacket and purple skirt, she opened her set with Welcome to New York, a trademark anthem of emphatic self-assertion.
Supported by 12 male dancers, four female backing singers and a five-man band, the concert featured 17 more songs and seven additional costume changes in the two-hour set.
Sartorial highlights included a figure-hugging black leather catsuit, a summery pink frock lit by LED lights and a silver gown encrusted with crystals.
Props, meanwhile, included an ornate silver piano, a golf club - wielded menacingly as she sang Blank Space, a self-parodying paean to her media portrayal as a serial dater - and illuminated umbrellas used in a Singin' In The Rain-style "brolly ballet".
The set-list was largely drawn from Swift's current smash hit album 1989
Swift's decision to distance herself from her country past was illustrated by a setlist dominated by songs from her latest release, the pop-leaning 1989.
Yet she found time to reinvent some of her older material, refashioning Love Story as a 1980s-style synth track and turning We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together into a noisy rock stomp with one booted foot in Glastonbury.
Filmed inserts showed Lena Dunham, Delevigne and others extolling the singer's virtues and Swift herself cradling her two cats, the quirkily named Dr Meredith Grey and Detective Olivia Benson.
The evening ended with Shake It Off, a defiantly upbeat tune which saw "Tay Tay" back on her bridge in a purple crop top and miniskirt.
It was a triumphant climax to an eventful week that began with Swift exhorting tech giant Apple to rethink the artist payment policy of its new music streaming service.
The 25-year-old plays two concerts in Dublin next week before returning to North America to continue her 1989 tour, named after her latest album as well as the year of her birth.
Ellie Goulding and John Newman also performed in Hyde Park on Saturday as part of the British Summer Time series of day-long mini-festivals.
SETLIST
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:48:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Tunisia survivor: 'Bullet hit my arm'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33291623#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man who survived a gun attack on a popular tourist beach in Tunisia speaks of the moment two gunmen struck.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Tunisia attack: British survivor hit by bullet
26 June 2015 Last updated at 17:48 BST
A man who survived a gun attack on a popular tourist beach in Tunisia has spoken of the moment two gunmen struck.
He described how they began firing on people on the beach in Sousse, leaving dozens dead.
Officials say one gunman has been shot dead and another is being pursued.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:38:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: 'Ball of flame' injures hundreds in Taiwan</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-33302243#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>More than 500 people were injured when fire ripped through crowds at a party at an amusement park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Taiwan water park explosion injures hundreds
28 June 2015 Last updated at 09:38 BST
More than 500 people were injured when fire ripped through crowds at a party at an amusement park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei.
Saturday's incident at the Formosa Water Park is believed to have happened when a coloured powder ignited after being discharged onto the crowd.
Footage showed people panicking and screaming. Inflatable water toys were used as stretchers.
Cindy Sui reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:51:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Greek parliament backs bailout vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33302245#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Greeks will vote next Sunday on the country's bailout programme after a late night sitting of parliament backed plans put forward on Saturday by the Prime Minister, Alexis Tsipras.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Greece debt crisis: Parliament backs PM's referendum plan
28 June 2015 Last updated at 05:51 BST
Greeks will vote next Sunday on the country's bailout programme after a late-night sitting of parliament backed plans put forward by Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras.
Eurozone partners have criticised to Greece's referendum announcement, and rejected its request to extend the bailout programme beyond 30 June.
There are concerns Greece could default on a 1.6bn (1.1bn) repayment to the IMF on that day.
Elaine Jung reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:39:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Kuwait mosque attack: Arrests made</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33302244#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Several people have been arrested on suspicion of involvement with the bombing of a Shia mosque that killed 27 people in Kuwait City.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Kuwait Shia mosque attack: Several arrests made
28 June 2015 Last updated at 02:39 BST
Several people have been arrested on suspicion of involvement with the bombing of a Shia mosque that killed 27 people in Kuwait City.
More than 200 people were injured in the attack, which took place during Friday prayers.
Mass funerals have been held, and the country observed an official day of mourning for those killed in what was the bloodiest ever attack on Shia Muslims in the country.
Murad Batal Shishani reports from Kuwait City.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:05:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Blue targets reduce sleeping sickness</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-33274658#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The lure of a bright blue target is helping to reduce numbers of tsetse flies which pass on the parasite responsible for sleeping sickness.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Tangled up in blue: A sticky end to sleeping sickness
28 June 2015 Last updated at 00:05 BST
The lure of a bright blue target is tempting a killer insect towards its own demise - thanks to scientists working in Uganda.
Up to 60 million people in sub-Saharan Africa are at risk of catching sleeping sickness which is caused by a parasite passed on by biting tsetse flies.
The symptoms include fatigue and swollen joints. Left untreated it is usually fatal.
But as Maryam Abdalla reports from Arua in northern Uganda, British researchers are hoping that their blue targets could spell the end of this deadly disease.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:11:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Armenians dance at electricity protest</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-33300190#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of Armenians continue their round-the-clock protest in the capital Yerevan against rising electricity tariffs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Armenians dance at round-the-clock electricity protest
27 June 2015 Last updated at 20:11 BST
Hundreds of Armenians continue their round-the-clock protest in the capital Yerevan against rising electricity tariffs.
The protest has become known on social media as Electric Yerevan and is being driven by young Armenians who want to put an end to years of corruption in their country.
The protesters told the BBC's Rayhan Demytrie that they were not there to replicate the protests in Kiev that led to the uprising in Ukraine.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:48:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Paradise lost? Greek islands' tourism fears</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33297662#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Residents on the Greek islands are concerned that government plans to end their favourable tax rate would damage tourism, as the BBC's James Reynolds reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Paradise lost? Greek islands fear tourism decline
27 June 2015 Last updated at 10:48 BST
Residents on the Greek islands are concerned that government plans to end their favourable tax rate would damage tourism.
The proposals form part of Greece's bailout deal with its foreign creditors.
Greece has to make a 1.5bn ($1.7bn; 1.06bn) IMF debt repayment on 30 June. If Greece defaults, it could exit the eurozone, with possible repercussions for the rest of Europe and the world economy.
The BBC's James Reynolds reports from Andros in Greece.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 02:04:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Device helps women avoid dirty toilets</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-33279396#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An Indian entrepreneur has come up with a female urination device that helps women stand and pee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
'Pee-Buddy' helps women in India avoid dirty toilets
27 June 2015 Last updated at 00:04 BST
Unhygienic toilets are one of the most common causes of Urinary Tract Infection or UTI amongst women in India.
But now an entrepreneur has come up with a female urination device that helps women stand and pee.
The BBC's Shalu Yadav hit the streets of Delhi to find out what women do to avoid dirty toilets.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:07:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The day my dog was cooked for dinner</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33283694#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The day my dog was cooked for dinner</Description>
        <MainBody>The day my dog was cooked for dinner
By Juliana Liu Hong Kong correspondent, BBC News
28 June 2015
From the section Magazine
Dogs for sale at the Yulin at the dog-meat festival
This week about 10,000 dogs and a number of cats were killed at an annual dog-meat festival in south-western China, to celebrate the longest day of the year. For the BBC's Juliana Liu it was a reminder of one of the most traumatic days of her childhood, in the Chinese city of Changsha.
When I was three years old, after months of begging, my parents finally gave in to my pleas for a puppy.
The day that my uncle, a lorry driver, brought me a fuzzy yellow mongrel from my grandmother's mountainous, faraway home was the happiest of my young life.
I named him "Doggie", and we immediately became inseparable.
As an only child born in 1979 at the beginning of China's one-child policy, I had always been alone, and Doggie became my best friend. He loved running around outside our one-room flat, gobbling up left-over rice and snuggling near the coal fire.
But these halcyon days did not last. After just one winter, my parents told me Doggie had to go.
In Chinese cities in the early 1980s owning a pet was considered highly undesirable, bourgeois behaviour. None of my neighbours had one. It was also not entirely legal. There was no access to animal vaccines or vets, so pets could pose a public health risk.
One day, my mother announced we were going shopping - and when we returned a few hours later Doggie was no more. He had been strung up by the legs in our communal yard, and was soon turned into a stew, complete with herbs and hard-boiled eggs.
No-one paid any attention to my tears. I heard the neighbours say I would soon forget the whole thing.
They, on the other hand, were in a celebratory mood. In the years before China's economic boom, when some food was still rationed, it was rare to have the chance to feast on a whole animal.
I refused to eat the stew - and I have never eaten dog in my life.
Men eating dog at the Yulin dog-meat festival, June 2015  Reuters
In China, the tradition of dog-eating goes back far beyond written history.
Along with pigs, oxen, goats, horses and fowl, dogs are one of the six animals domesticated during the Stone Age.
On the other hand, it is not the kind of thing that is eaten every day. It is a speciality meat, commonly believed to confer strength, vigour and virility on the eater.
How dog is eaten
Chinese food expert Fuchsia Dunlop writes:
Judging by the sporadic waves of outrage about dog-eating in China, you might think it was one of the pillars of the Chinese diet. Actually, however, the consumption of dog meat is extremely marginal: it's seldom seen in markets and on restaurant menus, and most Chinese people eat it rarely, if at all.
Dogs, like pigs, have been reared for their meat in China since the Neolithic age, but in modern times their flesh is regarded as a delicacy in just a few areas, such as Hunan and Guizhou. Even in these places, it tends to be eaten only occasionally, and in certain seasons. According to traditional Chinese medicine, dog is a "heating" meat which can offer a useful energy boost in midwinter, but is best avoided after the lunar new year.
In culinary terms, dog meat is normally blanched or soaked before cooking to dispel the earthier, heavier aspects of its flavour. It is then, typically, made into slow-cooked soups and stews seasoned with ginger, spring onion, rice wine and spices, although it may also be roasted, or served cold as an appetiser. The tender meat of puppies is favoured over that of older dogs.
In the course of many years of studying Chinese cuisine, I've only eaten dog meat on a handful of occasions. The first time, it reminded me of pork; the second, in a fiendishly spicy Hunanese stew, it recalled the taste of lamb.
About 716 million pigs are slaughtered in the country every year, and 48 million cattle. The number of dogs slaughtered is far lower - one animal rights group puts the figure at about 10 million.
But where do these dogs come from? According to some researchers, many are pets - like Doggie, except they have been stolen from their owners.
As dogs were arriving for the dog-meat festival at Yulin in Guangxi province this week, Peter Li of Humane Society International saw no animals with  quarantine inspection certificates to indicate they had been farmed.
"All of them can be suspected to be stolen urban pets, rural guard dogs and stray dogs and cats," he says.
Dogs for sale at a market in Yulin  AFP
A four-year inquiry into the dog-meat industry by Animals Asia also concluded that most dogs eaten in China are stolen.
"During the entire investigation, we found no evidence of any large-scale breeding facilities, where 100-plus dogs were bred and raised," says the report published earlier this month.
"The difficulty of large-scale breeding of dogs for food and the greed for profit give rise to stealing, snatching from the streets and even poisoning of dogs."
But Li says there is mounting pressure on Chinese authorities to take action against the eating of pets - and that society is turning against the idea of eating dog altogether.
There were far fewer stalls selling dog and cat meat at the Yulin festival this year than in 2014, he says.
"The overall attitude is against dog eating. China has 130 million dogs, of which 27 million are urban pets. That's a big number of pet owners.
"The younger generation, born in the 1990s, is not tolerant of animal cruelty."
A protester shouts slogans condemning the slaughter of dogs at the Yulin festival  AFP
Activists gave a dog a basket with the message "Child for sale"  AFP
In 2014, animal rights activists intercepted 18 lorries carrying dogs intended for eating, resulting in the rescue of some 8,000 animals, he says.
The Chinese media often carries stories of such rescues, in which activists force vehicles to stop and pool money to purchase the animals.
He dates the rise of animal protection activism in China to 2011, the same year when, for the first time ever, more people lived in cities than the countryside.
City dwellers, he says, view dogs and cats more as pets, rather than as working animals - guard dogs, for example - or sources of meat.
In May, on a visit to Shanghai, I saw a sight that delighted me.
While strolling on the Bund, I stopped a young tourist named Yang Yang who was carrying her tiny, fox-like dog in a sling on her chest, the way I normally carry my human baby.
"Oh, this way I can take him into restaurants and on airplanes," she explained.  "Otherwise, he wouldn't be allowed in with me. Where I go, he goes."
All three of us posed for a photo in front of Shanghai's iconic skyline.
How I wish more people had taken this attitude three decades ago.
My parents, now utterly embarrassed about having allowed my pet to be cooked, generally avoid the topic entirely.
But when I was five years old, my father left China to study abroad and the very first gift he sent me was a fuzzy, yellowish stuffed puppy.
I named him Doggie.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:10:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The boy and the helicopter</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-33287071#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The gadget that left a nine-year-old boy speechless</Description>
        <MainBody>28 June 2015
From the section Magazine
For the past 10 years I have been visiting White Horse Village in south-west China, reporting on its transformation from a farming community into a modern city - it's a microcosm of China's epic-scale urbanisation. Xiao Zhang's family has embraced the change, and as my last visit came ended, I took her children shopping in one of the new superstores.
The tiny nine-year-old and I have been staring at stuffed toys and superheroes for a very long time. "Peipei," I say. "You've got 300 yuan. You can get whatever you want. Now what is it you want?" He just keeps smiling up at me helplessly, hopping from one sparrow leg to the other.
It's already been a long day, which started at 5am when the BBC's White Horse Village crew stumbled from our hotel beds and straggled across the new city square to get ready for a live interview on Newsnight. The time difference between the UK and China is no friend to us.
We're not the earliest people on the square though. The pavement on the main road is thickening with farmers from the surrounding hill villages, laying out their vegetables for keen inspection by the city people who were farmers themselves only five minutes ago. The sky is turning pewter grey behind soaring black mountain ridges.
In the old days, and the old days here are only 10 years old there was only farming in this valley. The young people of White Horse Village all turned their backs on it to join the human tide surging to the coast in search of paid work in factories and construction sites. They left behind a rustling green patchwork of rice and maize, a landscape dotted with their parents and grandparents in straw hats bent under heavy wooden carrying poles.
More from White Horse Village
Xiao Zhang spent her childhood working in the fields, feeding the family's pigs. The destruction of rural China became, for her, a liberation - and an opportunity. This is the story of how her life changed as much as her country.
The village and the girl
Those generations are still up on the hill but now the grandson is in a subterranean superstore, on plastic floor tiles under neon lights, dazzled by indecision when his fairy godmother from a faraway land rolls into town and hands him more money than he has ever seen in his life.
Find out more
Listen to From Our Own Correspondent for insight and analysis from BBC journalists, correspondents and writers from around the world
Broadcast on Radio 4 on Thursdays at 11:00 BST and Saturdays at 11:30 and on the BBC World Service
Download the programme
I don't want you to think this is a lot of money. It's the equivalent of 30 (almost $50), an amount many of China's so called little emperors would shrug at. But Peipei is not the pampered child of a rich coastal city. Sailing down the escalator into the store his mother has just reminded me that she has never bought toys for him or his sister. She regards toys as a waste of money and a distraction from the serious business of study.
A rice and pig farmer for most of her own life, Xiao Zhang was pulled out of school at the age of 11 to help in the family fields and she is determined that her children will have a different destiny in the new China, one which includes university and white-collar jobs. But she is proud of her own job in the new city. She is chief cleaner at the courthouse.
I don't want to be talking about school and jobs right now though, so I send Xiao Zhang away, saying the children and I can manage our shopping perfectly well without her. No offence is meant and none is taken. After 10 years spent filming and recording the story of the epic transformation from village to city, everyone here is used to my eccentricities.
Yangyang at school
With her mother out of the way, 11-year-old Yangyang becomes immediately purposeful. She chooses a badminton set, a table tennis set and two studious books. She carefully counts the money left over and spends the last of it on pens and notebooks. Her shopping takes perhaps five minutes.
But Peipei still can't choose. We trail from store to store, I make suggestions, the shop assistants make suggestions but after an hour we have nothing in the trolley. I feel disappointed but I'm conscious of time. We're all due at a celebration dinner in a couple of hours. And I promised to have Peipei and Yangyang back at the courthouse in time to do their homework beforehand.
I suppose you can save the money and spend it when you see something you do like, I suggest. But he shakes his head fiercely and Yangyang says, "No, mum will just take it away."
Eventually it dawns on me what the problem is. Peipei keeps drifting along the shelves but drifting back to one spot to stand wordlessly in front of a remote-controlled helicopter. If I hadn't been up at 5am I might have noticed it sooner. I've known this boy his entire life and it's now perfectly clear to me that he wants that helicopter but can't say so because he knows his parents will disapprove.
Peipei with his mother and father
"Look Peipei," I say, "we don't know when I'm going to be here again. So let's just do this. We'll say I insisted on the helicopter." The grin that meets this suggestion is all the answer I need. He clutches the big helicopter box to his chest.
We glide back up an escalator into the daylight, and Xiao Zhang whisks the children off on the new family scooter to do their homework before the goodbye dinner. That dinner is another story in its own right and there's no time to tell it here.
Suffice it to say that the stars of our White Horse Village 10-year epic are there including the disgraced village Communist Party secretary with his wife, children and grandchildren, Mr Jin who is still wondering where he's going to be buried in the new city, and of course Xiao Zhang and her parents and children.
There are emotional toasts, a few tears, a lot of laughter and the maiden flight of Peipei's helicopter. And as we stand under the pillars of the Grand Emperor Hotel waving off the White Horse Village cast to their city apartments, I reflect that every word I'd just said in my toast was true. Over a decade, these people have been unfailingly kind and patient, not to mention courageous in ignoring government pressure and trusting us with their story. I will miss each and every one of them.
How to listen to From Our Own Correspondent :
BBC Radio 4: Thursdays at 11:00 BST and Saturdays at 11:30. Listen online or download the podcast .
BBC World Service: At weekends - see World Service programme schedule or listen online .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:30:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Iran nuclear deal be Hassan Rouhani's legacy?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-33268240#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Will a nuclear deal in Vienna be the Iranian president's legacy?</Description>
        <MainBody>Will Iran nuclear deal be Hassan Rouhani's legacy?
By Dr Massoumeh Torfeh Research Associate, LSE &amp; Soas
28 June 2015
From the section Middle East
President Hassan Rouhani promised Iranians he would get sanctions lifted
As international talks over Iran's nuclear programme come down to the wire, the success or failure to strike a deal could be make or break for President Hassan Rouhani.
After his election in 2013, the new president - seen as a moderate abroad - promised to work to lift years of sanctions which have crippled the economy and made life ever-harder for average Iranians.
Iranian hardliners have opposed concessions and compromise over Iran's "national right" to nuclear energy, but the balance so far appears to be heavily in favour of President Rouhani and his team of negotiators.
In the end, the Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has the final say.
He has publicly backed the negotiating team and in recent days provided them with more flexibility over some aspects of the negotiation while at the same time hardening his stance towards the West.
All UN and US "economic, financial and banking" sanctions must be lifted "immediately" a deal is signed - and the remaining  sanctions lifted "within reasonable time intervals", Ayatollah Khamenei said in a speech on Tuesday. He made no mention of EU sanctions.
The hardliners have been at pains for more than a year-and-a-half to refrain from any public criticism of the government while the nuclear talks were in progress.
The instructions to desist came from the Supreme Leader himself, who has called on all officials to ensure a united front was conveyed until the 30 June deadline.
Double-edged remarks from Ayatollah Khamenei, such as "I am neither for nor against the deal", have kept both the pro- and anti-camp in Iran satisfied.
The Supreme Leader has juxtaposed his position in several speeches, not only to survive a possible negative outcome but also to ensure he does not antagonise the powerful Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corp (IRGC).
The IRGC has never been too convinced by the talks, except for the obvious benefits of lifting sanctions which have affected its multi-billion dollar business empire, though it has given the negotiators its cautious backing.
Parliamentary intrigue
Over the past few months there have been intensive debates inside the conservative-dominated parliament between the two camps.
Iran's powerful Revolutionary Guards Corps has given cautious backing to the talks
Most of the heated discussions have been behind closed doors, but some of it has slipped out on social media and the wider press.
"The closer we get to the signing of the deal," said reformist Sharq newspaper on Monday, "the bigger becomes the wave of attacks, and insults on the government of Hassan Rouhani."
Another article blamed former President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad's camp for "scheming for months" to ruin the prospects of success in the deal for Iran.
The main voice of opposition in parliament is the faction that supports Mr Ahmadinejad, Mr Rouhani's predecessor.
In moves not dissimilar to the Republicans in the US Senate, the faction known as Paidary (persistence) Front, has tabled several motions to try to give parliament the power to challenge a final deal.
None has been successful, and its latest bill was amended in such a way as to take away the power of veto from parliament and put it in the hands of the Supreme National Security Council (SNSC), the top decision-making body in Iran and loyal to the Supreme Leader.
It is chaired by President Rouhani and includes parliamentary speaker Ali Larijani and his brother Sadeq Larijani, who heads the judiciary.
Its members are mainly hand-picked by Ayatollah Khamenei and also include the chiefs of the army and the IRGC, Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and a handful of other ministers.
That is why despite the verbal battles over the past few months, once the deal is sealed by the Supreme Leader there is little anyone can do to oppose it.
Risk of failure
The room for Iran's nuclear team to manoeuvre is limited. The oversight by SNSC would ensure that all requirements laid down by the Supreme Leader and the IRGC are met.
Ayatollah Khamenei has made it clear he will not accept any inspection of military sites (a key demand of the so-called P5+1 interlocutors), backing the requirement laid out by the IRGC.
Ayatollah Khamenei will have the final say over whether to accept or reject a nuclear deal
Despite the red lines, President Rouhani and his negotiators are protected by the Supreme Leader's endorsement.
The danger, however, would be if the deal failed or faced serious obstacles after the 30 June deadline.
In that case, although Ayatollah Khamenei may continue to call for calm, the IRGC, and the conservatives, angered at the failure to lift sanctions, would push the Supreme Leader to take a harder line, switching their substantive majority in parliament against the president, making it difficult for him to increase the reformist share of seats in the next parliamentary election due in February.
The president may continue to wield support from the public at large, but the machinations of those dominant groups are likely to make his position untenable for the next presidential elections due in June 2017.
It is with a view of those elections that not only the president but also all parliamentary factions are leaving themselves room for jockeying.
Dr Massoumeh Torfeh is a research associate at the London School of Economics (LSE) and School of Oriental and African Studies (Soas), specialising in the politics of Iran, Afghanistan and central Asia. Formerly she was the UN director of strategic communications in Afghanistan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:27:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Does the future of wildlife lie in captivity?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-33286942#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Will wild animals only be safe in captivity?</Description>
        <MainBody>From the section Science &amp; Environment
Look ahead towards the middle of the century and much-loved animals such as lemurs, rhinos and tigers will only survive in some form of captivity.
And extinction will be even more of a threat than it is now.
An overly bleak and pessimistic view? Maybe.
But after reporting on the state of wildlife in Madagascar this past week , I cannot see how many of the most iconic creatures will be able to roam in their natural habitats for much longer.
I don't mean a future necessarily confined to zoos, but one in which lives are led in special zones guarded by fences and patrols and CCTV. Free, but only up to a point.
The reasons are obvious: growing populations and the thirst for resources and the black market for animals all mean that humans and animals are increasingly competing for territory and survival. And the animals usually lose.
As we picked our way through the remaining pockets of forest in Madagascar, I heard that less than 10% of the original cover is left.
And those remaining stretches of jungle - the sole habitats for the country's famous lemurs - are under constant attack as local people seek to create farmland or hunt for fresh meat.
VIP protection
I was reminded of filming in a tiger reserve in Thailand a few years ago .
To try to keep about 60 tigers relatively safe from poachers, a small army of 200 rangers was on constant patrol.
Remote cameras, satellite monitoring and intelligence gathering were essential weapons against raiders with AK47s and poisoned bait encouraged by high prices for tiger parts in China.
And, earlier this year, I saw the pitiful sight of one of the last five of a particular species of rhino, the northern white - brought to the verge of extinction by the brutal market for rhino horn.  The final survivors need VIP protection.
Question of attitudes
In Madagascar's case, political instability that followed a coup adds to the scourge of corruption and well-organised gangs of animal traffickers - and it's not hard to predict that the last pockets of forest will keep shrinking and the numbers of lemurs will keep falling.
Even more challenging is a question of attitudes. For many in the rich West, it's a no-brainer that precious wildlife should be given a priority. Some of the most popular charities were set up to help animals. And wildlife wins royal support too.
But what about views in a destitute village on the edge of one of Madagascar's forests where families earn less than the equivalent of $2 (1.27) a day?
No surprise, but conservationists are not always welcome.
In the Maromizaha protected area, which is home to several different species of lemurs, we heard of occasional hostility towards people working to save the animals.
In an election, a village chief actively campaigned on a promise that more farmland could be claimed from the forest. And local conservation workers have received threatening phone calls and even death threats.
Financial temptation
In the Baly Bay National Park, which lies in a remote corner of the north-west of the country, the Durrell Wildlife Conservation Trust has endured several highly suspicious incidents while working to save the critically endangered ploughshare tortoise.
Once, a dead ploughshare tortoise was dumped on the charity's doorstep, a Godfather-like threat not to intervene in the highly lucrative black market for tortoises.
The ploughshare tortoise is only found in Madagascar
And last December, just as staff were busy with a day-long celebration of progress, a column of smoke was spotted rising from the core area of the park.
The project's entire operation was nearly engulfed in flames. Forest fires do happen naturally but this one may well have been deliberate. Conservation can create enemies.
For some local people, the financial prize of stealing tortoises is too large to be resisted. Others look forward to the development and jobs that may come with plans by a Chinese firm for a huge new iron ore mine nearby - and the conservationists may be seen as an obstacle.
So, in conservation circles, the latest thinking is that the only plausible way forward is to engage local people and to show them that the wildlife can be worth more alive than dead.
In Baly Bay and Maromizaha, villagers are hired to work as guides, keeping watch on the animals and being on hand to escort visitors.
Tourism can be a big earner. But it requires a lot of infrastructure such as hotels and transport links which are not always possible in a country as poor as Madagascar. And while those facilities take years to develop, hungry families are eyeing the forests right next door to them.
So what of the future?
Some initiatives are bound to succeed, if they are well-funded and well-integrated with local communities.  Much of the policing of the national parks and protected areas may well do its job and keep out incursions.  Quite a few local initiatives will flourish.
The habitats lemurs depend upon exist only in Madagascar
After our coverage this past week, a lot of people have got in touch to describe their conservation efforts in Madagascar or to enthuse about visits there.
But overall? A few weeks ago I heard something revealing on the conservation grapevine: that younger scientists, planning careers in fieldwork, are wondering if they should avoid Madagascar on the grounds that the forests might not survive long enough for them to complete studies over the next 20 years.
And that brings me back to my opening point: that maybe it's more realistic to start picturing a world in which the animals we care about most will only be safe in areas that are properly guarded.
The last major report on Madagascar's lemurs by the International Union for the Conservation of Nature signalled that captive breeding may have to be the answer.
That will work for some species. But the largest of the lemurs, the Indri, depends on a complex diet of leaves eaten at different times and no-one has yet worked it out.
So, for the moment, Indris kept in captivity do not reproduce and may not survive and extinction remains a constant danger.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:25:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The trouble with 'acceptable' language</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-33286949#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Who decides what kind of language is acceptable?</Description>
        <MainBody>The trouble with 'acceptable' language
By John McManus BBC News
28 June 2015
From the section World
Is it justified to ever use an offensive racist term - even if you're trying to have a conversation about racism, as President Obama was when he used the "N-word" on a US radio programme? And who decides what is offensive?
The president's choice of word immediately made headline news, reopening a familiar argument about whether it was fine for black people to reclaim and use the term but white people shouldn't, because it is nearly always a term of abuse - and of course, still is to many, as confirmed by a quick glance at Twitter after Mr Obama spoke.
The point the president was trying to make was that, in his opinion, racism still exists in many aspects of US life and confronting it must go way beyond a philosophical discussion on whether certain words can or can't be uttered in polite company.
Of course, reclaiming formerly offensive words isn't confined to racial minorities.
Across western Europe, some gay men for example, have taken an offensive slur, "queer", and turned it into a badge of identity.
Similarly, campaigners for women's rights in North America have been trying to reclaim the term "slut" , transforming it into a mark of female sexual freedom. "SlutWalks" have now also taken place in Europe, Latin America and Asia.
Yet there are problems.
Reclaiming a word isn't necessarily the same thing as rehabilitating it.
A "SlutWalk" demonstration in London
Take that word "queer" for example. It's used by a minority of gay men to describe their partial rejection of conventional society - for example, many self-defined "queers" reject marriage as an oppressive institution.
They would be less happy about heterosexuals using that same word. And many heterosexuals in turn would be wary as well. That's partly from confusion - because "queer" is still deployed as a term of abuse.
But there's also an issue of authenticity.
Simply put, can those who live outside a minority group ever truly know what it's like to be a member of that community, especially if it's being oppressed, or has been in the past?
Maybe not - so perhaps there should be caution about using language that implies that anybody can experience life - warts and all - on the same terms that minorities do.
Some gay men have embraced the term "queer"
It's why Jewish comedians can get plenty of laughs as they poke fun at those much-maligned Jewish mothers - but why those same jokes might be construed as anti-Semitic if told by a non-Jew.
More seriously, it also explains the derision that fans of rap music used to direct at white hip hop artists - because hip hop music grew out of, and spoke about, the unique experiences of young, black urban Americans.
And rap in particular highlights some of the difficulties behind this whole issue.
Many rap lyrics are liberally sprinkled with words which others find highly offensive - including the one which Mr Obama used.
But many rappers feel their language is a realistic expression of how many young, black urban Americans live. They've walked the walk so have permission, they feel, to talk the talk.
However it's the kind of talk that just can't appear in a piece of this kind - a perfect illustration of how hard it is to navigate a clear path around such sensitive issues.
The authenticity factor also lies behind the criticism directed at Rachel Dolezal , the American civil rights activist who said she spoke from the personal perspective of being an African-American, but in fact was described by her parents as a white woman, with a trace of Native American ancestry.
The debate about Barack Obama's choice of words reveals just how important context and authenticity are.
And if you don't believe me, just try to envisage a white US president - perhaps Bill Clinton or one of the two Bushes - trying to sympathetically use the same racial term Mr Obama used. Or, Mr Obama cracking a joke about interfering Jewish mothers.
I think you may feel a little bit uncomfortable.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:13:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From howling blues to twisted love</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32613468#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Howling blues to twisted love with DJ Rita Ray</Description>
        <MainBody>DJ Rita Ray's African tracks: From howling blues to twisted love
28 June 2015
From the section Africa
Howling desert blues from Mali, Afro-Cuban salsa with Angolan roots, a love story with a twist from the Democratic Republic of Congo and exhortations for unity from a Ghanaian pan-Africanist make up the first of a regular focus on new African music releases by DJ Rita Ray:
Artist: Samba Toure
Album: Gandadiko (Glitter Beat Records)
A guitar master from northern Mali, Samba Toure returns with his singular brand of Songhai blues.
Toure earned his stripes with the kora genius Toumani Diabate and the late Ali Farka Toure.
His new album Gandadiko, meaning Land of Drought or Burning Land, has a smouldering epic feel, featuring howling guitar riffs, the spiky ngoni (traditional West African lute) and emotive keening of the bowed one-string djerka.
The over revved, loping camel-gait rhythms evoke his arid homeland.
His lyrics, powerful and revealing, go behind the headlines and tell of the devastating reality of the social and political aftermath of Mali's recent traumas and the Islamist militant takeover of the north.
The hopeful sounds cushion the cautionary tales and astute observations of his songs, such as Touri Idje Bibi (Black Fruits) where he sings: "Oh earth, forgiveness, oh river forgiveness,
"Every day we offend you."
Artist: Ricardo Lemvo &amp; Makina Loca
Album: La Rumba Soy Yo (Cumbancha)
One of the few Africans to stamp his mark on the global salsa market, Ricardo Lemvo and his Makina Loca band offer a lush tropical offering with their new album.
La Rumba Soy Yo was a three-year recording adventure, a labour of love taking place across three continents and four countries - the US, Canada, France and Angola.
The Salsa star, raised in DR Congo, looks to his Angolan roots for inspiration - seamlessly mixing in kizomba and semba rhythms with the soukous guitars that augment his trademark upbeat Congolese-Cuban rumba.
The infectious dance of the track E Moyo exemplifies the steamy street party feel of the album.
Lemvo and Makina Loca have played around the globe over the years, hopefully this release will help them fulfil their long-held dream of touring Africa and Cuba.
Artist: Laurette La Perle
Single: Twist (Brown Touch Entertainment)
Laurette La Perle is an up and coming singer-songwriter from DR Congo, who also harbours dreams of touring far and wide with her forthcoming album.
Young and ambitious, she is already a multi-award winner, scooping up gongs including the Okapi Awards Best Song of the Year and Best Central African Female at The All Africa Music Awards in 2014.
La Perle was surrounded by music as a child, and received vocal training at a local Kinshasa church choir - her launch-pad into the world of musical competitions.
Now she infuses her distinctive brand of urban rumba-laced soukous with R&amp;B.
La Perle's lyrics fearlessly probe where others might fear to tread.
Twist, the single from her next album, is a tangled tale of love - a soap opera involving two women and a man.
It is not the age-old story, the twist is that the two women are also having an affair - with each other.
Artist: Rocky Dawuni
Album: Branches from the Same Tree (Cumbancha)
Ghanaian reggae singer Rocky Dawuni remains faithful to his mission to spread the message of love and unity.
The songs on his sixth album, Branches of the Same Tree, are an appealing blend of the sounds and rhythms of the black diaspora, which he calls Afro-soul.
Dawuni's music grows from the steady roots of reggae, then delves into the treasure trove found in music of black origin, including New Orleans funk, Brazilian samba and Afrobeat.
He is a passionate humanitarian activist from northern Ghana, whose world vision is expressed in his uplifting, thought-provoking songs.
Dawuni's pan-African vision finds him building bridges and making fans around the continent.
The track Nairobi features Kenyan dub poet Oneko Arika and was written when he visited the Kibera slum just before the 2013 elections.
It was a gesture of solidarity during a time of ethnic and political tension.
"I wrote it as a love song for a city, country and people," he said.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
