<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="BBC">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:04:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Leaders argue over post-vote deals</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2015-32549284#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Political leaders continue to argue over the possibility of post-election deals in the wake of Labour's Ed Miliband ruling out any formal deal with the SNP on BBC Question Time.</Description>
        <MainBody>Policy guide: Where the parties stand
"The threat today is the same as the threat yesterday. Ed Miliband propped up by the SNP not governing on behalf of the whole country."
SNP leader Nicola Sturgeon said people would be appalled by Mr Miliband's refusal to consider a deal with her party, and she said his comments would only galvanise more people to vote for the SNP so Scotland had a decisive voice at Westminster.
"If Ed Miliband is really saying he would rather have a Tory government than work with the SNP for more progressive politics, then it's final proof that Labour has lost the plot... it will be final nail in the coffin of Scottish Labour and I suspect Labour in other parts of the UK," she added.
In other election news:
Mr Miliband has said it is "brutally clear" David Cameron will cut child benefit , as he intensified Labour's attack on Conservative welfare plans
A referendum vote to stay in the EU would not make UKIP "redundant" , party leader Nigel Farage has said
A Labour parliamentary candidate has been suspended after being convicted of fraud, the party has confirmed
The Conservatives have also seized upon a comment from Labour's shadow health secretary Andy Burnham, who said that "of course" there would be dialogue with the SNP if a minority Labour administration needed to get its policies through the House of Commons.
Mr Burnham told BBC Radio 5 live: "Parties talk in the House of Commons about government business, that's what happens, all parties talk."
And Labour's Hilary Benn has also told the BBC's Daily Politics his party would have to have discussions with the SNP to get a Queen's Speech through parliament.
He said: "Whips talk to whips about the programme of business... that's the normal to and fro of the House of Commons but that his not the same as a deal with the SNP, an agreement with the SNP, or a coalition with the SNP because Ed Miliband could not have been clearer last night... we're not going there at all."
Mr Farage declined to name any specific "red lines" for his party in the event of a future deal
Earlier, on BBC Radio 4's Today programme, UKIP leader Nigel Farage said he didn't want UKIP to go into coalition.
However, he said he could do a "confidence and supply" deal with a Conservative and Liberal Democrat coalition.
In such a deal, a minor party would typically support a bigger party in any votes of no confidence which could threaten to topple the government, and in voting through the Budget.
'Compromise and betrayal'
Recent polls all suggest a hung parliament is the most likely outcome on 8 May.
Liberal Democrat leader Nick Clegg said Mr Miliband had been "foolish" to say he would implement his manifesto in full, even if he does not win a majority.
Mr Clegg said the NHS was a "red line" for his party
"It's just another ludicrous claim from Ed Miliband. It's just such a foolish thing to say," he said.
"If you don't win a majority and you have to govern with another party, you don't have the democratic right from the British people to insist on implementing your manifesto in full without any compromises.
"I know that Ed Miliband describes every compromise as a betrayal, but I don't.
"I'm the only politician left who says sometimes, just as in life, in politics you've got to be grown up, there's got to be give and take because that's the right thing for the country as a whole."
Mr Clegg made the comments on a visit to Manchester to set out one of his party's "red lines" before entering into any future coalition.
He said the Lib Dems would insist on securing 8bn funding for the NHS, and making sure mental health issues were treated with the "same esteem" as physical health before entering into any deal with another party.
* Subscribe to the BBC Election 2015 newsletter to get a round-up of the day's campaign news sent to your inbox every weekday afternoon.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:10:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal appeals for more helicopters</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32551499#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Nepal appeals for more helicopters for its quake relief operations, as survivors complain they are getting little help from only 20 in operation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal quake: Appeal for helicopters as desperation mounts
1 May 2015
From the section Asia
Nepal has appealed for countries to provide more aircraft for its relief effort as reports continue to emerge of desperate survivors in remote villages.
Fights have broken out with victims demanding to be evacuated and not enough space on board helicopters, the BBC's Sanjoy Majumder reports.
Nepal says 6,204 people are known to have died in the 7.8-magnitude quake and 13,932 were injured.
But the fate of thousands more in many remote areas remains unknown.
The government has warned that the death toll could rise to more than 10,000.
One thousand EU citizens remain unaccounted for in the quake that hit during the height of the trekking season, the EU ambassador to Nepal, Rensje Teerink, told reporters.
Relief and rescue teams have reached most areas but many people remain in urgent need.
At the scene - Sanjoy Majumder, BBC News, Kathmandu
At Kathmandu's historic Durbar Square, soldiers and volunteers form human chains to remove the debris, brick by brick.
The bricks come from temples and other historic buildings levelled by the earthquake. Many are very old and are being stored so that they can be used to rebuild these ancient sites.
The soldiers are joined by aid workers - but also tourists. One French visitor said she "just wanted to help". But it's an ad hoc approach which characterises the entire relief operation.
I met rescue and medical teams from France and China. After wandering around they left. "We don't know what we are supposed to be doing," one French rescue worker told me.
Their services are required in the remote villages where many are in urgent need of assistance - but they are stuck here in the capital because no-one is telling them what to do.
Landslides and poor weather have hampered efforts to reach isolated districts.
"Almost every house in my village is destroyed, and 20 people died," Kumar Ghorasainee told the AFP news agency amid the ruins of his hometown of Melamchi in Sindhupalchok, north-east of Kathmandu.
The region has been identified by the Red Cross as one of the worst-affected areas.
"We lost our cattle and our sheep," the 33-year-old English teacher said. "No-one has come to help us - the cars and the aid trucks just drive by... How will we manage now?"
There are only about 20 helicopters available for the rescue and relief operations taking place in a region that stretches hundreds of kilometres.
Near the quake epicentre, the Red Cross speaks of "almost total devastation"
China is expected to send more, but more besides are needed - along with more road vehicles to carry relief supplies.
"Inaccessibility to some remote areas, the lack of helicopters, poor communication and security concerns remain the main challenges in delivering relief," said Farhan Haq, a United Nations spokesman.
The UN on Wednesday launched a "flash appeal" for $415m (270m) to assist Nepal over the next three months - but on Friday it told the BBC it had so far received only $5.8m - 1.4% - in confirmed funding.
Nepal earthquake relief
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:38:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesla unveils battery to power homes</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-32545081#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>US electric carmaker Tesla Motors unveils batteries that can power homes and businesses in a bid to expand beyond its vehicle business.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tesla unveils batteries to power homes
1 May 2015
From the section Technology
US electric carmaker Tesla Motors has unveiled batteries that can power homes and businesses as it attempts to expand beyond its vehicle business.
Chief executive Elon Musk announced the firm would build batteries that store solar energy and serve as a back-up system for consumers during blackouts.
The device would allow consumers to get off a power grid or bring energy to remote areas that are not on a grid.
Tesla plans to start shipping the units to installers in the US by this summer.
In a highly anticipated event near Los Angeles, Mr Musk said the move could help change the "entire energy infrastructure of the world".
"Tesla Energy is a critical step in this mission to enable zero emission power generation," the company said in a statement .
The rechargeable lithium-ion battery unit would be built using the same batteries Tesla produces for its electric vehicles, analysts said.
The system is called Powerwall, and Tesla will sell the 7kWh unit for $3,000 (1,954), while the 10kWh unit will retail for $3,500 (2,275) to installers.
Energy comparison firm USwitch estimates that one kWh can power two days of work on a laptop, a full washing machine cycle or be used to boil a kettle 10 times.
Mr Musk said the company would partner with SolarCity to install the home batteries, but there would  be more companies announced.
Mr Musk is SolarCity's chairman and largest shareholder.
Analysis: Richard Taylor, BBC News, San Francisco
Tesla's move into so-called "stationary storage" is a market with enormous growth potential: as the world slowly moves away from fossil fuels, it is seen as critical to a more widespread adoption of "clean" energy sources like solar and wind.
There is also a strong commercial rationale for Elon Musk to leverage Tesla's expertise in building highly-efficient car batteries and put them in a single unit in consumers' residences.
The business strategy is a bit like the battery itself: high impact, but a slow release which will really only reap significant benefits over time. But it comes with risks. Tesla may face a challenge getting the cost-saving message across to potential customers, especially with a significant $3,500 upfront cost.
The carmaker also faces competition from battery-storage technology rivals with deep pockets such as GE (General Electric) and South Korea's top chemical company, LG Chem. There is also a danger that this particular lithium ion battery could be superseded within a few years by other technology, like hydrogen fuel cells, which Tesla is not equipped to make.
Still, these are risks Tesla is clearly prepared to take on. Its cars have won rave reviews, but precious few sales outside its California heartland. With a $5bn gigafactory not due to open until 2017, and only a single Tesla vehicle available to buy today, diversification of its product line into an area like this will be key to keeping investors happy.
The sales of battery storage systems for homes and businesses could yield as much as $4.5bn in revenue for Tesla, according to Deutsche Bank.
The automaker reported fourth quarter earnings that missed market expectations in February, as it saw a loss of $107.6m on production and delivery issues.
Friends of the Earth's renewable energy campaigner Alasdair Cameron said having solar panels and a home battery in the future could become as common as central heating.
"Just as the internet changed the way we use information so renewable sources, like wind and solar, are changing the way we make and use energy - and electricity storage is an important part of that change," he said.
"Cheaper and more efficient energy storage means individuals and businesses could save renewable energy until they need it, hugely reducing the need for climate-changing fossil fuels."
Colin Brown, director of engineering at the Institution of Mechanical Engineers said Tesla's announcement is timely considering the push by governments to reduce emissions.
"Without storage you've always got to have huge capacity just in case one of the peaks come through at a particular time - a very hot day when you need a lot of cooling, and so a lot of demand. With storage, you don't have to have all of that massive production of energy," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:49:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Freddie Gray 'died from bolt injury'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32546201#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Freddie Gray, the Baltimore man whose death sparked rioting in US cities, died in a police van when his head struck a bolt, TV report says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Freddie Gray 'died from head injury in police van'
1 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
The death of Freddie Gray has sparked both peaceful protest and violent rioting in Baltimore
Freddie Gray died when his head struck a bolt in a Baltimore police van, a local US TV news station has reported.
Citing police sources, ABC7 News said that an injury to Gray's head matched the shape of a bolt in the van.
Gray suffered a fatal spine injury while in police custody, sparking two weeks of protests in Baltimore which turned violent earlier this week.
His death is the latest in a series of police killings in the US which have sparked rioting and national debate.
Baltimore police have admitted that Gray was not secured in the van by a seatbelt, against department policy, and that he requested medical attention while being transported in the van but was denied.
Video footage filmed by a passerby showed a visibly distressed Gray being handcuffed on the ground pushed into the back of the van. Police said he ran after seeing two officers, who chased him and arrested him when they found a switchblade-style knife in his trousers.
A still from amateur video footage showed Gray being handcuffed and pushed into a police van
Gray lapsed into a coma following the journey on 12 May and died a week later.
Maryland medical examiner's office has refused to comment on cause of death while the investigation is ongoing.
New footage discovered
The van transporting Gray made a previously undisclosed fourth stop while en route to the police station, police revealed on Thursday.
Previously, police had said the van made three stops, including one to put him in leg irons and another to pick up different prisoner.
The fourth stop was captured on a CCTV camera outside a Korean food shop.
Freddie Gray
The shop's owner, Jung Hyun Hwang told the Associated Press news agency that police officers visited last week to make a copy of the recording - which was later lost when the shop was looted during the riots.
Mr Hwang said he had not viewed the recording and did not know what it showed.
Police said the footage was discovered during a view of public and private CCTV cameras in the area.
According to the police timeline of the arrest, the van took 30 minutes to take Gray to the police station, where paramedics were called.
Despite relative calm in Baltimore on Thursday, riot police were still massed in some areas
Investigators have now handed over their inquiry into Gray's death to the state's attorney's office.
The city's top prosecutor, Marilyn Mosby, will now decide whether to take the case to a grand jury to seek an indictment of any of the six officers involved.
Five of the six officers involved in the arrest gave statements to investigators the day Gray was injured. All six have been suspended.
A separate investigation by the US department of justice is also under way.
After two nights of violent protests, Baltimore's streets were relatively calm on Thursday. The city is still under a curfew requiring people to be off the streets by 22:00 (02:00 GMT).
Police timeline of Freddie Gray's arrest
Sunday, 12 April, 08:39: Officers approach Gray and he flees on foot
08:40: Gray arrested on corner of Presbury Street, Sandtown
08:42: Police request a van
08:54: Van departs with Gray inside, conscious and speaking
08:54-09:24: Van makes a total of four stops between arrest and police station arrival
09:24: Police request paramedics to take Gray to hospital
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:59:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge sets DJ Neil Fox sex trial date</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-32550574#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>DJ Neil Fox will stand trial on sex charges on 5 November, a court in London decides.</Description>
        <MainBody>DJ Neil Fox to face November trial over sex charges
1 May 2015
From the section London
DJ Neil Fox will stand trial on sex charges on 5 November, a London court has ruled.
He denies nine offences against six complainants spanning more than two decades.
Mr Fox - known as Dr Fox - appeared at Westminster Magistrates' Court before Senior District Judge Howard Riddle.
The judge said there should be further preliminary hearings on 23 July and 2 October, and he renewed Mr Fox's unconditional bail.
The trial is expected to last two weeks.
The allegations span the period from 1991 to 2014 and the youngest alleged victim was 13 at the time.
Two allegations relate to a motor show in 1991, one at Chessington World of Adventures in 1996, and the others at the offices of Capital Radio and Magic FM.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:07:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Church to cut fossil fuel investment</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32544480#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Church of England will sell investments worth £12m in companies where more than 10% of revenue comes from the "worst-polluting" of fossil fuels.</Description>
        <MainBody>Church of England to sell fossil fuel investments
1 May 2015
From the section Business
The Church of England is adopting a new climate change policy and will cut its investments in fossil fuel companies.
It will sell investments worth 12m in firms where more than 10% of revenue comes from extracting thermal coal or the production of oil from tar sands.
The Church said it had a "moral responsibility" to act on environmental issues to protect the poor, who were the most vulnerable to climate change.
The Church manages three investment funds worth about 8bn.
"Climate change is already a reality," said Rev Canon Professor Richard Burridge, deputy chair of the Church's Ethical Investment Advisory Group (EIAG).
"The Church has a moral responsibility to speak and act on both environmental stewardship and justice for the world's poor who are most vulnerable to climate change," he said.
'Belief and practice'
"This responsibility encompasses not only the Church's own work to reduce our own carbon footprint, but also how the Church's money is invested and how we engage with companies on this vital issue."
Analysis: Helen Briggs, environment correspondent
With the global campaign to move money out of fossil fuels gaining momentum, the Church of England's commitment to divest for the first time from the most polluting forms of energy is being seen as a significant step.
The church joins several UK institutions that have already signed up to the movement, including Glasgow University and the British Medical Association. But for some, the announcement does not go far enough.
The Church of England says it will withdraw investments worth 12m from companies that make money from extracting thermal coal - used in generating electricity - or producing oil from tar sands.
This is but a fraction of its total investment portfolio and some are already calling for the church to go further by divesting from all fossil fuels. But the church takes the view that engaging with fossil fuel companies is productive for other forms of energy, such as oil and gas, which may be needed as the world moves towards a low-carbon economy.
The new policy "marks the start of a process of divestment as well as engagement with fossil fuel companies and better aligns the Church's investment practice with its belief, theology and practice", added Bishop Nick Holtam, who is the Church of England's lead bishop on environment.
The Church said it also wanted more intensive engagement with companies that made a significant contribution to global greenhouse gas emissions. It recently filed shareholder resolutions at BP and Shell calling for more transparency over climate change.
Christian Aid's director of policy and public affairs, Christine Allen, said the policy ought to prompt energy firms to rethink their businesses: "The openness to further divestment from intransigent companies must be heard as a final warning to the energy industry: shift investment out of fossil fuels and into renewables or your investors will do so for you.
"Every pound divested by churches, public institutions or individuals is a sign that we are serious."
The Church of England does not directly invest in tobacco, pornography or payday lenders.
Two years ago, it emerged that the Church had indirectly invested in Wonga - which the Archbishop of Canterbury, Justin Welby, admitted to being "embarrassed and irritated" about. It has since ended that investment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Savile and Hall abuse report delayed</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-32551608#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A review into how Jimmy Savile and Stuart Hall abused people while at the BBC is delayed amid fears it could prejudice police investigations into sexual abuse.</Description>
        <MainBody>BBC Savile abuse: Dame Janet Smith review delayed
1 May 2015
From the section London
Publication of a report into how Jimmy Savile and Stuart Hall abused people while at the BBC has been delayed.
Dame Janet Smith's review is finished, the team working on it has confirmed.
However, the Metropolitan Police said publishing findings could hamper ongoing investigations into sexual abuse claims.
Publication is to take place "as soon as possible", the report's authors said.
'Disappointment'
Investigators interviewed 375 witnesses in connection with Savile and more than 100 about Hall - findings had been due to be published in the second half of this month.
A statement released by the review team said: "Dame Janet recognises that a further delay will be of particular disappointment to victims of Jimmy Savile and Stuart Hall whose accounts are in the report and other witnesses before the review, to all of whom she is very grateful.
"However, it is important that the Metropolitan Police's investigations should not be prejudiced."
Dame Janet Smith's review has been looking at how Savile and Hall abused people over decades while working at the BBC.
Stuart Hall was convicted of 14 charges of indecent assault in May 2013
It was set up in October 2012 by the BBC to examine the culture and practices of the corporation during the years Savile worked there after the former presenter was revealed to be a prolific sexual predator.
Shortly after Hall was convicted of 14 charges of indecent assault in May 2013, the BBC announced a further investigation into the former It's a Knockout presenter, which will feed into Dame Janet's review.
Liz Dux, abuse lawyer at Slater and Gordon, which represents 168 victims of Savile and Hall, said: "This will come as bitterly disappointing news to the victims of Savile and Hall.
"They desperately want the last of the investigations to be published and to be able to move on with their lives.
"Naturally, they do not want to prejudice any outstanding investigation.
"But given the amount of time that has elapsed since they gave their testimonies, they will question why police investigations are taking so long."
Dame Janet's review will examine the culture at the BBC at the time Hall and Savile worked there
In May 2014, Hall was sentenced to an extra two years and six months in prison for two counts of indecently assaulting a girl.
He was already serving a 30-month jail term after he pleaded guilty in 2013 to indecently assaulting 13 other girls, aged between nine and 17, over a 20-year period.
A report concluded in February that Savile had abused at least 63 people connected to Stoke Mandeville Hospital.
In April, Surrey Police said 22 pupils and one visitor had been sexually abused by him at a school for emotionally disturbed teenage girls.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:39:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lloyds loses £660m on TSB sale</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32545421#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Lloyds Banking Group says it has recorded a loss of £660m on the sale of TSB to Spanish bank Banco de Sabadell.</Description>
        <MainBody>Lloyds loses 660m on TSB sale
1 May 2015
From the section Business
Lloyds Banking Group says it has recorded a loss of 660m on the sale of TSB to Spanish bank Banco de Sabadell.
As a result, Lloyds saw its statutory profit before tax fall by 11% to 1.214bn in the first quarter of 2015.
But underlying profit was up 21% to 2.178bn, with boss Antnio Horta-Osrio saying there had been "continued improvement in financial strength".
The bank also said there had been no further provision during the quarter to cover the mis-selling of PPI products.
In early trade in London shares in Lloyds were up by 3.4% at 80p.
'Commitment'
Lloyds was forced by the European Commission to sell or spin-off TSB. This followed the UK government's purchase of a 43.4% stake in the group in 2009 - a move which the Commission said involved state aid.
Lloyds floated TSB on the stock market in 2014. A takeover of TSB by Sabadell was announced in March, but the deal has yet to be completed.
The sell-off of TSB is costing Lloyds because of the charges involved in removing TSB from its computer servers, with the cost estimated to be 450m.
In a statement accompanying its results, Lloyds said: "We agreed the sale of our remaining stake in TSB to Banco de Sabadell in the first quarter and as part of this agreement, we sold 9.99% of our stake in March.
"The full disposal of TSB will enable us to meet our commitment to the European Commission ahead of the mandated deadline."
'Increasingly healthy'
In its earnings report, the bank also said losses from bad debts fell 59% on the same period a year ago to 177m.
Lloyds also said it planned to pay a dividend for the half-year and full year for 2015, as previously indicated.
Richard Hunter, head of equities at Hargreaves Lansdown Stockbrokers, said: "The Lloyds business is looking increasingly healthy, while the strength of the balance sheet and income growth augur well for the proper resumption of the dividend later in the year."
He added: "The fact that, for the moment, there is no further PPI provision will be a welcome change for generally beleaguered bank investors."
Over the past two years, the government has been selling off tranches of shares in the taxpayer-backed bank.
And in April, David Cameron said that up to 4bn worth of Lloyds Bank shares would be offered to small investors at below-market prices if the Conservatives win the election.
The offer would be part of the 9bn sale of shares in the bailed-out bank announced in the Budget in March.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:22:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mansion fire probe 'will take time'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-surrey-32545837#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The investigation into the cause of a fire that ravaged Clandon Park House "will take some time", Surrey fire service says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Clandon Park House fire: Investigation 'will take time'
1 May 2015
From the section Surrey
The National Trust is due to meet structural engineers to assess the safety of the building
The investigation into the cause of a fire that ravaged Clandon Park House "will take some time" owing to its complexity, Surrey fire service said.
The blaze at the Grade I listed National Trust property near Guildford on Wednesday left the structure gutted.
Structural assessments of the building are continuing and will inform what happens to the 18th Century mansion in the future.
The trust said it was too early to discuss a restoration of Clandon.
About 80 firefighters tackled the blaze at its height and crews managed to save a "significant" number of valuable antiques, that have now been put into storage.
A spokesman for Surrey Fire and Rescue Service said: "The investigation into the cause of the fire is ongoing but due to the complexity of the incident this will take some time to complete.
"Guildford Borough Council and the National Trust are carrying out structural assessments.
"Artefacts rescued from the building have been stored away safely."
'Glimmer of hope'
The house contained a highly prized Baroque marble hall and valuable collections of 18th Century furniture and porcelain.
Parts of the hall remain intact and there is "a glimmer of hope" it could be restored, according to Christopher Rowell, who oversaw the restoration of Uppark House after a blaze in 1989.
Mr Rowell, now the National Trust's furniture curator, added: "There is a pile of debris in the central doorway which indicates there is plenty of material we may be able to sift through and find interesting things.
"It was covered with a fantastic ceiling, with wonderful plasterwork. All of that has collapsed to the floor."
He said two marble chimney pieces on either side of the hall had survived the fire.
Geri Silverstone, a spokesman for the National Trust, said: "We have not made any decisions yet and it is too early to be talking about restoration."
Two chimney pieces have survived in the marble hall
Some original pieces survive in the rubble, the National Trust says
The National Trust expects it to take several days to damp down Clandon Park House
The antiques salvaged from the fire have been catalogued in storage
Uppark fire
Mr Rowell said: "We have an expert who did the work at Uppark 25 years ago and replaced the ceilings, incorporating original material."
Uppark House, near Chichester in West Sussex, was devastated by a fire in August 1989, days before a restoration was due to be completed.
A fire broke out while workmen were using a blowtorch to repair lead flashing on the roof.
Much of the ground floor was damaged when the upper floors collapsed, causing less damage than the fire at Clandon Park House, the National Trust said.
The building was restored by the trust and reopened in 1995.
"I hoped that [Uppark] would be the biggest restoration we would do, but Clandon is a third bigger than Uppark. Our experience there will hold us in very good stead," Mr Rowell said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:07:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Private GP out-of-hours care 'worse'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-32536741#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>GP out-of-hours services provided by commercial companies perform slightly worse than NHS or not-for-profit equivalents, an analysis shows.</Description>
        <MainBody>Private GP out-of-hours care 'worse'
1 May 2015
From the section Health
GP out-of-hours services provided by commercial companies perform slightly worse than NHS or not-for-profit equivalents, an analysis indicates.
These services cover weekends and from 18:30 to 08:00 on weekdays.
The research, by Exeter Medical School, used data from the official GP patient survey in England to score the three types of providers out of 100.
On speed, confidence and overall experience, scores from patients seen by commercial providers were lower.
The score out of 100 for overall experience was:
73 for the NHS
72 for not-for profit
69 for the commercial sector
Similar results had been found for the other two measures, the study in the British Medical Journal said.
Prof John Campbell, who led the research, which involved more than 80,000 patients, said the results were "statistically significant".
"The overall trend is that patients report less positive experiences with commercial, and we now need to understand why," he said.
But he said the research did show that the very best individual scores by providers were seen in the commercial sector.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:07:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man admits council offices arson</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-oxfordshire-32549305#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man admits starting a series of fires in Oxfordshire, including one that caused major damage to council offices.</Description>
        <MainBody>Andrew Main admits Oxfordshire council offices arson attacks
1 May 2015
From the section Oxford
Andrew Main (pictured on the right) pleaded guilty to four counts of arson
A man has admitted starting a series of overnight fires in Oxfordshire, including one that caused major damage to council offices.
Andrew Main, 47, pleaded guilty to four counts of arson at a hearing at Oxford Crown Court.
Main, of Rokemarsh near Wallingford, pleaded not guilty to a further charge of arson with intent to endanger life.
South Oxfordshire District Council's office, an undertakers and a thatched cottage were set alight on 15 January.
The first fire was started at a thatched cottage on Quakers Corner in Rokemarsh
At their peak, 27 crews were tackling the fires in Rokemarsh and Crowmarsh Gifford which started within 10 minutes of each other shortly after 03:00 GMT. No-one was hurt.
In the first blaze, Jean Gladstone, 80, escaped unhurt from her thatched cottage on Quakers Corner in Rokemarsh.
Minutes later, a second fire was reported at Howard Chadwick Funeral Service in the village of Crowmarsh Gifford.
The third blaze engulfed the nearby council offices.
The South Oxfordshire District Council HQ was set alight on 15 January
No explanation as to why Main started the fires was given in court, though at the time there were suggestions it was in connection with a planning row.
It was revealed in court that he has mental health issues.
A decision on whether a trial will proceed over the count of arson with intent to endanger life will be made next month.
He has been remanded in custody.
The fires started within 10 minutes of each other shortly after 3:00 GMT
Main set the fires using gas cylinders. The burnt-out wreckage of a car that ploughed in to the council building moments before it became engulfed in flames was found in the foyer.
Gas canisters were found at all three fire sites as well as at Main's home.
Four hundred staff worked at the offices. The fire completely destroyed the planning department and badly affected the environmental health department and housing department.
Planning applications and comments submitted in the days before the fire were destroyed and had to be resubmitted
The complex also housed about two-thirds of the Vale of the White Horse District Council's staff.
The authorities' websites were also temporarily offline after the blaze.
The funeral parlour reopened last month following 100,000 of repair work.
The council has been operating out of Vale of the White Horse District Council offices in Abingdon since the fire.
It is hoped staff will be able to return to the offices at the start of next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:32:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uptown Funk adds new writers credits</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32546788#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mark Ronson and Bruno Mars give writers of The Gap Band's 1979 track Oops Up Side Your Head a writing credit on their hit Uptown Funk.</Description>
        <MainBody>Uptown Funk credits Oops Up Side Your Head writers
1 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Uptown Funk, which features vocals by Bruno Mars (centre), was released in early December
Mark Ronson and Bruno Mars have given The Gap Band a writing credit on their huge hit Uptown Funk, due to its similarities with their 1979 track Oops Up Side Your Head.
Uptown Funk, which topped the UK chart for seven weeks and the US chart for 14, originally had six songwriters.
The five writers of The Gap Band's hit were added earlier this week, according to RCA documents seen by Billboard .
It's said to have followed a claim from publisher Minder Music on their behalf.
The much-publicised Blurred Lines court case in March saw a jury order the track's writers, Robin Thicke and Pharrell Williams, to pay Marvin Gaye's estate $7.4m (4.8m) in damages because of its similarities with Gaye's 1977 hit Got to Give It Up.
Uptown Funk's original writers were listed as Ronson and Mars, plus co-producer Jeffrey Bhasker and Phillip Lawrence from Mars' production team The Smeezingtons.
Nicholas Williams - aka rapper Trinidad James - and producer Devon Gallaspy also got a credit for the use of a sample of James' track All Gold Everything.
They have now been joined by the five writers of The Gap Band's hit: band members Charlie, Robert and Ronnie Wilson and keyboardist Rudolph Taylor, plus producer Lonnie Simmons.
Pharrell Williams (left) and Robin Thicke's track Blurred Lines prompted a high-profile court case
Billboard said a lawyer for James's manager Danny Zook agreed the Blurred Lines case may have influenced the Uptown Funk writers' decision.
"Everyone is being a little more cautious. Nobody wants to be involved in a lawsuit," he told Billboard.
It is believed the claim from Minder Music was filed with YouTube's content management system in February.
'Dangerous precedent'
Vick Bain, CEO of The British Academy of Songwriters, Composers and Authors (BASCA), told the BBC that original songwriters "absolutely deserve proper credit".
"However it does get very blurred when people take inspiration," said Ms Bain.
"We can understand why Ronson and Mars wanted to avoid a very expensive court case, but I'm sure they would not have given credit if they hadn't felt that would be the right thing to do."
Ms Bain said BASCA hoped all songwriters could avoid expensive court cases in the future, with the Blurred Lines case setting a "dangerous precedent".
"One of our members, who is an expert musicologist, he looked at it and said, 'in this country they wouldn't have won'," she continued -  referring to the way the jury made its decision based on sheet music of Gaye's hit.
Echoing the comments of Pharrell Williams after the verdict, she said: "It sets a very sad and dangerous precedent, because all composers and all songwriters for hundreds of years have been influenced by everyone around them. So I really hope it doesn't stifle creativity."
In January, Sam Smith agreed to pay Tom Petty songwriting royalties for his single Stay With Me, because of its similarities to Petty's 1989 track I Won't Back Down.
A spokesman for Smith said the singer "acknowledged the similarity" but said the likeness was "a complete coincidence".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Apr 27 20:51:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal's treasures: Before and after</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32472307#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Images of the destruction wreaked on Nepal's Kathmandu valley landmarks by Saturday's deadly earthquake.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal's Kathmandu valley treasures: Before and after
27 April 2015
From the section Asia
A view of the collapsed Vatsala Durga temple in Bhaktapur
As well as the devastating loss of human life in Saturday's earthquake, Nepalis, and the world, have lost parts of the country's unique cultural heritage.
Irina Bokova, the Director-General of the UN's cultural organisation, Unesco, said there had been "extensive and irreversible damage" at the world heritage site in the Kathmandu valley.
Seven monument zones in the valley make up the world heritage site.
The three urban zones at the site are Durbar squares - meaning "noble courts" - in the settlements of Kathmandu, Bhaktapur and Patan.
Ms Bokova describes these three complexes as "almost fully destroyed".
The four other zones are religious sites: Buddhist stupas [monuments] at Swayambhunath and Boudhanath and Hindu temple complexes at Pashupatinath and Changu Narayan.
Unesco said in a statement that it would be sending international experts to assess the damage to the sites in the Kathmandu valley.
Kathmandu's Durbar Square
Kathmandu's Durbar Square, shown in June 2011 - the nine-storey Basantapur Tower is on the right
The same buildings in the capital's Durbar Square shown after the disaster - the Basantapur Tower's top tiers have collapsed
Another part of Kathmandu's Durbar Square, shown in 2010
The quake caused the statue of Hindu god Garud to topple from its pillar
The Durbar Square in Kathmandu's Old City is a mesh of palaces, courtyards and temples.
Unesco calls it "the social, religious and urban focal point" of the Nepalese capital.
Bhaktapur's Durbar Square
Bhaktapur's Durbar Square shown in July 2011, with intact Vatsala Durga temple (grey stone)
After the earthquake residents are taking refuge in the open space of the square - behind them is the rubble of Vatsala Durga
The main temple in Bhaktapur's square lost its roof, while the 16th Century Vatsala Durga temple, famous for its sandstone walls and gold-topped pagodas, was demolished by the quake.
Patan's Durbar Square
This photo from 2010 shows the historic square in Patan with intact temples
Looking back in the other direction along the square after the earthquake, several of the tiered temples appear to have collapsed
Patan, or Lalitpur, is across the Bagmati river to the east of Kathmandu.
The city was founded in the 3rd Century.
Swayambhunath temple complex
The stupa at Swayambhunath religious complex, pictured in 2010
This image taken the day after the earthquake shows damage to the surrounding buildings
A monk salvages items from the rubble of a building next to the stupa
The Buddhist temple complex at Swayambhunath, founded in the 5th Century, has also been damaged.
Video footage showed the toppled facade of one of the buildings, with the prayer flags surrounding it still fluttering in the wind.
But the iconic central stupa, with its gazing eyes of the Buddha, still stands.
Boudhanath temple complex
The magnificent Boudhanath Stupa, shown in 2014
There are reports that the Boudhanath stupa has sustained some damage, though details are not yet clear.
It is the largest stupa in Nepal.
Pashupatinath Hindu religious complex
Bodies of earthquake victims are cremated at Pashupatinath on the banks of the Bagmati river
The shrine at the Pashupatinath Hindu religious complex has not been damaged in the disaster, a devotee at the temple told the Indian Express .
Cremations are being held on the site continuously, the paper reports.
Dharahara tower
Dharahara pictured before the earthquake
Saturday's disaster reduced the tower to rubble
This landmark has been reduced to a stump by Saturday's quake.
Built by Nepal's first prime minister in 1832, the site, also known as the Bhimsen Tower, was popular among tourists who would climb up more than 200 steps to view Kathmandu from the top.
It is unclear whether all of these ancient monuments can, or will, be rebuilt.
Historian Prushottam Lochan Shrestha told the ekantipur.com website: "We have lost most of the monuments that had been designated as World Heritage Sites in Kathmandu, Bhaktapur and Lalitpur [Patan].
"They cannot be restored to their original states."
And yet many buildings that were destroyed in Nepal's 1934 earthquake were reconstructed, including the Dharahara tower.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:08:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Papers' verdict on Question Time special</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-the-papers-32544653#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The press examines Thursday's televised grilling of the three main party leaders, with some saying Ed Miliband "stumbled" over Labour's economic record and others focusing on his rejection of a pact with the SNP.</Description>
        <MainBody>Linkedin
The Daily Mail says the BBC's Question Time special, when David Cameron, Ed Miliband and Nick Clegg one by one faced a live audience, was when the election "roared into life" with "real voters finally" having their say. The paper says all the leaders faced tough questioning.
The Daily Telegraph judges that Ed Miliband had "stumbled" when answering audience questions about whether Labour had "overspent" in its last time in power. In what the Telegraph calls a "testy exchange", the Labour leader denied the last Labour administration had failed economically.
The Times said Mr Miliband was accused of lying by one audience member, and another said shadow chancellor Ed Balls should have been "sacked" for saying a note left by a Labour minister for his coalition successor saying "there is no money" was a joke.
The i focuses on the Labour leader's pledge to resist any pact with the SNP. It adds that Mr Cameron won an instant opinion poll taken in the wake of the programme, and the SNP says it will be "furious" if Mr Miliband's stance "lets the Tories back in".
The Guardian also focuses on the SNP statement, which it says was a "hardening" of Mr Miliband's position over the issue. The paper says Mr Cameron put in a "fluent performance" but faced audience pressure over how and where he would make 12bn in welfare cuts.
The Independent says a "combative" David Cameron denied a claim - taken from a 2012 document - that he wanted to cut child tax credit and child benefit but Mr Miliband said the PM had stopped short of giving a firm guarantee of no cuts in this area.
The Daily Star has the surprising story that Russell Brand - the comedian who has said voting is pointless - would like to serve as prime minister.
The Daily Mirror's front page story says a "surging number" of children are relying on schools to provide them handouts of clothes and food due to "brutal Tory austerity measures". The National Association of Head Teachers says the education service is now "a miniature welfare state".
Metro also carries the story, noting teachers representatives claim schools are being forced to give underprivileged children 43m a year to help them out. The head teachers' body says four out of five teachers report having to do more to help poorer pupils buy clothes.
The Daily Express says a "wonder drug" developed in America is promising to "halt Alzheimer's in its tracks". Researchers behind the new treatment say they have taken a totally different approach to the disease to existing thinking. The Express says a pill could be available within two years.
The Financial Times lead says that the EU is to tighten up its internet laws and take on the US technology giants such as Google and Amazon.
The Sun leads with the story of 32-year-old Carl Thompson, Britain's fattest man, who at 65 stone says he knows he is eating himself to death.
As you might expect, assessing the "winner" of BBC Question Time's leaders special depends very much on the political line taken by the paper you read.
The audience in Leeds gave David Cameron, Ed Miliband and Nick Clegg a fairly torrid time, as the "big three" faced separate inquisitions from an audience which was made up of 75% supporters of the three parties and 25% undecided voters.
The Daily Mail says: "The election roared into life last night as real voters had their say in a high-octane TV clash with the three main party leaders."
Newspaper pundits say the audience at Leeds Town Hall was the real star of the leaders' Question Time programme
It says Mr Miliband was "shredded" on "trust with the economy, Labour's spending and record on immigration".
The Daily Telegraph says the Labour leader, who made a slight misstep as he left the stage, had stumbled over the spending record of the last Labour government .
With all three leaders enduring difficult questions, Mr Miliband  "encountered the most hostile reception as he was attacked for Labour's previous economic record, his attitudes towards business and immigration," the paper says.
"Senior Conservatives were on Thursday night hoping that the testy exchanges... will finally mark a turning point in the election campaign," it adds.
The Times said Mr Miliband was "savaged" by the audience with one man telling the Labour leader "how can you stand there and say you didn't overspend. That's absolutely ludicrous. You are frankly just lying".
In its analysis, the paper said Labour's top man "appeared more on edge than in previous debates, and Mr Clegg was "relaxed and confident" at first, but became "tetchy" whereas it thinks "the prime minister held his own against a tough crowd".
The Daily Mirror takes a rather different view on the evening's broadcast.
It says Mr Cameron was "slippery as an eel" as he "spent 30 minutes trying hard not to tell the truth.
A snap poll for the Guardian suggested David Cameron had been most successful on the show
"Voters accused him repeatedly of lying and deceiving the British public."
The paper publishes a list of 10 things Mr Cameron told the audience which it says "aren't quite right" .
A snap poll published by the Guardian/ICM suggested that 44% of respondents thought Mr Cameron had "won" the night, with 38% plumping for Mr Miliband and 19% Mr Clegg.
The paper adds that only 8% of those polled said their vote may be swayed by the show.
The paper says the most significant portion of the programme came when Mr Miliband said: "I just want to repeat this point to you: I am not going to have a Labour government if it means deals or coalitions with the SNP. I want to say this to voters in Scotland."
SNP leader Nicola Sturgeon told BBC Scotland that Scottish voters would "never forgive Labour" if their stance allowed David Cameron to retain power.
School gates
Another story that plays big in Friday's papers is a survey on behalf of the National Association of Head Teachers (NAHT)  which, in the words of the Independent, "estimates that schools are spending 43m a year to offset the effect of poverty on their pupils".
The paper adds that teachers report buying clothes, breakfasts, toothbrushes, washing facilities, stationery and even family birthday cards for children from poor backgrounds.
Russell Hobby of the NAHT is quoted as saying: "Schools are starting to provide miniature welfare states to fill in the gaps that are emerging. We've got to talk about the children's budget rather than the schools' budget on this."
The paper's editorial says,  "We can be certain that the people who will most feel the effects of welfare cuts will be mostly those who already have to get by with very little money, whereas you need to have a decent budget to benefit from a ban on tax rises.
"The case for the Conservatives' strategy is that it rewards work and discourages anyone from choosing to live off welfare benefits.
"The downside is that it will exacerbate inequality, by making the poor poorer."
The Daily Mirror says, "Schoolchildren are bearing the brunt of David Cameron's five-year rampage of brutal cuts ".
Alison Graham, of the Child Poverty Action Group, tells the paper: "The bald fact is that child poverty is rising not falling, and teachers see it every day in their classrooms.
"The next government must act on the child poverty crisis and ensure families can get decent jobs, with decent pay, universal childcare, affordable housing and decent state support."
The Mirror adds: "The head teachers who completed the survey represent 10% of state schools in England, meaning the study provides the most comprehensive ever snapshot of life at the school gates."
Lost glory
The destruction wrought by a fire at Clandon Park House, near Guildford in Surrey,  is extensively covered in the press.
The Times says "the fate of the treasures... was largely determined by whether curators chose to display them in rooms to the left or right of Giacomo Leoni's grand marble entrance hall."
The paper explains that the blaze is thought to have begun in the basement under the right-hand wing of the house, giving fire-fighters and National Trust volunteers just 30 to 45 minutes to save countless antiques and priceless artefacts.
Fire chief Steve Owen-Hughes tells the paper: "The teams were moving through the building ahead of the flames and could hear the floors crashing down in the rooms behind us and the popping of windows."
The Trust, which has owned the house since 1956 when it was bequeathed by the family of the Earl of Onslow, said it would take some time to determine which of the building's artworks were lost in the disaster.
The Times says a 17th century tapestry, the Onslow's library, a collection of porcelain birds, paintings of the stately home's founders and a cloak of kiwi feathers are believed lost, as is a football which was kicked across no man's land at the start of the Battle of the Somme.
The Daily Telegraph says the 80-room Palladian-style mansion, built on the site of an earlier hall in the 1720s, was gutted and is now just a shell .
"Structural engineers from the local authority were due to assess the outer walls of the stately property to determine whether they are safe," it adds.
The Daily Mail says: "For many people, however, the most memorable items were in the basement . This was home to the Surrey Infantry Museum, custodian of the memorabilia and medals of men such as Corporal John McNamara of the 9th Battalion, The East Surrey Regiment.
"He was awarded the VC in 1918 for his single-handed defence of a captured enemy trench near Lens in France. Just a month later, he was killed in action, aged 30. The fate of his Victoria Cross, along with those of five other Surrey heroes, remains uncertain."
Art writer Jonathan Jones wonders in the Guardian if a "marble marvel" will be lost forever because of the damage.
Noting that the damage looks "catastrophic" he answers those who may ask if it matters that a bit of "posh heritage culture" has gone.
"Clandon's architecture - let alone its contents - embodied a great opening up of the British imagination.
"The audacity of its marble hall deserved to be better known as a national glory," he writes.
"Palladian architecture is utopian in its dreams of the perfect and yet liveable place. Something heavenly went up in flames this week."
'The general region'
Let's take a diversion away from the main pages to find Friday's quirkier and more unusual news.
The Daily Star has always taken a keen interest in breasts, and has a story on that very subject.
British women, the paper reckons, are increasingly fans of the natural look, now in evidence on model Katie Price, who had her famous implants removed.
Katie Price: now more natural
It adds that Botox and other non-surgical procedures are increasingly the cosmetic enhancement of choice, with analysts saying the rise of the "selfie" is driving demand.
The Guardian has a story located, as it were, further down the human anatomy.
The paper reports that an expert has criticised the size of codpieces worn by the male cast of the TV adaptation of Wolf Hall.
Victoria Miller, who is to give a paper on the bulging trouser adornments to Cambridge University, tells the paper: "They're way too small to be accurate - they should be at least double the size.
"You can kind of see them there, but they aren't really stuffed, and are easily missed - they've really toned them down for a mainstream audience. The codpiece was meant to draw the eye to the general region."
Ms Miller, who is researching the garment for her doctorate, says the codpiece was purely decorative and used like pockets.
"There are accounts of men pulling out oranges from them to impress the ladies," she notes.
Moving swiftly on, the Daily Telegraph is among a number of papers to report research into why people think wine tastes better if people think it is expensive .
The paper says University of Bonn scientists have found "preconceived beliefs created a placebo effect so strong that it changed the chemistry of the brain".
The researchers discovered this by scanning people's brains as they enjoyed wines which they were told cost between 3 and 55.
The German team repeated the results with milkshakes, with brain chemistry altering when people were told they were consuming expensive organic shakes.
Team leader Bernd Webber says, "Marketing actions can change the very biological processes underlying a purchasing decision, making the effect very powerful indeed."
I'll drink to that.
Independent : What happens to your body when you give up sugar?
Sun : Mayweather "plans filthy LA party" after bout
Express : Police cancel cycle race over "terror plot"
FT : Saudi Arabia burns through foreign currency
Latest Tweets
From Nick Sutton @suttonnick
Friday's Independent - Miliband: I will not do deal with the SNP to become PM #tomorrowspaperstoday #bbcpapers http://t.co/sgzR0BG8er
14 hours ago
Friday's Scottish Daily Mail front page  Ed: I'd prefer to lose than deal with SNP #tomorrowspaperstoday #bbcpapers http://t.co/zZg283LySG
15 hours ago
Friday's Daily Express back page: City's striker spree #tomorrowspaperstoday #bbcpapers http://t.co/PKlRAgudGk
15 hours ago
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:21:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Did Labour over-spend?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32549892#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Was Ed Miliband right when he insisted that the last Labour government didn't over-spend?</Description>
        <MainBody>From the section Business
comments
Members of the Question Time audience became conspicuously grumpy when Ed Miliband said the last Labour government did not over-spend.
So who was right - them or the Labour leader?
Well, they both have a point.
There was a gap between what Labour was spending and what it was receiving in tax revenues in the few years before the great crash and recession of 2008.
But that gap was not massive: sometimes it was a tiny bit bigger than the growth rate of the economy, sometimes a bit smaller; which means there was no significant increase in the ratio of public sector debt to national income or GDP.
Thus in 2007-8, public spending was 40.2% of GDP, compared with tax revenues that were 37.5% of GDP: so the deficit was 2.7% of GDP.
No shouting
Now there are plenty of economists and mainstream politicians who regard both public spending of that magnitude and a deficit of that scale as sustainable and indeed sensible.
And to put those figures into context, public spending by the government of Margaret Thatcher was significantly higher than that for her first seven years in office -  and she consistently ran a deficit of that scale till her last three years in office.
So it is quite hard to describe the fiscal conduct by the government of Tony Blair and Gordon Brown as wildly irresponsible. And, to be clear, neither George Osborne or David Cameron were at the time shouting that the Labour government was maxing out the credit card and was about to bankrupt Britain.
But that is not to let Miliband or his predecessors off the hook.
Insane and greedy
The Question Time audience did not seem altogether satisfied with the mea culpa that Ed Miliband did make, namely that Labour's mistake was to put in place inadequate oversight of the banks to prevent them behaving recklessly and mullering the economy.
And the audience's unease may not be irrational.
Of course the crisis would have been less acute if the Financial Services Authority and the Bank of England had taken earlier prophylactic action to prevent the banks lending and investing in their insane and greedy way.
Wilful and wrong
But Labour wasn't just asleep at the wheel when it came to City regulation. Arguably it was drunk at the wheel - in that it loved the City boom, for generating huge tax revenues that it then lavished on public services.
So the failure to keep the City properly in check was in a sense wilful and therefore doubly wrong.
And there's another thing. Even best-in-class regulation of the City can't protect any economy from periodic shocks.
Which is why there is something to be said for George Osborne's favourite cliche, that it is sensible to mend the roof when the sun is shining.
Or to put it another way, when the economy is growing strongly, as it did through most of Labour's years in office, it probably does no harm to finance growth in public services largely through the proceeds of growth, rather than through borrowing.
Why? Well, the lower the national debt at the time recession bites, the more scope there is to borrow to protect public services and increase benefits, to shield people from the pain of recession.
Austerity, austerity
The point is that since 2007-8, and as a direct result of the recession-induced collapse in tax revenues and surge in public spending on benefits, the national debt has doubled, from roughly 40% of GDP to 80% of GDP.
And the bleedin' obvious point is that if the national debt was today nearer 70% of GDP, almost the entire debate of this general election campaign wouldn't have to be about how much more austerity is needed and the timing of that austerity.
None of which is to say that the Tories are right to argue that the best thing for the economy at this juncture is to turn the deficit into a surplus as soon as possible: the Labour and Liberal Democrat case that a slower pace of welfare and departmental cuts would be fairer and better for our prosperity is supported by many economists.
What's more the debate remains lively (ahem) about whether the scale of cuts made by the current Tory and LibDem government in its early years was too great, and imposed too much hardship in the cause of regaining fiscal credibility.
But although Ed Miliband could plausibly argue that the Tories and LibDems forced more austerity on us than was necessary, it is not altogether surprising that his circumscribed admission of culpability for our economic woes causes a good deal of harrumphing.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:19:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How many staff does the NHS need?</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-32535859#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Increasing the number of staff in the NHS has been a major theme of the election. But does the health service really need all these doctors, nurses and midwives?</Description>
        <MainBody>1 May 2015
From the section Health
When the NHS was created in 1948 there were 144,000 members of staff. In less than seven decades that figure has risen tenfold to 1.4 million across the UK.
But with all the political parties promising more health workers in the coming years, just how many doctors, nurses, porters, therapists and managers does the NHS need?
Ask the experts and they will say something like 8,000 more GPs, 20,000 more nurses and 3,000 more midwives.
Unsurprisingly, these are the figures that are - more or less - being promised by politicians in this election campaign.
But how certain can we be that this right? After all, we live in an era of huge technological change that surely could revolutionise the way the system works?
NHS staff and workforce pressures in numbers
In 1948 the NHS employed 144,000 staff. There are now about 1.4m.
The consultant workforce grew by 54% between 2002 and 2012 and annual growth of 4% is predicted until 2020.
In 2012, almost 50% of the nursing workforce was aged 45 or over, compared to 33% in 2002.
When the NHS was created nearly half of people died before the age of 65, today just 14% do.
The number of over 85s has more than doubled since 1981 to 1.4m. In 20 years time there will be 3.6m.
The NHS in England spends 5bn a year on education and training.
Currently, face-to-face contact accounts for nearly 90% of all healthcare interactions.
But the potential for digital technologies and even simply increasing the amount of email, Skype and phone consultations could make a big difference.
In the US, the health company Kaiser Permanente has reduced the amount of GP visits being made by a quarter through greater use of phone and email.
Meanwhile, hospital doctors and nurses in West Yorkshire have set up video link-up with local care homes and reduced admissions by 35%.
There is also the potential for more self-management of illness, while the use of sensors and alarms in the home can make a big difference to the amount of home visits needed to check in on the frail elderly.
Even so, some have doubts about just how much of a revolution there will be.
Nigel Edwards, chief executive of the Nuffield Trust think tank, says: "It doesn't look like technology will be the breakthrough it has been in other industries.
"Health and care is pretty labour heavy - that means having people on hand."
Instead, he says, perhaps the more pressing issue is what sort of staff are actually needed.
It is a question posed by Health Education England's 15-year workforce strategy document published in October.
It doesn't make any firm predictions and instead acts as a discussion document, listing a host of factors likely to mean more staff have to be taken on, including the ageing population and the high numbers of staff reaching retirement age.
But it says if the drive to move care out of hospital and into the community is to be successful, it will require staff roles to change.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:52:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From 'Jillaroo' to Green Party leader</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2015-32493939#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Green Party leader Natalie Bennett's Aussie tones have become a familiar sound at the UK general election - but how did she get to where she is today?</Description>
        <MainBody>Natalie Bennett: From 'Jillaroo' to Green Party leader
By Paola Totaro Foreign Press Association, London
30 April 2015
From the section Election 2015
Most of us welcome New Year's Day with pledges for self-improvement. On 1 January, 2006, Natalie Bennett woke up and resolved she would take it one step further and try to "change the world".
"I had just stopped working nights and suddenly, it became possible to get on the same time schedule as everyone else," she tells the BBC.
"I thought for a while about the state of the world and that I needed to do something and decided then I'd join the Green Party."
Fast forward and here we are, chatting mid-April 2015. It is the day after the BBC party leaders' TV debate and Bennett, leader of the Green Party of England and Wales, is in a buoyant mood.
She is only the second leader of the party, which until recently shunned such a hierarchical concept, and although the Greens have only had one MP in the House of Commons, they are enjoying their highest media profile in years thanks, in part, to being invited to share a TV platform with the leaders of the main Westminster parties.
Bennett has attracted flak for her occasional media stumbles during this election campaign - she apologised to supporters for a moment of "brain fade" in an LBC radio interview on her housing policies - but she was deemed to have held her own in the leader debates, coming top on a measure of audience sentiment on Twitter, although snap polls of voters suggested she had made less of an impact.
Some have suggested that she is not the leader the party would want, with previous leader Caroline Lucas still seen as the face of the Greens to the average voter.
But there is no question that the party has seen a boost in the opinion polls with Bennett at the helm.
It has just celebrated signing up its 60,000th member, when combined with the tallies for its sister parties in Scotland and Northern Ireland, a tripling in numbers since last year, overtaking both the Liberal Democrats and UKIP.
'Unmodulated' Aussie
Not a bad fillip for an Aussie-born, political underdog who has yet to win a parliamentary seat in a campaign so close that even Britain's betting shops are having trouble setting odds.
So who is Natalie Bennett and where did she come from?
She comes across in person just as she appears on TV: no-nonsense, tough and keen to talk about the brand of radical politics, well to the left of today's Labour Party, that has been the hallmark of her leadership.
Bennett with her parents on graduation day at the University of Sydney
Her Australian accent, despite living in London for 15 years, remains unmodulated. She is palpably unsentimental about Australia, calls Britain home and even volunteers that she has allowed her Aussie passport to lapse.
Born in 1966 to teenage parents - a part-time secretary and an apprentice carpenter - Bennett was the couple's only child, growing up in Sydney's north-western suburbs.
She is keen to point out that hers was no clichd Sydney beachside upbringing. Instead, she reminisces about the moment when, aged five, she felt the first stirrings of politicisation and feminism.
"I wasn't allowed to have a bike," she says. "My working class granny thought it unladylike, and I encountered this all through my childhood - people telling me all the things I couldn't do or that I shouldn't want to do because I was a girl."
Bright and ambitious, Bennett won a scholarship to one of Sydney's top girls' schools, MLC in Burwood, and then, a place at the city's most prestigious university, Sydney.
Bennett says her time 'jillarooing' was short lived because she wasn't good enough on a horse
Melanie Currey, a school friend from MLC, remembers Bennett as academic, a great debater and chess player and a girl who always did as she said: "She had her beliefs and she stuck to them," she recalls. "You'd never catch her out doing the opposite."
Bennett says her decision to study Agricultural Science at university was the result of a romantic notion of "life on the land" that developed after a childhood holiday on a farm.
"Nobody in my family had gone to university so I had no-one to ask me: 'Is that right for you?' I decided to spend a year jillarooing [female workers employed to carry out a range of activities on a cattle or sheep station] but lasted just two months  I simply wasn't good enough on a horse or bike."
In 1989 tragedy struck when she and her parents were involved in a car crash. Bennett helped pull her father from the wreckage but her mother was killed. It is a trauma, she says, which had an indelible impact.
'No wallflower'
After graduation and a year's backpacking in Europe, Bennett turned her sights to journalism - starting on small country papers, before moving to the regional city of Tamworth and the Northern Daily Leader newspaper.
Britain's party leaders
Conservatives: David Cameron. The current prime minister is leader of the largest party (whose past leaders include Churchill and Thatcher) in the House of Common. His party formed a coalition with the Liberal Democrats and have been in power since 2010.
Labour Party: Ed Miliband. Labour leader is hoping to bring his party back into power - Tony Blair led it to victory in 1997, 2001 and 2005 but Gordon Brown led it to defeat in 2010. Polls suggest it is neck-and-neck between Conservatives and Labour.
Liberal Democrats: Nick Clegg. The Lib Dem leader took his party into government for the first time in decades in 2010 and has since seen poll ratings slump. The party is pitching its campaign on being a moderating influence on the two larger parties.
Scottish National Party: Nicola Sturgeon. Scotland's First Minister, who - despite not standing for election herself - has made much of the running in this campaign. Polls suggests the SNP is on course to take a chunk of Labour's 41 sets in Scotland.
UK Independence Party: Nigel Farage. Colourful former City trader leads UKIP, which campaigns from Britain's exit from the European Union and tighter immigration controls. It has done well in EU elections, but yet to transfer that into wins at General Elections.
Plaid Cymru: Leanne Wood. Former probation officer and leader of the party that campaigns for Welsh independence. Party won three MPs in 2010 and talks of a "progressive alliance" with the SNP, Greens and Labour at Westminster.
Tony Gillies, then the Leader's editor and now Editor-in-Chief of Australian Associated Press (AAP), remembers that in a newsroom of 25 reporters, she "was a big personality in a small room. And no wallflower".
Bennett returned to journalism while volunteering in Thailand
"I saw her mostly as someone with strong values and sense of self - she liked a debate," he remembers. "Natalie had a reasonable dose of cynicism in her so she was never likely to give anyone a free kick."
Ann Newling, now the Leader's editor, was a young reporter with Bennett and remembers her as "intense". "She was interested in serious stories - and in every regional newsroom you need a reporter like that," she says.
"She was opinionated, but not gratingly so, or not too much more than any of us in those days and those newsrooms. I remember Tony Gillies described Nat as having a voice like a Gatling gun."
By 1993 Bennett had itchy feet, applied to Australian Volunteers Abroad and moved to Thailand to work on the National Commission on Women's Affairs. When the stint ended, she decided to stay-on, working back in journalism at the Bangkok Post.
Grassroots campaigner
In 1999, the call of the UK became too strong and like many Australian journalists in Fleet Street's heyday, she worked in several newsrooms including the Telegraph, Independent and Times, before shifting to the Guardian where she also edited The Guardian Weekly.
Bennett says she was always sure that the time would come when she would move away from reporting and move to "doing".
Bennett's Green Party is 'unashamedly radical'
"As a journalist, you report, see the same stories year after year: famines, conflict, disaster. I'd always imagined that the next move would be into an NGO or the UN world, but in 2006, that New Year's Day, I decided to do something."
And "do" she did. Over the next six years, she worked in her spare time for the Greens, standing (unsuccessfully) in several seats, campaigning at grassroots and as communications' coordinator for the national executive.
Finally, in 2012, just as she had taken voluntary redundancy from The Guardian and was preparing to spend a leisurely year writing a book (the working title was "How we got into this economic and environmental mess and how to get out of it"), when Green Party leader Caroline Lucas announced she wanted to hand over the leadership to someone else so she could focus on her electorate.
Bennett threw her hat in to the ring and won.
On 7 May, the ambitious Aussie with the Gatling gun voice will go to the polls urging UK voters to join her in a "peaceful political revolution", with the promise of an unashamedly radical, left wing manifesto.
Among her pledges is a plan to redistribute wealth (higher taxes for the rich, boost the minimum wage by 10), re-nationalise railways, decommission Britain's nuclear weapons and install free, nationwide home insulation for nine million "cold homes".
Richard Jones, a British-born former New South Wales MP and high-profile environmentalist, said Bennett is little known in her birthplace but her party's manifesto is "exactly the kind of radical politics we need in this country today".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 13:36:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: The Alternative Big Fight Face-Off</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32528193#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Ahead of Saturday's super-fight, BBC News looks at how Floyd Mayweather and Manny Pacquaio stack up inside and outside the ring.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Mayweather-Pacquiao: The Alternative Face-Off
30 April 2015 Last updated at 11:36 BST
Fight fans have been comparing every stat of Floyd Mayweather and Manny Pacquiao's boxing careers ahead of Saturday's super-fight.
But which fighter has the biggest online punch? Whose bank balance hits heaviest? And who has the flashiest fight gear?
BBC News presents an alternative take on how the fighters stack up.
Video Journalist: Paul Ivan Harris
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:21:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>May Day dawn draws large crowds</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-oxfordshire-32536709#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Crowds gather in the centre of Oxford for the annual May Day celebrations centred on Magdalen Bridge.</Description>
        <MainBody>Oxford May Day: Thousands descend on Magdalen Bridge
1 May 2015
About 5,000 of people gathered on and around Magdalen Bridge
Crowds have descended on the centre of Oxford for the annual May Day celebrations.
The event saw about 5,000 people gather on and around Magdalen Bridge to celebrate the traditional spring festival.
The bridge was open to pedestrians but closed to traffic from 03:00 BST.
In past years revellers have been injured jumping into the river. The city council, police and ambulance called for "responsible" celebrations.
Peter McQuitty, of Oxford City Council, said: "May Morning is a popular traditional celebration and over the last few years we've provided a safe environment in which people can enjoy this event.
"It is always dangerous to enter the river, regardless of the water levels, and you are often unaware of the currents, the river levels or what lies on the river bed."
Crowds enjoyed dancing, singing and revelry around the city
Many wore green to celebrate May morning and the arrival of Spring
Each year Hymnus Eucharisticus is sung by 16 college choristers from the top of Magdalen College tower.
The hymn was composed in the 17th Century by a fellow of Magdalen and has been sung every year as the sun rises on the first morning of May.
Bells then ring out over the city for about 20 minutes.
Mark Blandford-Baker, home bursar of Magdalen College, said: "I was struck this morning by just how beautiful and timeless this event is - there's a lot of detailed planning that goes into it - it has to go just right."
Roads in the city centre were closed for the celebrations until about 09:00 BST.
In the past, revellers have been hurt jumping from Magdalen Bridge during the celebrations
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:39:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jam tart record bid for Alice party</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-north-west-wales-32536475#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A Conwy town is marking the 150th anniversary of the publication of Alice in Wonderland by attempting a world record for the longest line of jam tarts.</Description>
        <MainBody>Llandudno marking Lewis Carroll link with jam tart record attempt
1 May 2015
From the section North West Wales
1,500 tarts have been baked for the record attempt
A Conwy town is marking the 150th anniversary of the publication of Alice in Wonderland by attempting a world record for the longest line of jam tarts.
People living in Llandudno have made the 1,500 tarts needed for Friday's event.
Alice Liddell, the little girl who was Lewis Carroll's inspiration for Alice, spent her family holidays in Llandudno.
The record attempt began at 12:00 BST.
Bakery students at Coleg Llandrillo prepare for the event
Alice Liddell spent her family holidays in Llandudno
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:25:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murphy closes in on final place</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/snooker/32549210</Link>
        <Description>Shaun Murphy is on course to reach his third World Championship final after extending his lead over Barry Hawkins to 13-3.</Description>
        <MainBody>World Snooker Championship: Shaun Murphy leads Hawkins
World Snooker Championship
Venue: Crucible Theatre, Sheffield Dates: 18 April-4 May
Coverage: Watch live on BBC TV, HD, Red Button, Connected TV, online, tablets, mobiles and BBC Sport app. Full details here.
Former champion Shaun Murphy is on course to reach his third World Championship final after extending his lead over Barry Hawkins to 13-3.
Murphy resumed the best-of-33 semi-final 6-2 ahead and capitalised on some loose play from Hawkins with brilliant potting and two century breaks.
The 2005 champion completely dominated as he won seven of the eight frames.
Stuart Bingham leads Judd Trump 5-3 in the other semi-final, which resumes at 14:30 BST.
Hawkins needed a good start on Friday but despite a break of 50 he could not close out the opening frame, and Murphy responded with a clinical clearance.
The 32-year-old, who was also runner-up in 2009, then reeled off breaks of 73, 105 and 79 to go in at the interval with a 10-2 lead.
Hawkins finally got on the board with a 79 on the resumption but Murphy rattled in a brilliant 121 to re-establish control, and took the last two frames against an increasingly helpless-looking opponent.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:56:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Pearson &amp; Murphy's heated exchange</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/32543893</Link>
        <Description>Watch Leicester manager Nigel Pearson and BBC Sport's Pat Murphy exchange strong views at a news conference.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media Player help
Nigel Pearson: Leicester boss grilled by BBC Sport's Pat Murphy
Watch Leicester City manager Nigel Pearson and BBC Sport's Pat Murphy exchange strong views at the club's weekly news conference.
Murphy grills Pearson throughout and suggests the Foxes boss could appear to be a "bully" and "paranoid".
Pearson remains calm despite the BBC reporter's questions, which also includes asking if he has ever thought of taking anger management classes.
The exchange comes after Pearson apologised to a journalist for calling him an "ostrich" and "stupid" following Leicester's 3-1 Premier League defeat by Chelsea.
Their conversation lasted for seven minutes, including the following exchange:
Murphy: You are in danger of appearing a bully.
Pearson: Am I?
Pearson: Paranoid. OK. Anything else?
Murphy: Someone's got to tell you.
Pearson: OK. You're telling me.
Murphy: Has no-one ever told you that before? Has nobody ever taken you to one side and said: 'Nigel, I think you're out of order here'.
Pearson: If they have then that's my business.
Share this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:36:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Manny can do one thing, Floyd two'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/boxing/32546888</Link>
        <Description>BBC Sport pools the thoughts of boxers past and present in the build-up to Floyd Mayweather v Manny Pacquiao.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mayweather v Pacquiao: Boxing greats predict fight outcome
Mayweather v Pacquiao
Venue: MGM Grand, Las Vegas. Date: 2/3 May: 21:00 local time/05:00 Sunday BST
Coverage: Live text commentary on the BBC Sport website
By Ben Dirs, BBC Sport in Las Vegas
On Saturday in Las Vegas, Floyd Mayweather and Manny Pacquiao will engage in the richest fight in history at the MGM Grand Garden Arena.
So much has been said about the numbers involved that it is sometimes difficult to remember there are other things at stake - namely the WBC, WBA and WBO welterweight titles and the title of best boxer of the modern era.
It is a fight everyone has an opinion on and BBC Sport has pooled the thoughts of boxers past and present, including some of the sport's greatest names.
Bernard Hopkins - former two-weight world champion
"A turtle is only vulnerable when he sticks his head out - when he senses danger, he goes back into that shell. You can beat that shell up, but you're not hurting him. Pacquiao has to trick Mayweather out of that shell, make him think he's there for the counter. When he's not - 'bang' - capitalise on his mistake.
Mayweather and Pacquiao will take home about 215m between them after Saturday's fight
"Pacquiao has to make Floyd become the aggressor, something he's not comfortable with. He has to make Floyd bring the fight to him, let his hands go while Manny's letting his hands go and see who lands first. That's fun for us.
"Counter-punchers aren't good at catching up, we wait for you to come knocking at the door, we don't come to you. So counter-punchers need their opponents to be aggressive and then take advantage of slow feet and slow hands. It won't be a landslide win for Mayweather, it will be a hard-earned win. "
Carl Froch - IBF super-middleweight champion
"I can see how Manny Pacquiao is able to beat Mayweather - work the angles, high work-rate, volume of punches, fast hands, back Floyd into a corner or onto the ropes. Just outwork Mayweather and win round after round after round.
"Mayweather will put on a defensive masterclass, behind the shoulder, slipping and sliding, ducking and diving and not getting hit. He's a defensive genius, a magician in the ring. But Pacquiao should punch the shoulder, punch the arms, hit him round the back of the head, in the kidneys, take anything he can.
"Mayweather is just too good at adjusting, changing his style, adapting to what's in front of him. If there's ever a time for Mayweather to lose, that time is now, he's an ageing athlete. But I'm going for a close Mayweather points win."
Juan Manuel Marquez - three-weight world champion; lost to Mayweather, lost to Pacquiao twice, drew once, knocked him out in 2013
"Pacquiao needs to pressurise Mayweather and land punches with speed, power and accuracy. But Mayweather uses distance very well, is hard to hit and lands with counter-punches.
"I don't think it affected him when I knocked him out. I want Manny Pacquiao to win this fight, my heart is with Pacquiao as a boxer. But Mayweather wins because he's got such a difficult style."
Roy Jones Jr - four-weight world champion
"Manny has to be aggressive and Floyd's planning for him to be aggressive. Is Floyd going to match aggression with aggression, or is he going to use tactical boxing? He can do either. Manny can do one thing, Floyd can do two. Floyd will determine how the fight starts and how it ends.
"Manny's game plan has to be pressure, pressure, pressure. Floyd has never fought an opponent like Manny who throws so many punches, has power in both hands and is a southpaw. No-one has pressured Mayweather like Pacquiao will.
Mayweather-Pacquiao top facts
"Manny can be reckless and that's what Floyd will be planning on. He got reckless against Marquez when he had the fight won, went for the knockout and got knocked out himself. Hopefully he will have learned from that and be reckless at the right time. It's going to be a very good fight - I'm not sure who is going to win."
Amir Khan - former light-welterweight world champion, wants to fight the winner
"Both fighters still have so much to give and on Saturday I'm sure they're going to produce something very special for the fans.
"This is going to be a tremendous match-up.
"Manny has hand speed and fast feet, and that will cause Floyd some problems early on. But as it progresses, I expect Floyd to make the adjustments he tends to make to counter that before pulling away on the scorecards."
Ricky Hatton - former two-weight world champion, lost to both at the MGM Grand
Hatton was knocked out by Pacquiao in the second round of their fight in 2009
"Pacquiao has all the attributes to beat Mayweather - if anyone is going to beat Mayweather it will be someone with similar hand speed who is a southpaw. Pacquiao will definitely cause problems, it will be Mayweather's toughest task yet.
"But after a few rounds, Mayweather will do what he does best and suss things out. He always manages to adapt his style for the opponent he's facing and always finds a way to win. Love him or loathe him, he's a genius.
"I'm picking Mayweather to win on points. It will be a very close fight, nip and tuck, with almost nothing in it. But Mayweather will finish with his nose in front."
Sugar Ray Leonard - five-weight world champion
"Mayweather has a couple of ways to win the fight: as a counter-puncher, wait for Pacquiao to make mistakes and make him pay for those mistakes; or just box him, dance around, do what he does best. He's a little bit more versatile than Pacquiao.
"As for Pacquiao, if he can be the man who beat Oscar De La Hoya and Miguel Cotto, we're talking about a very interesting, physical fight.
"I think there will be a couple of surprises for the fans, in terms of knockdowns. But there could be dominance from Mayweather."
Mike Tyson - former heavyweight world champion
Tyson backs Pacquiao to win
"Floyd can't fight the way he's been fighting if he wants to beat Pacquiao. He has to go forward and throw punches.
"Pacquiao throws over 100 punches a round. Floyd, in his last fight, threw 38 punches a round.
"Mayweather can't be on the ropes against a guy like Pacquiao. It's not going to work out. I think that it's going to be a great fight.
"I like Pacquiao, although I'm not saying Floyd can't win. But he's got to change the way he's been fighting."
Kell Brook - IBF welterweight champion, wants to fight the winner
"Manny chucks a lot of shots and comes from awkward angles, which Mayweather won't be used to, especially from a southpaw stance. Pacquiao is a very active fighter, he'll pressure Mayweather and make him uncomfortable.
"But Mayweather is just too clever, his defence is great and he'll find a way to win. It's got points written all over it, although if Manny thinks he's losing the fight and starts getting desperate late on, I can see him getting knocked out."
George Foreman - former heavyweight world champion
George Foreman (right) lost to Muhammad Ali in the 1974 Rumble in the Jungle
"It's going to go to the end because they'll be so careful. Pacquiao understands that he could get knocked out and Mayweather will be thinking: 'Pacquiao has knocked out a lot of guys.'
"Mayweather is a defensive genius. But he's not an offensive machine. So I think Pacquiao will win. He's smart and he's the underdog - he'll feel the crowd pulling for him. I've got a feeling he can win it by one round."
Shane Mosley - three-weight world champion, lost to both
"It can be a very boring fight, with Mayweather just picking at Pacquiao, or it could be a very exciting fight if Mayweather stands more flat-footed.
"I almost knocked Mayweather out straight out of the gate - that would be a good tip for Pacquiao, he can't give Mayweather a chance to get comfortable or to pick up on his rhythm.
"If he is going to win against Mayweather, it's going to have to be in the first three or four rounds, tops. But Mayweather is the best in the world at avoiding punches, so I would have to go with Floyd."
Oscar De La Hoya - six-weight world champion, lost to both
"There are two scenarios: Pacquiao can push the pace and make Floyd fight. If he's in great shape, it can be an exciting fight; or Mayweather can figure him out and box him the whole night and have an easy win. He's going to fight in spurts and put the rounds in the bag. Nothing is going to change.
"The question is, can Pacquiao keep his composure and focus in the ring? He's going to have trouble hitting Floyd, so he has to stay calm and not get frustrated. He's going to throw five and six-punch combinations and maybe only one punch is going to land. If he gets frustrated, Mayweather will capitalise."
Fight is biggest event of 2015 - McGuigan
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:02:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Winston first pick in NFL draft</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/american-football/32545451</Link>
        <Description>Tampa Bay Buccaneers take Florida State quarterback Jameis Winston with first pick in the NFL's annual draft.</Description>
        <MainBody>Winston won the Heisman Trophy college award aged 19 when he led Florida State to a national championship
1 May 2015 Last updated at 09:02
print
NFL draft: Tampa Bay Buccaneers take Jameis Winston
Tampa Bay Buccaneers took Florida State's 21-year-old quarterback Jameis Winston with first pick in the NFL's annual draft.
In the draft, one of the biggest events in the US sporting calendar, teams pick from the best college players.
All 32 teams took part in Thursday's first of seven rounds.
Second pick was quarterback Marcus Mariota, taken by Tennessee Titans, while Jacksonville Jaguars took defensive end Dante Fowler Jr third.
Teams with the worst records from the previous season get first choice in the draft.
Rounds two and three are held on Friday, with London-born Jay Ajayi likely to be selected.
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:53:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Liverpool hope for Sturridge answers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/32548186</Link>
        <Description>Liverpool boss Brendan Rodgers says they hope to sort Daniel Sturridge's "underlying injury issues" in the United States.</Description>
        <MainBody>Daniel Sturridge joined Liverpool from Chelsea in January 2013
1 May 2015 Last updated at 10:53
print
Liverpool: Brendan Rodgers on Daniel Sturridge &amp; Steven Gerrard
Liverpool manager Brendan Rodgers says they hope to sort Daniel Sturridge's "underlying issues" with injury after sending him to the United States again.
The 25-year-old, who has played 18 times this season, has flown out to a specialist to fix his hip injury.
He also spent a month in the US in December to deal with a thigh problem.
Rodgers said: "The medical team here, liaising with medics in America, are doing everything we can to give Daniel every opportunity to stay fit."
He added: "If you look at his career, he's had little issues along the way.
"I think we have found some underlying issues that maybe relate to Daniel's problems this season and the ongoing ones he's had."
Rodgers was asked if some of the England striker's problems could be mental rather than physical.
"I'm not sure. Daniel is like every other player - he wants to play and be available," Rodgers added. "We have to do everything we can to get him on the training field and into the game, hence the reason for looking into the issue."
The 25-year-old England international is visiting Dr Peter Asnis, an orthopaedic surgeon based in Boston.
Meanwhile, captain Steven Gerrard, who has four games left before he leaves for US Major League Soccer team LA Galaxy, is expected to face QPR on Saturday, having been left out of the squad for Tuesday's loss to Hull.
"The Saturday-Tuesday games were always going to be difficult for him," Rodgers said. "But he's had a good week of preparation and he'll be fit and firing for the weekend."
And the Liverpool boss confirmed full-back Jon Flanagan will miss a large part of next season after knee surgery. The 22-year-old England international has not played this season.
"He's been a huge miss for us," Rodgers said. "Second half of last season he was arguably the best full-back in the league.
"He fought back, trained and looked brilliant - but for him and his career he definitely needed the operation. Six to nine months, then get him back fit and stronger than ever."
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:50:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Slowdown in UK manufacturing growth</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32548327#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Growth in the UK manufacturing sector slowed sharply in April, according to a closely watched economic survey.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK manufacturing growth in sharp slowdown
1 May 2015
From the section Business
Growth in the UK manufacturing sector slowed sharply in April, according to a closely watched economic survey.
Financial data company Markit said its monthly Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI) for manufacturing fell to 51.9 in April from 54 in March.
The fall in the index was the biggest since February 2013, although a figure above 50 still indicates expansion.
Companies said the strength of the pound against the euro was affecting competitiveness in the eurozone.
The survey follows the release of official figures on Tuesday that showed the UK's economic growth rate halved to 0.3% in the first quarter of the year.
Rob Dobson, senior economist at Markit, said: "Today's UK PMI delivered less-than-positive news on the health of the manufacturing sector.
"Any signs of rebalancing the economy towards manufacturing and exports remain frustratingly elusive."
Survey hits sterling
The survey found that new export orders fell at the fastest rate since January 2013, job creation was   "modest", and manufacturers cut prices at their fastest rate in almost six years.
In recent months, the pound has gained in value against the euro. In March, it was at its highest level compared with the single currency in seven years, making UK goods more expensive in the eurozone.
At the same time, sterling has weakened against the dollar, and the survey said prices paid for goods priced in dollars had risen.
The pound fell against both the dollar and the euro following the release of the PMI survey. Sterling dropped by about a cent against the dollar to $1.5281, and fell by about a euro cent against the euro to 1.3580.
David Tinsley, an economist at UBS, said: "The source of the drop [in the PMI] may be an indicator that the appreciation of sterling against the euro is having an impact on UK manufacturing competitiveness.
"One would hope that as the upswing in the eurozone gains traction demand may begin to compensate for the currency move, but it's a reminder that monetary policy will need to be sensitive to the pound."
However, Lee Hopley, chief economist at EEF, the manufacturers' organisation, said: "It would be premature to write off manufacturing's contribution to growth in the future, not least because continued employment growth points to some confidence about longer term prospects."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:21:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Borrowers warned on mortgage deals</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32533495#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Homeowners wanting to take advantage of tumbling mortgage rates are being warned to look out for high fees attached to them.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mortgages: Borrowers warned over fees on low-rate deals
By Brian Milligan Personal Finance Reporter
1 May 2015
comments
Mortgages have never been cheaper
Homeowners wanting to take advantage of tumbling mortgage rates are being warned to look out for high fees attached to them.
It follows news that the Co-op is launching a two-year fixed mortgage at 1.09%, said to be the lowest rate ever.
Two weeks ago HSBC announced a five-year fix at a record low of 1.99%.
But experts say borrowers need to look closely at the fees involved, and the rates people will be charged when the fixed-rate period is finished.
Anyone wanting to take out one of the above mortgages will have to pay a fee of 1,500.
The average fee for taking out a mortgage is only 920.
"These rates come at a cost," said Rachel Springall of Moneyfacts.
"If you think you are going to have to move your mortgage again in two years time, you've got to think whether you are going to have to pay another fee," she told the BBC.
'Price war'
The Co-op's rate of 1.09% is only available to borrowers with a 40% deposit.
Customers are also being warned about the so-called "reversion rate" -  the interest they will be charged at the end of the fixed-term period, if they don't move elsewhere.
In the case of the Co-op, the reversion rate is a relatively high 4.74%.
Some experts believe mortgage rates could go even lower still.
"We're going to see a few months yet of this price war," said Rachel Springall.
Economists expect the Bank of England to maintain base rates at their current low of 0.5% until February 2016.
Mortgage rates are expected to rise as that date approaches.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:55:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miliband: Child benefit 'threatened'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2015-32545985#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Ed Miliband says it is "brutally clear" the Conservatives will cut child benefit, but David Cameron says the benefit is "vital" to families and "stays".</Description>
        <MainBody>Election 2015: Miliband steps up attack on Tory welfare plans
1 May 2015
From the section Election 2015
Ed Miliband said only Labour could protect family budgets
Ed Miliband has said it is "brutally clear" David Cameron will cut child benefit, as he intensified Labour's attack on Conservative welfare plans.
The Labour leader said family budgets faced being "devastated" by Tory proposals for 12bn in welfare savings.
The Tories say they will freeze working-age benefits, including child benefit, for two years but have not spelt out what else will be targeted.
But Mr Cameron said it was "vital" to parents and "stays" in place.
With six days to go to polling day, the party leaders have all resumed campaigning after Thursday's TV election specials, the last major set-piece cross-party event of the campaign.
Mr Miliband, Mr Cameron and Nick Clegg were all put on the spot about post-election deals and their economic records in a Question Time Special, where they also set out some of their pre-conditions for negotiations with other parties.
In other election news:
Nigel Farage said he didn't want UKIP to join a coalition with any other party but would support a Conservative-Lib Dem coalition if it granted a "full, free and fair" EU referendum
David Cameron has committed the Conservatives to further reducing the North-South economic divide
The Lib Dems said 8bn in extra funding for the NHS would be a "red line" in coalition negotiations
In a speech in Cardiff, Mr Miliband focused on welfare, promising to begin the process of reversing cuts to housing benefits for social tenants - dubbed by critics as the "bedroom tax" - on day one of taking office.
Claiming the policy had caused "untold misery" for up to half-a-million people, he said Labour would also make extra "hardship funds" available to councils across the UK to help those affected.
The Labour leader also returned to the attack over child benefit, claiming there were "six days left to save" the benefit from Conservative cuts.
'Election arithmetic'
Labour claim the Conservatives cannot find the 12bn in welfare savings they say they need to achieve a budget surplus by 2017-8 without restricting tax credits and child benefits,
The opposition has seized on Lib Dem claims that their coalition partners considered 8bn worth of curbs to child benefit in 2012.
"The prime minister was asked three times (on Thursday) whether he had a plan to cut child benefit," Mr Miliband said.
"He apparently used 600 words when just one word would have done - the word no. But he did not use that word.
"Three times he refused to answer, three times he sent a brutally clear message to British families - he wants to cut child benefit. He has done it before and he will do it again."
The Conservatives have said they will freeze working-age benefits, including tax credits and child benefit, between 2016 and 2018, affecting 11 million households and saving 3bn.
This comes on top of a one-year freeze in the value of child benefit in 2013-4 and a 1% cap on increases between 2014-6.
David Cameron said he would continue to reform welfare to make work pay
Speaking during a visit to an Asda depot in Leeds, Mr Cameron suggested there would be no further reforms to child benefit.
"With child benefit we've made our reform. We said that it's absolutely a vital benefit for Britain's families: it goes straight to the mother in most cases; it forms the key part of families' budgets; and we've made our reform.
"We've said that we had to freeze it in this Parliament, we said that we're going to have to freeze it for the start of the new Parliament, but child benefit stays because it's so important."
'No trading'
Mr Miliband has ruled out any coalition or formal agreement with the SNP to keep a minority Labour government in office and insisted it will not "trade or barter away" key elements of its manifesto in post-election discussions.
But asked whether they would be "dialogue" between different parties after the election, Labour frontbencher Andy Burnham said "of course".
"Parties talk in the House of Commons about government business, that's what happens, all parties talk," he told BBC Radio 5Live.
Speaking on a tour of marginal seats in Yorkshire, Mr Cameron again brandished a note left by a Labour minister in 2010 saying "there is no money" left, saying Mr Miliband's denials that it had over-spent showed that the party had learnt nothing.
And senior Conservative Michael Gove said assumptions in sections of the media that there would be a hung Parliament were premature.
"There are 23 seats we need to win on the basis of current arithmetic and 11,000 people in those 23 seats that we need to convince to vote Conservative. If people want David Cameron in Downing Street, then voting Conservative is the only way to ensure that."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:37:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Labour suspend candidate over fraud</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2015-england-32545431#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A Labour parliamentary candidate is suspended by the party after he was found guilty of fraud.</Description>
        <MainBody>Labour's Wellingborough candidate Richard Garvie suspended over fraud
1 May 2015
From the section Election 2015 England
Richard Garvie said he had been in a "difficult financial situation"
A Labour parliamentary candidate has been suspended after being convicted of fraud, the party has confirmed.
Richard Garvie, 30, who is standing for Wellingborough and Rushden, was found guilty of buying about 900 worth of train tickets using a bank account he knew contained insufficient funds.
He had denied the offence and told the BBC he "did not set out to defraud East Midlands Trains".
His name will stay on ballot papers as it is too late for it to be removed.
Garvie, from Corby, Northamptonshire, was convicted at Wellingborough Magistrates' Court on Thursday and will be sentenced at a later date.
He said he ran up a debt in his own name in 2012 because he had been "desperate to see the people he cared about" in Berkshire.
"I didn't know I'd get into trouble. I intentionally went overdrawn on my account, that account was then sent to a debt collection agency and the debt was paid off," he said.
"What happened since is East Midlands Trains have brought the prosecution.
"I didn't confide in anybody. I genuinely believed I hadn't done anything wrong."
'Act of stupidity'
The former candidate, who intends to appeal against his conviction, said he was "devastated, not just for [himself] but for the constituency" and is still considering his political options.
"It was an act of stupidity three years ago. I've apologised and hope it doesn't have any impact on the party," he said.
"If people still want to vote Labour, then vote for me on the ballot paper.
"If Labour were to win the election, I think there would be a question mark for me as to whether it would be right for me to continue as an MP."
The Labour Party has not yet offered any guidance on what its voters should do if they want to vote for them next Thursday.
The Wellingborough seat was held by Conservative Peter Bone who won by a majority of 11,787 votes in 2010.
Mr Bone is standing again, against Chris Nelson for the Liberal Democrats, Marion Turner-Hawes of the Green Party and UKIP's Jonathan Munday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 17:56:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'First natural birth' for diabetic</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-norfolk-32531067#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A diabetic woman is the first in the world to give birth naturally after using an artificial pancreas while pregnant, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody>'First natural birth' for diabetic woman with artificial pancreas
30 April 2015
From the section Norfolk
Catriona Finlayson-Wilkins had her son after wearing the device to keep her blood sugar levels normal
A diabetic woman has become the first in the world to give birth naturally after using an artificial pancreas while pregnant, experts have said.
Catriona Finlayson-Wilkins, 41, of Knapton, Norfolk, gave birth to son Euan on Tuesday at the Norfolk and Norfolk University Hospital.
She is also the first woman to give birth after using the device outside the main research site in Cambridge.
Ms Finlayson-Wilkins said she was "thrilled" by her son's safe arrival.
The new mother-of-two has Type 1 diabetes and wore the piece of kit throughout her pregnancy to produce insulin and prevent symptoms of the disease.
Three other mothers have previously given birth in Cambridge after using the device but by caesarean section.
Artificial pancreas breakthrough
The artificial pancreas is made up of a glucose monitor, digital controller and insulin pump
An artificial pancreas device system (APDS) is a small portable piece of equipment designed to carry out the function of a healthy pancreas.
It helps to control blood glucose levels using digital communication technology to automate insulin delivery.
An APDS is worn on the body during pregnancy and has a continuous glucose monitor (CGM), a digital controller and an insulin pump.
The device carries out the function of a healthy pancreas in controlling blood sugar levels
Ms Finlayson-Wilkins, who is a face and body painter and has also decorated models for local charity Break's GoGo gorilla and dragon art trails , said: "I'm thrilled.
"It's a huge weight off your mind after being pregnant and diabetic, which is really risky.
"It's the most amazing piece of kit and I can really see how it's going to benefit all types of people with diabetes in the future."
Her first son was taken into intensive care when he was born because his blood sugar levels dropped dangerously low and she did not see him for a day.
Baby Euan was born at the Norfolk and Norwich University Hospital and weighed 8lb 14oz (4kg)
Dr Helen Murphy, principal investigator of the study Ms Finlayson-Wilkins took part in, said Euan's arrival was an exciting step in the treatment of diabetes in pregnancy.
"Women who have diabetes in pregnancy face higher rates of birth defects, over-sized babies, pre-term delivery and stillbirth than other pregnant women," she said.
"Treating diabetes in pregnancy can be particularly challenging because hormone levels are constantly changing and blood sugars can be difficult to predict."
The results of the ongoing National Institute for Health Research's Closed Loop in Pregnancy study are due to be published later this year.
Its findings could mean the technology benefits more pregnant women with diabetes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3D windpipe 'saves children's lives'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-32496547#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Three babies have been saved from a life-threatening condition by using 3D printed windpipe splints to help them breathe, a pilot study reveals.</Description>
        <MainBody>3D windpipe 'saves children's lives'
By Smitha Mundasad Health reporter, BBC News
Kaiba is now a healthy three-year-old
The man who fixed his own heart
Three babies have been saved from a life-threatening condition by using 3D printed windpipe splints to help them breathe, a pilot study reveals.
The patients suffer from a rare illness that means their windpipes can collapse and prevent air getting in.
The device was rapidly customised for each individual. And unlike most 3D implants, it was made of material that changed shape as the children grew.
The research appears in Science Translational Medicine .
Last resort
Due to the small number of children involved in the study it does not prove it will work in every case.
But it does show the splints could be a promising option for a condition that has no cure, researchers from CS Mott Children's Hospital at the University of Michigan say.
One in 2,000 children have tracheobronchomalacia - a weakening and collapse of the windpipe (trachea) that would normally allow air to travel to the lungs.
Those with the most severe form have a poor chance of surviving. But if they can get to the the age of three, their windpipes have often strengthened enough to allow them to breathe well.
Kaiba Gionfriddo had the procedure when he was just three months old. He was in a critical condition, needing intensive care because his body was not getting the oxygen it needed.
So doctors sought emergency approval to use the device as a a last resort.
Lead researcher Dr Glenn Green described it as a ground-breaking case.
Kaiba is now "an active, healthy three-year old in preschool with a bright future", researchers said.
Dissolving device
Almost three years later the splint shows signs of melting away as planned. And doctors say his windpipe appears strong enough for him to breathe without its support.
April Gionfriddo, Kaiba's mum, said: "The first time he was hospitalised, doctors told us he may not make it out.
"It was scary knowing he was the first child to ever have this procedure, but it was our only choice and it saved his life."
The team have now carried out the surgery on two other children.
Both are doing well and are back at home, though one continues to need a machine to help his breathing, because of problems the splint could not address.
Dr Patrick Finlay, of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, described it as an advanced piece of engineering.
He said: "The problem represents some formidable difficulties.
"You have to construct something that can cope with growth and coughing and sneezing.
"And they seem to have done this - it is very exciting."
He said the splint could be thought of as similar to a section of vacuum cleaner pipe that had been split in the middle.
It is customised to match the exact anatomy of each patient and made of a bio-absorbable material.
Doctors sew it in place on the outside of the windpipe as an incomplete ring.
The aim is for it to provide support without constricting growth.
US researchers have filed a patent on the device and are now embarking on a larger trial.
More on This Story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:22:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Schools 'feeding and clothing pupils'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/education-32540801#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Head teachers are warning that schools are having to act like "mini-welfare states" in providing and food and clothes to some pupils.</Description>
        <MainBody>Schools feeding and clothing pupils, say heads
By Sean Coughlan Education correspondent
1 May 2015
From the section Education &amp; Family
Heads warn they have to feed and clothe some pupils without any extra support in school budgets
Head teachers are warning that schools are having to act like "mini-welfare states" in having to provide food, spare uniform and even to wash clothes and provide showers for some pupils.
The National Association of Head Teachers says such welfare support is costing 43.5m from school budgets.
Heads' leader Russell Hobby said it was a "hidden national scandal".
A Conservative spokesman said "the number of children living in poverty has fallen by 300,000".
The warning from members of the NAHT, as they gather for their annual conference in Liverpool, is that schools are having to step in with welfare support for pupils, either because of poverty or dysfunctional families.
Washing clothes
The union's report, based on responses from more than 2,000 head teachers in England, found examples of schools supplying food, clothes, PE kit, headlice treatment, transport costs and equipment for lessons.
There were schools which now had facilities for washing clothes and providing showers for pupils.
Heads' leader Russell Hobby warns that such welfare support needs to be funded
This was not a representative survey, but NAHT leader Mr Hobby said the responses from so many schools revealed the rising pressure on heads to deliver many different kinds of non-educational support.
"Schools have held families together and kept children out of the criminal justice system," he said.
Mr Hobby warned that the financial cost of this extra support was not recognised, with estimates that it cost schools an average of 2,000 to 3,000 per year.
Individual heads and teachers were also bringing in their own food for pupils, but without any this cost being recorded.
Mr Hobby said that head teachers wanted "a level of honesty around what we expect from schools".
"Schools are starting to provide mini-welfare states to fill in the gaps that are emerging," Mr Hobby said.
"Regardless of the promise to protect education spending in the next parliament, cuts to other public services will come home to roost at the school gates."
Funding pledges
A Conservative party spokesman said that their education budget plans would provide more spending on schools than Labour's proposals and defended their record in government.
"Under the Conservatives, the number of children living in poverty has fallen by 300,000. By introducing the pupil premium, we are specifically targeting an extra 2.5bn toward the education of the most disadvantaged every year, which is helping close the attainment gap with their peers."
But Labour's Tristram Hunt said: "David Cameron's plan for extreme cuts - double the cuts next year than this - plus his refusal to match Labour's plan to protect the entire education budget in real terms, means a perfect storm is brewing for children and young people.
"Labour has a better plan - protecting early years education, school spending and post-16 education in real terms."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:41:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Private school pupils at record high</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/education-32535248#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Independent Schools Council says the number of pupils at private schools is at a record high.</Description>
        <MainBody>Independent school pupils at record high
1 May 2015
From the section Education &amp; Family
Parents pay more than 15,500 a year for private schooling
The number of pupils at independent schools in the UK is at its highest level since records began.
Figures published by the Independent Schools Council (ISC) show a slight rise in the numbers of privately educated pupils since last year.
The data also shows parents are on average now paying more than 15,500 a year for private schooling.
In total, there are 517,113 pupils at ISC schools this year, according to the council's annual survey of members.
This is up by about 1%, or 5,000 more students, on 2014.
The council says this means that student numbers are at their highest levels since records began 40 years ago.
'Remarkable'
There are 10 more schools in the ISC than last year, with 1,267 in total. And comparing only those schools that took part in the survey in both years, there has been a 0.6% rise in numbers.
There were increases in the numbers both of British and international pupils taking up places, the ISC said.
The survey also reveals that school fees have risen by 3.6% this year, with parents now paying 5,225 a term on average to educate their child privately.
This equates to about 15,675 for a whole year.
Fees range from an average of 10,123 per term to send a child to a private boarding school, to 4,398 for day pupils at either a boarding school or private day school.
ISC chairman Barnaby Lenon said: "It is remarkable that, although we are only at the start of an economic recovery, the number of pupils at UK independent schools is at the highest levels since records began in 1974.
"It shows that parents continue to value an independent education."
In total, 7% of schoolchildren were educated in the independent sector, while 14% of sixth-formers - those aged 16 and over - attended an ISC school, the council said.
The proportion of international students at British private schools has remained fairly steady at about 5% over the past few years.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:48:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grooveshark music service shuts down</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-32547376#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Music-streaming service Grooveshark has announced that it is shutting down.</Description>
        <MainBody>Grooveshark music-sharing service closes down
1 May 2015
Grooveshark was set up in 2006 and, at its peak, had millions of users
Music-streaming service Grooveshark has announced that it is shutting down.
The closure is part of a deal worked out with record companies who sued the service claiming it was harbouring pirated pop.
In a statement on its website, Grooveshark said it had failed to get licences for the copyrighted music shared on the service.
It has also agreed to delete the music it offered and hand the website and apps over to the record industry.
Huge fine
"We made very serious mistakes," said the statement. "We failed to secure licences from rights holders for the vast amount of music on the service.
"That was wrong. We apologise. Without reservation," it said.
The shut-down also ends the legal action started by Warner, Sony, and Universal Music in 2011.
Pre-trial hearings for that case were heard earlier this week during which the judge in the case described Grooveshark's copyright violations as "wilful".
It was accused of illegally sharing almost 5,000 songs which meant that, if it had been found guilty, it would have faced a damages bill of up to $736m (480m). Although Grooveshark's defence against the charges would probably have reduced the overall damages it would have faced.
The threat of the large bill has been lifted with the ending of the legal action. However, the terms of the settlement with the music industry mean the service's founders could still face a financial penalty if they do not respect its terms.
"This is an important victory for artists and the entire music industry," said the Recording Industry Association of America in a statement.
It said Grooveshark had built its business without providing proper compensation to artists.
"This settlement ends a major source of infringing activity," it said.
Grooveshark was set up in 2006 and had, at its peak, about 35 million users per month who were allowed to upload any song they chose. Employees at Grooveshark also uploaded songs to expand the library of music available to users.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:18:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Facebook bug blocked image posts</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-32543299#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Facebook faced a backlash from users who found some posts disappeared while others couldn't link to content outside the social network.</Description>
        <MainBody>Anger as Facebook bug blocked pictures
1 May 2015
From the section Technology
Photo-scraping software that shows a relevant picture when links are shared in posts failed
Facebook has faced a backlash from users who found some posts disappeared while others couldn't link to content outside the social network.
The problems which began on Thursday followed a software update that seems to have caused the glitch.
Some users wanting to post updates containing links were mistakenly sent a warning saying they were violating the site's security policy.
Facebook has apologised and said it is rolling out a fix for the bug.
It appears the issue was with Facebook's image-scraping tool that automatically detects pictures connected with links to content within posts. The tool is supposed to   help users present links to other content with a photo from the site they are linking to. The post, complete with picture, then appears friends' timelines.
Pictures sell content
Publishers who use Facebook to promote their content were particularly vocal about the impact on their businesses.
Facebook forum messages show publishers in particular were worried about the image-blocking bug
"An error in our system that helps block bad links on Facebook incorrectly marked some URLs [web addresses] as malicious or inappropriate. As a result, some existing posts were hidden, while other posts were blocked completely" said Facebook in a statement.
"We've resolved the issue and the remaining affected URLs are being unblocked. We apologise for the inconvenience this has caused."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:50:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Step forward for quantum computing</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-32534763#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Scientists have made progress towards correcting the errors that are expected to arise in quantum computing.</Description>
        <MainBody>Step forward for quantum computing
By Paul Rincon Science editor, BBC News website
1 May 2015
From the section Science &amp; Environment
IBM wants quantum computers to help design new drugs and materials
Scientists have made progress towards correcting the errors that are expected to affect quantum computing.
Quantum computers could offer a massive performance boost over conventional types, but progress toward commercially useful machines has been slow.
Now, scientists from IBM's Watson Research Center have successfully demonstrated a new method for correcting errors on a quantum circuit.
The basic units of information in classical computers are called "bits" and are stored as a string of 1s and 0s. But their equivalents in a quantum system - qubits - can be both 1s and 0s at the same time.
In theory, this should give quantum machines much greater computational power than conventional types.
But quantum information is fragile, and errors in calculations carried out in a quantum system can creep in through interference from factors such as heat, electromagnetic radiation and defects in materials.
Controlling or removing such errors is one of the great challenges for harnessing the power of quantum computing.
Scaling up
The IBM team was able to detect and measure two key types of quantum error (called bit-flip and phase-flip) that will occur in any real quantum computer.
"Up until now, researchers have been able to detect bit-flip or phase-flip quantum errors, but never the two together," said co-author Jay Gambetta.
The team demonstrated its error-protection protocols on a quantum circuit consisting of a square lattice of four superconducting qubits on a chip roughly one-quarter inch square.
IBM claims the square shape of the circuit makes it more scalable than the linear arrays that have been used by other groups.
Prof Alan Woodward, a computing expert from the University of Surrey, UK, said the work represented a step forward, but was a "significant evolution" rather than a "revolution".
"We all know that error correction is very important in quantum computing because of the inherent errors that are caused by the way qubits tend to operate, but this isn't the first time it's been addressed," he told BBC News.
For example, an American team of physicists published a separate protocol for quantum-error detection just last month.
But Prof Woodward said: "What we're seeing is the move from the drawing board to actual implementation.
"This is the first time we have seen groups actually implementing real hardware which is then proven experimentally to have significant error correction properties."
"Which architecture, if any, actually wins out remains to be seen. Each has pros and cons but at the moment there isn't really an obvious winner."
But he said the "dark horse in the race" was topological quantum computing, an architecture that is intrinsically more fault-tolerant. A team at the University of California, Santa Barbara, has been working on this method, and is being backed in its efforts by Microsoft.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:05:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Song heralds new bird's arrival</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-32536484#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The distinctive song of a secretive and elusive bird in central China helps researchers to describe it as a new species to science.</Description>
        <MainBody>Song heralds arrival of new bird species
By Mark Kinver Environment reporter, BBC News
1 May 2015
From the section Science &amp; Environment
The surrounding dense habitat makes the bird difficult to spot but its song reveals its presence
The distinctive song of a secretive and elusive bird in central China has helped researchers to identify it and deem it to be a new species to science.
Scientists first heard the harsh call of the Sichuan bush warbler in 1987, but they only recently gathered enough data to formally describe it.
The new species, Locustella chengi, has been named after Prof Cheng Tso-hsin, a distinguished Chinese ornithologist.
The details have been published in the Avian Research journal .
"These birds are almost impossible to see when they are not singing," explained one of the scientists to describe the new species, Per Alstrom from the Swedish Species Information Centre, based at the Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences.
"If the species had not been singing when we first heard it back in 1987, we would never have seen it.
"They are incredibly difficult to see because they are so secretive, sneaking around in the dense vegetation, close to or on the ground. But when they are singing, you can hear them from quite a long distance.
He told BBC News: "By being patient or using tapes to attract them, you can see them - although they will stay in the dense habitat."
Harsh tones
The song of the new species is harsher than that of its closest relative, the russet bush warbler, and consists of a "drawn-out note followed by a shorter note that are repeated in series".
The team of researchers, from Sweden, China, Vietnam, the UK and US, carried out DNA analysis that showed the two birds were very closely related and were probably separated from a common ancestor about 850,000 years ago.
Prof Alstrom explained that the publication of the paper formally describing the Sichuan bush warbler came after a search lasting almost 30 years.
"I have been trying to find this bird ever since we first heard it back in 1987," he said. We suspected that it was something different, something new (to science).
"Last year, we had received information from colleagues that both these birds - the unknown species and the Russet Bush warbler - were present on the same mountain.
"We had not found both of them together previously, so we went there specifically to get more information on how they interacted together; whether they occurred in different habitats, etc, to see if they were actually ecologically and reproductively isolated in these areas."
Although the two species have slight differences in proportions, it is the the birds' songs that mark a clear distinction.
Prof Alstrom suggested that was probably the result of random processes that had resulted in the two species evolving different vocalisation patterns.
"It is probably a combination of chance factors, such as individuals undergoing vocal "mutation', and also sexual selection," he suggested.
"Songs are used to attract females and to deter other males from their territory, so there is probably a factor of strong sexual selection evolution involved in these differences."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:05:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>R&amp;B legend Ben E King dies at 76</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32547474#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>R&amp;B and soul singer Ben E King, best known for the classic song Stand By Me, dies at the age of 76.</Description>
        <MainBody>R&amp;B legend Ben E King dies at 76
1 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Ben E King received an award from the Songwriters Hall of Fame in 2012
R&amp;B and soul singer Ben E King, best known for the classic song Stand By Me, has died at the age of 76.
King started his career in the late 1950s with The Drifters, singing on hits including There Goes My Baby and Save The Last Dance For Me.
After going solo, he hit the US top five with Stand By Me in 1961.
It returned to the charts in the 1980s, including a three-week spell at number one in the UK, following its use in the film of the same name and a TV advert.
The song has charted nine times on the US Billboard 100 over the years - King's version twice and seven times with covers by artists like John Lennon and Spyder Turner.
Ben E King had six songs in the US Billboard top 40 between 1961-75
It was also sampled for Sean Kingston's 2007 number one single Beautiful Girls.
In 1999, the BMI announced that the song, written by King with Jerry Leiber and Mike Stoller, was the fourth most-played track of the 20th Century on US radio and TV.
Earlier this year, the US Library of Congress added it to the National Recording Registry, declaring that "it was King's incandescent vocal that made it a classic".
King's other hits included Spanish Harlem, Amor, Don't Play That Song (You Lied) and Supernatural Thing - Part I.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:05:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Modern Family star's battle over embryos</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32547470#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Modern Family actress Sofia Vergara is in a legal battle with her former fiance, who wants to have children from the couple's frozen embryos.</Description>
        <MainBody>TV star Sofia Vergara in battle over frozen embryos
1 May 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Sofia Vergara faced questions about the case at the premiere of her new film in Hollywood on Thursday
Modern Family actress Sofia Vergara is in a legal battle with her former fiance, who wants to have children from the couple's frozen embryos.
Nick Loeb said he wants a surrogate to carry and give birth to two embryos he and Vergara created through in vitro fertilisation before they split up.
He said the actress, who plays Gloria in the ABC comedy, has refused.
Vergara, who has been named the highest-earning actress on TV for the last three years, declined to comment.
Writing in the New York Times , Loeb said he and Vergara had signed a document at the time of the IVF stating that any embryos could only be brought to term with both parents' consent.
However he is trying to have that document declared void because it did not specify what would happen if the couple separated.
Nick Loeb and Sofia Vergara split up last year
"When we create embryos for the purpose of life, should we not define them as life, rather than as property?" the businessman wrote.
He said he had offered to pay all expenses and take full responsibility for raising the children.
"A woman is entitled to bring a pregnancy to term even if the man objects," he said.
"Shouldn't a man who is willing to take on all parental responsibilities be similarly entitled to bring his embryos to term even if the woman objects?"
He added that he did not want "the two lives I have already created be destroyed or sit in a freezer until the end of time".
Asked whether she had anything to say about Loeb's article at the premiere of her new film Hot Pursuit in Hollywood on Thursday, Vergara said: "No."
Her lawyer Fred Silberberg also declined to comment.
The actress has earned Emmy, Golden Globe and Screen Actors Guild award nominations for her role in the mockumentary-style comedy, which is into its sixth season and is shown on Sky 1 in the UK.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:12:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Go Figure: The week in numbers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-magazine-monitor-32547468#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The week's big numbers, visualised.</Description>
        <MainBody>Find #BBCGoFigure on Twitter and on Facebook
Latest Tweets
From BBC News Magazine @BBCNewsMagazine
German women would kill their children and themselves to avoid being raped by Soviet soldiers http://t.co/WfWoH5mjPe http://t.co/p6ZhvS0NGo
2 minutes ago
Burundi students tell @MaudJullien they spent the night by the US embassy as it was the only place they felt safe http://t.co/Xk25ZHFr36
31 minutes ago
RT @BBCMonitoring : South Korea students hold snoozing contest to tackle exam stress http://t.co/jpJJWdyuZw #NewsfromElsewhere http://t.co/s
56 minutes ago
Content from Twitter. Learn more about content from Twitter.
News navigation
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Fri Apr 24 19:46:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 things we didn't know last week</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-magazine-monitor-32429711#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The taste of shipwrecked champagne, and other news nuggets.</Description>
        <MainBody>10 things we didn't know last week
News snippets Sliced and diced for your convenience
24 April 2015
Subscribe to the BBC News Magazine's email newsletter to get articles sent to your inbox.
Latest Tweets
From BBC News Magazine @BBCNewsMagazine
German women would kill their children and themselves to avoid being raped by Soviet soldiers http://t.co/WfWoH5mjPe http://t.co/p6ZhvS0NGo
2 minutes ago
Burundi students tell @MaudJullien they spent the night by the US embassy as it was the only place they felt safe http://t.co/Xk25ZHFr36
31 minutes ago
RT @BBCMonitoring : South Korea students hold snoozing contest to tackle exam stress http://t.co/jpJJWdyuZw #NewsfromElsewhere http://t.co/s
57 minutes ago
Content from Twitter. Learn more about content from Twitter.
News navigation
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:10:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sex-on-duty policeman is jailed</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-stoke-staffordshire-32551145#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A police officer who had sex with vulnerable women while on duty is jailed for three years.</Description>
        <MainBody>PC Adam Rushton is jailed for sexual misconduct
1 May 2015
From the section Stoke &amp; Staffordshire
Adam Rushton has been branded a "disgrace"
A police officer who had sex with vulnerable women while on duty has been jailed for three years.
PC Adam Rushton, 37, who was branded "a disgrace to the police service", was sentenced at Birmingham Crown Court for five counts of misconduct.
Rushton, of Newcastle-under-Lyme, Staffordshire, was also found guilty of breaching data protection laws.
The ex-Staffordshire Police officer was based in Longton, Stoke-on-Trent when the offences took place.
'Frightened women'
Rushton's conviction relates to five women he met while working, two of whom he was found guilty of having sex with when on duty.
The offences spanned four years, from 2008 to 2012.
During his three-week trial, prosecutor Duncan Bould said the officer's duties had brought him into contact with "vulnerable and frightened" women, often in "extreme circumstances".
Rushton, who has been with the force for 10 years, said it was "not very professional" to go to one woman's home for oral sex, while separately sleeping with two others.
Rushton denied his actions amounted to criminal misconduct
However, he rejected claims his conduct amounted to criminal misbehaviour.
Judge Murray Creed said it was concerning to hear colleagues had tried to warn Rushton over his behaviour, and said that on one occasion "you did not tell the truth to senior officers seeking to help you".
'Smelled of garlic'
The court heard the most serious incident involved a very vulnerable victim Rushton had visited in uniform at her home.
He had made up the reason for the visit - accusing her over a "bogus cyber bullying issue" - and convinced her to expose herself as part of his fake investigation, the court heard.
Judge Creed said: "Plainly that must have been humiliating."
Another woman he met through an internet dating site and he was found guilty of receiving oral sex from her during a work-time break.
He was also convicted of going to her home, while in uniform, with the intention of having sexual contact.
The judge said: "She believed you wanted to have sex, but in any event it didn't take place as she found you smelled of garlic."
Deputy Chief Constable Nick Baker said: "Adam Rushton brought shame on himself, his colleagues and Staffordshire Police.
"I hope it [the sentence] brings some comfort to those who have suffered as a result of Adam Rushton's actions."
Rushton was dismissed by Staffordshire Police Chief Constable Jane Sawyers after a misconduct hearing on Monday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:10:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dinghy prank man in lifeboat rescue</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-norfolk-32549602#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A man who was pushed out to sea in a dinghy for a joke by his friends and then carried off by strong winds is rescued by lifeboat crews.</Description>
        <MainBody>Great Yarmouth dinghy prank man in lifeboat rescue
1 May 2015
From the section Norfolk
The unnamed 22-year-old was "lucky" as the dinghy could have been blown into shipping lanes, the lifeboat service said
A man who was pushed out to sea in a dinghy for a joke by his friends and then carried off by strong winds has been rescued by lifeboat crews.
Great Yarmouth and Gorleston lifeboats were called to reports of a man, 22, in a dinghy near Britannia Pier, Great Yarmouth on Thursday afternoon.
He did not have any paddles when he was found. He was taken to Gorleston.
Lifeboat crews said it was a "prank gone wrong", and Coxswain Paddy Lee added: "He is a very lucky man".
"This could have easily been a different outcome. He was being blown offshore into wind farm traffic and shipping lanes.
"The dinghy was losing air. The sea is still very cold," he said.
The rescued man had been dressed in shorts and a T-shirt and did not have any paddles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:25:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Post-election talk dominates campaign</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2015-scotland-32543559#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Ed Miliband visits Scotland the day after appearing to rule out a deal with the SNP - even it meant putting the Conservatives in power.</Description>
        <MainBody>Election 2015: Post-election talk dominates campaign
1 May 2015
Ed Miliband is to visit Scotland the day after appearing to rule out a deal with the SNP - even it meant putting the Conservatives in power.
It comes after SNP leader Nicola Sturgeon said Scottish voters would never forgive Labour if it allowed the Conservatives back into office.
The Tories said Mr Miliband faced "wipeout by the Sturgeon tsunami".
The Liberal Democrats have claimed the SNP views the election as a stepping stone to another independence vote.
Labour leader Mr Miliband said during a special BBC Question Time programme on Thursday evening that a Labour government is "not going to happen" if the price of power was doing a deal with the SNP.
He added: "I'm not going to sacrifice the future of our country, the unity of our country, I'm not going to give in to SNP demands around Trident, around the deficit or anything like that."
Scottish founder
Mr Miliband has come under sustained pressure from the Conservatives throughout the election campaign over the prospect of a Labour-SNP deal in the event of a hung parliament.
Ms Sturgeon faced questions from a studio audience on BBC Scotland following Mr Miliband's appearance on Question Time.
She said: "I heard Ed Miliband and he sounded awfully like he was saying, and I hope that I am wrong about this because I think people across Scotland and much of the UK will be appalled if I am right, he sounded as if he was saying that he would rather see David Cameron and the Conservatives back in government than actually work with the SNP.
"Now, if he means that then I don't think people in Scotland will ever forgive Labour for allowing the Conservatives back into office."
Polls have suggested Labour is facing the prospect of a heavy defeat in its former Scottish stronghold, with the SNP on course to win the vast majority of seats.
Keir Hardie was the main founder of the Labour Party in 1900
During the Labour rally in Glasgow, Mr Miliband will evoke the names of Labour's Scottish founder Keir Hardie and the architects of devolution John Smith and Donald Dewar, and ask Scots who their parents and grandparents would want to lead the country.
Mr Miliband will say the UK "could be on the verge of electing a Labour government", and will add: "Nationalism never built a school. It never lifted people out of poverty. It never created a welfare state that healed the sick and protected our most vulnerable.
"It is Labour values, Labour ideas and the determination of people across Scotland that has built this country to what it is today."
Ms Sturgeon will make campaign stops in East Lothian, Dundee and Fife on Friday as she takes the SNP's message to communities around the country.
Ms Sturgeon said: "Ed Miliband's disastrous revelation that he would rather let the Tories back in than work with the SNP to keep them out will galvanise even more people to vote SNP. Already, more than half a million people who voted Labour at the last general election are journeying to voting SNP next Thursday.
"Ed Miliband has allowed his campaign to be dictated and pushed around by the Tories south of the border - and Labour will pay a heavy price in Scotland."
'Cap in hand'
Elsewhere, Scottish Conservative leader Ruth Davidson was to join Borders candidate John Lamont at a rally followed by a street stall event in Galashiels.
Ms Davidson said on Thursday that the choice facing voters in next Thursday's election was between "a party which will keep Scotland's economy strong and keep Scotland in the UK and a weak Labour government haggling with the SNP over how to run the UK".
A Conservative spokesman said: "Ed Miliband is heading to Scotland cap in hand for votes invoking the past not focusing on the future.
"It goes to show that, next Friday, Ed Miliband cannot be prime minister without being propped up by the SNP. If you want to stop that happening, vote Conservative on 7 May."
Meanwhile, Scottish Lib Dem leader Willie Rennie met therapy animals as he revealed plans to boost mental health services.
Mr Rennie visited volunteers from Canine Concern in Edinburgh. The group's Therapet programme brings together pet owners with individuals struggling with mental or physical ill health.
Mr Rennie said his party would use their planned 800m investment in the NHS in Scotland to rebalance support between physical and mental health services.
On potential post-election deals, he said the voters faced a choice between a government influenced by Nigel Farage, Alex Salmond or the Liberal Democrats.
Mr Rennie insisted the Lib Dems would hold politics in the centre ground and help keep the economy on track fairly, and said Scotland needed to focus on the issues that mattered rather than a second independence referendum.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:08:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Funeral for unidentified baby boy</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-edinburgh-east-fife-32545381#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>More than 200 people have turned up for the funeral of an unidentified baby boy found dead on a path two years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Funeral for unidentified baby boy
1 May 2015
From the section Edinburgh, Fife &amp; East Scotland
The minister leading the service said people had been touched by the story of the little boy
More than 200 people have turned out for the funeral of an unidentified baby boy found dead on a path two years ago.
The remains of the infant, thought to be up to six weeks old, were found wrapped in a blanket on an old railway path in the Seafield area of Edinburgh in July 2013.
His mother or family have never been traced, and his identity remains a mystery.
He was laid to rest following a funeral service at Seafield Cemetery.
The service was arranged by Police Scotland and members of the public were invited to attend.
Leading the service, Reverend Erica Wishart, of Tranent Parish Church, told mourners: "This is the kind of tragedy that surely touches everyone who hears about it. All of us who gather here today are grieving.
"We represent everyone in this community and beyond who feels deep sadness that this tiny baby is never going to have the chance to grow up and live his life."
The minister said those gathered may feel "anger and shock" at what had happened, or perhaps a whole range of emotions.
"We are here to say goodbye to this wee one, with the dignity and respect he deserves. We are here to mourn the life that could have been. And we are here to affirm that every life is precious in God's eyes," she said.
"This baby boy may not have been given a name - we may not know where he came from or who gave birth to him - but the Bible tells us that God knew him even before he was born and his whole being - body, soul and spirit - is engraved on the palm of God's hand."
A number of mourners were visibly tearful as the boy's tiny white coffin was lowered into the ground and as a lone piper played.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:03:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Almost 100 jobs to go at Howden</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-northern-ireland-32550441#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>An engineering factory in east Belfast is set to close with the loss of around 100 jobs.</Description>
        <MainBody>Howden: Around 100 jobs to go at Belfast engineering factory
1 May 2015
From the section Northern Ireland
Staff at Howden on the Queen's Road were given the news on Friday
An engineering factory in east Belfast is set to close with the loss of around 100 jobs.
Howden UK, formerly Sirocco Engineering, is based at Queen's Road and makes equipment for power generation and mining.
The company said most of the work of the Belfast operation would transfer to Glasgow.
Howden is American-owned, operating in more than 17 countries.
A company statement said it would "endeavour" to offer the Belfast workers alternative employment.
It said low cost suppliers were a major threat to its market.
'History'
"This shows no sign of improving with the vast majority of sales opportunities being in lower cost regions such as China, India and South East Asia."
Consultations will now be held with trade unions.
The statement also said the company wanted to "consolidate our manufacturing to fewer sites".
Sirocco Works has been part of the industrial landscape in east Belfast for more than a century.
It was founded in 1881 by Irish inventor and engineer Samuel Davidson.
The company made its name by developing the Sirocco fan, which revolutionised working conditions for miners and factory workers.
It is also credited with developing air conditioning.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:41:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Roads closed in north Belfast alert</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-northern-ireland-32550443#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A number of roads in north Belfast have been closed after police discovered a suspicious object in the area.</Description>
        <MainBody>North Belfast: Several roads closed as police discover suspicious object
1 May 2015
From the section Northern Ireland
Police say a number of roads have been closed in north Belfast as part of an ongoing security alert
Police have closed a number of roads in north Belfast after the discovery of a suspicious object.
Officers are searching areas north of the city and a number of routes are closed to traffic.
They include the Crumlin Road between Ballysillan Road and Cambrai Street, Woodvale Road, between the Ardoyne Roundabout and the Ballygomartin Road, Twaddell Avenue between Ardoyne Roundabout and Ballygomartin Road.
Supt Paula Hilman said: "We apologise for the disruption caused within the area due to the ongoing policing operation."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miliband rules out deal with Plaid</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2015-wales-32548284#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The Labour leader confirms his refusal to work with the SNP in a hung parliament also applies to Plaid Cymru.</Description>
        <MainBody>Election 2015: Ed Miliband says no deal with Plaid Cymru
1 May 2015
From the section Election 2015 Wales
Ed Miliband has confirmed that his refusal to work with the SNP in a hung parliament also applies to Plaid Cymru.
Plaid leader Leanne Wood has said she could do a deal to put Labour in power even if the SNP was not involved.
She said Mr Miliband was irresponsible to rule out an SNP deal, claiming it could "open the door" to the Tories.
The Labour leader said he was "not interested in deals or coalitions", but in being "a Labour prime minister who puts forward a Labour programme".
Family appeal
Speaking at a Labour party rally in Cardiff on Friday, Mr Miliband said it was a "pretty dead cert" that David Cameron wanted to cut child benefit.
Accusing the Conservatives of planning to reduce tax credits for families if they win next week's election, the Labour leader said his first act as prime minister would be to find money to scrap the so-called bedroom tax.
Family finances, he said, were "on the ballot paper at this election".
Mr Miliband said: "For the hundreds of thousands of families in Wales, they should know David Cameron is planning to cut your child benefit. That is the choice in six days' time.
"You've got six days to save your child benefit, and the way to do that is to vote Labour.
"Because Mr Cameron denied he was going to means test child benefit at the last election and then did.
"He's not even denying further cuts to child benefit at this election. So it's a pretty dead cert that that is exactly what he's going to do."
Facing a BBC Question Time audience on Thursday night, Mr Cameron said he did not want to cut child benefit or child tax credits if he won the election, but said it was possible to save more from the welfare budget.
Asked if this amounted to an "absolute guarantee," the prime minister said child tax credit "would not fall" and that child benefit was "one of the most important benefits there is" and did not need to change.
Wage rates
Elsewhere in the election campaign on Friday, Conservative Home Secretary Theresa May is due to visit neighbourhood watch teams in south Wales.
Plaid Cymru leader Leanne Wood is promoting party pledges to scrap zero-hours contracts and raise the minimum wage.
Marking International Workers' Day, she said her party was committed to increasing the minimum wage of 6.50 an hour to the so-called living wage - currently 7.85 an hour - by 2020.
Ms Wood will also be taking part in the second and final TV election debate involving Welsh leaders of the six main parties in Cardiff on Friday evening.
Carwyn Jones passes a household with split loyalties while campaigning in Barry in the Vale of Glamorgan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:39:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>130 factory jobs at risk after fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-south-west-wales-32551451#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Up to 130 jobs are at risk at a Swansea factory which was destroyed by fire after the firm which owns it decided not to replace the unit.</Description>
        <MainBody>130 factory jobs at risk after fire at Pure Wafer, Swansea
1 May 2015
From the section South West Wales
Up to 130 jobs are at risk at a Swansea factory which was destroyed by fire after the firm which owns it decided not to replace the unit.
Nearly 70 firefighters tackled the blaze at Pure Wafer in Llansamlet in December.
The company switched its production of silicon wafers for computer chips to a sister site in the United States.
But now that it has settled its claim with insurers, it has decided not to reopen the Swansea base.
In a statement, Pure Wafer said the decision not rebuild came "after careful consideration of the costs of rebuilding the factory and replacing the specialist machinery, the time which this would take and the fact that many of the customers of the Swansea facility have already migrated to competitors".
The details of the insurance settlement have not been revealed.
Swansea council said it was "extremely disappointed" with the decision.
A spokesperson added: "If our discussions can't convince the company to change its decision then we'll work to mitigate the potential impact this proposal will have on employment in Swansea."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:58:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>African singers against xenophobia</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32548354#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>African music giants Ladysmith Black Mambazo and Salif Keita release a song in response to xenophobic violence in South Africa.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ladysmith and Salif Keita release anti-xenophobia song
1 May 2015
From the section Africa
Ladysmith Black Mambazo's Sibongiseni Shabalala calls for a united Africa
Two of Africa's most famous musicians have released a song against the recent violence against foreigners in South Africa.
The song United We Stand brings together Ladysmith Black Mambazo from South Africa and Malian singer Salif Keita.
Lyrics include the line "Africa is our home, make it a better place".
At least seven people have died over a month of attacks on foreigners and foreign-owned property in South Africa.
Ladysmith Black Mambazo singer Sibongiseni Shabalala told the BBC he was trying to send the message that "Africa is for all of us".
"You can't say you don't like the foreigners to stay in your country. This is not your country, this is our country.
"We are saying people should unite. If there's problems, people should sit down and talk.
Malian singer Salif Keita is known as the "golden voice of Africa"
"One day your child will want to go and live in Mali, Nigeria or Ghana but because of your decision today it will be very difficult for your future generation to be able to do the same."
The song is playing on South African radio from Friday, will be premiered on TV on Friday evening and will be released on iTunes on Monday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:51:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Burundi students flock to US embassy</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32548350#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of students in Burundi have spent the night in front of the US embassy after their university was closed amid anti-government protests.</Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi students of closed university camp out at US embassy
1 May 2015
From the section Africa
Students queue outside the US embassy after their university shut down
Hundreds of students in Burundi have spent the night in front of the US embassy after their university was closed amid anti-government protests.
They told the BBC they went to the embassy as there was no security for them in the capital city Bujumbura.
Social media has been blocked, radio stations closed and protests banned.
People have been protesting since Sunday over President Pierre Nkurunziza's decision to stand for re-election in June.
The government closed the university on Thursday citing "insecurity".
Mr Nkurunziza has already served two terms as president
Earlier on Thursday several hundred students tried to organise a march into the centre of Bujumbura. They wanted to stop the president from officially presenting his nomination papers to the electoral commission.
The students told the BBC's Maud Jullien that the US embassy was the only place they felt safe and that they feared security forces were pursuing them.
She estimates around 500 students are outside the embassy.
The US has not reacted to their presence.
Senior US diplomat Tom Malinowski met Mr Nkurunziza on Thursday, and afterwards said he had warned that the situation in Burundi was "dangerous".
"Some of the measures that have been taken... to shut down social  media, to suspend radio stations not only are wrong as a matter of principle  but very counter-productive," he told journalists.
The protests have been the biggest in Burundi since the civil war ended in 2005.
Mr Nkurunziza, a former rebel leader, has warned that anyone who wants to create problems for the governing party would find himself "in trouble".
People have been protesting against the president running for a third term
Under the constitution, presidents can only be elected to two terms in office but Mr Nkurunziza's allies say his first term does not count as he was appointed by parliament.
Burundi's senate has announced that the constitutional court will examine the legality of the bid.
Mr Nkurunziza has been in power since 2005, when a 12-year civil war officially ended.
More than 300,000 people died in the conflict between the minority Tutsi-dominated army and mainly Hutu rebel groups, such as Mr Nkurunziza's CNDD-FDD.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:00:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uber office in Guangzhou 'raided'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32548712#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Private online car-hire service Uber has its offices in the southern Chinese city of Guangzhou raided by authorities, according to reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Uber office in Guangzhou 'raided'
1 May 2015
From the section Business
Private transport firm Uber has faced legal difficulties in many countries across the world
Private online car-hire service Uber has had its offices in the southern Chinese city of Guangzhou raided by authorities, reports say.
According to local media, the US company is under investigation for "organising private drivers to provide unlicensed businesses".
The local transport, police and industry bodies are said to have seized equipment including mobile phones.
Guangzhou considers car-hire services that involve private drivers illegal.
"Law enforcement departments have come down hard on such illegal businesses as they disrupt the market and we will not be soft on these activities in the future," the Guangzhou Transport Commission said in a recent statement.
Uber first launched in China last year and its service is now available in the capital, Beijing, as well as the cities of Hangzhou, Guangzhou and Shenzhen.
According to reports, Uber's offices in the southern Chinese city of Shenzhen were also visited by authorities this week for a "routine inspection".
In a statement, Uber said it "prides itself on providing efficient and convenient transportation options for riders to get from point to point, helping cities reduce congestion pollution.
"We have maintained open channels of communications and are working closely with local authorities in co-operation."
Analysis: John Sudworth, BBC Shanghai correspondent
China's transport authorities, like those in many other countries, have been struggling to cope with the impact of mobile phone based taxi hailing apps, in particular the huge popularity of the so called ride-sharing service provided by unlicensed, private drivers.
Popular, it seems, because they offer cleaner, more modern cars and, often, a higher level of customer service compared to traditional taxis.
In recent months, some of these drivers, in a number of Chinese cities, have been stopped and fined up to $5,000.
Uber's market share is dwarfed by that of the larger home-grown taxi app companies, Didi Dache and Kuaidi Dache, which recently merged. If the Guangzhou raid is a sign that the government is preparing to get tougher, then some observers will wonder if the smaller, foreign-owned target has been chosen for reasons of political convenience.
Growth problems
Uber has been expanding aggressively in recent years, but has run into problems in a number of countries, including South Korea and India.
The San Francisco-based firm has seen its service banned in both Asian nations - as well as Germany and Sao Paulo in Brazil - because of safety concerns and industry opposition.
In India, for example, Uber came under fire and was banned after a driver in Delhi allegedly raped a female passenger.
The fast-growing start up, which was founding in 2009, is estimated to be worth $40bn following its most recent fundraising round.
Uber operates in more than 250 cities in 57 countries, according to its website.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:52:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police probe slap therapy man</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-australia-32545732#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Australian police are investigating a seven-year-old boy's death following his attendance at a "slapping workshop" by a visiting Chinese therapist.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australian police probe Sydney boy Aidan Fenton's death
1 May 2015
From the section Australia
The health centre said they had rented a room to Xiao Hongchi for a health seminar
Australian police are investigating a seven-year-old boy's death following his attendance at a "slapping workshop" by a visiting Chinese therapist.
Aidan Fenton from Sydney, who reportedly suffered from diabetes, was found unconscious at a hotel in a Sydney suburb on Monday.
He and his mother had attended Xiao Hongchi's workshop on alternative therapies at a health centre in Sydney.
Police are reportedly investigating whether he had stopped taking insulin.
Mr Xiao ran the workshop at the Pan Health Medical Centre in Hurstville, Sydney, from 22-28 April at a cost of AU$1,800 (928, $1,420).
'Clear the meridians'
The therapist has been interviewed by police and has since left the country, the Sydney Morning Herald said. A spokeswoman for the New South Wales (NSW) police said this was standard procedure following any unexplained death.
NSW police told the BBC ambulance services were called to a hotel in Hurstville after a family member found the boy unconscious.
Traditional Chinese medicine, including cupping therapy (above). is seen as an alternative or a replacement for modern Western practices.
"Paramedics performed CPR on the boy, but he was pronounced dead at the scene, and an investigation into the boy's death is underway," NSW police said in a statement.
Tasly Healthpac Australia, the owner of Pan-Health Management Centre, said in a statement: "We are deeply saddened to learn the unexpected passing of this young boy... from the information that we have, the boy was not a patient of Pan-Health and had not been treated by any of our doctors.
Xiao Hongchi advocates repeated slapping to clear the blood of toxins
"Mr Xiao rented a room from our centre to conduct what was described to us as a series of health seminars. The boy and his mother were participants in the seminar."
Mr Xiao, a former investment banker, advocates the practise of paida lajin, a therapy which involved slapping and stretching the body to drive out toxins.
"The slapping and stretching work together to clear the meridians of blocks and help the body get rid of disease," he told The Hindu newspaper last month.
He said the practice, taught to him by a Taoist monk, had "cured" several medical conditions at his workshops, including diabetes and hypertension.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:00:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Airbus to sue over German spying row</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32542140#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Aviation giant Airbus says it will file a criminal complaint over allegations in the media that German spies helped the US carry out industrial espionage.</Description>
        <MainBody>Airbus to sue over US-German spying row
1 May 2015
From the section Europe
Aviation giant Airbus says it will file a criminal complaint over allegations that German intelligence helped the US carry out industrial espionage.
German media reports suggest the country's spy agency BND collected data on European firms at the behest of the US National Security Agency.
An Airbus statement quoted by AFP news agency said it was "alarmed" by the reports but did not want to speculate.
The company said it had asked for more information from the German government.
"We are aware that large companies in the sector, like ours, are targets of espionage," read the statement.
"However, in this case we are alarmed because there is concrete suspicion."
Leaks from a secret BND document suggest that its monitoring station at Bad Aibling checked whether European companies were breaking trade embargos after a request from the NSA.
German Interior Minister Thomas de Maiziere is under pressure over the revelations
Embarrassment in Berlin - the BBC's Jenny Hill writes:
There is mounting pressure on the German government to disclose how much it knew about the espionage.
In the firing line is Interior Minister Thomas de Maiziere, who in 2008 was the minister in charge of the chancellery and directly responsible for the BND.
He insists he knew nothing about malpractice within the secret service.
Tabloid newspaper Bild printed a picture of Mr de Maiziere on Wednesday- his nose elongated to Pinocchio proportions.
"Herr de Maiziere!" the accompanying headline screamed, "You lie with impunity!"
Spy scandal turns tables on Merkel government
Airbus was named by the German press as one of the firms that was targeted.  It is believed that BND eavesdropped on online, phone and other communications in order to gather information.
It is also alleged that it spied on France's presidential palace and foreign ministry, and the European Commission.
According to the reports, the agency did not target German or US officials in the surveillance, as they are protected by a BND-NSA agreement signed in 2002.
However, it has emerged that the German government knew about NSA spying on European arms businesses as early as 2008. The government found "shortcomings" in the BND's operations, German TV reports.
Interior Minister Thomas de Maiziere has denied claims of a cover-up.
Mr de Maiziere said he had no knowledge of malpractice at German intelligence agencies, but called for the internal BND report to be presented to a parliamentary committee.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:50:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy opens 'feed the planet' Expo</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32546961#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A major global commercial fair - Milan Expo 2015 - opens in northern Italy with feeding the planet as its theme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Milan Expo: Italy opens major 'feeding the planet' fair
1 May 2015
From the section Europe
US ambassador John Phillips opened the American pavilion
A major global commercial fair - Milan Expo 2015 - has opened in northern Italy with food as the theme.
Italy, stuck in recession, hopes the fair will be a big money-spinner. Ten million tickets have been sold already for the six-month event.
Representatives of 145 countries are in Milan for the fair, which boasts 54 national pavilions at a sprawling site .
The food theme focuses on nutrition and combating hunger globally. But it is also a showcase for Italian cuisine.
Ahead of the opening several officials in the Expo organising body were arrested for corruption.
Some groups have criticised the fair, calling it a symbol of big business interests, and have pledged to stage protests. There was an anti-globalisation march by students in Milan on Thursday.
Italy hopes the fair, covering a one million sq m (10.7m sq ft) site, will attract some 20 million visitors.
Italy's Prime Minister Matteo Renzi will speak at the official opening ceremony shortly, which features a display by the Frecce Tricolore aerobatic team.
China's exhibit highlights the country's success in conquering food shortages
Israel focuses on the transformation of arid soil into fertile land
Italy's pavilion is called "the nursery" with a tree as the central symbol
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:30:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Colombian spy chief jailed</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32544248#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The former head of Colombia's secret police, Maria del Pilar Hurtado, is jailed for 14 years for spying on politicians, judges and journalists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ex-Colombia spy chief Maria del Pilar Hurtado jailed for 14 years
1 May 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Maria del Pilar Hurtado fled Colombia in 2010 and was granted asylum in Panama
The former head of Colombia's secret police, Maria del Pilar Hurtado, has been jailed for 14 years for spying on politicians, judges and journalists.
The 51-year-old was in charge of the now-defunct Administrative Security Department (DAS), when the offences occurred between 2007 and 2008.
She was convicted of intercepting phone calls and abusing public office.
Those targeted were political opponents of Alvaro Uribe, who was president at the time.
Mr Uribe's former chief of staff, Bernardo Moreno, was given an eight year sentence for his involvement, to be served at his home.
Colombia's Supreme Court has also called for Mr Uribe to be investigated for his role in the scandal.
He is now a senator and the head of a right-wing opposition party.
The former president tweeted that he would answer the court on Tuesday and that he was saddened to hear about the sentencing of his former aides.
Mr Uribe has denied any knowledge of the illegal intercepts.
The allegations were made public in 2010, after Mr Uribe left office.
Hurtado fled to Colombia at the time and was granted asylum in Panama.
She turned herself over to the authorities in January after it was revoked.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 18:51:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-leaders express Venezuela concerns</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32532865#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A group of 26 former heads of state and governments demands that the Venezuelan government release jailed opposition leaders.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ex-leaders demand jailed Venezuela politicians be freed
30 April 2015
From the section Latin America &amp; Caribbean
Supporters of the jailed opposition leaders say their arrests were politically motivated
A group of former world leaders has sent an open letter to the Venezuelan government expressing its concern "for the difficult social, economic and political situation" in Venezuela.
The group also urged the release of opposition leaders who were jailed for allegedly inciting violence.
The letter was signed by 26 ex-leaders from Latin America, Europe, Africa and Asia.
Venezuela has not yet responded to their appeal
Deadly protests
The signatories are members of the Madrid Club, an independent organisation made up of former heads of state and government.
They include former Brazilian President Henrique Cardoso, the ex-leader of Mexico, Felipe Calderon, as well as former Polish President Aleksander Kwasniewski, Dutch ex-Prime Minister Ruud Lubbers and the former president of Nigeria, Olusegun Obasanjo.
Colombia's former president, Andres Pastrana (left) and Mexico's ex-leader, Felipe Calderon, were among those who signed the letter
In their letter, they call for the release of "all those citizens who are in prison today for having exercised their right to freedom of expression", including Caracas Mayor Antonio Ledezma and opposition leaders Leopoldo Lopez and Daniel Ceballos.
They go on to demand that former Spanish Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez be allowed to travel to Venezuela to work with Mr Lopez's defence counsel.
They also claim their "right to appear in the oral hearing of Leopoldo Lopez", scheduled for mid-May.
Mr Lopez handed himself in to the authorities in February last year.
He is on trial on charges of inciting violence at mass protests which swept through Venezuela in the first half of last year.
Forty-three people from both sides of the political divide died during several months of protests.
Not welcome
Venezuela's National Assembly last week declared Mr Gonzalez "persona non grata" after President Maduro accused him of waging a "psychological war" with the aim of destabilising Venezuela.
Felipe Gonzalez wants to travel to Venezuela to attend the hearing of Leopoldo Lopez
Last month, President Maduro called Felipe Gonzalez a "lobbyist, who is getting a huge salary in euros for publicly joining the campaign against Venezuela, backing a coup against the country, a coup against me".
Felipe Gonzalez, who trained as a lawyer before becoming Prime Minister of Spain from 1982 to 1996, had announced earlier that he would join the team defending Mr Lopez and Mr Ledezma.
Mr Ledezma was arrested in February and charged with conspiracy. He is accused of backing an alleged plot to depose President Maduro.
Mr Ledezma, like Mr Lopez and Mr Ceballos, is a member of the opposition.
Their supporters say the charges against them are politically motivated, but the government argues they want to violently overthrow the democratically elected government of Mr Maduro.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:29:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saudis 'repel Houthi border attack'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32537543#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Three Saudi troops and "dozens" of Houthi rebels were killed as Saudi forces repelled a major attack from inside Yemen, Saudi officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen crisis: Saudi Arabia 'repels Houthi border attack'
1 May 2015
From the section Middle East
Houthi rebels launched an assault on border posts in Najran, Saudi officials say
Three Saudi troops and "dozens" of Houthi rebels were killed as Saudi forces repelled a major attack from inside Yemen, Saudi officials say.
The rebels attacked near the town of Najran, reports say, in what would be their biggest assault on Saudi soil since a Saudi military campaign began.
A Saudi-led coalition has staged air strikes against rebels since late March in support of Yemen's exiled president.
Meanwhile aid groups say a lack of fuel is threatening their operations there.
Interactive video: Why my country is in a mess
A statement by the Saudi Press Agency, SPA, said the overnight attack happened on its southern border.
Identifying the attackers as Shia Houthi rebels and groups allied to them, SPA said Saudi ground troops exchanged fire with them and called in air strikes.
The rebels - who control much of northern Yemen, including the capital Sanaa - have been fighting forces linked to the government for several months.
Saudi Arabia and other Arab states have been carrying out air strikes over the last month, with the declared aim of restoring exiled President Abdrabbuh Mansour Hadi.
'Snipers in the streets'
Earlier on Thursday, a Saudi border guard was killed by a mortar shell close to the border with Yemen in the south-west Saudi province of Jizan. Seventeen Saudi troops have been killed in attacks by Yemeni rebels during the last five weeks.
More than 300,000 people have been forced to flee their homes in Yemen
Aid agencies say that they are especially concerned about the plight of children
Meanwhile, UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon said that he was gravely concerned about the "continued ground fighting and aerial bombardment in Yemen and its impact on innocent civilians".
More than 1,200 people have been killed and 300,000 have fled their homes in the past six weeks, according to the UN.
"There are credible reports of families in Aden trapped by the bombardment and snipers targeting civilians in the street," a statement from Mr Ban said.
He called for an immediate ceasefire and urged all parties to ensure that humanitarian agencies have safe and reliable access.
The UN estimates half the country is suffering from food shortages
On Thursday, the UN's World Food Programme (WFP) said it had been forced to withdraw from the western Hudaydah province after running out of fuel there - and that it may have to pull out of other areas soon.
The warning was echoed by the International Committee for the Red Cross, that said a lack of fuel - as well as restrictions on imports - meant hospitals were struggling to provide an adequate level of care .
Purnima Kashyap, the WFP's country director in Yemen, said: "This is a country where half the population are considered food-insecure, meaning that many families do not know where their next meal will come from."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:44:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shake-up in Saudi state oil firm</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32552594#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Aramco, the Saudi state oil company, is to be separated from the oil ministry as part of a wider restructuring.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saudi Arabia shakes up state oil firm Aramco
1 May 2015
From the section Business
Saudi Arabia's state oil company is to be separated from the oil ministry as part of a wider restructuring.
The move was approved by the Supreme Economic Council, which was set up by King Salman this year to replace the Supreme Petroleum Council.
The new 10-member council is headed by the King's son, Prince Mohammed bin Salman.
He was appointed this week as the new deputy crown prince and is regarded as second in line to the throne.
On Wednesday, King Salman appointed Saudi Aramco's chief executive as chairman of the company and health minister as part of a major political reshuffle.
The main facets of Saudi oil policy - including maintaining the ability to stabilise markets by holding extensive reserves and a reluctance to interfere in the market for political reasons - are set by the top members of the ruling royal family.
There are no signs that the move will lead to any significant changes in the way that the world's top oil exporter and de facto Opec leader makes its decisions.
However, separating Aramco from the oil ministry is likely to be just the first step in a shake-up of the Saudi oil sector, according to analysts.
Mohammad al-Sabban, a former senior adviser to Saudi oil minister Ali al-Naimi, said: "This decision will bring more flexibility to the company to take decisions on a commercial basis, and keep full financial control."
Delicate balance
The move could pave the way for a prince to be appointed as the next oil minister to replace 79-year-old Mr al-Naimi.
It had been thought that the royal family regarded the role of oil minister as so important that giving it to a prince could upset the kingdom's delicate balance of power and risk making oil policy hostage to bickering among the many princes.
Earlier this year, King Salman promoted his son, Prince Abdulaziz bin Salman - a long-serving member of Saudi Arabia's Opec delegation - to the role of deputy oil minister from assistant oil minister.
Ehsan ul-Haq, oil analyst at KBC Energy Economics, said it was highly likely that Prince Abdulaziz, a son of the King, could be appointed oil minister.
"[Falih's] shift to the health ministry suggests that he might not follow Naimi. His appointment to the chairman of Aramco, on the other hand, is only ceremonial," he said.
Aramco could not be reached for comment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:04:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chicago 'to host Obama library'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32544101#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>President Barack Obama has chosen his hometown of Chicago as the location for his presidential library, ahead of New York City and Hawaii, US media report.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chicago 'to host Barack Obama's library'
1 May 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Obama is a big fan of Chicago White Sox
Chicago has beaten New York City and Hawaii as the chosen location for President Barack Obama's library, according to US media.
The winning proposal will be "connected to" the University of Chicago, although the site has not been decided on yet, NBC in Chicago reports .
The president was a law professor at the university and still has a home on the city's South Side.
The library will store his papers and help frame his legacy as president.
A formal announcement will be made the week after next, reports CBS .
It says the president indicated he was leaning towards choosing his hometown in a recent phone call with Chicago Mayor Rahm Emanuel, once his closest adviser at the White House.
Mr Obama met his wife, First Lady Michelle, when working at a law firm in the city in 1989.
The losing cities also have strong connections to the Obama story - he grew up in Hawaii and attended Columbia University in New York.
The other Chicago bid that completed the shortlist of four was from the University of Illinois.
The 13 presidential libraries - spanning from Herbert Hoover to George W Bush - are administered by the US National Archives.
Former President Bill Clinton's presidential library is in Little Rock and George W Bush has one at the Southern Methodist University in Dallas.
All five living presidents gathered for the dedication of the Bush library in 2013, a ceremony that moved Mr Bush to tears.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="60">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:29:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Navy to assist ships through Gulf</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-32543904#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>US Navy ships are to accompany US-flagged vessels through the Strait of Hormuz, after Iran detained a Danish cargo ship in the area.</Description>
        <MainBody>US Navy to assist US-flagged ships through Strait of Hormuz
30 April 2015
From the section US &amp; Canada
Ships in the Strait of Hormuz in January 2012
Defence officials have said that US Navy ships will accompany US-flagged commercial vessels through the Strait of Hormuz, to make sure they are not interfered with by Iran.
Iranian patrol boats surrounded a US cargo ship in the strait on Friday.
Earlier this week, Iranian naval ships reportedly fired warning shots near a Marshall Islands-flagged cargo ship before seizing it and its crew.
The strait connects the Arabian Sea and the Persian Gulf.
The US navy will not be escorting the ships - a different procedure from accompanying them. Instead, it will monitor the area as the ships pass across the strait.
The crew of the Marshall Islands-flagged container ship seized by Iran in the strait on Tuesday are safe and "in good spirits", Danish shipping company Maersk said.
Maersk said it still did not know the reason why the Marshall Islands-flagged vessel was seized, and noted it had been in an international shipping lane.
Iranian media cited an official as saying the ship was seized based on a court order in connection with a complaint made by a private Iranian company about debts.
The crew includes a British national, but no Americans, as initial reports suggested.
The narrow strait lies partly in Iranian waters.
Shipping traffic is allowed to pass through under an internationally-recognised protocol called "innocent passage", so long as the ships are not carrying weapons, collecting intelligence, or violating other restrictions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="61">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:37:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In pictures: The Sim Project</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-32529571#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Robotic patients helping doctors to learn</Description>
        <MainBody>In pictures: The Sim Project
1 May 2015 Last updated at 03:37
The Sim Project, by photographer Alicia Bruce, documents the robotic patients used globally for medical teaching.
The Sim Project, by photographer Alicia Bruce, documents the robotic patients used globally for medical teaching.
Bruce visited centres in Scotland and in North America, where medical students operate on lifelike hi-tech mannequins in simulated theatres.
Captivated by the "theatrical possibilities of the situation", Bruce felt the operation "became very real as the doctors fought to save Stans [the mannequin's] life".
"Im interested in the tensions between real and unreal, staged and unstaged, familiar and unfamiliar, the moment where belief is suspended," she says.
The work was supported by the Royal Scottish Academy Morton Award (for artists working in lens-based media), which she won in August last year.
She also photographed a SimBaby, two children and SimMom, a pregnant woman mannequin.
A film, Sim Scenario, and other works from The Sim Project by Alicia Bruce are on show at The Royal Scottish Academy Annual exhibition until 3 June 2015.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="62">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 18:35:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In pictures: Clandon Park House fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-32529573#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Images of the aftermath of a fire at Grade I listed Clandon Park House.</Description>
        <MainBody>In pictures: Clandon Park House fire
30 April 2015
From the section In Pictures
A fire at Grade I listed Clandon Park House, near Guildford, Surrey, has led to widespread damage to the house that was home to a prized collection of 18th Century furniture, porcelain and textiles.
As the fire raged, some items of value were rescued from the property.
At one point, about 80 firefighters tackled the blaze, which spread quickly having begun at about 16:00 BST on Wednesday.
Fire-damaged timbers can be seen through the broken windows of the property.
National Trust conservators have been at work. Here, they unroll an 18th Century painting of Richard Onslow, Speaker of the House of Commons, which was cut from its frame by the fire brigade in order to remove it from the flames engulfing the house.
Other items that have been saved include this fragment of an antique book.
Pieces of antique furniture that survived have also been removed to a nearby location.
Dame Helen Ghosh, director general of the National Trust, said the stately home was essentially "a shell" after most of the roof, lintel, ceiling and floors collapsed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="63">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 18:16:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Election 2015 in pictures: 30 April</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-32529572#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Images from the campaign trail: 30 April</Description>
        <MainBody>Election 2015 in pictures: 30 April
30 April 2015
From the section In Pictures
SNP leader and First Minister Nicola Sturgeon was in Edinburgh to launch her party's final poster of the election campaign. No, not that one...
This one. On Thursday, her campaign was boosted by the news the Scottish Sun newspaper had come out in favour of the SNP in this election, saying it will "fight harder for Scotland's interests at Westminster".
Candidate Ian Paisley Jr bounced on a trampoline for the cameras while out canvassing for the Democratic Unionist Party in Ballymoney, County Antrim.
Green Party leader Natalie Bennett visited Ridley Road Market in the London borough of Hackney. An Ipsos Mori opinion poll suggested her party could win 8% of the vote.
UKIP candidate Chris Adams joked with a child in the market square in Aylesbury, Buckinghamshire, ahead of a visit by party leader Nigel Farage.
UKIP Leader Nigel Farage (centre) is hoping candidate Chris Adams (left) can win the seat from the Conservative Party. It was a seat, he said, that could produce a "real shock".
Nicola Sturgeon boarded an SNP branded helicopter at Prestonfield House as she began a tour of Scotland.
In Dewsbury, West Yorkshire, Ed Miliband answered questions on Labour's plans ahead of Thursday evening's leaders' special Question Time programme chaired by David Dimbleby.
Prime Minister David Cameron was also in West Yorkshire, meeting potential supporters in Wetherby.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="64">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 00:22:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vietnam War by Associated Press photographers</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-32483307#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>AP photographers mark 40th anniversary of fall of Saigon</Description>
        <MainBody>Vietnam War by Associated Press photographers
28 April 2015
From the section In Pictures
Warning: Readers may find some of the images disturbing
To mark the 40th anniversary of the fall of Saigon and the end of the Vietnam War, an exhibition in London by the US news agency Associated Press showcases some of its most striking images taken by photographers embedded with US troops fighting the Communist Viet Cong.
During the conflict, AP's Saigon bureau won six Pulitzer Prizes for its war coverage, four of them for photography.
During the 1960s and 70s, the Saigon bureau gathered together a group of some of the most experienced photojournalists, including Malcolm Browne, Nick Ut, Eddie Adams, Hugh van Es, Dang van Phuoc and French-Vietnamese photographer Henri Huet who captured this shot in 1966 of the body of an American paratrooper killed in action in the jungle near the Cambodian border being raised up to an evacuation helicopter.
The celebrated combat photographer Horst Faas served as AP's Saigon photo chief at the height of the war. Speaking to the BBC in 2007, Faas described his job in simple terms. "I tried to be in the newspapers every day, to beat the opposition with better photos. I didn't try to do anything grandiose. The photos were used and published and asked for, because Vietnam was on the front pages year after year."
While in Saigon, Faas trained and mentored young Vietnamese photographers who made many of the war's defining images. Their daily photos from Vietnam helped inform the world of the traumas faced by people caught in the cross-fire of conflict.
From a journalist's perspective the war in Vietnam was unique. It was the first war in modern times without censorship, where reporters and photographers were allowed virtually unrestricted access to the battlefields.
AP photographers captured images that quickly became synonymous with the conflict: among the most notable was Eddie Adams's image of the South Vietnamese Gen Nguyen Ngoc Loan killing a Viet Cong officer with a single shot to the head. The image was to change the public perception of the war and haunted Gen Loan until his death.
Another was Nick Ut's picture of nine-year-old Phan Thi Kim Phuc - a young girl, running naked and terrified down the road after a napalm attack - which became one of the iconic images of the entire conflict.
Nearly 60,000 US soldiers died in Vietnam, with more than 300,000 injured. For the Vietnamese, though, the figures were far higher, with estimates of more than half a million killed and many millions wounded.
Vietnam: The Real War, A Photographic History by the Associated Press will run until the end of May 2015 at the Guardian News and Media's gallery, King's Cross, London.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="65">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 17:46:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Election 2015 in pictures: 29 April</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-32515926#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Images from the campaign trail: 29 April</Description>
        <MainBody>Election 2015 in pictures: 29 April
29 April 2015
From the section In Pictures
Labour leader Ed Miliband spoke at the Royal Institute of British Architects in London where cupcakes reflected the theme of his message.
Mr Miliband said: "Seven-and-a-half million families would lose an average of 760 a year if David Cameron was re-elected."
Shadow chancellor Ed Balls added: "As for David Cameron's promises on VAT, they're not worth the 2010 manifesto paper they were written on."
Prime Minister David Cameron met workers at the site of a new Marks and Spencer in Longbridge.
Mr Cameron then spoke at the Sertec Group in Coleshill, where he said take-home pay would go up with the Conservatives and down with Labour - because Ed Miliband would increase taxes.
Meanwhile, Samantha Cameron was drumming up support in Hounslow with Conservative candidate Mary Macleod, here at the home of local businessman Baljinder Hansra.
SNP leader and First Minister Nicola Sturgeon delivered a speech in Glasgow on the day a new poll suggested that her party could win all 59 Scottish seats in the general election.
SNP candidate Mhairi Black, at 20 years old, is the youngest person standing in the general election. She is going head to head with Labour's Douglas Alexander in Paisley and Renfrewshire South.
Jim Murphy took the Scottish Labour Party message to a day centre in Glasgow.
During a visit to Tayside, Scottish Conservative leader Ruth Davidson focused on defence - specifically the need to renew Trident and ensure the armed forces are properly equipped.
Later in the day Mr Balls was back in front of the cameras again, this time with shadow work and pensions secretary Rachel Reeves, during a visit to the Book Nook bookshop in Hove, East Sussex. Together they delivered their interpretation of the children's book, We're Going On a Bear Hunt.
Deputy PM Nick Clegg was visiting a school in Chippenham, with his wife, Miriam. He said: "The Conservatives want to impose billions of pounds of cuts on schools like this and nurseries and colleges up and down the country."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="66">
        <date>Tue Apr 28 04:15:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heavily loaded</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-32479496#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Queuing for the journey from Italy to Tunisia</Description>
        <MainBody>From the section In Pictures
So far this year more than 35,000 people fleeing war and poverty in Africa are thought to have crossed to Europe, with many having died while attempting the journey. Yet on a Saturday the port of Palermo is full of cars loaded with goods heading the other way, from Italy to north Africa.
Photographer Eugenio Grosso took pictures of the heavily loaded cars, mainly belonging to Tunisian immigrants who gather to take a ferry to Tunis.  Grosso says that some of them are travelling home for a holiday, while others are professional sellers who go back and forth each week, following in the footsteps of their ancestors.
"All of them carry something to sell. Since the economic crisis hit Europe, numerous immigrants have lost their jobs. By reviving the old practice of sea trade, these people have created a new chance for business and an effective way to deal with the slump."
"In the era of globalisation, when huge cargo ships move products from one corner of the world to another, these immigrants are modern safe-keepers of a much older custom."
"As well as their products, these people bring along their traditions and knowledge, contributing to the ongoing creation of the Mediterranean culture."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="67">
        <date>Tue Apr 28 06:01:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The race to cover a mosque in mud</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-32485152#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Thousands race to replaster a massive mosque in a day</Description>
        <MainBody>The race to cover a Mali mosque in mud
28 April 2015
From the section Africa
Every year for one day a whole town of thousands gets together to cover this massive mosque in Mali in mud as Alex Duval Smith &amp; Nadia Zephinie report.
There has been a mosque on this site Djenne since the 13 Century. The current structure is the largest earthen building in the world. People manage to get to the top to slap on mud.
They do so by using these ladders made of timber and rope. The erosion is caused by the rain and cracks are caused by changes in temperature and humidity.
Even though thousands of people took part in applying the mud, no serious injuries were recorded.
Teams compete to finish first. "There is no prize but the honour lasts all year. You gain respect," says 15-year-old Abdoulaye Sahampo.
Teenagers pass up their baskets of mud to teams of masons who slap it on the walls.
The younger children scrape the mud from the river bed. Mason Limbo Bocoum chants the names of their favourite food. He says they work better if they are looking forward to a good meal.
It is the one day of the year where children can get as muddy as they like and their mothers will not complain.
Master mason Boubacar Kouroumansse noticed more people bringing Malian flags this year. He suggests people want to demonstrate their attachment to their country at a time of violence.
By 08:00 it is already more than 30C in Djenne and the render that was pasted on the front of the mosque at 05:00 is almost dry.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="68">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 14:04:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal earthquake: Devastation in maps and images</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32479909#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Before and after satellite images and maps</Description>
        <MainBody>How a search and rescue operation is carried out

Strong buildings

Rescue workers need to be swift to assess where they are most likely to find survivors inside collapsed buildings. Stairwells or the spaces under large concrete beams can provide what rescue workers call 'voids', in which people may have survived.
Video cameras

Video cameras placed on the end of flexible poles can be squeezed through gaps in the rubble to help locate survivors. Using this technique means time is saved as less rubble is shifted unnecessarily. Thermal imaging equipment can also be used to locate survivors as their body heat can warm the rubble around them.
Listening for survivors

Specialist sound equipment can detect the faintest of noises to within a few metres. Silence on the site is needed while a member of the rescue team bangs three times and hopes to hear a response. Carbon dioxide detectors can be used to find survivors rendered unconscious. They work best in confined spaces where they detect the greater CO2 concentration in the air exhaled by those still breathing.
Weak buildings

Many of the buildings in Nepal collapsed in the initial earthquake or the aftershock. Many older neighbourhoods in the capital, Kathmandu, were made up of poorly-constructed brick buildings and these were largely destroyed in the disaster. Fewer, modern structures collapsed.
Local knowledge

Local people often know the best locations to begin the search for survivors. After speaking to them rescue workers can quickly select the most promising place to begin their work. Many local people have also joined in the search for survivors.
Search and rescue

The co-ordinating agency, usually the UN, and the host country, have to take the difficult decision of when to stop looking for a few remaining trapped people and concentrate resources on looking after the thousands of other survivors. The average time for this switch is between five and seven days, but individuals have been known to survive as long as 13 days, if they have access to water.
Rescue dogs

Dogs are extremely effective at using their sense of smell to pick up on signs of life that human rescuers cannot. They are also able to cover large areas quickly, speeding up the search and rescue process.
Lifting equipment

Diggers and hydraulic jacks are among the heavy machinery that rescue workers employ to shift rubble. Large concrete slabs on the outside of buildings can be pulled aside by diggers, enabling rescuers to get a view of any people still trapped inside. Rescue workers are also taking chainsaws and other power tools to cut through wreckage.
Shifting rubble

Before the heavy-lifting equipment arrives, rescuers use pick axes and shovels to dig through the rubble. Other tools used by rescuers include chainsaws, disc-cutters and rebar cutters - which can be used to tackle the metal bars in reinforced concrete.
The United Nations, which estimates 6.6 million people live in the districts affected by the earthquake, is helping to co-ordinate rescue efforts.
Many have been left homeless by the disaster and the country is already reported to be running out of water and food. There are also frequent power cuts.
The British organisation, Search and Rescue Assistance in Disasters (SARAID) has sent a team of experts with 1.5 tonnes of specialist equipment. This includes an electrical power generator and power tools for cutting through concrete and steel.
They also have their own tents and food supplies, so they will not be a drain on local resources.
India and China are among the other countries to send teams of rescuers.
How a search and rescue operation is carried out
Strong buildings
Rescue workers need to be swift to assess where they are most likely to find survivors inside collapsed buildings. Stairwells or the spaces under large concrete beams can provide what rescue workers call 'voids', or gaps in which people may have survived.
Video cameras
Video cameras placed on the end of flexible poles can be squeezed through gaps in the rubble to help locate survivors. Using this technique means time is saved as less rubble is shifted unnecessarily. Thermal imaging equipment can also be used to locate survivors as their body heat can warm the rubble around them.
Listening for survivors
Specialist sound equipment can detect the faintest of noises to within a few metres. Silence on the site is needed while a member of the rescue team bangs three times and hopes to hear a response. Carbon dioxide detectors can be used to find survivors rendered unconscious. They work best in confined spaces where they detect the greater CO2 concentration in the air exhaled by those still breathing.
Weak buildings
Many of the buildings in Nepal collapsed in the initial earthquake or the aftershocks. Many older neighbourhoods in the capital, Kathmandu, were made up of poorly-constructed brick buildings and these were largely destroyed in the disaster. Fewer, modern structures collapsed.
Local knowledge
Local people often know the best locations to begin the search for survivors. After speaking to them rescue workers can quickly select the most promising place to begin their work. Many local people have also joined in the search for survivors.
Search and rescue
The co-ordinating agency, usually the UN, and the host country, have to take the difficult decision of when to stop looking for a few remaining trapped people and concentrate resources on looking after the thousands of other survivors. The average time for this switch is between five and seven days, but trapped individuals have been known to survive as long as 13 days, if they have access to water.
Rescue dogs
Dogs are extremely effective at using their sense of smell to pick up on signs of life that human rescuers cannot. They are also able to cover large areas quickly, speeding up the search and rescue process.
Lifting equipment
Diggers and hydraulic jacks are among the heavy machinery that rescue workers employ to shift rubble. Large concrete slabs on the outside of buildings can be pulled aside by diggers, enabling rescuers to get a view of any people still trapped inside. Rescue workers are also taking chainsaws and other power tools to cut through wreckage.
Shifting rubble
Before the heavy-lifting equipment arrives, rescuers use pick axes and shovels to dig through the rubble. Other tools used by rescuers include chainsaws, disc-cutters and rebar cutters - which can be used to tackle the metal bars in reinforced concrete.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="69">
        <date>Wed Mar 25 22:08:15 EET 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Finance Bill second reading</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/democracylive/house-of-commons-32057693</Link>
        <Description>MPs pass the Finance Bill at second reading.</Description>
        <MainBody>Finance Bill second reading
25 March 2015 Last updated at 20:08 Help
MPs passed the Finance Bill, which brings into law the changes announced in the Budget, at second reading on 25 March 2015.
Full text commentary is available here .
Share this page
Copyright  2015 BBC. The BBC is not responsible for the content of external sites. Read more.
This page is best viewed in an up-to-date web browser with style sheets (CSS) enabled. While you will be able to view the content of this page in your current browser, you will not be able to get the full visual experience. Please consider upgrading your browser software or enabling style sheets (CSS) if you are able to do so.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="70">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:40:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: British woman films as avalanche hits</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32545637#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A British woman captures the moment she and her fellow climbers were engulfed in an avalanche following Saturday's earthquake in Nepal.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Nepal earthquake: Moment British woman caught in avalanche
1 May 2015 Last updated at 13:40 BST
A British woman has captured the moment she and fellow climbers were caught in an avalanche following Saturday's earthquake in Nepal.
Annie Tinsley from Devon was half an hour from base camp when she and her fellow climbers were engulfed.
Speaking to the BBC's Clive Myrie after her ordeal, she said that she and her fellow climbers were lucky not to have been closer to the earthquake's epicentre.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="71">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:04:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Chile volcano erupts for third time</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-32545006#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>More than 2,000 people have been forced from their homes after Chile's Calbuco volcano erupted for the third time in eight days.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Chile's Calbuco volcano erupts for third time in eight days
1 May 2015 Last updated at 05:04 BST
Calbuco volcano in southern Chile has erupted for a third time in eight days, after 54 years of inactivity.
The latest eruption has led to the evacuation of 2,500 people, some of whom had just returned to their homes following the previous eruptions.
Gideon Long reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="72">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:09:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Climbers remain at Everest Base Camp</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-32545631#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The BBC's Ian Pannell reports from Everest Base Camp where a recovery operation is under way following Saturday's devastating earthquake.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Nepal earthquake: Climbers remain at Everest Base Camp
1 May 2015 Last updated at 08:09 BST
A recovery operation is still under way at the world's highest peak, Mount Everest.
Saturday's earthquake in Nepal caused rock slides along popular trekking trails, and an avalanche killed 19 climbers.
The BBC's Ian Pannell reports from Everest Base Camp.
Read more
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="73">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:54:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: 'Obesity killed my son'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-32550231#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Satish Appleby speaks about the death of her overweight son.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Obesity 'was a factor' in death of 18 year old
1 May 2015 Last updated at 12:54 BST
Satish Appleby's son Shaun died from sudden adult death syndrome at the age of 18.
The teenager was overweight, had been addicted to junk food and spent up to 12 hours a day playing computer games.
Doctors told his mother obesity was a contributing factor in his death.
Satish is speaking out in the hope of stopping other young people facing a similar fate.
Watch the full version of this story here at Victoria Derbyshire weekdays from 09:15-11:00 BST on BBC Two, the BBC News Channel, and online.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="74">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:06:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Newsround kids put Nick Clegg on spot</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/32533534#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Four Newsround viewers spoke to the leader of the Liberal Democrat party, Nick Clegg, to ask him questions about education, why people should trust him, and paying for the NHS.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Nick Clegg put on the spot by Newsround kids
1 May 2015 Last updated at 07:06 BST
In the run-up to the General Election on May 7, Newsround viewers have been sending their questions in for each of the main party leaders.
Four viewers got the the chance put their questions to Liberal Democrat leader Nick Clegg.
They asked him about funding for schools, the cost of going to University and what his hardest challenge as a politician has been.
He also spoke about why he thinks young people should vote as soon as they can.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="75">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:40:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Meet 'the Middle East's Jon Stewart'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-32530451#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Egyptian Bassem Youssef - hailed as the Middle East's answer to popular US TV satirist Jon Stewart - presents his own take on the state of his country and the turmoil engulfing the wider region.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Bassem Youssef's guide to the Middle East
1 May 2015 Last updated at 00:40 BST
As Egypt protested against then-president Hosni Mubarak in 2011, Bassem Youssef did his part by making satirical YouTube videos about the regime.
Now just four years later, the former doctor is widely hailed as Egypt's Jon Stewart, in reference to the popular host of long-running US "fake news" programme The Daily Show.
The 41-year-old has even appeared on Stewart's show as its Senior Middle East Correspondent.
On a recent visit to London, BBC News asked Bassem Youssef for his unique take on the state of his country and the surrounding region.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="76">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:40:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Fears in Odessa over fragile ceasefire</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32545133#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The ceasefire between government forces and pro-Russia rebels in eastern Ukraine is largely holding, but Nato's top military commander says he's concerned the lull is being used to prepare another offensive.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Nato warning over fragile ceasefire in Ukraine
1 May 2015 Last updated at 06:40 BST
The ceasefire between government forces and pro-Russia rebels in eastern Ukraine is largely holding, but Nato's top military commander, General Philip Breedlove, has told a US Senate Committee he's concerned the lull is being used by the rebels to prepare for another offensive.
That fear is evident in the city of Odessa - which has been the target of a bombing campaign in recent months.
David Stern reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="77">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:18:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: What Nasa's Messenger discovered about Mercury</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-32546014#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>NASA's Messenger spacecraft has ended its mission to Mercury by making a planned crash landing on the planet.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
Nasa's Messenger spacecraft smashes into Mercury
1 May 2015 Last updated at 08:18 BST
NASA's Messenger spacecraft has ended its mission to Mercury by making a planned crash landing on the planet.
After running out of fuel, it plunged from orbit onto the rocky surface, leaving behind a crater thought to be the size of a tennis court.
The probe was launched in 2004 and was only expected to orbit Mercury for one year.
Science correspondent Jonathan Webb reports.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="78">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:02:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The rape of Berlin</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32529679#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>How Soviet troops took revenge on German women</Description>
        <MainBody>By Lucy Ash BBC News, Berlin
1 May 2015
From the section Magazine
The USSR's role in the defeat of Nazi Germany World War Two 70 years ago is seen as the nation's most glorious moment. But there is another story - of mass rapes by Soviet soldiers of German women in the dying days of the war.
Some readers may find this story disturbing.
Dusk is falling in Treptower Park on the outskirts of Berlin and I am looking up at a statue dramatically outlined against a lilac sky. Twelve metres (40ft) high, it depicts a Soviet soldier grasping a sword in one hand and a small German girl in the other, and stamping on a broken swastika.
This is the final resting place for 5,000 of the 80,000 Soviet troops who fell in the Battle of Berlin between 16 April and 2 May 1945.
The colossal proportions of the monument reflect the scale of the sacrifice. At the top of a long flight of steps, you can peer into the base of the statue, which is lit up like a religious shrine. An inscription saying that the Soviet people saved European civilisation from fascism catches my eye.
But some call this memorial the Tomb of the Unknown Rapist.
Stalin's troops assaulted an uncounted number of women as they fought their way to the German capital, though this was rarely mentioned after the war in Germany - West or East - and is a taboo subject in Russia even today.
The Russian media regularly dismiss talk of the rapes as a Western myth, though one of many sources that tells the story of what happened is a diary kept by a young Soviet officer.
Vladimir Gelfand, a young Jewish lieutenant from central Ukraine, wrote with extraordinary frankness from 1941 through to the end of the war, despite the Soviet military's ban on diaries, which were seen as a security risk.
The so far unpublished manuscript paints a picture of disarray in the regular battalions - miserable rations, lice, routine anti-Semitism and theft, with men even stealing their comrades' boots.
In February 1945, Gelfand was stationed by the Oder River dam, preparing for the final push on Berlin, and he describes how his comrades surrounded and overpowered a battalion of women fighters.
"The captured German female cats declared they were avenging their dead husbands," he writes. "They must be destroyed without mercy. Our soldiers suggest stabbing them through their genitals but I would just execute them."
It gets worse.
One of the most revealing passages in Gelfand's diary is dated 25 April, once he had reached Berlin. Gelfand was whirling around on a bicycle by the River Spree, the first time he'd ever ridden one, when he came across a group of German women carrying suitcases and bundles.
In broken German, he asked them where they were going and why they had left their homes.
"With horror on their faces, they told me what had happened on the first night of the Red Army's arrival," he writes.
"'They poked here,' explained the beautiful German girl, lifting up her skirt, 'all night. They were old, some were covered in pimples and they all climbed on me and poked - no less than 20 men,' she burst into tears.
"'They raped my daughter in front of me,' her poor mother added, 'and they can still come back and rape her again.' This thought horrified everyone.
"'Stay here,' the girl suddenly threw herself at me, 'sleep with me! You can do whatever you want with me, but only you!'"
By this stage, German soldiers had been guilty of sexual violence and other horrors in the Soviet Union for almost four years, as Gelfand had become aware as he fought his way to Berlin.
"He went through so many villages in which the Nazis had killed everyone, even small children. And he saw evidence of rape," says his son, Vitaly.
Vitaly Gelfand discovered his father's diary after he died
The Wehrmacht was supposedly a well-ordered force of Aryans who would never contemplate sex with untermenschen.
But the ban was ignored, says Oleg Budnitsky, a historian at the Higher School of Economics in Moscow. Nazi commanders were in fact so concerned about venereal disease that they established a chain of military brothels throughout the occupied territories.
It's hard to find direct evidence of how the German soldiers treated Russian women - many victims never survived - but in the German-Russian Museum in Berlin, director Jorg Morre shows me a photograph taken in Crimea from a German soldier's personal wartime album. A woman's corpse is sprawled on the ground.
"It looks like she was killed by raping, or after the rape. Her skirt is pulled up and the hands are in front of the face," he says.
"It's a shocking photo. We had discussions in the museum, should we show the photos - this is war, this is sexual violence under German policy in the Soviet Union. We are showing war. Not talking about war but showing it."
As the Red Army advanced into what the Soviet press called "the lair of the fascist beast" posters encouraged troops to show their anger: "Soldier: You are now on German soil. The hour of revenge has struck!"
In fact, the political department of the 19th Army, which fought its way into Germany along the Baltic Coast, declared that a true Soviet soldier would be so full of hatred that he would be repulsed by sex with Germans.  But once again soldiers proved the ideologists wrong.
While researching his 2002 book, Berlin, The Downfall, historian Antony Beevor found documents about sexual violence in the state archive of the Russian Federation. They were sent by the NKVD, the secret police, to their boss, Lavrentiy Beria, in late 1944.
"These were passed on to Stalin," says Beevor. "You can actually see from the ticks whether they've been read or not - and they report on the mass rapes in East Prussia and the way that German women would try to kill their children, and kill themselves, to avoid such a fate."
Another wartime diary, this time kept by the fiancee of an absent German soldier, shows that some women adapted to the appalling circumstances, in order to survive.
Starting on 20 April 1945, 10 days before Hitler's suicide, the anonymous author is, like Vladimir Gelfand, brutally honest, with razor-sharp powers of observation and occasional flashes of gallows humour.
Describing herself as "a pale-faced blonde always dressed in the same winter coat", the diarist paints vivid pictures of her neighbours in the bomb shelter beneath her Berlin apartment block, including a "young man in grey trousers and horn-rimmed glasses who on closer inspection turns out to be a young woman" and three elderly sisters, "all dressmakers, huddled together like a big black pudding".
Soviet soldiers distribute food in Berlin, in May 1945 (photograph: Timofey Melnik)
As they await the arrival of the Red Army, they joke "better a Russky on top than a Yank overhead" - rape is preferable to being pulverised by bombs. But when the soldiers reach their basement and try to haul women out, they beg the diarist to use her Russian language skills and complain to the Soviet command.
Braving the chaos on the rubble strewn streets, she manages to find a senior officer. He shrugs his shoulders. Despite Stalin's decree banning violence against civilians, he says, "It happens anyway."
The officer returns to the cellar with her and reprimands the soldiers, but one is seething with fury.
"'What do you mean? What did the Germans do to our women!' He is screaming: 'They took my sister and' The officer calms the man down and gets them outside."
But when the diarist steps back into the corridor to check they have gone, the men have been lying in wait and grab her. She is brutally raped and nearly strangled. The terrified neighbours, or "cave dwellers" as she calls them, had slammed the basement door shut.
"Finally the two iron levers open. Everyone stares at me," she writes. "My stockings are down to my shoes, I'm still holding on to what's left of my suspender belt. I start yelling 'You pigs! Here they rape me twice in a row and you leave me lying like a piece of dirt!'"
Eventually the diarist realises that she needs to find one "wolf" to stave off gang rape by the "male beasts". The relationship between aggressor and victim becomes less violent, more transactional - and more ambiguous. She shares her bed with a senior officer from Leningrad with whom she discusses literature and the meaning of life.
"By no means could it be said that the major is raping me," she writes.  "Am I doing it for bacon, butter, sugar, candles, canned meat? To some extent I'm sure I am. In addition, I like the major and the less he wants from me as a man, the more I like him as a person."
US troops watch a Russian soldier with a female friend in Berlin
Many of the diarist's neighbours made similar deals with the conquerors in the ruins of Berlin.
When the diary was published in German in 1959 under the title A Woman in Berlin, the author's frank account of the choices she made to survive was attacked for "besmirching the honour" of German women. Not surprisingly, she refused to allow the book to be republished until after her death.
Seventy years after the end of the war, new research on sexual violence committed by all the Allied forces - American, British and French as well as Soviet - is still emerging. But for years the subject slid under the official radar. Few reported it and even fewer would listen.
Besides the social stigma, in East Germany it was sacrilegious to criticise Soviet heroes who had defeated fascism while across the Wall in the West, the guilt for Nazi crimes made German suffering unmentionable.
But in 2008, there was a film adaptation of the Berlin Woman's diary called Anonyma, starring the well-known German actress Nina Hoss. The film had a cathartic effect in Germany and encouraged many women to come forward, including Ingeborg Bullert.
Ingeborg: "My mother liked to boast that her daughter hadn't been touched"
Ingeborg, aged 90, now lives in Hamburg in a flat filled with photos of cats and books about the theatre. She was 20 in 1945, dreamed of becoming an actress and lived with her mother in an upmarket street in Berlin's Charlottenberg district.
When the Soviet assault on the city began, like the woman diarist, she took refuge in the cellar of her building.
"Suddenly there were tanks in our street and everywhere the bodies of Russian and German soldiers", she recalls. "I remember the dreadful whining sound made by those Russian bombs - we called them Stalinorgels (Stalin organs)."
During a lull in the air raid, Ingeborg left the cellar and ran upstairs to look for a piece of string to use as a wick for a lamp. "Suddenly there were two Russians pointing their pistols at me," she says. "One of them forced me to expose myself and raped me, and then they changed places and the other one raped me as well. I thought I would die, that they would kill me."
Ingeborg didn't talk about her ordeal at the time, or for decades afterwards - she said it was too difficult. "My mother liked to boast that her daughter hadn't been touched," she says.
Ingeborg: "I thought I was going to die"
But the rapes had affected women in households across Berlin. Ingeborg recalls that women between the ages of 15 and 55 were ordered to get tested for sexually transmitted diseases. "You needed the medical certificate to get the food stamps and I remember that all the doctors doing these certificates, had waiting rooms full of women."
What was the scale of the rapes? The most often quoted number is a staggering 100,000 women in Berlin and two million on German territory. That figure - hotly debated - was extrapolated from scant surviving medical records.
In a former munitions factory which now houses the State Archive, Martin Luchterhand shows me an armful of blue cardboard folders. These contain abortion records dated July to October 1945 from Neukolln, just one of Berlin's 24 districts - it's a small miracle that they survived intact.
Abortions were illegal in Germany according to Article 218 of the penal code, but Luchterhand says "there was a small window for those women because of that special situation of the mass rapes in 1945".
Altogether 995 pleas for abortion were approved by this one district office in Berlin office between June 1945 to 1946. The files contain over 1,000 fragile scraps of paper of different colours and sizes. In childish round handwriting, one girl testifies that she was assaulted in the living room of her home in front of her parents.
We will probably never know the true scale of the rapes. Soviet military tribunals and other sources remain classified. The Russian parliament recently passed a law which says that anyone who denigrates Russia's record in World War Two could face fines and up to five years in prison.
Vera Dubina, a young historian at the University of Humanities in Moscow, says she knew nothing of the rapes until a scholarship took her to Berlin. She later wrote a paper on the subject but struggled to get it published.
"The Russian media reacted very aggressively," she says. "People only want to hear about our glorious victory in the Great Patriotic War and now it is getting harder to do proper research."
It's the fate of history to be rewritten to suit the agenda of the present. That's why first-hand accounts are so valuable - from those who brave the subject now, in their old age, and from those younger voices who put pencil to paper on the spot.
Vitaly Gelfand, son of the Red Army diarist Vladimir Gelfand, doesn't deny that many Soviet soldiers showed great bravery and sacrifice in World War Two - but that's not the whole story, he says.
Recently Vitaly did an interview on Russian radio, which triggered some anti-Semitic trolling on social media, saying the diary's a fake and he should clear off to Israel (he has in fact lived in Berlin for the last 20 years). Yet he is hoping the diary will be published in Russia later this year. Parts of it have been translated into German and Swedish.
"If people don't want to know the truth, they're just deluding themselves", he says.  "The entire world understands it, Russia understands it and the people behind those new laws about defaming the past, even they understand it. We can't move forward until we look back."
The Battle for Berlin (April - May 1945)
Red Army soldier raises the Soviet flag over the Reichstag in Berlin
After the Red Army captured Vienna, Joseph Stalin ordered his forces on to Berlin, determined to take the city before US forces
Two and a half million Red Army troops, 6,000 tanks and more than 40,000 artillery pieces were deployed, supported by thousands of aircraft
After heavy fighting and substantial losses, by 21 April, Red Army soldiers had entered the outlying suburbs of Berlin
In a staff conference on 22 April Adolf Hitler came close to admitting defeat but instead resolved to fight on, directing troops from his underground bunker
As Soviet forces took the city, it is estimated that close to 100,000 women were raped by Red Army soldiers
On 30 April Hitler killed himself and by 2 May the Reichstag had fallen
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="79">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:05:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The migration of the eagle hunters</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32410874#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>The annual trek across icy mountains and frozen lakes</Description>
        <MainBody>The migration of the eagle hunters
1 May 2015 Last updated at 00:05
Crossing frozen lakes and mountain passes, the nomadic Kazakhs of western Mongolia make an epic journey with their livestock every spring - Timothy Allen joined Shohan's family in February.
The Kazakhs of western Mongolia, known for hunting with eagles, are a nomadic people whose lives revolve around the movement of their livestock. Between February and April, about 200 families travel cross the Altai mountains on a 150km journey - it takes them about five days. (1/20) (All images copyright Timothy Allen - www.humanplanet.com)
This is Shohan's winter home: Most of his family and possessions travel to their spring camp on a truck, but his livestock must cross the mountains on foot to find fresh pastures. (2/20)
This is the family's last meal before leaving their winter home. As usual, says photographer Timothy Allen, it consisted of meat and tea - plus a few bottles of vodka to toast good health and safe passage. (3/20)
From their winter home, the livestock travelled through the village of Ulaanhus before heading off into the mountains. (4/20)
Shohan makes the journey with his cousin and his neighbour - plus their dogs. Together they herd about 500 livestock, including horses, yaks, camels, Kashmir goats, sheep and cows. (5/20)
On the lower sections of the migration route where there is no snow on the ground, the wind can quickly whip up a dust storm. The herders must then round up all the animals and wait for the wind to die down. (6/20)
There are clusters of drovers' huts dotted along the route. Provided by the Mongolian government, they are positioned at popular overnight camping spots and near the high mountain passes where bad weather often forces herders to seek shelter. (7/20)
Shohan's golden eagle travels on the back of one of the camels. The bird is wrapped up and hooded to protect it from the cold. (8/20)
As the animals begin to climb, the weather becomes harsher. The recent winter was unusually dry in western Mongolia, with many areas seeing hardly any snow. (9/20)
Shohan chooses to move his animals in February - before the lambing season. While the journey can be much harder than in March or April, it should mean fewer fatalities among his flock of pregnant ewes. (10/20)
The herders' camels carry frozen meat and a stove so the men can cook up a hearty evening meal. Some is kept for lunch the next day to be eaten with bread. The nomadic diet is heavy with meat and dairy products. Few vegetables grow in western Mongolia and imported produce would quickly freeze solid during winter journeys. (11/20)
The small huts that provide shelter for people on the move can fill up quickly. Herders bring animal skins to sleep on. (12/20)
When they reach streams and rivers, the animals are afraid to walk on the slippery frozen surfaces, so herders sprinkle dirt on the ice to create a pathway. They drag a young animal across, prompting its mother to chase it. The rest of the herd then follows en masse. (13/20)
In winter, the lakes freeze solid - the animals are afraid of the ice and will only cross when it is disguised by a covering of snow. (14/20)
Yaks cope well in snow storms, but what the herders fear most is a white-out caused by snow and strong winds. Visibility can go down to zero and animals can easily get lost. (15/20)
This is Shohan one morning, after a -40C night. Each day he starts to move the animals before first light when the temperature is still very low. (16/20)
Camels carry everything that might be needed to survive in the wild - but in reality herders will only need to camp out if they are stopped by bad weather or if the migration route is busy and the drovers' huts are full. (17/20)
Neighbouring families often make the journey together, but there can be problems when different herds accidently begin to mix. Separating them is hard and time consuming. (18/20)
The herders carry long-wave radios so they can listen to weather reports. If the weather gets too bad on the days they plan to cross high passes, they must wait until it improves. (19/20)
After the five-day migration, Shohan is reunited with his wife Perna at their spring home in Tavan Bogd National Park in western Mongolia. Their family moves six times a year between three wooden winter houses and various summer camping spots. (20/20) (All images copyright Timothy Allen - www.humanplanet.com)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="80">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:20:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mumford and Sons: 'There's a lot we can improve'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-32512533#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Mumford and Sons set the record straight on their 'new' sound</Description>
        <MainBody>Mumford and Sons: 'There's a lot we can improve'
By Mark Savage Entertainment reporter
30 April 2015
From the section Entertainment &amp; Arts
Mumford and Sons: (L-R) Winston Marshall, Marcus Mumford, Ben Lovett and Ted Dwane
They've gone electric! They killed the banjo! They burned their waistcoats!
But the recent reports of Mumford and Sons' radical reinvention have been over-exaggerated.
Their third album, Wilder Mind, might be low on hoe-downs, but it retains the band's surging, anthemic choruses - albeit with a more adventurous sonic sweep.
Speaking the morning after a warm-up gig in Brighton - where mobile phones were outlawed - frontman Marcus Mumford explains the band's new sound, and why the band still have "a lot to work out".
How did last night's show go?
It was good - but we've got a lot of work to do.
In what way?
Our live show is our crown jewel. Brighton was good, but it feels like there's a lot we can improve on. We've got new crew, different instruments, a different set-up, so there's quite a lot to work out, logistically.
Mumford, who is married to film star Carey Mulligan, was born in California but raised in London
Did everyone obey the mobile phone ban?
Everyone did! It's quite authoritarian, isn't it? But it creates such a nice vibe in the room. Honestly, I wish we could do it at every show. At the moment, we've done it just in advance of the album coming out because we want the first time people hear it to be the recordings we've made.
But actually, the collateral from it is just that when people get into the room, they have conversations with other people rather than staring at their phones.
Have you ever got your own phone out at a gig?
I've done it. We've all done it... Arcade Fire at Reading, Vampire Weekend at Fuji Rocks in Japan, Eric Clapton at the Albert Hall, because Steve Gadd was playing drums.
I totally understand the idea of documentation. It's just been refreshing to do some shows without it.
Two days before you played Glastonbury in 2013, Ben Lovett (guitarist) was watching Arctic Monkeys from the BBC compound. Halfway through their set he said: "I don't think we've got enough songs."
[Laughs] Yes, we were nervous. Sometimes headline slots on the Pyramid Stage just don't work. But when the audience were as amazing as they were, it was a moment of affirmation for us. It was like some sort of homecoming.
Wilder Mind follows 2012's Babel, which won a Grammy for best album
Shortly after that, you announced the band was taking a hiatus.
No, we didn't! Some journalist used the word hiatus. But we didn't argue with it, because we thought: "Oh cool, we'll get some space to make a record."
And the not-hiatus didn't last that long anyway...
We'd never taken time off as a band, so it was an extraordinary thing for us to do. We had three months off and all went away to do different things.
How long did it take you to get back into the swing of things?
We took it pretty slowly to start with. Three weeks on, a couple of weeks back at home, and it was really fun.
We've never made an album in the studio before. We've only ever written songs on the road and then stolen time away to go and record them. This was much more intentional.
Is that what allowed you to experiment with new sounds?
Exactly. Because when you're writing songs on the road, you're restricted to your set-up on stage. You only have an hour to soundcheck and in that hour you're trying to play new songs to each other. That's how loads of songs came about - from both Sigh No More and Babel, which is why they have a similar sound.
Whereas going into a studio where anyone can play any instrument they want - and record it, then erase it if they want to - it suddenly opens up the restrictions you've put in place for yourself.
It doesn't feel like there's been a totally drastic shift in your style.
Yeah, but it has been fun to try out songs like Monster or Tompkins Square Park that have a steady groove all the way through. We've never written to a drum groove before - whereas Monster, we started with a drum beat and a guitar part I'd written in a guitar shop in Chicago.
So now we have medium-paced songs, rather than just being super-quiet or super-loud.
Marcus Mumford (second from left) says there is 'a lot of doubt' on the new album
Scanning the titles, the album seems to be populated by scary creatures: Snake Eyes, Monsters, Broad Shouldered Beasts. Were there demons you were trying to cast off?
I think there are in every song you write. It's a very cathartic process. You say things in songs you wouldn't say to someone's face.
But we were writing in a bit of a bubble. It wasn't until we put all the songs together that we realised: "Oh there's quite a lot of beasties in here."
You've gone a bit Tolkien.
Ha! Yes, we've gone a bit Tolkien. But that's fine. It's not a concept goblin album or anything.
You've said the lyrics were more of a group effort this time around. Why is that?
I was knackered out by the Babel process - so we had a sit-down in Australia in 2012 and I said: "For the next album, it'd be nice if everyone wrote a bit more." That was a healthy conversation to have.
But when it came to recording, we've always said it's a competition between songs rather than writers. So now, we're going to each other saying: "How about this line? Let's tear the others up."
There's a overwhelming sense of doubt and being emotionally adrift.
There's a lot of doubt. It's all pretty autobiographical. But also on this album, we've written our very first love songs - Only Love, Monster - and that's been really fun.
What's your favourite line?
In Tompkins Square Park - "I only ever told you one lie, but it could have been a thousand/It might as well have been a thousand."
That's a great line. I didn't write it, so I can say that.
The quartet have become a stadium-sized act since their debut Sigh No More in 2009
You've got some big festival dates again this summer. How are you planning for those?
Well, we still go through a process we call FBCM, which is fully blown crisis mode. We go from FBCM into chiselling the set, learning which songs work next to each other. And once we get to Coney Island, which is the first show on our tour, we need to be all guns blazing. So we're knuckling down.
And now that you've got a balls-out rock number like The Wolf , have you been trying to locate your inner Bono?
I've thought about it. You watch your favourite bands and see the stage-craft that goes into it - Mick Jagger practicing in front of a full-length mirror and all that stuff - but I'm not that guy.
I think that putting the effort into singing well is more important than waving your arms around.
Wilder Mind is out on 4 May on Island Records.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="81">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:22:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The women who are obsessed with Parkour</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32533679#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Is this the sport humans are born to do?</Description>
        <MainBody>The women who are obsessed with Parkour
30 April 2015
From the section Magazine
Parkour is a sport that revolves around moving quickly and creatively over obstacles. It has its roots in military training, but it has a growing following - especially among women. Author Christopher McDougall joined a crew as they made their way through the urban terrain of London.
On the Thursday morning I arrive in London, my phone pings with a message from a teenage mother and school dropout named Shirley Darlington: "Kilburn tube station, 7pm."
I get there 10 minutes early, but about 20 women are already warming up, including the British movie actress Christina Chong and her sister Lizzi, a professional dancer.
Every Thursday, Shirley emails the 100 or so members of her all-female Parkour crew, revealing the secret location for that night's challenge. She keeps the venue a surprise so her crew never knows what to expect, and she keeps guys away because the biggest threat to Parkour - as even Parkour's all-male founders would agree - is testosterone.
"Young guys turn up, and lots of times all they want is the flash and not the fundamentals," says Dan Edwardes, the master instructor who gave Shirley her start. "They want to backflip off a wall and leap around on rooftops. With a group of lads, you'll get the show-off, the questioner, the giddy one. But in a women's group, there's none of that. It's very quiet. They get to it."
What I was after was even more fundamental than the fundamentals. I'd only come to Parkour by accident while chasing the secrets of the most remarkable athletes of our time - World War Two resistance fighters.
I'd become fascinated with the underground when I realised it wasn't made up of hardened soldiers. Often, they were civilians hiding behind enemy lines who had to live off the land while attacking Hitler's forces in gruelling hit-and-run operations.
Take Crete - on that small Greek island, farmers and shopkeepers were joined by British academics and poets who'd essentially been recruited just because they knew Ancient Greek. For the next four years, these misfits routinely covered ultra-marathon distances over mountain peaks and pulled off feats of strength and endurance that would stagger an Olympic athlete. I wanted to learn - what was their secret? And could I master it too?
One clue came from Samuel Gridley Howe, an American medic who joined the Greek Revolution in the early 1800s. Howe was amazed by the way Greek fighters seemed to bounce along the landscape, using so little effort that they barely needed food or rest. "A Greek soldier," Howe commented, "will march, or rather skip, all day among the rocks, expecting no other food than a biscuit and a few olives, or a raw onion, and at night, lies down content upon the ground with a flat rock for a pillow."
More than 100 years later, a British operative on Crete during WW2 recalled how difficult it was to keep pace with a heavyset Cretan twice his age who "tripped daintily along from boulder to boulder, his body bouncing with every step like an inflated rubber beach toy".
The origins of Parkour
Takes its name from phrase "parcours du combattant", the military obstacle course training devised by French physical educationalist Georges Hebert (1875-1957)
Modern Parkour was popularised by French actor and stuntman David Belle - his video "Speed Air Man" played a large part in popularising the sport
Practitioners of Parkour are often known as traceurs
To me, this sounded remarkably similar to what I knew of Parkour, the French street art of using the body's natural elastic recoil to leap and flow across the urban outback.
I wondered if Parkour's pioneers, seven French street kids who called themselves the "Yamakasi", and learned their basic moves from a survivor of colonial jungle fights in French-occupied Asia - might have rediscovered the same ancient athletic principle which allowed the Cretans to cover fantastic distances with remarkably little effort.
Once you learn Parkour's basic moves, I'd been told, the world around you changes. You don't see things anymore - you see movement. Maybe if I got some Parkour under my belt, the tumbled boulders on a Mediterranean island would transform from stuff in the way, into stuff to bounce off. "The same thing we do in the city, they do in mountain terrain," Dan Edwardes says. "That 'Cretan bounce' you were asking about? That comes from precision. When you hit a rock and bounce off, it's because you hit it square. You can't brake or doubt. You have to trust your body and go."
And when he says "your body", he means it. Movement isn't natural if it only applies to half the species, he says, which is why he's convinced that Parkour is one of the truest representations of human athleticism.
Most spectator sports were created by and for men, so they accentuate specific male attributes of bulk, upper-body strength, and explosive power. But Parkour is grounded in the full range of natural human movement, he says, so it's the ideal sport for everyone, regardless of age, gender, or athletic background.
That's what makes Shirley Darlington both an ideal coach and case study. She was 16 when she dropped out of school to help support her family after her father died, and 19 when she had a baby of her own. She sold shoes by day while getting her education at night, then began university studies while creating a job for herself with the health council as a mentor for other teenage mothers.
"I had to grow up fast," she explains. "I was working full-time and caring for an infant. I didn't have time to play." She only went to her first Parkour class to support a cousin who was too shy to go on her own.
They found themselves alone in a sea of lads pulling themselves over brick walls twice as high as their heads. But the heckling and the babying they expected never came.
When Shirley and her cousin struggled with a drill, two of the lads who'd already finished silently circled back and completed it by their side. "There's no written code for Parkour, but pretty much everywhere you find the same principles," Dan says. "At some point, even the strongest person freezes on a jump. It teaches you humility and reminds you where you came from."
That's why no one ever finishes a challenge alone. "Even from the beginning, with the Yamakasi," he points out, "Parkour was always about community."
Night after night, he watched Shirley show up for class even though she was weak and clumsy and usually exhausted from work and class and pre-dawn baby feedings.
For two years, Shirley struggled to do her first pull-up. "She used to just hang from the bar," Dan says. "She'd pull and pull and she wouldn't move one centimetre."
But she continued showing up and grabbing for the bar until a year later, Shirley nailed her first "muscle-up" - a challenging and essential Parkour manoeuvre in which you continue the pull-up until you're waist high on the bar and can vault yourself on top.
By her fifth year, Shirley was not only outperforming the men, she'd become the one circling back to help struggling lads. The real obstacle wasn't strength, she discovered. It was trust. "I never knew what my body could do, so it took a long time to build the confidence to throw my full weight into a movement," Shirley says. "Once I did, it changed everything."
On this Thursday evening, Shirley leads me and 40 or so women off at a jog, arriving about half a mile later at a cement courtyard in the middle of a high-rise housing estate.
Shirley has us line up at the top of a long, zigzagging access ramp and drop to all fours. We monkey-walk on hands and feet about 40 yards to the bottom, then bunny-hop up the stairs and do it again backwards, then crab style, then squat-hopping, each time with a new twist and a push-up between circuits.
By the 13th loop, my hands are cement-scuffed and my head is spinning from being at knee-height for so long, but the parade of hopping, bear-crawling, push-upping women shows no sign of slowing.
I look around for Shirley, but she's disappeared into our midst. "The best Parkour coaches are invisible," Dan tells me. "They get you started, then get out of the way."
I spot her again when three men take a seat on the wall and begin sharing a smoke and loud comments on the women's bodies. Shirley quietly peels off from the circuit and trots over to a swing set. She leaps for the crossbar, and in a blur somehow ends up squatting on top. She lowers herself from the bar with such slow grace and power that the three mopes on the wall shove their cigarettes in their mouths so their hands are free to applaud.
When Shirley's tribe heads out, I have to sling my bag on my back in a hurry and sprint to catch up. For the next two hours, north west London is our playground. Shirley leads us to metal benches, where we practice diving into shoulder rolls and popping back up on a dead run.
She finds a beauty of a wall where we work on running arm jumps - running straight up the bricks, basically, and grabbing for the top of the wall, and hoisting ourselves up when momentum dies and gravity takes over.
Well after dark, we're all clinging to a railing as we traverse a cement wall in a hanging squat. My feet are slipping and I'm in danger of dropping off when Lizzi Chong tucks in beside me.
"Get your knees higher," she says. "You're relying on your arms, but this is about legs."
Step by step, we work our way to the end, then drop to all fours and bear-crawl on hands and feet back to the beginning, press out our 40th or so push-up of the night, and get ready for another loop.
I try to thank Lizzi for the help, but she waves me off. "I needed a hand to hold when I started because I thought it was too dangerous," she says. "If I break an ankle, that's my career." But after her first class, she was hooked.
"I could see the dance in it. The flow, the rhythms, the strength and danger. You're always on the edge of fear, because your body senses it can do more than your mind will let it."
By the time Shirley cuts us loose for the night, I never want to do Parkour again but can't wait to come back. I didn't just run and climb all over London - I still had its cement grit deep under my fingernails.
This must be what one of the Cretan resistance fighters meant when he said a true citizen is a dromeus - a runner. Someone who can handle any obstacle and circle his hometown like a guardian spirit.
"We have to shape our training to fit our lifestyle," Dan Edwardes says. "We're no longer surrounded by trees, so we have to learn to climb walls."
Christopher McDougall is the author of Natural Born Heroes: How a Daring Band of Misfits Mastered the Lost Secrets of Strength and Endurance
More from The Magazine
James Rudge was born with one arm and is earning a reputation online for doing parkour around Bristol, the city he loves.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="82">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:13:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quiz of the week's news</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32533672#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>What's Batman about to reveal?</Description>
        <MainBody>Quiz of the week's news
1 May 2015
From the section Magazine
It's the Magazine's weekly news quiz - a chance to prove to yourself and others that you have been paying attention to what's been going on over the past seven days.
7 days 7 questions
Users of the BBC News app tap here to take the quiz.
What do this week's stories look like as told through graphical icons? Try Newsbeat's emoji quiz .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="83">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:11:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: The virtuoso performance - at a bomb site</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32536978#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>A virtuoso performance - at a bomb site</Description>
        <MainBody>Media playback is unsupported on your device
The virtuoso performance - at a bomb site
1 May 2015 Last updated at 03:11 BST
Videos of an Iraqi cellist performing at the site of a car bomb attack in Baghdad which killed several people this week were widely shared online.
Karim Wasfi's defiant performance echoes the story of the cellist of Sarajevo, who played in the besieged city during the Bosnian conflict in the 1990s. Wasfi explained to to BBC Newsday why he decided to fight violence with music.
For more videos subscribe to BBC Trending's YouTube channel.
You can follow BBC Trending on Twitter @BBCtrending .  All our stories are at bbc.com/trending
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="84">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:30:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Football 'must level jobs playing field'</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-32509958#sa-ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_source=PublicRSS20-sa</Link>
        <Description>Opening up football careers to more than just white men</Description>
        <MainBody>Football 'must level jobs playing field'
By Bill Wilson Business reporter, BBC News
1 May 2015
From the section Business
Chelsea, Aston Villa and Arsenal are setting a recruitment example, says Kick It Out
Football has been making great strides in tackling discrimination against players from ethnic minority backgrounds, but there are concerns it has taken its eye off the ball when it comes to other parts of its workforce.
Football boardrooms, as well as executive and administrative posts, remain predominantly white and male, as do most behind-the-scenes roles such as coaching or physiotherapy.
Now charity Kick It Out has called on clubs to alter their recruiting policies, to ensure they give a fair opportunity to people from all backgrounds to be considered for jobs in football.
It is also encouraging a greater representation of women at professional football clubs and institutions.
Apartheid lesson
Kick It Out's chairman, Sir Herman Ouseley - who first set up a project to tackle football racism back in 1993 - says that Chelsea, Aston Villa, and Arsenal are three clubs who are providing an example for others when it comes to implementing equality in the industry.
For Arsenal chief executive Ivan Gazidis there is an added motivation. When he was born in South Africa in 1964 his father was in prison because of his anti-apartheid activities.
Arsenal chief executive Ivan Gazidis has encouraged diversity at all levels of the club's staffing
Mr Gazidis says the experience has informed his "value set" throughout his life,  and that "inclusion and diversity" runs through the core of Arsenal's recruitment policies, and not just for the playing squad.
"What you see on the football pitch is the tip of the iceberg," he says, pointing out that there are hundreds of other people working behind the scenes at football clubs who should also reflect the values of equality.
However, despite the work at Arsenal - which has been awarded the Advanced Level award from Kick It Out for monitoring and promoting equal opportunities - too often football can seem a secretive, cliquey, closed shop.
'Open selection process'
"Football employers and institutions have to make it clear they welcome people from all backgrounds," says Sir Herman.
"Too often organisations don't interview people from these [black and other ethnic minority] backgrounds before they give someone a job. There has to be open and competitive selection processes, not just a club owner or manager appointing his mate.
"Clubs and institutions have to reach out to all parts of their communities and say 'we want your experience, to learn from your background'."
Sir Herman Ouseley says football businesses have a duty to seek out the best talent
Too often positions on football boards and backroom staff are shut off to racial minorities and to women, he said.
"If you are going to foreclose the recruitment options available to you, then you are not doing the best you can as a business," he said.
"Too many jobs in football management and other parts of the industry, such as executive and administrative level, are not advertised. We want to see a more open process.  You as a club chairman or owner have to allow yourself the chance to see and consider all the talent that is out there."
But he said appointments should not be made for box-ticking or "politically correct" reasons, as appointments made on that basis were doomed to failure.
"It is about taking responsibility as corporate and social bodies to get the best talent you can," he said.  "Football organisations will benefit with different sorts of people, in what is now a global marketplace."
Sexism
One woman from an ethnic minority who made it into the male-dominated football world is Sangi Patel, who worked as a physiotherapist at two big-name London professional clubs.
After being appointed to the Crystal Palace academy, she worked her way up to become acting lead physio at Queens Park Rangers (QPR) in the Premier League, along the way working with managers such as with Iain Dowie, Peter Taylor, Neil Warnock and Paul Hart.
Sangi Patel spent nine years working for two major English football clubs
The 32-year-old says that, in her experience, football has a bigger problem dealing with sexism rather than racism when it comes to making backroom appointments.
While the players and managers at both clubs were welcoming, she said she encountered issues in the broader football industry.
"I had a real difficult time with sexism... but never actually racism. I was never targeted that way," she says, adding that when she ran on the pitch to treat a player she would be bombarded with wolf-whistles and catcalls from opposition fans.
She says her outgoing personality, and ability to give as good as she got in the "banter" stakes, meant she was able to stand up for herself in the macho world of football.
"For females I still think it is tough getting into football, in fact I think it is incredibly difficult", she says.
Sangi Patel during her time working at Premier League football club QPR
"Sometimes clubs may think it is easier to appoint a male - it is easier not to have to worry about potential sexism issues, or players feeling they have to watch what they say in front of a woman."
When QPR was relegated in 2013 there was major upheaval at the club and Ms Patel thought it was the best time to make a change. After nine years in football, she now works at Thames Valley Athletics multi-sports centre in Eton, and in a private health clinic in London.
She was a mentor at the recent Kick It Out Raise Your Game conference, held to give males and females of all backgrounds a better understanding of how to access a career within football.
And she has strong advice for other women wanting to carve out a career in the sport.
"Go for it. You are always going to be faced by barriers and rejections, but always have belief in yourself," she says. "And never accept that it is OK for people to say 'you can't do it'."
'Confidence issues'
Student Lekan Odushola, 17, is one of the younger generation who is already planning a football career.
"I want to become a coach, working on player development," he says.
He already coaches part-time at the Kinetic Foundation academy in Croydon.
"Definitely more could be done - football should look to pro-actively bring through more young people of black, Asian, gay backgrounds," he says.
Student Lekan Odushola says clubs could use social media to explain recruitment
"They might have confidence issues, and be wary about getting involved.  [QPR director of football] Les Ferdinand referred recently to covert racism preventing ethnic minorities from getting top jobs in management, which is another worry."
He says clubs and other football organisations could build better awareness about their recruitment processes among young people from minority backgrounds, by making use of social media and by going into schools and colleges.
"Also, backroom jobs in football, such as coaching, should be promoted as desirable careers, not something seen as just a second choice for failed footballers," he adds.
"There needs to be more knowledge given to young people about the wide range of roles available in football."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="85">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:05:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why riches alone can't revive boxing</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/boxing/32536128</Link>
        <Description>Why riches alone can't revive boxing, says Dan Roan</Description>
        <MainBody>Mayweather v Pacquiao: Why richest fight may not revive boxing
Mayweather v Pacquiao
Venue: MGM Grand, Las Vegas. Date: 2/3 May: 21:00 local time/05:00 Sunday BST
Coverage: Live text commentary on the BBC Sport website
BBC sports editor Dan Roan reporting from Las Vegas.
There are countless examples of how closely linked sport and money have become, but here in Las Vegas this week, the relationship has appeared too close for comfort.
Such is the supercharged media frenzy over the so-called "fight of the century", and the ramped-up interest in events here in Nevada, this will be one of the most lucrative sporting events in history, generating an estimated half a billion dollars.
Floyd 'Money' Mayweather is already the richest sportsman in the world. Now the American is set to earn another $200m (130m) for this weekend's world welterweight title fight.
Opponent Manny Pacquiao will have to be content with around $130m (85m). And the Filipino is doing well outside the ring too, having recently signed new endorsement deals with the likes of Nike, Foot Locker, and Nestle.
Mayweather v Pacquiao: Promoter Bob Arum on why fight is "right up there"
The anticipation for Mayweather v Pacquiao is understandable. After all, these are two of the greatest pound-for-pound fighters of their era - one undefeated; the other a champion of six weight divisions. Something has to give. And few sports can match boxing for sheer fervour when it comes to fight-nights such as this.
And yet, despite the barely believable numbers being generated here, they are also perhaps symbolic of a sport that has sold its soul and lost its way.
The fight is generating record revenue for a boxing bout. But much of that is down to the pent-up demand created by six years of negotiations over money, quarrels between television networks, and delays over drugs testing.
This is the first super-fight of the social media age, and it has benefited from unprecedented levels of hype and a recovering US economy. That may be good for the fighters' bank balances, but surely the sport would have been better served if the two men had fought at their peak, not as they begin to think about retirement.
The fight will generate gate receipts of $74m (48m), breaking the record set by Mayweather's clash with Saul Alvarez in 2013. But given that it is taking place in an arena with just 16,500 seats - only 500 of them available to the public - this is hardly an event staged with the average sports fan in mind.
Tickets have been advertised for hundreds of thousands of dollars, surpassing the level of demand for the Super Bowl, but most will go to members of the fighters' entourages, guests of wealthy corporations, or the casinos' most valued clients - the so-called 'high-rollers' (as long as they have credit-lines with the casino of $250,000).
At the Excalibur hotel - over the road from the MGM where the fight will take place - guests are being charged $400 (260) just to watch the action on a TV screen in a bar. Fans are even being charged to attend the weigh-in.
Has sport ever felt as far from its Corinthian ideals?
Mayweather-Pacquiao top facts
This week I sat through one of the best attended, yet most anodyne and subdued media conferences many boxing reporters had ever witnessed when Mayweather and Pacquiao appeared together for the first time here.
No need for needle, we were told. Too much mutual respect. The fight sells itself. But it was hard not to conclude that Mayweather's predictable, stock answers were indicative of a man for whom money rather than his reputation as a sportsman is now the priority.
After reeling off a long list of sponsors he wanted to thank, promoter Bob Arum claimed the hype surrounding the fight was fantastic for the sport.
But it is hard to see how hosting the fight in a small, exclusive arena and behind a prohibitive pay wall is the best way of exposing a new generation of fans to the sport and increasing its appeal.
The fight will be watched by three to four million people in the US, many more than the record 2.4 million viewers who paid to see Mayweather take on Oscar De La Hoya in 2007. But for many others in the US, watching the fight on pay-per-view TV is simply too expensive when it costs $99 (65) in HD.
Mayweather earned more money in 2014 than any other sports star
More than the interests of the sport, this is about what is good for the two fighters, their promoters, joint host broadcasters HBO and Showtime, the MGM hotel and casino, secondary ticket selling agencies, and of course the city of Las Vegas - where room rates have hit record highs.
It all seems a far cry from 1995 when 28 million Americans tuned in to see Mike Tyson beat Buster Mathis on Fox. Or 1985 when 19 million TV viewers across Britain watched Barry McGuigan become world champion.
I visited McGuigan last week at the gym he runs with his son in Battersea. He would not begrudge the fighters maximising the money they could make, and pointed to the dangers involved.
Like Arum, he insisted the Mayweather-Pacquiao fight was a huge shot in the arm for a sport that has seen its popularity fade in recent years. While acknowledging the rampant commercialism behind the event, he was delighted that boxing was back in the headlines, and providing 2015 with arguably its biggest sporting moment.
There are indeed causes for some optimism. Al Haymon - Mayweather's adviser - has recently invested $20m establishing the Premier Boxing Championship in the US. In partnership with NBC, the PBC series is an attempt to return boxing to the mainstream - staging fights on network television with the aim of building a new audience.
McGuigan himself is doing his bit to return the sport to terrestrial screens on this side of the Atlantic, having struck a deal with ITV to televise his fighter Carl Frampton's bout with Chris Avalos back in February, the channel's first world title fight since 2008. The free-to-air show attracted an audience of almost two million.
The fact 80,000 people turned up at Wembley last June to watch Carl Froch fight George Groves is further encouragement.
He's behind you... oh hello Floyd!  Mayweather interrupts Dan's broadcast
Yet the sport still has a long way to go before confounding those who have predicted its death.
The confusing and fractured competitive landscape created by having four sanctioning organisations, with no single governing body, continues to do untold damage. After years of mismanagement, greed and corruption, there are too many belts, too few household names, and growing competition from mixed martial arts such as UFC.
The fear remains that Mayweather v Pacquiao is a one-off. The interest and money generated by what is being described as boxing's last great super-fight proves that the sport retains appeal, even today in such a crowded sporting marketplace. But don't necessarily expect it to restore the credibility of a sport that has a long way to go before staging the revival it craves.
This may be the most lucrative fight in boxing history, but its legacy remains harder to predict.
Pacquiao leads his supporters and training companions on a morning jog
Some passengers of low budget airline AirAsia in the Philippines are being given free tickets to fly to Manila to watch the bout on big screens
Floyd Mayweather's cutman Rafael Garcia (centre) puts tape on the eyes and face of Manny Pacquiao in a poster advertising the bout
Also related to this story
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
