<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>White House: President Obama briefed by advisors on attack at Air Products factory, an American company - @NBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/white-house-president-obama-briefed-by-advisors-o</Link>
        <Description>White House: President Obama briefed by advisors on attack at Air Products factory, an American company - @NBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Kuwait City governor says at least 10 killed in mosque bombing attack - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/kuwait-city-governor-says-at-least-10-killed-in-mo</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait City governor says at least 10 killed in mosque bombing attack - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>English tourist who witnessed attack thought he was hearing firecrackers but 'it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire' - @NBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/tunisia-attack-gunmen-kill-least-19-people-attack-sousse-beach-n382346</Link>
        <Description>English tourist who witnessed attack thought he was hearing firecrackers but 'it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire' - @NBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Gunmen opened fire on a beach popular with tourists in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 27 people, the country's interior ministry said.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry told NBC News that at least six people were injured in the attack in the Mediterranean city of Sousse and that one attacker had been killed. The interior ministry said the operation was ongoing.
Gary Pine, a product manager from the U.K., told NBC News he was one of dozens of vacationers on the beach when the attack took place not far from his hotel, the El Mouradi Palm Marina.
He said he initially thought he was hearing firecrackers but that "it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire." His 22-year-old son saw one person get shot, Pine added.
He said guests started running off the beach and were told to go to their rooms by hotel staff, he said. Some guests ran back out onto the beach to get their room keys, he added.
The entertainment manager at the hotel, who only gave his first name, Hamouda, said guests had told him two gunmen "came from the sea" and attacked the beach. He confirmed that staff had told guests to hide in their rooms.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Bomb halts trains between Cairo and Alexandria, no injuries reported - @ahramonline</title>
        <Link>http://english.ahram.org.eg/NewsContent/1/64/133754/Egypt/Politics-/Bomb-explosion-halts-trains-between-Cairo-and-Alex.aspx</Link>
        <Description>Bomb halts trains between Cairo and Alexandria, no injuries reported - @ahramonline</Description>
        <MainBody>Improvised bomb explosion halts trains between Cairo and Alexandria, no injuries
The improvised explosive device did not cause any injuries
Ramses train station (Photo: Reuters)
Related
Bomb diffused in train station in Upper Egypt's Beni Suef
An improvised bomb attack in Egypt on Friday halted trains between Cairo and the Mediterranean city of Alexandria, but left no casualties, security officials said.
A home-made bomb went off near the city of Damanhour, some 70 kilometres from Alexandria, director of security Maj. Gen. Mohamed Fathy said. 
The blast left no casualties, he said, but caused damage to the railway line, bringing train movement to a halt.
Railway lines are frequently targeted by anti-government militants operating in Egyptian cities.
Bomb explosions in Kafr El-Zayat in the Nile Delta briefly halted Cairo-Alexandria trains in February.
Similar attacks also disrupted services in the southern city of Aswan and in the Nile Delta city of Zagazig the previous month.
No casualties were reported in relation to the incidents.
Search Keywords:

Comment
Ahram Online welcomes readers' comments on all issues covered by the site, along with any criticisms and/or corrections. Readers are asked to limit their feedback to a maximum of 1000 characters (roughly 50 words). All comments/criticisms will, however, be subject to the following code
We will not publish comments which contain rude or abusive language, libelous statements,                                             slander and personal attacks against any person/s.
We will not publish comments which contain racist remarks or any kind of racial                                             or religious incitement against any group of people, in Egypt or outside it.
We welcome criticism of our reports and articles but we will not publish personal                                             attacks, slander or fabrications directed against our reporters and contributing                                             writers.
We reserve the right to correct, when at all possible, obvious errors in spelling                                             and grammar. However, due to time and staffing constraints such corrections will                                             not be made across the board or on a regular basis.
Please Wait
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/Reuters/status/614376401882497024</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Officials: At least 19 killed in Tunisia hotel attacks - @BBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/officials-at-least-19-killed-in-tunisia-hotel-att</Link>
        <Description>Officials: At least 19 killed in Tunisia hotel attacks - @BBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Firefighters responding to 2-alarm apartment fire in Carrollton, Texas</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcdfw.com/news/local/Firefighters-Respond-to-2-Alarm-Apartment-Fire-in-Carrollton-310048981.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_DFWBrand</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Firefighters responding to 2-alarm apartment fire in Carrollton, Texas</Description>
        <MainBody>Privacy Policy | More Newsletters
Carrollton Fire Department
Firefighters responded to a 2-alarm fire at an apartment leasing office in Carrollton Friday morning. (June 26, 2015)
An apartment lease office erupted into flames Friday morning in Carrollton.
Authorities responded to the two-alarm fire at the Green Tree Apartments clubhouse in Carrollton. The cause of the fire is unknown, and the fire was isolated in the clubhouse.
No other buildings were exposed to the fire, authorities said.
No one was injured in the incident, and no residents were displaced.
NBC 5 has crews on the way and will provide updates as soon as more information comes in.
Published 34 minutes ago
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Tunisia's Interior Ministry confirms 1 gunmen killed, police pursuing the other in hotels terror attack - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/tunisias-interior-ministry-confirms-1-gunmen-kill</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's Interior Ministry confirms 1 gunmen killed, police pursuing the other in hotels terror attack - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>7 killed as gunmen attack 2 Tunisian hotels, wound others and exchange fire with police - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/7-killed-as-gunmen-attack-2-tunisian-hotels-wound</Link>
        <Description>7 killed as gunmen attack 2 Tunisian hotels, wound others and exchange fire with police - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Disney World will ban selfie-sticks from its theme parks beginning Tuesday - @orlandosentinel</title>
        <Link>http://www.orlandosentinel.com/travel/attractions/theme-park-rangers-blog/os-disney-world-ban-selfie-sticks-from-parks-2015-post.html</Link>
        <Description>Disney World will ban selfie-sticks from its theme parks beginning Tuesday - @orlandosentinel</Description>
        <MainBody>1
Visitors will be told of the policy in locations such as the parking lots and at the resort's hotels. The prohibition will be added to the park rules post on Disney World's website.
The issue has been building at Disney. Previously, the sticks were prohibited from its rides, and "no selfie-sticks" signs were at select rides, such as Big Thunder Mountain Railroad at Magic Kingdom. Cast members have given verbal warnings to rule breakers.
Several incidents preceded the change, but officials have been discussing the rules for some time, Disney said. This week at Disney California Adventure park, a roller coaster was halted after a passenger pulled out a selfie-stick. The ride was closed for an hour.
Selfie-stick users put smartphones and cameras on the ends of poles to extend their reach, frequently capturing theme-park moments through self-portraits. The tools have been banned in public places  including some museums and stadiums  worldwide for obstructing views or causing safety issues.
Disney World already prohibits items such as skateboards, inline skates, wagon, folding chairs and glass containers, according to its official website, which also lists other items that we determine may be harmful or disruptive.
Universal Orlando has prohibited banned selfie-sticks and other loose items from certain thrill rides at Universal Studios and Islands of Adventure theme parks, but it has not instituted parkwide bans. SeaWorld Orlando also does not keep the sticks from entering the parks.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Interior Ministry says gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 coastal hotels in Tunisia - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/interior-ministry-says-gunmen-kill-at-least-7-peop</Link>
        <Description>Interior Ministry says gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 coastal hotels in Tunisia - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>4 killed, 8 critically injured in suicide attack at Kuwait mosque - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/4-killed-8-critically-injured-in-suicide-attack-a</Link>
        <Description>4 killed, 8 critically injured in suicide attack at Kuwait mosque - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Swiss Court rejects bid by arrested FIFA official to be released on bail - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/swiss-court-rejects-bid-by-arrested-fifa-official</Link>
        <Description>Swiss Court rejects bid by arrested FIFA official to be released on bail - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Line of mourners waiting for the funeral of Rev. Clementa Pickney in Charleston, S.C. - @trymainelee</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/trymainelee/status/614390128992223232</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Line of mourners waiting for the funeral of Rev. Clementa Pickney in Charleston, S.C. - @trymainelee</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Islamic State claims responsibility for mosque attack in Kuwait, according to statement posted on social media - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/islamic-state-claims-responsibility-for-mosque-att</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State claims responsibility for mosque attack in Kuwait, according to statement posted on social media - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Reported attack against tourist hotel in Tunisian town of Sousse, local radio and security sources say - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/reported-attack-against-tourist-hotel-in-tunisian</Link>
        <Description>Reported attack against tourist hotel in Tunisian town of Sousse, local radio and security sources say - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Interior ministry: Suspected accomplices to French factory attack being held by police - livestream</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/interior-ministry-suspected-accomplices-to-french</Link>
        <Description>Interior ministry: Suspected accomplices to French factory attack being held by police - livestream</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Mosque explosion in Kuwait caused by suicide bomber, several people wounded or killed, witness says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/mosque-explosion-in-kuwait-caused-by-suicide-bombe</Link>
        <Description>Mosque explosion in Kuwait caused by suicide bomber, several people wounded or killed, witness says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>President François Hollande confirms decapitated body had Arabic writing on it - @BBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/world-europe-33287095</Link>
        <Description>President François Hollande confirms decapitated body had Arabic writing on it - @BBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>LiveFrance attack: Live Updates
Summary
One man has been killed and two others injured in a suspected Islamist attack near the city of Lyon
Officials say one man has been arrested
French President Francois Hollande says it was a "terrorist attack"
The attack began with several explosions at a factory
President Hollande is leaving an EU summit in Brussels early
This page automatically updates
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
