<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar tie for National Spelling Bee title; 2nd consecutive year of co-champs - @ScrippsBee</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/29/gokul-venkatachalam-and-vanya-shivashankar-tie-for</Link>
        <Description>Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar tie for National Spelling Bee title; 2nd consecutive year of co-champs - @ScrippsBee</Description>
        <MainBody>May 29, 2015, 02:01 AM GMT
(
)
Gokul Venkatachalam and Vanya Shivashankar tie for National Spelling Bee title; 2nd consecutive year of co-champs - @ScrippsBee
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Shanghai Composite Index down 10% from May 27 close, falling into correction territory - @WSJbreakingnews</title>
        <Link>http://www.wsj.com/</Link>
        <Description>Shanghai Composite Index down 10% from May 27 close, falling into correction territory - @WSJbreakingnews</Description>
        <MainBody>Off Duty
IMAGE 1 of 7
If there is a ground zero for summer tourism, it may be the Mona Lisa, whose smile seems less mysterious than long-suffering when viewed against the constant crush of tourists around her. As many as 40,000 people rush the picture every day at the Louvre, according to the Paris museum. TIPS/ZUMA PRESS
Travel
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Rosenberg, Texas, officials issue voluntary evacuation for residents near flooding Brazos River - @abc13houston</title>
        <Link>http://abc13.com/746067/</Link>
        <Description>Rosenberg, Texas, officials issue voluntary evacuation for residents near flooding Brazos River - @abc13houston</Description>
        <MainBody>Rosenberg officials issue voluntary evacuation for residents along Brazos River
Thursday, May 28, 2015 08:48PM
ROSENBERG, TX (KTRK) --
Rosenberg officials have issued a voluntary evacuation for residents who live near the Brazos River.
"In anticipation of continued rising waters, Rosenberg encourages all residents that could potentially be affected to immediately take precautions and make the necessary preparations to protect themselves and their property in the event flooding does occur. The City has plans in place to notify all Residents identified as potentially in harm's way," according to the City of Rosenberg Emergency Management.
Residents affected by the voluntary evacuation will be visited by officers. The city will notify everyone if the evacuation becomes mandatory.
Meanwhile, the City of Lake Jackson says it is monitoring the Brazos River for potential flooding.
Lake Jackson officials point to river forecasts that predict the Brazos River leaving its banks north of the Harris Reservoir. If that happens, the city says it is likely that Brazos River flood waters will enter the Oyster Creek and Bastrop Bayou watersheds. As this occurs, water levels in Oyster Creek and the Bastrop Bayou are expected to rise.
Lake Jackson City Manager Bill Yenne says in the 1991-1992 Brazos River flood, the river level at Rosharon exceeded 51 feet for 10 days. Flood stage at Rosharon is 43 feet.
Currently, the city says the gauge at Rosharon is at 48.22 feet. It is forecast to rise to 50.2 feet by June 1st and then begin to recede.
Lake Jackson says the current situation is like the October 1994 that was less intense than the 1991-1992 flood, but warns this could change.
A release from Lake Jackson says, "This forecast all depends on whether any more rain falls in the Brazos River watershed north of our area. City crews are in a standby mode. We will continue to monitor this potential flooding event."
Related Topics:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>More: About 140 people believed to live on remote Japanese island of Kuchinoerabu where Mount Shindake volcano erupted - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/4829e620e62e46cdadfb33351a6aabc3/volcano-erupts-southern-japanese-island</Link>
        <Description>More: About 140 people believed to live on remote Japanese island of Kuchinoerabu where Mount Shindake volcano erupted - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>Volcano erupts on southern Japanese island
May. 28, 2015 9:50 PM EDT
Share article


TOKYO (AP)  A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, and authorities ordered residents to evacuate the island.
Mount Shindake erupted about 10 a.m. (0100 GMT) in spectacular fashion, spewing towering black-gray clouds into the sky.
The Japan Meteorological Agency reported that pyroclastic flows from the volcano had reached the shore to the northwest.
The government was surveying the island by helicopter to assess damage.
The national broadcaster NHK cited local officials as saying that 80 residents had taken refuge in a shelter on the island.
About 140 people live on Kuchinoerabu island in the Ryukyu archipelago, 50 miles (80 kilometers) southwest of the main southern island of Kyushu. Tourism and fishing are the main activities on the heavily forested, mountainous island, which is a national park.
The Japan Meterological Agency raised the volcano alert level to five, the highest on its scale. Shindake also erupted in August last year for the first time since 1980.
Kuchinoerabu island can be reached only by a once-a-day ferry from Yakushima island, 12 kilometers (about 7 miles) to the east, which has an airport and a population of more than 13,000 people.
SEE FULL ARTICLE
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Volcano erupts on small southern Japanese island; residents urged to evacuate - @AP, @japantimes</title>
        <Link>http://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2015/05/29/national/volcano-erupts-isle-kagoshima-prompting-evacuation-order/</Link>
        <Description>Volcano erupts on small southern Japanese island; residents urged to evacuate - @AP, @japantimes</Description>
        <MainBody>Sorry, but your browser needs Javascript to use this site.
If you're not sure how to activate it, please refer to this site: http://www.enable-javascript.com/
This image from the Meteorological Agency shows an eruption on Kuchinoerabu Island, Kagoshima Prefecture, on Friday. | KYODO
Volcano erupts on Kuchinoerabu isle off Kagoshima, prompting evacuation order
Kyodo, Staff Report
SHARE
The Meteorological Agency said Friday that there was a volcanic eruption on Kuchinoerabu Island in Kogashima Prefecture at 9:59 a.m.
The agency raised the alert level to 5, in which islanders need to evacuate, from 3, where people are restricted from entering the mountain.
Pyroclastic flows have reached the ocean, the agency said.
Kagoshima Prefecture meanwhile ordered all of the islands roughly 30 inhabitants to evacuae.
The prime ministers office also set up a task force.
The island is located about 100 km south of the southern tip of Kagoshima Prefecture.
Photos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Kenyan man pleads guilty in US terrorism support case; man supported al-Shabaab in Africa and extremist organizations operating in Syria, including al-Qaida, court documents show - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/5726ce88b0a54982b05c22696d62e724/kenyan-pleads-guilty-us-terrorism-support-case</Link>
        <Description>Kenyan man pleads guilty in US terrorism support case; man supported al-Shabaab in Africa and extremist organizations operating in Syria, including al-Qaida, court documents show - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>

MIAMI (AP)  A Kenyan man pleaded guilty in the U.S. on Thursday to terrorism support charges in a case that involved Internet chat room and other online communications with undercover FBI operatives.
Mohamed Said pleaded guilty to one count of conspiracy to provide material support to foreign terrorist organizations. A factual statement signed by Said identifies those groups as al-Shabaab in Africa and extremist organizations operating in Syria, including al-Qaida.
Said, 27, faces a maximum 15-year prison term when he is sentenced Aug. 14 by U.S. District Judge Ursula Ungaro. A co-defendant, Gufran Mohammed, is already serving that same 15-year sentence after pleading guilty last year.
The case evolved from FBI monitoring of Internet chat rooms frequented by Muslim extremists, according to court documents. FBI undercover employees posed as online terrorism recruiters and fundraisers in communications with both Mohammed and Said, who were both overseas.
Said admitted in the factual statement that in 2011 he received more than $11,600 in wire transfers from Mohammed for al-Shabaab and that he had told Mohammed later, "I sent it and it was distributed among the mujahedeen."
"I am sending more this week (Allah willing)," Mohammed wrote back.
Said's defense had centered on claims that prosecutors could not prove he was the person typing on a computer in Africa when the incriminating communications were sent. But according to authorities, Said admitted his involvement in terrorism in conversations with inmates at a Miami detention center.
Said and Mohammed were arrested in August 2013 in Saudi Arabia, where Mohammed was based at the time. According to the statement, Said thought he was traveling there from Africa to pick up more money for the terrorist organizations.
Before his arrest, Said admitted discussing travel routes, training and possible terrorist operations with an FBI confidential source posing as an al-Shabaab recruit. In such conversations, the recruits were called "tomatoes" or "dogs," according to the statement.
Mohammed is a naturalized U.S. citizen originally from India who has a master's degree in computer science from California State University in Los Angeles. He had been living in Saudi Arabia since 2011. Said was living in Mombasa, Kenya, and had never been to the U.S. before his arrest.
___
Follow Curt Anderson on Twitter: http://twitter.com
SEE FULL ARTICLE
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Vehicles stranded by flood waters in Wichita Falls, Texas - @JamesKAUZ</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/JamesKAUZ/status/604086285838327808</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Vehicles stranded by flood waters in Wichita Falls, Texas - @JamesKAUZ</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Actor Reynaldo Rey, best known for work on 'Friday' and 'White Men Can't Jump', dies at 75, manager says - @Variety</title>
        <Link>http://variety.com/2015/film/news/reynaldo-rey-dead-friday-white-men-cant-jump-1201507615/</Link>
        <Description>Actor Reynaldo Rey, best known for work on 'Friday' and 'White Men Can't Jump', dies at 75, manager says - @Variety</Description>
        <MainBody>Alex Stedman
News Editor, Variety.com @a_sted
Reynaldo Rey , a longtime actor who appeared as Reds father in 1995 hit  Friday , died Thursday in Los Angeles, his manager confirmed. He was 75.
The actor died from complications of a stroke he suffered late last year.
Along with his memorable role in Friday, Rey is also known for appearing in Harlem Nights (1989), White Men Cant Jump (1992), House Party 3 (1994) and For Da Love of Money (2000). The comedian has more than 52 film credits to his name.
He had several TV credits, including appearances in The Bernie Mac Show, Sanford and Son, The Wayans Bros., 227, The Tonight Show, Sister, Sister, Parents in Crime and The Royal Family.
Rey also had a career as a stand-up comedian, and served as a co-host on BETs stand-up show Comic View. He has recorded three comedy albums and three videos.
Rey was born in Sequoyah County, Okla., and as an adult moved to Cleveland, where he became a member of the Karamu House Theatre and launched his comedy career. He later moved to New York and joined the Harlem Theatre Group, which is when he made his first film appearance.
The actor most recently wrote, directed, financed and starred in the play Hollywood P.O.
TMZ first reported the news.
Filed Under:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>2 more bodies recovered from flooded Central Texas streams, bringing death toll from Texas and Oklahoma storms and flooding to 23; at least 15 still missing, authorities say - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/e46838e54b1c4023b029c13cdf26d663/latest-flooding-officials-threat-remains-across-texas</Link>
        <Description>2 more bodies recovered from flooded Central Texas streams, bringing death toll from Texas and Oklahoma storms and flooding to 23; at least 15 still missing, authorities say - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>
7:45 p.m. (CDT)
Emergency officials have reduced the number of missing people in Houston from Monday night's flash flooding from two to one.
That was after they determined Thursday that one of the bodies recovered a day earlier turned out to be the second passenger missing from a capsized Houston Fire Department rescue boat.
That reduces the number of people counted as missing statewide from the Memorial Day weekend flooding to at least 14. Twenty-three are known dead, including 19 in Texas, with seven of those in the Houston area.
___
7 p.m. (CDT)
Two more bodies have been recovered from flooded Central Texas streams, and authorities have added five more people to the list of the missing.
Officials in Blanco County said Thursday that the body of 42-year-old Zachary Jones of Blanco was found inside his vehicle along the Blanco River early Sunday.
Blanco County emergency management spokesman Ben Oakley says the body of an unidentified man was found Thursday off Ranch Road 32 in the southeastern part of the county. Oakley says an autopsy will be needed to determine the person's identity.
Oakley also said for the first time that five people are missing in Blanco County. That's in addition to the 10 people already counted as dead and eight missing in Central Texas flooding.
The developments bring the death toll from the storms and flooding to 23  19 in Texas and four in Oklahoma  and the number of missing to at least 15.
___
6 p.m. (CDT)
Floodwaters have cut off road access to four subdivisions along a Houston-area river.
Jeff Lindner is the meteorologist for the Harris County Flood Control District. He says the roads into the subdivisions along the West Fork of the San Jacinto River in Harris County were under up to 3 feet of water Thursday afternoon and were accessible by boat only.
Lindner says residents of between 100-200 homes have evacuated those neighborhoods. Many homes there are on stilts.
___
5:50 p.m. (CDT)
Authorities say many of the residents from about 300 homes in the small southeastern Texas city of Wharton that have been asked to leave due to possible flooding are taking heed of the warning.
Mayor Domingo Montalvo Jr. says all of the residents he's talked to whose homes could be flooded by the Colorado River are not staying. The city, about 60 miles southwest of Houston, has opened a shelter but so far only one person is at the facility.
The National Weather Service says the river was at 39.26 feet Thursday afternoon, just above flood stage. The river was expected to crest at 45.5 feet by either late Friday or early Saturday.
Montalvo says more than 60 percent of Wharton's roughly 9,000 residents live in a flood plain.
___
5:15 p.m. (CDT)
A portion of the San Jacinto River in Houston has been overflowing onto roadways affecting four subdivisions, limiting the ability of some residents to leave or return home.
Kim Jackson, Harris County Flood Control District spokeswoman, said Thursday afternoon that the river was at about 53 feet, about 4 feet above flood level. She says it's expected to stay at that level through Saturday.
She says most of the homes in those neighborhoods are elevated.
Jackson says residents in two neighborhoods of elevated homes at another spot on the river have time to leave before flood level is reached later Thursday. Floodwaters were expected to close by Friday morning the one road still clear.
Jackson says more rain may force the closure of a highway over a reservoir.
___
4:50 p.m. (CDT)
Authorities say the flooded Brazos River has crested at an evacuated North Texas subdivision and the floodwaters have begun to recede ... for now.
Parker County Emergency Management spokesman Joel Kertok says the Brazos River Authority closed the floodgates on the Possum Kingdom Lake dam upstream. That has allowed the river to crest at 23.6 feet about noon Thursday, almost 3 feet above flood stage. He said floodwaters lapped at the foundations of 11 homes but rose no further, and the river had fallen to 22.74 feet by 3 p.m. Thursday, about 2 feet above flood stage, and was expected to fall below flood stage about midnight Thursday.
There's a big "if" in the forecast, though. Kertok says severe thunderstorms were expected to develop west of the area Thursday evening. If the drop heavy rain on the lake or upstream, and if the Possum Kingdom flood gates reopen, the river levels would rise again downstream.
___
4 p.m. (CDT)
Storms have drenched areas of West Texas, flooding streets in some communities and forcing the closure of at least one highway in what is typically one of the state's driest regions.
Charles Aldrich, a National Weather Service meteorologist, says about 3 inches of rain fell Thursday in Shallowater, a city of about 2,500 residents about 60 miles east of the New Mexico border. A section of Interstate 27 was closed.
Nearby Lubbock got another 1.6 inches of rain, bringing its monthly total to 10.9 inches. Aldrich says more rain is possible later Thursday, which could push Lubbock past its May record of 12.69 inches, which was set in 1941.
Recent storms have caused widespread flooding in Texas and Oklahoma, killing at least 21 people. Ten others remain missing in Texas.
___
1:45 p.m. (CDT)
Authorities say floodwaters from the swollen Brazos River are lapping at the foundations of 11 homes in a North Texas community west of Fort Worth.
Parker County Emergency Management spokesman Joel Kertok said Thursday that the river has eclipsed its 21-foot flood level and is expected to crest tonight at 24.1 feet. He says it is threatening the homes in Horseshoe Bend, but hasn't entered any of them yet.
Residents were asked to evacuate about 250 homes there Wednesday.
In Eastland County, just southwest of Parker County, about 20 homes along Lake Leon were flooded Wednesday. Residents of about 100 to 150 homes were asked to leave.
Recent storms have caused widespread flooding in Texas and Oklahoma, killing at least 21 people. Ten people have also gone missing in Texas.
___
12 p.m. (CDT)
An Oklahoma emergency official says the state is still trying to get a sense of how many residents were displaced or left homeless by recent storms and flooding.
Keli Cain, a spokeswoman for the Oklahoma Department of Emergency Management, said Thursday that several bridges that service main roads remain flooded in Marshall County, along Oklahoma's border with Texas, and that some residents are effectively cut off. Atoka and LeFlore counties are also still dealing with the storm fallout.
Cain says some people who had to evacuate their homes in the past few days haven't been able to return and that the flood threat persists due to swollen waterways.
The Oklahoma Department of Transportation says nearly 30 roads in at least 18 mostly rural counties remain closed due to flooding or damage.
___
11:50 a.m. (CDT)
Authorities in Central Texas say more rain could hamper their efforts to search for eight people who went missing during the storms and flooding of recent days.
Hays County emergency management coordinator Kharley Smith says more rain is expected Thursday night, and it could shift debris fields and complicate efforts to find entangled victims.
A weekend flash-flood along the Blanco River killed at least four people in the area, including a young boy whose body hasn't been positively identified.
The recent storms have caused extensive flooding in Texas and Oklahoma and have been blamed for a total of 21 deaths. In addition to the eight missing in Central Texas, searchers are looking for two people who went missing in the Houston area.
___
11:35 a.m. (CDT)
The National Weather Service says hail, tornadoes and thunderstorms are possible across the southern Plains and that flooding remains the greatest threat for areas that have received record rainfall.
Steve Goss, a meteorologist with the National Weather Service's Storm Prediction Center in Norman, Oklahoma, says much of the area from western Kansas to West Texas should prepare for thunderstorms later Thursday that will be intense and slow moving. He says the storms could dump up to 3 inches of rain on some areas.
Much of Texas and Oklahoma have received record rainfall this month.
Weather service officials in areas of Texas already hit by heavy rains say the threat of thunderstorms will persist throughout the weekend, and that there is a 50 percent chance of them in the Houston, San Antonio and Austin areas.
___
10:40 a.m. (CDT)
The National Weather Service says hail, tornadoes and thunderstorms are possible across the southern Plains and that flooding remains the greatest threat for areas that have received record rainfall.
Meteorologist Steve Goss, of the Storm Prediction Center in Norman, Oklahoma, says much of the area from western Kansas to West Texas should prepare for thunderstorms later Thursday. He says the storms will be intense and slow moving.
Much of Texas and Oklahoma have already received record rainfall this month and forecasters say more rain would likely cause more flooding.
Goss says the storms Thursday are expected to move into the region around noon and could dump up to 3 inches of rain on some areas.
___
9:35 a.m. (CDT)
Authorities are asking those who live in about 300 homes in the small southeastern Texas city of Wharton to leave due to the risk of flooding.
Wharton emergency management coordinator Steve Johnson says the Colorado River should crest in the city at about 45.5 feet on Friday night or early Saturday.
Paula Favors, a spokeswoman for the city about 60 miles southwest of Houston, says the river was at about 38 feet Thursday morning, a foot below the flood level. She says it spills into low-lying areas at about 43 feet.
Residents of the most at-risk homes haven't been ordered to leave, but they are being asked to do so.
Mayor Domingo Montalvo Jr. says more than 60 percent of Wharton's roughly 9,000 residents live in a flood plain.
___
9:05 a.m. (CDT)
Arkansas transportation officials have indefinitely closed a section of highway near its border with Texas due to flooding along the Red River.
The Arkansas State Highway and Transportation Department shut down the section of State Highway 41 early Thursday. Officials say it will remain closed until the water recedes and engineers can assess the damage.
Senior Meteorologist Jason Hansford with the National Weather Service in Shreveport, Louisiana, says up to an inch of rain could fall in southwest Arkansas on Thursday. He says the area has received 5 to 10 inches of rain this month, which is above average.
Up to 2 more inches are possible this weekend and the weather service warns that additional flooding is possible along the Red River.
___
7:35 a.m. (CDT)
The Brazos River is almost cresting in North Texas following days of relentless rains, but officials say no homes have flooded in the closest rural community.
Parker County Emergency Management spokesman Joel Kertok says officials are monitoring the situation Thursday in Horseshoe Bend and will know more as the day progresses.
He says the river, which has a flood level of 21 feet, is close to cresting Thursday at 23.46 feet. It will crest at 23.6 feet.
Residents were asked to evacuate about 250 homes on Wednesday, and Kertok says he believes most people decided to leave. He says residents in the area west of Fort Worth were told to stay away for at least two or three days.
___
7:10 a.m. (CDT)
The National Weather Service is warning of new flooding across much of Oklahoma, where creeks, rivers and lakes remain swollen from spring showers.
Meteorologist Michael Scotten, in Norman, says two bouts of bad weather should hit the state Thursday. Morning rainfall will likely dwindle before noon, but a system moving in after 2 p.m. could spawn thunderstorms, hail and tornadoes.
Some parts of the state could see as much as 3 inches of rain. The greatest threat for severe weather Thursday afternoon is in western Oklahoma, where tennis ball sized hail and tornadoes are possible.
The service has issued a flood advisory for central Oklahoma and a flash flood watch for most of the state. Oklahoma City is in its wettest month ever recorded with 19.5 inches of rain.
___
6 a.m. (CDT)
While the barrage of deadly thunderstorms that hit Texas this week has tapered off, many cities remain in danger, and officials are warning about possible flooding from rain-swollen rivers.
In suburban Houston, subdivisions along the San Jacinto River are expected to flood.
In Wharton, located southwest of Houston, residents in 300 homes on the west side of the city have been asked to evacuate due to the predicted rise of the Colorado River. And in the North Texas town of Horseshoe Bend, about 250 residents were asked to evacuate their homes, as the Brazos River swelled toward its flood stage Thursday.
The death toll from the storms and flooding has climbed to 21  17 in Texas and four in Oklahoma. Houston alone had seven storm-related deaths.
SEE FULL ARTICLE
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Update: Chula Vista, Calif., police standoff ends after suspect found dead of apparent suicide - @nbcsandiego</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcsandiego.com/news/local/Reported-Chula-Vista-Shooting-E-Street-305331981.html</Link>
        <Description>Update: Chula Vista, Calif., police standoff ends after suspect found dead of apparent suicide - @nbcsandiego</Description>
        <MainBody>&gt; local
10-Hour Standoff Ends in Chula Vista
Many roads were closed to traffic during the standoff, including a portion of Third Avenue and E Street
YOU MAY ALSO BE INTERESTED IN...
View Gallery

Updated 2 hours ago
A shooting in Chula Vista, south of downtown San Diego, led to a nearly 10-hour SWAT standoff at an apartment complex Thursday after the shooting suspect barricaded himself inside a unit with his family while armed with a rifle.
The standoff ended when SWATofficers discovered the man had taken his own life.
Millionaire Mom Sentenced to 18 Years in Son's Hotel Poisoning Death
The initial shooting happened around 7:40 a.m. (10:40 a.m. ET) at 160 E. Street near 2nd Avenue, near the Mission Gardens apartment complex. More than a dozen police officers plus SWAT teams were called to the scene. Three armored SWAT vehicles also surrounded the area.
Chula Vista Police Department (CVPD) Capt. Lon Turner said police received multiple calls reporting gunfire in the area. Many witnesses reported hearing between four and 10 shots fired and seeing a man holding what may have been an AK-47.
Shooting Suspect Barricades Himself Inside Apartment
A shooting at a Chula Vista apartment complex on E Street led to a SWAT standoff after the shooting suspect barricaded himself inside an apartment with three family members -- two of them children. NBC 7's Elena Gomez reports on May 28, 2015. (Published Thursday, May 28, 2015)
When police arrived, they found a critically wounded man down in between cars near an apartment complex. Capt. Turner said that mans condition is unknown. CVPD Lt. Fritz Reber also confirmed the suspect had shot the victim near a car. The victim's name was not released.
Capt. Turner said the shooting suspect barricaded himself inside an apartment with his family. Police said two children were inside, both under 10 years old, with the suspect's wife, referred to as Laura by police. The suspect's name is Michael, or "Mike," Capt. Turner said. It is unknown if the children are the suspect's biological kids.
By 3:35 p.m. -- eight hours into the standoff  the woman and kids were released from the apartment unit, police said. The suspect did not exit with them.
Capt. Turner said the woman and children were safe and were being evaluated by medics on scene.
Capt. to Suspect: "We Need to Talk to You"
Chula Vista Police Department Capt. Lon Turner had a direct message for the shooting and standoff suspect barricaded inside an apartment in Chula Vista on May 28, 2015. " Michael, we need to talk to you. We are calling your cell phone. So, either you or Laura need to pick up the phone. We want this to happen peacefully.  (Published Thursday, May 28, 2015)
The suspect remained holed up inside the apartment, and about an hour later, three shots rang out. Lt. Reber said the first came from a police test canon shot. The second was inside the apartment and did not come from officers. The third was a flash bang grenade that shattered a window so the SWATteam could send in two robot and check on the suspect.
One robot spotted a man down in an upstairs room, and a SWATteam soon followed to confirm. They found the suspect dead inside.
Pedestrian Killed in Chula Vista
"Biggest thing that I'm happy about being able to report is that the wife and kids are out of there. Fortunately, they didn't lose their life in this incident. Clearly it's a tragedy when there's any loss of life,"said Capt. Turner at a 5:30 p.m. briefing.
Capt. Turner said the scene will now switch from a tactical one to a crime scene investigation. Investigators have gotten reports from other family that there may be additional weapons inside the home, so officers obtained a search warrant so they could enter.
Man With Screwdriver Shot, Killed by Deputy
The captain said the man had been talking about surrendering but had backed out of doing so several times during the long standoff.
Throughout the day, the suspect had been speaking with crisis negotiators and, at one point, sounded suicidal, according to police. They asked him to surrender without hurting anyone or himself.
Fire at Fish Market Restaurant
At a 1 p.m. news briefing, Capt. Turner said police had a very specific message for him.
If he is watching on television right now: Michael, we need to talk to you. We are calling your cellphone. So, either you or Laura need to pick up the phone. We want this to happen peacefully, said Turner, staring into news cameras.
Girl Reports Being Followed by Stranger
We understand that there are two sides to every story. Lets not make any rash decisions as it stands right now. Just pick up the phone so that we can communicate with you, he continued.
Capt. Turner said officials would continue to call the man's phone but if he doesn't answer, police may initiate other ways of contacting him. Again, the captain stressed the importance of bringing the standoff to a peaceful end.
At a 2 p.m. news briefing Capt. Turner confirmed that crisis negotiation teams were back in contact with the suspect and were able to speak with him on the phone.
Weve been talking with Mike, said Capt. Turner. Weve asked him again to surrender peacefully. Were concerned about the safety of him and his family.
Police said the couple have been married for one year. The suspect was not making any sort of demands, officials said.
The standoff prompted officials to shut down traffic in parts of the surrounding downtown Chula Vista area and evacuate some residents from the apartment complex.
The CVPD confirmed the 200 block of E Street had been shut down due to the heavy police activity. At 10:30 a.m, police closed additional roadways due to the standoff including Third and First avenues, and F and D streets. Only residents were allowed in the area.
Hilltop Middle School is near the complex, but Capt. Turner said no lockdown had been ordered at the campus. He said parents should keep abreast on road closures as they file in to pick up their students later in the day.
Meanwhile, police urged residents to stay indoors and shelter-in-place, and all others to stay away from the area.
A police captain said members of the shooting victims family had been escorted out of the complex safely and were with police just before 11 a.m. At that point, police said they had not ordered residents of the complex to evacuate, but officers were prepared to lead evacuations if necessary.
Police said they would utilize city resources to evacuate residents to the nearby Norman Park Senior Center at 270 F St., where residents would be given food and shelter while the standoff played out. Police said one resident, a 93-year-old man, had been safely evacuated from the complex due to medical issues earlier in the day.
At 11:35 a.m., an MTS bus arrived at the complex.By 11:45 a.m., it was confirmed that residents were being evacuated. About 10 residents exited several buildings at the complex, walking toward the bus alongside officers.
Police said the apartment complex is made up of four different sectors and officials were evacuating the property in an orderly fashion, sector by sector.
By 2 p.m., Capt. Turner said their evacuation of all residents at the complex had been completed. In all, he said 56 residents had been evacuated safely from the complex, including approximately 15 children. He said no forced evacuations had been necessary, as residents cooperated with the evacuation plan.
Some evacuees went to the senior center while others were picked up by family members.
We have made sure we know who has come in and who has come out of this location, said Capt. Turner, adding that officials planned to work their way from the inside out during the evacuation process.
The captain said officials found two to three rounds fired from the suspects weapon at the scene that indicated the suspect was armed with a long rifle, posing a major threat to the complex, thus prompting the evacuation.
Rifled ammunition has much more significant range than a handgun. It goes a lot further and it goes through a lot more things than a handgun, said Capt. Turner. [This] poses a greater threat to the public and our officers.
Investigators said the shooting may have stemmed from a dispute that escalated between neighbors. The motive is under investigation.
Investigators are currently seeking a search warrant and researching the suspects background. Police said they will continue to hold news briefings throughout the day offering the latest updates on this case.
Officials said they hope to bring the standoff to a peaceful resolution without further injuries.
The shooting, standoff and very heavy law enforcement response came as a shock to residents at the apartment complex.
One resident who has lived there for 10 years told NBC 7 he heard a loud blast but thought it was related to nearby construction and didnt think much of it.
He took one of his three children to school and when he returned, police cars had the street outside his home blocked off.
I thought it was a gas explosion, seriously I didnt think it was a gun, the man said.
The resident told NBC 7 he didnt hear screaming or fighting before the blast.
The resident said he's been talking his mother who is in the apartment with his other children. He said they are safe and staying inside.
Another resident told NBC 7 he heard at least six back-to-back gunshots erupt as he was leaving for work. Seconds later, he heard one final shot.
Another man said he was outside when shots rang out. He said he could almost feel the ricochet as the bullets erupted.
The American Red Cross is at the evacuation site providing residents and police officers with food and beverages amid the standoff. There were approximately 15 evacuees using the center as of 1:20 p.m.
One evacuee told NBC 7 something just wasnt right with the suspect. She said he lives at the apartment complex.
Another evacuee  a little boy  told NBC 7 he was very scared when officers began escorting his family out of their home. He thanked officials for keeping him safe.
Published at 8:47 AM PDT on May 28, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Oologah, Okla., police officer shot; manhunt underway for suspect, police say - @FOX23Morgan</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/FOX23Morgan/status/604078406221737985</Link>
        <Description>Oologah, Okla., police officer shot; manhunt underway for suspect, police say - @FOX23Morgan</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Floodwaters cut off road access to 4 subdivisions along San Jacinto River in Houston-area - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/e46838e54b1c4023b029c13cdf26d663/latest-flooding-officials-threat-remains-across-texas</Link>
        <Description>Floodwaters cut off road access to 4 subdivisions along San Jacinto River in Houston-area - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>
7:45 p.m. (CDT)
Emergency officials have reduced the number of missing people in Houston from Monday night's flash flooding from two to one.
That was after they determined Thursday that one of the bodies recovered a day earlier turned out to be the second passenger missing from a capsized Houston Fire Department rescue boat.
That reduces the number of people counted as missing statewide from the Memorial Day weekend flooding to at least 14. Twenty-three are known dead, including 19 in Texas, with seven of those in the Houston area.
___
7 p.m. (CDT)
Two more bodies have been recovered from flooded Central Texas streams, and authorities have added five more people to the list of the missing.
Officials in Blanco County said Thursday that the body of 42-year-old Zachary Jones of Blanco was found inside his vehicle along the Blanco River early Sunday.
Blanco County emergency management spokesman Ben Oakley says the body of an unidentified man was found Thursday off Ranch Road 32 in the southeastern part of the county. Oakley says an autopsy will be needed to determine the person's identity.
Oakley also said for the first time that five people are missing in Blanco County. That's in addition to the 10 people already counted as dead and eight missing in Central Texas flooding.
The developments bring the death toll from the storms and flooding to 23  19 in Texas and four in Oklahoma  and the number of missing to at least 15.
___
6 p.m. (CDT)
Floodwaters have cut off road access to four subdivisions along a Houston-area river.
Jeff Lindner is the meteorologist for the Harris County Flood Control District. He says the roads into the subdivisions along the West Fork of the San Jacinto River in Harris County were under up to 3 feet of water Thursday afternoon and were accessible by boat only.
Lindner says residents of between 100-200 homes have evacuated those neighborhoods. Many homes there are on stilts.
___
5:50 p.m. (CDT)
Authorities say many of the residents from about 300 homes in the small southeastern Texas city of Wharton that have been asked to leave due to possible flooding are taking heed of the warning.
Mayor Domingo Montalvo Jr. says all of the residents he's talked to whose homes could be flooded by the Colorado River are not staying. The city, about 60 miles southwest of Houston, has opened a shelter but so far only one person is at the facility.
The National Weather Service says the river was at 39.26 feet Thursday afternoon, just above flood stage. The river was expected to crest at 45.5 feet by either late Friday or early Saturday.
Montalvo says more than 60 percent of Wharton's roughly 9,000 residents live in a flood plain.
___
5:15 p.m. (CDT)
A portion of the San Jacinto River in Houston has been overflowing onto roadways affecting four subdivisions, limiting the ability of some residents to leave or return home.
Kim Jackson, Harris County Flood Control District spokeswoman, said Thursday afternoon that the river was at about 53 feet, about 4 feet above flood level. She says it's expected to stay at that level through Saturday.
She says most of the homes in those neighborhoods are elevated.
Jackson says residents in two neighborhoods of elevated homes at another spot on the river have time to leave before flood level is reached later Thursday. Floodwaters were expected to close by Friday morning the one road still clear.
Jackson says more rain may force the closure of a highway over a reservoir.
___
4:50 p.m. (CDT)
Authorities say the flooded Brazos River has crested at an evacuated North Texas subdivision and the floodwaters have begun to recede ... for now.
Parker County Emergency Management spokesman Joel Kertok says the Brazos River Authority closed the floodgates on the Possum Kingdom Lake dam upstream. That has allowed the river to crest at 23.6 feet about noon Thursday, almost 3 feet above flood stage. He said floodwaters lapped at the foundations of 11 homes but rose no further, and the river had fallen to 22.74 feet by 3 p.m. Thursday, about 2 feet above flood stage, and was expected to fall below flood stage about midnight Thursday.
There's a big "if" in the forecast, though. Kertok says severe thunderstorms were expected to develop west of the area Thursday evening. If the drop heavy rain on the lake or upstream, and if the Possum Kingdom flood gates reopen, the river levels would rise again downstream.
___
4 p.m. (CDT)
Storms have drenched areas of West Texas, flooding streets in some communities and forcing the closure of at least one highway in what is typically one of the state's driest regions.
Charles Aldrich, a National Weather Service meteorologist, says about 3 inches of rain fell Thursday in Shallowater, a city of about 2,500 residents about 60 miles east of the New Mexico border. A section of Interstate 27 was closed.
Nearby Lubbock got another 1.6 inches of rain, bringing its monthly total to 10.9 inches. Aldrich says more rain is possible later Thursday, which could push Lubbock past its May record of 12.69 inches, which was set in 1941.
Recent storms have caused widespread flooding in Texas and Oklahoma, killing at least 21 people. Ten others remain missing in Texas.
___
1:45 p.m. (CDT)
Authorities say floodwaters from the swollen Brazos River are lapping at the foundations of 11 homes in a North Texas community west of Fort Worth.
Parker County Emergency Management spokesman Joel Kertok said Thursday that the river has eclipsed its 21-foot flood level and is expected to crest tonight at 24.1 feet. He says it is threatening the homes in Horseshoe Bend, but hasn't entered any of them yet.
Residents were asked to evacuate about 250 homes there Wednesday.
In Eastland County, just southwest of Parker County, about 20 homes along Lake Leon were flooded Wednesday. Residents of about 100 to 150 homes were asked to leave.
Recent storms have caused widespread flooding in Texas and Oklahoma, killing at least 21 people. Ten people have also gone missing in Texas.
___
12 p.m. (CDT)
An Oklahoma emergency official says the state is still trying to get a sense of how many residents were displaced or left homeless by recent storms and flooding.
Keli Cain, a spokeswoman for the Oklahoma Department of Emergency Management, said Thursday that several bridges that service main roads remain flooded in Marshall County, along Oklahoma's border with Texas, and that some residents are effectively cut off. Atoka and LeFlore counties are also still dealing with the storm fallout.
Cain says some people who had to evacuate their homes in the past few days haven't been able to return and that the flood threat persists due to swollen waterways.
The Oklahoma Department of Transportation says nearly 30 roads in at least 18 mostly rural counties remain closed due to flooding or damage.
___
11:50 a.m. (CDT)
Authorities in Central Texas say more rain could hamper their efforts to search for eight people who went missing during the storms and flooding of recent days.
Hays County emergency management coordinator Kharley Smith says more rain is expected Thursday night, and it could shift debris fields and complicate efforts to find entangled victims.
A weekend flash-flood along the Blanco River killed at least four people in the area, including a young boy whose body hasn't been positively identified.
The recent storms have caused extensive flooding in Texas and Oklahoma and have been blamed for a total of 21 deaths. In addition to the eight missing in Central Texas, searchers are looking for two people who went missing in the Houston area.
___
11:35 a.m. (CDT)
The National Weather Service says hail, tornadoes and thunderstorms are possible across the southern Plains and that flooding remains the greatest threat for areas that have received record rainfall.
Steve Goss, a meteorologist with the National Weather Service's Storm Prediction Center in Norman, Oklahoma, says much of the area from western Kansas to West Texas should prepare for thunderstorms later Thursday that will be intense and slow moving. He says the storms could dump up to 3 inches of rain on some areas.
Much of Texas and Oklahoma have received record rainfall this month.
Weather service officials in areas of Texas already hit by heavy rains say the threat of thunderstorms will persist throughout the weekend, and that there is a 50 percent chance of them in the Houston, San Antonio and Austin areas.
___
10:40 a.m. (CDT)
The National Weather Service says hail, tornadoes and thunderstorms are possible across the southern Plains and that flooding remains the greatest threat for areas that have received record rainfall.
Meteorologist Steve Goss, of the Storm Prediction Center in Norman, Oklahoma, says much of the area from western Kansas to West Texas should prepare for thunderstorms later Thursday. He says the storms will be intense and slow moving.
Much of Texas and Oklahoma have already received record rainfall this month and forecasters say more rain would likely cause more flooding.
Goss says the storms Thursday are expected to move into the region around noon and could dump up to 3 inches of rain on some areas.
___
9:35 a.m. (CDT)
Authorities are asking those who live in about 300 homes in the small southeastern Texas city of Wharton to leave due to the risk of flooding.
Wharton emergency management coordinator Steve Johnson says the Colorado River should crest in the city at about 45.5 feet on Friday night or early Saturday.
Paula Favors, a spokeswoman for the city about 60 miles southwest of Houston, says the river was at about 38 feet Thursday morning, a foot below the flood level. She says it spills into low-lying areas at about 43 feet.
Residents of the most at-risk homes haven't been ordered to leave, but they are being asked to do so.
Mayor Domingo Montalvo Jr. says more than 60 percent of Wharton's roughly 9,000 residents live in a flood plain.
___
9:05 a.m. (CDT)
Arkansas transportation officials have indefinitely closed a section of highway near its border with Texas due to flooding along the Red River.
The Arkansas State Highway and Transportation Department shut down the section of State Highway 41 early Thursday. Officials say it will remain closed until the water recedes and engineers can assess the damage.
Senior Meteorologist Jason Hansford with the National Weather Service in Shreveport, Louisiana, says up to an inch of rain could fall in southwest Arkansas on Thursday. He says the area has received 5 to 10 inches of rain this month, which is above average.
Up to 2 more inches are possible this weekend and the weather service warns that additional flooding is possible along the Red River.
___
7:35 a.m. (CDT)
The Brazos River is almost cresting in North Texas following days of relentless rains, but officials say no homes have flooded in the closest rural community.
Parker County Emergency Management spokesman Joel Kertok says officials are monitoring the situation Thursday in Horseshoe Bend and will know more as the day progresses.
He says the river, which has a flood level of 21 feet, is close to cresting Thursday at 23.46 feet. It will crest at 23.6 feet.
Residents were asked to evacuate about 250 homes on Wednesday, and Kertok says he believes most people decided to leave. He says residents in the area west of Fort Worth were told to stay away for at least two or three days.
___
7:10 a.m. (CDT)
The National Weather Service is warning of new flooding across much of Oklahoma, where creeks, rivers and lakes remain swollen from spring showers.
Meteorologist Michael Scotten, in Norman, says two bouts of bad weather should hit the state Thursday. Morning rainfall will likely dwindle before noon, but a system moving in after 2 p.m. could spawn thunderstorms, hail and tornadoes.
Some parts of the state could see as much as 3 inches of rain. The greatest threat for severe weather Thursday afternoon is in western Oklahoma, where tennis ball sized hail and tornadoes are possible.
The service has issued a flood advisory for central Oklahoma and a flash flood watch for most of the state. Oklahoma City is in its wettest month ever recorded with 19.5 inches of rain.
___
6 a.m. (CDT)
While the barrage of deadly thunderstorms that hit Texas this week has tapered off, many cities remain in danger, and officials are warning about possible flooding from rain-swollen rivers.
In suburban Houston, subdivisions along the San Jacinto River are expected to flood.
In Wharton, located southwest of Houston, residents in 300 homes on the west side of the city have been asked to evacuate due to the predicted rise of the Colorado River. And in the North Texas town of Horseshoe Bend, about 250 residents were asked to evacuate their homes, as the Brazos River swelled toward its flood stage Thursday.
The death toll from the storms and flooding has climbed to 21  17 in Texas and four in Oklahoma. Houston alone had seven storm-related deaths.
SEE FULL ARTICLE
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Police in Manta, Ecuador, seize about 200,000 shark fins destined to be illegally exported to Asia, officials say - @GuardianAus</title>
        <Link>http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/may/29/200000-shark-fins-seized-by-police-in-ecuador-bound-for-asia-markets?CMP=soc_568</Link>
        <Description>Police in Manta, Ecuador, seize about 200,000 shark fins destined to be illegally exported to Asia, officials say - @GuardianAus</Description>
        <MainBody>Ecuador
200,000 shark fins seized by police in Ecuador, bound for Asia markets
Shark fins worth up to $1.5m discovered after raids on nine properties in the port city of Manta
Hundreds of shark fins seized by the police in Manta, Ecuador. Photograph: Ecuador's Attorney General/AP
Associated Press
Share on WhatsApp
Police in the Ecuadorian port city of Manta say they have seized about 200,000 shark fins destined to be illegally exported to Asia where they would fetch up to $1.5m.
Colonel Rommel Tapia, the head of the judicial police in Manta, said on Thursday nine properties were raided in the city and six people were arrested, including one of Chinese nationality. Those arrested face charges of damaging wildlife.
The interior minister, Jos Serrano, told the Democracia radio station that authorities in Ecuador had dealt a major blow to an international network that trafficked shark fins.
The fins are often used to make shark fin soup, a traditional Chinese dish.
Manta is 260 kilometres south-west of the capital, Quito.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Trees reported down as estimated winds of 80 mph hit west of Wichita Falls, Texas - @weatherchannel</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/weatherchannel/status/604073223165104128/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Trees reported down as estimated winds of 80 mph hit west of Wichita Falls, Texas - @weatherchannel</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Update: Gunshot heard from inside condo with suspect gunman involved in Chula Vista, Calif., standoff with police; officers reportedly sending in robot to see if suspect hurt himself, local media reports - @PriceCBS8</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/PriceCBS8/status/604068523707510785</Link>
        <Description>Update: Gunshot heard from inside condo with suspect gunman involved in Chula Vista, Calif., standoff with police; officers reportedly sending in robot to see if suspect hurt himself, local media reports - @PriceCBS8</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>North Korean leader Kim Jong-un's younger sister makes first public appearance in about 50 days, state media reports - @YonhapNews</title>
        <Link>http://english.yonhapnews.co.kr/news/2015/05/29/8/0200000000AEN20150529001600315F.html?input=www.tweeter.com</Link>
        <Description>North Korean leader Kim Jong-un's younger sister makes first public appearance in about 50 days, state media reports - @YonhapNews</Description>
        <MainBody>Print
SEOUL, May 29 (Yonhap) -- North Korean leader Kim Jong-un's younger sister, who was believed to be pregnant, made her first public appearance in about 50 days, the North's media reported Friday, cementing speculation that she might have given birth in May.
Kim Yo-jong, 28, accompanied the young leader on his field guidance to a tree nursery, which is being constructed by the Korean People's Army (KPA), according to the North's Korean Central News Agency (KCNA).
In April, South Korea's spy agency said that Kim would likely give birth in May, adding that her husband may be an alumnus of her alma mater, Kim Il-sung University. The agency did not provide more details.
Kim Yo-jong made her last public appearance April 12 when she accompanied the current leader on his inspection to the construction site of a second airport terminal in Pyongyang.
Experts said that her absence seemed to back up speculation that she has recently given birth.
In November last year, North Korea unveiled her official title: deputy director of the North's ruling Workers' Party of Korea.
Both the current leader and his sister were born to Ko Yong-hui, known as the fourth wife of late leader Kim Jong-il.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Health officials say more than 150 people possibly had contact with patient who died of Lassa fever in New Jersey - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/51f22cd8ec2e4445af0204766dc1a5c5/cdc-150-possibly-had-contact-lassa-fever-victim</Link>
        <Description>Health officials say more than 150 people possibly had contact with patient who died of Lassa fever in New Jersey - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>

NEW YORK (AP)  Federal and state health officials have identified more than 150 people who possibly had contact with a patient who died of Lassa fever, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said Thursday.
So far, most of those people face no danger, but six are at a high risk of having been exposed, CDC spokesman Benjamin Haynes said in a statement. Thirty-three are at low risk. All are being monitored, Haynes said.
A New Jersey man died Monday after traveling in West Africa and returning to New York City's Kennedy Airport on May 17.
Eight of the people being monitored were on the Royal Air Maroc flight that the victim boarded in Morocco after flying from Monrovia, Liberia, according to a government official with knowledge of the investigation who spoke to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because the official was not authorized to release information publicly.
Officials have said he did not have symptoms while on the plane but developed a sore throat and lethargy later and went to a hospital.
University Hospital in Newark said Tuesday the man was transferred there Saturday from another hospital because it could deal with viral hemorrhagic fevers. The hospital said it was reviewing whether any of its employees were at risk of exposure to the virus.
Saint Barnabas Medical Center in Livingston said in a statement Wednesday that the 55-year-old man came to the emergency room on May 18 and was treated and released. He returned three days later with a sore throat, fever and tiredness and was later transferred to University Hospital.
The disease is far less likely to be fatal than Ebola and does not spread through casual contact but rather through contact with the blood, feces or vomit of an infected person, or the urine or droppings of infected rodents.
Lassa fever was named after a Nigerian town where Western-trained doctors first noted it in 1969. An estimated 100,000 to 300,000 infections occur in West Africa each year, including about 5,000 deaths. In some areas of Sierra Leone and Liberia, 10 to 15 percent of people admitted to hospitals every year have Lassa fever.
The disease can cause a wide range of symptoms, including sore throat, back and abdominal pain, facial swelling, vomiting, hearing loss and tremors.
SEE FULL ARTICLE
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Water rescues reported during flooding in Lawton, Okla. - @wx5law</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/wx5law/status/604064115586420736</Link>
        <Description>Water rescues reported during flooding in Lawton, Okla. - @wx5law</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
