<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Novak Djokovic reaches 7th straight Wimbledon quarterfinals following 2-day, 5-set win over Kevin Anderson - @NBCSports</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/NBCSports/status/618409549532258304/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Novak Djokovic reaches 7th straight Wimbledon quarterfinals following 2-day, 5-set win over Kevin Anderson - @NBCSports</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Video: Stranded passengers stand outside Eunos station on the MRT line after power failure suspended service - @TODAYonline</title>
        <Link>http://www.todayonline.com/singapore/train-services-down-north-south-and-east-west-lines</Link>
        <Description>Video: Stranded passengers stand outside Eunos station on the MRT line after power failure suspended service - @TODAYonline</Description>
        <MainBody>Train services down on North-South and East-West lines
Blackout inside an MRT train. Photo: @vvictorriax/Twitter
Scene at Eunos MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Louisa Tang
Scene at Bishan MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Sharayna Pillai
Scene at Eunos MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Holly Matthews
Scene at Yew Tee MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Twitter/ @Milo_Aizz
Scene at Yew Tee MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Tristan Loh
Scene at Yew Tee MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Tristan Loh
Scene at City Hall MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Alfred Chua
Scene during a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Twitter/ @Jackyyapp
Scene during a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Twitter/ @shahirahazhr
Scene at Jurong East MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Twitter/ @petikool
Scene at Bishan MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Regina Marie Lee
Scene at Bishan MRT following a train disruption on July 7, 2015. Photo: Regina Marie Lee
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>France's foreign minister Fabius says main sticking points in Iran nuclear talks remain limitation on research and development, sanctions, unsolved IAEA investigation - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/07/frances-foreign-minister-fabius-says-main-stickin</Link>
        <Description>France's foreign minister Fabius says main sticking points in Iran nuclear talks remain limitation on research and development, sanctions, unsolved IAEA investigation - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 07, 2015, 01:19 PM GMT
(
13:19
)
France's foreign minister Fabius says main sticking points in Iran nuclear talks remain limitation on research and development, sanctions, unsolved IAEA investigation - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Missouri Gov. Jay Nixon signs bill for stillborn baby tax exemption - @41ActionNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.kshb.com/news/state/missouri/gov-jay-nixon-signs-missouri-bill-for-stillborn-baby-tax-exemption</Link>
        <Description>Missouri Gov. Jay Nixon signs bill for stillborn baby tax exemption - @41ActionNews</Description>
        <MainBody>41
Weather Alerts
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 2:14AM CDT expiring July 8 at 1:00PM CDT in effect for: Ray
Flash Flood Watchissued July 6 at 3:40AM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:00PM CDT in effect for: Anderson, Coffey, Douglas, Franklin, Lyon, Osage
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 4:02AM CDT expiring July 8 at 3:06PM CDT in effect for: Atchison, Leavenworth
Flash Flood Watchissued July 6 at 2:55AM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:00PM CDT in effect for: Bourbon, Cherokee, Crawford
Flash Flood Watchissued July 6 at 10:53PM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:00PM CDT in effect for: Barry, Barton, Benton, Camden, Cedar, Christian, Dade, Dallas, Dent, Douglas, Greene, Hickory, Jasper, Laclede, Lawrence, McDonald, Maries, Miller, Morgan, Newton, Ozark, Phelps, Polk, Pulaski, Saint Clair, Stone, Taney, Texas, Vernon, Webster, Wright
Flash Flood Watchissued July 6 at 3:44AM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:00PM CDT in effect for: Adair, Bates, Buchanan, Caldwell, Carroll, Cass, Chariton, Clay, Clinton, Cooper, Daviess, DeKalb, Grundy, Henry, Howard, Jackson, Johnson, Lafayette, Linn, Livingston, Macon, Pettis, Platte, Randolph, Ray, Saline, Sullivan
Flash Flood Watchissued July 6 at 3:44AM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:00PM CDT in effect for: Johnson, Leavenworth, Linn, Miami, Wyandotte
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 12:44AM CDT expiring July 11 at 8:12AM CDT in effect for: Carroll, Lafayette, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 12:44AM CDT expiring July 11 at 1:00AM CDT in effect for: Chariton, Howard, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 12:44AM CDT expiring July 11 at 9:24PM CDT in effect for: Carroll, Chariton, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 12:44AM CDT expiring July 10 at 1:00AM CDT in effect for: Clay, Jackson, Ray
Flood Warningissued July 7 at 12:44AM CDT expiring July 10 at 5:47PM CDT in effect for: Jackson, Lafayette, Ray
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:30PM CDT expiring July 8 at 11:21PM CDT in effect for: Leavenworth
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 11:45PM CDT expiring July 10 at 6:36AM CDT in effect for: Miami
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:43PM CDT expiring July 8 at 8:24AM CDT in effect for: Buchanan
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 8:32PM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:06AM CDT in effect for: Clay, Ray
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:41PM CDT expiring July 10 at 11:30PM CDT in effect for: Bates
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:43PM CDT expiring July 10 at 4:36AM CDT in effect for: Platte
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:43PM CDT expiring July 9 at 10:25PM CDT in effect for: Platte
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 8:51AM CDT expiring July 9 at 1:08AM CDT in effect for: Bourbon
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 9:52PM CDT expiring July 7 at 12:51PM CDT in effect for: Bates, Vernon
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 8:04PM CDT expiring July 9 at 6:30PM CDT in effect for: Cass, Henry, Johnson
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 8:04PM CDT expiring July 10 at 6:33AM CDT in effect for: Bates, Cass, Henry
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:41PM CDT expiring July 10 at 6:36AM CDT in effect for: Miami
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 7:30PM CDT expiring July 8 at 5:34PM CDT in effect for: Atchison, Leavenworth
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 6:58PM CDT expiring July 8 at 3:30AM CDT in effect for: Clay, Platte
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 6:23PM CDT expiring July 8 at 8:41PM CDT in effect for: Atchison, Leavenworth
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 6:23PM CDT expiring July 8 at 10:41PM CDT in effect for: Leavenworth
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 6:17PM CDT expiring July 7 at 3:05PM CDT in effect for: Jackson, Shawnee
Flash Flood Watchissued July 6 at 2:55AM CDT expiring July 8 at 7:00PM CDT in effect for: Barry, Barton, Benton, Camden, Cedar, Christian, Dade, Dallas, Dent, Douglas, Greene, Hickory, Jasper, Laclede, Lawrence, McDonald, Maries, Miller, Morgan, Newton, Phelps, Polk, Pulaski, Saint Clair, Stone, Texas, Vernon, Webster, Wright
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 10:22AM CDT expiring July 9 at 8:30AM CDT in effect for: Jackson, Lafayette, Ray
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 10:22AM CDT expiring July 10 at 5:30AM CDT in effect for: Carroll, Lafayette, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 10:22AM CDT expiring July 9 at 8:30AM CDT in effect for: Jackson, Lafayette, Ray
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 10:22AM CDT expiring July 10 at 5:30AM CDT in effect for: Carroll, Lafayette, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 10:22AM CDT expiring July 10 at 8:12PM CDT in effect for: Carroll, Chariton, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 10:22AM CDT expiring July 10 at 8:12PM CDT in effect for: Carroll, Chariton, Saline
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 9:40AM CDT expiring July 9 at 8:12AM CDT in effect for: Cass, Henry, Johnson
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 9:40AM CDT expiring July 9 at 2:00PM CDT in effect for: Bates, Cass, Henry
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 9:40AM CDT expiring July 9 at 8:12AM CDT in effect for: Cass, Henry, Johnson
Flood Warningissued July 6 at 9:40AM CDT expiring July 9 at 2:00PM CDT in effect for: Bates, Cass, Henry
Flood Warningissued July 1 at 4:39AM CDT expiring July 6 at 7:46AM CDT in effect for: Cooper, Saline
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Panel of experts finds the World Health Organization lacks the 'capacity and culture' to deal with global health emergencies, proved by the Ebola crisis - @BBCBreaking</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.com/news/health-33422635?ocid=socialflow_twitter</Link>
        <Description>Panel of experts finds the World Health Organization lacks the 'capacity and culture' to deal with global health emergencies, proved by the Ebola crisis - @BBCBreaking</Description>
        <MainBody>WHO 'unfit for health emergencies'
By Michelle Roberts Health editor, BBC News online
7 July 2015
From the section Health
The Ebola crisis proves the World Health Organization (WHO) lacks the "capacity and culture" to deal with global health emergencies, says a damning independent report, commissioned by the WHO itself.
The review panel says WHO was too slow to act to get on top of the deadly virus which has now killed more than 11,000 people in West Africa.
And it calls for an urgent overhaul of the organisation.
WHO says it has plans for reform.
It has already admitted that it waited too long to declare Ebola a public health emergency of international concern.
Inaction
The disease began spreading in December 2013, but it took until August 2014 for WHO to sound the alarm. By that point, more than 1,000 people had died of the virus.
The death toll now stands at more than 11,000.
According to the report, WHO lacked a culture of rapid decision-making.
In the early stages of the Ebola crisis, messages were sent about the seriousness of the situation but these "either did not reach senior leaders or senior leaders did not recognise their significance".
"There seems to have been a hope that the crisis could be managed by good diplomacy rather than by scaling up emergency action," the report says.
WHO was also criticised for failing to keep governments and the public up to speed about the extent and severity of the outbreak.
But the review praised WHO for playing a critical role in pushing forward work to find new treatments and cures for Ebola.
And it said WHO should be given the job of leading future health emergency responses - be that for Ebola or an outbreak of pandemic flu, for example.
It suggests an immediate contribution from all member countries towards a $100 million special outbreak response fund, and says WHO should establish a Centre for Emergency Preparedness and Response.
The panel's head, Dame Barbara Stocking, former chief executive of the charity Oxfam, said the WHO must now be made fit for the task.
"To me, coming from somewhere like Oxfam which is an emergency culture, you are very much, if you like, on the front foot. You are always trying to prevent a situation coming through or grab it when it starts and really get it under control very fast and those are some of the internal changes that have to be made at WHO."
The WHO said it was "already moving forward on some of the panel's recommendations including the development of the global health emergency workforce and the contingency fund to ensure the necessary resources are available to mount an initial response".
Dr Jeremy Farrar, Director of the Wellcome Trust, said: "The recommendations outlined by the independent panel should give WHO the mandate it needs to lead the global response to future health crises. The proposal to establish a WHO Centre for Emergency Preparedness and Response is encouraging.
"It's essential that this new body is accountable and can show leadership in the face of emerging health threats, with the authority and independence to act quickly when needed. The support of the global community is also crucial if we are to avert another catastrophe on the scale of Ebola."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Train service on all MRT lines in Singapore suspended due to power fault - @SMRT_Singapore</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/SMRT_Singapore/status/618394897947582464</Link>
        <Description>Train service on all MRT lines in Singapore suspended due to power fault - @SMRT_Singapore</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>British government announces plans to allow shops to open longer on Sundays - @BDliveSA</title>
        <Link>http://www.bdlive.co.za/world/europe/2015/07/07/plan-to-increase-sunday-shopping-hours-in-britain</Link>
        <Description>British government announces plans to allow shops to open longer on Sundays - @BDliveSA</Description>
        <MainBody>Plan to increase Sunday shopping hours in Britain
by Agency Staff,        2015-07-07 15:01:15.0
Agency Staff
Plan to increase Sunday shopping hours in Britain
LONDON  The British government announced plans on Tuesday to allow shops to open longer on Sundays to compete with online shopping and global tourist destinations like Paris and New York.
Finance Minister George Osborne said he wanted to give mayors and local authorities the power to decide Sunday shopping hours in his budget, which will be unveiled on Wednesday.
"It is clear that there is still a growing appetite for shopping on a Sunday," Mr Osborne said.
"The rise of online shopping, which people can do round the clock, also means more retailers want to be able to compete by opening for longer at the weekend."
A previous bid to reform Sunday shopping hours proved controversial and failed amid protests in 2006, and Mr Osbornes plan is expected to meet opposition from unions and the Church of England, which has defended a common day off on Sunday as important for "family stability and community life".
Britains existing 1994 law prevents larger shops from opening for more than six hours on Sundays, a rule that was relaxed during the London Olympics in 2012.
Mr Osborne described the Olympics trial as a success and said there was a "growing appetite" for Sunday trading in high streets and retail parks, but said that the decision would be not be made nationally. "This wont be right for every area, so I want to devolve the power to make this decision to mayors and local authorities," Mr Osborne said.
The Treasury has said that Britain has fallen behind as France recently relaxed its laws to allow shops to open more frequently on Sundays, while New York has no restrictions.
In Britain, shops larger than 280 square metres can open for a maximum of six hours between 10am and 6pm on Sundays.
Retail campaign group the Association of Convenience Stores (ACS) said the change would force small shops out of business.
"Existing Sunday trading laws are a popular compromise that balance the needs of consumers, shopworkers, small stores and families," said ACS chief executive James Lowman.
"The short period of time that small stores are open while large stores are shut is a crucial advantage for convenience stores, most of which are owned by small businesses."
AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Iranian diplomat says differences remain on 'sanctions, nuclear activities and UN resolutions' in talks - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/07/iranian-diplomat-says-differences-remain-on-sanct</Link>
        <Description>Iranian diplomat says differences remain on 'sanctions, nuclear activities and UN resolutions' in talks - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>'We've made substantial progress in every area, but this work is highly technical &amp; high stakes for all of the countries involved' - John Kerry's adviser @marieharf</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/07/weve-made-substantial-progress-in-every-area-bu</Link>
        <Description>'We've made substantial progress in every area, but this work is highly technical &amp; high stakes for all of the countries involved' - John Kerry's adviser @marieharf</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 07, 2015, 01:08 PM GMT
(
13:08
)
'We've made substantial progress in every area, but this work is highly technical &amp; high stakes for all of the countries involved' - John Kerry's adviser @marieharf
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>German media giants, broadcaster ProSiebenSat.1 and publishing company Axel Springer, in talks for a merger - @BDliveSA</title>
        <Link>http://www.bdlive.co.za/world/europe/2015/07/07/german-media-giants-discuss-combining-businesses</Link>
        <Description>German media giants, broadcaster ProSiebenSat.1 and publishing company Axel Springer, in talks for a merger - @BDliveSA</Description>
        <MainBody>German media giants discuss combining businesses
by Wall Street Journal,        2015-07-07 14:52:56.0
Wall Street Journal
German media giants discuss combining businesses
GERMAN broadcaster ProSiebenSat.1 and publishing company Axel Springer are in talks to combine their businesses in a transaction that would shake up the media market in Europes biggest economy, people familiar with the matter said.
The two companies combined market capitalisation is about 14.4bn. The media companies envision a tie-up with ProSiebenSat.1 emerging as the senior partner, according to the people.
Shares in ProSiebenSat.1 gained 3.5% in early trade on Tuesday, while those in Axel Springer rose about 6% in response to the news.
Negotiations remain at an early stage and could still break down, the people said. A deal would face several issues, including regulatory scrutiny.
A tie-up could let the companies jointly tackle the challenge of new digital rivals. Still, industry bankers and lawyers said the deal would face antitrust hurdles.
Axel Springer is Europes biggest newspaper publisher and ProSiebenSat.1s channels together have the highest market share among nonstate-controlled broadcasters in Germany.
Both trail closely held Bertelsmann, Germanys largest media company, which posted revenue last year of 16.7bn. ProSiebenSat.1 and Axel Springer together reported revenue of about 5.9bn.
The two companies know each other well. Axel Springer in 2005 launched a takeover bid for ProSieben that valued the Munich-based broadcaster at more than 4bn. The deal was rejected a year later by Germanys federal cartel office and the local media watchdog KEK.
But last year, Germanys federal administrative court ruled that the KEKs refusal was unjustified, potentially removing at least one obstacle from a transaction. Industry bankers and lawyers said the rise of digital rivals had changed the competitive landscape and could facilitate a deal. But they added that getting approval could require the companies to shed some assets.
Unlike 10 years ago, ProSieben is now the larger company with a market capitalisation of about 9.7bn. Axel Springer is currently valued at about 4.7bn.
Axel Springer owns Germanys best-selling daily, Bild, and daily Welt. It also bought news broadcaster N24 from ProSieben last year.
Both companies have launched initiatives to fight off newcomers and build new revenue streams. Video-on-demand platforms like Netflix or Amazon.com are increasingly grabbing market share from traditional broadcasters, undermining their viewer base and threatening advertising revenue.
ProSiebenSat.1 in April extended a licensing deal with Warner Bros International Television Distribution to continue broadcasting Hollywood blockbusters. And in a move to boost nonadvertising-related revenue sources, ProSieben in June spent 170m for an 80% stake in Verivox, Germanys largest independent consumer portal for comparing energy prices.
Axel Springer, meanwhile, is finding itself under pressure from free content offered by internet rivals that are hurting print publications. The Berlin-based company in April last year sold off newspaper titles, including Hamburger Abendblatt and other local papers, instead investing in online platforms including job board Stepstone and property portal Immonet.
A deal would require approval of Friede Springer, widow of founder Axel Springer, who owns 57% of the company. CE Mathias Dpfner holds 3.1% and stock investors own the remaining free float.
ProSiebenSat.1 said it recorded a domestic market share of 28.9% of the free-TV market in the first quarter. German broadcaster RTL in June said its market share stood at 28.6%.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Hostess Brands takes itself off the auction block, will pursue IPO - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.businessinsider.com/r-exclusive-twinkies-maker-hostess-brands-shelves-sale-for-ipo---sources-2015-7</Link>
        <Description>Hostess Brands takes itself off the auction block, will pursue IPO - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Flickr/Christian Cable Twinkies
(Reuters) - Hostess Brands LLC, the U.S. bakery company whose snack cake brands include Twinkies and Ding Dongs, has pulled itself from the auction block and will instead pursue an initial public offering (IPO), according to people familiar with the matter.
The move underscores the growth prospects of Hostess as well as its quick turnaround. In 2013 the Kansas City, Missouri-based company was picked up from bankruptcy by private equity firm Apollo Global Management LLC &lt;apo.n&gt; and consumer industry investor C. Dean Metropoulos for $410 million.
Hostess, which launched a process to sell itself earlier this year, snubbed offers in recent weeks from other companies and private equity firms that valued it at between $2.4 billion and $2.5 billion, including debt, the people said.
Hostess will now borrow money to pay a dividend to its owners, the people said. It will also begin preparations in the coming months for an IPO that it believes will give it a higher valuation than the acquisition proposals it received, the people added.
The sources asked not to be identified because the deliberations are confidential. Apollo declined to comment, while Hostess and Metropoulos did not respond to requests for comment.
Founded in 1930, Hostess is one of the largest wholesale bakers and distributors of breads and snack cakes in the United States. Its products, particularly the golden, cream-filled Twinkies cakes, are deeply ingrained in American pop culture and have long been packed in school children's lunch boxes.
When the company filed for bankruptcy three years ago, it blamed heavy debt and burdensome wage and pension obligations for its financial woes.
Under Apollo and Metropoulos, it relaunched its brands, improved its profitability and regained market share, focusing on distribution channels where it had historically lacked a significant presence, such as dollar stores and vending.
"Operating performance during fiscal 2014 has exceeded our expectations," Standard &amp; Poor's Financial Services LLC analysts wrote in a research note last March.
The credit ratings agency noted however that Hostess's market share is still below pre-bankruptcy levels. It has the No. 2 spot in U.S. sweet baked goods, trailing McKee Foods Corp.

(Reporting by Olivia Oran and Greg Roumeliotis in New York; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama)
Read the original article on Reuters .  Copyright 2015. Follow Reuters on Twitter .
More from Reuters:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Death toll in bombing in Zaria, Nigeria, rises to 25; 2-year-old among the dead, governor says - @cnnbrk</title>
        <Link>http://www.cnn.com/2015/07/07/africa/nigeria-violence/index.html</Link>
        <Description>Death toll in bombing in Zaria, Nigeria, rises to 25; 2-year-old among the dead, governor says - @cnnbrk</Description>
        <MainBody>CNN Leadership
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ad_bnr_atf_01" class="ad-ad_bnr_atf_01"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Nigeria bombing kills 25, governor says
By Christian Purefoy and Jason Hanna, CNN
Updated 1351 GMT (2051 HKT) July 7, 2015
JUST WATCHED
Bombings kill at least 28 in Nigeria on Monday 01:11
Story highlights
Northern Nigeria has seen near-daily attacks on civilian and government targets this month
Bomb rips through government building in Zaria on Tuesday, witness says
More than 200 have died in Nigeria in bombings and gun attacks since July 1
Lagos, Nigeria (CNN)
A bomb killed 25 people at a local government building in north-central Nigeria Tuesday, a state governor said -- marking the latest in a series of recent deadly attacks in a country where the government is battling the Islamic extremist group Boko Haram .
The bomb -- "most likely carried by a suicide bomber" -- exploded at a local government council's office in the Sabon Gari section of the city of Zaria, Kaduna state Gov. Nasir El-Rufai said.  Thirty-two other people were injured and being treated at a hospital, he said.
The building was crowded because residents were welcoming the new chairman of Sabon Gari's interim management committee, El-Rufai said. That leader was taking office Tuesday, and other civil servants were being registered at the building.
A 2-year-old child was among the dead, the governor said.
El-Rufai said extra security forces would be deployed throughout the state. An official statement from the state government called the attack "mindless."
"We call on our citizens to be vigilant and avoid crowded places like markets, mosques, churches and motor parks in the next few weeks," El-Rufai said on Twitter following the incident.
I am sad that a terrorist bomb attack just killed 20 people in Sabon Gari Zaria. May the souls of our innocent departed rest in peace, Amen.
Also Tuesday: In Kenya, at least 14 killed in attack on residential building
Northern Nigeria has seen near-daily attacks on civilian and government targets since last week, leaving more than 200 dead. Witnesses and government officials have blamed last week's attacks on Boko Haram, the terror group that has been fighting the Nigerian government for more than a decade, pushing to bring an extreme version of Islamic law, or Sharia, to the masses.
No group immediately claimed responsibility for Tuesday's attack in Zaria.
A summary of northern Nigeria's bloody July:
 On July 1, Boko Haram fighters raided villages in northeastern Nigeria's Borno state , killing more than 150 people, witnesses and government officials said.
 On Sunday in Jos state, just east of Kaduna, an explosion ripped through a restaurant full of customers in a shopping complex. Also in Jos that day, attackers shot at a crowded mosque before launching a rocket-propelled grenade at the building. At least 44 people were killed and 47 others were injured in the pair of attacks , said Mohammed Abdussalam, an official at Nigeria's National Emergency Management Agency. No claims of responsibility were immediately made.
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A video of Abubakar Shekau, who claims to be the leader of the Nigerian Islamist extremist group Boko Haram, is shown in September 2013. Boko Haram is an Islamist militant group waging a campaign of violence in northern Nigeria. The group's ambitions range from the stricter enforcement of Sharia law to the total destruction of the Nigerian state and its government. Click through to see recent bloody incidents in this strife-torn West African nation:
Hide Caption
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Hide Caption
2 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Bodies lie in the streets in Maiduguri, Nigeria, after religious clashes on July 31, 2009. Boko Haram exploded onto the national scene in 2009 when 700 people were killed in widespread clashes across the north between the group and the Nigerian military.
Hide Caption
3 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
An official displays burned equipment inside a prison in Bauchi, Nigeria, on September 9, 2010, after the prison was attacked by suspected members of Boko Haram two days earlier. About 720 inmates escaped during the prison break, and police suspect the prison was attacked because it was holding 80 members of the sect.
Hide Caption
4 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Nigerian President Goodluck Jonathan, second from left, stands on the back of a vehicle after being sworn-in as President during a ceremony in the capital of Abuja on May 29, 2011. In December 2011, Jonathan declared a state of emergency in parts of the country afflicted by violence from Boko Haram.
Hide Caption
5 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Rescue workers help a wounded person from a U.N. building in Abuja, Nigeria, on August 26, 2011. The building was rocked by a bomb that killed at least 23 people, leaving others trapped and causing heavy damage. Boko Haram had claimed responsibility for the attack in which a Honda packed with explosives rammed into the U.N. building , shattering windows and setting the place afire.
Hide Caption
6 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A photo taken on November 6, 2011, shows state police headquarters burned by a series of attacks that targeted police stations, mosques and churches in Damaturu, Nigeria, on November 4, 2011. Attackers left scores injured -- probably more than 100 -- in a three-hour rampage, and 63 people died.
Hide Caption
7 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Men look at the wreckage of a car after a bomb blast at St. Theresa Catholic Church outside Abuja on December 25, 2011. A string of bombs struck churches in five Nigerian cities, leaving dozens dead and wounded on the Christmas holiday , authorities and witnesses said. Boko Haram's targets included police outposts and churches as well as places associated with "Western influence."
Hide Caption
8 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A paramedic helps a young man as he leaves a hospital in the northern Nigerian city of Kano on January 21, 2012. A spate of bombings and shootings left more than 200 people dead in Nigeria's second-largest city. Three days later, a joint military task force in Nigeria arrested 158 suspected members of Boko Haram.
Hide Caption
9 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A photo taken on June 18, 2012, shows a car vandalized after three church bombings and retaliatory attacks in northern Nigeria killed at least 50 people and injured more than 130 others, the Nigerian Red Cross Society said.
Hide Caption
10 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A French family kidnapped February 19, 2013, in northern Cameroon is released after two months in captivity in Nigeria. The family of four children, their parents and an uncle were kidnapped in Waza National Park in northern Cameroon, situated near the border with Nigeria. One of the captive men read a statement demanding that Nigeria and Cameroon free jailed members of Boko Haram.
Hide Caption
11 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A soldier stands in front of a damaged wall and the body of a prison officer killed during an attack on a prison in the northeastern Nigerian town of Bama on May 7, 2013. Two soldiers were killed during coordinated attacks on multiple targets . Nigeria's military said more than 100 Boko Haram militants carried out the attack.
Hide Caption
12 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A deserted student hostel is shown on August 6, 2013, after gunmen stormed a school in Yobe state , killing 20 students and a teacher, state media reported.
Hide Caption
13 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A photograph made available by the Nigerian army on August 13, 2013, shows improvised explosive devices, bomb-making materials and detonators seized from a Boko Haram hideout. Gunmen attacked a mosque in Nigeria with automatic weapons on August 11, 2013, killing at least 44 people.
Hide Caption
14 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Nigerian students from Jos Polytechnic walk on campus in Jos, Nigeria, on September 30, 2013. Under the cover of darkness, gunmen approached a college dormitory in a rural Nigerian town and opened fire on students who were sleeping. At least 40 students died, according to the News Agency of Nigeria.
Hide Caption
15 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Soldiers stand outside the 79 Composite Group Air Force base that was attacked earlier in Maiduguri on December 2, 2013. Hundreds of Boko Haram militants attacked an Air Force base and a military checkpoint, according to government officials.
Hide Caption
16 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Catholic priest Georges Vandenbeusch speaks to reporters outside Paris after his release on January 1, 2014. Vandenbeusch was snatched from his parish church in Cameroon on November 13. Boko Haram claimed responsibility for kidnapping the priest.
Hide Caption
17 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
A man receives treatment at Konduga specialist hospital after a gruesome attack on January 26, 2014. It was suspected that Boko Haram militants opened fire on a village market and torched homes in the village of Kawuri, killing at least 45 people.
Hide Caption
18 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Police officers stand guard in front of the burned remains of homes and businesses in the village of Konduga on February 12, 2014. Suspected Boko Haram militants torched houses in the village, killing at least 23 people, according to the governor of Borno state on February 11.
Hide Caption
19 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Yobe state Gov. Ibrahim Gaidam, left, looks at the bodies of students inside an ambulance outside a mosque in Damaturu. At least 29 students died in an attack on a federal college in Buni Yadi, near the capital of Yobe state, Nigeria's military said on February 26, 2014. Authorities suspect Boko Haram carried out the assault in which several buildings were also torched.
Hide Caption
20 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Rescue workers try to put out a fire after a bomb exploded at the busiest roundabout near the crowded Monday Market in Maiduguri on July 1, 2014.
Hide Caption
21 of 22
Boko Haram: Nigeria's crisis 22 photos
Police in riot gear block a route in Abuja on October 14, 2014, during a demonstration calling on the Nigerian government to rescue schoolgirls kidnapped by Boko Haram. In April, more than 200 girls were abducted from their boarding school in northeastern Nigeria, officials and witnesses said.
Hide Caption
22 of 22
EXPAND GALLERY
 On Sunday in the city of Potiskum in Yobe state, a suicide bomber blew himself up in a church , killing the priest and four other worshippers, witnesses and police said.
 On Monday in the city of Kano, explosives carried by a 13-year-old female suicide bomber detonated near a mosque. The girl died; no one else was hurt, police said.
Nigerian President Muhammadu Buhari on Friday called last week's attacks "inhuman and barbaric" and pledged that every last "Boko Haram bandit ... would be hunted down without mercy and compromise."
Elected earlier this year, Buhari vowed to focus on the fight against the terrorist group, which has pledged allegiance to ISIS. But so far, he has struggled to stop the heavy bloodshed in the Northeast.
Along with suicide bombings, Boko Haram has attacked churches and mosques, raided once-peaceful villages and kidnapped people young and old, most infamously more than 200 girls taken in April 2014 from a school in Chibok .
Boko Haram's strongest presence is in northern Nigeria, where the majority of the country's Muslims live. The country's south is largely Christian and animist.
JUST WATCHED
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Crowd gathering outside home of Subway spokesman Jared Fogle after word of FBI raid - @CarrieWTHR</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/CarrieWTHR/status/618401106415230978</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Crowd gathering outside home of Subway spokesman Jared Fogle after word of FBI raid - @CarrieWTHR</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>US trade deficit climbs 2.9% in May to $41.9 billion - @MarketWatch</title>
        <Link>http://www.marketwatch.com/story/us-trade-deficit-climbs-29-in-may-to-419-billion-2015-07-07?mod=BreakingNewsMain&amp;link=sfmw</Link>
        <Description>US trade deficit climbs 2.9% in May to $41.9 billion - @MarketWatch</Description>
        <MainBody>Published: July 7, 2015 8:30 a.m. ET
Share
JeffryBartash
Reporter
WASHINGTON (MarketWatch) - The nation's trade deficit rose 2.9% in May, mostly because the U.S. exported fewer aircraft and other manufactured goods. The U.S. trade deficit climbed to a seasonally adjusted $41.9 billion from a revised $40.7 billion in April, the Commerce Department said Tuesday. Economists surveyed by MarketWatch had forecast a deficit of $42.1 billion. Exports dipped 0.8% to $188.6 billion, hurt by a strong dollar and weaker growth outside the U.S. Imports slid 0.1% to $230.5 billion. The trade deficit has averaged $41.3 billion in the first two months of the second quarter, down from a $43.4 billion average in the first quarter. So the trade deficit is unlikely to be a big drag on U.S. gross domestic product in the second quarter like it was in the first three months of the year, when the economy contracted. For the first time since 1990 the U.S. ran a surplus with Canada, the result of lower oil imports and a stronger dollar. The deficits with China and the European Union both rose, however.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Zambia to cut power supplies to copper mines by up to 30% as early as next week due to drought - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/07/zambia-to-cut-power-supplies-to-copper-mines-by-up</Link>
        <Description>Zambia to cut power supplies to copper mines by up to 30% as early as next week due to drought - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 07, 2015, 12:48 PM GMT
(
12:48
)
Zambia to cut power supplies to copper mines by up to 30% as early as next week due to drought - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>More: Federal authorities have raided the Zionsville, Ind., home of Subway spokesman Jared Fogle, FBI sources say; earlier this year former Jared Foundation director Russell Taylor was arrested in a child pornography case, but it is unclear if the incidents are related - @FOX59</title>
        <Link>http://fox59.com/2015/07/07/federal-authorities-raid-home-of-subway-spokesman-jared-fogle/</Link>
        <Description>More: Federal authorities have raided the Zionsville, Ind., home of Subway spokesman Jared Fogle, FBI sources say; earlier this year former Jared Foundation director Russell Taylor was arrested in a child pornography case, but it is unclear if the incidents are related - @FOX59</Description>
        <MainBody>
Federal authorities raid home of Subway spokesman Jared Fogle in child pornographyinvestigation
ZIONSVILLE, Ind. (July 7, 2015)  Federal authorities raided the home of Subway spokesman Jared Fogle Tuesday morning. FBI sources told FOX59 state and federal investigators were serving warrants at Fogles Zionsville home in connection with a child pornography investigation.
The raid started around 6:30 a.m. Tuesday. An evidence truck could be seen parked in the driveway. Investigators from the FBI and Indiana State Police were at the scene.
By IlliniGradResearch (Own work) [CC BY-SA 2.5 ( http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5 ) or CC BY-SA 3.0 ( http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0 )%5D, via Wikimedia Commons
Earlier this year, Russell Taylor, the former director of the Jared Foundation started by Fogle, was arrested in a child pornography case . He was accused of possessing and producing child pornography. Investigators said a search of Taylors home turned up more than 500 videos with images of child pornography. In May, Taylor unsuccessfully tried to kill himself while in jail.
Fogle said the foundation severed all ties with Taylor following the arrest. Investigators wouldnt say if Tuesdays raid was connected to that case.
Fogle gained national fame after attributing massive weight loss to eating Subway sandwiches. He was a freshman at Indiana University at the time. He later became a visible presence in Subway ad campaigns, pitching the restaurants sandwiches and touting their health benefits.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Carnival Corporation granted US approval for travel to Cuba - @CNBC, @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.cnbc.com/id/102812878</Link>
        <Description>Carnival Corporation granted US approval for travel to Cuba - @CNBC, @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>CNBC.com
SHARES
Carnival has gained U.S. approval for limited cruises to Cuba as early as next year as part of its recently launched social impact cruising brand, the company said Tuesday.
The tripswhich are cleared under existing U.S. Treasury rules that allow approved travelers to go to the island for cultural and humanitarian exchangesstill need a green light from Cuban authorities.
"We look forward to working with the Cuban authorities for their approval to help make the social, cultural and humanitarian exchanges between U.S. citizens and the people of Cuba a reality," Carnival CEO Arnold Donald said in a statement.
It was not immediately clear what additional Cuban approvals the company would need to launch the Miami-to-Cuba trips.
Source: Carnival
Carnivals Adonia ship is being turned into a new brand called Fathom.
Carnival's efforts come as Washington and Havana attempt to normalize diplomatic relations that were severed more than 50 years ago. The countries last week announced an agreement to re-open embassies in each other's capitals, possibly this month.
The Obama administration has pushed for goods and people to flow more freely between the U.S. and Cuba. The Carnival initiative falls under "fathom," the "social impact" line the carrier launched in June.
Seven-day trips to Cuba would start at $2,990 per person, the company said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Iran nuclear deal to be ready in next few days, Russia's foreign minister Lavrov says - Interfax</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/07/07/iran-nuclear-deal-to-be-ready-in-next-few-days-ru</Link>
        <Description>Iran nuclear deal to be ready in next few days, Russia's foreign minister Lavrov says - Interfax</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>Confederate monument at Durham, NC, courthouse vandalized with spray painted 'black lives matter' - @ABC11_WTVD</title>
        <Link>http://abc11.com/news/confederate-monument-at-durham-courthouse-vandalized/833057/</Link>
        <Description>Confederate monument at Durham, NC, courthouse vandalized with spray painted 'black lives matter' - @ABC11_WTVD</Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate monument at old Durham courthouse vandalized
The words "black lives matter" were spray-painted on the side of the monument
Embed
&lt;iframe width="476" height="270" src="http://abc11.com/video/embed/?pid=833057" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Tuesday, July 07, 2015 09:24AM
DURHAM (WTVD) --
Vandals spray-painted "black lives matter" on the Confederate monument located next to the old Durham County Courthouse on East Main Street sometime overnight Tuesday.
The attack is similar to ones at the "Silent Sam" Confederate memorial on the campus of UNC Chapel Hill over the 4th of July weekend and another at the Confederate memorial in Durham's Maplewood Cemetery July 1.
The courthouse monument features a statue of a Confederate soldier atop a granite tower decorated with the Confederate seal. At the base of the monument are four cannon balls and two lighted lamps.
The inscription reads "in memory of the boys who wore the gray." It was dedicated in 1924.
Workers were already out Tuesday morning with pressure washing equipment to clean graffiti off the monument.
Related Topics:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>Big GOP donor seeks to block Donald Trump from presidential debate stage - @businessinsider</title>
        <Link>http://www.businessinsider.com/donald-trump-debate-stage-gop-civility-2015-7</Link>
        <Description>Big GOP donor seeks to block Donald Trump from presidential debate stage - @businessinsider</Description>
        <MainBody>Mexico unites against Trump: 'He has no respect for human beings'
WASHINGTON (AP)  Worried about "Republican-on-Republican violence," top party donors are taking action, with one firing off a letter calling for more civility and another seeking to block businessman Donald Trump from the debate stage altogether.
Foster Friess, a Wyoming-based investor and one of the party's top 20 donors in the last presidential contest, issued a letter to 16 White House prospects and the Republican National Committee late last week calling for candidates to stay on the "civility reservation."
"Our candidates will benefit if they all submit to Ronald Reagan's 11th Commandment, 'Thou shall not speak ill of a fellow Republican,'" Friess wrote in a letter sent to Republican National Committee chairman Reince Priebus. A copy was obtained by The Associated Press.
In the dispatch, Friess cites the backing of casino magnate Sheldon Adelson and Chicago Cubs co-owner Todd Ricketts. "Would you join the effort to inspire a more civil way of making their points?" Friess wrote. "If they drift off the 'civility reservation,' let's all immediately communicate that to them."
The call for calm comes as the sprawling Republican field shows signs it could tip into a bare-knuckles struggle for the nomination  a scenario that the party's elite donors see as a distressing echo of four years ago.
New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie on Monday charged that Republicans don't need Texas Sen. Ted Cruz's "lectures." Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker repeatedly dismisses Republicans in Congress as doing little. And Kentucky Sen. Rand Paul regularly jabs his Republican opponents by name.
Yet no candidate has injected more provocation into the 2016 Republican presidential primary than Trump.
While few party officials see the reality television star as a credible candidate, he has lashed out at a growing number of Republican critics who have condemned his recent description of Mexican immigrants as criminals and rapists. Trump over the weekend posted a message from another user on his Twitter account charging that former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush "has to like the Mexican illegals because of his wife," Columba, who was born in Mexico.
Campaigning in New Hampshire over the weekend, Bush said he "absolutely" took the remark personally. Trump has not apologized, but said Monday evening "somebody else" retweeted the message and "I don't know anything about it" even though it was under his account.
Reuters/David BeckerFormer Florida Gov. Jeb Bush (R).
Trump stood firm on his comments about immigrants, saying earlier Monday "the Mexican government is forcing their most unwanted people into the United States," and "criminals, drug dealers, rapists" are among them. He said "many fabulous people" come from Mexico and the U.S. is better for them, but this country is "a dumping ground for Mexico."
Republican donor John Jordan said Monday that GOP leaders should take steps to block Trump's access to the first presidential debate in early August.
Debate organizers at Fox News Channel, backed by the Republican National Committee, have released guidelines saying the top 10 candidates in national polling will be allowed to participate. Trump would qualify under the current terms, while contenders such as Ohio's two-term Gov. John Kasich would not.
"Someone in the party ought to start some sort of petition saying, 'If Trump's going to be on the stage, I'm not going to be on there with him,'" Jordan told the AP on Monday. "I'm toying with the idea of it."
"It's something I feel strongly about as somebody who not only cares about the Republican Party, but also Latinos," Jordan said.
Even as the other candidates say they're trying to avoid intraparty backbiting, however, they can't seem to avoid it.
In an interview Sunday on NBC's "Meet the Press," Cruz refused to condemn Trump's comments, saying he's not going to perpetrate "Republican-on-Republican violence." Christie, who entered the presidential race last week, wasn't having it.
"I find it ironic, right, that Ted Cruz is giving lectures on Republican-on-Republican violence," Christie said on Fox News, accusing the Texan of sponsoring hardball ads against Republican Sen. Lamar Alexander in the 2014 primaries. "I mean, all due respect, I don't need to be lectured by Ted Cruz."
Fox NewsSen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas)
The Republican National Committee has dramatically reduced the number of primary debates before the 2016 contest largely to avoid the kind of attacks that bloodied their 2012 nominee, Mitt Romney.
As the last GOP nomination heated up in January 2012, Romney and former House Speaker Newt Gingrich got particularly nasty. Gingrich joined Obama supporters in attacking Romney's business background, calling him a "vulture capitalist."
Donors remember those exchanges well and fear a repeat of primary vitriol would lead to another general election loss. "Ninety-nine percent of leading donors saw the candidates carve each other up in the 2012 primaries and come out weaker for it and are determined not to let that happen again," said Fred Malek, who has helped raise money for GOP presidential candidates for four decades.
Responding to Friess' letter, former Arkansas Gov. Mike Huckabee wrote he plans on "becoming the nominee by playing a better game, not by breaking the legs of my rivals."
"I hope that we don't commit fratricide again as a party," Huckabee wrote, according to a copy of his response obtained by the AP.
___
Associated Press writer Jonathan Lemire in New York City contributed to this report.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
