<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Highway troopers work to remove a car from the Caney River, north of Collinsville, Okla.; officials say no one was inside the vehicle - @TiffanyAlaniz</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/TiffanyAlaniz/status/594122736609427457/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Highway troopers work to remove a car from the Caney River, north of Collinsville, Okla.; officials say no one was inside the vehicle - @TiffanyAlaniz</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Chevron's 1st-quarter earnings per share, revenue fall sharply - @MarketWatch</title>
        <Link>http://www.marketwatch.com/investing/stock/CVX?siteid=bullytweet</Link>
        <Description>Chevron's 1st-quarter earnings per share, revenue fall sharply - @MarketWatch</Description>
        <MainBody>4 min ago9:06 a.m. May 1, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
7 min ago9:03 a.m. May 1, 2015
- The Wall Street Journal Interactive Edition
35 min ago8:35 a.m. May 1, 2015
- FOXBusiness
46 min ago8:24 a.m. May 1, 2015
- TheStreet.com
53 min ago8:17 a.m. May 1, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
8:42 p.m. April 30, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
4:01 p.m. April 30, 2015
- TheStreet.com
2:26 p.m. April 30, 2015
- TheStreet.com
1:30 p.m. April 30, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
1:15 p.m. April 30, 2015
- benzinga.com
9:18 a.m. April 30, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
3:06 a.m. April 30, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
6:33 p.m. April 29, 2015
- The Wall Street Journal Interactive Edition
1:59 p.m. April 29, 2015
- 247WallSt.com
1:05 p.m. April 29, 2015
- TheStreet.com
10:29 a.m. April 29, 2015
- Seeking Alpha
8:30 a.m. April 29, 2015
- TheStreet.com
7:22 a.m. April 29, 2015
- InvestorPlace.com
6:50 a.m. April 29, 2015
- InvestorPlace.com
2:37 p.m. April 28, 2015
- The Wall Street Journal Interactive Edition
Loading more headlines...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Fiat-Chrysler reports April sales up 5.8%, below estimates of 7.5% increase - @Lebeaucarnews</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/Lebeaucarnews/status/594117694661730304</Link>
        <Description>Fiat-Chrysler reports April sales up 5.8%, below estimates of 7.5% increase - @Lebeaucarnews</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Pope Francis delivers message at start of food-themed Milan Expo, says the real protagonists of the event should be 'the faces of the men and women who are hungry, who fall ill and even die because of an insufficient or harmful diet' - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/05/01/us-italy-expo-idUSKBN0NM2WD20150501</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis delivers message at start of food-themed Milan Expo, says the real protagonists of the event should be 'the faces of the men and women who are hungry, who fall ill and even die because of an insufficient or harmful diet' - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>MILAN | By James Mackenzie
Italian tenor Andrea Bocelli performs in front of the Duomo with a concert to inaugurate the Expo 2015 in Milan, Italy, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Flavio Lo Scalzo
MILAN (Reuters) - Italy opened the Milan Expo on Friday, torn between hopes the showcase of global food, culture and technology will lift a gloomy national mood and fears it will be overshadowed by scandal, delays and protests.
Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, counting on the Expo to reinforce fragile signs of economic recovery, says the event will be a test for the future of Italy after years of stagnation and recession.
"Today it is as though Italy is embracing the world," he said at the opening ceremony. "All you experts who kept saying 'we'll never do it', this is your answer," he said.
But the event, on the theme of sustainable food production, has already faced a corruption investigation that saw several top officials in the organizing body arrested, cost overruns, and construction hold-ups that meant large parts of the site were not ready for opening day.
Planned demonstrations by anti-Expo campaigners, who see the event as a bloated symbol of waste and corruption, and fears of security incidents following an unrelated gun attack in a Milan courthouse last month have also dampened the mood.
Officials say the problems will be forgotten once the six-month-long exhibition gets underway.
With 10 million tickets already sold, they are counting on some 20 million people attending, and hope overall revenues will top 10 billion euros ($10.75 billion), half from foreign visitors drawn to Milan.
But the fair, which follows the 2010 Expo in Shanghai, has also rallied a range of protesters, from anti-globalization and environmentalist activists to students and anti-austerity campaigners.
Pope Francis, who spoke via a televised linkup to the opening ceremony, referred to the irony of a global mega spectacle devoted to sustainable development and feeding the poor.
"In certain ways, the Expo itself is part of this paradox of abundance, it obeys the culture of waste and does not contribute to a model of equitable and sustainable development," he said.
The real protagonists of the event should be "the faces of the men and women who are hungry, who fall ill and even die because of an insufficient or harmful diet," he said.
Tens of thousands of demonstrators, grouped under the umbrella label NoExpo, are expected to take to the streets of Milan on Friday in protest against an event many see as a symbol of big business interests hiding behind a cover of green sustainability. Around 4,000 police have been assigned to counter the protests.
Expo 2015 will feature interactive technological displays on the theme of "Feeding the Planet", with national pavilions from 54 countries presenting educational exhibitions and samples of local cuisine.
Cultural events, futuristic architecture, a "supermarket of the future" and dozens of restaurants fill the site, which, critics note, required more than 1 million square meters of farmland on the outskirts of Milan to be concreted over.
In all, more than 140 countries are taking part, with 54 national pavilions. China, an increasing presence in Italian after a string of high-profile business acquisitions, is particularly well represented.
(Additional reporting by Sara Rossi; Editing by Jeremy Gaunt )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Sources: Ex-Chris Christie appointee David Wildstein expected to enter plea deal in connection with bridge closure scandal - @NBCNewYork</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcnewyork.com/investigations/George-Washington-Bridge-Lane-Closure-Scandal-Chris-Christie-David-Wildstein-302121241.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_NYBrand</Link>
        <Description>Sources: Ex-Chris Christie appointee David Wildstein expected to enter plea deal in connection with bridge closure scandal - @NBCNewYork</Description>
        <MainBody>David Wildstein speaks during a hearing Thursday, Jan. 9, 2014, at the Statehouse in Trenton.
Updated 30 minutes ago
The former Port Authority official who resigned amid the political uproar over the George Washington Bridge lane closures in September 2013 is due in federal court in Newark Friday, where he is expected to enter into a plea deal in the scandal, according to sources familiar with the matter.
David Wildstein, a former ally of Gov. Chris Christie and a Christie appointee to the Port Authority, is expected to plead guilty to unspecified criminal charges in connection with the lane closures at an 11 a.m. court appearance, sources familiar with the case said.
Baltimore Public Defender's Post About Jail Goes Viral
Authorities have also planned an afternoon news briefing for Friday, at which point they are expected to announce the names of other former Christie aides indicted in the scandal, which skewered the Republican's presidential ambitions and caused his popularity in the Garden State to tank.
Specific charges any former aides may face remain unclear. A federal grand jury has been hearing evidence for months in the case.
Top News Photos of the Week
The lane closings at the bridge, which links Fort Lee and New York City, caused massive traffic problems for days and investigators had been looking to see if the closure was retribution against Fort Lee's Democratic mayor for failing to endorse Christie's gubernatorial re-election bid.
Wildstein's lawyer Alan Zegas did not return calls and emails for comment Wednesday and Thursday. Spokesmen for U.S. Attorney Paul Fishman, the Justice Department and the FBI have all declined to comment.
Timeline: George Washington Bridge Scandal
Christie has denied knowing about any lane closure plans, saying he first learned of the controversy when stories appeared in the media.  Christie has said he believed his aides and their claims that the closure was part of a traffic study. But a lawyer for Wildstein alleged in February 2014 that the governor knew about them and that he had evidence tying the governor to it.
Officials familiar with the investigation have told NBC 4 New Yorkthat there is no evidence showing Christie had any advance knowledge of the lane closures.
In email exchanges obtained by news outlets last year, Wildstein and Bridget Anne Kelly, a Christie deputy chief of staff, wrote about shutting down the bridge.
"Time for some traffic problems in Fort Lee," Kelly wrote.
Youth Football Coach Who Fought to Prevent Violence Shot, Killed in Car: NYPD
A few weeks later, on the weekend before the lane closures, Wildstein wrote to her: "I will call you Monday AM to let you know how Fort Lee goes."
The unannounced closings caused traffic backups that lasted hours on streets in Fort Lee, where the mouth of the bridge is located.
Freddie Gray Investigation: What's Next?
Text messages also obtained by NBC 4 New York and other news outlets show an unidentified person texting Wildstein about the Fort Lee mayor, Mark Sokolich, asking for help on the second day of the closures: "Is it wrong that I am smiling?"
He texted back: "No."
The other person texted about feeling bad for children not being able to get to school because of the traffic.
Wildstein wrote back: "They are the children of Buono voters," referring to Christie's 2013 opponent for governor, Democrat Barbara Buono.
In December, a 136-page interim report by a joint legislative panel tasked with investigating the lane closures found no evidence Christie was involved in the scheme. The report echoed the findings of an independent investigation commissioned by Christie's administration that found no proof the governor was involved in the closures or subsequent cover-up, and the governor has consistently denied any advance knowledge of the traffic scheme.
Federal prosecutors issued a new subpoena to the Port Authority last month in connection with the case seeking evidence related to claims that members of the Christie administration may have engaged in retaliatory action against Jersey City's mayor for the non-endorsement. The request included records from former Port Authority officials who were appointed by or were allies of Christie.
The investigation has remained a point of frustration for many supporters of Christie, who has termed the lane closings "inexplicably stupid." Lawyers hired by the governor and a legislative committee investigating the circumstances of the lane closures have found no evidence to contradict his denials of any advance knowledge of them.
News of Wildsteins expected guilty plea was first reported by Bloomberg News.
Published 2 hours ago
Follow Jonathan Dienst on Twitter @jonathan4NY , Facebook or email him: jonathan.dienst@nbcuni.com

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>12 EU citizens confirmed dead in Nepal quake, ambassador says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/01/12-eu-citizens-confirmed-dead-in-nepal-quake-amba</Link>
        <Description>12 EU citizens confirmed dead in Nepal quake, ambassador says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>12 EU citizens confirmed dead in Nepal quake, ambassador says - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Obama administration to provide $20 million in grants towards body cameras for local police, Justice Department says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/01/obama-administration-to-provide-20-million-in-gra</Link>
        <Description>Obama administration to provide $20 million in grants towards body cameras for local police, Justice Department says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>May 01, 2015, 11:53 AM GMT
(
11:53
)
Obama administration to provide $20 million in grants towards body cameras for local police, Justice Department says - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>1,000 Europeans unaccounted for after Nepal quake, head of EU delegation says - @Reuters, @AFP</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/AFP/status/594103883141623808</Link>
        <Description>1,000 Europeans unaccounted for after Nepal quake, head of EU delegation says - @Reuters, @AFP</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Street in Beşiktaş, Istanbul after police use water cannon and tear gas - @CNNTURK_ENG</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/CNNTURK_ENG/status/594100154204082176/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Street in Beşiktaş, Istanbul after police use water cannon and tear gas - @CNNTURK_ENG</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Police clash with May Day demonstrators in Beşiktaş, Istanbul - @MithatcanAydos</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/MithatcanAydos/status/594098488713019393/video/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Police clash with May Day demonstrators in Beşiktaş, Istanbul - @MithatcanAydos</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Police in Beşiktaş, Istanbul - @ZiaWeise</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/ZiaWeise/status/594098163943940096/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Police in Beşiktaş, Istanbul - @ZiaWeise</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Turkish police use water cannon and tear gas on stone-throwing protesters in Istanbul - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/01/turkish-police-use-water-cannon-and-tear-gas-on-st</Link>
        <Description>Turkish police use water cannon and tear gas on stone-throwing protesters in Istanbul - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkish police use water cannon and tear gas on stone-throwing protesters in Istanbul - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: May Day demonstrations in Turkey - @selingirit</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/selingirit/status/594096578882904064/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: May Day demonstrations in Turkey - @selingirit</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Police and army clean up Patan Darbar Square in Kathmandu, Nepal - @kundadixitPho</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/kundadixit/status/594061443663732736/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Police and army clean up Patan Darbar Square in Kathmandu, Nepal - @kundadixitPho</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: May Day in Beirut - @_RichardHall</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/_RichardHall/status/594080804558524416/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: May Day in Beirut - @_RichardHall</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: May Day in Turkey as police enforce lockdown in central Istanbul - @HDNER</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/HDNER/status/594064191042015233/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: May Day in Turkey as police enforce lockdown in central Istanbul - @HDNER</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Lloyds bank upgrades profit forecasts - @telegraph</title>
        <Link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/banksandfinance/11575945/Lloyds-profits-fall-by-155m-on-TSB-sale-costs.html</Link>
        <Description>Lloyds bank upgrades profit forecasts - @telegraph</Description>
        <MainBody>Comments
Lloyds hiked its profit forecasts and showed it was ready to become a major dividend payer on Friday, in a pre-election fillip for George Osborne.
Shares in the bank rose by more than 3pc to above 80p, well above the Treasurys break-even price, in a boost to the Chancellors plan for a multi-billion pound share sale to the public.
On Friday, Lloyds said that profit margins this year would be above previous forecasts , after a substantial decline in funding costs. The banks capital ratio  a measure of the buffers it has built up to absorb losses  rose substantially, suggesting the bank will be free to pay a healthy dividend at interim results in July.
TSB was spun out of Lloyds and floated last year, and the bank retained a 50pc stake before Sabadell came calling with a 1.7bn offer in March .
The bank currently rents its IT systems from Lloyds but they will transfer to the Spanish lenders platform when the deal completes, triggering a 450m dowry payment from Lloyds agreed when TSB was floated . This payment, along with IT licensing fees the bank will no longer see from TSB, triggered the 660m charge realised in Fridays results.
This sent first-quarter profits falling by 11pc to 1.2bn, despite a healthy improvement in the banks underlying performance.
The share price rise came as a boost to the Chancellor
Operating profits were up 21pc year-on-year to 2.2bn, and the net interest margin  the key profit margin on lending for banks  was up from 2.32pc to 2.65pc. As a result, Lloyds said net interest margins would be higher than the 2.55pc it had originally expected.
The capital ratio, which has been built up in recent years at the expense of dividends, rose to 13.4pc, well above management targets, suggesting a significant chunk of future profits can be paid out to shareholders. Lloyds said it expects to pay an interim and full-year dividend.
Todays results clearly show that management is delivering and we think investors will welcome a very clean set of numbers, given the rest of UK banks sector is still producing very messy results, said Joseph Dickerson, a banking analyst at Jefferies.
The Treasury is slowly selling down its stake in Lloyds in a drip-feed process co-ordinated by Morgan Stanley , which has seen its stake in the bank fall to under 21pc in recent months.
Mr Osborne has pledged that a Conservative government would sell 4bn of shares to the public in the first year of a new parliament at a 5pc discount , although it will not do so below the Treasurys 73.6p break-even price, which represents the 20.5bn cost of bailing out Lloyds in 2008.
Antonio Horta-Osorio, chief executive of Lloyds
On Friday, Lloyds shares jumped as much as 3.5pc to 80.1p, boosting Mr Osbornes hope of a successful sale. Analysts see a Labour-led government as a significant risk to Lloyds, with Ed Miliband planning to break up the biggest banks and potentially drive down house prices.
The biggest risk to the bank as a pure UK play is the elections, said Bernsteins Chirantan Barua.
Lloyds chief executive Antonio Horta-Osorio brushed off election fears, saying the economic recovery will prove resilient.
We continue to see the economy going quite well, he said. All of our key customer segments present a very favourable trend, I dont think that these trends will change any time soon.
The most successful companies in the world that you've almost certainly never heard of

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Heavy rain in Brisbane, Australia leads to flooding - @SkyNewsAust</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/SkyNewsAust/status/594063235558572033</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Heavy rain in Brisbane, Australia leads to flooding - @SkyNewsAust</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>Istanbul goes into security lockdown to prevent May Day rallies at Taksim Square - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/01/istanbul-goes-into-security-lockdown-to-prevent-ma</Link>
        <Description>Istanbul goes into security lockdown to prevent May Day rallies at Taksim Square - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Istanbul goes into security lockdown to prevent May Day rallies at Taksim Square - @Reuters
End of alert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>Online music streaming service Grooveshark shuts down after 4-year legal battle - statement</title>
        <Link>http://grooveshark.com/</Link>
        <Description>Online music streaming service Grooveshark shuts down after 4-year legal battle - statement</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
