<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Lightning strikes as storms approach Wichita Falls, Texas - @Weatheric</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/Weatheric/status/603357372367544320/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Lightning strikes as storms approach Wichita Falls, Texas - @Weatheric</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Officials report tornadic circulation 5 miles northwest of Morgan Mill, Texas, moving slowly southeast - @NWSFortWorth</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/breakingweather/status/603354332734615553</Link>
        <Description>Officials report tornadic circulation 5 miles northwest of Morgan Mill, Texas, moving slowly southeast - @NWSFortWorth</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Police take 1 person into custody in connection to ongoing barricade situation in Koreatown, Los Angeles - @KTLA</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/kareennews/status/603352923381190657</Link>
        <Description>Police take 1 person into custody in connection to ongoing barricade situation in Koreatown, Los Angeles - @KTLA</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Orlando Executive Airport placed on lockdown as police search for robbery suspects on property - @WESH</title>
        <Link>http://www.wesh.com/news/search-for-robbery-suspects-prompts-lockdown-at-orlando-executive-airport-police-say/33231488?absolute=true&amp;utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=wesh</Link>
        <Description>Orlando Executive Airport placed on lockdown as police search for robbery suspects on property - @WESH</Description>
        <MainBody>Search for robbery suspect prompts lockdown at Orlando Executive Airport, officials say
Suspect is considered armed, police say
UPDATED8:50 PM EDT May 26, 2015
ALarge Text
Photos
Orlando Executive Airport was placed on lockdown Tuesday night while officers searched for a robbery suspect on the property, according to the Federal Aviation Administration officials.
More
Authorities issued the lockdown shortly before 8 p.m. while they looked for the suspect by foot and with a helicopter.
Orlando police said the suspect is wanted in connected to an armed robbery at the Mattress One store on East Colonial Drive. He is described as Hispanic man weighing 160 to 180 pounds and wearing a white shirt and khaki shorts. He is approximately 5 feet 9 inches, police said.
Anyone with information is asked to call Crimeline at 407-423-TIPS.
See breaking news photos uploaded by WESH.com u local members below. Upload your photos here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>EVA Air Flight 12, from Taipei to Los Angeles, taken to secure area of Los Angeles airport as authorities investigate bomb threat - @latimes</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-fbi-bomb-threat-lax-taipei-20150526-story.html?track=rss&amp;utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;dlvrit=649324</Link>
        <Description>EVA Air Flight 12, from Taipei to Los Angeles, taken to secure area of Los Angeles airport as authorities investigate bomb threat - @latimes</Description>
        <MainBody>Shortly after landing at LAX about 3:40 p.m., EVA Air Flight 12 was taken to a secure area as airport officials and federal agents investigated the bomb threat, according to law enforcement sources.
According to FBI spokeswoman Laura Eimiller, the threat to the aircraft was made via telephone.
The LAPD's bomb squad was also en route to the airport, according to a department spokeswoman.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Oklahoma City Community College evacuated because of bomb threat, school spokesperson says - @koconews</title>
        <Link>http://www.koco.com/news/occc-evacuated-because-of-bomb-threat/33231050?absolute=true&amp;utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=koconews</Link>
        <Description>Oklahoma City Community College evacuated because of bomb threat, school spokesperson says - @koconews</Description>
        <MainBody>Nothing suspicious found on OCCC campus after bomb threat causes evacuation
Police believe bomb threat was bogus, officials say
UPDATED7:52 PM CDT May 26, 2015
ALarge Text
Photos
Oklahoma City police officers did not find anything Tuesday evening on Oklahoma City Community College's campus after the library was evacuated, officials said.
The campus has been released and given the all-clear, according to officials.
Officials believe the bomb threat was bogus.
OCCC's police dispatch received a call Tuesday about a bomb threat, officials said. Campus and Oklahoma City police evacuated the library and searched the scene.
The school was scheduled to host a town hall meeting in the library with Congressman Steve Russell. The town hall meeting was scheduled to start at 5:45 p.m.
Russell was on campus, and he was evacuated with everyone else, officials said. The town hall meeting was moved to the Family and Community Education Center, officials said.
Stay with KOCO.com for breaking news updates.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Australian Cardinal George Pell says he is prepared to give evidence in person to the Royal Commission in child sex abuse case - @SkyNewsAust</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/SkyNewsAust/status/603348289329594368</Link>
        <Description>Australian Cardinal George Pell says he is prepared to give evidence in person to the Royal Commission in child sex abuse case - @SkyNewsAust</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Strong winds fan growing wildfire burning in Carn Brea, England - @pderuvo</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/pderuvo/status/603327083868217344</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Strong winds fan growing wildfire burning in Carn Brea, England - @pderuvo</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Man sentenced to 6 years in federal prison, ordered to pay $6.5 million for fires set in California's Sequoia National Forest - @LANow</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-sequoia-forest-fire-sentence-20150526-story.html?track=rss&amp;utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;dlvrit=649324</Link>
        <Description>Man sentenced to 6 years in federal prison, ordered to pay $6.5 million for fires set in California's Sequoia National Forest - @LANow</Description>
        <MainBody>Man ordered to pay $6.5 million for Sequoia National Forest fires
Man sentenced for starting fire
Mark Ralston / AFP/Getty Images
A man was sentenced to federal prison fo sparking fire in the Sequoia National Forest last year.
A man was sentenced to federal prison fo sparking fire in the Sequoia National Forest last year.
(Mark Ralston / AFP/Getty Images)
Man sentenced for sparking a large fire last year in the Sequoia National Forest
A Perris man was ordered to pay $6.5 million in restitution for starting the Nicolls fire
A Perris man was sentenced Tuesday to more than six years in federal prison and ordered to pay about $6.5 million in restitution to the U.S. Forest Service after fires he lighted at a marijuana growing site sparked a 1,600-acre wildfire.
Tack him to a dead tree and set him on fire, that would seem about right.
Central squared
7
The Nicolls fire started in the Kiavah Wilderness Area just southeast of Onyx in Kern County and destroyed 1,680 acres of forest, causing more than $6.5 million in damage.
Fournier was watering and tending to 2,090 marijuana plants at a large-scale growing operation in the Smith Canyon area of the Sequoia National Forest, according to court documents.
He admitted to lighting several fires July 11 and 12 in and near the marijuana growing site within the Kiaviah Wilderness Area.
The fires grew out of control and eventually became one massive wildfire.
Although the fire destroyed portions of the forest, it did not damage the marijuana site. But authorities said the marijuana operation caused significant damage to the forest and its national resources.
For breaking news in California, follow @VeronicaRochaLA .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Police seal off neighborhood near Koreatown, Los Angeles, where fugitive wanted for murder is barricaded - @NBCLA</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/local/Fugitive-Holed-Up-in-LA-Neighborhood-305089871.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_LABrand</Link>
        <Description>Police seal off neighborhood near Koreatown, Los Angeles, where fugitive wanted for murder is barricaded - @NBCLA</Description>
        <MainBody>Updated 47 minutes ago
KNBC
LAPD officers were in a standoff with a fugitive wanted for murder in a Los Angels neighborhood on Tuesday, May 26, 2015.
Police were evacuating a Los Angeles neighborhood where a fugitive wanted for murder was barricaded Tuesday, officials said.
Officers were sealing off the 200 block of N. Kenmore Avenue ( map ), between Beverly Boulevard and 1st Street, Los Angeles Police department officials said.
A SWAT team was called in to take the fugitive into custody.
No further information was immediately available
Southern California Images in the News
Refresh this page for updates on this developing story.
Published 2 hours ago
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Large tornado reported on the ground near Gordon, Texas; residents urged to seek shelter - @NewsFixDFW</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/NewsFixDFW/status/603345641666777088/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Large tornado reported on the ground near Gordon, Texas; residents urged to seek shelter - @NewsFixDFW</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Tornado touches down south of Hydro, Okla.; storm moving east - @themahler</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/themahler/status/603343223478591488/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Tornado touches down south of Hydro, Okla.; storm moving east - @themahler</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Local media reports 1 dead, 10 injured after roof collapses during heavy rain in Saltillo, Mexico - @zerlaramontoya</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/zerlaramontoya/status/603336548923277312</Link>
        <Description>Local media reports 1 dead, 10 injured after roof collapses during heavy rain in Saltillo, Mexico - @zerlaramontoya</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Police: 1 person killed, 8 injured in multi-vehicle crash in Queens, New York - @NBCNewYork</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/NYC-Queens-Fatal-Accident-Injuries-Truck-Cars-305042141.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_NYBrand</Link>
        <Description>Police: 1 person killed, 8 injured in multi-vehicle crash in Queens, New York - @NBCNewYork</Description>
        <MainBody>Privacy Policy | More Newsletters
Updated at 2:19 PM EDT on Tuesday, May 26, 2015
One person was killed and eight other people were injured in a three-car crash in Queens on Tuesday morning, according to the NYPD.
A GMC Suburban collided with a Dodge Neon at South Conduit Avenue and 130th Street in South Ozone Park, police said. That forced the Neon in front of a box truck, which crippled the car and pushed it up against a guard rail, police said.
Man Removed Pizza Sign From Car, Tried to Enter NJ Home: PD
Over a dozen firefighters arrived at the scene and tried to remove someone from the Neon.
Eight people, including five children, were taken to area hospitals, the NYPD said. The Neon's passenger, a 53-year-old woman, was pronounced dead upon arrival at Jamaica Hospital Medical Center. The 30-year-old woman driving the Neon was taken to the same hospital in stable condition.
9 Brains Found Next to Train Tracks in NY
Five children were headed to school in the Suburban. They were taken to an area hospital with minor injuries, police said. The driver of the Suburban was taken to an area hospital in stable condition.
Geeta Bisram's two nephews were among the injured. She said one of the boys injured his nose when he was forced against the front seat during the crash. She said the other boy, who was in the front seat, injured his legs.
"They're pretty traumatized,"Bisram said.
The driver of the box truck was treated at the scene, according to police.
Police said the investigation is ongoing and that no one has been arrested.
Published at 1:52 PM EDT on May 26, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Editor's note: The death toll from severe storms in Oklahoma and Texas over the weekend currently stands at 18. In Texas, 11 people have been confirmed dead, including 4 in the Houston area. Severe storms and flooding have also killed 7 people in Oklahoma since Friday. At least 13 people remain missing in Texas.  - Jillian</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/05/26/the-death-toll-from-severe-storms-in-oklahoma-and</Link>
        <Description>Editor's note: The death toll from severe storms in Oklahoma and Texas over the weekend currently stands at 18. In Texas, 11 people have been confirmed dead, including 4 in the Houston area. Severe storms and flooding have also killed 7 people in Oklahoma since Friday. At least 13 people remain missing in Texas.  - Jillian</Description>
        <MainBody>May 26, 2015, 11:27 PM GMT
(
23:27
)
Editor's note: The death toll from severe storms in Oklahoma and Texas over the weekend currently stands at 18. In Texas, 11 people have been confirmed dead, including 4 in the Houston area. Severe storms and flooding have also killed 7 people in Oklahoma since Friday. At least 13 people remain missing in Texas.  - Jillian
End of note
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Lightning strike seen in Oklahoma City earlier today as severe storms hit area - @jimintheair via @themahler</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/themahler/status/603336546142543872/photo/1</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Lightning strike seen in Oklahoma City earlier today as severe storms hit area - @jimintheair via @themahler</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Flight from Taipei to Los Angeles lands safely after reported threat onboard, airport says; FBI on scene - @flyLAXairport</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/flyLAXairport/status/603336534113267713</Link>
        <Description>Flight from Taipei to Los Angeles lands safely after reported threat onboard, airport says; FBI on scene - @flyLAXairport</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Emergency officials evaluate damage to supermarket in Queens, New York after car crashes into building - @NBCNewYork</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/Car-Crash-Pathmark-Supermarket-Flushing-Queens-Injuries-305087541.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_NYBrand</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Emergency officials evaluate damage to supermarket in Queens, New York after car crashes into building - @NBCNewYork</Description>
        <MainBody>@NYPD109Pct/Twitter
Updated 8 minutes ago
A car barreled into a supermarket in the Flushing section of Queens Tuesday evening, critically injuring at least one person, authorities say.
A photo of the scene tweeted out by the NYPD shows what appears to be an SUV inside the Pathmark supermarket on Farrington Street. The 109th Precinct account warned residents to avoid the area, and that there were "numerous injuries."
The FDNY says EMS has transported one person in critical condition to Booth Memorial Hospital.
Check back for updates to this developing story.
Photo credit: @NYPD109Pct/Twitter
Published 2 hours ago
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>Dallas-Fort Worth Airport reopens runway after nearby sinkhole causes closure - @dfwairport</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/dfwairport/status/603334082475397120</Link>
        <Description>Dallas-Fort Worth Airport reopens runway after nearby sinkhole causes closure - @dfwairport</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
