<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Breaking News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>White House: President Obama briefed by advisors on attack at Air Products factory, an American company - @NBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/white-house-president-obama-briefed-by-advisors-o</Link>
        <Description>White House: President Obama briefed by advisors on attack at Air Products factory, an American company - @NBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Greece's finance minister suggests that his country may not pay the 1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to IMF on Tuesday - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.brandonsun.com/world/breaking-news/the-latest-greece-wants-european-central-bank-to-keep-giving-its-banks-emergency-help-310433991.html?thx=y</Link>
        <Description>Greece's finance minister suggests that his country may not pay the 1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to IMF on Tuesday - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>Enlarge Image
Tourists walks past a graffiti made by street artist N_Grams that read ''NO'' in German but also ''YES, IN'' in Greek language in Athens, on Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
ATHENS, Greece - The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations (all times local):
___
4:10 p.m.
Greece's finance minister is suggesting that his country might not pay the 1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis refused to reply to a direct question Sunday on the payment. Instead, he told BBC radio that the European Central Bank should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014. Varoufakis calls that idea "a very sensible transfer."
Asked directly, for the second time, whether Greece will pay up Tuesday, Varoufakis replies: "We are owed money by one part of the troika and we owe money to another part of the troika? Why don't they sort themselves out and transfer money from one pocket ... to the other?"
___
3:35 p.m.
The European Central Bank has announced it is maintaining emergency credit to Greek banks at its current level.
The decision keeps a key financial lifeline open but does not provide further credit to Greece's banks, which are seeing deposits drain away as anxious Greeks withdraw savings.
The ECB said it was working closely with the Bank of Greece to maintain financial stability and added it could reconsider the decision on credit levels.
ECB head Mario Draghi said "we continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies."
___
3:20 p.m.
France's prime minister is urging Greece and other nations to do whatever they can to keep Greece in the 19-nation bloc that uses the euro currency.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said Sunday that "we don't know  none of us  the consequences of an exit from the eurozone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the eurozone." He was speaking on France's i-Tele TV.
Valls added that "means respecting Greece and democracy, but it's also about respecting European rules. So Greece needs to come back to the negotiating table."
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' call for a national referendum on creditors' demands has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil.
___
2:35 p.m.
Germany's Foreign Ministry is advising travellers to Greece to ensure they have enough cash on them before they depart.
An updated version of the ministry's travel advice issued Sunday noted that people seeking to withdraw cash in Greece could face "significant waits" and possible shortages at cash machines.
Worried Greeks were lining up at ATM machines on Sunday, the day after the Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for a referendum on creditors' financial proposals in return for rescue loans and creditors refused to extend Greece's international bailout beyond Tuesday.
While some machines in Greece were running out of cash, others were being replenished. Another top Greek financial official urged Greeks on Sunday to remain calm and not withdraw all their savings.
___
1:45 p.m.
The European Central Bank faces a major decision.
It has been allowing Greek banks to draw emergency credit from Greece's central bank, a financial lifeline that has been keeping Greece's four major banks going during the country's tense bailout negotiations with creditors. The ECB has been slowly increasing the emergency credit to compensate for the increase in withdrawals from Greek banks.
But the ECB has said it can only continue such assistance if the banks are basically solvent. A failure by Greece's government to get more aid before its bailout ends Tuesday and a big payment to the International Monetary Fund is due could prompt the ECB to decide the Greek banks are not financially solid any more.
Capping the aid would quickly force Greek banks to limit withdrawals  but such controls could take Greece a step closer to leaving the 19-nation eurozone.
ECB President Mario Draghi has said it's up to elected officials to decide Greece's fate. Analysts say the central bank wants to give politicians every chance to negotiate a deal.
___
12:50 p.m.
Two opinion polls indicate most Greeks want to keep using the shared euro currency and would prefer a deal with Greece's European partners rather than a rupture.
The polls published Sunday were both conducted before Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras declared early Saturday that he was calling a referendum on financial proposals made by Greece's creditors in return for continuing to fund the country with bailout loans. Still, they provide an indication of public sentiment.
In the poll by Alco for the Proto Thema Sunday paper, 57 per cent said they believed Greece should make a deal with its EU partners while 29 per cent wanted a rupture. A separate poll by Kapa Research for the To Vima newspaper found 47.2 per cent of respondents would vote in favour of a new, painful agreement with Greece's creditors, compared to 33 per cent who would vote no and 18.4 per cent undecided.
Both nationwide polls were conducted from June 24-26. The Alco poll had a margin of error of 3.1 per cent while Kapa Research's was 3.09 per cent.
___
12:25 p.m.
A Greek finance official says the government expects the European Central Bank to continue approving emergency liquidity assistance that Greek banks can draw even after Tuesday, when Greece's international bailout officially expires.
The ECB was expected to meet Sunday to decide what action to take about Greece. The central is bank is under pressure to end that emergency assistance.
A decision by Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras to call for a national referendum on creditor demands in exchange for bailout loans has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil. In response, other nations in the 19-nation eurozone are refusing to extend Greece's bailout program beyond its Tuesday expiration date.
Alternate Greek Finance Minister Nadia Valavani told private Mega television on Sunday "we are expecting the funding of Greek banks to continue normally via the ELA after Tuesday."
Worried Greeks have formed lines at ATM machines all weekend and some machines were running out of cash Sunday morning.
Valavani said the country's banks could see "business as usual" next week if they receive the emergency support "so long as there is calm" and Greeks don't attempt to withdraw all their savings.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Kuwait City governor says at least 10 killed in mosque bombing attack - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/kuwait-city-governor-says-at-least-10-killed-in-mo</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait City governor says at least 10 killed in mosque bombing attack - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Burundi's head of parliament flees country, calls for Monday elections to be postponed - @BreakingF24</title>
        <Link>http://www.france24.com/en/breaking/20150628-burundi-parliament-head-leaves-country-calls-elections-be-postponed?ns_campaign=reseaux_sociaux&amp;ns_source=twitter&amp;ns_mchannel=social&amp;ns_linkname=breaking&amp;aef_campaign_ref=partage_aef&amp;aef_campaign_date=2015-06-28&amp;dlvrit=135121</Link>
        <Description>Burundi's head of parliament flees country, calls for Monday elections to be postponed - @BreakingF24</Description>
        <MainBody> 2015 Copyright France 24  All rights reserved
France 24 is not responsible for the content of external websites
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>English tourist who witnessed attack thought he was hearing firecrackers but 'it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire' - @NBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/tunisia-attack-gunmen-kill-least-19-people-attack-sousse-beach-n382346</Link>
        <Description>English tourist who witnessed attack thought he was hearing firecrackers but 'it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire' - @NBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Gunmen opened fire on a beach popular with tourists in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 27 people, the country's interior ministry said.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry told NBC News that at least six people were injured in the attack in the Mediterranean city of Sousse and that one attacker had been killed. The interior ministry said the operation was ongoing.
Gary Pine, a product manager from the U.K., told NBC News he was one of dozens of vacationers on the beach when the attack took place not far from his hotel, the El Mouradi Palm Marina.
He said he initially thought he was hearing firecrackers but that "it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire." His 22-year-old son saw one person get shot, Pine added.
He said guests started running off the beach and were told to go to their rooms by hotel staff, he said. Some guests ran back out onto the beach to get their room keys, he added.
The entertainment manager at the hotel, who only gave his first name, Hamouda, said guests had told him two gunmen "came from the sea" and attacked the beach. He confirmed that staff had told guests to hide in their rooms.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
=======
        <title>Photo: Festival goers read up on the day's news at a stand distributing the Glastonbury Free Press to the estimated 135,000 in attendance at this year's event in Somerset, England - @GlastoLive</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/GlastoLive/status/615149645648502785</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Festival goers read up on the day's news at a stand distributing the Glastonbury Free Press to the estimated 135,000 in attendance at this year's event in Somerset, England - @GlastoLive</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Bomb halts trains between Cairo and Alexandria, no injuries reported - @ahramonline</title>
        <Link>http://english.ahram.org.eg/NewsContent/1/64/133754/Egypt/Politics-/Bomb-explosion-halts-trains-between-Cairo-and-Alex.aspx</Link>
        <Description>Bomb halts trains between Cairo and Alexandria, no injuries reported - @ahramonline</Description>
        <MainBody>Improvised bomb explosion halts trains between Cairo and Alexandria, no injuries
The improvised explosive device did not cause any injuries
Ramses train station (Photo: Reuters)
Related
Bomb diffused in train station in Upper Egypt's Beni Suef
An improvised bomb attack in Egypt on Friday halted trains between Cairo and the Mediterranean city of Alexandria, but left no casualties, security officials said.
A home-made bomb went off near the city of Damanhour, some 70 kilometres from Alexandria, director of security Maj. Gen. Mohamed Fathy said. 
The blast left no casualties, he said, but caused damage to the railway line, bringing train movement to a halt.
Railway lines are frequently targeted by anti-government militants operating in Egyptian cities.
Bomb explosions in Kafr El-Zayat in the Nile Delta briefly halted Cairo-Alexandria trains in February.
Similar attacks also disrupted services in the southern city of Aswan and in the Nile Delta city of Zagazig the previous month.
No casualties were reported in relation to the incidents.
Search Keywords:

Comment
Ahram Online welcomes readers' comments on all issues covered by the site, along with any criticisms and/or corrections. Readers are asked to limit their feedback to a maximum of 1000 characters (roughly 50 words). All comments/criticisms will, however, be subject to the following code
We will not publish comments which contain rude or abusive language, libelous statements,                                             slander and personal attacks against any person/s.
We will not publish comments which contain racist remarks or any kind of racial                                             or religious incitement against any group of people, in Egypt or outside it.
We welcome criticism of our reports and articles but we will not publish personal                                             attacks, slander or fabrications directed against our reporters and contributing                                             writers.
We reserve the right to correct, when at all possible, obvious errors in spelling                                             and grammar. However, due to time and staffing constraints such corrections will                                             not be made across the board or on a regular basis.
Please Wait
=======
        <title>4 people ages 17 to 20 charged with murder in Cary, NC, hit-and-run that left 16-year-old girl dead - @ABC11_WTVD</title>
        <Link>http://abc11.com/news/4-charged-with-murder-in-cary-hit-and-run/811777/</Link>
        <Description>4 people ages 17 to 20 charged with murder in Cary, NC, hit-and-run that left 16-year-old girl dead - @ABC11_WTVD</Description>
        <MainBody>4 charged with murder in Cary hit-and-run that left high school student dead
Katherine Burdick-Crow
Sunday, June 28, 2015 10:03AM
CARY, NC (WTVD) --
The Cary Police Department has charged four people with murder in a hit-and-run that left 16-year-old Green Hope High School student Katherine Burdick-Crow dead.
They're identified as:
Jourdan Chanquion Mack, 20, of Rambling Hill Drive, Morrisville
Beth Strange, 18, of Fallborough Court, Morrisville
Abijah James Masse, 17, of Narrow Leaf Drive, Morrisville
Joshua Odell Simmons, 17 of Autumn Day Drive, Morrisville
PHOTOS: Hit-and-run suspects
Around 9:20 p.m. on Friday, police and emergency services got a 911 call from Lawrence Road near the entrance of Walnut Street Park from a witness who came up on the scene and said the teen may have fallen off or out of a car.
"Apparently, she was on a car and fell off and a gentleman is here with blood all over his face. He is acting very strange. He said not to call the police but I am calling you cause this girl, I don't feel a pulse or anything, so someone needs to get here very quickly," reported the caller.
Emergency workers tried frantically to save the teen but she died.
Cary police said they believe the four charged got together with Burdick-Crow to make a drug deal, but in the course of the transaction Burdick-Crow was robbed and became involved in an altercation with the suspects.
During the struggle, Burdick-Crow fell from a pickup truck driven by Simmons as the suspects fled the scene.
The Ford F150 has been located by police and processed for evidence.
Although arrests have been made, police say anyone with information is still encouraged to contact the Town of Cary Police Department at (919) 469-4012 or file a report anonymously with Cary Crime Stoppers at (919) 460-4636. Crime Stoppers pays up to $2,500 for the arrest or indictment of those responsible for committing certain types of crimes. All calls will be kept CONFIDENTIAL at the caller's request.
Related Topics:
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Photo: Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/Reuters/status/614376401882497024</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
=======
        <title>6 nations negotiating nuclear agreement with Iran plan to continue talks past Tuesday deadline, says senior US official - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://uk.reuters.com/article/2015/06/28/iran-nuclear-timing-idUKL2N0ZE02K20150628</Link>
        <Description>6 nations negotiating nuclear agreement with Iran plan to continue talks past Tuesday deadline, says senior US official - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Commodities | Sun Jun 28, 2015 1:51pm BST
Iran, big powers plan to keep negotiating beyond June 30
VIENNA, June 28
VIENNA, June 28 The six nations seeking to negotiate a long-term agreement with Iran to curb the most sensitive parts of its nuclear programme plan to continue negotiating beyond Tuesday's deadline, a senior U.S. official said.
The official, who spoke to reporters on condition of anonymity on Sunday, said Washington was not troubled by Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif's decision to return to Tehran overnight, saying it was always expected that ministers would come and go from Vienna as the nuclear talks heated up.
Iran's Tasnim news agency reported that Zarif would return to Austria on Monday.    (Reporting By Arshad Mohammed and Louis Charbonneau)
Trending On Reuters
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Officials: At least 19 killed in Tunisia hotel attacks - @BBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/officials-at-least-19-killed-in-tunisia-hotel-att</Link>
        <Description>Officials: At least 19 killed in Tunisia hotel attacks - @BBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>3 UK students; 3 adults in hospital after Belgium bus crash - @BBCBreaking</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33303121</Link>
        <Description>3 UK students; 3 adults in hospital after Belgium bus crash - @BBCBreaking</Description>
        <MainBody>NI driver killed in Belgium school trip bus crash
28 June 2015
From the section Northern Ireland
A bus driver from Northern Ireland has been killed in a coach crash in Belgium.
He was on a bus carrying 34 school children from an Essex school in the UK.
Another driver, also from Northern Ireland, has been seriously injured.
A pupil from Brentwood School who was on the bus suffered a head injury and is in intensive care. It is understood that three pupils and two teachers are in hospital.
The bus company, Richmond Coaches, is from Lisburn, County Antrim.
The bus overturned on the A18 (E40) at Middelkerke, West Flanders at 09:45 local time (08:45 BST).
Eyewitnesses said it crashed into a motorway bridge pillar.
West Flanders traffic police confirmed that one person is dead and one is injured.
A rescue worker carries students' backpacks from the bus
Thirty-one children and three teachers walked away from the crash.
The children from Brentwood School were all aged from 11 to 13 years old.
Ian Davies, the school's head teacher said: "There are three children in hospital. We don't know the full extent of their injuries.
"I know that one boy has a head injury which is being monitored very carefully.
"I have spoken to the lead teacher on the trip. He is in hospital, I think he broke his collar bone, but seemed in as good a shape as could be expected."
A spokesman from Richmond Coaches of Ballinderry Road, Lisburn, confirmed that one of its vehicles had been involved in the crash.
He said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved and they were cooperating fully with the authorities.
Janna Rommel-Opstaele, the mayor of the nearby coastal town of Middelkerke, told press agency Reuters that the bus driver had been killed and another seriously injured.
"Some of the children with light injuries have been taken to hospital and local medical centres," she said.
A spokesman for the Foreign and Commonwealth Office said they were aware of the crash and were working with  the Belgian authorities to establish details.
Have you been affected by this incident? You can email haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk with your experiences.
If you are willing to speak further to a BBC journalist, please include a contact phone number.
Email your pictures to yourpics@bbc.co.uk , upload them here , tweet them to @BBC_HaveYourSay or text 61124. If you are outside the UK, send them to the international number +44 7624 800 100.
Or WhatsApp us on +44 7525 900971
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Photo: Firefighters responding to 2-alarm apartment fire in Carrollton, Texas</title>
        <Link>http://www.nbcdfw.com/news/local/Firefighters-Respond-to-2-Alarm-Apartment-Fire-in-Carrollton-310048981.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_DFWBrand</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Firefighters responding to 2-alarm apartment fire in Carrollton, Texas</Description>
        <MainBody>Privacy Policy | More Newsletters
Carrollton Fire Department
Firefighters responded to a 2-alarm fire at an apartment leasing office in Carrollton Friday morning. (June 26, 2015)
An apartment lease office erupted into flames Friday morning in Carrollton.
Authorities responded to the two-alarm fire at the Green Tree Apartments clubhouse in Carrollton. The cause of the fire is unknown, and the fire was isolated in the clubhouse.
No other buildings were exposed to the fire, authorities said.
No one was injured in the incident, and no residents were displaced.
NBC 5 has crews on the way and will provide updates as soon as more information comes in.
Published 34 minutes ago
=======
        <title>Irish couple confirmed dead in Tunisia beach attack, bringing confirmed toll for Ireland to 3 - @rtenews</title>
        <Link>http://www.rte.ie/news/2015/0628/711121-tunisia-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Irish couple confirmed dead in Tunisia beach attack, bringing confirmed toll for Ireland to 3 - @rtenews</Description>
        <MainBody>MORE RELATED CLIPS +
The couplehave one daughter.
Mr Hayes was a school bus inspector with Bus ireann and had worked at the company for 20 years, beginning as a bus driver in Galway.
The companyextended its sympathy to the couple's family, andfriends as well as Mr Hayes' colleagues.
Garda and officials from the Department of Foreign Affairs are liaising with the family.
The third Irish victim is Lorna Carty, a mother-of-two from Robinstown in Co Meath.
She was on holidayin the popular beach resort of Sousse with her husband Declan when the attack happened.
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan urged people travelling to Tunisia to exercise extreme caution.
"I'm not in the business of imposing travel bans but I would say to people be extremely vigilant and extremely cautious in implementing any holiday plans in the region and keep in close contact with the tour operators and the police authorities."
Tour companies have already evacuated thousands of holidaymakers from Tunisia following the attack in which 38 people died, the majority of whom were British.
Tunisia's tourism minister called the attack a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Sousses tourism commissioner said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had left the town yesterday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
The British Foreign Office confirmed that 15 Britons had died in the attack, which was carried out by a lone gunman.
Among the British citizens killed was Joel Richards, 22, who played for James Connolly Gaelic Football Club in Birmingham and was also actively involved in Birmingham County FA Youth Council.
Sad to learn that one of those killed in Tunisia was Joel Richards, who played Gaelic Football for the James Connolly club in Birmingham.
 Daniel Mulhall (@DanMulhall) June 28, 2015
1/3 James Connollys GFC is devastated to learn of the death of one of our players, Joel Richards, during the horrific attack in Tunisia.
 Connollys GFC (@Connollys_Gaa) June 27, 2015
Mr Richards' uncle, 46-year-old Adrian Evans and his 78-year-old grandfather Patrick Evans, were also killed in the attack.
His 16-year-old brother Owen survived.
Lincolnshire Photographer Carly Lovett, 24, was killed as were Sue Davey and her partner Scott Chalkley from Staffordshire.
Another British couple, Jim and Ann McQuire from Cumbernauld, are also among the dead.
Tunisian studentSaif Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before making his way to the pool and hotel before being shot dead by police.
Tunisian authorities said Rezgui was not on any watchlist of known potential militants.
But one source said he appeared to have been radicalised over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
The self-styled Islamic State group later claimed responsibility for the attack.
It identified the gunman asAbu Yahya al-Qayrawani - a "soldier of the caliphate".
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
Traveller safety 'paramount' - Sunway
A spokeswoman for Irish tour operator Sunway saidit istrying to contact as many of its customers as possible, including a large number who no longer want to travel to Tunisia.
Sunway said while it is still flying to Tunisia, traveller safety is paramount and it will be guided by the Department of Foreign Affairs.
The 177 people due to travel to Tunisia next Friday are being offered a full refund or a change of destination depending on availability.
Tanya Airey confirmed a high proportion wanted to change their destination and Friday's flight to Monastir is being kept under review.
For departures from 10 July, passengers can cancel for a fee, stay with Tunisia, or be offered a chance to switch to another destination.
There will be no full refunds for departures from 10 July.
Sunway is also facilitating those traveled to Tunisia despite the attack with 59 of the 177 booked on Fridays flight deciding not to go to Tunisia.
"We are holding welcome meetings for them at hotels," Ms Airey said, adding that many of the hotels are at another resort around half an hour away from Sousse where the attack occurred.
Sunway only deals with a proportion of Irish holidaymakers to Tunisia.
Many others are travelling with English companies who are taking direction from the British Foreign office.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Tunisia's Interior Ministry confirms 1 gunmen killed, police pursuing the other in hotels terror attack - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/tunisias-interior-ministry-confirms-1-gunmen-kill</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's Interior Ministry confirms 1 gunmen killed, police pursuing the other in hotels terror attack - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>On Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif's return to Iran amid nuclear talks, US official says it was expected ministers would come and go as negotiations heat up - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/28/on-iranian-foreign-minister-mohammad-javad-zarifs</Link>
        <Description>On Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif's return to Iran amid nuclear talks, US official says it was expected ministers would come and go as negotiations heat up - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28, 2015, 12:47 PM GMT
(
12:47
)
On Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif's return to Iran amid nuclear talks, US official says it was expected ministers would come and go as negotiations heat up - @Reuters
End of alert
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>7 killed as gunmen attack 2 Tunisian hotels, wound others and exchange fire with police - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/7-killed-as-gunmen-attack-2-tunisian-hotels-wound</Link>
        <Description>7 killed as gunmen attack 2 Tunisian hotels, wound others and exchange fire with police - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>More: ECB head Mario Draghi says, 'We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies' - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/d3885a1eb5b24c79964aabbbd4da8697/latest-greece-wants-ecb-keep-giving-emergency-help</Link>
        <Description>More: ECB head Mario Draghi says, 'We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies' - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Greek minister hints no payment Tuesday to IMF
Jun. 28, 2015 9:15 AM EDT
Share article
16 photos
Tourists walks past a graffiti made by street artist N_Grams  that  read \'\'NO\'\' in German but also \'\'YES, IN\'\' in Greek language in Athens, on Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece\'s parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras\' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations (all times local):
___
4:10 p.m.
Greece's finance minister is suggesting that his country might not pay the 1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis refused to reply to a direct question Sunday on the payment. Instead, he told BBC radio that the European Central Bank should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014. Varoufakis calls that idea "a very sensible transfer."
Asked directly, for the second time, whether Greece will pay up Tuesday, Varoufakis replies: "We are owed money by one part of the troika and we owe money to another part of the troika? Why don't they sort themselves out and transfer money from one pocket ... to the other?"
___
3:35 p.m.
The European Central Bank has announced it is maintaining emergency credit to Greek banks at its current level.
The decision keeps a key financial lifeline open but does not provide further credit to Greece's banks, which are seeing deposits drain away as anxious Greeks withdraw savings.
The ECB said it was working closely with the Bank of Greece to maintain financial stability and added it could reconsider the decision on credit levels.
ECB head Mario Draghi said "we continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies."
___
3:20 p.m.
France's prime minister is urging Greece and other nations to do whatever they can to keep Greece in the 19-nation bloc that uses the euro currency.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said Sunday that "we don't know  none of us  the consequences of an exit from the eurozone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the eurozone." He was speaking on France's i-Tele TV.
Valls added that "means respecting Greece and democracy, but it's also about respecting European rules. So Greece needs to come back to the negotiating table."
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' call for a national referendum on creditors' demands has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil.
___
2:35 p.m.
Germany's Foreign Ministry is advising travelers to Greece to ensure they have enough cash on them before they depart.
An updated version of the ministry's travel advice issued Sunday noted that people seeking to withdraw cash in Greece could face "significant waits" and possible shortages at cash machines.
Worried Greeks were lining up at ATM machines on Sunday, the day after the Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for a referendum on creditors' financial proposals in return for rescue loans and creditors refused to extend Greece's international bailout beyond Tuesday.
While some machines in Greece were running out of cash, others were being replenished. Another top Greek financial official urged Greeks on Sunday to remain calm and not withdraw all their savings.
___
1:45 p.m.
The European Central Bank faces a major decision.
It has been allowing Greek banks to draw emergency credit from Greece's central bank, a financial lifeline that has been keeping Greece's four major banks going during the country's tense bailout negotiations with creditors. The ECB has been slowly increasing the emergency credit to compensate for the increase in withdrawals from Greek banks.
But the ECB has said it can only continue such assistance if the banks are basically solvent. A failure by Greece's government to get more aid before its bailout ends Tuesday and a big payment to the International Monetary Fund is due could prompt the ECB to decide the Greek banks are not financially solid any more.
Capping the aid would quickly force Greek banks to limit withdrawals  but such controls could take Greece a step closer to leaving the 19-nation eurozone.
ECB President Mario Draghi has said it's up to elected officials to decide Greece's fate. Analysts say the central bank wants to give politicians every chance to negotiate a deal.
___
12:50 p.m.
Two opinion polls indicate most Greeks want to keep using the shared euro currency and would prefer a deal with Greece's European partners rather than a rupture.
The polls published Sunday were both conducted before Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras declared early Saturday that he was calling a referendum on financial proposals made by Greece's creditors in return for continuing to fund the country with bailout loans. Still, they provide an indication of public sentiment.
In the poll by Alco for the Proto Thema Sunday paper, 57 percent said they believed Greece should make a deal with its EU partners while 29 percent wanted a rupture. A separate poll by Kapa Research for the To Vima newspaper found 47.2 percent of respondents would vote in favor of a new, painful agreement with Greece's creditors, compared to 33 percent who would vote no and 18.4 percent undecided.
Both nationwide polls were conducted from June 24-26. The Alco poll had a margin of error of 3.1 percent while Kapa Research's was 3.09 percent.
___
12:25 p.m.
A Greek finance official says the government expects the European Central Bank to continue approving emergency liquidity assistance that Greek banks can draw even after Tuesday, when Greece's international bailout officially expires.
The ECB was expected to meet Sunday to decide what action to take about Greece. The central is bank is under pressure to end that emergency assistance.
A decision by Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras to call for a national referendum on creditor demands in exchange for bailout loans has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil. In response, other nations in the 19-nation eurozone are refusing to extend Greece's bailout program beyond its Tuesday expiration date.
Alternate Greek Finance Minister Nadia Valavani told private Mega television on Sunday "we are expecting the funding of Greek banks to continue normally via the ELA after Tuesday."
Worried Greeks have formed lines at ATM machines all weekend and some machines were running out of cash Sunday morning.
Valavani said the country's banks could see "business as usual" next week if they receive the emergency support "so long as there is calm" and Greeks don't attempt to withdraw all their savings.
SEE FULL ARTICLE
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Disney World will ban selfie-sticks from its theme parks beginning Tuesday - @orlandosentinel</title>
        <Link>http://www.orlandosentinel.com/travel/attractions/theme-park-rangers-blog/os-disney-world-ban-selfie-sticks-from-parks-2015-post.html</Link>
        <Description>Disney World will ban selfie-sticks from its theme parks beginning Tuesday - @orlandosentinel</Description>
        <MainBody>1
Visitors will be told of the policy in locations such as the parking lots and at the resort's hotels. The prohibition will be added to the park rules post on Disney World's website.
The issue has been building at Disney. Previously, the sticks were prohibited from its rides, and "no selfie-sticks" signs were at select rides, such as Big Thunder Mountain Railroad at Magic Kingdom. Cast members have given verbal warnings to rule breakers.
Several incidents preceded the change, but officials have been discussing the rules for some time, Disney said. This week at Disney California Adventure park, a roller coaster was halted after a passenger pulled out a selfie-stick. The ride was closed for an hour.
Selfie-stick users put smartphones and cameras on the ends of poles to extend their reach, frequently capturing theme-park moments through self-portraits. The tools have been banned in public places  including some museums and stadiums  worldwide for obstructing views or causing safety issues.
Disney World already prohibits items such as skateboards, inline skates, wagon, folding chairs and glass containers, according to its official website, which also lists other items that we determine may be harmful or disruptive.
Universal Orlando has prohibited banned selfie-sticks and other loose items from certain thrill rides at Universal Studios and Islands of Adventure theme parks, but it has not instituted parkwide bans. SeaWorld Orlando also does not keep the sticks from entering the parks.

=======
        <title>European Central Bank says it is maintaining emergency support for Greek banks at current level, keeping lifeline open but with no further credit - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/d3885a1eb5b24c79964aabbbd4da8697/latest-greece-wants-ecb-keep-giving-emergency-help</Link>
        <Description>European Central Bank says it is maintaining emergency support for Greek banks at current level, keeping lifeline open but with no further credit - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Greek minister hints no payment Tuesday to IMF
Jun. 28, 2015 9:15 AM EDT
Share article
16 photos
Tourists walks past a graffiti made by street artist N_Grams  that  read \'\'NO\'\' in German but also \'\'YES, IN\'\' in Greek language in Athens, on Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece\'s parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras\' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations (all times local):
___
4:10 p.m.
Greece's finance minister is suggesting that his country might not pay the 1.6 billion euros ($1.8 billion) it owes to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis refused to reply to a direct question Sunday on the payment. Instead, he told BBC radio that the European Central Bank should pay the money to the IMF out of the profits it made on Greek bonds in 2014. Varoufakis calls that idea "a very sensible transfer."
Asked directly, for the second time, whether Greece will pay up Tuesday, Varoufakis replies: "We are owed money by one part of the troika and we owe money to another part of the troika? Why don't they sort themselves out and transfer money from one pocket ... to the other?"
___
3:35 p.m.
The European Central Bank has announced it is maintaining emergency credit to Greek banks at its current level.
The decision keeps a key financial lifeline open but does not provide further credit to Greece's banks, which are seeing deposits drain away as anxious Greeks withdraw savings.
The ECB said it was working closely with the Bank of Greece to maintain financial stability and added it could reconsider the decision on credit levels.
ECB head Mario Draghi said "we continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of Member States in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies."
___
3:20 p.m.
France's prime minister is urging Greece and other nations to do whatever they can to keep Greece in the 19-nation bloc that uses the euro currency.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said Sunday that "we don't know  none of us  the consequences of an exit from the eurozone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the eurozone." He was speaking on France's i-Tele TV.
Valls added that "means respecting Greece and democracy, but it's also about respecting European rules. So Greece needs to come back to the negotiating table."
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' call for a national referendum on creditors' demands has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil.
___
2:35 p.m.
Germany's Foreign Ministry is advising travelers to Greece to ensure they have enough cash on them before they depart.
An updated version of the ministry's travel advice issued Sunday noted that people seeking to withdraw cash in Greece could face "significant waits" and possible shortages at cash machines.
Worried Greeks were lining up at ATM machines on Sunday, the day after the Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called for a referendum on creditors' financial proposals in return for rescue loans and creditors refused to extend Greece's international bailout beyond Tuesday.
While some machines in Greece were running out of cash, others were being replenished. Another top Greek financial official urged Greeks on Sunday to remain calm and not withdraw all their savings.
___
1:45 p.m.
The European Central Bank faces a major decision.
It has been allowing Greek banks to draw emergency credit from Greece's central bank, a financial lifeline that has been keeping Greece's four major banks going during the country's tense bailout negotiations with creditors. The ECB has been slowly increasing the emergency credit to compensate for the increase in withdrawals from Greek banks.
But the ECB has said it can only continue such assistance if the banks are basically solvent. A failure by Greece's government to get more aid before its bailout ends Tuesday and a big payment to the International Monetary Fund is due could prompt the ECB to decide the Greek banks are not financially solid any more.
Capping the aid would quickly force Greek banks to limit withdrawals  but such controls could take Greece a step closer to leaving the 19-nation eurozone.
ECB President Mario Draghi has said it's up to elected officials to decide Greece's fate. Analysts say the central bank wants to give politicians every chance to negotiate a deal.
___
12:50 p.m.
Two opinion polls indicate most Greeks want to keep using the shared euro currency and would prefer a deal with Greece's European partners rather than a rupture.
The polls published Sunday were both conducted before Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras declared early Saturday that he was calling a referendum on financial proposals made by Greece's creditors in return for continuing to fund the country with bailout loans. Still, they provide an indication of public sentiment.
In the poll by Alco for the Proto Thema Sunday paper, 57 percent said they believed Greece should make a deal with its EU partners while 29 percent wanted a rupture. A separate poll by Kapa Research for the To Vima newspaper found 47.2 percent of respondents would vote in favor of a new, painful agreement with Greece's creditors, compared to 33 percent who would vote no and 18.4 percent undecided.
Both nationwide polls were conducted from June 24-26. The Alco poll had a margin of error of 3.1 percent while Kapa Research's was 3.09 percent.
___
12:25 p.m.
A Greek finance official says the government expects the European Central Bank to continue approving emergency liquidity assistance that Greek banks can draw even after Tuesday, when Greece's international bailout officially expires.
The ECB was expected to meet Sunday to decide what action to take about Greece. The central is bank is under pressure to end that emergency assistance.
A decision by Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras to call for a national referendum on creditor demands in exchange for bailout loans has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil. In response, other nations in the 19-nation eurozone are refusing to extend Greece's bailout program beyond its Tuesday expiration date.
Alternate Greek Finance Minister Nadia Valavani told private Mega television on Sunday "we are expecting the funding of Greek banks to continue normally via the ELA after Tuesday."
Worried Greeks have formed lines at ATM machines all weekend and some machines were running out of cash Sunday morning.
Valavani said the country's banks could see "business as usual" next week if they receive the emergency support "so long as there is calm" and Greeks don't attempt to withdraw all their savings.
SEE FULL ARTICLE
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Interior Ministry says gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 coastal hotels in Tunisia - @AP</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/interior-ministry-says-gunmen-kill-at-least-7-peop</Link>
        <Description>Interior Ministry says gunmen kill at least 7 people in attack on 2 coastal hotels in Tunisia - @AP</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Photo: Crews on the scene of a crash involving a bus carrying British schoolchildren, in West Flanders, Belgium; the driver died and 2 others were seriously injured - @Independent_ie</title>
        <Link>http://www.independent.ie/world-news/europe/driver-dead-as-bus-carrying-34-british-children-crashes-in-belgium-31335409.html</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Crews on the scene of a crash involving a bus carrying British schoolchildren, in West Flanders, Belgium; the driver died and 2 others were seriously injured - @Independent_ie</Description>
        <MainBody>Europe 
Irish driver dead as bus carrying 34 English children crashes in Belgium
A rescue services worker carries students' backpacks at the site where a bus carrying 34 British schoolchildren crashed off the E40 highway in Middelkerke, Belgium. AFP PHOTO / BELGA / NICOLAS MAETERLINCK.
Rescuers stand next to a British bus, transporting 34 children and which overturned and crashed on a motorway, near the city of Middelkerke Belgium REUTERS/Dominique Jauquet
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>4 killed, 8 critically injured in suicide attack at Kuwait mosque - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/4-killed-8-critically-injured-in-suicide-attack-a</Link>
        <Description>4 killed, 8 critically injured in suicide attack at Kuwait mosque - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Suspect in decapitation at French factory, Yassin Salhi, has confessed, say sources - @AFP</title>
        <Link>http://news.yahoo.com/confession-french-beheading-attack-gruesome-selfie-emerges-102118918.html</Link>
        <Description>Suspect in decapitation at French factory, Yassin Salhi, has confessed, say sources - @AFP</Description>
        <MainBody>Confession in French beheading attack as gruesome 'selfie' emerges
By Richard Carter, Stphane ORJOLLET 3 hours ago

.
.
Paris (AFP) - The man suspected of decapitating his boss in an attack on a gas factory in France has confessed to the grisly crime, sources close to the investigation said Sunday.
Yassin Salhi, 35, "has also given details about the circumstances" surrounding the killing, according to the sources, who said he would be transferred to Paris for further questioning later Sunday by anti-terrorist police.
Salhi's confession came after it emerged the married father-of-three sent a gruesome selfie photo of himself and the severed head to a WhatsApp number in Canada.
Investigators have warned however that it could be a relay number and the intended recipient could be anywhere in the world.
After several hours of silence, Salhi has begun to open up to investigators about the assault, which came six months after 17 were killed in Islamist attacks in Paris that began with the Charlie Hebdo massacre.
On Friday morning, Salhi rammed his van into the US-owned Air Products factory near France's second city of Lyon in what President Francois Hollande said was a "terrorist" attack designed to blow up the whole building.
He was overpowered by a firefighter as he was trying to prise open a bottle of acetone in an apparent suicidal bid to destroy the factory.
View gallery
French security stand next to the enclosed area where a decapitated body was found, near the Air Pro
Police then made the grisly discovery of the severed head of Salhi's boss, 54-year-old Herve Cornara, lashed to the gates of the factory near two flags on which were written the Muslim profession of faith.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls repeated that the world was engaged in a "war against terrorism".
"We cannot lose this war because it's fundamentally a war of civilisation. It's our society, our civilisation that we are defending," Valls told iTELE rolling news channel.
France is facing "a major terrorist threat" which needs to be fought "over the long-term", warned the prime minister.
It's not a question of whether there will be another attack, but "when" and "where", stressed Valls.
- Day of bloodshed -
View gallery
French special forces escort an unidentified woman as they leave the building housing the apartment 
Friday's attack came on a day of bloodshed on three continents that saw 38 people mown down on a Tunisian beach and 26 killed in a suicide attack in Kuwait.
The Islamic State extremist group has claimed responsibility for those two attacks but no group has said it carried out the French operation.
Sources close to the investigation said Salhi was radicalised more than a decade ago after contact with Muslim convert Frederic Jean Salvi -- known as "Ali" -- who is suspected of preparing attacks in Indonesia with Al-Qaeda militants.
An autopsy on the victim has proved inconclusive, with experts unable to determine whether he was killed before being beheaded or decapitated alive.
The French probe is naturally focusing on Syria, where hundreds of people from France have gone to wage jihad, officials said.
Anti-terrorist authorities have identified 473 people who have left France to fight in Iraq or Syria and Valls said 1,800 people in France were "linked" in some way to the jihadist cause.
French President Francois Hollande delivers a statement during an EU summit in Brussels on June 26, 
- 'Being here, together' -
Nearly six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre, the attack raised painful memories for France, which is still on high alert for potential repeats.
Around 200 people in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier -- where the attack took place -- staged a minute's silence in the victim's honour followed by a rousing and spontaneous rendition of the French national anthem.
One man, Philippe Ouastani, said he came to show solidarity with the victim. "It's unheard of to decapitate someone in the 21st century. What weapons do we have to combat that? Being here, together."
Another woman, wearing the Muslim headscarf, said she was "unable to speak" when she heard the news.
"These acts have got nothing to do with religion. The Prophet never said to kill innocent people," raged the woman, who asked to remain anonymous.
Trying to find the words to explain the killing to her four-year-old son, she said: "There are naughty people who have done bad things. The police will put them in prison to punish them for their silly, silly actions."
Like the Charlie Hebdo attackers and Islamist Mohamed Merah who gunned down soldiers and Jewish children in the southwest city of Toulouse in 2012, Salhi had been known to French security services for "radicalisation" but slipped through the net.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said Friday Salhi had been investigated for links to radical Salafists in Lyon, but was not known to have participated in terrorist activities and did not have a criminal record.
Europe has for months been bracing for so-called "lone wolf" attacks by supporters of Islamic State, which has urged its followers to strike wherever they can.
France, which has the highest Muslim population in Europe, last week passed a controversial new spying law granting sweeping powers to snoop on citizens.
Company Legal &amp; Law Matters
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Swiss Court rejects bid by arrested FIFA official to be released on bail - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/swiss-court-rejects-bid-by-arrested-fifa-official</Link>
        <Description>Swiss Court rejects bid by arrested FIFA official to be released on bail - @Reuters</Description>
=======
        <title>Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis says creditors did not meet his country's requests 'even quarter way' - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/28/greek-finance-minister-yanis-varoufakis-says-credi</Link>
        <Description>Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis says creditors did not meet his country's requests 'even quarter way' - @Reuters</Description>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Photo: Line of mourners waiting for the funeral of Rev. Clementa Pickney in Charleston, S.C. - @trymainelee</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/trymainelee/status/614390128992223232</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Line of mourners waiting for the funeral of Rev. Clementa Pickney in Charleston, S.C. - @trymainelee</Description>
=======
        <title>Photo: The Dalai Lama speaks to festival goers at the Glastonbury Festival in Somerset, England - @DJPuddles</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/DJPuddles/status/615124926421442565</Link>
        <Description>Photo: The Dalai Lama speaks to festival goers at the Glastonbury Festival in Somerset, England - @DJPuddles</Description>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Islamic State claims responsibility for mosque attack in Kuwait, according to statement posted on social media - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/islamic-state-claims-responsibility-for-mosque-att</Link>
        <Description>Islamic State claims responsibility for mosque attack in Kuwait, according to statement posted on social media - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Dalai Lama makes rare comment on escalating violence in Syria and Iraq during speech at Glastonbury festival, says, 'The worst thing [about] the conflict is the killing of others in the name of faith. Unthinkable.' - guardiannews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/28/dalai-lama-makes-rare-comment-on-escalating-violen</Link>
        <Description>Dalai Lama makes rare comment on escalating violence in Syria and Iraq during speech at Glastonbury festival, says, 'The worst thing [about] the conflict is the killing of others in the name of faith. Unthinkable.' - guardiannews</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28, 2015, 12:06 PM GMT
(
12:06
)
Dalai Lama makes rare comment on escalating violence in Syria and Iraq during speech at Glastonbury festival, says, 'The worst thing [about] the conflict is the killing of others in the name of faith. Unthinkable.' - guardiannews
End of alert
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Reported attack against tourist hotel in Tunisian town of Sousse, local radio and security sources say - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/reported-attack-against-tourist-hotel-in-tunisian</Link>
        <Description>Reported attack against tourist hotel in Tunisian town of Sousse, local radio and security sources say - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Greece to consider closing banks on Monday, says finance minister, as sources say ECB to end or cap emergency lending - @BBCBreaking</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-33303105</Link>
        <Description>Greece to consider closing banks on Monday, says finance minister, as sources say ECB to end or cap emergency lending - @BBCBreaking</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece debt crisis: ECB 'to end' bank emergency lending
28 June 2015
From the section Europe
An Athens ATM: The ECB has been sending cash so that Greek banks can continue to lend
The European Central Bank is expected to end emergency lending to Greece's banks on Sunday, the BBC understands.
Well-placed sources told BBC economics editor Robert Peston a decision to end the Emergency Liquidity Assistance (ELA) would be made by the ECB's governing council later on Sunday.
Greek banks depend on ELA funds daily.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis said his government would consider overnight what measures to take "to minimise the burden on our people".
Cutting the ECB lifeline could push Greece out of the euro.
Such an ECB cut would mean "Europe has failed", Mr Varoufakis told the BBC's World this Weekend.
It would mean Europe had "failed in its duty to preserve in parallel a democratic process and a monetary union", he said. "It is a dark hour for Europe."
The lenders have "not met Greece even a quarter of the way", he complained.
The government would consider "what can be done to minimise the burden on our people from Europe's refusal to grant us democratic rights".
A BBC reporter in Athens says long queues are forming at bank ATMs.
The EU-IMF bailout for heavily indebted Greece expires on Tuesday and talks have broken down.
Greek banks would find themselves in serious straits as soon as Monday if the ECB cut the ELA funding, Robert Peston says.
Greece will probably have to announce a bank holiday on Monday, pending the introduction of capital controls, he says.
Historic decision
It is one of the most momentous decisions the ECB has ever faced, since the euro was launched on 1 January 1999.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said the ECB "is independent but... I don't think it can cut off rations [for the Greeks]". He said "it's the Greek nation that is suffering".
Capital controls are restrictions on how much customers can withdraw from banks. Until now, the Greek government has signalled that it does not want to impose such controls.
In recent weeks, Greeks have withdrawn billions of euros from banks.
Grexit risk looms
A Greek withdrawal from the euro - known as "Grexit" - is not inevitable, says Robert Peston, as the eurozone did resolve Cyprus's banking crisis in 2013 and the country stayed in the euro.
Capital controls were imposed on Cypriot banks, and remained in place for a long time - the last restrictions were only lifted in April this year.
Greece's situation is more difficult, our editor reports. Capital controls are seen as an important step towards leaving the euro, because the single currency's rules require free movement of capital.
But Greece could remain in if its government and the bailout providers - the EU and IMF - can restart constructive negotiations, he reports.
Greek PM Alexis Tsipras says voters must decide whether the bailout is acceptable
A country on the brink - chief correspondent Gavin Hewitt writes:
It is the most important decision in the ECB's history.
A withdrawal of funding could plunge Greece into chaos and yet the ECB cannot break its own rules by funding a banking system where the country is heading for a default.
Alexis Tsipras has gambled both with his future and that of his country. He committed Greece to a vote, but only after the current bailout has expired, so leaving Greece vulnerable and exposed.
What are the Greek papers saying?
On Saturday eurozone finance ministers - the Eurogroup - refused to extend Greece's desperately-needed bailout beyond Tuesday.
The ministers blamed Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras's surprise call for a referendum on 5 July on the bailout conditions.
The final 7.2bn (5bn; $8bn) of Greece's second bailout has been frozen since last summer, as lenders demanded more Greek progress on deep economic reform.
Without more lending to Greece the country will default on a 1.6bn repayment due to the IMF on Tuesday.
Economic pain
Under the rules governing the euro, the ECB's emergency lifeline could not be continued if the ECB considered Greek banks to be insolvent.
Robert Peston says that with Greece no longer participating in a formal rescue programme, the solvency of the Greek state would be in doubt, as it is so intimately linked to the banks' solvency.
Mr Tsipras's leftist Syriza government rejects the bailout terms, after five years of lender-imposed austerity that has increased Greek unemployment and cut pensions and welfare benefits.
Greece has endured five years of recession, and total output (GDP) has shrunk by 25%.
Greek referendum preparations are under way at the interior ministry
Greek repayments due
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>Photo: Tree limbs block a street in Salem, Mass., after heavy rain and strong winds overnight, with more rain in the forecast for the rest of Sunday - @sjforman138</title>
        <Link>https://twitter.com/sjforman138/status/615115968285667329</Link>
        <Description>Photo: Tree limbs block a street in Salem, Mass., after heavy rain and strong winds overnight, with more rain in the forecast for the rest of Sunday - @sjforman138</Description>
        <MainBody>Already using Twitter via text message?
To bring you Twitter, we and our partners use cookies on our and other websites. Cookies help personalize Twitter content, tailor Twitter Ads, measure their performance, and provide you with a better, faster, safer Twitter experience. By using our services, you agree to our Cookie Use .
Close
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Interior ministry: Suspected accomplices to French factory attack being held by police - livestream</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/interior-ministry-suspected-accomplices-to-french</Link>
        <Description>Interior ministry: Suspected accomplices to French factory attack being held by police - livestream</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Utility DTE Energy says 108,000 customers remain without power in southeast Michigan, majority in Wayne County, after harsh weather Saturday - @NBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/28/utility-dte-energy-says-108000-customers-remain-w</Link>
        <Description>Utility DTE Energy says 108,000 customers remain without power in southeast Michigan, majority in Wayne County, after harsh weather Saturday - @NBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28, 2015, 11:54 AM GMT
(
11:54
)
Utility DTE Energy says 108,000 customers remain without power in southeast Michigan, majority in Wayne County, after harsh weather Saturday - @NBCNews
End of alert
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>Mosque explosion in Kuwait caused by suicide bomber, several people wounded or killed, witness says - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/26/mosque-explosion-in-kuwait-caused-by-suicide-bombe</Link>
        <Description>Mosque explosion in Kuwait caused by suicide bomber, several people wounded or killed, witness says - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>THE FASTEST EMAIL ALERTS IN NEWS
Major story alerts in your inbox (averages 1 per day)
Sign up successful. You will need to confirm your email address to receive alerts.
=======
        <title>Victim killed in Belgium bus crash identified as driver from Northern Ireland's Richmond Coaches - @BBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-33303121?ns_mchannel=social&amp;ns_campaign=bbc_breaking&amp;ns_source=twitter&amp;ns_linkname=news_central</Link>
        <Description>Victim killed in Belgium bus crash identified as driver from Northern Ireland's Richmond Coaches - @BBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>NI driver killed in Belgium school trip bus crash
28 June 2015
From the section Northern Ireland
A bus driver from Northern Ireland has been killed in a coach crash in Belgium.
He was on a bus carrying 34 school children from an Essex school in the UK.
Another driver, also from Northern Ireland, has been seriously injured.
A pupil from Brentwood School who was on the bus suffered a head injury and is in intensive care. It is understood that three pupils and two teachers are in hospital.
The bus company, Richmond Coaches, is from Lisburn, County Antrim.
The bus overturned on the A18 (E40) at Middelkerke, West Flanders at 09:45 local time (08:45 BST).
Eyewitnesses said it crashed into a motorway bridge pillar.
West Flanders traffic police confirmed that one person is dead and one is injured.
A rescue worker carries students' backpacks from the bus
Thirty-one children and three teachers walked away from the crash.
The children from Brentwood School were all aged from 11 to 13 years old.
Ian Davies, the school's head teacher said: "There are three children in hospital. We don't know the full extent of their injuries.
"I know that one boy has a head injury which is being monitored very carefully.
"I have spoken to the lead teacher on the trip. He is in hospital, I think he broke his collar bone, but seemed in as good a shape as could be expected."
A spokesman from Richmond Coaches of Ballinderry Road, Lisburn, confirmed that one of its vehicles had been involved in the crash.
He said what had happened was "a tragedy" and the company was co-operating with the authorities.
He said the company's thoughts were with everyone involved and they were cooperating fully with the authorities.
Janna Rommel-Opstaele, the mayor of the nearby coastal town of Middelkerke, told press agency Reuters that the bus driver had been killed and another seriously injured.
"Some of the children with light injuries have been taken to hospital and local medical centres," she said.
A spokesman for the Foreign and Commonwealth Office said they were aware of the crash and were working with  the Belgian authorities to establish details.
Have you been affected by this incident? You can email haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk with your experiences.
If you are willing to speak further to a BBC journalist, please include a contact phone number.
Email your pictures to yourpics@bbc.co.uk , upload them here , tweet them to @BBC_HaveYourSay or text 61124. If you are outside the UK, send them to the international number +44 7624 800 100.
Or WhatsApp us on +44 7525 900971
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>President Franois Hollande confirms decapitated body had Arabic writing on it - @BBCNews</title>
        <Link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/world-europe-33287095</Link>
        <Description>President Franois Hollande confirms decapitated body had Arabic writing on it - @BBCNews</Description>
        <MainBody>LiveFrance attack: Live Updates
Summary
One man has been killed and two others injured in a suspected Islamist attack near the city of Lyon
Officials say one man has been arrested
French President Francois Hollande says it was a "terrorist attack"
The attack began with several explosions at a factory
President Hollande is leaving an EU summit in Brussels early
This page automatically updates
=======
        <title>Greek Financial Stability Council to convene at 1600 local time (9 am ET) to discuss banking situation, says finance ministry - @Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://www.breakingnews.com/item/2015/06/28/statement-greek-financial-stability-council-to-co</Link>
        <Description>Greek Financial Stability Council to convene at 1600 local time (9 am ET) to discuss banking situation, says finance ministry - @Reuters</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28, 2015, 11:41 AM GMT
(
11:41
)
Greek Financial Stability Council to convene at 1600 local time (9 am ET) to discuss banking situation, says finance ministry - @Reuters
End of alert
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
