<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="canada">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Why you really shouldn’t touch a Queen’s Guard on your summer vacation: He’ll pull a gun on you</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/really+shouldn+touch+Queen+Guard+your+summer+vacation+pull/11169314/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The red-coated guards outside of Royal palaces are fixtures in slapstick comedy about tourists to the U.K. but even they have a line &amp;#8212; and a very pointy rifle-style bayonet</Description>
        <MainBody>
gun-pull
The Queens Guard outside of Royal palaces in the United Kingdom are famous for their stoicism in the face of tourists taunts, but even they have their limits.
One visitor to Windsor Castle put one hand over that line  and saw the other end of a rifle in return.
The tourist can be seen in a YouTube video hamming it up alongside the red-coated guard in his tall black hat as he marches along the palace. Its a typical tourist video of some idiot trying to make the guards break into a smile or mess up their routine. But then the man touches the guards soldier and he bellows, Get back from the Queens Guard! and he levels the rifle-style bayonet in the visitors face.
The tourist can be seen scampering away as his friends burst out in laughter.
The guard, upper lip stiff as ever, keeps calm and carries on his march.
The ministry of defence backed the guard up, saying members of the public should show respect, the Daily Mail reports.
The Queens Guard were installed after the Restoration and Charles II ascent to the throne in 1660.
Though their presence is a historic symbol, they do have real powers. They can detain troublesome tourists, and raising their gun is said to be a final warning.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Quasi Modo named world's ugliest dog</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Quasi+Modo+named+world+ugliest/11173183/story.html</Link>
        <Description>PETALUMA, Calif. &amp;#8212; A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year&amp;#8217;s World&amp;#8217;s Ugliest Dog contest. The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and her owner took the $1,500 prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that applauds imperfection, organizers said. [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>Quasi Modo named world's ugliest dog

By The Associated Press, Ottawa Citizen June 27, 2015



Quasi Modo wins top honors in the World's Ugliest Dog Contest at the Sonoma-Marin Fair on Friday, June 26, 2015, in Petaluma, Calif. Quasi Modo's owners, who travelled from Florida to compete, will receive $1500.
Photograph by: Noah Berger                , Ottawa Citizen
PETALUMA, Calif.  A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this years Worlds Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and her owner took the $1,500 prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that applauds imperfection, organizers said.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Fla., according to her biography posted on the contests website.
My appearance can be a little unsettling to some (I have had grown men jump on top of their cars to get away from me because they thought I was a hyena or Tasmanian devil) but once they get to know me I win them over with my bubbly personality, her biography said.
Sweepee Rambo, a Chinese Crested, was recognized with an award at the Worlds Ugliest Dog Competition in Petaluma, Calif.
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
An eight-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the spirit award, honouring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles and/or are providing service to the community. Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest is in its 27th year.The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Final legal and diplomatic hurdles being cleared for Ukraine mission, Jason Kenney says</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/national/Final+legal+diplomatic+hurdles+being+cleared+Ukraine/11173044/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Legal and diplomatic obstacles to deploying Canadian military trainers in Ukraine have largely been cleared away, Defence Minister Jason Kenney says</Description>
        <MainBody>Final legal and diplomatic hurdles being cleared for Ukraine mission, Jason Kenney says

By The Canadian Press June 27, 2015



Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko (L) shaking hands with Canadadian Minister of National Defence and Minister for Multiculturalism Jason Kenney as he welcomes him prior to talks in Kiev on June 26, 2015.
KYIV, Ukraine  Legal and diplomatic obstacles to deploying Canadian military trainers in Ukraine have largely been cleared away, Defence Minister Jason Kenney says.
He was scheduled to tour the multi-national centre at Yavoriv, near the Polish border, on Saturday where the roughly 200 combat instructors will set up shop in the coming weeks.
Both the U.S. and Britain have been at the training grounds since the spring, running hundreds of Ukrainian national guardsmen through remedial, basic military courses.
Canadas contribution was announced with much political fanfare in mid-April, but it could be August before the full contingent is on the ground.
We do not yet have a technical assistance agreement with Ukraine, he said in an interview with The Canadian Press. We need a legal framework before we can fully deploy our trainers here. Thats one of the reasons for my visit. Its to resolve some of the outstanding, technical legal issues.
Kenney did not say what the hang-ups might be, but pointed out the Americans had worked on their technical agreement with Kyiv over year before Canada and that they were in a better position to move ahead quickly.
Aside from negotiating the legal framework with the Ukrainian government, Kenney says the Pentagon only recently gave Canada the green light to share the training base, which was originally leased to NATO at a time when the former Soviet republic was on its way to joining the alliance.
We realized we could save a lot of money if co-located with the Americans at the same training base and shared logistics and there would be an economy of scale there, and for internal reasons they couldnt actually give the green light until quite recently, he said.
There was a similar gap between the announcement and the deployment of troops and aircraft last fall to do battle with the Islamic State. Canadian officials had to scramble to exchange diplomatic notes with Iraq in order to define legal protections for troops and pilots who would called upon to use deadly force.
The Harper government elected to not go all of the way with Baghdad and create a status of forces agreement, something that concerned opposition parties.
There are, at the moment, approximately 40 Canadians on the ground in Ukraine, conducting a reconnaissance and preparing for the larger contingent.
The bulk of that force, which will be in Yavoriv, will carry out combat arms training, but a handful will also be sprinkled at other centres, notably the Ukrainian Ministry of Defence de-mining centre in Kamyanets-Podilsky in the countrys extreme southwest.
There will also be medical trainers, military police instructors, flight safety teachers and others showing Ukrainians how to set up an effective military supply chain.
But it is the hard-won Afghan war skills of detecting, avoiding and dismantling roadside bombs that will be of exceptional value, Ukrainian military officials have said privately.
On Thursday, NATO announced it is establishing a new trust fund for Ukraine that will aim at de-mining, and also on countering improvised explosive devices.
Seven Ukrainian soldiers died earlier this month when their truck hit a mine not far from Krasnogorivka, west of Donetsk. A passenger bus blew up after striking a mine last spring, killing three people in the same region.
The United Nations Childrens Fund (UNICEF) has warned that unexploded mines and ammunition pose a special threat to children in eastern Ukraine.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>‘I will conquer the world’ for you: How a ‘swashbuckling’ young Winston Churchill impressed women at parties</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/will+conquer+world+swashbuckling+young+Winston+Churchill/11170168/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Winston was so determined the wedding night would go well he sought advice from an expert: his mother. She reputedly had had 200 lovers</Description>
        <MainBody>

As a young man, Churchill had a colourful love life which saw him rate women at parties, offer to 'conquer the world' for them and ask his mother for advice about his wedding night, it has been claimed.
With a happy 57-year marriage and a lifetime devotion to politics, Sir Winston Churchill is not often considered as anything approaching a Lothario figure.
But as a young man, he had a colourful love life which saw him rate women at parties, offer to conquer the world for them and ask his mother for advice about his wedding night, it has been claimed.
According to one historian, a youthful Sir Winston attacked his romantic life with gusto in the same way he tackled any other problem. He tried to present himself as a swashbuckling suitor, startled female staff at Chartwell by running between rooms in the nude, and even told his mother-in-law that he found sex a delightful occupation.
The personal stories, unearthed by historian Sonia Purnell as she researched her book about Clementine Churchill, Sir Winstons wife, reveal a rather different man to the statesman known and loved by Britain.
Speaking at the Chalke Valley History Festival, Purnell argued it was time the women in his life had a fair crack of the whip. Sir Winstons eventual success with Clementine, she said, led to his popularity as a politician, thanks to a loving and ultimately world-saving marriage. Her research, she claimed, put paid to scurrilous rumours about Sir Winston being gay, arguing that his 57-year-long marriage was the real deal. Her book, First Lady: the Life and Wars of Clementine Churchill, has made use of diaries, letters and personal accounts from surviving staff members.
She said Sir Winston was a rarity among alpha males because he was not a sexual predator. He wasnt a Bill Clinton with interns, he wasnt a JFK with actresses. He wasnt even a John Major with a certain Tory MP, she said.
Once he determined he ought to get married, she said: He decided he would present himself as a swashbuckling hero who would rescue any damsels.
She added: So he and Eddie Marsh  would go to balls, and they would stand there and look at all the attractive single women and give them a rank.
Either they had a face that could launch a thousand ships, who were therefore eligible, merely 200, who were very borderline, or a small gun boat at most, meaning they were out of the question, clearly. When Sir Winston came across Pamela Plowden, she added, he told her: Marry me, and I will conquer the world and lay it at your feet.
Winston was so determined the wedding night would go well he sought advice from an expert: his mother
He went on to have liaisons with shipping heiress Muriel Wilson, actress Ethel Barrymore and a music hall girl who found Winston had done nothing but talk into the small hours on the subject of himself.
Then he met Clementine. Winston was so determined the wedding night would go well he sought advice from an expert: his mother, said Purnell.
She reputedly had had 200 lovers. She obviously gave very good advice and it all went terribly well, so he wrote to her thanking her for the advice and telling her we have loved and loitered.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>Richard Matt, one of the New York prison escapees, shot dead by border patrol agent</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Richard+Matt+York+prison+escapees+shot+dead+border+patrol/11170445/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Authorities tracked down and killed&amp;#160;Richard&amp;#160;Matt&amp;#160;after a person towing a camper reported that there was a bullet hole through the back of it, Gov. Andrew Cuomo said</Description>
        <MainBody>Richard Matt, one of the New York prison escapees, shot dead by border patrol agent

By The Associated Press June 26, 2015



One of two convicted murderers who staged a brazen escape from an upstate maximum-security prison three weeks ago was shot and killed by a border patrol agent in a wooded area 30 miles from the prison on Friday, and the other was on the run, authorities said.
Authorities tracked down and killedRichardMattafter a person towing a camper reported that there was a bullet hole through the back of it, Gov. Andrew Cuomo and state police said. David Sweat hasnt been spotted, Cuomo said.
The shooting of the camper led officers to a cabin in Malone, where they discovered the smell of gunpowder, said Joseph DAmico, superintendent of the New York State Police. There were indications someone had recently been there and fled out the back door, he said.
While searching the property, officers heard coughs and detected movement, and tactical teams came uponMattin the woods.
They verbally challenged him, told him to put up his hands. And at that time, he was shot when he didnt comply, DAmico said.
A 20-gauge shotgun was found onMatt, who didnt fire the weapon, DAmico said.Mattwas shot by a border patrol agent from Vermont, U.S. Sen. Charles Schumer said.
It was unclear ifMattand Sweat were together at the time of the shooting, authorities said. The pair escaped from the Clinton Correctional Facility together early June 6. Cuomo called them dangerous, dangerous men.
Police blocked off roads in the area as officers hunted for Sweat on Friday. The search area for him was centred on Titusville Mountain State Forest in Malone and spanned 22 square miles, down from 75 square miles earlier this week, authorities said.
Authorities have followed up on more than 2,400 leads, Cuomo said.
Mitch Johnson said one of his best friends checked on his hunting cabin in Malone on Friday afternoon and noticed a liquor bottle that hadnt been there the day before. Johnson said his friend, correction officer Bob Willett, told him he immediately alerted police, about an hour beforeMattwas fatally shot.
Authorities sent a team to the camp area, and Willett and police later heard a gunshot in the woods, Johnson said.
Officers then flooded the woods, and then Willett heard more shots, Johnson said.
He heard: Pop pop pop pop pop pop pop, Johnson said.
State police Maj. Charles Guess said earlier Friday that the search area had shifted slightly northwest to Malone after investigators found evidence left behind by the escapees. Items were found Thursday at a cabin and Friday morning in a field, both in Malone, he said.
DAmico cited numerous instances of break-ins and evidence left behind by the inmates in the area in the last week. On Wednesday, a screen was discovered cut out of a cabin and a window was broken into. On Friday morning, search teams found a camp, where candy wrappers and other items were seized, and saw evidence that someone had laid down there.
Mattand Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a 2-foot-thick brick wall, squirmed through pipes and emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
Sweat, 35, was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriffs deputy in Broome County in 2002.Matt, 49, was serving 25 years to life for the killing and dismembering of his former boss. They were added to the U.S. Marshals Services 15 Most Wanted fugitives list two weeks after getting away.
A pair of prison workers has been charged in connection with the inmates escape.
Prosecutors said Joyce Mitchell, a prison tailoring shop instructor who got close to the men while working with them, had agreed to be their getaway driver but backed out because she felt guilty for participating. Authorities also said Mitchell had discussed killing her husband, Lyle Mitchell, as part of the plot.
Joyce Mitchell pleaded not guilty June 15 to charges including felony promoting prison contraband, which authorities said included hacksaw blades and chisels.
Authorities said the men had filled their beds in their adjacent cells with clothes to make it appear they were sleeping when guards made overnight rounds. On a cut steam pipe, the prisoners left a taunting note containing a crude caricature of an Asian face and the words Have a nice day.
Clinton County District Attorney Andrew Wylie said the inmates apparently used tools stored by prison contractors, taking care to return them to their toolboxes after each nights work.
On June 24, authorities charged Clinton correction officer Gene Palmer with promoting prison contraband, tampering with physical evidence and official misconduct. Officials said he gave the two prisoners frozen hamburger meat Joyce Mitchell had used to hide the tools she smuggled to Sweat andMatt. Palmers attorney said he had no knowledge that the meat contained hacksaw blades, a bit and a screwdriver.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Three attacks, three countries: Suspected Islamic terrorists kill more than 80 people</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Three+attacks+three+countries+Suspected+Islamic+terrorists/11171061/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Warning &amp;#8212; graphic images: Security forces were on maximum alert Friday after suspected Islamic terrorists appeared to mount simultaneous attacks on three continents</Description>
        <MainBody>Three attacks, three countries: Suspected Islamic terrorists kill more than 80 people

By Tristin Hopper June 26, 2015


Warning: Graphic images
From the English Channel to the Persian Gulf, security forces were on maximum alert Friday after suspected Islamic terrorists appeared to mount simultaneous attacks on three continents, murdering more than 80 people in Tunisia, France and Kuwait.
A decapitated head was found mounted on the fence outside a chemical factory near Lyon, France, alongside a black flag carrying Arabic inscriptions.
In Kuwait City, a suicide bomb exploded in a mosque packed with Shiite worshippers, killing at least 27.
But the deadliest attack came in Tunisia, where a gunman dressed as a tourist pulled a Kalashnikov rifle from an umbrella and opened fire on beachgoers at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse. At least 39 people died, most of them tourists.
We were in the pool when we heard automatic gunfire. People ran past saying there was an armed man on the beach, read a Twitter post by John Yeoman, a British guest at the hotel who spent the attack barricaded in his room.
The hotel caters largely to foreign tourists. Among the dead were people from Ireland, Belgium, Germany and the U.K.
He was choosing who to shoot, one witness told Tunisian radio. Some people, he was saying to them, You go away. He was choosing tourists, British, French.
Wives were killed in front of husbands, sunbathers were cut down as they sprinted to safety, and a 16-year-old British boy reportedly saw his parents and a grandparent murdered.
Matthew James, a vacationer from Wales, suffered multiple bullet wounds after using himself as a human shield to protect his fiance.
He was covered in blood from the shots but he just told me to run away, she told the British press.
On social media, Britons begged for information about missing relatives.
Havent spoke to my Dad since the attack,please, please, please retweet as he is missing along with his partner, read one widely circulated message from a man in the East Midlands.
This is worse than terrible, said Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi.
Tunisia cannot stand up to the Islamist threat alone, he said, but we are determined to take the most painful measures to deal with an even more painful scourge.
Although the three attacks have not been definitively linked, they appear to fulfill a promise by propagandists from the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant that the Muslim fasting month of Ramadan would bring a calamity to the worlds non-Muslims.
Although the victims in Kuwait City were Muslim, the jihadists consider them heretics because they are Shiites. In a statement, ISIL said the bomb had targeted a temple of the apostates.
Worshippers at the Imam Sadiq Mosque were standing shoulder to shoulder in group prayer when they were interrupted by a man repeatedly screaming Allahu Akbar (God is great). A powerful explosion then ripped through the rear of the building.
We couldnt see anything, so we went straight to the wounded and tried to carry them out. We left the dead, said Hassan al-Haddad, 21, who was among the first rescuers to arrive.
The mosque bombing was the third attack in five weeks to be claimed by a purported ISIL affiliate, the Najd Province, named for the central region of Saudi Arabia where the ultra-conservative Sunni ideology of Wahhabism originated.
Kuwaiti Prime Minister Sheikh Jaber al-Mubarak al-Sabah declared the attack had been aimed at the countrys national unity, but the Arab nation of 3.4 million is much stronger than anything terrorists could deliver.
This is a wakeup call to fight harder, he said.
This month, the U.S.-based Institute for the Study of War forecast Ramadan was likely to be violent as ISIL held to a jihadist tradition of increasing attacks during the holy month.
Previously, Ramadan had heralded increased insurgent violence from al-Qaida in Iraq, ISILs predecessor.
The first message to take from these attacks is that (ISIL) is steadily and successfully spreading beyond its territorial heartland in Syria and Iraq, read a Friday assessment by Shashank Joshi, a Middle East expert with the Royal United Services Institute in London.
Fridays attacks were notable in that they targeted Kuwait and Tunisia, two countries often seen as bastions of calm in the middle of war-torn regions.
Kuwait has consistently ranked as one of the worlds most peaceful Arab countries, in sharp contrast to its next-door neighbour, Iraq.
Tunisia, similarly, is one of the most secular countries in North Africa, and its switch to democracy in 2011 has been one of the few success stories of the Arab Spring.
I believe that it is not accidental that Tunisia is among the countries attacked by terrorists, Donald Tusk, head of the European Commission, said in Brussels.
However, the country also has no shortage of armed jihadists carrying its passports. According to an estimate this month, Tunisia has contributed more recruits to ISIL than any other country outside Iraq and Syria.
Fridays massacre was the worst terrorist attack in Tunisias history, although it comes only months after a similar assault on the Bardo National Museum in Tunis, where two gunmen killed 22 mostly-foreign visitors.
Both attacks, notably, targeted the countrys critical tourist sector. Tunisia is only a two-hour flight from most major European cities, and relies on tourism for 400,000 jobs and seven per cent of its gross domestic product.
By Friday afternoon, German tour operators were allowing customers to cancel Tunisian bookings. In spite of the violence, however, planeloads of European vacationers continued to touch down at Tunisian airports.
In Dublin, the Irish travel agent Sunway offered 170 Tunisia-bound vacationers who were at the airport the chance to cancel. Only 59 took up the offer, according to Irish public radio.
The perpetrator in the French attack is believed to be Yassin Salhi, a 35-year-old delivery man, who was investigated for religious extremism in 2006, but who has evaded the notice of authorities since 2008.
We have a normal family life. He goes to work and comes home. He doesnt pick up the phone when I call, it goes to the answer machine, Salhis wife told Europe 1 radio. She was arrested soon after the interview.
The victim, whose severed head was found outside a factory owned by Air Products, has been identified as Salhis boss at a local delivery firm.
The gas factory was a customer of the delivery company, which is how investigators suspect Salhi was able to gain entry.
He is also believed to have started a series of small fires at the facility by setting off explosions using gas canisters. He was arrested by a firefighter and remains in custody.
This was a terrorist attack, given that a corpse was found decapitated and with inscriptions, said French President Franois Hollande.
Islamist violence also struck Syria and Somalia Friday.
Dozens of soldiers were reportedly killed in Somalia after a remote African Union base was stormed by fighters with Al-Shabaab, a jihadist group with links to al-Qaida.
A suicide bomber blew open the bases front gates, after which Al-Shabaab fighters armed with assault rifles and rocket-propelled grenades surged in. Agence France-Presse reported.
In northeast Syria, an ISIL suicide bomber killed at least 20 troops loyal to Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported.
National Post, with files from The Telegraph and The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Matthew Fisher: Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras calls referendum on debt deal in latest twist in Greek tragedy</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Matthew+Fisher+Prime+Minister+Alexis+Tsipras+calls+referendum/11170924/story.html</Link>
        <Description>It is rather late to be asking this question, with Greece hours away from being officially bankrupt, but what were the eurozone's founding fathers thinking?</Description>
        <MainBody>

Matthew Fisher: Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras calls referendum on debt deal in latest twist in Greek tragedy

By Matthew Fisher June 26, 2015



Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras arrives to speak to journalists after an EU summit at the EU headquarters in Brussels on June 26, 2015.
Analysis
BRUSSELS  It is rather late to be asking this question, with Greece hours away from being officially bankrupt, but what were the eurozones founding fathers thinking when they included Greece, Spain, Italy and Portugal in their common currency project?
Did any of these fantasists truly believe that by simply waving a wand it was possible to make these struggling southern countries as productive and prosperous as those of the eurozones thriving northern economies or that it was possible to put all Europeans on a common economic footing? If so, the idea has failed spectacularly.
Yet even at this late hour, with Greece accumulating billions of dollars in fresh debt every month, the European Union is still trying to figure out whether there are any stopgap measures that might prevent Greece from defaulting and keep it in the eurozone.
It is easy to liken what is happening to a Greek tragedy or even a farce.
These proposals, which clearly violate the European rules and the basic rights to work, equality and dignity show that the purpose of some of the partners and institutions was not a viable agreement for all parties, but possibly the humiliation of an entire people
Friday night, the drama took another turn when Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras announced he was calling a referendum for July 5, in which the EUs latest proposals will be put to the people, perhaps a fitting forum for a such a decision in the birthplace of democracy.
In a televised address, Tsipras made no secret of what he thought of the creditors latest offer.
These proposals, which clearly violate the European rules and the basic rights to work, equality and dignity show that the purpose of some of the partners and institutions was not a viable agreement for all parties, but possibly the humiliation of an entire people, he said, according to reports.
He said he would seek an extension of the fast approaching Tuesday expiration of Greeces current bailout program to hold the referendum.
Everyone denies an ultimatum had been issued, but that seems to be a matter of semantics. German Chancellor Angela Merkel, who holds the keys to Europes vault, had declared she would not be blackmailed into providing a 1.54 billion euro loan by Tuesday so Greece does not default on a much bigger loan.
If it was only a matter 1.5 billion euros, terms could probably be quickly worked out. But Greece must repay another 2.5 billion euros by mid-July. Then, it still owes 245 billion euros to the EU, the ECB, the IMF and other international creditors and has no obvious way of ever repaying much, if any, of the principal.
Greek and EU negotiations are so tired of each other  and remain so far apart on the key issues of cutting pensions and raising taxes on consumers, rather than on businesses  it is gets harder every day to see any way to avoid Grexit, as Athens ejection from the eurozone has been dubbed.
Earlier Friday, Tsipras gamely met Merkel on the sidelines of an EU summit that was supposed to be about the continents refugee crisis. Their tte--tte encouraged a blitz of reports the differences between the EU and Greece on how to satisfy the countrys many creditors might somehow be papered over. But as happened when the same kind of somewhat optimistic bulletins surfaced last weekend, hopes sputtered later in the day when Tsipras rejected a proposal that would have given negotiators another five months to try to come up with a lasting solution.
Visiting Athens and Brussels this week has been like travelling between two solitudes. The philosophical differences over how to collect and spend money and repay creditors are so profound the two sides talk past each other, rather than confront their differences head-on.
Seething with bitterness, vexed Greeks claim that as democrats they cannot allow outsiders to dictate financial term. What they mean is that they elected Tsipras, who started his political life as a communist and remains a deeply committed socialist, because he promised to ease austerity and to protect their pensions, so he must be allowed to soften the terms of any deal with the EU. Of course to do that Tsipras needs a lot more EU money.
Fearing the worst, Greeks have removed billions of euros from their already teetering banks. The guessing is almost all of that money was sent out of the country. Almost certainly none of it will be coming back any time soon.
With increasing anger the northern Europeans, led by Germany, have rejected the idea they somehow owe Greeks a decent living. With increasing vigour, they are questioning the wisdom of throwing more money at what has become a black hole and have wondered out loud whether it might be for the best for Greece to sort out the mess itself.
To try to scare the Greeks into acceding to its terms, the EU has made no secret of what the Financial Times has called Plan B. Its starting point is that default equals Grexit. While Athens might receive some emergency humanitarian aid, the EU would isolate itself economically from Greece to try to prevent the contagion from spreading.
The biggest question is no longer how to try to fix Greece, but whether there is a way to prevent the fragile economies of Italy, Spain and Portugal from entering the same death spiral and to stop the aftershocks from destroying what remains of the common currency project that has formed the backbone of the European Union and is, to many Europeans, its raison dtre.
National Post
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Barack Obama leads emotional rendition of ‘Amazing Grace’ at funeral of slain pastor Clementa Pinckney</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Barack+Obama+leads+emotional+rendition+Amazing+Grace+funeral/11170451/story.html</Link>
        <Description>U.S. President Barack Obama spoke Friday at the funeral service for South Carolina state senator Rev. Clementa Pinckney, one of the nine victims of the racially-motivated massacre at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston June 17 and a personal friend of Obama's</Description>
        <MainBody>

CHARLESTON, S.C.  Invoking scripture and song, President Barack Obama stood Friday before those grieving the deaths of nine black people slain in church and called on Americans to confront the uncomfortable truths of the racial prejudices that still infect American society.
Eulogizing the Rev. Clementa Pinckney, the pastor and legislator that was killed in the attack, Obama said it would be a betrayal of everything the man stood for if we allowed ourselves to slip into a comfortable silence again once the eulogies have been delivered, once the TV cameras move on.
He pleaded with Americans not to go back to business as usual.
Obama, in his 40-minute address, spoke movingly of all that Pinckney had done in his life, then confronted the hard questions raised by his death and the deaths of eight others slain by a white man.
He said it was time to remove the Confederate flag from American flagpoles, saying that action would not be an insult to the valour of Confederate soldiers but an acknowledgement that the cause for which they fought, the cause of slavery, was wrong, as was racial segregation and resistance to civil rights efforts.
The Confederate battle flag represented the southern states in the 19th century U.S. civil war, in which northern states fought to abolish slavery and the South fought to preserve it.
Removing the flag, he said, would be one step in an honest accounting of Americas history, a modest but meaningful balm for so many unhealed wounds.
The president called, too, for an American reckoning with the nations history of gun violence, saying for too long weve been blind to the mayhem that gun violence inflects upon this nation.
He closed his rousing address by singing the words to the famous Christian hymn Amazing Grace, and calling on Americans not to lose our way again by failing to reckon with the questions stirred in the past week.
The deaths of Pinckney and eight others sparked spirited debate in Southern states over the Confederate battle flag, which for years has flown at a monument on the grounds of the South Carolina statehouse. But the slayings have also exposed the scant appetite in Washington for restarting discussions on gun control legislation, which have made no progress during Obamas presidency.
The sombre setting in Charleston was a marked contrast to the jubilant mood at the White House this week, where Obama and his advisers have relished back-to-back victories on trade and health care.
First lady Michelle Obama, along with Vice-President Joe Biden and his wife, Jill, joined the president for the funeral in Charleston.
Following the service for Pinckney, the president was expected to meet privately with the families of other victims.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Same-sex marriage legal anywhere in the United States, Supreme Court rules</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Same+marriage+legal+anywhere+United+States+Supreme+Court/11169393/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally</Description>
        <MainBody>Same-sex marriage legal anywhere in the United States, Supreme Court rules

By The Associated Press June 26, 2015



WASHINGTON The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States.
Gay and lesbian couples already could marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia. The courts 5-4 ruling means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
Gay rights supporters cheered, danced and wept outside the court when the decision was announced.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote the majority opinion, just as he did in the courts previous three major gay rights cases dating back to 1996. It came on the anniversary of two of those earlier decisions.
No union is more profound than marriage, Kennedy wrote, joined by the courts four more liberal justices.
The stories of the people asking for the right to marry reveal that they seek not to denigrate marriage but rather to live their lives, or honor their spouses memory, joined by its bond, Kennedy said.
The four dissenting justices each filed a separate opinion explaining their views, but they agreed that states and their voters should have been left with the power to decide who can marry.
This court is not a legislature. Whether same-sex marriage is a good idea should be of no concern to us, Chief Justice John Roberts wrote in dissent. Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in nearly 10 years as chief justice.
If you are among the many Americans  of whatever sexual orientation  who favor expanding same-sex marriage, by all means celebrate todays decision, Roberts said. But do not celebrate the Constitution. It had nothing to do with it.
Justice Antonin Scalia said he is not concerned so much about same-sex marriage, but about this courts threat to American democracy. Justices Samuel Alito and Clarence Thomas also dissented.
President Barack Obama welcomed the decision via Twitter, calling it a big step in our march toward equality.
The ruling will not take effect immediately because the court gives the losing side roughly three weeks to ask for reconsideration. But some state officials and county clerks might decide there is little risk in issuing marriage licenses to same-sex couples.
The cases before the court involved laws from Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee that define marriage as the union of a man and a woman. Those states have not allowed same-sex couples to marry within their borders and they also have refused to recognize valid marriages from elsewhere.
Just two years ago, the Supreme Court struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law that denied a range of government benefits to legally married same-sex couples.
The decision in United States v. Windsor did not address the validity of state marriage bans, but courts across the country, with few exceptions, said its logic compelled them to invalidate state laws that prohibited gay and lesbian couples from marrying.
The number of states allowing same-sex marriage has grown rapidly. As recently as October, just over one-third of the states permitted same-sex marriage.
There are an estimated 390,000 married same-sex couples in the United States, according to UCLAs Williams Institute, which tracks the demographics of gay and lesbian Americans. Another 70,000 couples living in states that do not currently permit them to wed would get married in the next three years, the institute says. Roughly 1 million same-sex couples, married and unmarried, live together in the United States, the institute says.
The Obama administration backed the right of same-sex couples to marry. The Justice Departments decision to stop defending the federal anti-marriage law in 2011 was an important moment for gay rights, and Obama declared his support for same-sex marriage in 2012.
The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States.
Gay and lesbian couples already could marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia. The courts 5-4 ruling means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote the majority opinion, just as he did in the courts previous three major gay rights cases dating back to 1996. It came on the anniversary of two of those earlier decisions.
No union is more profound than marriage, Kennedy wrote, joined by the courts four more liberal justices.
The four dissenting justices each filed a separate opinion explaining their views.
But this court is not a legislature. Whether same-sex marriage is a good idea should be of no concern to us, Chief Justice John Roberts wrote in dissent. Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in nearly 10 years as chief justice.
Justice Antonin Scalia said he is not concerned so much about same-sex marriage, but about this courts threat to American democracy. Justices Samuel Alito and Clarence Thomas also dissented.
The ruling will not take effect immediately because the court gives the losing side roughly three weeks to ask for reconsideration. But some state officials and county clerks might decide there is little risk in issuing marriage licenses to same-sex couples.
The cases before the court involved laws from Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee that define marriage as the union of a man and a woman. Those states have not allowed same-sex couples to marry within their borders and they also have refused to recognize valid marriages from elsewhere.
Just two years ago, the Supreme Court struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law that denied a range of government benefits to legally married same-sex couples.
The decision in United States v. Windsor did not address the validity of state marriage bans, but courts across the country, with few exceptions, said its logic compelled them to invalidate state laws that prohibited gay and lesbian couples from marrying.
The number of states allowing same-sex marriage has grown rapidly. As recently as October, just over one-third of the states permitted same-sex marriage.
There are an estimated 390,000 married same-sex couples in the United States, according to UCLAs Williams Institute, which tracks the demographics of gay and lesbian Americans. Another 70,000 couples living in states that do not currently permit them to wed would get married in the next three years, the institute says. Roughly 1 million same-sex couples, married and unmarried, live together in the United States, the institute says.
The Obama administration backed the right of same-sex couples to marry. The Justice Departments decision to stop defending the federal anti-marriage law in 2011 was an important moment for gay rights and President Barack Obama declared his support for same-sex marriage in 2012.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>Kalashnikov-wielding attacker opens fire on sunbathers at Tunisian resort, killing 37 and wounding 36</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/least+dead+beach+resort+massacre+gunmen+open+fire+Tunisian/11169217/story.html</Link>
        <Description>It was one of three deadly attacks from Europe to the Middle East on Friday that followed a call to violence by Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant</Description>
        <MainBody>Kalashnikov-wielding attacker opens fire on sunbathers at Tunisian resort, killing 37 and wounding 36

By The Associated Press June 26, 2015


Warning: Graphic images
SOUSSE, Tunisia  A young man unfurled an umbrella and pulled out a Kalashnikov, opening fire on European sunbathers in an attack that killed 37 people at a Tunisian beach resort  one of three deadly attacks from Europe to the Middle East on Friday that followed a call to violence by Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant extremists.
Health Ministry spokesman Choukri Nafti said another 36 people were wounded in Fridays attack and two or three of them are in critical condition.
The Health Ministry said the dead included Tunisians, British, Germans and Belgians, without giving a breakdown.
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond says at least five Britons were killed.
Canadas Foreign Affairs department says its officials in Tunisia are trying to determine whether any Canadians are among the dead. The department says 826 Canadians were known to be in the country. However, that number is only an estimate, since registration is voluntary and the figure is typically not fully representative of the actual number residing or visiting an area.
The killings in the Tunisian resort of Sousse happened at about the same time as a bombing at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait which killed at least 25 and an attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France that included a beheading. It was unclear if the violence was linked but it came days after the ISIL militants urged their followers to make Ramadan a month of calamities for the nonbelievers.
The attack in Tunisia, the countrys worst ever, comes just months after the March 18 assault on the national museum in Tunis that killed 22 people, again mostly tourists, and has called into question the newly elected governments ability to protect the country.
Authorities initially thought there was more than one gunman in Fridays attack, but top security official Rafik Chelli told The Associated Press later that it was just one person, a young student not previously known to authorities. The rampage at the RIU Imperial Marhaba hotel ended when he was shot to death by police.
He was certainly involved with certain extremists, said Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry.
The attack followed two others Friday in France and in Kuwait. The Islamic State group claimed responsibility for an attack at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait City that killed at least 25 people, while a man with ties to Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory in southeastern France, where a severed head was found on a post at the entrance.
In a video released Tuesday, ISIL called on its supporters to increase attacks during Ramadan and be keen on waging invasion in this eminent month and commit martyrdom.
The carnage in Tunisia began on the beach, where tourists described hearing what sounded like fireworks and then running for their lives when they realized it was gunfire. Video footage of the aftermath showed medics using beach chairs as stretchers to carry away people in swimsuits.
He had a parasol in his hand. He went down to put it in the sand and then he took out his Kalashnikov and began shooting wildly, Chelli said.
The gunman then entered the pool area of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before moving into the building, killing people as he went.
Olivia Leathley, 24, from Manchester in northwest England, told Britains Press Association she saw one woman whose husband had been shot in the stomach in front of her.
She said the woman was dragged away by hotel reps trying to get her to safety but she was a complete mess. She was in hysterics.
Leathley said: All she said was that hed been shot and that he was there bleeding on the beach and he was just saying, I love you I love you, and then his eyes rolled back into his head.
Debbie Horsfall from Huddersfield in northern England told the BBC the gunman had started firing on people at the sandbanks right next to her.
As he began to fire we just got up and ran straight to our hotel, she said.
A lawmaker said at least one woman from Ireland was among the dead. The politician, Ray Butler, says he has spoken by telephone to the husband of the dead woman. He says the two were vacationing in Tunisia together when she was shot on the beach outside their hotel, and the husband was still inside.
He is absolutely distraught, Butler says.
Butler says the woman was in her 50s and from the village of Robinstown, County Meath, northwest of Dublin.
The Irish Department of Foreign Affairs says it cannot confirm whether an Irish citizen is among those killed in Fridays attack. It says more than 60 Irish holidaymakers are in the country.
British tourist Gary Pine told AP he was on the beach with his wife around noon when heard what sounded like firecrackers going off very quickly. They shouted for their son to get out of the water, grabbed their bag and ran for the hotel. Their son told them he saw someone shot on the beach.
Back at the hotel, the situation was sheer panic. There were a lot of concerned people, a few people in tears with panic and a few people  older guests  theyd turned their ankles or there was a few little minor injuries and nicks and scrapes, Pine said.
Elizabeth OBrien, an Irish tourist on holiday with her two sons, told Irish Radio she was on the beach when the shooting began.
I thought, Oh my God. It sounds like gunfire, so I just ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things before fleeing to their hotel room, she said.
Since overthrowing its secular dictator in 2011, Tunisia has been plagued by terror attacks  though only recently have they targeted the vital tourism sector. Tourism is a major part of the Tunisian economy, especially in coastal resorts like Sousse, and it suffered in the aftermath of the 2011 revolution.
Tunisias economy is heavily dependent on tourism and that revenue is now about to all but disappear, leaving Tunisia in dire straits at a critical junction in its political transition, North Africa analyst Geoff Porter said.
A Pentagon spokesman says it is too early to say if the three attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France were co-ordinated.
Col. Steve Warren says Pentagon condemns these terrorist attacks and will continue to work with international partners to fight the Islamic State group and other violent extremist groups.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Where can you watch Larry King and Jesse ‘The Body’ Ventura? On Kremlin-backed TV of course</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Where+watch+Larry+King+Jesse+Body+Ventura+Kremlin+backed/11169964/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The Kremlin&amp;#8217;s ultimate goal, President Vladimir Putin has said, is 'to try to break the monopoly of Anglo-Saxon media over the global flows of information'</Description>
        <MainBody>

In this April 1, 2013 file photo. talk show host Larry King attends a season-opening baseball game between the Los Angeles Dodgers and the San Francisco Giants in Los Angeles. Larry King is back on air, beaming his high-octane brand of talk to households around the world. One place you can catch him? Kremlin-backed TV.
MOSCOW  Larry Kings back on the air, beaming his high-octane brand of talk to households around the world. Where can you catch him? Kremlin-backed TV.
Moscow wants you to pay better attention to what its saying, and to better reach your eyes and ears its spending around a half-billion dollars a year and carrying top-name talent like King and former governor and professional wrestler Jesse The Body Ventura.
Worried that the Russian message is getting through, Western countries are pushing back, including with a proposed action plan that European Union leaders are discussing at a summit in Brussels on Thursday and Friday.
As relations with the U.S. and some of its allies become more publicly fractious and at times openly hostile, Russias government has assembled a gigantic media machine not only for its own people, but to target a foreign audience from Warsaw to Washington with news items like these:
CIA Director Admits: US Foreign Policy Causes Terrorism
US wants to make Ukraine a base to attack Russia
NATO breaks treaty to establish permanent forces in Baltic
The Kremlins ultimate goal, President Vladimir Putin has said, is to try to break the monopoly of Anglo-Saxon media over the global flows of information.
Western governments have disseminated their own brand of news and information for years, as has Russia. The United States, Western European countries and some Latin American and Asian ones sponsor media that broadcast their particular world views around the globe.
What sets the new Russian effort apart, experts say, is how comprehensive, sophisticated and unrelenting it is.
The West is playing 19th century Victorian boxing while Russia is using karate, said Ben Nimmo, a former NATO press officer who writes about security issues.
On the shows carried by the Russian government-financed, English-language television channel RT, King does the same thing that made him a legend on CNN: interviewing newsmakers, show biz figures and celebrities of all calibres.
Themes chosen by Ventura, a former Navy SEAL and one-term governor of Minnesota, are typically harder-edged. RT shows with Ventura this month featured torture whistleblower John Kiriakou, quoted as saying the CIA is run by lunatics, and scrutinized the U.S. Federal Reserve, dubbed an illegal institution in an RT promo.
RT management did not respond to Associated Press requests for interviews, and AP got no response to requests through the station for comment from King and Ventura. On her blog, RT Editor-in-Chief Margarita Simonyan has said she is determined to offer overseas audiences an alternative view on events, and is driven by love for Russia.
I realize why I keep working at a channel which is alone facing thousands, tens of thousands of Western media outlets, telling the other side of the story, finding itself in the cross-hairs of those media and struggling to fend off their attacks. Because its my Motherland, she wrote.
AP provides text, photos and raw video footage to RT, and its commercial arm Global Media Services provides production services to some RT shows.
For Lt. Col. Simon West, a British Army specialist on strategic communications, RTs programming lineup is a canny move designed to achieve both audience share and trust.
Larry King, well, you and I know him. Hes a chap of great broadcasting credibility, said West, consultant at a Riga, Latvia-based facility opened by NATO member states last year in large part to address the information challenge from Moscow.
Polish parliament member Witold Waszcyzkowski said its part of a strategy that leaves many viewers unaware that they have tuned into a Kremlin-bankrolled information source, since the typical RT newscaster sounds like your neighbour.
Indeed, in the view of many Western analysts, Moscows new brand of information for export has dropped the Soviet-era pretention that the Russians were building a virtual workers paradise, and sometimes appears focused on discrediting U.S. and European leaders and institutions in the eyes of their own citizens.
If you follow the RT Twitter feed, as I do to my eternal teeth-gritting annoyance, its full of stories of racism in the U.S., police corruption in the UK, gay propaganda in Sweden, Nimmo said.
RTs oft-repeated slogan is question more. In the final analysis, Britains ambassador to NATO told AP, Russian media may not be trying to persuade foreign publics, but to confuse them.
They arent concerned to prove they are right, but to muddy the information space so much that its hard to get the truth through, Sir Adam Thomson said.
Unlike its Western competitors, Putin said last year as he celebrated the inauguration of RT service to Argentina, the Kremlin-backed channel does not aggressively impose its own views on others. But EU leaders, at odds with Moscow since Russias 2014 annexation of Crimea, generally disagree, and will try to agree on countermeasures at their Brussels summit.
Were not winning because were not doing, said Lithuanian Foreign Minister Linas Linkevicius.
The draft EU action plan on strategic communication, obtained by AP, calls for an array of measures including the creation by Sept. 1 of a special team to parry Russias ongoing disinformation campaigns.
If approved by EU heads of state and government, the special unit would be in charge of anticipating and replying to any disinformation targeting the bloc, and working with member states to alert them to the dangers of such campaigns.
In the U.S., Assistant Secretary of State for European Affairs Victoria Nuland, in March testimony to a House committee, requested more than $20 million in new funding for State Department programs to counter Russian propaganda. Already in fiscal 2013, budgets for the government-financed Voice of America and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty operations totalled $288.5 million.
Nuland said Moscows wide-ranging effort to sway Western leaders and publics includes funding political campaigns and false NGOs that defend Russian interests. Russia has also organized troll farms of pro-Kremlin bloggers and social media posters to disseminate its official view and attack those who disagree.
Major brands in the export division of Russian mass media include RT, the RIA Novosti news agency and its Sputnik radio and website. Despite the pounding Russias economy is taking from the slump in the price of oil and the Wests Ukraine-related sanctions, government funding for RT has grown by 30 per cent since 2014, to the ruble equivalent of $289 million.
In the United States, Comcast carries RT to many of its 22 million video subscribers in 39 states and Washington. The channel, which already broadcasts in English and Spanish, is adding French and German.
On some subjects, especially whats happening in Ukraine, RT just completely toes the Kremlin line
During two recent semesters, classes at the Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism in New York monitored RT and drew a number of conclusions.
On some subjects, especially whats happening in Ukraine, RT just completely toes the Kremlin line, said professor Ann Cooper, summing up the findings. Also, theyre not going to criticize Putin. For a Russian government-bankrolled medium, that may have been predictable.
But what surprised her students, Cooper said, was the quantity of programming on the channel that would likely appeal to a U.S. or European audience that doesnt trust government, is pretty cynical about government and is open to believing in certain conspiracy theories.
For such viewers, the journalism professor said, there is quite a lot on RT.
Dahlburg reported from Brussels. Edie Lederer at the United Nations, Vladimir Isachenkov in Moscow and Matt Lee in Washington contributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Suicide bomber kills at least 25, wounds 202 in deadly attack on Kuwait Shiite mosque</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Deadly+explosion+during+midday+prayers+Kuwait+mosque+leaves/11169344/story.html</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber purportedly from an Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant affiliate unleashed the first terrorist attack in Kuwait in more than two decades</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide bomber kills at least 25, wounds 202 in deadly attack on Kuwait Shiite mosque

By The Associated Press June 26, 2015


Warning: Graphic images
KUWAIT CITY  A suicide bomber purportedly from an Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant affiliate unleashed the first terrorist attack in Kuwait in more than two decades on Friday, killing at least 25 people and wounding scores more in a bombing that targeted Shiite worshippers after midday prayers.
The bombing struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque in the residential neighbourhood of al-Sawabir in Kuwaits capital, Kuwait City. It is one of the oldest Shiite mosques in Kuwait, a predominantly Sunni Arab nation where at least at third of the population is believed to be Shiite Muslims.
It was the third attack in five weeks to be claimed by a purported ISIL affiliate calling itself the Najd Province, a reference to the central region of Saudi Arabia where the ultra conservative Sunni ideology of Wahhabism originated.
The upstart ISIL branch had claimed two prior bombing attacks on Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia that killed 26 people in late May. The group was unheard of until the first Saudi bombing.
The attack took place as worshippers were standing shoulder to shoulder in group prayer, according to one of the witnesses at the mosque, Hassan al-Haddad.
The explosion ripped through the back of the mosque, near the door, he said, adding that other worshippers behind him said they saw a man walk in, stand in the back with other congregants and detonate his device.
Another witness, Ahmed al-Shawaf, said he heard a man interrupt prayer by shouting Allahu Akbar, or God is Great in Arabic, several times. The man then he yelled out something about joining the Prophet Muhammad for iftar, the dusk meal with which Muslims break their daytime fasting during the holy month of Ramadan, which started last week. Then, the blast came, al-Shawaf said.
The explosion took place near the end of a second prayer, which is traditional to Shiites and follows the main midday Friday prayer.
The Ministry of Interior said 25 people were killed and 202 wounded. Police formed a cordon around the mosques complex immediately after the explosion, banning people from entering or gathering near the area. Ambulances could be seen ferrying the wounded from the site.
We couldnt see anything, so we went straight to the wounded and tried to carry them out. We left the dead, said witness Hassan al-Haddad, 21, who said he saw several lifeless bodies.
A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claimed the explosion was work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt. It said the attack was carried out by the Najd Province, which also claimed the Saudi bombings.
The Islamic State group regards Shiite Muslims as heretics, and refers to them derogatively as rafideen or rejectionists. The IS Twitter statement said the bomber had targeted a temple of the apostates.
Immediately after the attack, Kuwaits ruler, Emir Sabah Al-Ahmad Al-Sabah, who is in his mid-80s, visited the site of the attack. The Cabinet convened an emergency session later in the afternoon. Kuwaiti Justice and Islamic Affairs Minister Yaacoub al-Sanea condemned the attack in a statement carried by the official Kuwait News Agency.
But the attack also drew accusations from some Kuwaiti Shiites, who said that Kuwaits leaders should have been more pro-active in protecting Shiites, and that their response to the attack is too little too late.
Former Sunni lawmaker, Abdullah al-Neybari, said the Kuwaiti government is not doing what it should be doing to fight extremism in the country. 
This is a wakeup call to fight harder, he said.
The last massive attack to take place in Kuwait was in 1983, when Iranian-backed Shiite militants from Iraq carried out bombings that killed at least five and wounded nearly 90.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Plaintiffs celebrate U.S. same-sex marriage ruling</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Plaintiffs+celebrate+same+marriage+ruling/11169697/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States, a historic culmination of two decades of litigation over gay marriage and gay rights generally. (June 26)</Description>
        <MainBody>Plaintiffs celebrate U.S. same-sex marriage ruling

By The Associated Press, Calgary Herald June 26, 2015



The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States, a historic culmination of two decades of litigation over gay marriage and gay rights generally. (June 26)


People celebrate outside the Stonewall Tavern in the West Village in New York on June 26, 2015. The US Supreme Court ruled Friday that gay marriage is a nationwide right, a landmark decision in one of the most keenly awaited announcements in decades and sparking scenes of jubilation. The nation's highest court, in a narrow 5-4 decision, said the US Constitution requires all states to carry out and recognize marriage between people of the same sex.
Photograph by: TIMOTHY A. CLARY, Calgary Herald

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Attacker posted severed head at French factory’s gate, triggered explosion with car: police</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Attacker+posted+severed+head+French+factory+gate+triggered/11169127/story.html</Link>
        <Description>'No doubt about the intention &amp;#8212; to cause an explosion,' President Francois Hollande said, calling the attack 'of a terrorist nature'</Description>
        <MainBody>

An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into an American gas factory Friday in southeastern France, officials said, adding that a severed head and banners with Arabic inscriptions were found at the factorys entrance. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
President Francois Hollande said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car made it through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion that injured two people, he said, speaking in Brussels.
Three French officials say the decapitated victim found in an attack was the suspects employer.
No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion, Hollande said, calling the attack of a terrorist nature.
Hollande saidhe is raising the security alert to the highest level for three days in the southeastern region where a suspect attacked an thegas factory.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man from the Lyon region who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter. He said several other people were also taken into custody after the attack and authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was at the gate and body was found elsewhere on the factory premises.
People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody, he said.
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. Still, the minister said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
It was not clear if French authorities were searching for any more possible accomplices.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company said all its employees had been accounted for and evacuated but did not say if any had been wounded.
The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities, the company said in a statement.
The severed head at the factorys entrance appeared to be an echo of ISILs practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. A security official said two flags  one white and one black, both bearing Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation was ongoing, said the victim was believed to have died before the suspect got a car through the factorys gates and rammed into gas canisters Friday morning. That triggered an explosion that officials say injured two people.
A French police official says the man in custody, Yassine Salhi, is a resident in his 30s of the Lyon suburb of Saint-Priest. Police have not named his employer but say he is the head of a local transportation company.
French police say they have the suspect in custody, along with the suspects wife and others. Hollande says the key question is to determine whether there were any accomplices.
Frances anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of a terrorist group. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested in April after authorities said he was plotting to gun down people in churches in the Paris region.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>You’ll never guess which debt-ridden European country is popping bottles like it’s going out of style</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/never+guess+which+debt+ridden+European+country+popping/11169357/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Ok, it's Greece. The country that has the global economy on tenter hooks guzzled 18 per cent more champagne last year but 'consumption is still lower than before the crisis'</Description>
        <MainBody>
Greece consumed 18 per cent more champagne last year despite its economic woes.
Chapagne consumption in Greece jumped by almost a fifth last year, making the troubled country the worlds fastest growing market for bubbly.
Greeces champagne sales by volume increased by 18 per cent in 2014, compared to the global growth of 0.5 per cent, according to data from Euromonitor International.
Consumption in the sparkling wines home country of France dropped by 1.9 per cent, while sales in the UK, champagnes second biggest market, crept up by just 0.4 per cent.
The disparity was even stronger in 2013, when Greek champagne consumption soared by 56 per cent while dropping by 0.8 per cent, 3.4 per cent and 0.5 per cent in the world, France and the UK, respectively.
The relative size of the markets goes some way to explaining the vastly different growth rates.
Its not that all the Greeks in the last couple of years decided to go party and forget their troubles, said Spiros Malandrakis, alcoholic drinks analyst at Euromonitor. In general, were talking about minimal volumes in total. Champagne consumption is still lower than before the crisis.
More tourists are coming in the country, but they are also higher end tourists
Around 300,000 litres of champagne were drunk in Greece last year, a fraction of the size of Frances 107.2?m and even the UKs 20.4?m.
Nonetheless, the champagne market in Greece is growing rapidly.
It does appear to be a shocking figure, said Mr Malandrakis, adding it would be almost entirely based on the countrys tourism influx, particularly to popular islands such as Mykonos and Santorini.
More tourists are coming in the country, but they are also higher end tourists, he said. About 24m people visited Greece in 2014, a second consecutive record year for the country of 11 million, which relies on tourism for roughly one sixth of its economy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Turkey accused of allowing ISIL fighters to cross its border to attack a Kurdish town only recently freed of militants</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Turkey+accused+allowing+ISIL+fighters+cross+border+attack/11169334/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Twin car bombs blew up close to the border crossing, and Kurdish activists and residents claimed the bombers had crossed from the Turkish side</Description>
        <MainBody>

Turkey accused of allowing ISIL fighters to cross its border to attack a Kurdish town only recently freed of militants

By The Telegraph June 26, 2015



A Turkish soldier stand guard on the way to Mursitpinar crossing gate in Suruc in Turkey's Sanliurfa province across the Syrian border town of Kobane on June 25, 2015.
LONDON  Turkey was accused Thursday of allowing Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant fighters to cross its border to attack the Kurdish town of Kobane, months after the jihadists were driven out.
Twin car bombs were detonated close to the border crossing at the Turkish town of Mursitpinar, and Kurdish activists and residents claimed the bombers had crossed from the Turkish, despite a heavy police presence.
A convoy of cars carrying up to 40 Isil fighters  reportedly using the uniform of Kurdish YPG militia as a disguise  then attacked Kobane from three sides in the early hours of yesterday.
Kobane became an important symbol in the battle against Isil after the group launched an offensive against the town last year. Kurdish forces backed by US-led air strikes waged a four-month battle to repel the group, finally securing the town in January.
Months of fighting prompted a mass exodus of residents, with some 200,000 fleeing across the border into Turkey. About 35,000 Syrians returned home a few months ago after Kobanes liberation.
The Kurds and many of Turkeys Middle Eastern neighbours have regularly accused President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of sympathising with Isil, or at least allowing it to use Turkish territory to gain access to the front lines in Syria.
The clashes started at 4:30am, said Kali Maho, a local activist. A terrorist armed group entered the city, holding explosive belts. They targeted the civilians.
Scores of Kurdish fighters and civilians were said to have been killed in subsequent fighting, which may have involved as few as 35-40 attackers.
Redur Xelil, the spokesman for the YPG, said: So far, 15 of this group were killed. Three of them managed to escape to Turkey. There are still some elements hiding inside the city. Isil was also accused of killing 20 civilians, including women and children, in the nearby village of Barkh Botan.
Saif Haj Omar, 53, said that two of his cousins were killed in their house on Kobanes south-eastern outskirts.
They entered their house and shot them and their families, he said by telephone. According to the injured women, they entered the house and shouted, you are kuffar (infidels) before they opened fire.
Mustafa Bali, a Kurdish activist who lives less than a mile from the scene of the bombing, told this newspaper: I could see the smoke and hear the sound of the attack. Two cars blew up on the Syrian side. Most probably the cars came from the Turkish side.
If they entered from the Syrian side, they would have first come upon many more important targets related to the YPG, such as the main headquarters building where there are tens of fighters and leaders, or the local administration HQ.
It seemed unlikely they would pass these by and then go to the crossing to kill civilians, he said.
Syrian state media also said the attackers came from Turkey. The Turkish deputy prime minister, Numan Kurtulmus, rejected the allegation. The claim that Daesh (Isil) militants passed through the Turkish border is entirely a lie and part of a black propaganda, he said.
The government claimed that the attackers came from the Isil-held town of Jarablus to the west. However, that did little to appease Turkeys many critics, who claim that the area in Turkey around Jarablus is the main point of entry to Syria for large numbers of Isils foreign fighters. The YPG  the main Syrian Kurdish militia  won worldwide recognition last autumn for its defence of Kobane against a concerted Isil siege.
Since then, it has pressed forward, uniting a long border territory under its rule and coming within 30 miles of the jihadists de facto capital, Raqqa.
However, the lightning attack yesterday showed Isil is able to hit back strongly
Arrests of British teenagers on terror offences have tripled to 46 in the past year, with authorities fearing the rise of Isil is responsible for the growing number attempting to flee to Syria.
The Daily Telegraph
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>EU leaders agree to relocate 40,000 migrants from Greece, Italy</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/News/world/leaders+agree+relocate+migrants+from+Greece+Italy/11167878/story.html</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS &amp;#8212; European Union leaders have agreed to relocate 40,000 migrants from Italy and Greece to other EU countries over the next two years, in an effort to share the burden of a growing migrant crisis. EU President Donald Tusk [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>EU leaders agree to relocate 40,000 migrants from Greece, Italy

By The Associated Press, Canada.com June 26, 2015



Migrants wait near the sea in the city of Ventimiglia on the French-Italian border on June 24, 2015.
Photograph by: VALERY HACHE                , AFP/Getty Images
BRUSSELS  European Union leaders have agreed to relocate 40,000 migrants from Italy and Greece to other EU countries over the next two years, in an effort to share the burden of a growing migrant crisis.
EU President Donald Tusk said the agreement was reached after an overnight summit early Friday, to show solidarity with frontline countries.
French President Francois Hollande said the EU will also resettle 20,000 refugees, essentially from Syria and Iraq, who at this moment are in camps and who will be reinstalled in Europe.
The migrant crisis has caused tensions among EU countries.
02:13ET 26-06-15
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Nine people on small sightseeing plane die in Alaska crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/News/world/Nine+people+small+sightseeing+plane+Alaska+crash/11167681/story.html</Link>
        <Description>By Mark Thiessen ANCHORAGE, Alaska &amp;#8211; All nine people aboard a sightseeing plane died in crash Thursday in southeast Alaska, authorities said, but stormy weather was preventing the immediate recovery of the bodies. &amp;#8220;We have nine fatalities,&amp;#8221; said Clint Johnson, [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>Nine people on small sightseeing plane die in Alaska crash

By The Associated Press, Canada.com June 25, 2015



The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska, on Thursday, June 25, 2015. Officials say eight passengers on an excursion off the ship and a pilot were in plane that was found crashed against the granite rock face of a cliff about 20 miles northeast of Ketchikan, Alaska. The conditions of the nine onboard the plane weren't immediately known.  (AP Photo/Ketchikan Daily News, Taylor Balkom).
By Mark Thiessen
ANCHORAGE, Alaska  All nine people aboard a sightseeing plane died in crash Thursday in southeast Alaska, authorities said, but stormy weather was preventing the immediate recovery of the bodies.
We have nine fatalities, said Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Boards Alaska office.
Rain and wind forced an end to recovery efforts Thursday night in the rugged terrain about 20 miles northeast of Ketchikan. Officials would mount a recovery attempt again on Friday, he said.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop crashed. It was found Thursday against the granite rock face of a cliff, 800 feet above Ella Lake.
Johnson said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain, Johnson said. Its a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down.
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 800 miles southeast of Anchorage.
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families, the statement said. Holland America Line is extending its full support to travelling companions of the guests involved.
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling, Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy.
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airlines website advertises tours of the 2-million-acre Misty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape, it says.
___
Associated Press writer Kathy McCarthy in Seattle contributed to this report.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>‘Have they found out what is in the walls yet?’: Creepy letters from ‘The Watcher’ drive family from home</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Have+they+found+what+walls+Creepy+letters+from+Watcher+drive/11166566/story.html</Link>
        <Description>A couple who says they were scared away from their new US$1.4-million New Jersey home because of creepy letters from a stalker has sued the sellers</Description>
        <MainBody>

'Do you need to fill the house with the young blood I requested?' one letter reads, according to the suit
ELIZABETH, N.J.  A couple who says they were scared away from their new US$1.4-million home because of creepy letters from a stalker has sued the sellers for not telling them about a person with a mentally disturbed fixation on the house.
Derek and Maria Broaddus said the former owners of the home in Westfield, 40 kilometres west of New York City, should have warned them of the person who signs the letters as The Watcher.
The letter writer claims to have been controlling the house for two decades and that former owners John and Andrea Woods sold it because it was their time to move on and kindly sold it when I asked them to, according to the lawsuit filed this month.
Do you need to fill the house with the young blood I requested? one letter reads, according to the suit. Once I know their names I will call to them and draw them too (sic) me.
Details of the suit posted by Gawker claim that the first letter read that the home has been subject of my family for decades and that My grandfather watched the house in the 1920s and my father watched in the 1960s. It is now my timeI have been put in charge of watching and waiting for its second coming.
Additional letters asked have they found out what is in the walls yet? and in time they will and asked who has the bedrooms facing the street? The letters claimed that All of the windows and doorsallow me to watch you and track you as you move through the house. Who am I? they read. I am the Watcher.
The lawsuit also names an insurance company and settlement company as defendants. Officials from the companies didnt immediately return calls for comment. Contact information for the Woods and their attorneys wasnt immediately available.
The Broadduses says they would never have bought the house if the sellers had warned them about the letter writer. They are now attempting to re-sell the house as they are unable to live in the home without extreme anxiety and fear for their childrens safety and wellbeing, according to the lawsuit.
The suit says they are having a hard time selling because of the letters. They want the former owners to refund them the purchase price and pay punitive damages.
The real estate listing for the 6-bedroom, 3.5-bath house describes a grand turn-of-the century home with many quality updatesPeriod features include high ceilings, coffered ceilings, elegant foyers, built-in window seats, fireplaces and more.
At a township council meeting Tuesday, Westfield Mayor Andrew Skibitsky pleaded with anyone with information to call the police.
Our police have conducted an exhaustive investigation into the threatening letters. Our police went the extra measure and left no stone unturned, Skibitsky said, adding that no charges have been filed.
The Union County prosecutors office also is investigating.
We also would urge anyone who receives correspondence of any nature that they feel is threatening to contact the police immediately, said spokesman Mark Spivey.
With files from Post staff
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>Sutcliffe, Adam: Two takes on the fallout from Charleston shootings</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Analysis+takes+aftermath+Charleston+shootings/11166323/story.html</Link>
        <Description>A week and a day&amp;#160;after the horrific shooting of nine African-Americans by a white supremacist at a&amp;#160;historic church in Charleston, South Carolina, repercussions of his&amp;#160;act are still unfolding in America. Today, two Citizen columnists offer two different takes&amp;#160;on how Americans are reacting to the tragedy. &amp;#160; Mohammed Adam is deeply disappointed at the many expressions [&amp;#8230;]</Description>
        <MainBody>Sutcliffe, Adam: Two takes on the fallout from Charleston shootings

By The Ottawa Citizen, Ottawa Citizen June 25, 2015



COLUMBIA, SC - JUNE 23:  Ernest Branch (L) shake hands with a man carrying a Confederate flag (who didn't want to provide his name) saying, that he respects the fact the guy likes the flag but that he is against the flag flying on the Capitol grounds on June 23, 2015 in Columbia, South Carolina. The South Carolina governor Nikki Haley asked that the flag be removed afer debate over the flag flying on the capitol grounds was kicked off after nine people were shot and killed during a prayer meeting at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, South Carolina.
Photograph by: Joe Raedle                , Ottawa Citizen
A week and a dayafter the horrific shooting of nine African-Americans by a white supremacist at ahistoric church in Charleston, South Carolina, repercussions of hisact are still unfolding in America.
Today, two Citizen columnists offer two different takeson how Americans are reacting to the tragedy.

Mohammed Adam is deeply disappointed at the many expressions of denial that camefrom prominent Republicans and conservatives.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
