<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="canada">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>Sex on the beach lands man two and a half years in jail for ‘lewd’ behaviour on Florida seaside</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/beach+lands+half+years+jail+lewd+behaviour+Florida+seaside/11194333/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Witnesses testified that a 3-year-old saw them. The Bradenton Herald reported the woman said she &amp;#8216;had been dancing on Caballero or 'nudging' him to wake him&amp;#8217;</Description>
        <MainBody>
A beach in Manatee County
BRADENTON, Fla.  A man convicted of having sex on a Florida beach in front of families was sentenced to two and a half years in prison on Monday.
Jose Caballero, 40, and Elissa Alvarez, 21, were convicted in May of two counts of lewd and lascivious behaviour in a case that drew international attention for the couples brazen act. They were videotaped having sex on a Manatee County beach last summer in broad daylight. Witnesses testified that a 3-year-old girl saw them.
Caballero told jurors that he and Alvarez were not having sex and that witnesses were mistaken. The Bradenton Herald reported Alvarez said she had been dancing on Caballero or nudging him to wake him up.
Jurors listened to graphic testimony from witnesses and saw a video of Alvarez moving on top of Caballero in a sexual manner in the middle of the day while others watched.
We are grateful that the state has offered 2 1/2 years, said Ronald Kurpiers, defence attorney for Caballero.
He said Caballero planned to appeal his case. Alvarez, who was recently sentenced to time served, filed an appeal in her case in June.
It takes a certain type of person to do that in front of children a few feet away
Prosecutors say they were tougher on Caballero because he previously served eight years for cocaine trafficking. Both must now register as sex offenders. The Bradenton Herald reports the jury found them guilty after deliberating only 15 minutes. The couple had faced 15 years in prison.
If you think about 2:30 in the afternoon on a crowded beach. It takes a certain type of person to do that in front of children a few feet away, said Assistant State Attorney Anthony Dafonseca.
Prosecutors said it was important that the community knew what wouldnt be tolerated on public beaches.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>Greece losing its power to shock investors</title>
        <Link>http://montrealgazette.com/business/greece-losing-the-power-to-shock-investors</Link>
        <Description>Bond fund manager Lutz Roehmeyer was vacationing in Greece last week as the nation headed for its showdown with the European Union. He's made no change to his "neutral" holdings of eastern European debt.</Description>
        <MainBody>More from Bloomberg News
Published on: July 7, 2015 | Last Updated: July 7, 2015 7:01 AM EDT
An elderly man stands beside a lifebuoy hanging on a wall outside a chapel in central Athens on July 7, 2015. ARIS MESSINIS / AFP/Getty Images
Share Adjust Comment Print
by Lyubov Pronina and Maciej Onoszko
Bond fund manager Lutz Roehmeyer was vacationing in Greece last week as the nation headed for its showdown with the European Union. Hes made no change to his neutral holdings of eastern European debt.
Greece is now isolated after so many years of talk about the Grexit, said Roehmeyer, who oversees about $1.1 billion for Landesbank Berlin Investment, including the Weltzins-Invest fund which beat 92 percent of peers for the past five years.
Whereas previous flashpoints in the Greek crisis have sent shockwaves across eastern European markets, even the most vulnerable countries are now better insulated. The central bank in Bulgaria, where Greek lenders own 28 percent of the banking industry, has boosted foreign-currency reserves by around 69 percent in the past four years. The European Central Bank is set to extend a backstop facility to Bulgaria and other nations in the region to ward off contagion from Greece, people familiar with the situation said last week.
Bulgarias bonds in euros due 2022 fell 0.3 cent on the dollar to 95.96 cents on Monday. They declined the most since their sale in March on June 29, after Greece announced plans to hold a referendum on Europes austerity demands. Romanias euro notes due 2024 slipped 0.4 cent. Ten-year local bonds in those countries advanced, data compiled by Bloomberg show.
The risk for most central and eastern European countries lies in their ties with the wider euro area and the extent to which the Greek crisis triggers stress across the region, William Jackson, a senior economist at Capital Economics Ltd. in London, wrote in a research note. Mondays market moves suggest contagion may be limited, he said.
Greeces four largest lenders all have units in Bulgaria and Romania. Piraeus Bank SA, Eurobank Ergasias SA, the National Bank of Greece SA and Alpha Bank AE hold 28 percent of total bank assets in Bulgaria. Greek lenders own about 12 percent of Romanian bank assets, central bank data show.
Bulgarias central bank accumulated $17.2 billion in currency reserves by the end of May, compared with $10.2 billion four years earlier.
The ECB could step in with some bazooka and this also supports lesser nervousness, Marcin Karasiewicz, a fixed- income trader at PKO Bank Polski SA in Warsaw, said by e-mail Monday.
Risk aversion may escalate significantly unless comments from Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and euro area leaders suggest that the worst-case scenario of a Greek exit can be averted, Piotr Matys, a foreign-exchange strategist at Rabobank International in London, said by e-mail on Monday.
We maintain our very cautious approach adopted even before the negotiations collapsed and Tsipras called a referendum, Matys said.
Tsipras is heading to Brussels in a last-ditch attempt to secure a rescue from European leaders and keep his country in the euro region. German Chancellor Angela Merkel said Monday time is running out as she and French President Francois Hollande responded to referendum that backed Tsiprass anti- austerity stance.
Polish bonds in euros due in 2027 were little changed on Monday after four days of gains at 87.75 cents. Hungarys notes due in 2019 fell less than 0.1 cent.
As long as core Europe isnt affected, Greeces crisis will have very limited impact on countries like Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary, said Peter Schottmueller, who helps manage $17 billion as the head of emerging-market fixed income at Deka Investment GmbH in Frankfurt.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 to giving sedative to at least one woman he sought sex with: documents</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/entertainment/celebrity/Bill+Cosby+admitted+2005+giving+sedative+least/11192625/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Cosby&amp;#8217;s lawyers insisted that two of his accusers knew they were taking quaaludes from the comedian, according to the unsealed documents</Description>
        <MainBody>

Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 to giving sedative to at least one woman he sought sex with: documents

By The Associated Press July 7, 2015 3:27 AM



PHILADELPHIA  Bill Cosby admitted in 2005 that he got quaaludes with the intent of giving them to young women he wanted to have sex with, and that he gave the sedative to at least one woman and other people, according to documents obtained Monday by The Associated Press.
Cosbys lawyers insisted that two of his accusers knew they were taking quaaludes from the comedian, according to the unsealed documents.
The Associated Press had gone to court to compel the release of the documents from the deposition in a sexual abuse lawsuit filed by former Temple University employee Andrea Constand  the first of a cascade of sexual abuse lawsuits against him. Cosbys lawyers had objected on the grounds that it would embarrass their client.
Cosby settled that lawsuit under confidential terms in 2006. His lawyers in the Philadelphia case did not immediately return phone calls Monday. Constand, a Canadian from Pickering, Ont., consented to be identified but did not want to comment, her lawyer said Monday.
Cosby, 77, has been accused by more than two dozen women of sexual misconduct, including allegations by many that he drugged and raped them in incidents dating back more than four decades. Cosby has never been criminally charged, and most of the accusations are barred by statutes of limitations.
Cosby, giving sworn testimony in the lawsuit accusing him of sexual assaulting Constand at his home in Pennsylvania in 2004, said he got seven quaalude prescriptions in the 1970s. The lawyer for Constand asked if he had kept the sedatives through the 1990s  after they were banned  but was frustrated by objections from Cosbys lawyer.
When you got the quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with? lawyer Dolores M. Troiani asked.
Yes, Cosby answered on Sept. 29, 2005.
Did you ever give any of these young women the quaaludes without their knowledge?
Cosbys lawyer again objected, leading Troiani to petition the federal judge to force Cosby to co-operate.
Cosby later said he gave Constand three half-pills of Benadryl, although Troiani in the documents voices doubt that was the drug involved. The two other women who testified on Constands behalf said they had knowingly been given quaaludes.
Three of the women accusing Cosby of sexually assaulting them have a defamation lawsuit pending against him in Massachusetts. They allege that he defamed them when his agents said their accusations were untrue. Cosby is trying to get their case thrown out before discovery.
Cosby had fought the APs efforts to unseal the testimony, with his lawyer arguing the deposition could reveal details of Cosbys marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno asked last month why Cosby was fighting the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Temple womans lawsuit were already in the public eye.
Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts? Robreno said.
Cosby resigned in December from the board of trustees at Temple, where he was the popular face of the Philadelphia school in advertisements, fundraising campaigns and commencement speeches.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>Matthew Fisher: ‘No’ victory gives Greece a feel-good moment while rest of Europe looks on in disbelief</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Matthew+Fisher+victory+gives+Greece+feel+good+moment+while/11192810/story.html</Link>
        <Description>What hangs in the balance is not only Greece&amp;#8217;s economic future and that of the euro, but quite possibly the European project Merkel and others have held so dear for decades</Description>
        <MainBody>

ATHENS  Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras called Sundays referendum outcome, which robustly repudiated a European Union bailout offer, a triumph for democracy.
It was, at best, a Pyrrhic victory.
Tsiprass Hail Mary Pass may have given the country a feel-good moment, but it left Greeces long list of creditors and the continents leading political players unamused and unmoved. Greece will still have to accept the conditions of its erstwhile partners or it will surely be kicked out of the eurozone and into far deeper quicksand than the mud it wallows in now.
The first sign Sundays referendum will likely be nothing more than a balm for Greeces wounded pride came early Monday.
Tsiprass abrasive finance minister, Yanis Varoufakis, resigned. In character to the end, the British- and Australian-educated economist left office shouting, I shall wear the creditors loathing with pride.
His successor, Euclid Tsakalotos, named after the father of geometry, will need all his namesakes brilliance and then some to keep Greece from drowning in a sea of red ink.
Varoufakiss sudden departure added another dimension to the perverse schizophrenia that prevailed across Greece. Lineups at the few automated teller machines still dispensing euros were longer than they were when panic began to set in last week.
With banks closed for the foreseeable future, those waiting for their daily stipend of 60 euros ($80) speculated about exactly when the machines they have come to regard as a lifeline would run out. Most of the guessing was it would be sometime on Tuesday or Wednesday.
At the same time, a party atmosphere reigned throughout much of downtown Athens as those who had voted No proudly told each other and anyone else who could bear to listen the cradle of democracy had told the Europeans to get stuffed.
The view elsewhere in Europe was total disbelief  if not outright derision  at their euphoria when financial collapse appeared imminent.
The dominant opinion outside the country was the ballot result was an affront to the 18 democracies that share the euro with Greece and have been fronting it tens of billions of euros for years, and Greece was dancing on the way to its own grave.
The mood was particularly sour in Germany, which is on the hook for 89 billion euros of Greeces still-mushrooming debt. Chancellor Angela Merkels thrifty centre-left coalition could shatter if she bends, as France and a few other southern European countries would like her to, and tosses Greece a few more euros.
With Greece in urgent need of further emergency assistance to avoid a liquidity crisis that even Tsiprass government finally admitted Monday would close all the ATMs by the end of the week if urgent help was not immediately forthcoming, the chancellors spokesman noted there was no basis yet for any fresh talks with Greece.
German commentators attacked Merkel for having done too much to help Greece or not enough to punish it. Their second theme was she had badly mismanaged and squandered Germanys undeclared leadership of the European Union.
Der Spiegel magazine ran a picture on its cover of a sheepish-looking Merkel photoshopped in front of the ruins of the Parthenon. It also carried a photograph of her walking alone under the headline, Angelas ashes.
Not to be outdone, Stern, the glossy magazine that follows in the tradition of Life and Look magazines, ran a tattered European Union flag unfurled above the Acropolis with the stark caption, Endspiel um Europa (Endgame in Europe).
The damoclean sword hanging over Merkels head is Tsipras.
The hard-left prime minister, who was once again talking mischief with Russias Vladimir Putin, apparently is scheming to get Greece another six billion or so euros of what the European Central Bank calls emergency liquidity assistance to get the country through the next week or two. This would be followed by 100 billion euros in debt relief  all of it coming directly out of the pockets of other European taxpayers.
In return for this staggering amount of debt forgiveness, Tsipras will once again pledge to implement the tough reforms he and his predecessors have been cavalierly dodged undertaking for years.
The mystery is why at this juncture any European leader would even consider believing Greece, when its leaders have been cooking the countrys books forever and have allowed their citizens to turn tax evasion into an Olympic sport.
With Spain, Italy and Portugal now pondering why they bothered to follow the EUs rules to get bailouts, what hangs in the balance is not only Greeces economic future and that of the euro, but quite possibly the European project Merkel and others have held so dear for decades.
National Post
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>South Carolina senators vote to take Confederate flag down from Capitol</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/South+Carolina+senators+vote+take+Confederate+flag+down+from/11193136/story.html</Link>
        <Description>A second vote will be needed Tuesday to send the proposal to the House, where it faces a less certain future. But Monday's 37-3 vote was well over the two-thirds majority needed</Description>
        <MainBody>South Carolina senators vote to take Confederate flag down from Capitol

By The Associated Press July 6, 2015



COLUMBIA, S.C.  The South Carolina Senate voted Monday to pull the Confederate flag off the Capitol grounds, clearing the way for a historic measure that could remove the banner more than five decades after it was first flown above the Statehouse to protest integration.
A second vote will be needed Tuesday to send the proposal to the House, where it faces a less certain future. But Mondays 37-3 vote was well over the two-thirds majority needed to advance the bill.
If the House passes the same measure, the flag and flagpole could be removed as soon as Gov. Nikki Haley signs the papers. The flag would be lowered for the last time and shipped off to the states Confederate Relic Room, near where the last Confederate flag to fly over the Statehouse dome is stored.
The vote came at the end of a day of debate in which several white senators said they had come to understand why their black colleagues felt the flag no longer represented the valor of Southern soldiers but the racism that led the South to separate from the United States more than 150 years ago.
As the senators spoke, the desk of their slain colleague, Clementa Pinckney, was still draped in black cloth. Pinckney and eight other black people were fatally shot June 17 during Bible study at a historic African-American church in Charleston. Authorities have charged a gunman who posed for pictures with the rebel banner. Police say he was driven by racial hatred.
Several senators said the grace shown by the families of the victims willing to forgive the gunman also changed their minds.
We now have the opportunity, the obligation, to put the exclamation point on an extraordinary narrative of good and evil, of love and mercy that will take its place in the history books, said Sen. Tom Davis, a Republican.
After the vote, Sen. Vincent Sheheen, a Democrat whose suggestion that the flag be taken down while running for governor last year was called a stunt by Haley, was given a high-five from a fellow legislator.
I thought it would happen, but never this fast, Sheheen said.
Republican Sen. Larry Martin, who for decades fought off attempts to remove the flag from Statehouse grounds, said the church shooting drew him to the same conclusion that his black colleague arrived at long ago  that the rebel flag has more to do with what was going on in the 1960s as opposed to the 1860s.
Martin, who is white, had family who came to South Carolinas then-rugged northern backcountry from Scotland in the early 1800s. That was about the time the enslaved relatives of Sen. Darrell Jackson, a black Democrat, involuntary ended up near Columbia.
Jackson helped write the compromise that took the Confederate flag off the Statehouse dome in 2000 and put it in its current location on a pole on the Capitols front lawn.
On Monday, he said his great-grandfathers brother fled a plantation and joined the Union army when Gen. William Sherman came storming through Columbia.
Jackson said he regretted not going further to get rid of the flag completely 15 years ago. But he welcomed the chance now to honor his great-grandfather, Ishmael Jackson, who escaped to freedom.
You said we lost the war. No we didnt. Not Ishmael Jackson and the 57 percent of people who looked like him. As far as they are concerned, they won the war, Jackson said.
The Senate rejected three amendments. One would have put a different Confederate flag on the pole. A second would fly the flag only on Confederate Memorial Day, and the third would leave the flags fate up to a popular vote.
State Sen. Lee Bright, who suggested the popular vote, said the Confederate flag has been misused by people like Dylann Roof, who is charged with murder in the church shootings and who posed in pictures with the rebel banner.
Im more against taking it down in this environment than any other time just because I believe were placing the blame of what one deranged lunatic did on the people that hold their Southern heritage high, said Bright, a Republican.
The flag still has at least a few days to fly, even with Haley, business leaders and civil rights proponents wanting it down as soon as possible. There are indications the proposal could have a tougher road in the House. Some powerful Republicans have not said how they will vote, including Speaker Jay Lucas.
Some Republicans want to keep the flagpole and put a different flag on it. Suggestions have included the U.S. flag, the South Carolina flag and a flag that may have been flown by Confederate troops but does not have the same connections as the red banner with the blue cross and white stars.
House Minority Leader Todd Rutherford vowed that no Democrat would vote for a bill that leaves the flagpole up.
The bill is expected to be sent directly to the House floor Wednesday with several amendments offered, said Republican Rep. Greg Delleney, chairman of the Judiciary Committee, which would normally receive the bill before it got to the floor.
If any amendments pass, a conference committee would probably be needed to hash out differences.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>Barack Obama says anti-ISIL coalition ‘starting to see some progress’</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Barack+Obama+says+anti+ISIL+coalition+starting+some+progress/11193083/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Although the president said there were "no current plans" to send more U.S. troops to Iraq, he did not rule out that possibility in the future</Description>
        <MainBody>

WASHINGTON  President Barack Obama portrayed the U.S.-led coalition Monday as gaining ground against the Islamic State amid an expanded U.S. effort and ample signs of progress, but conceded more difficulties ahead in fighting what he described as a nimble and opportunistic enemy.
Were starting to see some progress, the president said during a rare visit to the Pentagon, ticking off a list of towns in Iraq and Syria he said had been wrested from ISIL control in recent weeks.
Flanked by top military commanders, Obama also warned of the Islamic States efforts to recruit and inspire vulnerable people in the United States, and called on the American-Muslim community to step up in terms of pushing back as hard as they can. He said that while the U.S. is now better prepared to thwart large-scale terrorist attacks like 9/11, the threat from individual lone wolves or small terrorist cells has increased.
Were going to have to pick up our game to prevent these attacks, Obama said.
The Pentagon visit followed a wave of weekend airstrikes by the U.S.-led coalition in eastern Syria, including the de facto ISIL capital of Raqqa, in one of the most sustained aerial operations carried out in Syria to date. Obama pointed to those and other airstrikes as proof of an intensified U.S. effort to undermine the militant groups base of operations and cut off their sources of funding.
Obamas afternoon visit to the Pentagon offered a public display of presidential support for the military one day before Defense Secretary Ash Carter and Joint Chiefs of Staff Chairman Martin Dempsey were expected to be grilled on Capitol Hill. Senate Armed Services Chairman John McCain, R-Ariz., has sharply criticized Obama for not doing more militarily to defeat ISIL, and said Monday that the U.S. is losing the battle as the extremist group continues to gain territory in Iraq and Syria.
President Obamas comments today reveal the disturbing degree of self-delusion that characterizes the administrations campaign against ISIL, McCain said.
Although the president said there were no current plans to send more U.S. troops to Iraq, he did not rule out that possibility in the future. Obama has vowed to keep American service members out of direct combat, but has sent more than 3,000 U.S. troops to advise and assist the beleaguered Iraqi military  including the deployment of 450 additional service members announced last month.
Efforts to train local forces in Iraq and Syria, however, have been slow to take shape. Last month, Obama acknowledged that the U.S. lacks a complete strategy for training Iraqi troops to carry out ground missions. And in Syria, fewer than 100 rebels are being trained by the U.S., far fewer than the goal of producing 5,400 fighters a year.
At the Pentagon, Obama also walked a fine line on whether hell sign a massive defense policy bill favored by Republicans. The White House has threatened to veto the bill, arguing that it uses gimmickry to increase defense spending without increasing domestic spending by an equal amount, as Obama has insisted. Some Republicans have questioned, however, whether Obama would really veto the bill should it come to his desk.
Our men and women are going to get paid, Obama said, noting that U.S. service members havent missed a paycheck since he took office. Yet he also insisted he wouldnt accept a bill that shortchanges long-term investments in technology, education and the economy. Were not going to eat our seed corn by devoting too much money on things we dont need now and robbing ourselves of the capacity to make sure that were prepared for future threats.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>Experimental drug to treat dwarfism speeds rate of growth by 50 per cent in children but critics still skeptical</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/Experimental+drug+treat+dwarfism+speeds+rate+growth+cent+children/11191768/story.html</Link>
        <Description>BioMarin Pharmaceutical Inc.&amp;#8217;s BMN 111 has had positive results in experimental trials, but some parents won't be treating their children with the new drug</Description>
        <MainBody>

Experimental drug to treat dwarfism speeds rate of growth by 50 per cent in children but critics still skeptical

By Bloomberg News July 6, 2015


Chelley and Dave Martinka pose with daughter Adelaide, who has the condition achondroplasia.
An experimental drug to treat dwarfism by lengthening childrens bones is meeting skepticism from the leading U.S. group that represents little people, which questions giving kids a medication that might make them less little.
Parents like Chelley Martinka, whose daughter has the condition, achondroplasia, say they have no intention of giving their children injections of BioMarin Pharmaceutical Inc.s BMN 111. That wont change even if the drug lives up to the promise of its early trials, said Martinka, who blogs about her daughters condition at A Is for Adelaide.
My daughter is incredibly smart, shes funny, she is the most loving person Ive ever met, said Martinka, who doesnt have achondroplasia.
I cant ask for anything else. To do something superficial, to give her a couple of inches, its ridiculous.
BioMarin is betting it can persuade parents to embrace the drugs potential to add height and avert health issues that come with the genetic disorder. The medicine will be a hot topic at the annual meeting of Little People of America, which starts Friday in St. Louis.
Leaders in the organization are talking regularly with San Rafael, California-based BioMarin. They worry the drug is being presented as a way to address an affliction.
Just because a person has achondroplasia doesnt mean they are going to have health issues, said Gary Arnold, the groups president, who encourages new parents to get to know others in the community. This drug might be right for some people, but we also think its important to get across the message that its not necessary to live a healthy and productive life.
The average man with achondroplasia grows to a height of 131 centimeters, or 4 feet 4 inches, while the average woman with the condition reaches 4 feet 1 inch. The condition arises from a mutation in the FGFR3 gene, which produces a protein that inhibits the formation of bone from cartilage. The mutation makes the protein overly active, which researchers believe limits bone development.
BMN 111 is a man-made version of a natural peptide that can spur bone growth. BioMarins drug, also called vosoritide, boosted the speed of growth by as much as 50 percent in the first study of children with the condition, the company reported last month. That translated to almost an extra inch of height a year.
BioMarin shares jumped 12 percent the following day. The company estimates there are 24,000 children under age 18 in its potential patient population. If the drug is effective for children across that age range, that would create a market of as much as $1.8 billion a year, estimated Robyn Karnauskas, an analyst at Deutsche Bank, in a presentation to clients. Michael Yee, an analyst at RBC Capital Markets, estimates that BioMarin could charge $300,000 for the drug, which would be the companys biggest product.
The study involved just 26 children with an average age of 7.8 years, with the 10 getting the highest dose seeing the most benefit. There was no placebo comparison, so the trial didnt examine how they fared compared to children getting no treatment.
Theres no evidence so far that the therapy made the proportions of the childrens bodies more like an average persons. And theres no way to know if the accelerated growth would stop, a potential problem since other drugs tested to treat the condition have been difficult to control.
If its proven to be safe, I dont think any average- height person with a baby is going to say no.
A final study of BMN 111 will probably involve 50 to 100 patients treated for six to 12 months, according to BioMarin. That may not be enough time to show if it helps children avoid serious health complications or if long-term use comes with side effects or potential harm.
Vosoritide may do more than just increase height, said Henry Fuchs, BioMarins chief medical officer. Kids who grow more normally could avoid some of the side effects of achondroplasia, such as a curved spine, he said.
The stunted growth can lead to a host of complications, including neurological and breathing problems, when the spinal cord, tonsils and other unaffected tissue grows faster than the surrounding bone, said Melita Irving, the lead investigator of BioMarins trial and a consultant in clinical genetics at the Guys and St. Thomas hospital system in London.
If it works, the drug could replace lengthy, painful and expensive surgeries to break and stretch bones. The process, which takes months, is currently the only option in a quest for longer limbs and better function.
If its proven to be safe, I dont think any average- height person with a baby is going to say no, said Kristina Gray, the mother of a 4-year-old boy with achondroplasia in Warwickshire, England. I see this as giving my son a better quality of life.
Bloomberg
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>Over two dozen people with ties to India’s $1-billion exam scam have died mysteriously in recent months</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Over+dozen+people+with+ties+India+billion+exam+scam+have+died/11191722/story.html</Link>
        <Description>A television journalist covering the scandal, which has implicated medical schools, bureaucrats and even a governor, is the latest casualty</Description>
        <MainBody>

Ashish Chaturvedi is a whistleblower in one of the largest corruption investigation in central India -- a murky, multimillion dollar corruption racket, which involved rampant rigging of tests for medical schools and government jobs. The accused and witnesses are dying mysteriously, baffling investigators. Chaturvedi has been attacked 14 times and here is seen with the court-assigned police constable.
GWALIOR, India  Nobody knows exactly when or why the witnesses and small-time crooks caught up in one of Indias biggest corruption scandals began dying under mysterious circumstances. But in the past two years, thats whats happened to more than two dozen people implicated in a $1 billion test-rigging scheme.
Even by standards in India, where corruption is routine, the scale of the scam in the central state of Madhya Pradesh is mind-boggling. Police say that since 2007, tens of thousands of students and job aspirants have paid hefty bribes to middlemen, bureaucrats and politicians to rig test results for medical schools and government jobs.
So far, 1,930 people have been arrested and more than 500 are on the run. Hundreds of medical students are in prison  along with several bureaucrats and the states education minister. Even the governor has been implicated.
Police have had their hands full racing to meet a July deadline in the criminal probe. And now they are faced with the deaths of more witnesses and suspects. In the past week, police said, one of those accused died after having chest pains in prison, another drowned in a village pond and a third died of a liver infection.
On Saturday, television reporter Akshay Singh died while investigating a suspects death. Singh sipped tea during an interview and began coughing and foaming at the mouth, according to media reports. He was rushed to the hospital, where doctors said he had suffered a heart attack. Police said the initial examination did not reveal anything suspicious.
(5/7/15) Candle light vigil demanding justice for late journalist Akshay Singh held in Varanasi pic.twitter.com/lSdKjTgbC7
 ANI (@ANI_news) July 6, 2015
The states government, run by the Bharatiya Janata Party, has said that no conspiracy was found in the recent deaths. But others involved in the case fear otherwise. The states chief minister, Shivraj Singh Chouhan, said on Sunday that his mind is in agony and pain and promised that all the deaths will be investigated.
The police say they keep coming up against a wall in their investigation every time someone is found dead, said Chandresh Bhushan, chairman of the special investigation team that was appointed by the state court to monitor the police probe. We ask them, Why are so many dying in road accidents in this case? Does this have any link to the scam? There is no evidence of a link yet, but we cannot overrule it, either.
Cheating on school and college tests is commonplace in India. A few months ago, photographs of parents hanging precariously from school windows to throw cheat sheets to their children caused nationwide outrage.
But in Madhya Pradesh, cheating on tests became a sophisticated racket using various approaches. High-scoring students from around the country toting fake identity cards were brought in to impersonate applicants taking tests. Applicants would be told to leave their answer sheets blank so that scorers could fill them out in a separate room. And scores would be manipulated by testing board officials to favour bribe-paying candidates.
There is so much information with the investigators that it could bring the government down
In July 2013, after a tip-off from whistleblowers, police raided a test center in Indore and arrested eight impersonators taking the medical school test. Police say that the scheme was operated by a syndicate of agents, doctors, officials and politicians across five states and that there was no single ringleader.
There is so much information with the investigators that it could bring the government down, said Ashish Chaturvedi, 26, one of the whistleblowers. He has been attacked 14 times by unknown assailants, he said. Six of the assaults took place in front of a police officer assigned by a court to protect him last year.
But so far they have just gone after students, middlemen and lower officials, Chaturvedi said. They are not even probing the roles of the big fish in the state.
One of the most complex, multi-layered scandals affecting public life in Indiais fast acquiring the shades of a macabre crime thriller
The news portal the Wire called the scam one of the most complex, multi-layered scandals affecting public life in India, one that is fast acquiring the shades of a macabre crime thriller.
Many of the mysteriously dead are young  either students who paid money and made it into medical schools or job aspirants trying to take tests to become police officers, school teachers, forest rangers and food inspectors.
Some of the accused, called racketeers in police files, have died from poison. Others died in freak road accidents, or by consuming too much alcohol, or by hanging. One medical college dean died in a fire. A medical student was found dead on railway tracks. The son of the state governor was found dead at his fathers home in March, ostensibly from a brain hemorrhage.
Last week, Narendra Singh Tomar, a 29-year-old veterinarian who was in prison on charges of arranging impersonators for medical school applicants, complained of chest pain, police said, and died soon after in a hospital. His family told reporters that they suspected Tomar was murdered.
#BREAKING | Vyapam scam accused Narendra Singh Tomar dies, 24th death in the case | Read: http://t.co/0i3pg7SlwM pic.twitter.com/1aaI1VDRLo
 The Indian Express (@IndianExpress) June 28, 2015
A day later, a 40-year-old assistant professor at a medical college, Rajendra Arya, who was out on bail after being charged in the case, died of a heart attack.
My father had switched his cellphone off for the last six days, said Rahul Arya, his 18-year-old son. He was getting some calls that caused a lot of stress to him. If indeed there (is) no foul play in these deaths, someone needs to ask why so many people are dying of natural causes in this case.
Everybody was making money, said Vivek Tankha, a lawyer representing the whistleblowers in the Supreme Court. It is no wonder that we are now witnessing one of the biggest coverup operations in Indian corruption history.
Bribes for admission to medical schools ranged from $15,000 to $40,000.
On a recent sultry morning, Chaturvedi, the whistleblower, rode his bicycle down the narrow lane in Gwalior, followed by a police constable on another cycle, sweating and panting. The guard is supposed to trail him wherever he goes, but sometimes the officer fails to show up.
I worry about my safety because my task is not finished yet, Chaturvedi said as he pedaled. If I am not careful now, my whole battle of the last five years will go to waste.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>Miss Universe Paulina Vega refuses to give up crown despite condemnation from Donald Trump</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Miss+Universe+Paulina+Vega+refuses+give+crown+despite/11192468/story.html</Link>
        <Description>'It doesn't make any sense that Donald Trump calls me a hypocrite because I'm not giving up my crown'</Description>
        <MainBody>Miss Universe Paulina Vega refuses to give up crown despite condemnation from Donald Trump

By The Associated Press July 6, 2015


Miss Universe Paulina Vega, from Colombia, jokingly sticks her tongue out at photographers.
BOGOTA, Colombia  The reigning Miss Universe has refused to relinquish her crown despite a tide of condemnation following pageant owner Donald Trumps remarks on Mexican immigrants.
Paulina Vega on Monday said she would continue doing the organizations social work and dismissed Trumps accusation that she is a hypocrite for condemning his recent comments but declining to step down as Miss Universe.
The fact that I am not giving up my crown doesnt mean that I am changing my stance about everything I said, the Colombian beauty said in her native country during an interview with radio station La W. It doesnt make any sense that Donald Trump calls me a hypocrite because Im not giving up my crown.
In his June presidential campaign announcement, Trump said that some Mexican immigrants to the U.S. bring drugs and crime, and some are rapists.
On Sunday, a few days after Vega called his remarks unjust and hurtful, Trump tweeted: Miss Universe, Paulina Vega, criticized me for telling the truth about illegal immigration, but then said she would keep the crown  Hypocrite.
As a Colombian and as Miss Universe, I want to show my support and validate the sentiments of the Latin community, Vega had said on her Instagram account last week.
Vega, 22, won the 2014 Miss Universe pageant last January in Miami.
Pressure on her to quit has increased over the past several days, with Colombia retiring its bid to host the event and Mexico announcing that it wont be sending any candidate to the competition.
Univision also cut its ties with Trump and all of his enterprises, and Colombian superstar Shakira, in reference to the tycoons comments, tweeted that no one living in this century should stand behind so much ignorance.
Vega, born in Barranquilla, stressed to the radio station that the Miss Universe pageant existed long before Trump acquired it and that it will continue to exist if he stops being its owner someday.
I have kept doing my job as Miss Universe all these days. The work continues as always despite all this craziness going on, she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>The pot taboo is breaking for U.S. presidential candidates</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/taboo+breaking+presidential+candidates/11192326/story.html</Link>
        <Description>'When I was growing up, it was political suicide for a candidate to talk about pot being legal'</Description>
        <MainBody>The pot taboo is breaking for U.S. presidential candidates

By The Associated Press July 6, 2015



In this photograph taken Tuesday, June 30, 2015, Republican presidential hopeful Sen. Rand Paul of Kentucky speaks during a campaign stop at a sports bar in the Cherry Creek area in Denver. Earlier in the day, Paul made a stop at a cannabis industry convention in downtown Denver to speak to people in the marijuana industry behind closed doors. Presidential candidates are talking about marijuana in ways unimaginable not long ago.
DENVER Presidential candidates are talking about marijuana in ways unimaginable not long ago.
White House hopefuls in both parties are taking donations from people in the new marijuana industry, which is investing heavily in political activism as a route to expanded legalization and landed its first major candidate, Rand Paul, at a trade show last month.
Several Republicans, like Democrats, are saying they wont interfere with states that are legalizing a drug still forbidden under federal law. And at conservative policy gatherings, Republicans are discussing whether drug sentences should be eased.
A quarter century after Bill Clinton confessed he tried marijuana but insisted I didnt inhale, the taboo against marijuana is shrinking at the highest level of politics, just as it appears to be with the public.
When I was growing up, it was political suicide for a candidate to talk about pot being legal, said Tim Cullen, owner of Colorado Harvest Co., a chain of medical and recreational marijuana dispensaries.
Cullen attended a Hillary Rodham Clinton fundraiser in New Mexico last month and talked to the Democratic candidate about her position on legalizing pot.
Shes not outwardly hostile to the idea, which is a big step forward, Cullen said. Shes willing to openly talk about it at least.
A slim majority of Americans, 53 percent, said in a Pew Research Center survey in March that the drug should be legal. As recently as 2006, less than a third supported marijuana legalization in another measure of public opinion, the General Social Survey.
Politicians are shifting, but slowly.
Republican candidates Jeb Bush, Ted Cruz and Rick Perry are among those who say states should decide marijuana laws, even as they brand legalization a bad idea. In June, Paul became the first major-party presidential candidate to hold a fundraiser with the new marijuana industry, courting about 40 donors in Denver.
But the Kentucky senator used a private back door, and aides erected a screen so photographers couldnt see the candidate standing by a green Cannabis Business Summit sign. Paul didnt talk about pot at a public meet-and-greet afterward.
A few days earlier in the same building, six other GOP presidential contenders talked to about 4,000 people at a gathering of Western conservatives. There, Perry defended the right of states to change marijuana laws, even if they foul it up.
Colorado comes to mind, the former Texas governor said, to laughs and applause. I defend the right of Colorado to be wrong on that issue.
Altogether, 23 states and the District of Columbia are flouting federal law by allowing marijuana use for medical or recreational purposes.
Not all candidates say leave it to the states. New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie and former Pennsylvania Sen. Rick Santorum say they would fight to roll back marijuana legalization efforts in states such as Colorado.
Democrats are generally less critical of states legalizing pot, but theyre treading carefully, too.
Clinton said last year that more research needed to be done on marijuanas medical value, but there should be availability under appropriate circumstances. She didnt elaborate what those circumstances should be.
As for her main Democratic rival, Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders sounds lukewarm about legalization, despite his counterculture roots and liberal social views. He told Yahoo News that pot should be decriminalized but he was not ready to go beyond that. He said he smoked pot twice in the old days and coughed a lot.
Bush and Cruz have also acknowledged using marijuana in their youth, as has President Barack Obama.
Marijuana entrepreneurs say even tepid support for legalization is a step forward, and theyre opening their wallets in hopes of seeing more change.
The largest marijuana lobbying group, Marijuana Policy Project, plans to donate tens of thousands to 2016 presidential candidates. Executive Director Rob Kampia was among those at the Denver pot fundraiser.
We wouldnt have heard a presidential candidate talking that way four years ago, Kampia said. Attendees said Paul talked about changing federal drug-sentencing laws but stopped short of calling for nationwide legalization.
Its unclear how much money the marijuana industry will spend on the presidential race. Many pot-business owners dont list their businesses on campaign-finance disclosure forms, given the drugs federal illegality. And some marijuana activists are likely to spend not on the presidential contest but on campaigns in the six to 10 states likely to have some sort of marijuana policy on ballots next year.
Still, the presidential race appears certain to include more talk of marijuana policy than before.
There are a lot of loose bricks in the walls of resistance to changing drug laws in America, said William Martin, who studies drug policy at Rice University. Its no longer a silly question, legalizing marijuana.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>Aaden Moreno, a seven-month-old boy, disappears after his suicidal father leaps from bridge into Connecticut River</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Aaden+Moreno+month+disappears+after+suicidal+father+leaps/11192060/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Family who called 9-11 believed the man had his baby with him on the bridge. When officers arrived, they saw the man jump, but did not see a child with him as he fell</Description>
        <MainBody>

Aaden Moreno, a seven-month-old boy, disappears after his suicidal father leaps from bridge into Connecticut River

By Jake Edmiston July 6, 2015



Aaden Moreno, the seven-month-old boy who went missing after his father jumped from a Connecticut bridge on Sunday night.
Police are searching the Connecticut River for a seven-month-old infant after his father leapt from a bridge on Sunday night.
Tony Moreno, 22, was threatening to jump from the Arrigoni Bridge in Middletown, Conn., around 11:45 p.m. Sunday, according to a police statement.
Family who called 9-11 believed the man had his baby, Aaden Moreno, with him on the bridge, said Lt. Heather Desmond, a Middletown police spokesperson.
The father was caring for the child that night, she said.
When officers arrived, they saw the Moreno jump, but did not see his child with him as he fell. Police rescued the man, but have yet to find the infant. The father is in hospital in serious condition and is not able to speak with investigators, Desmond said.
Police, dive teams and canine units are scouring the river and the nearby forest. Investigators are also contacting the fathers family and friends, to see if he left the boy in someone elses care.
Aaden was last seen wearing a black- and white-striped Mickey Mouse t-shirt.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>Tories, NDP use situation in Greece to spar over economic credentials</title>
        <Link>http://news.nationalpost.com/news/world/tories-ndp-use-situation-in-greece-to-spar-over-economic-credentials</Link>
        <Description>Economists say the threat to Canada&amp;#8217;s economy from the situation in Greece is minimal because many European banks have unloaded their Greek debt</Description>
        <MainBody>StumbleUpon
OTTAWA  The governing Conservatives say questions surrounding Greeces future in the Eurozone after that country rejected the terms of a bailout agreement are reason to re-elect the Tories in the fall vote.
In a statement released Monday, a spokesman for Prime Minister Stephen Harper highlighted three-year-old comments from NDP Leader Tom Mulcair about his belief the government should have given money to a global fund to prop up faltering European banks.
The statement also questioned Liberal support for the same plan put forward by the International Monetary Fund and G20 nations, which the Conservatives ultimately turned down.
The NDP put out a statement as well Monday afternoon, questioning the Conservative record on the economy, highlighting that Canadas GDP has shrunk for four consecutive months.
Economists say the threat to Canadas economy from the situation in Greece is minimal because many European banks have unloaded their Greek debt.
In a research note to clients, BMO economists say the European Central Bank has enough firepower to ensure there is no meaningful contagion from the problems in Greece.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>Pope Francis emphasizes love, family and grace at Ecuador mass attended by hundreds of thousands of faithful</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/More+than+million+faithful+expected+gather+Pope+Francis+mass/11191684/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Hours before Pope Francis arrives in Ecuador's port city of Guayaquil, thousands are already waiting in the Samanes Park where the pope is expected to celebrate mass</Description>
        <MainBody>

Pope Francis emphasizes love, family and grace at Ecuador mass attended by hundreds of thousands of faithful

By The Associated Press July 6, 2015



Hundreds of thousands of people filled a park in Ecuadors main port city Monday for Pope Francis first big event of his three-nation South American tour, hoping for a glimpse of Latin Americas first pope returning to his home soil for a mass dedicated to the family.
Many pilgrims spent the night outdoors, and some walked for miles to reach the park on Guayaquils northern outskirts where the crowd sang hymns and sought pockets of shade to keep cool amid the scorching sun and high humidity. Firefighters sprayed them with water hoses to provide relief.
Im tired. Im hungry, I havent slept but Im also full of emotion and joy in my heart, said Vicente Huilcatoma, a 47-year-old retired police officer who walked 40 kilometres to reach Samanes Park.
The Vatican had originally estimated more than 1 million people would turn out for the mass, and government organizers put the crowd at above 1 million people in the hour before the service began. But Gabriel Almeida, the government spokesman at the scene, rolled back the estimate to several hundred thousand after officials viewed aerial images of the area.
Across the park, Ecuadoran national flags and papal banners waved above the enormous sea of people, who were divided into quadrants that Francis looped around slowly on his popemobile to cheers of Francisco! Francisco!
In his homily, Francis praised families as the bedrock of society  the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly  and said miracles are performed every day inside a family out of love. But he said sometimes the love and happiness runs out.
How many women, sad and lonely, wonder when love left, when it slipped away from their lives? he asked. How many elderly people feel left out of family celebrations, cast aside and longing each day for a little love?
Francis has dedicated the first two years of his pontificate to family issues, giving weekly catechism lessons on different aspects of family life and inviting the entire church to study ways to provide better pastoral care for Catholic families, people who are divorced, gays and families in nontraditional situations.
A preliminary meeting of bishops on these issues ended last year in bitter divisions between liberals and conservatives, particularly over ministering to gays and to Catholics who divorce and remarry outside of the church. Church teaching holds that Catholics who enter into a second marriage without having the first one annulled cannot receive Communion.
In his homily Monday, Francis said he hoped the second meeting of bishops on family life, scheduled for October, would come up with concrete solutions to the many difficult and significant challenges facing families in our time.
I ask you to pray fervently for this intention, so that Christ can take even what might seem to us impure, scandalous or threatening, and turn it  into a miracle.
Families today need miracles! he added.
The Vatican spokesman, the Rev. Federico Lombardi, said Francis wasnt referring to the gay or divorce issue specifically but was making a more general reference that he hoped the bishops would help the church chart this path of leaving a situation of sin to one of grace.
On his arrival in Guayaquil, the pontiff allowed several acolytes on the tarmac to take selfies with him. He then headed to the Shrine of the Divine Mercy, where 2,000 invitees gathered including child cancer patients, residents of homes for the elderly abandoned by their families and some of Guayaquils poorest people.
He told those gathered that he would pray for them and I wont charge you a thing. All I ask, please, is that you pray for me.
The crowd in Los Samanes park was festive, with young and old overjoyed at seeing the first pope in their lives.
Ill ask the pope to intercede so that God gives me my health, said 90-year-old Guillermina Aveiga Davila, who arrived at dawn from the coastal city of Chone, some 300 kilometers (about 185 miles) away. I want to reach 100.
After the open-air mass, a private lunch was planned with a group of Jesuits.
A highlight was to be a reunion with the Rev. Francisco Cortes, a priest affectionately known as Padre Paquito, to whom the Argentina-born pope, then the Rev. Jorge Mario Bergoglio, entrusted his seminarians on study trips to Ecuador years ago.
In a recent interview with The Associated Press, Cortes couldnt fathom that Bergoglio remembered him, much less made a point of coming to have lunch.
I dont know what to ask him, the soon-to-be 91-year-old Cortes said. He said he wanted to see me and Im amazed that hes coming. For the first time, I have known a pope.
The pope of the poor returned to Spanish-speaking South America for the first time as pontiff Sunday, stressing the importance of protecting the needy and the environment from exploitation and  in a nation whose president was booed as his vehicle followed the papal motorcade Sunday  to foster dialogue among all sectors of society. Its a message hes expected to repeat during his next stops in Bolivia and Paraguay, South Americas two poorest countries.
Francis only other trip back to Latin America since being elected pope was in 2013, when he visited Brazil, where Portuguese is the main language.
Francis environmental message  from a pope who last month issued a treatise staking the Earths preservation as a core mission for humanity  is particularly relevant for Ecuador, a Pacific nation that is home to one of the worlds most species-diverse ecosystems but is also an OPEC country heavily dependent on oil. High crude prices allowed Correa to lift 1.3 million people out of poverty in his eight years in office.
But now that prices have fallen, the generous social safety net Correa has woven is threatened. Hes had to cut government spending and been buffeted for nearly a month by the most serious anti-government street protests of his tenure.
Along Francis motorcade route, the crowds alternated chants of adulation for the pontiff with jeers of Correa out! when the presidents entourage followed.
Correa also has angered environmentalists and the nations main indigenous group, CONAIE, by moving forward with oil drilling and mining projects in pristine Amazon forests.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>Could the Philae lander have found life on the comet that’s hurtling it through our solar system?</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Could+Philae+lander+have+found+life+comet+that+hurtling/11191997/story.html</Link>
        <Description>But the European Space Agency team that sent the lander on its fact-finding journey don't think it's the right place to look, nor is Philae equipped to find out</Description>
        <MainBody>

A Euopean Space Agency photo shows the point of final touchdown, during Philae's descent from Rosetta. Some researchers believe there might be life on the comet Philae latched onto last year.
The Philae lander that latched on to a comet hundreds of thousands of kilometres away could have found signs of extraterrestrial life,a pair of British researchers argue.
Philae is part of the exploratory Rosetta mission, which was launched over two decades ago to help scientists better understand comets, their role in the formation of our solar system, as well as the galaxy and our universe.
The lander detached from the Rosetta space craft late last year andattached itself toComet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, the first time humans successfully landed spacecraft on a comet.
That comet could be a prime site for tiny, microbial life, a pair of astronomerssaid during the Royal Astronomical Societys National Astronomy Meeting this week in Wales. Cardiff University Professor Chandra Wickramasinghe helped with the early stages of planning for Philae and the Rosetta spacecraft that carried it out into our galaxy.
What were saying is that data coming from the comet seems to unequivocally, in my opinion, point to micro-organisms being involved in the formation of the icy structures, the preponderance of aromatic hydrocarbons, and the very dark surface,Wickramasinghe said, according to a Sky News report . These are not easily explained in terms of pre-biotic chemistry.
He wanted to include instruments to examine the comet for microbial life, which would be similar to the  extremophile  bacteria that lives in extreme conditions on earth, like deep ocean hydrothermal events, he told The Guardian newspaper . Wickramasinghe is one of many theorists who believe life on Earth may have begun when such microbes were introduced to the planet on a comet, and believes Philae should have been set up to look for the tiny organisms.
But the scientists who executed the jaw-dropping feat of landing Philae on a comet travelling 135,000 kilometres an hour nearly 500 million kilometres away arent so sure. They scoff at the notion Philae could find aliens, even teeny, tiny microbial ones.
The Daily Telegraph reports Rosetta project scientist Matt Taylor dismissed the claims, saying Its pure speculation I think it is unlikely.
Wickramasinghes work has previously fallen short underscrutiny, Popular Mechanics notes in a piece debunking the claim Philae could be home to life.
Is there any news from @Philae2014 on Comet #67P ? Video update from the LCC:  (FW) #Philae #Rosetta pic.twitter.com/7tENTWrAd1
 DLR  English (@DLR_en) July 6, 2015
The Philae lander recently woke up after months of hibernation when the comets orbit moved closeenough tothe Sun for Philaes solar panels to gobble up sufficient energy to send back a signal. A test on Sunday to renew that contact failed, but European Space Agency scientists expect to try again on Thursday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>Albino children locked away to keep them safe from witch doctors who claim their body parts bring good fortune</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Albino+children+locked+away+keep+them+safe+from+witch+doctors/11191795/story.html</Link>
        <Description>At least 75 kids and adults with albinism have been killed in Tanzania since 2000 and more than 62 have escaped with severe injuries following the witch doctors&amp;#8217; attacks</Description>
        <MainBody>

Baraka Cosmas Rusambo, 6 years old with albinism from Tanzania, is treated at Global Medical Relief Fund and Shriners Hospital for Children in Philadelphia on Wednesday, June 17, 2015.  In March, assailants lopped off the right hand of Rusambo.  Tanzanians subscribing to superstition see those with albino complexions as demons or ghosts with mystical powers whose body parts are cut off and used in witchcraft and potions.
It was from neighbours that Scola Joseph first heard of two strange men in the village asking after her children. She knew immediately the moment she dreaded had come.
Packing small bags for Elijah, 3, and Christine, 5, she led them away from their home and towards the nearest town, to a government camp where hundreds others like them were living under protection. It was the only way to keep them alive.
Buhangija is one of nine such centres in Tanzania. This is where the countrys endangered class ofalbinochildren are moved in an attempt to keep them safe from witch doctors, who claim their body parts, ground up and put in charms, can bring wealth and fortune.
Separated from their families and forced to largely stay indoors because of the effects on their skin of the east African sun, they sleep three or four to a bed. They survive on basic food rationed by their head teacher because of erratic government funding.
These children are living like refugees and its shameful, said Peter Ajali, the headteacher. I try to take the part of the parents and love them and keep them safe but its not humanitarian for them to live like this.
Albinism, caused by a lack of pigmentation in their skin, hair and eyes, affects about one in 20,000 people worldwide, but is for unknown reasons more common in sub-Saharan Africa and Tanzania particularly, where it claims one in 1,400.
At least 75 children and adults with albinism have been killed here since 2000 and more than 62 others have escaped with severe injuries following the witch-doctors attacks.
With witch-doctors paying as much as $75,000 for a full set of body parts, which they bury or grind up to keep in charms, some of those implicated in the killings are members of the victims own families. The UN warned recently of a marked increase in attacks onalbinos, which it said were at greater risk with the approach of national and local elections in October. The fear is unscrupulous politicians will turn to the traditions of the witch-doctors, known as mganga, and their ambitious promises.
The government has arrested 200 witch-doctors and this month a home affairs minister told MPs that murderingalbinos would never win them their seats. Orders have gone out to the provinces to safeguard people with albinism in their communities. With scant resources, their answer has been to herd them into camps.
At Buhangija in the northern town of Shinyanga, the numbers ofalbinochildren arriving at what was originally a primary school for children with special needs has risen from 170 last year to 295 at present. Many more are expected in the coming months.
They join 64 deaf pupils already at the cash-strapped centre, and a further 40 who are blind.
Buhangija was built with boarding space for 40 children. Its headteacher has been forced to turn the library, outhouses and a half-built classroom into more dormitories. Inside, metal bunks stacked three-high are topped with foam mattresses and tatty sheets, and children sleep three or four to a bed.
Aged as young as two and as old as 25, they spend their time outside classes playing football with rolled plastic bags and sitting talking on the dusty ground. Visitors are quickly encircled and clutched at by the little hands of those eager for a moment of the affection they are now forced to go without.
Scola Joseph comes to see her children each month and stays for several days but the majority of parents leave their children and never come back.
Ajali saidalbinochildren were still seen as a curse. Many womens families make them leave after they are born, he said. We ask members of the local community to come and greet our children because they lack love and it makes them feel better.
Mary Mabula, 15, was sent to the centre in 2010 and hasnt seen her mother, father or siblings since. Asked if she misses them, she ducks her head and whispers yes.
Her parents said the centre was the only place she would be safe. People used to say to me: Youre the one who can make us rich, she said.
The threats are not empty. A month ago, a 30-year-old woman had her right arm severed below the elbow by two men who broke into the hut where she was sleeping with her four children.
In March, a woman trying to shield her one and three-year-old children suffered machete injuries inflicted by five men. The baby boys limbless torso was found days later in a nearby forest. His father was arrested.
The potential value of Buhangijas 295 occupants means armed police join private security guards from dusk until dawn. Unable to leave the dusty compound, Mary concentrates on reading and dreams of becoming a doctor. I hope I can go home one day, she said.
Among the centres supporters is Under The Same Sun, a charity set up by a Canadian man with albinism. Martin Haule, a trained accountant and teacher who heads its educational projects, said: Even people who have albinism do not understand that its just about the skin. They too believe they are somehow not fully human.
January Makamba, a candidate vying to take over from President Jakaya Kikwete, said a better solution had to be found for people with albinism to live safely in Tanzania.
Its an embarrassment to this country that we have to keep them in camps like this, he said. Its true some of those who procure body parts operate at the highest levels of society. These are deep-seated beliefs and we must confront them as a nation.
The SundayTelegraph
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>Princess Charlotte’s christening was filled with tributes to her late grandmother, Princess Diana</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/Princess+Charlotte+christening+filled+with+tributes+late/11191833/story.html</Link>
        <Description>From the choice of godparents to the choice of music, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge made sure the memory of Diana was centre-stage</Description>
        <MainBody>
The day belonged to Princess Charlotte, but the inspiration was pure Diana, Princess of Wales.
From the choice of godparents to the choice of music, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge made sure the memory of Princess Charlottes late grandmother was centre-stage.
Having chosen to hold their daughters christening at the church of St. Mary Magdalene, Sandringham, where the Princess of Wales was baptized, the couple chose Dianas niece, Laura Fellowes, as one of five godparents named on the day.
And that was only the start of the homage to the Dukes late mother, whose name, of course, would be one of those with which two-month-old Charlotte was christened.
The music included Vaughan Williamss Prelude on Rhosymedre, used at their wedding as processional music and in the wedding of the Prince and Princess of Wales in 1981.
Even Prince Georges outfit evoked memories of the grandmother he never met. His red shorts and embroidered white shirt were the nearest possible matches for the outfit worn by Prince William when he was taken to see his mother and newborn brother Prince Harry in hospital in 1984. Kensington Palace confirmed it was no coincidence.
On an occasion otherwise laden with tradition, the Duke and Duchess sprang a surprise with their choice of godparents. No member of the Royal family made it on to an informal list of friends and relatives. The Dukes cousin Ms. Fellowes and the Duchesss cousin Adam Middleton were joined by Thomas van Straubenzee and James Meade, school friends of the Duke who made speeches at his wedding, and the Duchesss friend Sophie Carter.
Princesses Beatrice and Eugenie, favourites to be chosen, did not even make it to the ceremony as only close family, godparents and their spouses were invited. Speculation that Princess Beatrice missed out because of a supposed clash of personalities between the Duke and her boyfriend Dave Clark will only gather pace.
From then on, it was a classically stage-managed royal occasion. The Duke and Duchess walked from Sandringham House to the church, with the Duchess pushing Princess Charlotte in a Millsons pram used by the Queen for her two youngest children, Princes Andrew and Edward.
They were joined by just 20 people, excluding the organist and choir. The Queen, the Duke of Edinburgh, the Prince of Wales and Duchess of Cornwall were the only other Royal family members; the Middletons were represented by the Duchesss parents Michael and Carole and siblings Pippa and James. Apart from the five godparents and four spouses (Miss Carter is single) the only others were those doing a job: the Archbishop of Canterbury, the Most Rev Justin Welby, who conducted the christening, the Rev Canon Jonathan Riviere, Rector of the Sandringham group of parishes, and Prince Georges nanny Maria Borrallo.
In his homily the Archbishop referred to one of Princess Charlottes ancestors, the Grand Duchess Elizabeth, who was sainted and buried in the Holy Land after being murdered by the Bolsheviks in Russia in 1918. A grandmother of Queen Victoria, she sold her possessions to found a charity in Moscow and joined a convent. The Archbishop spoke of her beauty of character, and referred to families of the 30 British victims of the Tunisia terror attack needing such lives of beauty around them.
The Duke and Duchess chose the hymns Praise to the Lord, The Almighty and Come Down, O Love Divine, and Mr Meade read the lesson from Matthew 18, verses 1-5.
The baptism itself was carried out using water brought to Norfolk from the River Jordan, where Christ was baptised, and using the Lily Font, part of the Crown Jewels brought from the Tower of London, where it has been kept since 1841, when it was first used for Queen Victorias eldest daughter Princess Victoria. Princess Charlottes christening robe also owed its design to Princess Victoria; her silk and lace robe was used for every royal baby for 163 years until it was deemed too fragile in 2004 and replaced with a replica.
After the half-hour service guests retired to Sandringham for afternoon tea, including christening cake taken from a tier of the Duke and Duchesss wedding cake. There was a last nod to the Princess of Wales as her favourite photographer, Mario Testino, took the official photographs, to be released this week.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>This is real life: Robotics company Cyberdyne introducing ‘service’ robots with artificial intelligence</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/This+real+life+Robotics+company+Cyberdyne+introducing+service/11191778/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Under the Japanese national robot strategy announced in January, the government aims to enlarge the market size to 2.4 trillion yen (about $19.6 billion) in 2020</Description>
        <MainBody>
The real-life Cyberdyne isn't producing world-destroying Terminator robots like its movie namesake  yet.
TOKYO  More and more Japanese companies are developing robots for the service industry, as demand is expected to rise among non-manufacturers who want robots for such physical work as nursing care and transporting luggage.
Demand for such robots is likely to be on par with that for industrial robots widely used in manufacturing. The government aims to promote the use of robots as a solution for the countrys labor shortage amid the graying population.
Cyberdyne, an emerging robot development firm based in Tsukuba, Japan, said Thursday it will introduce artificial intelligence-aided cleaning robots and porter robots for passengers at Haneda Airports terminals.
The robots will know their own position at the airport and automatically move around the facility if their destination information is input in advance, avoiding people and obstacles.
For human workers at the airport, power-assisted suit-type robots will be introduced to help them carry heavy luggage. Under a lease contract between the airport operator and Cyberdyne, 11 robots will be installed at the passenger terminals by September.
Were providing technologies that will change the airport staffs ways of working, Cyberdyne Chief Executive Officer Yoshiyuki Sankai said proudly.
Wearable robots are believed to be gaining popularity in the nonmanufacturing sector, as they reduce the physical burden on workers in charge of such tasks as transporting luggage and nursing care.
Activelink, a Nara-based subsidiary of Panasonic, announced Thursday that its power-assist suit-type robot for mass production will go on sale from September. The company minimized the robots weight by making the body with carbon fiber. The firm plans to aggressively market the product to logistics operators and construction companies.
Some robots produced for the service sector can communicate with people. In June, SoftBank Group started marketing Pepper, a robot that can be used for corporate promotion activities such as handing out packs of tissues on the street, in addition to family tasks. A Toshiba robot developed last year uses sign language for those with difficulty hearing.
Under the national robot strategy announced in January, the government aims to enlarge the market size to 2.4 trillion yen (about $19.6 billion) in 2020 from the current 660 billion yen. For non-manufacturers  including service providers, and medical treatment and nursing care service providers  the government forecasts sharp market growth to 1.2 trillion yen from the current figure of 60 billion yen.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>Sex on the beach conviction could see Florida man sent to prison for 15 years</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/beach+conviction+could+Florida+sent+prison+years/11191749/story.html</Link>
        <Description>Jose Caballero and 21-year-old Elissa Alvarez were convicted in May of two counts of lewd and lascivious behavior</Description>
        <MainBody>Sex on the beach conviction could see Florida man sent to prison for 15 years

By The Associated Press July 6, 2015


A beach in Manatee County
BRADENTON, Fla.  A man convicted of having sex on a Florida beach in front of families will soon learn how long he must spend in prison.
Jose Caballero is scheduled to be sentenced Monday. He faces a possible 15 years in prison, but prosecutors say they will seek 2.5 years.
He and 21-year-old Elissa Alvarez were convicted in May of two counts of lewd and lascivious behavior. They were videotaped having sex on a Manatee County beach last July in broad daylight. Witnesses testified that a 3-year-old girl saw them.
Alvarez was recently sentenced to time served. Prosecutors say they are being tougher on the 40-year-old Caballero because he previously served eight years for cocaine trafficking.
The case drew international attention because of the couples brazenness. Both must register as sex offenders.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>North Korean defector set to testify on regime’s use of humans to test biological and chemical weapons</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/North+Korean+defector+testify+regime+humans+test+biological/11191659/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The defector worked as a scientist and managed to bring a device with him containing 15 gigabytes of data about the regime's use of humans to test weapons</Description>
        <MainBody>

his undated photo released by North Korea's official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) on June 21, 2013 shows North Korean leader Kim Jong-Un (C) visiting the Namhung Youth Chemical Complex in Anju, South Pyongan.
A North Korean scientist involved in the regimes biological and chemical weapons programmes has defected, apparently with evidence of tests on human subjects.
The researcher, who has only been identified by his surname, Lee, was based at a microbiology research centre in Ganggye, near the Chinese border, but defected on June 6, South Koreas Yonhap news agency reported.
Lee, 47, fled to Finland via the Philippines, according to a group that campaigns for human rights in North Korea.
He was carrying an electronic data storage device allegedly containing 15 gigabytes of information on the use of humans by Kim Jong-uns regime to test biological and chemical weapons.
He plans to give testimony to the European Parliament this month to highlight the Norths abuse of its own people, the rights group said.
There have been similar reports in the past. Im Cheon-yong, an officer in North Koreas special forces, defected in the mid-1990s, telling South Korean intelligence officials that the final straw was seeing mentally and physically disabled children being used in chemical weapons tests as part of his training.
For the biological and chemical warfare tests, we needed objects, he said in an interview last year.
At first, they used the chemical agents on mice and showed us how they died. Then we watched the instructors carrying out the tests on humans to show us how a person dies. I saw it with my own eyes.
Im said tests were conducted at three or more facilities operated by the military, including one alongside a political prison camp close to the city of Hyanghari. Anthrax was frequently tested, along with as many as 40 chemical weapons that the regime had concocted itself.
In February, South Korean intelligence warned that Pyongyang had stepped up biological and chemical warfare drills, carrying out at least a dozen large-scale exercises in the previous year.
A report issued last year by 38 North, a respected website operated by the US-Korea Institute at Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies, suggested that North Korea devotes substantial resources to chemical weapons.
Based on testimony from soldiers who have defected, the study claimed the regime was able to manufacture 4,500 tons of chemical agents a year, with capacity to ramp that up to 12,000 tons. The regime was producing hydrogen cyanide, phosgene, sarin, tabun, chlorine and a number of agents from the mustard gas family and had reportedly provided chemical weapons or technology to Egypt, Iran, Libya and Syria since the 1990s, it said.
Coming after United Nations investigations into North Koreas human rights abuses, Lees testimony will be closely watched.
The international community will have to collect the data and, if it can be verified that such experiments have taken place, then that would seem to violate international humanitarian law, said Daniel Pinkston, an analyst with the International Crisis Group in Seoul.
After that, it is up to the international community to do everything in its power to prevent this happening again, to terminate these programmes and to hold those responsible for carrying them out accountable, he said.
North Korea is already the subject of UN sanctions and it is not clear what further steps might be taken.
The Daily Telegraph
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>‘It started to fire on its own’: San Francisco pier attack suspect says he shot woman by mistake</title>
        <Link>http://www.vancouversun.com/news/world/started+fire+Francisco+pier+attack+suspect+says+shot+woman/11191639/story.html</Link>
        <Description>The shooting has drawn criticism of the city&amp;#8217;s sanctuary ordinance after officials revealed Sanchez has seven felony convictions and was deported five times</Description>
        <MainBody>
Francisco Sanchez
SAN FRANCISCO  A Mexican man arrested in the seemingly random fatal shooting of a woman at a San Francisco pier admitted in a jailhouse interview that he shot her, but said it was an accident.
Francisco Sanchez, 45, told KGO-TV Sunday in a mix of Spanish and English that he found a gun wrapped inside a shirt while he was sitting on a bench at the pier and smoking a cigarette.
So I picked it up and  it started to fire on its own, Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
He appeared confused and sometimes spoke incoherently during the interview, and said he has poor vision and was under the influence of sleeping pills at the time of the shooting.
All I want to say is that in the courts, I want them to give me the punishment I deserve and get it over with as soon as possible, Sanchez said during the roughly 45-minute interview.
Kathryn Steinle, 32, was gunned down while out for an evening stroll at Pier 14 with her father and a family friend on Wednesday. Police said witnesses heard no argument or dispute before the shooting, suggesting it was a random attack.
Witnesses at the popular waterfront attraction snapped photos of Sanchez immediately after the shooting, and the images helped police make the arrest while he was walking on a sidewalk a few blocks away.
The shooting has drawn national attention and criticism of the citys sanctuary ordinance after federal officials revealed that Sanchez has seven felony convictions and was deported five times to his native Mexico.
U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement had turned Sanchez over to authorities in San Francisco on March 26 on an outstanding drug warrant.
The Sheriffs Department released Sanchez on April 15 after the San Francisco district attorneys office declined to prosecute him for what authorities said was a decade-old marijuana possession case.
ICE spokeswoman Virginia Kice said the agency had issued a detainer for Sanchez, requesting notification of his release and that he stays in custody until immigration authorities could pick him up. The detainer was not honoured, she said.
Freya Horne, counsel for the San Francisco Sheriffs Department, said Friday that federal detention requests are not sufficient to hold someone. Under the citys sanctuary ordinance, people in the country illegally arent handed over to immigration officials unless theres a warrant for their arrest.
Sanchez said he returned to the U.S. after being deported because he found better-paying jobs in the country than in Mexico.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
