<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Growing support in US Congress for lifting Cuba embargo</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Growing-support-in-US-Congress-for-lifting-Cuba-embargo-26310.html</Link>
        <Description>HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- There is growing bipartisan support in the US Congress for legislation that will lift restrictions to travel and agricultural trade with Cuba, asserted Tom Udall, the Democratic senator for New Mexico, during a visit to Havana with other Democratic lawmakers.</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Growing support in US Congress for lifting Cuba embargo
Published onMay 29, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
US congressional delegation visiting Havana this week
HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- There is growing bipartisan support in the US Congress for legislation that will lift restrictions to travel and agricultural trade with Cuba, asserted Tom Udall, the Democratic senator for New Mexico, during a visit to Havana.
On a visit to Cuba with other Democratic lawmakers, Udall said in a press conference on Wednesday that the most difficult task that lies ahead in relations between the two countries is the work in Congress, which is the body that can repeal the embargo legislation.
"In the Senate we're trying to eliminate the blockade with specific legislation, such as the lifting of the travel ban and agricultural trade, among others," he pointed out, adding that he was optimistic of making progress in that direction.
"The big question is how quickly we can do it, he noted.
The majority of members of Congress, both Democrats and Republicans, support the lifting of restrictions to trips to Cuba.
He stressed that it does not mean this will happen tomorrow, while recalling that next year there will be a presidential campaign in the US, with the implications this brings.
"We are taking steps in this direction to achieve the approval of these initiatives," he specified.
Udall described as a key moment in history the process of reestablishment of bilateral relations and assured that there is support from the US people for the normalization of relations, although a lot remains to be done.
For his part, Senator Al Franken pointed out that great enthusiasm for the improvement of relations and the lifting of the embargo is apparent and confessed that he is among those in favour of eliminating this measure.
"Even in states like Florida there is great pressure for the normalization of relations with the island, although there is a small minority who has objections," he noted.
He reiterated that the majority of US citizens are in favour of reestablishing relations, but said that "in Congress we have much work ahead."
Similarly, he reiterated how beneficial the lifting of the embargo would be for an agricultural state like Minnesota  where he was elected senator  which would allow commercial exchanges.
In turn, Raul Grijalva, representative for Arizona, agreed with Udall in highlighting how impressed they were with their tour of the Zapata Swamp.
"We can work together on the issue of protected areas. Our tour of the Swamp really impressed us," he underlined.
In that sense, Udall identified two key areas where the two countries can cooperate: tourism and environmental conservation and cultural exchanges.
"We participated in the Biennial Exhibition and for the first time five Cuban artists and the same number of US creators have worked together in this meeting. Cultural exchanges are one of the ways friendship and understanding between peoples can deepen," stressed the senator from New Mexico.
For his part, John Larson, representative for Connecticut, recalled the words of President John Kennedy decades ago, when he said: "Although we cannot end our differences right now, at least we can help make the world safe for diversity. Because the final analysis is the following: our most basic common link is that we all live in this small planet; we all breathe the same air; we all cherish our children's future; and we are all mortal."
The four agreed that their stay in Cuba was very productive. The delegation has been in Havana for five days and has held several exchanges with officials of the ministries for foreign trade and investment, foreign affairs and agriculture, members of the self-employed sector, of small cooperatives, and with investors from foreign countries on the island.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Feature: Scripps Spelling Bee unites two Caribbean sisters after 15 years</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Feature%3A-Scripps-Spelling-Bee-unites-two-Caribbean-sisters-after-15-years-26311.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Feature: Scripps Spelling Bee unites two Caribbean sisters after 15 years
Published onMay 29, 2015
By Claudette de la Haye
Founder and Executive Editor
Caribbean Financial Network News
Caribbean News Now contributor
WASHINGTON, USA -- In the annual pilgrimage to the Scripps Howard National Spelling Bee to chronicle the historic efforts of four children from the extended Caribbean, namely, US Virgin Islands, Bahamas, Puerto Rico and Jamaica, this year began as usual, calling around to the various schools with the celebratory felicitations to applaud the respective headmasters, headmistresses and principals and their respective champions, as well as extracurricular accolades.
Claudette de la Haye
The phone call to St Croix, USVI took a strange turn of events. When I called and spoke to headmistress Espinoza at the Lew Muckle Elementary School in St Croix, I was informed that the school had conferred its Teacher of the Year Award on a Juliette Heddad-Miller.
My body went numb and I started to cry... In my disbelief I kept asking Mrs Espinoza to repeat the name again, and again.
I finally let out the most hysterical scream and I yelled, My Ju Ju is teacher of the year!
Headmistress Espinoza said, "Do you know the person?"
And in a sea of tears, I said, Yes, she is my sister!"
The headmistress was indeed surprised and politely turned and said, "Mrs Miller, what is the name of your sister?"
My sister replied, Claudette!
The headmistress let out a joyful, "Wow!"
Now, this is not your everyday coincidence of two women of Jamaican heritage growing up in Nottingham, England, who are contributing their God-given talents towards a better America. Not to mention the fact that the Scripps Howard National Spelling Bee has reunited us. As Juliette's big sister, I am overwhelmed with joy and proud of my sister. She is the best and at every stage of adversity she has conquered seemingly insurmountable odds.
Juliette Heddad-Miller
My little sister Juliette and I had come from at risk communities filled with prostitution in an area called Hyson Green and Forest Fields in Nottingham. We attended Manning All Girls Comprehensive School, where our racist headmistress, Margaret Clarke, sought to deny Juliette being head girl but she persevered.
Our teachers, of Jamaican and Caribbean heritage fell in line behind Mrs Clarke and the school went in uproar.
Some teachers, but not all, betrayed the entire Jamaican community and those that did not betray us as children did their best that they could for us in the community and moved on.
However, it is gratifying to see two little girls of the same mother but different fathers (Chinese and African) diverge and emerge decades later as contributing members of American society. Can you imagine me, the school angel, and Juliette, the school bully, one year apart at Stanley Junior Primary School, where a deputy head, Gary Exeter from New Zealand, challenged us as kids? It is to his credit that he turned the light on for Juliette and kept plugging away at her to get a good education.
Today, my sister Juliette has been an at risk intervention teacher in St Croix for the last six years and I am the first Caribbean and Jamaican journalist since Marcus Garvey in Detroit and the Midwest. I benchmark in automotive journalism, photography, Scripps and all things Caribbean American.
I have not seen my sister in 15 years but I think this story has a notable quality to what two people can do on a positive level in America. We bring to the table a sense of "can do attitude and passion" as well as, which is so important to children, a sense of belongingness, purpose and culture.
And if we all had that as kids the world would be a brighter place to live in.
And in a place like America the possibilities are boundless. Our late mother, Violda Dobbs, would be ecstatic to know that her daughters, her pearls", are still striving for excellence in their respective careers.
I love my sister Juliette dearly and wish her every continued success in St Croix, and that it is truly amazing grace that Scripps Spelling Bee has indeed united us once again.
Follow Claudette de la Haye on Facebook for more coverage of the Scripps Howard Spelling Bee.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former administration alleged to have embezzled $3.5 billion from Panama</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Former-administration-alleged-to-have-embezzled-%243.5-billion-from-Panama-26312.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Former administration alleged to have embezzled $3.5 billion from Panama
Published onMay 29, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Kenneth Rijock
PANAMA CITY, Panama -- The latest calculation quoted in the unfolding corruption investigation in Panama is an educated estimate that the government of former president Ricardo Martinelli embezzled at least $3.5 billion from public funds. This figure exceeds even the guesstimates previously appearing in local media.
Ricardo Martinelli
Martinelli himself came into office on a purported reform platform and many Panamanians felt that, since their new president was himself a wealthy man, the chances of corruption were slim.
However, Martinelli is now believed to have illegally enriched himself by more than a billion dollars during his presidency, now being characterized as a kleptocracy by anti-corruption prosecutors, who have charged many members of his former administration.
How far will the prosecutions go, and will there only be true reform if those in the new reform government that are themselves guilty of past corruption are themselves turned out of office and arrested?
There are those who want the current president charged for his past dark deeds, and those Panamanians also want the entire Supreme Court of Justice removed for fixing cases for bribes.
Kenneth Rijock is a banking lawyer turned-career money launderer (10 years), turned-compliance officer specialising in enhanced due diligence, and a financial crime consultant who publishes a Financial Crime Blog . The Laundry Man, his autobiography, was published in the UK on 5 July 2012.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Four more offshore banks reach resolutions with US Justice Department</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Four-more-offshore-banks-reach-resolutions-with-US-Justice-Department-26313.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Four more offshore banks reach resolutions with US Justice Department
Published onMay 29, 2015
WASHINGTON, USA -- The US Department of Justice announced on Thursday that the following four banks reached a resolution under the departments Swiss Bank Program:
 Socit Gnrale Private Banking (Lugano-Svizzera)
 MediBank AG
 LBBW (Schweiz) AG
 Scobag Privatbank AG
Todays agreements reflect the Tax Divisions continued progress towards reaching appropriate resolutions with the banks that self-reported and voluntarily entered the Swiss Bank Program, said Acting Assistant Attorney General Caroline D. Ciraolo of the Department of Justices Tax Division. The department is currently investigating accountholders, bank employees, and other facilitators and institutions based on information supplied by various sources, including the banks participating in this Program. Our message is clear  there is no safe haven.
The Swiss Bank Program, which was announced on August 29, 2013, provides a path for Swiss banks to resolve potential criminal liabilities in the United States. Swiss banks eligible to enter the program were required to advise the department by December 31, 2013, that they had reason to believe that they had committed tax-related criminal offences in connection with undeclared US-related accounts. Banks already under criminal investigation related to their Swiss-banking activities and all individuals were expressly excluded from the program.
Under the program, banks are required to:
 Make a complete disclosure of their cross-border activities;
 Provide detailed information on an account-by-account basis for accounts in which US taxpayers have a direct or indirect interest;
 Cooperate in treaty requests for account information;
 Provide detailed information as to other banks that transferred funds into secret accounts or that accepted funds when secret accounts were closed;
 Agree to close accounts of accountholders who fail to come into compliance with US reporting obligations; and
 Pay appropriate penalties.
Swiss banks meeting all of the above requirements are eligible for a non-prosecution agreement.
According to the terms of the non-prosecution agreements signed on Thursday, each bank agrees to cooperate in any related criminal or civil proceedings, demonstrate its implementation of controls to stop misconduct involving undeclared US accounts and pay the penalties in return for the departments agreement not to prosecute these banks for tax-related criminal offences.
Socit Gnrale Private Banking (Lugano-Svizzera) SA (SGPB-Lugano) was established in 1974 and is headquartered in Lugano, Switzerland. Through referrals and pre-existing relationships, SGPB-Lugano accepted, opened and maintained accounts for US taxpayers, and knew that it was likely that certain US taxpayers who maintained accounts there were not complying with their US reporting obligations.
Since August 1, 2008, SGPB-Lugano held and managed approximately 109 US-related accounts, with a peak of assets under management of approximately $139.6 million, and offered a variety of services that it knew assisted US clients in the concealment of assets and income from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), including hold mail services and numbered accounts. Some US taxpayers expressly instructed SGPB-Lugano not to disclose their names to the IRS, to sell their US securities and to not invest in US securities, which would have required disclosure and withholding.
In addition, certain relationship managers actively assisted or otherwise facilitated US taxpayers in establishing and maintaining undeclared accounts in a manner designed to conceal the true ownership or beneficial interest in the accounts, including concealing undeclared accounts by opening and maintaining accounts in the name of non-US entities, including sham entities, having an officer of SGPB-Lugano act as an officer of the sham entities, processing cash withdrawals from accounts being closed and then maintaining the funds in a safe deposit box at the bank and making transitory accounts available, thereby allowing multiple accountholders to transfer funds in such a way as to shield the identity and account number of the accountholder.
SGPB-Lugano will pay a penalty of $1.363 million.
Created in 1979 and headquartered in Zug, Switzerland, MediBank AG (MediBank) provided private banking services to US taxpayers and assisted in the evasion of US tax obligations by opening and maintaining undeclared accounts. In furtherance of a scheme to help US taxpayers hide assets from the IRS and evade taxes, MediBank failed to comply with its withholding and reporting obligations, providing hold mail services and offering numbered accounts, thus reducing the ability of US authorities to learn the identity of the taxpayers.
After it became public that the Department of Justice was investigating UBS, MediBank hired a relationship manager from UBS and permitted some of that persons US clients to open accounts at MediBank. Since August 1, 2008, MediBank had 14 US related accounts with assets under management of $8,620,675. MediBank opened, serviced and profited from accounts for US clients with the knowledge that many likely were not complying with their US tax obligations.
MediBank will pay a penalty of $826,000.
LBBW (Schweiz) AG (LBBW-Schweiz) was established in Zurich in 1995. Since August 2008, LBBW-Schweiz held 35 US related accounts with $128,664,130 in assets under management. After it became public that the department was investigating UBS, LBBW-Schweiz opened accounts from former clients at UBS and Credit Suisse.
Despite its knowledge that US taxpayers had a legal duty to report and pay tax on income earned on their accounts, LLB permitted undeclared accounts to be opened and maintained, and offered a variety of services that would and did assist US clients in the concealment of assets and income from the IRS.
These services included following US accountholders instructions not to invest in US securities and not reporting the accounts to the IRS and agreeing to hold statements and other mail, causing documents regarding the accounts to remain outside the United States.
LBBW-Schweiz will pay a penalty of $34,000.
Headquartered in Basel, Switzerland, Scobag Privatbank AG (Scobag) was founded in 1968 to provide financial and other services to its founders, and obtained its banking licence in 1986. Since August 2008, Scobag had 13 US related accounts, the maximum dollar value of which was $6,945,700. Scobag offered a variety of services that it knew could and did assist US clients in the concealment of assets and income from the IRS, including hold mail services and numbered accounts.
Scobag will pay a penalty of $9,090.
In accordance with the terms of the program, each bank mitigated its penalty by encouraging US accountholders to come into compliance with their US tax and disclosure obligations. While US accountholders at these banks who have not yet declared their accounts to the IRS may still be eligible to participate in the IRS Offshore Voluntary Disclosure Program, the price of such disclosure has increased.
Most US taxpayers who enter the IRS Offshore Voluntary Disclosure Program to resolve undeclared offshore accounts will pay a penalty equal to 27.5 percent of the high value of the accounts. On August 4, 2014, the IRS increased the penalty to 50 percent if, at the time the taxpayer initiated their disclosure, either a foreign financial institution at which the taxpayer had an account or a facilitator who helped the taxpayer establish or maintain an offshore arrangement had been publicly identified as being under investigation, the recipient of a John Doe summons or cooperating with a government investigation, including the execution of a deferred prosecution agreement or non-prosecution agreement.
With Thursdays announcement of these non-prosecution agreements, noncompliant US accountholders at these banks must now pay that 50 percent penalty to the IRS if they wish to enter the IRS Offshore Voluntary Disclosure Program.
These four additional bank agreements signal a change in terrain for offshore banking, said Chief Richard Weber for the IRS-Criminal Investigation (CI). No longer is it safe to hide money offshore and expect that it will not be discovered.  IRS CI Special Agents will continue to follow the money to find those who circumvent the offshore disclosure laws and hold them accountable.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charter boat crew assaulted and robbed while anchored off St Vincent</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Charter-boat-crew-assaulted-and-robbed-while-anchored-off-St-Vincent-26314.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Charter boat crew assaulted and robbed while anchored off St Vincent
Published onMay 29, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
CHATEAUBELAIR, St Vincent -- Earlier this month, a chartered catamaran anchored by itself in the northern part of Chateaubelair, St Vincent, well away from the two or three other cruising boats anchored in the bay, was boarded at night by swimmers, Caribbean Safety and Security Net (CSSN) reported.
The crew was roughed up and robbed of their wallets and passports.
The criminals took the dinghy to make their escape, and abandoned it ashore after removing the outboard motor.
A police report was made.
This is the second such incident reported this month.
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IMF concludes consultation with Haiti</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-IMF-concludes-consultation-with-Haiti-26315.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
IMF concludes consultation with Haiti
Published onMay 29, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
WASHINGTON, USA -- On May 18, 2015, the executive board of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) concluded the 2015 Article IV consultation with Haiti.
In December 2014, Haiti completed an arrangement under the extended credit facility (ECF), which helped to support economic growth and maintain macroeconomic stability after the 2010 earthquake. A drought that affected agricultural output slowed GDP growth to 2.7 percent in FY2014 (from 4.2 percent in FY2013), but inflation remained in the mid-single digits. The overall fiscal deficit of the central government remained high, in part due to one-off investment related to the Sandy storm. International reserves remained appropriate at about 5 months of imports.
The implementation of structural reforms to support growth underpins the medium-term outlook, which is nonetheless subject to downside risks. GDP growth in FY2015 is expected to be between 23 percent, and to increase to 34 percent in the medium term. Inflation is projected to remain in the mid-single digits, and gross international reserves to be equivalent to between 45 months of imports, thanks to a prudent policy mix. Risks are mainly associated with a rebound in international oil prices, a stop in external financing from Venezuela, and weather events.
Executive Board Assessment
Directors commended the authorities for maintaining macroeconomic stability in the aftermath of the 2010 earthquake -- noting positive growth, moderate inflation, adequate international reserves, and an improvement in Haitis debt assessment. Nevertheless, growth remains insufficient to reduce poverty significantly, and vulnerabilities remain against the backdrop of a challenging domestic and external environment. Directors agreed that the authorities new program appropriately focuses on entrenching macroeconomic stability, and ambitious structural reforms to enhance competitiveness, spur inclusive growth and strengthen policy buffers. They stressed that strong ownership and well-coordinated donor support will be important for the success of the program.
Directors welcomed the approval of a revised FY2015 budget consistent with reducing the deficit of the non-financial public sector to about 2.5 percent of GDP over the medium term, in line with debt sustainability and program objectives. They supported the front-loaded fiscal consolidation, and noted that the adoption of an automatic fuel price mechanism and measures to improve the performance of the electricity sector will help contain fiscal risks, and create space for increased priority social and investment spending. They stressed the importance of mitigating the impact of the reforms on the poor and vulnerable. Going forward, directors encouraged the authorities to follow through on reforms to improve public financial management, including the implementation of the Treasury Single Account; and to strengthen tax administration and collection; and budgetary transparency.
Directors encouraged the authorities to maintain a tight monetary stance, as needed, until the fiscal deficit is reduced, and to be ready to increase exchange rate flexibility, in order to preserve adequate international reserve buffers and anchor inflationary expectations. A number of directors expressed concern that, if downside risks materialize, meeting the target for net international reserves could be challenging. Directors took note of the contingency measures that may need to be implemented in such case. Directors also encouraged the authorities to strengthen the monetary policy framework, through improvements in reserve management and the functioning of the foreign exchange market.
Directors noted that the banking sector remains well-capitalized and profitable, while calling for continued vigilance against financial sector risks. They also stressed the importance of sustained efforts to further develop financial intermediation and inclusion. In this regard, they welcomed adoption of the new financial inclusion strategy, and encouraged the authorities to enact pending laws on financial cooperatives and microfinance institutions.
Directors supported the programs emphasis on structural reforms designed to lift Haitis growth potential and enhance its competitiveness. Priorities include: improvements to property rights, credit access and labor productivity; streamlining business regulations; and infrastructure development -- most notably by strengthening the governance and performance of the electricity sector.
Directors encouraged the authorities to improve the quality of the economic data, with technical assistance from the Fund and other donors.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jamaica hosts regional workshop on salmonella surveillance and risk management</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Jamaica-hosts-regional-workshop-on-salmonella-surveillance-and-risk-management-26316.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Jamaica hosts regional workshop on salmonella surveillance and risk management
Published onMay 29, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Participants at the salmonella regional workshop in Kingston, Jamaica
KINGSTON, Jamaica (IICA) -- Twenty-five participants, including personnel from the Jamaican poultry and egg industries and veterinarians, microbiologists and public health inspectors from across the Caribbean region, participated in a recently held workshop on salmonella surveillance and risk management on poultry and egg production and processing.
The workshop, which was held in Kingston, Jamaica, on May 20 and 21, 2015, was funded under the 10th European Development Fund (EDF) Sanitary and Phytosanitary (SPS) Measures Project, being executed by the Inter-American Institute for Cooperation on Agriculture (IICA).
Salmonella is a type of bacteria that is frequently found in poultry meat, eggs and unpasteurised milk. It can cause salmonellosis, a type of food poisoning. It is therefore a major food safety concern.
According to the Caribbean Public Health Agency (CARPHA) and the Pan American Health Organisation (PAHO/WHO), salmonella is the most prevalent cause of food borne illness in the Caribbean.
To address this issue, the Caribbean Animal Health Network (CaribVET) veterinary public health working group in collaboration with PAHO/WHO organised the regional workshop to develop Caribbean regional guidelines for integrated surveillance and risk management in poultry and eggs.
Participants were drawn from several countries in the region, including Dominica, Grenada, Guyana, Jamaica, Suriname and Trinidad and Tobago.
This salmonella workshop provides an opportunity for us to practice One Health by working together between ministries of health and agriculture and the poultry producers and processors towards a common goal, said Dr Sandra Vokaty, chair of the CaribVET veterinary public health working group and advisor, veterinary public health at the PAHO/WHO.
One Health refers to an interdisciplinary approach to minimizing harms and maximizing benefits from the co-management of human, animal and environmental health. She further stated that the veterinary public health working group deals with food borne and zoonotic diseases, and therefore has adopted a One Health approach to its work.
Zoonotic diseases are diseases that people can get from animals.
In his greetings on behalf of PAHO/WHO, Dr Kam Suan Mung, disease prevention and control advisor for PAHO, Jamaica, reminded participants of the importance of collaboration on food safety.
He said, Food safety requires a multisectoral coalition that includes ministries of health and agriculture, food safety regulators, food producers, processors, distributors, food markets, restaurants and hotels, and consumers.
Highlighting recent collaborative efforts to combat food borne diseases, Shauna Brandon, rural development specialist of IICA, Jamaica, stated, Over the past 12 months the SPS measures project has worked with key collaborators (FAO, PAHO/WHO, OIE, CaribVET and CARPHA) to execute several interventions to build capacity and coordination to strengthen animal health and food safety in the region.
The 10th EDF SPS measures project seeks to assist CARIFORUM states to gain and improve market access by complying sanitary and phytosanitary (SPS) measures of the European Union and to develop and strengthen regionally harmonized SPS measures. The specific objective of the SPS project is to increase production and trade in agriculture and fisheries which meet international standards while protecting plant, animal and human health and the environment.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trinidad MP arrested; US seeks extradition</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Trinidad-MP-arrested%3B-US-seeks-extradition-26295.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Trinidad MP arrested; US seeks extradition
Published onMay 28, 2015
Jack Warner
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- Following his indictment in the US on eight counts of racketeering, fraud and money laundering, Trinidad member of parliament Jack Warner, former regional vice president of FIFA, was arrested and taken into custody on Wednesday afternoon and brought before the chief magistrate where the charges were read to him and he was granted bail in the sum of $2,500,000 (US$395,000) with conditions. Under the treaty between the United States and Trinidad and Tobago, the US now has 60 days to produce a formal request for Warners extradition.
Trinidad and Tobagos Attorney General Garvin Nicholas said that, on Wednesday morning, the Central Authority of Trinidad and Tobago received a request from the US Department of Justice for a provisional arrest warrant for the purposes of Warners extradition.
Attorney General Garvin Nicholas
In keeping with our international obligations, the Central Authority of Trinidad and Tobago immediately facilitated the process to obtain the said warrant, which was issued by the Chief Magistrate, Ms Marcia Ayers-Caesar, Nicholas said in a statement.
According to the attorney general, Wednesdays events were the result of continued successful cooperation between the Central Authority of Trinidad and Tobago and the US Department of Justice, which has spanned a period of approximately two years in respect of the present matter.
The nature of this matter is global in scale. It is therefore expected that this matter would draw not only national but international attention. This matter is however of a very serious and sensitive nature and is now in the hands of the court. I have full confidence in the institutions involved to carry out their roles in a professional and fair manner, Nicholas added.
On Wednesday morning, seven top executives of the Federation Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) were arrested in Zurich, Switzerland, as a result of an international investigation conducted by the United States. These seven were among 14 high-ranking officials of FIFA, as well as leading officials of other related soccer governing bodies, indicted on charges in the US.
The allegations arising out of the investigation include bribery, corruption, wire fraud conspiracy and money laundering.
Warner was indicted on eight counts including:
a) One count of conspiracy to knowingly agree to conduct or participate in racketeering activity, relating to wire fraud and other offences, which either engages in or affects interstate or foreign commerce, in violation of Title 18, United States Code, Section 1962(d);
b) Two counts of conspiracy to devise any scheme or artifice to defraud, including for the intangible right of honest services, using wire, radio, or television communications to execute such scheme or artifice, in violation of Title 18, United States Code, Section 1343, 1346, and 1349;
c) Two counts of devising any scheme or artifice to defraud, using wire, radio, or television communications to execute such scheme or artifice, in violation of Title 18, United States Code, Section 1343;
d) Two counts of conspiring to transport, transmit and transfer monetary instruments and funds from places inside the United States to and through places outside the United States and to places in the United States from and through places outside the United States, with the intent to promote the carrying on of specified unlawful activity, in violation of Title 18, United States Code, Sections 1956(a)(2)(A) and 1956(h); and
e) One count of transporting, transmitting and transferring monetary instruments and funds from places inside the United States to and through places outside the United States and to places in the United States from and through places outside the United States, with the intent to promote the carrying on of specified unlawful activity, in violation of Title 18, United States Code, Sections 1956(a)(2)(A)
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guyana's new president defends size of cabinet and renaming of ministries </title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Guyana%27s-new-president-defends-size-of-cabinet-and-renaming-of-ministries--26296.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Guyana's new president defends size of cabinet and renaming of ministries
Published onMay 28, 2015
GEORGETOWN, Guyana (GINA) -- President David Granger has dismissed claims that the new APNU/AFC coalition government in Guyana is a large government, and pointed out that there are fewer ministries than those under the previous administration.
President David Granger
It is the amalgamation of the ministries that would have created concerns, the president said. I have not created a larger number of ministries than existed before; there are now fewer than there were before, as far as the names are concerned, I have explained that some of the changes in name were to emphasise the functions.
Citing one example, the president pointed out that the ministry of the presidency always existed as it is merely the renaming of the Office of the President.
I felt it necessary to have a minister of state, who would continue to act authoritatively to ensure that the Cabinet decisions are implemented throughout the government service, Granger explained.
Explaining the name change of the ministry of local government to ministry of communities, Granger said, We are not simply building houses or building roads, we are building communities where human beings live and that is why it was renamed to emphasise the human aspect of local development, local government, of regional government and of housing schemes and water supply.
The new head of state stressed the need to see places where citizens dwell, not just a collection of buildings, but a collection of families, so that emphasis can be placed on sporting facilities, culture and other types of community life. These and more, the president said, are more often than not absent from newly developed housing schemes across the country.
The renaming of the ministry of home affairs to the ministry of public security, the president said is self-explanatory: What does home affairs mean? Home affairs is an old title which is taken from the British Empire, they had foreign affairs which dealt with international matters and home affairs, but we do not have an empire, so why should we call it home affairs?
Likewise the ministry of public infrastructure from the ministry of public works is also self-explanatory as it caters to infrastructure for public use, and will be dealing with stellings, roadways and bridges.
Meanwhile, responding to the issue of no consultations being held before the renaming of some of the ministries, Granger said, There is a lot of criticism, but some of it is not well informed. The ministry of indigenous peoples (affairs), the indigenous people said that they prefer to be called indigenous peoples rather than to be called Amerindians.
With regard to the appointments, he said, I had to have some consultations before the appointments were made; I could not sit down by myself and make Mr Ramjattan a vice president.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More Caribbean governments should invest in LIAT, say regional PMs</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-More-Caribbean-governments-should-invest-in-LIAT%2C-say-regional-PMs-26297.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
More Caribbean governments should invest in LIAT, say regional PMs
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Ken Richards
BASSETERRE, St Kitts (WINN) -- Vincentian Prime Minister Ralph Gonsalves and Antigua and Barbudas Prime Minister Gaston Brown have urged Caribbean governments that are not major shareholders of regional airline LIAT to change that status by giving meaningful financial support to the airline.
St Vincent and the Grenadines Prime Minister Ralph Gonsalves
Both made that appeal at last weeks CDB sponsored seminar on making air transport work better for the Caribbean. Gonsalves spoke in his capacity as chairman of the group of shareholder governments of LIAT.
Browne said, while LIAT must seek to improve its operations, the airline needs to be subsidized, arguing that LIAT is making a significant contribution to the integration process and should be supported by the governments of the region.
Its not clear what the position of the new Team Unity administration in St Kitts and Nevis on LIAT will be. Former prime minister Denzil Douglas said his government had in its last six months in office been taking a critical look at the LIAT problem.
Antigua and Barbuda Prime Minister Gaston Brown
Douglas said under consideration was the use of the Sugar Industry Diversification Fund (SIDF) funds to help Basseterre become a major shareholder of LIAT.
A CDB commissioned study on the regional airline industry proposes the setting up a Caribbean Community (CARICOM) airlines association to identify opportunities to reduce cost, create greater synergies and earn more revenue.
Republished with permission of West Indies News Network

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ECLAC study on foreign direct investment puts focus on Caribbean</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-ECLAC-study-on-foreign-direct-investment-puts-focus-on-Caribbean-26298.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
ECLAC study on foreign direct investment puts focus on Caribbean
Published onMay 28, 2015
SANTIAGO, Chile -- The Caribbean receives higher amounts of foreign direct investment (FDI) when compared to other developing economies, according to a newly published report from the Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC).
ECLAC Executive Secretary, Alicia Brcena
Entitled Foreign Direct Investment in Latin America and the Caribbean, the flagship report was launched by ECLAC executive secretary, Alicia Brcena, on 27 May at the organizations headquarters in Santiago, Chile.
For the first time, the flagship report dedicates an entire chapter to FDI in the Caribbean, thus placing increased emphasis on the importance of FDI for the region. FDI inflows into the Caribbean amounted to approximately five percent of GDP in 2014, compared to three percent for Latin America, and less in other developing regions.
In the Caribbean, FDI is important both as a source of funds for development and as a source of foreign exchange. Nevertheless, questions remain about the extent to which these flows contribute to growth and development in the Caribbean.
Given the increasing propensity of many large Caribbean transnationals to make significant cross-border investments, the report looks at outward FDI from Caribbean countries to regional and extra-regional economies.
The publication discusses recent developments in key sectors, which either attract the most FDI inflows or possess potential for increased FDI. Examples include tourism, natural resources, manufacturing, business process outsourcing, financial services, and offshore education. Potential benefits and drawbacks of FDI are examined.
The report provides an analysis of the modalities commonly utilized by Latin American and Caribbean countries to attract and leverage FDI. It also looks at the extent to which these methods attract FDI, which contributes to economic growth and sustainable development.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean to improve climate resilience with US$10 million programme</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-to-improve-climate-resilience-with-US%2410-million-programme-26299.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean to improve climate resilience with US$10 million programme
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
WASHINGTON, USA -- The Caribbean region will increase its resilience to climate change by enhancing the adaptive capacity across the region through a US$10.39 million grant approved by the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) through support from the pilot programme for climate resilience (PPCR) of the Climate Investment Funds (CIF).
The project is to be executed by the Mona Office of Research and Innovation (MORI), University of the West Indies (UWI) in Jamaica and will be co-implemented by regional organizations working on climate change in the region, including the Caribbean Community Climate Change Centre (CCCCC); Caribbean Institute for Meteorology and Hydrology (CIMH), Climate Change Studies Group of UWI, Caribbean Public Health Agency (CARPHA), Caribbean Agricultural Research and Development Institute (CARDI), and the Caribbean Regional Fisheries Mechanism (CRFM).
The project is the implementation of the investment plan for the Caribbean regional track of the PPCR, and it will help the Caribbean region improve regional processes of climate relevant data acquisition, storage, analysis, access, transfer and dissemination, and pilot and scale up innovative climate resilient initiatives directly in PPCR countries  Jamaica, Haiti, Dominica, Grenada, St Lucia and St Vincent and the Grenadines.
However, it is expected that the region as a whole will benefit from the improved capacity and increased information and services related to climate change.
The project will focus on: (i) Improving geospatial data and management for adaptation planning, sea level rise and storm surge impact analyses  the use of radar in bathymetric and coastal topographic analysis will be a key activity; (ii) Consolidating and expanding the regional climate network and global platform linkages  improvements in the acquisition of weather data and climate services will be key activities; (iii) Downscaling and expanded climate projection models and high resolution maps  improvements to and enhancement of the downscaled future climate projections in the Caribbean in support of adaptation planning, decision making, and sector level modeling/projection efforts will be key activities ; and (iv) the application of adaptation initiatives utilizing the information generated as part of the project in the areas of health, agriculture, marine resources, water and climate change policies.
There will be a strong emphasis on disseminating the lessons learned and information generated from the implementation of the project activities as well as the information related to the benefits of the PPCR approach in building climate resilience to countries in the Caribbean.
Thanks to this programme, the Caribbean will build on its historical regional approach to addressing the impacts of climate change and strengthen adaptation efforts across the region, providing an example for other regions globally.
The US$10 million grant is a five year program and will be supervised by the Climate Change and Sustainability Division within the Infrastructure and Environment Sector Department of the IDB.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Haiti to get US$50m grant for cleaner water and better sanitation in cholera hot spots</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Haiti-to-get-US%2450m-grant-for-cleaner-water-and-better-sanitation-in-cholera-hot-spots-26300.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Haiti to get US$50m grant for cleaner water and better sanitation in cholera hot spots
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
WASHINGTON, USA -- About 300,000 people from Haitis cholera-affected rural areas and small towns will benefit from increased access to clean water and sanitation as a result of a US$50 million grant from the International Development Association (IDA) approved on Wednesday by the board of directors of the World Bank.
The sustainable rural and small towns water and sanitation project aims to save lives by preventing cholera and waterborne diseases in high prevalence zones, and strengthen the capacity of local agencies to deliver water and sanitation services in rural areas and small towns.
Haiti has made progress in controlling the cholera epidemic since the 2010 outbreak, with reported case numbers decreasing from a monthly average of more than 30,000 in 2011 to about 2,200 cases per month in 2014. However, due to heavy rains, cases rose sharply in the first quarter of 2015, to a monthly average of 3,400 cases. While deaths from cholera and waterborne diseases declined last year and remain below one percent of cases, cholera resurgence remains a threat and water borne diseases are one of the leading causes of infant mortality in the country.
We hear a lot in Haiti that Water is life. With this project we have an opportunity to make this a reality for hundreds of thousands of Haitians, said Benito Dumay, director general of the National Water and Sanitation Directorate - DINEPA. This project supports the governments ten-year cholera elimination plan and aims to prevent thousands more Haitian children from dying from waterborne diseases.
Wednesdays grant is part of an encompassing World Bank initiative that builds on the immediate emergency response after the outbreak in 2010, which benefited more than three million people through prevention education campaigns, training of community health workers and medical personnel, and direct treatment. It also complements cholera prevention and treatment efforts for US$20 million under an ongoing health project focused on epidemiological surveillance and treatment.
The World Bank said it is committed to mobilize donors and other partners to join forces in substantially improving water and sanitation coverage in Haiti, and strengthening health services.
Despite much progress in Haitis fight on cholera, too many people are still getting sick, mainly because they dont have access to clean water and sanitation systems. This is even more vital in rural areas where less than one in two Haitians have access to safe drinking water and only 16 percent have access to improved sanitation, said Mary Barton-Dock, World Bank special envoy. By improving water and sanitation coverage in these targeted areas, we are not only saving lives, but also helping reduce poverty and improve livelihood opportunities of these communities.
The new project will target priority communes with high cholera incidence rates in the dry season. It will reinforce and complement the activities carried out by other local and international partners in the country, and will have an impact across the Island of Hispaniola and on the border with the Dominican Republic, including bi-national markets.
Among the concrete results to be achieved are:
 150,000 people will gain access to improved water sources through household connections and water kiosks;
 50,000 people will benefit from improved sanitation through community-led sanitation campaigns, hygiene promotion, and construction of latrines in schools, health centers, markets and other public spaces;
 100,000 people will benefit from small repairs and expansions;
 A roadmap for universal access to water and sanitation by 2030 will be developed.
 A regional surveillance system for pandemics will be designed with support from the government of the Dominican Republic.
This six-year project will be implemented by DINEPA under the ministry of public works, transport and communications (MTPTC).
World Bank Group response to cholera
The World Banks International Development Association (IDA) has been financing cholera response activities since the outbreak in the end of 2010. It disbursed US$15 million as part of a cholera emergency response project, which closed in March 2014. More than three million people benefited from prevention education campaigns, training, and direct treatment through the project. Specifically, more than 5,400 community health workers and medical personnel were trained.
In addition to Wednesdays US$50 million grant, the World Bank has made US$20 million available to the ministry of health for cholera prevention and treatment under a new health project (total US$90 million) for epidemiological surveillance, treatment, including rapid response mobile teams, hygiene and health promotion, and water and sanitation activities. The International Finance Corporation (IFC) has also supported DLO Haiti, which is developing a network of water kiosks where water is purified and distributed to nearby communities at an affordable price.
In collaboration with the government of Haiti, the UN and development partners, the World Bank also hosted an international round table to discuss best practices and lessons learned on combating cholera, and a high profile conference in Washington DC to bring attention to the financing gap.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British Virgin Islands to host regional parliamentary conference</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-British-Virgin-Islands-to-host-regional-parliamentary-conference-26301.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
British Virgin Islands to host regional parliamentary conference
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Linton Leonard
ROAD TOWN, BVI -- The British Virgin Islands (BVI) will host the 40th annual conference of the Caribbean, Americas and the Atlantic Region of the Commonwealth Parliamentary Association (CPA).
Over 70 parliamentarians drawn from member states of that body are expected to arrive in the BVI in July as delegates and observers to this annual event. The opening of the conference will take place on July 27, 2015 under the theme: Promoting Democracy and Good Governance: A Unified Approach. Deliberations will take place from July 25 until August 1.
According to the clerk of the House of Assembly and conference coordinator, Phyllis Evans, the theme is relevant, given the challenging democratic circumstances being currently faced by member states.
Evans said, It will allow parliamentarians to get together to share perspectives, which may well be different, given their unique circumstances. I believe we can learn from each other and explore ways of tackling these problems.
Evans stated that the CPA conference is also being held at a critical point in the history of the BVI, at the implementation of the National Youth Policy that includes the creation of the Virgin Islands Youth Commission, the National Youth Council and the National Youth Parliament.
The 40th annual conference will include the eighth conference of Commonwealth women parliamentarians, the regional executive committee meeting, plenary sessions, the annual general meeting and the regional youth parliament.
A two-day meeting of the regional sub-group of the Commonwealth Women Parliamentarians (CWP) will precede the main conference. The female parliamentarians will discuss topics including Strategies to Increase Womens Representation in Parliaments.
Delegations to the regional CPA will include participants who will also participate in the annual session of the Caribbean Youth Parliament.
During the launch of the National Youth Policy on April 27, 2015, minister for education and culture, Myron Walwyn, stated that, as early as July, the youth of the territory will have the opportunity to take ownership of the youth policy as they participate in the upcoming sitting of the Commonwealth Youth Parliament at the CPA meeting to be held in the BVI.
The minister added that the youth parliament will enable young people across the territory to develop their skills and advocate meaningfully on different platforms and themes that impact them.
Walwyn further stated, The Parliament contributes to a strong and secure territory by developing our young people and by their participation, allowing them to mature as politically accountable and responsible citizens, grounded in a civic consciousness, national identity, democracy and the rule of law, and respect for rights and diversity."
The purpose of the Commonwealth Parliamentary Association branches of the Caribbean, the Americas and the Atlantic Region is to provide a forum to promote the aims and objectives and implement the activities of CPA CAA and the branches in the region.
The aims and objectives of the association are to promote knowledge of the respective constitutions, as well as the legislative, economic, social and cultural aspects of parliamentary democracy, with particular reference to the Commonwealth countries in the region.
Member states of the CPA include Anguilla, Antigua and Barbuda, Barbados, Belize, Bermuda, British Virgin Islands, Cayman Islands, Dominica, Grenada, Guyana, Jamaica, Montserrat, Trinidad and Tobago, St Kitts and Nevis, St Lucia, St Vincent and the Grenadines, the Bahamas and the Turks and Caicos Islands.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Carnival comes to communities across Antigua-Barbuda</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Carnival-comes-to-communities-across-Antigua-Barbuda-26302.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Carnival comes to communities across Antigua-Barbuda
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
ST JOHNS, Antigua -- With the early launch of the 2015 Carnival Celebrations, the Antigua Barbuda Festivals Commission (ABFC) is ready and set to bring Carnival into communities across the island with the unveiling of the 2015 Carnival Road Shows.
The aim of the 2015 Carnival Road Shows is to generate awareness in the communities, whilst simultaneously promoting the Summer Festival. In addition to this, the road shows are designed to expose local entertainers, and provide an avenue for them to build support for Carnival 2015.
However, the road shows are not just limited to artistes, but to all entities involved in making the 2015 Carnival  The Caribbeans Greatest Summer Festival .
The ABFC will host a series of road shows featuring soca and calypso artistes, DJs, steel and iron bands, mas troupes, and so much more. The first show will be held in Liberta on Sunday, May 31, and will kick off at 4 pm. The chairman of the ABFC has promised an action-packed evening for the family, filled with lots of entertainment.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Let's Talk Business: There is never enough time in a day, or is there?</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Let%27s-Talk-Business%3A-There-is-never-enough-time-in-a-day%2C-or-is-there%3F-26303.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Let's Talk Business: There is never enough time in a day, or is there?
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Billie Bowe
Its odd that I would choose this topic to write about, as I would be the first to utter the words, There is never enough time in a day! A day in the life of Billie Bowe looks a little like this: get up, shower, take daughter to school, attend client meetings, write articles for three columns, conduct interviews, send emails, return phone calls, prepare for speaking engagements, network, conduct corporate training, pick up daughter from school, volunteer in my community, remember to eat, practice my golf swing, and the list goes on and on. Before I can unpack my luggage after returning home from a business trip, I am off again sitting on another plane heading to another destination. It can certainly drive one insane. So when it comes to time management, it is a struggle Id admit, and I would imagine I am not the only one.
Billie Bowe has been a successful senior manager in human resources for the private sector for more than ten years and is the president and CEO of Benchmark Consulting Services Ltd , a management consulting firm, in Freeport, Grand Bahama. Email: bbowe@bcsbahamas.com
There is a phrase that says, you cant eat an elephant in one sitting; well thats the essence of this article, which by the way is due today! As I offer tips to my readers on how to better manage their time, I am giving myself some sage advice as well. I am learning right along with you. There has to be a way to accomplish what needs to be done in a day without wanting to run off to some secluded island where there are no phones, Internet, or even human beings.
Here are five things WE can start doing today to manage our daily tasks, plans, schedules, whatever it is, in order to be more efficient:
1. Use technology  we have smartphones, computers, and tablets; all of which have awesome apps to help us stay organized. I can name many but really it depends on your personal preference. One of the things I do now to help me shave some time off my hectic schedule is record tons of voice notes on my mobile phone. Especially for my writing assignments. Once Ive recorded the key points, then I can write without having to waste time thinking of a topic or staring at a blank page. I do this when preparing speeches; training presentations, even email correspondences. And when do I it? Dont ask. Sometimes its while I am driving (safely of course) or waiting for my daughter to emerge from the schoolyard, or most often on a plane. And what about those tasks that are necessary but can take a lot of time, like banking and paying bills? It amazes me when I see how many people are still paying their bills in person. Just about every major company allows online bill pay. Due to my immense dislike for long lines, I do 90 percent of my banking online.
2. Take it day-by-day and not week-by-week  using the analogy of the elephant, we must be realistic about what we can actually accomplish in a day. Now this takes discipline but the benefits are awesome. Take it one day at a time. There is no sense in trying to cram 15 things in one workday when we can prioritize and narrow it down to five. Youll be surprised as to how easy it is to accomplish. I tend to think of the entire week when, instead, just focusing on one day and fewer tasks, I have a better chance of ensuring that I complete those assignments on time. Youre probably thinking, easier said than done right? But give it try.
3. Delegate  whenever possible find tasks to delegate that can lighten your workload. But be careful of this. Delegating is not about dumping the things you dont want to do off to someone else, especially in the work environment. Delegating is meant to be a learning experience for the person being delegated to. This takes practice but can truly reap awesome rewards, allowing you to focus on the bigger picture. You may be asking what if I have no one to delegate to. I have no silver bullet solution for this, however, all I can say is perhaps we havent really taken an inventory as to exactly how we currently spend our time. There may very well be tasks that can be delegated if only we pause and take stock. Who knows, you may find that you are spending time doing something that has nothing to do with accomplishing the task or goal at hand. In my business, I try to think of time in segments. For example, allotting time for income generating activities. If I am doing more maintenance and not lead generation, then my business could plateau. Not good for a consultant.
4. Ask for help  this is one I often struggle with. Unlike delegating, which in the business context is meant to allow for the transfer of skills from one to another, asking for help is a totally different ballgame. There is no shame in asking for help when needed. A trend that is becoming increasingly popular for businesses is outsourcing. If you find a company that you can outsource to, then do it. An example may be recruiting, especially for SMEs (small and medium enterprises). If you consider the cost (in time and money) of you trying to recruit someone, place ads, review resumes and applications, screen candidates in and out, there is likely a company that can handle that process for you. It may be well worth it in the end and you may even have a broader talent pool to access as recruitment firms typically have a pool of potential candidates from which to feed from.
5. Give yourself a break  when we rush about like chickens without heads, what are we really accomplishing? Speaking from experience, if I dont pause or just say no when asked to do something that I full well know cant fit into my schedule, I wind up with a lot of unfinished business. My solution to this problem is for one, start saying no when it really is necessary to do so. Secondly, there is no substitute for getting a good nights rest. If I am frazzled because my plate is too full, I never finish my meal. In the same vein, if we dont take care of our body, which is a biological machine that requires fuel to operate, it will break down. Then what? If youre not around or at your optimal performance level because youve run your body down, then chances are the quality of your work and life will suffer as a result.
I started out by saying that I have to take my own advice. It is a work in progress; it requires discipline that comes with practice. As a wife, mother, daughter, sister, friend, employer and business owner, it is critical that I manage my time effectively. The thing to remember is youre not the only one trying to manage time. That meeting you had to postpone due to time constraints may actually be grateful that you did, as they too cant find enough time in a day. Now isnt that ironic!

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Prepare, the Ingrahamites are near!</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Prepare%2C-the-Ingrahamites-are-near%21-26304.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Prepare, the Ingrahamites are near!
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Youri Kemp
Ever since the opposition party in The Bahamas, the Free National Movement, elected their leader, Dr Hubert Minnis, in a snap mini-convention and with Dr Minnis having staved off and cut off a surging challenge from his fellow opposition member of parliament colleague, Mrs Loretta Butler-Turner, his leadership has been met with fierce criticism from persons within his own party. Most of which are from a small, but yet powerful faction of persons loyal to their former leader and former prime minister of The Bahamas, the Right Honourable Hubert Ingraham.
Youri Kemp is president and CEO of Kemp Global, a management consultancy firm, based in The Bahamas, which serves all markets. Email: globalviewtoday@gmail.com
None more prominent in the cacophony of discontent within the Free National Movement with their leadership is that of the former deputy prime minister under Mr Ingraham, Frank Watson.
Mr Watson has said that the current leader of the FNM is tone-deaf to his and other's suggestions on how the party should proceed. He also said that the party is in serious problems if Dr Minnis's current style of management continues. He was directly quoted as saying that the current chairman of the FNM is "talking nonsense" and that the chairman is "out of the loop" with the real players in the party. And that was just last week!
Without a doubt Mr Ingraham has left an indelible mark on Bahamian politics. The first prime minister in the era post the near invincible Sir Lynden Pindling, and having served three terms to boot. Quite a feat in a modern and fair democratic government process for anyone from anywhere in the world to have served as leader for more than ten years, whether consecutively or non-consecutively.
Of course, this means that there are a lot of people that are very, very loyal to Mr Ingraham. No doubt, he has in fact helped a great deal of people. He also had an uncanny knack for placing people in strategic positions in the public and private sector, persons who have been able to maintain and make valuable contributions to our country.
However, as with many a leader in democratic, and not-so-democratic fashion, the love affair between them and the people often goes sour after it becomes stale and methods become ineffective. Good enough for us that his departure from front line politics was met with peaceful transition, and not with a coup or some form of violence. I am proud to be a Bahamian on that score. Truly.
Mr Ingraham was beaten by his immediate predecessor and his successor to his first term in office. To be succinct: the current prime minister, the Right Honourable Perry Christie, had a one term stint in between Mr Ingraham's terms of service. Mr Christie won in 2002, lost in 2007 and then won again in 2012.
What's also a pretty well known fact is that Mr Christie and Mr Ingraham share a very funny distinction: They were both fired as cabinet ministers at the same time on the same day in the same circumstances under the Sir Lynden Pindling government.
Without labouring through the oftentimes murky and gossipy reasons as to why they were fired, to cut a long story short, Mr Christie and Mr Ingraham ran as independents in that subsequent election that the governing party, the Progressive Liberal Party, won, with Mr Christie opting to go back to the PLP and Mr Ingraham opting to go with the FNM and then becoming prime minister in 1992.
Sure enough, along with that distinction, they also, as reports claim, share a close bond and friendship. They were former law partners in addition to standing as godparents for each other's children. They also share the same small group of friends and associates.
Leading anyone who does not fall into the spell of the occult-like style of politics in The Bahamas: We have essentially been ruled and governed by the same small group of people for over the last 20 plus years.
Regardless of what anyone tells you, even with a strong man like Mr Ingraham: No one runs a country by themselves. All strong leaders, and more so with not-so-strong leaders, have supporters, cronies, lackeys, bag men, go to guys, key writers, image makers, covert operatives and public relations gurus that all play a part in making them look on the ball, as well as their relational associates and family ties that hold them down, at all times.
To go even further with this relationship that both men share, during the 2007 campaign and at a campaign rally when Mr Ingraham won that election year, Mr Ingraham remarked in a quite jovial, but yet sneering and mocking manner, at a point where then sitting prime minister Christie, during a time where he had fallen ill and had to take an indeterminate time of leave, had asked him to "run" the cabinet and the country until he had time to convalesce and get back on his game. By-passing his then deputy, Cynthia "Mother" Pratt and the rest of his cabinet ministers in the PLP.
So, essentially the "Ingrahamites" aren't just near, they probably never left. Which is quite important for our country, because as mentioned previously: Ideas, ways of doing business, methods, people and their minds become stale and ineffective. While continuity is important, quite frankly, when you look at our daunting issues: Who wishes that?
When you sit in one spot for too long you become immune and blind to what's around you. You don't see "the problems", you just continue with your solutions which you feel worked 20 years ago and so they must work today. This is even worse for those that are eating their fair-square three meals a day and have no worries about those meals tomorrow.
This clearly suggests, at least over the last ten years, the same solutions have not been productive or user friendly. To say the very least.
With all of that being said, however, I think this is a perfect time to hear from former prime minister Ingraham.
The way he left after the 2012 election was, to put it quite mildly, abrupt, seemingly callous and a little selfish. It was like the Bahamian taxpayers werent allowing him a salary and leeway to do what it is he was charged to do. This was a lot worse than the first time he left the scene, more or less, at the height of a mild recession after he had lost in 2002. The state of affairs then was not "this bad".
The country has not fully recovered since the 2008 global recession. Unemployment is still stubbornly up; the ease of doing business rankings are slipping; investment, both local and foreign, is not vibrant and with the latter we need less of and more of the former; crime is still miles high; public services are still reeling from the ravages of the recession and morale is low because more burdens were placed on them; and the overall sentiment from Bahamians is one of hopelessness amidst waves and waves of missteps and oversights that turned into full-blown fiascos under the current administration, all at a time when we need concerned and concerted consistency and clarity on all fronts.
I mentioned to one of my colleagues just recently that I would like to hear from Mr Ingraham about all and sundry, regardless of how it looks now: From the current state of the economy, the way we look internationally, how he feels businesses can be better served, how the small and not-so-small can better integrate themselves into the process he left behind and his overall outlook on his party, the FNM and the fighting that is looking very, very nasty.
To be fair, he did not give us our just due as citizens in giving a full account of his tenure. A de-briefing, of sorts.
Even a very prominent businessman, Franklyn Wilson of Arawak Homes, feels the same way as I do. He too also wants to know, and in particular, why did Mr Ingraham leave South Eleuthera at such a disadvantage as Mr Wilson has lamented in one of his recent discussions with reporters.
Some have suggested, and this is probably why persons like Mr. Ingraham's former deputy Frank Watson and a few others have been getting antsy and vocal as of late, that Mr Ingraham is planning a comeback. Stronger than when many feel he usurped power of the FNM from leader elect Tommy Turnquest and put his name in the hat at the FNM's convention leading up to the 2007 general election.
I can only laugh, especially considering all we know now and all we read in only this submission. Laugh because Mr Ingraham, Mr Watson and the others loyal to the Ingrahamite cause, if this is the case, may as well come out as full, card carrying members of the governing PLP. That ought to make this into the full scale spectacle that those and sundry want us to be embroiled in and one that it appears to be.
One of my colleagues, a very seasoned man and one who was in the mix back in the day and knows both Mr Christie and Mr Ingraham very well, assured me that both men speak to each other on a regular basis on governing The Bahamas and that Mr Ingraham's input is seen and felt every day. I can believe that! **sips tea**

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Garifuna leaders meet with St Vincent opposition leader in New York</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Garifuna-leaders-meet-with-St-Vincent-opposition-leader-in-New-York-26305.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Garifuna leaders meet with St Vincent opposition leader in New York
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Wellington C. Ramos
In 1797, after the British finally defeated the Garifuna people after years of resistance, they removed them from their native homeland Yurumein, now known as St Vincent and the Grenadines, to Baliceaux, an adjacent island.
Born in Dangriga Town, the cultural capital of Belize, Wellington Ramos has BAs in Political Science and History from Hunter College, NY, and an MA in Urban Studies from Long Island University. He is an Adjunct Professor of Political Science and History
On this island, after their Garifuna nation was dismantled, they were imprisoned, tortured, killed and the survivors, estimated about 5,000, were taken to Roatan, Honduras, where they landed on April 12 of that same year. Many Garifuna people disliked the conditions on this island and appealed to the British to find a better place for them.
In 1801, some of these Garifuna people, numbering about 150, left Roatan and sailed to Belize. They were granted permission by the British to settle in the southern part of Belize in a town they named Dangriga. In 1823, after the slaughtering of some Garifuna men, women and children in San Juan, Honduras, a large contingent of Garifuna people, led by Elijio Beni and Satulle, left the country to join their people in Dangriga, where they live up to this day. The British also made a deal with the Spanish crown and some of them were allowed to settle along the coast of Honduras.
During these negotiations most of their names were changed from their original names to Spanish names to hide their true identities. During the nationalist and civil wars in Honduras, many Garifuna people fought in these battles and were killed. As a result of these wars and the British occupation of Bluefield, Nicaragua, some Garifuna people migrated to neighbouring Nicaragua, Guatemala, Belize and later on to the United States.
No matter which country the Garifuna people live, they all identify themselves with their motherland Yurumein. It is and remains the dream of all the Garinagu people in the Diaspora that one day the people and government of their motherland Yurumein will acknowledge their rights to this nation as theirs as well.
Garifuna peoples intentions has never been and will never be to deny citizenship and rights of all their brothers and sisters who became citizens of Yurumein after March 11, 1797. Why? Because the Garifuna peoples history has always been to stand up and fight for the injustices committed against other human beings.
This was why they risked their lives and died fighting against the Spanish, French and British in what is known as the Carib Wars. Not only did they fight against these powerful nations but they also stole their slaves and brought them to Yurumein to live with them as one people. The leaders of the Garifuna organization shared their history, the current state of affairs in all the countries where they live today and their constant struggle to be accepted as citizens to freely practice their culture without government interference.
Also discussed were current human rights violations in some of these countries, especially Honduras, such as health, education, poverty, inadequate and lack of political representation, environment, farming fishing, cooperative, autonomy, unlawful detention, imprisonment, lots, lands, economic development, unequal distribution of their nations wealth were all brought to the leader of the oppositions attention.
The leader was taking notes and listened keenly to what was being relayed to him. He was shocked, amazed, appalled, disgusted and angry by some of the testimonies he was hearing from his Garifuna brothers and sisters. He said to them, My political party, namely, the New Democratic Party (NDP), and myself held an executive meeting before I departed to the United States and agreed to take a bold stand on issues related to our Garifuna people in the Diaspora countries.
All the delegates present were delighted when they heard this statement.
In our Garifuna culture our ancestors and the elders have always warned us about favouring one political party over the other because it will be used to divide us as a people. In Honduras, most of our people tend to support the Liberal Party and when the Nationalist Party becomes the new government they are hostile to our people.
In Nicaragua, some of our people were with President Ortega and became victims when he was removed from power. Today, he is back in power and they are trying to get back their lands that were taken away from them under the previous governments.
Garifuna people in Guatemala mostly live in the town of Labuga, in English meaning Livingston, and Puerto Barrios. The number of Garifuna people living in Guatemala is not large. Plus, Guatemala is known for having military coups so their votes will play no role in elections.
In the beginning of Belizes history most of our people like the other ethnic groups supported the oldest political party, namely, the Peoples United Party (PUP). Then later on they started to support the United Democratic Party (UDP). Garifuna people in Belize tend to vote more for the candidate than the party. However, as time went by, the Garifuna people have seen very little return coming from these two parties but false promises so they change these parties from time to time.
Some Garifuna individuals and an organization in Belize are only in politics to promote themselves, their self interest and not their people. They are harmful to their people because once they become insulated in these political parties and they cannot speak out against their party policies that affect their people. I just hope and pray that this is not the same in Yurumein St Vincent and the Grenadines and the other countries where our people reside. Most Garifuna people in the United States support the Democratic Party.
This coming Sunday, May 30, 2015, there will be a town hall meeting, where the leader of the opposition New Democratic Party, Honourable Arnhim Eustace, will be making a proclamation on behalf of his Garifuna brothers and sisters who live in the Diaspora. The meeting will be held at the Friends of Crown Heights Hall located at 671 Prospect Place in Brooklyn between Franklin and Bedford Avenue at 5:00 pm.
The Garifuna organizations are calling on all their people to come and witness this historic event. Why? Because we have never heard what the position of this political party was when it comes to us, only what we were told by the other main party. It is always wise to listen to both sides before we come to a conclusion.
We have heard the position of the current party (ULP) that has been in power in St Vincent under Prime Minister Ralph Gonsalves for 14 years now, and have been given several promises but none of them has materialized. Promises undelivered in 14 years are unacceptable to our brave men and women who are living because of the sacrifices our ancestors made with their lives to make us exist. One year is too long to be waiting on anything much less 14 years.
We do not have that kind of patience and so should you my people. There is a famous saying that goes, A promise is a comfort to a fool. Our people are not fools because we know what we want and we are willing to fight for it. We will be looking forward to see you all at the town hall meeting on Sunday to hear this proclamation.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: From promises to policy to fruition</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-From-promises-to-policy-to-fruition-26306.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: From promises to policy to fruition
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
What is the agriculture sector contribution to GDP, particularly agro-processing?
Meeting of the Minds: Ken Morris, President of the Toco Fishing Association (left); Kishore Boodram, President of the Claxton Bay Fishing Association (right) as well as north coast farmers and community members in discussion with agricultural economist Omardath Maharaj (center) on the state of agriculture and fisheries recently.
Dear Sir:
At a public meeting in Valencia tonight, chairman of the PNM, Franklin Khan, promised road from Valencia to Toco and Ferry Service between Toco and Scarborough. No doubt many are hoping that these plans, though overdue, considered the increased traffic on the waterfront, reef protection, effluent pollution, noise and other variables which will impact turtle nesting, fisheries, sea moss and other niche market activities which sustain several families in those communities.
Careful assessment of the current state and potential of agriculture, land tenure and use, and their combined contribution with fisheries (need for proper stakeholder education followed by enforcement  fisheries management legislation) must be done. These are poised to quickly spur economic activity by absorbing unskilled and semi-skilled labour. Any meaningful, coordinated programme or project in consultation with the communities from Matura to Matelot will tangibly impact poverty alleviation with no less of a medium-term goal of sustaining livelihoods.
Nonetheless, there is still an impetus to strengthen our "bread baskets" and nurture new areas in the struggle to get planting material, support for activities from the line Ministry and affiliated State Agencies, support for public education and awareness, reduce the food import bill, reduce food price inflation, supply safe and affordable food, develop local food and nutrition security capacity, create viable agri-businesses especially for smallholders, respect for farmers and the land, equal opportunity employment in the sector and other mandates as set out in the Medium Term Policy Framework (2011-2014).
The geographic distribution of poverty in Trinidad and Tobago is highly unequal. The north-east and the south-west of Trinidad are among the two poorest areas; alongside the specific needs of East Port-of-Spain. Manzanilla, Kernahan Village, Mayaro, among others, come in high for consideration as well. The electorate will certainly look forward for justifications and performance reports of projects undertaken in the five growth pole areas targeted for concentrated economic development over the last 5 years vis--vis outcomes.
Will any clear development plans or realistic agriculture sector policy be discussed this election season? Will an understanding of the intricate links between agriculture and any other sector as well as its role in development albeit at the individual, community or national level be brought into office? Will the grassroots, the Tableland Pineapple Farmers Association, Claxton Bay Fishing Association, Otaheite Fisher Folk Association, Felicity Charlieville Fishing Association, Women in Fishing Association, La Brea Fishing Association, and the Guayaguayare Ortoire Mayaro Fishing Association for example, be consulted and included in any national development agenda? Will Trinidad and Tobago experience government of the people, by the people, for the people in 2015?
Thousands in the sector and our dependents are asking.
Omardath Maharaj
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WIPA 'disappointed' in treatment of Chanderpaul by WICB</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-WIPA-%27disappointed%27-in-treatment-of-Chanderpaul-by-WICB-26307.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
WIPA 'disappointed' in treatment of Chanderpaul by WICB
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
KINGSTON, Jamaica -- The president and the executive of the West Indies Players Association has expressed its immense disappointment over the treatment by the West Indies Cricket Board (WICB) of Shivnarine Chanderpaul, who has given over two decades of service to West Indies cricket.
Shivnarine Chanderpaul
The WIPA said in a press release that the treatment is especially disturbing since it has come after a statement made by WICB president Dave Cameron where he stated: at the end of a long and illustrious career like Shivnarine Chanderpauls we want to ensure that whatever we do, it is well respected and that he knows and the region knows how much we value his services to West Indies cricket.
Chanderpaul, the WICB/WIPA Test Cricketer of the Year for 2014, was not selected by the WICB to play in the upcoming home series against Australia. He averages 51.37 and has played in 164 Test matches, the most by a West Indian. At present he is the West Indies highest ICC ranked Test batsman and a man who has on numerous occasions held the West Indies batting innings together, the WIPA pointed out.
His contributions were also acknowledged by chairman of selectors Clive Lloyd, when he said at a recent press conference: The guy has been a great servant to our cricket and when that time comes, I think he should be given that sort of send-off that is expected of a player of his calibre.
WIPAs president and CEO Wavell Hinds, when questioned on the issue, said on Wednesday: The West Indies Players Association acknowledges and accepts that the purview of selecting the West Indies cricket team lies solely and independently with the selection panel led by chairman Clive Lloyd, however we are very disappointed in the manner which Mr Chanderpaul was treated. WIPA believes the process of omitting Mr Chanderpaul was untidy and distasteful. We will continue to have dialogue with the West Indies Cricket Board with the hope to bring an amicable solution in the best interests of Shivnarine Chanderpaul and West Indies cricket.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smile and Wave wins first Heineken Star Cup in Puerto Rico</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Smile-and-Wave-wins-first-Heineken-Star-Cup-in-Puerto-Rico-26308.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Smile and Wave wins first Heineken Star Cup in Puerto Rico
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Smile and Wave, winner of the Heineken Star Cup Circuit
SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico -- The Puerto Rico Heineken International Regatta (PRHIR) and the Puerto Rico International Dinghy Regatta ended with great results, after three days of intense competition at The Yacht Club in Palmas del Mar, Humacao.
Past 2 in the afternoon, the vessels started arriving to the marina after their last races of the competition, where they anxiously awaited the award ceremony.
Nature blessed us with great winds and great sunlight. Nevertheless, we would like to thank everyone that worked voluntarily at the regatta and we hope that next time its just as successful as this one so we can keep encouraging the sport of sailing in the island, said Ral Ros, president of the Sailing Federation of Puerto Rico.
This year, the Puerto Rico Heineken International Regatta premiered the Heineken Star Cup, a new circuit that joined all the best sailing events of the Caribbean.
The Smile and Wave team, captained by Jaime Torres, was awarded the prestigious Cup after demonstrating excellent performance in all participating categories and having the best results in three of the four regattas. These include the St Maarten Heineken Regatta, Puerto Del Rey Challenge, British Virgin Islands Spring Regatta and the Puerto Rico Heineken International Regatta, where the winner was announced and awarded.
Even though we are exhausted, I feel very happy and terribly satisfied after three months of nonstop competition, Torres said.
The team and I are very excited because the Heineken Star Cup is the birth of a new circuit thats going to become a world class event and we are very proud that Smile and Wave is the first winner of the Cup, he added.
Smile and Wave won the Heineken Star Cup with a trophy designed and inspired by navigational elements, made by the renowned Puerto Rican sculptor, Victor Monserrate. Its a unique piece, handmade with recycled metal, carbon fiber and glass from Heineken bottles. The team led by Jaime Torres also received $1,000 as cash prize.
In addition to the Melges 32s award, the results of PRHIR culminated as follows: In the category CSA  Racing, the boat Dark Star won, captained by Jonathan Lipuseck. Meanwhile, in the Jib &amp; Main category the first place went to Swan 53, led by Claudia Nicolow. In the IC 24, Mike Finley won first place with his boat, Ocean Potion; in Chalanas 24, Alfred Fortier led with his boat Hurricane and in the category Raya, Carlos Rosario won in Guatu.
It was an excellent and the very close competition. My team were all sailing students with just 15 hours of instruction and little by little they kept learning and getting better so I am very happy with the results we achieved, said Yoyo Berros, owner and instructor of Y Sailing, whose team finished third in the Jib and Jab category.
On the other hand, the Puerto Rico International Dinghy Regatta, that ran along with the PRHIR, resulted as followed: for the Optimist Advanced category, the winner was Jos Arturo Daz; in the Optimist Green category (Beginners), Enrique Matta won; in the Sunfish Open, the first place went to Ramn Gonzlez Bernazar; in the Lazer 4.7 won Ricardo Valenzuela and in the Hobie 16 B category, Julio Cceres. Finally, in the Hobbie Cat 16 category, the Heineken team retained the first place, captained by Francisco Faccio Figueroa and Jolliam Berrros.
The weather conditions were always on our favor and that was noticeable during the three days of competition. There is no doubt that the Puerto Rico Heineken International Regatta and the Puerto Rico International Dinghy Regatta are great examples of the continuous development of the sailing sport in the Island, said Jolliam Berros, senior brand manager at Mndez &amp; Co. and outstanding sailor.
Over 67 vessels participated in both in the Puerto Rico Heineken International Regatta and the Puerto Rico International Dinghy Regatta. Weather conditions were optimal for sailing during the three days.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu May 28 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cuban national baseball team to play Baltimore Orioles this year</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cuban-national-baseball-team-to-play-Baltimore-Orioles-this-year-26309.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cuban national baseball team to play Baltimore Orioles this year
Published onMay 28, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
The Baltimore Orioles will play the Cuban national baseball team later this year
HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- Cuba's national baseball team will face the Baltimore Orioles this year, at a date yet to be fixed.
The president of the Cuban Sports Institute (INDER), Antonio Becali, told the press that there will be an exhibition game with the Orioles, which will take place on the island during 2015.
Becali said that in recent months other top baseball teams in the US have expressed their interest in playing against the Cuban team.
The Baltimore Orioles made history 16 years ago as the first Major League Baseball (MLB) team to play against a Cuban rival since 1959, by staging a two-game friendly series, held in both countries. The US squad won 3-2 in the first game, held at Havana's Latin American Stadium on March 28, 1999, while on May 3 of that same year Cuba defeated the Baltimore Orioles 12-6, at Oriole Park, Camden Yards, in Baltimore.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cuba visit would be great pleasure for Obama, says White House</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cuba-visit-would-be-great-pleasure-for-Obama%2C-says-White-House-26282.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cuba visit would be great pleasure for Obama, says White House
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
White House spokesman, Josh Earnest
WASHINGTON, USA (ACN) -- A visit to Cuba would give President Barack Obama, and especially Havana, great pleasure, White House spokesman, Josh Earnest, stated at a press conference in Washington.
"I know a visit to Cuba would give him great pleasure and especially Havana," Earnest told Cuban television journalist Cristina Escobar in the last question granted by the official, after Oliver Knox, accredited correspondent for Yahoo News, highlighted the presence of the island's press delegation in Washington to cover the third round of negotiations between the two countries.
The spokesman welcomed the press group to Washington, something unprecedented in recent decades at the headquarters of the executive.
In his regular meeting with dozens of reporters at the White House, the spokesman commented some issues of the bilateral dialogue process.
Earnest assured in relation to the talks that the president declared in December, when changes toward Cuba were announced, his intention to work with the Cuban government to open a US embassy on the island and in the United States.
"This is the intention," he pointed out.
He said that the rapprochement between the two nations would benefit his country from the commercial point of view since business opportunities could increase.
Julia Sweig, former director for Latin American Studies at the Council on Foreign Relations, a US think tank, told reporters that the change in policy toward the island is one of the five most successful initiatives developed by Obama in his two terms and will contribute to his legacy in international affairs.
US public opinion, even in Florida, has changed in favour of improved relations between the United States and Cuba.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guyana's new president should avoid being baited by Chinese investors, says author</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Guyana%27s-new-president-should-avoid-being-baited-by-Chinese-investors%2C-says-author-26283.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Guyana's new president should avoid being baited by Chinese investors, says author
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
NEW YORK, USA -- Citing several instances of Chinese corrupt practices, and accusing them of being guilty of seriously compromising the Guyanese citizenship process, Guyana born author, researcher and international journalist Dennis Adonis has urged the countrys newly sworn in head of state, Brigadier (ret.) David Granger, not to be baited by a Chinese invitation to speak at a conference organized by a trade organization that is representing their interest in Guyana.
Dennis Adonis
Adonis suggested that, if the head of state accepts such an invitation, it would amount to a presidential endorsement of Bai Shan Lin, and all of the other Chinese operations that had mercilessly raped Guyana under the recently defeated PPP/C government.
As such, Adonis urged the recently elected Guyanese president to use his better judgment and send some other lower ranking official to the event to simply give them a hearing, rather than putting himself there.
He was at the time facilitating a Skype opinion interview on judicial corruption with the New York Times, in which a few other international media houses were allowed to listen in.
According to the sometimes controversial author, it is public knowledge that hundreds of foreign nationals, mainly Chinese, Indians and Brazilians are in possession of Guyanese passports that were obtained by barefaced underhand dealings and which would deny them the right to even be sitting in the same room with a Guyanese head of state.
He stated that, should Granger attend the conference, he would be rolling himself in flour that is overwhelmingly mixed with corruption.
He added that, after that proverbial flour stage, the president would be repeatedly fried by these people without even realizing it.
While agreeing that there may be a few genuine Chinese investors in Guyana, he labeled most of them as commercial exploiters who have no other objective than to extensively enrich themselves at the expense of the poor.
As such, he added that any meeting with them would mean sitting invitingly in bed with the people who are plundering the country.
If the president speaks at that conference, he would be sitting in bed with a group of people who have plundered our countrys natural resources, exploited our people, and are responsible for the loss of thousands of jobs that belongs to the Guyanese people, he said.
Adonis is of the view that the president should first meet with the local business community to hear their story, and organizations that represents the ordinary citizens before he adheres to any request to speak to a group of foreign nationals who are fully aware that they will soon be targeted for corrupt practices and past indiscretions that they have committed against the country.
Guyana is believed to have the largest population of migrating Chinese in the Caribbean, and similarly the largest working population of Brazilians, Russians and Indian nationals for any Caribbean Community (CARICOM) member state.
The countrys citizens and businesses have repeatedly accused Chinese investors of exploiting their economic generosity and continue to blame them for Guyanas growing unemployment crisis.
The then opposition APNU+AFC, led by now elected President Granger, had long promised to tackle corrupt practices involving a number of Chinese owned entities in Guyana.
Granger became head of state after defeating the PPP/C at the recently held May 11 general elections, on a platform to tackle corrupt practices that were allegedly flourishing under the previous administration.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OAS congratulates people of Suriname for exemplary civic spirit in 2015 general elections</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-OAS-congratulates-people-of-Suriname-for-exemplary-civic-spirit-in-2015-general-elections-26284.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
OAS congratulates people of Suriname for exemplary civic spirit in 2015 general elections
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PARAMARIBO, Suriname -- The electoral observation mission of the Organization of American States (OAS/EOM) has congratulated the citizens of Suriname for their exemplary civic spirit and active participation in the electoral process, reflected in the voter turnout in Mondays general elections.
The 24-member team comprised of 13 nationalities, headed by Chilean international expert Irene Klinger, observed the elections in 61% of polling stations in all ten districts of the country and was pleased to witness that the process was carried out in an orderly, peaceful and even festive manner.
The OAS/EOM thanked the government of Suriname for the invitation to observe this process and recognizes the efforts undertaken by the ministry of home affairs, the Central Polling Authority and the Independent Electoral Council to prepare and conduct the 2015 general elections.
The OAS team reported that the polling stations observed opened on time, were adequately staffed and fully equipped with all the materials required for the election. The mission highlighted the extraordinary commitment and diligence of polling station members, oversight personnel and security agents in the exercise of their duties and commends political parties for the camaraderie shown throughout the day at polling stations.
The OAS/EOM was pleased to verify that some of the recommendations made by the OAS in 2010 have been adopted for this electoral process. These include the introduction of separate ballot boxes (stembuzen) for the local and national elections, which facilitated the ballot counting after the closing of the polls, and the increase in the political representation of women in political party candidate lists.
In the spirit of further assisting Suriname in its efforts to continue strengthening its electoral process, the electoral observation mission offered the following preliminary findings and recommendations, which are based on a thorough analysis of the electoral legal framework, and on the information gathered by the delegation as a result of exchanges with national and electoral authorities, as well as with the Surinamese civil society, political parties and the international community in the pre-electoral phase and during election day.
1. The OAS/EOM noticed that the average number of people represented in each electoral district varies significantly. A seat in one district can represent almost ten times more voters than in another. Suriname could explore mechanisms to remedy these disparities to ensure a more balanced representation of inhabitants per district while at the same time securing representation for all regions.
2. The mission noted that Suriname has limited regulations regarding political-campaign financing and information disclosure on sources of funding. In addition, no form of political party direct or indirect public financing exists. The OAS/EOM identified the need for Suriname to discuss and incorporate regulations regarding political-campaign financing and to consider introducing some sort of public funding scheme for political parties.
3. The OAS electoral observation mission was pleased to observe the increased number of female candidates and the progress seen in their ranking in higher positions in party lists as a result of the efforts made by the National Assembly and civil society organizations. On this occasion 128 candidates, or 33% of the total number, were women compared to 90 in the last election. The mission urged parties to continue providing women with more favorable positions within party structures and in the candidate lists in order to enhance their possibilities of being elected. Affirmative action measures, such as quotas and alternation mechanisms, could be introduced to promote gender equality in electoral competition.
4. The OAS/EOM welcomes the efforts made to improve the access to polling stations for persons with disabilities, including the introduction of special voting booths. However, throughout the country OAS observers noticed that there were discrepancies in the procedures used to assist the elderly and persons with disabilities. In some polling stations family members accompanied them, while in others assistance was provided by polling station personnel and party representatives. The mission suggested that electoral authorities consider drafting a uniform procedure for assisting those voters who require additional help.
The mission reminded the public that official results of the National Assembly and regional and local council elections will be provided by the Central Polling Authority and certified by the Independent Electoral Council in accordance with the national legislation.
The EOM thanked the governments of Canada, Chile, France, Italy, the United Kingdom, the United States and Spain for their contributions that made this mission possible.
In the coming weeks Klinger will present a detailed report on the observations and recommendations of the OAS electoral observation mission to the OAS Permanent Council in Washington, DC.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
