<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CARICOM summit a success, says Barbados PM</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-CARICOM-summit-a-success%2C-says-Barbados-PM-26813.html</Link>
        <Description>BRIDGETOWN, Barbados (BGIS) -- Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM), Barbados Prime Minister Freundel Stuart, considers the just-concluded 36th CARICOM heads of government meeting, held in Barbados from July 2 to 4, a success.</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
CARICOM summit a success, says Barbados PM
Published onJuly 7, 2015
CARICOM Heads of Government in Barbados
By Melissa Rollock
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados (BGIS) -- Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM), Barbados Prime Minister Freundel Stuart, considers the just-concluded 36th CARICOM heads of government meeting, held in Barbados from July 2 to 4, a success.
Speaking during the closing press conference on Saturday night, Stuart said he and his colleagues focused on three major areas: energy; bolstering education systems to build the social and economic resilience of countries; border issues  particularly the existing dispute between Venezuela and Guyana  and the looming humanitarian crisis in Haiti created by the actions of the Dominican Republic.
On the issue of energy, Stuart said the leaders welcomed the establishment of a Caribbean Centre for Renewable Energy, which will be the implementation hub for sustainable energy activities and projects within the Caribbean. He added that Barbados would be the host country for this centre.
The CARICOM chairman further disclosed that the government of Trinidad and Tobago had proposed the creation of a Caribbean Energy Fund, which received the support of the other heads. During their discourse, the leaders also addressed the ongoing border dispute between Venezuela and Guyana. Stuart cautioned, however, that it was not one that could be resolved with the snap of a finger, as it was a very old dispute.
We met with a delegation from Venezuela and we tried to get some of those issues sorted out. Of course, the main target of that decree was our original CARICOM member state the co-operative Republic of Guyana. And, therefore, we felt as a matter of principle and solidarity with our CARICOM brothers and sisters in Guyana, we had to take a stand, the chairman stated.
He continued: "Border issues are inherently very difficult and, therefore, what one has to aim for is a cooling of tempers whenever they flare up. We do not think there can be any compromise as far as Guyana's territorial borders are concerned...."
Stuart pointed out, however that CARICOM also enjoyed cordial relations with Venezuela, and was not about to disrupt or pollute that relationship.
Turning his focus to the treatment of Haitians in the Dominican Republic, the chairman said that CARICOM would fight for its Haitian brothers and sisters.
We think what has been happening to undocumented Haitians in the Dominican Republic and what has been happening to people of Haitian descent being born in the Dominican Republic is totally unacceptable to us in CARICOM. It is inconsistent with the values to which we subscribe.
CARICOM's position is extremely clear; we are going to fight this issue to the end...and we will not rest until we get that situation brought under control. More and more attention is being drawn to the horror of the situation which Haitians are facing in the Dominican Republic. We are sure that the robustness of public opinion, global opinion on this issue will help in the resolution of this matter," Stuart asserted.
Other matters discussed during the three-day conference were, access to concessional development financing for Small Island Developing States  the leaders believe that a vulnerability measure instead of one based on GDP per capita should be used to determine the economic health of these islands; and a universally binding agreement that would include a limit on global warming to below 1.5 degrees centigrade with regards to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change.
Talks also centred on an assessment of decision-making mechanisms within the Caribbean community in light of the fact that decisions made within CARICOM territories were all subject to review by the Caribbean Court of Justice.
Generally speaking, I think we had a successful conference. As I said in my opening address on Thursday evening, there will always be things that the Caribbean Community has not yet been able to do, and there will always be things that we have already done that it can be argued that we can do better. But, in the context of the realities we now face, I am satisfied, and I think the consensus of the conference was, at its close, that we had a successful CARICOM conference, Stuart emphasised.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bahamas government moves to get back land from bankrupt developer</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bahamas-government-moves-to-get-back-land-from-bankrupt-developer-26814.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bahamas government moves to get back land from bankrupt developer
Published onJuly 7, 2015
By Candia Dames
Nassau Guardian Managing Editor
NASSAU, Bahamas -- In the latest developments surrounding the Baha Mar crisis, the Bahamas attorney general has filed a writ seeking to claw back Crown land from the developer of the troubled Cable Beach project.
However, under its agreement with the government, Baha Mar would still have an option to get ownership of the land if it completes the project within three years.
The writ filed by the attorney general states that Baha Mar and the government entered into several agreements in 2005 in connection with the development of a resort complex.
The writ states that all of the agreements contained clauses stipulating that in certain circumstances if Baha Mar failed to complete specified obligations by expressed dates, the government could exercise the right to serve notices on Baha Mar requiring it to re-convey the properties it purchased as part of the deal.
These properties include the Nassau Beach parcel, the Wyndham parcel, the Hobby Horse parcel, the extinguished JFK connector parcel and the old West Bay Street parcels.
The relevant circumstances have arisen and in particular the defendant (Baha Mar) has failed to fulfill its obligations within the relevant time periods as specified in the agreements, the writ states.
Consequently, by respective notices served and dated June 30, 2015, and by tendering and making the appropriate payments (and undertaking the pay pursuant to the formulas specified in the agreement any further sums due), the plaintiff (the government) invoked its right and the defendants obligation to re-convey the properties.
Under the agreement for sale of the land dated April 6, 2005 and signed by prime minister and minister of finance Perry Christie, Baha Mar and the government agreed that if the project was not completed by December 31, 2010, Baha Mar shall re-convey the property to the government.
The agreement stipulates that the government would re-instate the lease previously held by the developer.
Thereafter, the agreement states, the government shall grant to the purchaser a purchase option whereby Baha Mar shall have the right to immediately purchase the land if the project is completed within three years from the effective date of the re-conveyance of the land.
Under the agreement, project completion refers to the opening for business of the luxury hotel facilities.
Under the amended agreement Baha Mar entered into with the Ingraham administration, the date for project completion was amended to December 31, 2014.
The date by which the government had to give notice for Baha Mar to re-convey the land in the absence of the project being completed was amended to June 30, 2015, hence the urgency in the government providing notice last week.
One legal source explained that if this goes on for more than three years, then the Bahamian peoples interest in the property is protected.
Another source added that if the government failed to take steps by June 30 to have the land re-conveyed, the properties would have been vested in Izmirlians companies.
The land re-conveyance issue arises as Baha Mar remains stalled and embroiled in a sticky legal dispute with its contractor.
Last Monday, Baha Mar filed for chapter 11 bankruptcy in the U.S. district of Delaware and warned that it would have to cut jobs if it does not resolve the matter in the next few weeks.
A day later, it filed a lawsuit in England against its contractor, China State Construction Engineering Corporation, seeking more than $192 million in damages to compensate for delays and reported substandard work.
The future of the project is uncertain. It is unknown when it will likely be complete, although Baha Mar alleges it is 98 percent complete.
The parties are due back in the Bahamian Supreme Court on Tuesday as Baha Mar seeks to convince Justice Ian Winder to approve orders secured in a US court to tap into a financing facility it says it intends to use to continue paying employee wages, benefits and vendor claims, It also received authorization for severance payments.
Baha Mars lawyer Roy Sweeting said in court last Thursday that approval of those orders is crucial to keeping the lights on at Baha Mar and keeping operations going.
The government and Baha Mars lenders, China Export-Import Bank, have both objected to the orders being approved locally.
Republished with permission of the Nassau Guardian

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian investigators to examine doctor's body in Panama to confirm death</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Canadian-investigators-to-examine-doctor%27s-body-in-Panama-to-confirm-death-26815.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Canadian investigators to examine doctor's body in Panama to confirm death
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Controversial oncologist Dr Arthur Porter died in custody in Panama on June 30, 2015
By Toni Frederick
BASSETERRE, St Kitts (WINN) -- Investigators with Quebec's Anti-Corruption Unit have received permission to view the body of Dr Arthur Porter in Panama in order to confirm his death, the Toronto Star reported.
Porter, the physician at the centre of a recent St Kitts and Nevis diplomatic controversy, died in custody in Panama last Tuesday.
According to the Star, a spokesperson for the Anti-Corruption Unit confirmed that investigators will be allowed to enter the morgue in order to collect fingerprints and visually identify Porter's body.
The Sierra Leone national and Canadian citizen, who set up cancer clinics throughout the Caribbean, was accused of diverting millions of dollars in a hospital bribery scandal in Canada.
Porter, an oncologist who had held prominent posts in Canada including the chairmanship of the Intelligence Review Committee, overseeing Canada's intelligence agency (CSIS), had terminal lung cancer when he was detained in Panama in 2013.
At the time, Porter and his wife were travelling from The Bahamas to St Kitts and Nevis via Panama, when they were arrested at the Panama City Airport on an international warrant, by INTERPOL and the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP).
He was reported to have been travelling on a St Kitts and Nevis diplomatic passport.
Porter, who gained St Kitts and Nevis citizenship through its citizenship by investment programme, reportedly owned at least two properties on St Kitts, and was supposed to establish a cancer treatment centre in the Federation.
Former prime minister Dr Denzil Douglas insisted that Porter did not have a diplomatic passport. Douglas told the Parliament that Porter had been approved by Cabinet to serve as St Kitts and Nevis consul general to the Bahamas, but said that the Bahamian government had not granted approval.
Porter died under armed guard at the Instituo Oncologico Nacional hospital in Panama. Before being transferred to the hospital he had been held in custody in jail, awaiting extradition to Canada.
Porter was allegedly involved in a multi-million dollar kickback scheme in that country, and was wanted in connection with fraud, conspiracy to commit fraud, fraud against the government, embezzlement, breach of trust, secret commissions and laundering proceeds of crime, according to Quebec's Anti-Corruption Unit.
The Canadian Prime Ministers Office has said it will not be issuing a statement about Porters death. As he was a member of the Privy Council Office, protocol dictates that flags be lowered to half mast. The Montreal Gazette reported, however, that a source within the Prime Ministers Office has said that in this case, the protocol would be waived.
The Toronto Star meanwhile reported that the head of the Anti-Corruption Unit and a Quebec Crown prosecutor have both said they would not close Porter's file without official confirmation of his death.
According to the Star, two officers from the Anti-Corruption Unit arrived in Panama on Friday and were expected to visit the morgue on Monday.
Republished with permission of West Indies News Network

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South African minister arrives in Haiti following visit to Suriname</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-South-African-minister-arrives-in-Haiti-following-visit-to-Suriname-26816.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
South African minister arrives in Haiti following visit to Suriname
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Luwellyn Landers
PORT AU PRINCE, Haiti -- Luwellyn Landers, South Africas deputy minister of international relations and cooperation, arrived in Haiti on Monday after concluding a successful visit to Suriname.
While in Suriname, Landers held bilateral discussion with the minister of foreign affairs, Winston Lackin. During the visit to Suriname, the two countries also signed a memorandum of understanding on political consultations. The MoU will serve as a framework for the two countries to manage their bilateral relations and will further help to strengthen diplomatic relations.
The deputy minister also paid a courtesy call on the governor of the Central Bank of Suriname, Gilmore Hoefdraad. The two exchanged views on various pertinent issues and also echoed the need for South Africa and Suriname to find common areas of cooperation.
Suriname and South Africa have enjoyed cordial reciprocal diplomatic relations since 1995. Suriname was represented in the Global African Diaspora Summit held in South Africa in 2012. The economy of Suriname is dominated by the mining industry, with exports of oil, gold and alumina accounting for about 85% of its exports.
During his visit to Haiti, Landers is expected to hold bilateral discussions with the minister of foreign affairs, Lener Renauld. The deputy minister will also pay a courtesy call on President Michel Martelly.
Haiti is the fourth country the deputy minister is visiting during his five nation tour to the Caribbean.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Visiting yachtsman stabbed multiple times in robbery attempt in St Lucia</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Visiting-yachtsman-stabbed-multiple-times-in-robbery-attempt-in-St-Lucia-26817.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Visiting yachtsman stabbed multiple times in robbery attempt in St Lucia
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
RODNEY BAY, St Lucia -- In an apparent attempt to rob a visiting vessel in May, a swimmer tripped over and woke the skipper who was sleeping in the cockpit of a boat anchored near shore at Reduit Beach in Saint Lucia, Caribbean Safety and Security Net (CSSN) reported.
The robber proceeded to attack the skipper with a knife; the skipper received 20 stab wounds, 17 of which required stitches, before the skipper was able to throw the attacker overboard. A second person onboard was awakened by the activity and assisted in summoning help and transporting the victim to police who were waiting ashore and then transported the victim to the local hospital for treatment.
The skipper was hospitalized for six days. A police report was made, but no arrests followed.
Meanwhile, earlier this month in Bequia, St Vincent and the Grenadines, the crew and a dog on board a visiting vessel were awakened at 4:30 am by strange, sloshing sounds. Two men in a local (later learned to be stolen) double bow skiff were discovered at the stern step of the catamaran. Lights and yelling caused the men to paddle away after making excuses about "being fishermen", etc.
The next day, the catamaran owner made a report on the local VHF net and went ashore, where the skiff and its true owner were discovered. The owner indicated he planned to lock the skiff up in the future.
A police report was attempted, but yacht owners were advised since they had not been boarded and nothing was taken, no report could be made. The skiff owner did make a police report.
The local Coast Guard patrol boat was back in operation the following night and made several passes through the anchorage.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Changing the international perception of the Caribbean from tourism</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Changing-the-international-perception-of-the-Caribbean-from-tourism-26818.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Changing the international perception of the Caribbean from tourism
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
The group of IPAs that attended the tour
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- One of the challenges we face in the region is how to change the perception of the Caribbean as being that of a destination solely for vacation tourism. This was the view from president of the Caribbean Association of Investment Promotion Agencies (CAIPA), McHale Andrew, of Invest Saint Lucia last week during a study tour to Columbian Investment Promotion Agencies (PROColombia) and Invest in Bogota, where a delegation supported by the Caribbean Export Development Agency (Caribbean Export) in collaboration with CAIPA, visited to seek insight in to the best practices for country branding strategies to attract foreign direct investment (FDI).
The Caribbean is well known a top holiday destination that promises sun, sea and sand all year round; however, increasingly the need for the Caribbean to be known for more than this is being called for to attract the levels of FDI required to provide economic diversity and growth for our long term sustainability.
PROColombia and Invest in Bogota have been recognised as best practice examples for in-country and city branding, respectively. Twenty investment promotion representatives from 14 of the regions investment promotion agencies (IPAs) were part of the three-day visit to increase their understanding and exposure to how an in-country branding strategy could assist in influencing perceptions and ultimately attracting investment.
Through this visit, we were able to engage with investment promotion experts who have been integral to the process of changing perceptions of investors about the country of Colombia and have seen significant successes in a short period of time, noted McHale.
A key suggestion from the mission was the importance of developing integrated campaigns that focus on the unique aspects of the Caribbean. These campaigns would ideally target Caribbean nationals locally to support the instillation of national pride across the region, and cultivate a brand that all Caribbean citizens can utilise in the promotion of their products or services in addition to fostering ongoing regional integration.
This activity was implemented with support from the Inter-American Development Bank as a part of a Regional Public Goods Programme with the Caribbean entitled: Support to FDI in the Caribbean. The study tour was also made possible with the support of the European Union under the 10th European Development Fund Regional Private Sector Development Programme which includes the Bi-National Haiti/Dominican Republic Programme. It supports Caribbean Exports objective of strengthening Caribbean IPAs in order to increase foreign direct investment in the region and follows on several such initiatives undertaken recently including a CAIPA study Tour to PRONicaragua and JAMPRO in 2014.
Participating IPAs included: Antigua and Barbuda Investment Authority (ABIA), Invest Barbados, the Bahamas Investment Authority (BIA), the Belize Trade &amp; Investment Development Service (BELTRAIDE), Curacao Investment and Export Promotion Agency (CINEX), the Centre for Exports and Investment in the Dominican Republic (CEI-RD), the Grenada Industrial Development Corporation (GIDC), the Guyana Office for Investment (GO-INVEST), the Centre for Facilitation of Investments in Haiti, Invest Saint Lucia (ISL), Jamaica Promotion Corporation (JAMPRO), investSVG (St Vincent and the Grenadines), the Investment and Development Corporation of Suriname (IDCS), invesTT (Trinidad and Tobago).

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Blindfolds measure up conveniently in St Lucia</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Blindfolds-measure-up-conveniently-in-St-Lucia-26819.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Blindfolds measure up conveniently in St Lucia
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Melanius Alphonse
Under Saint Lucias party control system, defining a distinctive edge to untapped generation change, accompanied by political change is nonexistent. Alongside this backdrop, an unreal strategic assessment of market conditions and unrelated investment is contributing to widening the socio-economic divide.
Melanius Alphonse is a management and development consultant. He is an advocate for community development, social justice, economic freedom and equality; the Lucian Peoples Movement (LPM) spokesman on youth initiative, infrastructure, economic and business development. He can be reached at malphonse@rogers.com
Based on this approach, market fragmentation is assisting to ensure party elites interest become the will of the people in the institutions of state power. The take away from this is despite the fact that Saint Lucia is endowed with a natural environment, and many competitive options there is little room for comfort in a disruptive marketplace poorly inhabited with deepening inequality.
Outside the spectacle of theatre, the business community is on the rocks with an almost indefensible feeling, contemplating their next move.
Like the economy, government continues to fail in the delivery of the most basic services.
Access and affordability to good health care is inadequate. The educational system is problematic. Attention to sanitation is poor. The delivery of reliable drinking water, housing, a reliable food source and dependable security has outgrown present day suitability.
And it does not take much visual insight and intellectual competence to sum up the adverse impact of these unacceptable basic deficiencies to people and country.
Statistics of distraction
Irrespective of the applicable concepts of political distraction, people are up in arms; they have not progressed by definition, and done well as expected from increases in tourism arrivals!
According to tourism officials, visitor arrivals to the region were up 6% at the end of the first quarter, whilst Saint Lucia alone recorded a 6.4% growth over the same period last year. At the end of the first five months of the year, total stay-over arrivals to the island were 159,077; up 5.5% from the same period in 2014.
Ideally, this crescendo should be stacked up against modest development, along with an impact assessment on the business community, climate change, farmers, vendors, and to what extent service providers have taken ownership of the industry!
This information is essential to understand the real statistics that matter; the socio-economic impact on the overall economy and deprivation strategies.
But really, are Saint Lucians feeling the effects of 6.4% increase and previous figures over the last three years that show record arrivals? The answer is an obvious no!
The troubling evidence is a visible decline in visitor expenditure and buoyancy in the economy, which is in sync with the common reality, except government handlers are carefully muzzled to disclose and prescribe otherwise.
In the politics of statistics, attention is adjudicated to perception, focusing on what will most likely sink-in with a distracted electorate. And since statistics work in this instance, repetition is relentless for credit ratings by a deficient government, up to its neck in debt, unable to make a difference in the lives of people and country.
The important factor at play is Saint Lucias hopeless future of indebtedness on the heels of general election as creditors and decision makers look over the island fiscal structure with significant fear.
The visible indignity
Definitely, a change in mindset on what do to is required to gain forward momentum.
Recently, publicprivate partnership (P3s or PPP), is bandied around by the ardent socialist government of Saint Lucia, as if to having uncovered a novel concept. In any case, better late than never. However, it important to acknowledge, that P3s are a vital investment and development component for economic upturn.
On the other hand, when the pathway is influenced by external factors, with advance capability, to list Saint Lucia at number five on the slowest projected annual growth rate, or CAGR, from 2014 through 2017, based on the forecasts from the World Bank's Global Economic Prospects 2015 GDP: -0.60% 2016 GDP: +0.80% 2017 GDP: +1.40% 2014-17 GDP CAGR: +0.15%, among countries like: Ukraine, Venezuela, Libya, Belarus, Russia, Serbia, Brazil and Yemen  this is an about turn!
Appropriately, this report has stirred much discussion, but what should be taken away from this is Saint Lucias economy has been in a zombie state for the past four years, with no end in sight and borrowing heavily to quench the thirst for magnified expenditure.
Therefore, if the government look before you leap position is worthy of confirmation that it is now clear that the figures attributed to the World Bank are incorrect and outdated, then, are the numbers reported in the budget annually and information reported to other international institutions incorrect and outdated?
Because, irrespective of the attacks across the aisle, these numbers are significant in the global marketplace, with long lasting implications to Saint Lucias reputation and business classification which is already unfavourable at best.
The other aspect of significance is the European Union blacklist of the worlds worst tax havens.
It is encouraging that Saint Lucia was not placed on the list, unlike other Caribbean islands that were not so fortunate. However, there is work to be done and the Caribbean region must respond to this situation with collective action!
The instructive way
It has come to pass that the finance minister is unable to put the Saint Lucian economy in order, and hold persons responsible for the current dilemma.
Pretence will not deliver the prescription for development; therefore, cutting off the hands of corruption is a course correction that must be undertaken to uphold international covenants and preserve sovereignty.
Overcoming the current crisis is finding new paths to fairness and growth; meanwhile it should be made clear that the government of Saint Lucia cannot continue to show scant regard for accountability and transparency, to satisfy their mendicant habits with other peoples money.
Next, it is most critical that the finance minister undergoes a transformation to understand that the laws of finance should trump dark political art form that is incomparable with good governance, logic, arithmetic and science. And to reflect true priorities get funded to unlock economic potential .
Seeking a shortcut through the sale of Saint Lucian passports, the sale of the Queens chain and other prime holdings covertly, is ill advised at this time of unfettered risk, even though, favourable punctuated by party elites, with deep interest.
Industry observers note that the residence and citizenship programme as presented is flavored at the behest of intoxication, committed to the art form of prostitution on Saint Lucias patrimony, comprising the affluent Lambirds matter, IMPACS, the Cuban visa mystery and the possible smuggling ring in Saint Lucia that continues to boggle the minds of the professed best brains.
The reality is, when politicians and bureaucratic interest dont know what to do, they resort to raising process issues, which leaves the situation vulnerable to political charlatans, which tend to muddy the water in search of an escape route.
The fact of the matter is the elephant is still in the room and it is only an illusion to think that with time it will disappear or succumb to a natural death.
What this will trigger is an expeditious encounter with the US Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and the Department of Justice (DOJ).
These are some of the public issues overdue for in-depth analysis and correction, if the blindfolds of the state apparatus are favourable to light and the well being of the people and country. In contrast to the blindfolds and clever tailspins of deep seated benefactors.
Its like ignoring the law of gravity.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Baha Mar, a flagging economy and more bad news!</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Baha-Mar%2C-a-flagging-economy-and-more-bad-news%21-26820.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Baha Mar, a flagging economy and more bad news!
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Youri Kemp
The Baha Mar megaresort project in The Bahamas has hit a snag. Its developer, Mr Sarkis Izmirilian, filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy in the US state of Delaware on 29 June 2015. This is what one would call the sum of all fears!
Youri Kemp is president and CEO of Kemp Global, a management consultancy firm, based in The Bahamas, which serves all markets. Email: globalviewtoday@gmail.com
According to the declaration sent to the US courts in Delaware made by Baha Mar's CEO Tom Dunlap on behalf of its board of directors, essentially Baha Mar hit a cash-flow crisis resulting from delays in opening this megaresort due to a prolonged construction phase and additionally claims of less than stellar work done by the general contractor, China State Construction and Engineering, with the project also being financed by the Export Import Bank of China.
In a nutshell: Recurring costs through incomplete construction, in addition to weak revenue due to the fact that the project has not yet fully opened is really what it is.
Baha Mar was scheduled to open on two separate occasions, including the one now scheduled for October 2015: Once back in May 2015 that was put back because of construction being incomplete and back in November 2014 for reasons unknown at the time but that we can now say was due to the construction being incomplete.
The recent Chapter 11 filing puts the new opening date of October of this year in jeopardy as well. One glaring issue is that it is already July, and the bankruptcy filing was done no more than one week ago. The bankruptcy hearing can last for up to 120 days, which may not indicate that financing cannot be secured through the Delaware court to complete the project within that time, but even for that financing to snake down the pipeline; engage new contractors who may or may not work out in the short term; and continue on with Baha Mar's other management issues as a result of this bankruptcy filing, leaves one to question how doable the October 2015 date is as well.
We can only hope that this new date is doable and that the project hits all green lights coming down the lane in heavy, rush hour traffic. That and, even if only a short term measure, at least 50% of the resort can be opened and that the major works are fully completed with only finish-work remaining; i.e., cosmetic and aesthetically pleasing work.
To bolster the claim made in the bankruptcy filing in the Delaware court against the China State Construction Company is a simultaneous writ filed by the Baha Mar Group in the high court of the United Kingdom, seeking payment due to alleged damages done by the same construction company for $192 million dollars that Baha Mar officials claim was as a result of shoddy workmanship and cost overruns, resulting in further delays and damages.
To say that this is one huge cluster of confusion is an understatement. A huge cluster of confusion made more confusing due to the fact that the courts in Delaware granted Baha Mar Group access to $30 million in financing to help with payroll due to the filing, as well as deal with a few other minor matters. The Supreme Court of The Bahamas has seen fit not to move on that ruling from the court in Delaware (at least not up to the penning of this submission) and has instead gone on record as being "minded" not to grant this to Baha Mar. Under what premise exactly, we are not sure. However, as indicated by the attorney general, it raises sovereignty issues in that how can a court ruling in a foreign jurisdiction have any sway over the judicial system here?
Whatever the case is, I am minded to remind everyone that The Bahamas is an offshore financial centre. We deal with international business companies, their operations and wind-ups all the time. IBCs that conduct business in other countries but whose subsequent incorporation and supposed managerial structure is here in The Bahamas. This is not new to us, or should not be new to us.
Sovereignty concerns aside, the more important issue for us as a supposed financial and offshore jurisdiction leaves one to question why would a Bahamian company, albeit owned by a foreigner with status here in The Bahamas, feel the need to file in the Delaware court and also have his businesses incorporated there to boot?
A second important issue is that what should now be said, sovereignty sentiments aside, is how do we incorporate what is done in Delaware here in The Bahamas? Particularly in light of the fact that The Bahamas was promoted by the powers that be as having the potential to be an arbitration centre for such matters such as this Chapter 11 bankruptcy filing made by Baha Mar and the subsequent writ in the British High Court to the tune of $192 million. While this is something we can and should explore, but due to length and concentration I won't at this time.
However, this speaks to a second part of my humble submission: The lack and weakness of other components within the Bahamian economy.
It's no secret the Bahamian economy is faltering. One moiety being due to us putting so much time, money and human resources trying to shepherd one mega project, Baha Mar, to a successful completion and launch. The other part is due to what we have always been doing: Not taking concerted efforts and focus on diversifying established economies and trying to find out the potential of other sectors of the economy in creative and spirited ways.
Just recently, Standard and Poor's sent out an advisory about the possibility of a further downgrade of the Bahamian economy. Reasons they cite are, of course, the chaotic mess Baha Mar finds itself in, and how that affects every other part of the economy due to factors we have already mentioned: Over focus on said project and lack of focus on other areas.
Just to give a little more information on how and why the S&amp;P advisory should be taken very seriously: The Central Bank of The Bahamas, in addition to the International Monetary Fund in concert with the ministry of finance, have all pegged GDP growth in The Bahamas at a modest 1%. A negligible figure, for all intents and purposes. However, this 1% projected growth had factored in Baha Mar being opened and operating fully.
Clearly Baha Mar is not open and to make up any ground within the next two quarters of this fiscal year  which started on July 1, for all intents and purposes  with a very liberal date being set for Baha Mar's opening in October, we have some serious steering to do.
All of this having been made worse by a newly implemented value added tax in January 2015. The projected tax-take for the last two quarters of the previous fiscal year was $150 million, albeit unconfirmed. The total yearly projected tax-take is slated at just about $300 million.
What's even more concerning as the new VAT take is added into the mix, a weaker than normal growth trend, and with ratings agencies like S&amp;P wanting us to show more wisdom with our finances, the government has seen fit to pay the workers at Baha Mar their salaries to the tune of $7.5 million and have thusly foregone some of their debt obligations for a short time. We hope!
If this were to be a prolonged trend, with VAT gains being used to support Baha Mar's opening, with no idea if the resort will make what it claims it can make in this economy, with this Baha Mar project already estimated at having received over $1 billion in concessions that may not be in dollar figures account to value not being placed on other areas, in addition to Baha Mar having anywhere between 25% to 30% of our tourism revenue when you account for air arrivals, rooms, amenities, entertainment, employment and other related expenditures as a result of tourism activity, one cannot say that S&amp;P is not justified in their approach to cautioning us on a downgrade at their next visit and assessment of The Bahamas.
As this author had mentioned before with regard to an IMF consultation assessment done back in February of 2015, we just could not see, outside of the IMF being diplomatic and calming through times of change and chaos, could any favourable assessment be made with the prevailing matter of Baha Mar the way it was even back then, in addition to other matters highlighted and raised.
One can only hope for better for the future. But cautions being raised on the pending S&amp;P downgrade leave us a little dispirited and looking for solutions.
While a potential downgrade was not something expected to take place on the back of the stumbling of the Baha Mar project, particularly when the budget for the project was pegged at $3.5 billion, but we hope the wizards at the ministry of finance could persuade the ratings agencies to look at other areas of this economy in an attempt to show more favourable prospects in both long and medium term.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Senator Nazim Burke: The man who's bringing about change</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Senator-Nazim-Burke%3A-The-man-who%27s-bringing-about-change-26821.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Senator Nazim Burke: The man who's bringing about change
Published onJuly 7, 2015
Senator Nazim Burke speaking in New York
Dear Sir:
The Grenadian community in New York on Sunday, June 19, welcomed senator and leader of the National Democratic Congress (NDC) political party in Grenada, Nazim V. Burke, as he conveyed his views and positions to them. He said his party is committed to values providing real solutions for real problems.
We will continue to facilitate party growth and action at all levels. These values guide us in countering and changing consumption and destructive competition.
This present government is proving incapable of governing or working with people of this country. Without a true opposition party, as a counterweight, this NNP government will continue to serve only its 1%. It is imperative that we in the NDC find ways to make systemic changes. It is our responsibility to build the political culture of Grenada in order to stop erosion of our rights, and policies that perpetuate social and economic injustices. In order words, as leaders of the NDC political party, we must fundamentally change our Grenada's broken political system.
The leader engaged with his constituents in New York on policy issues by facilitating a series of three public meetings that culminated in one special event that saw him and the people engage in a truly national conversation on the issues. Following the success of the leader's final event, one observer noted, "The genie is now out of the bottle, it is no longer possible for politicians in Grenada to avoid the hard questions from their constituents."
In a face-to face interview with the leader, I asked him, "What is the status of the present government economy? His response, "A healthy economy is essential for improved infrastructure. The Grenadian economy is not growing. Economic growth must precede population growth. Grenada is beset by problems in the economy, a steadily worsening economy. It is with growth that jobs are created, standards of living elevated, and more Grenadians become taxpayers. With their tax payments, their stake in Grenada grows, as does their interest in an efficient and frugal government. Grenada is economically sinking and morally decaying. How can a country battered by public corruption, economically stagnating at home and vacilitating weakly, lay claim to the future? The answers lie perhaps in taking stock. By measuring, then marshaling assets tangible and unseen, we can glimpse a shining tomorrow if we are but willing to scrub our way through today.
I asked the leader, "Are the older politicians ever going to hand over the baton to young blood? He responded unequivocally that young and potential leaders must be committed, groomed and engaged as they will be future leaders. It is ultimately the voters who will decide if young leaders are ready.
The leader spoke highly of two young exceptional men within the NDC political party, Mr Ali Dowden and Mr Tevin Ishmael Andrews. Many youths are discovering that they can play some important roles in politics, saying "It's your future, so why let someone else determine your destiny. You can play a significant role in determining it yourself." His supporters say the leader is a powerful champion of the "little man".
Senator Burke wants to do everything he could to ensure that the NDC would remain what he believes it has become, the most creative political party in Grenada. Grenada is an atlas, very much alive, bursting with energy, straining to build, produce and grow. Powered by visions and values, by the people of the land.
"We as leaders of the NDC, stand and always will stand up for the people. We will stand for competition that will help to raise the well-being of the people to a higher level.
"We as a Grenadian people are usually acknowledged to be the most efficient people in the Caribbean as individuals, but we sometimes allow ourselves to be organized, or rather disorganized, at the top of the most miserably inefficient form of government that it would be possible to conceive. This NNP government is becoming increasingly dangerous to our national welfare.
"He who wrestles with us," wrote Burke, "strengthens our nerves, and sharpens our skill. Our antagonist is our helper."
A good opposition forces a government to improve itself. Grenada does not have a real democratic opposition in Parliament at this time, that's the reason this Mitchell NNP government does whatever they feel. We need to put policy in place to fight and represent our people. Her Majestys Opposition is recognized to be an integral part of the government system."
Senator/leader of the National Democratic Congress is a perfect picture of the professional politician that the people want in government. A winning leader and the people must continue with their support. There is a serious flaw in the NNP political scheme, which is the difficulty of finding anybody to speak for the people and country as a whole.
The NDC mission and purpose and historic role is of course to unite men, not divide. The NNP government in Grenada is not a mass party and, in all likelihood, will never become one. But it has a solid core of some hardened professional revolutionists, from the people's viewpoint they are expendable, so it is natural for the leader of government to employ them for all sorts of conspiratorial purposes.
We the people, as we plan for the general welfare, do not choose to be "protected", to the contrary, we in the NDC have adopted it as our "way of life" our method of doing the work of governing for which, as citizens, we are responsible.
"Certainly, our action must be guided, not by the principles of the NNP, but by ours, the principles of the NDC. This government has no sense of community responsibility. Unless the economic well-being of our citizens and our communities can be maintained, local businesses and our people will continue to suffer. Therefore we in the NDC will continue the fight for change, we are the new leaders.
Helen Grenade
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CONCACAF announces reform framework</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-CONCACAF-announces-reform-framework-26822.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Email To Friend  Print Version
MIAMI, USA -- The Confederation of North, Central America and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF) has announced that its executive committee has approved an expansive reform framework that seeks to substantially strengthen the Confederation's governance, management, and operations.
The reform framework was unanimously approved by CONCACAF's executive committee at an in-person meeting on Saturday in Vancouver, Canada. The new phase of reforms to governance, management, and operations will start being implemented immediately.
The reform framework, which was developed at the request of the Confederation's executive committee, is an additional step toward ushering in systemic organizational change to further enhance CONCACAF's business operations through improved governance, increased public disclosure, and enhanced anti-corruption controls.
In a statement, CONCACAF said: "This Reform Framework reflects CONCACAF's commitment to strengthening our governance, management, and operations. These reforms are intended to apply best practices for sound corporate governance to CONCACAF's business operations. In implementing the reform framework, the Confederation will demonstrate to its fans, sponsors, member associations and other stakeholders that CONCACAF is resilient and devoted to managing, developing, and promoting the game with accountability and transparency."
Proposals contained in the reform framework fall into three categories: corporate governance; fraud prevention and compliance; and transparency.
The new reform framework follows several other actions taken by CONCACAF in the last few weeks. Since May 27, CONCACAF's executive committee has also provisionally banned officials allegedly involved in wrongdoing; initiated a full review of all current expenditures and contracts with vendors and sponsors; and engaged the global professional services firm Alvarez &amp; Marsal to assess and recommend improvements in the Confederation's business operations.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean leaders undecided on Commonwealth nominee </title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-leaders-undecided-on-Commonwealth-nominee--26795.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean leaders undecided on Commonwealth nominee
Published onJuly 6, 2015
CARICOM Chairman and Barbados Prime Minister, Freundel Stuart making a point during the closing press conference of the 36th CARICOM Heads of Government Conference. Looking on is Prime Minister of St Vincent and the Grenadines, Ralph Gonsalves. (A. Gaskin/BGIS)
By Caribbean News Now contributor
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- Caribbean leaders have still not decided on a consensus candidate for the soon-to-be vacant post of Commonwealth Secretary-General.
CARICOM chairman and Barbados Prime Minister Freundel Stuart stated that a decision had not been made regarding the choice of a candidate to be put forward for the position of Commonwealth secretary-general, as there were currently three candidates nominated by various member states in the region.
Speaking during a press conference on the final day of the 36th regular meeting of the Conference of Heads of Government of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM), Stuart claimed that other issues, namely the Venezuela/Guyana land dispute, dominated discussions and we were not able at this conference to make that decision; in fact we did not even get to the issue.
What Stuart apparently failed to point out was that the matter of candidates for the Commonwealth secretary-general at the election in Malta in November was, in fact, never on the agenda for the Barbados summit, and it could not have been because not all CARICOM members are Commonwealth states -- Suriname, Haiti and Montserrat are not members of the 53-nation Commonwealth.
Any discussion of the Commonwealth secretary-general's post could therefore only have taken place in the margins of the CARICOM meeting and then only with the agreement of all the heads of government.
Nevertheless, while reassuring the media that the issue was not a dead one due to the inability to come to a conclusion, the prime minister stressed that it was a decision that cannot be made lightly. The conference chairman added that although in an ideal world we should not have been in this situation, as it was the reality, strategies must be put in place to solve the current predicament.
Currently nominated and vying for the position of Commonwealth secretary-general are Sir Ronald Sanders (Antigua and Barbuda), Baroness Patricia Scotland (Dominica) and Dr Bhoendradatt Tewarie (Trinidad and Tobago).
According to the Barbados Government Information Service (BGIS), Commonwealth regulations require that a candidate must be put forward by the region by the Commonwealth Heads of Government Conference, to be held in Malta in November this year.
However, in fact, there is no Commonwealth regulation that a candidate for the post of secretary general has to be nominated by a region, contrary to the factually incorrect statement on the Barbados government website. Indeed, only individual member states can nominate candidates.
In the entire history of the Commonwealth, candidates for the post of secretary-general have been nominated only by their own countries. While regional support would be useful, it is certainly not a Commonwealth regulation. As an example, in the current contest for the post, it is Botswana alone that has nominated its candidate, not the African region.
In fact, much of what Stuart had to say on the matter, as reported by BGIS, is misleading.
In Cuba, on December 8 last year, at a meeting of the Commonwealth Caribbean countries in the margins of a Cuba-CARICOM conference, nine of the 12 Commonwealth Caribbean countries indicated clearly that they would stand behind the Antigua and Barbuda candidate, Sir Ronald Sanders, for the post.
Stuart, who had absented himself from the meeting, reportedly insisted when he learned of the decision that formal endorsement should await a meeting where all heads of government would be present. That meeting was held in February 2015 in The Bahamas and although Antigua and Barbuda's candidate continued to enjoy overwhelming support, Trinidad and Tobago refused to withdraw its candidate Dr Bhoendradatt Tewarie and Barbados and Dominica declined to withdraw the British Baroness Patricia Scotland.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Opposition wrong on claims that general election date is illegal, says Trinidad PM</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Opposition-wrong-on-claims-that-general-election-date-is-illegal%2C-says-Trinidad-PM-26796.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Opposition wrong on claims that general election date is illegal, says Trinidad PM
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Prime Minister Kamla Persad-Bissessar
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- Claims by Trinidad and Tobago opposition leader, Dr Keith Rowley that the 2015 general election date of September 7 is illegal have been dismissed as misleading and inaccurate, according to a statement issued by the Office of the Prime Minister (OPM) on Friday.
Prime Minister Kamla Persad-Bissessars office said a letter was sent to then acting president, Raziah Ahmed, on June 15, 2015, indicating Monday, September 7, 2015 as the date to be fixed for the general election. The Office of the President responded by letter dated June 17, confirming the date for the general election, and that Nomination Day would be Monday, August 17, 2015.
The acting president also indicated that the chairman of the Elections and Boundaries Commission would be immediately requested to prepare the Writs of Election.
The OPM release stated: It is highly inappropriate for anyone to attempt to create and propagate this kind of misinformation, especially when time-honoured processes have been followed.
Such attempts must be seen as deliberate acts to cause panic and confusion among citizens, particularly as the Kamla Persad-Bissessar administration has a record of always holding elections when they are constitutionally due.
The opposition People's National Movement (PNM) had claimed that the September 7 general election date is illegal and can be changed because the proper protocols had not been observed.
PNM vice-chairman Colm Imbert said that, although Persad-Bissessar announced the election date in Parliament, she has deliberately not written to President Anthony Carmona advising him about the date.
He said PNM general secretary Ashton Ford contacted President's House last week and was informed that no correspondence had been sent to Carmona advising him of the election date in accordance with Section 69(1) of the country's constitution.
Clearly, Imbert was misinformed or, as Persad-Bissessar said, was a deliberate act to cause panic and confusion.
Imbert went on to say that the PNM also checked with the Government Printery to see if a writ of election had been issued.
However, Attorney General Garvin Nicholas later outlined the electoral process, which shows there is still time for the writ of election to be issued.
By practice, once the prime minister has announced the date for the general election, she would also announce Nomination Day. She has stated that August 17 is Nomination Day. Hence, the writ of election must be issued no later than 3 August, 2015. The general election must be held not less than 21 days after Nomination Day. That date has been announced as 7 September, Nicholas explained.
Section 33 of the Representation of the People Act, Chap. 2:01 provides the president with the power to issue the writ of election no later than 14 days before nomination day.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former FIFA vice president charged in Cayman Islands fraud case</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Former-FIFA-vice-president-charged-in-Cayman-Islands-fraud-case-26797.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Former FIFA vice president charged in Cayman Islands fraud case
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
GEORGE TOWN, Cayman Islands (CNS) -- The former FIFA vice president and Cayman Islands football boss, Jeffrey Webb, has been charged with fraud and breach of trust in relation to a local hospital card payment case.
Canover Watson and Miriam Rodrigues are also facing further charges in relation to the ongoing local investigation into the CarePay Card contract, the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) said in a statement on Friday. While Watson and Rodrigues are expected to appear in court on Tuesday, a warrant has been issued for Webbs arrest.
Ex-CONCACAF president Jeffrey Webb in Zurich hours before his arrest by Swiss authorities
Officials said they were expecting to begin extradition proceedings in relation to these charges, as Webb remains on remand in Switzerland, where he is already fighting extradition to the US in connection with the massive FIFA corruption probe.
Following months of speculation that Webb and others were also under investigation in relation to the $11 million contract award, a short statement was released on Friday afternoon by ACC chair David Baines, who is also the commissioner of police.
Watson and Webb have been jointly charged with two counts of conspiracy to defraud contrary to common law, one count of breach of trust under the 2008 anti-corruption law and a charge of conspiracy to convert criminal property contrary to both the Penal Code and the proceeds of crime law. Watsons former PA, Miriam Rodrigues, has also been charged with one count of conspiracy to convert criminal property.
Watson and Rodrigues are already scheduled to go on trial in November. The Crown had successfully postponed an earlier trial in May after a trillion bytes of digital information was handed over to investigators in April in connection with the case from Watsons former employer, Admiral Administration.
Canover Watson
Watson already faces numerous charges in relation to the case, including six counts of money laundering in relation to around US$169,000 over an 18-month period between December 2010 and June 2012, when he was chair of the Health Services Authority (HSA) board. He is also charged with conflict of interest, failing to disclose a pecuniary interest, breach of trust and fraud.
Rodrigues faces fraud and money laundering charges.
The Crown alleges Watson has direct connections to AIS and that he helped to secure the company two lucrative contacts at the hospital while he was the HSA boards chair, which forms the basis of the corruption accusations. Prosecutors say that he created the bank accounts for the firm and told the principals what to say and do, which they claim is supported by email communication.
Both Watson and Rodrigues have denied all charges.
Miriam Rodrigues
Officials have not yet made any claims regarding the part they say Webb played in the local corruption case but it is understood that Webb was a close business associate of Watson and had a number of companies together. Watson was also a FIFA official before he was suspended from one of the organisations committees after he was charged in the local CarePay case.
The details of the charges against Webb are likely to remain under wraps for some considerable time as he is unlikely to be returned to Cayman anytime soon. On Thursday, an official extradition application was filed in Switzerland by the US authorities for Webb, who has been detained in a Zrich jail since he was arrested with six other FIFA officials in May.
Given the circumstances, the application by the Cayman authorities will take second place when filed against the background of the US request. Webb is understood to be fighting the extradition to the United States but there has been no indication whether he will also fight extradition to Cayman.
Republished with permission of Cayman News Service

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Lucia government pressed on economic citizenship proposal</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Lucia-government-pressed-on-economic-citizenship-proposal-26798.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Lucia government pressed on economic citizenship proposal
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Caribbean News Now contributor
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- The Saint Lucia governments desire to sell thousands of passports abroad in exchange for huge sums of cash through the economic citizenship by investment programme should be of concern to all Saint Lucian citizens who love their country and desire transparency regarding this process, the Lucian Peoples Movement (LPM) said in a press release on Sunday.
Moreover, given the unscrupulous history of this programme in most resource-poor nations that are desperate for cash and have already instituted it, there is an even greater danger, which is their limited capacity to manage the kinds of serious international criminal activities associated with economic citizenship by investment, the LPM said.
According to the LPM, this programme will attract a number of foreign nationals who have earned their money illegally and who will not hesitate to take advantage of the safe haven that Saint Lucian economic citizenship affords them.
Therefore, notwithstanding other pertinent arguments of a patriotic nature, which beg the question of whether our governments proposed action amounts to a cheapening of Saint Lucian citizenship, the LPM, without any malice or ill will, is humbly requesting that the government of Saint Lucia update our nation on the following matters:
A) Has our government entered into a consultative agreement with Christian Kalin of the Swiss law firm Henley &amp; Partners with a view to enact the Economic Citizenship by Investment Programme here in Saint Lucia? If so, what is the total cost, if any, to the government and the people of Saint Lucia?
B) Are any other foreign organisations or entities associated with this ongoing process?
C) Which individual(s), organisation(s) or entities will administer or facilitate the drive to sell Saint Lucian passports abroad? Moreover, will these individuals, organisations or entities be licensed by the government of Saint Lucia, and is there a commission involved?
D) Will the government of Saint Lucia seek the assistance of Interpol or perhaps other international law enforcement agencies before issuing the passports? In addition, will these agencies be granted unfettered rights to monitor our nations activities with regard to the proposed Economic Citizenship by Investment Programme?
Finally, the LPM hopes that the government of Saint Lucia will accede to the preceding request in the interest of our nation and that it will not act with disdain towards the party for raising these important issues, which are rooted in the premise of good governance.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Montserrat continues steps towards full implementation of CARICOM treaty</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Montserrat-continues-steps-towards-full-implementation-of-CARICOM-treaty-26799.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Montserrat continues steps towards full implementation of CARICOM treaty
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version

Premier of Montserrat, Donaldson Romeo as he delivered remarks at the opening ceremony of the 36th Meeting of the Conference of Heads of Government of CARICOM in Barbados on Thursday 2 July, 2013
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- Montserrat is continuing to take steps towards the full implementation of the Revised Treaty of Chaguaramas.
Premier Donaldson Romeo gave the assurance that Montserrat, a British Overseas Territory, was continuing its engagements to ensure the timely completion of the processes to this end.
He made the announcement at the opening ceremony of the 36th meeting of the Conference of Heads of Government of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) on Thursday 2 July, 2015, in Bridgetown, Barbados.
Regarding the Revised Treaty of Chaguaramas, we continue our exchanges with Her Majestys Government, and are preparing the required Legislation to submit to the Legislative Assembly of Montserrat. The CARICOM Authority has granted timelines for completion of the processes and for the full implementation of the Revised Treaty.
We are very clear that our accession to the Caribbean Development Fund (CDF), which will assist our efforts to integrate, and the Original Court of the Caribbean Court of Justice (CCJ), which safeguards the rules of trade, are necessary pillars that will move Montserrat forward, Romeo said.
He added that CARICOM secretary-general, Irwin LaRocque, who visited Montserrat earlier this year, had assured him that all courtesies and assistance would be granted as needed to help Montserrat advance as a founding member of CARICOM, with the current new and revised arrangements of our regional integration movement.
As a number of studies have shown, it is in the strategic interest of both CARICOM and Montserrat that we remain inclusive, particularly in the area of natural resources, the environment and climate change, he said.
Romeo was attending his first regular meeting of the Conference of Heads of Government of CARICOM, which concluded Saturday evening.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canadian doctor dies in custody in Panama while awaiting extradition</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Canadian-doctor-dies-in-custody-in-Panama-while-awaiting-extradition-26800.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Canadian doctor dies in custody in Panama while awaiting extradition
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Former St Kitts and Nevis Prime Minister Dr Denzil Douglas with Dr Arthur Porter (R)
By Kenneth Rijock
PANAMA CITY, Panama -- Dr Arthur Porter, a prominent Canadian physician, who was accused of diverting tens of millions of dollars, in a major hospital bribery scandal, has died, while in custody, in the Panama. Porter was allegedly involved in a $22.5 million kickback scheme in Canada.
The back story of his unnecessary and untimely death paints an ugly picture of the avarice of Panama's leading banks, which reportedly maneuvered to delay his extradition. The purpose of the delay was apparently to ensure that he would expire in Panama, having large accounts in local banks, which the banks intended to seize and convert to their own use.
Porter, who was formerly the chairman of the Intelligence Review Committee, overseeing CSIS, Canada's intelligence agency, had terminal lung cancer when he was detained in Panama in 2013.
It has been widely reported in Panama City that bank executives at those Panamanian financial institutions where Porter kept large accounts conspired to pressure local prosecutors, under the corrupt former Martinelli administration, to delay his extradition indefinitely, for the sole purposes of retaining the funds after his premature death.
Due to the criminal denial of treatment for Porter, who passed away on July 1, is said to have suffered greatly in jail; he could have survived for a long period of time had he been allowed to return to Canada to face the charges, and be treated for his illness.
The attitude of Porter's Panamanian bankers, which has shocked even the most hardened Panama observers, is indicative of the amoral culture that exists among the most senior bankers in Panama. Whether those individuals, whose improper influence resulted in Porter's mistreatment and excessive period of incarceration, when he had already waived any defences, and asked to be extradited, receive justice for their crimes, is another matter.
Related articles:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>An interview with Curacao's first and only independent payment gateway</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-An-interview-with-Curacao%27s-first-and-only-independent-payment-gateway-26801.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
An interview with Curacao's first and only independent payment gateway
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Leo Dos Santos of CX Pay BV
By Josefina Josepha
josefina@caribbeannewsnow.com
WILLEMSTAD, Curacao -- Caribbean News Now recently had the opportunity to interview a company that claims to be the first and only independent payment gateway that processes merchant transactions in Curacao, known as CX Pay BV.
In an atmosphere where companies look for opportunities to expand their markets and client base, the switch to e-commerce becomes inevitable, stated CX Pay director, Luis Santine Jr.
"In order to be able to capture business outside of Curacao, it is essential for companies to have the capability to collect sales from abroad. To do so, a payment gateway is required to bridge the sales gap between the merchant, the client and the processing bank," he continued.
Mr Santine stated that local companies in Curacao can now experience the ease of global payment acceptance through CX Pays secure payment processing infrastructure.
The following is a candid interview with Luis Santine Jr., son of one of the executive officers of the company, Luis Santine Sr.
Josefina Josepha: When were you incorporated in Curacao?
Luis Santine Jr.: We were incorporated in 2014
Josefina Josepha: Who are the chief executives of CX Pay?
Luis Santine Jr.: The chief executives of CX Pay are Luis Santine, my father, and Christopher van Rosberg.
Josefina Josepha: Approximately how many persons does CX Pay employ?
Luis Santine Jr.: Presently we operate a five-person staff.
Josefina Josepha: Do you have any satellite offices besides your head office?
Luis Santine Jr.: No. However, clients and prospective clients can call us at 789-0025 or via email at hello@cxpay.cw
Josefina Josepha: Who are your affiliations and partnerships (a) nationally and (b) globally?
Luis Santine Jr.: Well, we cannot disclose this information, but only to clients we are engaging with.
Josefina Josepha: What is CX Pays projected average annual revenue forecast over the next three years?
Mr. Luis Santine Jr.: I am not at liberty to disclose that information either!
Josefina Josepha: Who is your intended target audience?
Luis Santine Jr.: Audience refers to clients/customers. CX Pay provides online merchant services focusing mostly on hospitality, retail, and gaming industries to both local and international merchants.
Josefina Josepha: What type of impact do you envision CX Pay to have on Curacao and the Curacao economy?
Luis Santine Jr.: We help facilitate local merchants to expand their sales capability by accessing international markets through online sales.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amnesty International calls for further action to protect Dominicans of foreign descent</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Amnesty-International-calls-for-further-action-to-protect-Dominicans-of-foreign-descent-26802.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Amnesty International calls for further action to protect Dominicans of foreign descent
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
SANTO DOMINGO, Dominican Republic -- Amnesty International carried out a visit to the Dominican Republic from 14 to 27 June 2015, with the aim of assessing the situation of people who were deprived of their Dominican nationality by the ruling 168-13 of the Constitutional Court. The visit also aimed at advocating with the Dominican authorities to avoid the expulsion of those people and other human rights violations.
Amnesty International thanked the Dominican authorities for their availability to meet with the organizations delegates, to provide information and to engage in a constructive dialogue.
Amnesty International has documented for years the human rights violations occurring in the Dominican Republic as a consequence of the deprivation of identity documents that has left thousands of people in a legal limbo affecting their lives in multiple ways and preventing them to exercise their human rights. Amnesty International acknowledged that Law 169-14 has sought to provide for a solution to a number of Dominican-born people of Haitian descent who had been denied for years of their identity documents, including those made stateless by the 2013 Constitutional Court ruling.
However, such solution for people born in the Dominican Republic to undocumented foreign parents and whose birth were at some points registered (so-called group A) has come at a very slow pace and through a process that in many occasions lacked clarity and transparency both for the affected people and the general public. Despite the adoption of law 169-14, Amnesty International still documented cases of dozens of people whose rights have been neglected or severely affected due to the states refusal to provide them with the identity documents they are entitled to.
Amnesty International welcomed the announcement on 26 June 2015 by the Central Electoral Board that 55,000 people from so-called group A would now be able to access their identity documents. It is important to note, however, that until 22 June Amnesty International still witnessed and documented the persistence of bureaucratic obstacles and procedural hurdles that prevented affected people to obtain or re-access their identity documents in several communities.
The authorities should allow a process of thorough monitoring that fully includes the participation of civil society organisations to be able to confirm that the affected population of so-called group A receive all their identity documents, are able to register their children and have all their citizenship rights fully granted.
Amnesty International said it is concerned that many of the people included in the list of the 55,000 will have their birth certificates transcribed in a separate civil register, (libro de transcripcin), which is not a well-defined mechanism in the law and could translate in future acts of arbitrariness.
Furthermore, given that affected people who need to register their children will now have to go through a longer process than if they had been able to register them within 60 days from their birth, the Dominican authorities should provide adequate legal and financial support to those families in order for them to be able to carry out this registration process, especially considering that the delay in registration is imputable to the state.
As far as people from so-called group B (people born in the Dominican Republic to undocumented foreign parents and whose births had never been registered) are concerned, Amnesty International noted that many of the 8,755 people who applied to the naturalization plan under law 169-14 do not seem to have received a final response to their applications after 5 months since the expiration of the plan.
While their situation remains uncertain, Amnesty International said it is mostly concerned by the fate of those who were not able to enroll in the naturalization plan under law 169-14.
Dominican authorities interviewed by Amnesty International do not seem to acknowledge that many people were left out from the naturalization process established by law 169-14 and deny that the vast majority of people in such group remain stateless, unless they have acquired another nationality.
Amnesty International interviewed dozens of people who did not enroll in the naturalization plan due to several reasons, including unawareness of the process, lack of resources to pay for the requested documents, inability to apply within the deadline, and the impossibility to obtain their parents identity documents  a requisite not foreseen by the law and its implementing regulation but nevertheless imposed by most application units.
Following the expiration of the deadline set up by law 169-14 on 1 February 2015, there is currently no legal recourse for people under group B who could not apply to re-access their Dominican nationality and to obtain identity documents, essential for the exercise of several human rights, including access to higher education, adequate medical care and formal employment.
This group represents one of the most vulnerable and marginalised population living in the Dominican Republic. Most of these people live in extreme poverty in remote rural communities, and are at risk of violence and exploitation. Because of their undocumented status, they are unable to improve their socio-economic situation and to register their own children. Amnesty International documented families composed of three generations of undocumented people of Haitian descent. In some parts of the country, Amnesty International documented cases where hospitals denied the issuance of the proof-of-birth certificate to babies born there, which automatically prevents the declaration of birth of those babies, born of Haitian mothers or Dominican mothers of Haitian descent.
While Dominican authorities have provided clear assurances that people belonging to group A and those from group B who applied under law 169-14 will not be expelled, the situation of those from group B who could not enrol to the naturalisation plan and therefore continue to be undocumented still remains uncertain ahead of the deportation operations due to start soon.
Dominican authorities have assured Amnesty International that no massive deportations will take place. The authorities committed to assess each case individually and to respect due process. They have explained that, if intercepted by migration officers or detained, people from group A and group B who applied under law 169-14 will be easily identified and protected from expulsion.
According to the authorities, undocumented people claiming to have been born in the Dominican Republic, if intercepted or detained by migration officers, will have to demonstrate that they were born in the country by going through an interview process.
Amnesty International urged the Dominican authorities to:
 Promptly expedite the issue or renewal of identity documents to all people whose names have been published by the Central Electoral Board on 26 June and ensure that all their children are promptly registered, including by providing legal and financial support to families for this purpose;
 Ensure that nobody born in the Dominican Republic, whose names are not included in the list provided by the Central Electoral Board, is in the future deprived of or denied their identity documents on the basis of their parents ancestry or migration status;
 Eliminate practices which prevent the declaration of birth of people of Haitian descent, and in particular the children of people pertaining to groups A and B;
 Promptly provide valid documents to the 8,755 people from so-called group B who applied to the naturalisation plan, enabling them to apply for the Dominican nationality within two years;
 Acknowledge the existence of a number of people from so-called group B who could not register under law 169-14 and who, in the majority of cases, are stateless, unless they have acquired another nationality;
 Put in place adequate and effective measures to ensure that people who have been rendered stateless can be identified (taking into account that families belonging to this group live in very remote areas, have very limited financial resources and have limited access to mass media) and have access to claim their Dominican nationality;
 Establish transparent, clear and fair procedures to screen and protect from expulsion people born in the Dominican Republic to undocumented foreign parents, in particular those lacking any identity document, and make them public;
 Maintain the prohibition of mass deportations and ensure that each case is individually assessed and due process is respected;
 Review all relevant legislation in order to ensure that deportation orders are issued through a judicial procedure and that every person at risk of being deported is granted with the right to appeal the deportation order;
 Grant access to the detention centres to national human rights organisations and international observers;
 Allow for national human rights organisations and international observers to thoroughly and closely monitor the deportation operations;
 Establish accountability mechanisms, and strengthen those already in place, to ensure that all migration officers and members of the security forces involved in the deportation operations comply with due process and respect human rights, and that allegations of human rights violations are thoroughly and independently investigated.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Global Crisis Room Support Programme starts crisis training in Trinidad and Tobago</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Global-Crisis-Room-Support-Programme-starts-crisis-training-in-Trinidad-and-Tobago-26803.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Global Crisis Room Support Programme starts crisis training in Trinidad and Tobago
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- The Caribbean region is particularly vulnerable to a wide range of natural hazards, including hurricanes, droughts and flooding as well as threats from transnational crimes such as drug smuggling, human trafficking and cybercrimes.
One of the key challenges that countries in the region face is to become more proactive in order to predict and prevent conflicts and reduce the impact of disasters and crisis situations.
It is with this issue in mind therefore that the Global Crisis Room Support Programme (GCRSP) commenced its first training course on June 29 in Port of Spain at the CARICOM Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (IMPACS).
This training is part of a two-year capacity development initiative of the European Union External Action Service (EEAS) to support Latin American and Caribbean regional organizations and their Member States to enhance their conflict and disaster early-warning capabilities and effectively reduce the potentially devastating impact of these types of events on people and property.
Experts from Caribbean Community agencies (Caribbean Disaster and Emergency Management Agency (CDEMA), Caribbean Public Health Agency (CARPHA), Regional Security System (RSS), CARICOM IMPACS and its two sub-agencies (Regional Intelligence Fusion Centre (RIFC) and the Joint Regional Communication Centre (JRCC)) participated in this first training course on Open Source Information (OSI).
Participants are expected to develop a range of skills including how to monitor social media information for crisis support, the use of data processing tools and the principles of safer searching. This training will improve participants capacities to anticipate potential crises with the help of open source media while improving online anonymity and security.
The Global Crisis Room Support Programme (GCRSP) aims to build and strengthen crisis response and early warning capacity in the Latin American and Caribbean regions. The GCRSP also seeks to improve the interconnectivity between crisis response centres within the region as well as strengthen cooperation with the EU Crisis Room and other EU institutions in the field of crisis response and early warning.
Activities include training, workshops and technical information sessions in Europe covering risk and scenario analysis, early warning, conflict analysis, open source information, knowledge management, and other related topics.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean employer organizations hold forum in Barbados to develop policy positions</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-employer-organizations-hold-forum-in-Barbados-to-develop-policy-positions-26804.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean employer organizations hold forum in Barbados to develop policy positions
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
(L-R) Wayne Chen, President, CEC; Ambassador Mikael Barfod, Head, EU Delegation to Barbados and the Eastern Caribbean; Sen. Dr Esther Byer-Suckoo; Minister of Labour, Social Security and Human Resource Development for Barbados; Anne Knowles, Senior Specialist, Employers Activities, and Ian Gooding-Edghill, President, Barbados Employers Confederation
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados  Thirty-two representatives from 19 employers organizations from the English- and Dutch-speaking Caribbean participated in a regional forum entitled Facilitating Participation of CARIFORUM Civil Society in Regional Development and Integration Processes in Barbados from 22-24 June 2015.
The activity was part of the European Union (EU)-funded project, whereby the International Labour Organization (ILO) is the executing agency to strengthen the capacity of the Caribbean Employers Confederation (CEC) to play a greater role in regional policy making, and to ensure CEC can effectively lobby advocacy strategies on behalf of its members  employers organisations at national level.
At the opening, the minister of labour, social security and human resource development for Barbados, Sen. Dr Esther Byer-Suckoo, spoke about the economic realities of the Caribbean region and challenged participants to address the gaps necessary to meet EPA obligations in the context of Caribbean development, particularly during the period of the projects support - 2015-2018.
Ambassador Mikael Barfod, head, EU Delegation to Barbados and the Eastern Caribbean, spoke on the importance the EU attached to the fundamentals of social dialogue, labour standards and decent work and his belief that the strengthening of such pillars through the support of the project would benefit the entire Caribbean.
Anne Knowles, senior specialist, employers activities, ILO; Wayne Chen, president, CEC; and Ian Gooding-Edghill, president, Barbados Employers Confederation, also spoke at the opening ceremony with each of them expressing appreciation for the opportunity to be able to focus on ensuring employers throughout the Caribbean had their voice heard at national and regional policy making forums.
Prior to the forum a survey had been completed by each employer organisation to have them prioritise issues of key importance at national and enterprise levels. Presentations were then made by participants on topics including the following:
 Review of regulatory barriers to develop an enabling environment for sustainable enterprises;
 TVET institutions  matching skills training to employment needs;
 Climate change and enterprise resilience;
 Institutionalizing tripartism at both national and regional levels, to ensure a systemic approach to input from Employers' Organizations on social and economic policies;
 Productivity and competitiveness, particularly in small and medium enterprises; and
 Legislative focus to support the implementation of the Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) Social Chapter, which incorporates the core ILO Conventions.
Other topics discussed at the forum included migration and free movement of labour, international trends affecting employers and their organizations and social dialogue mechanisms. Findings from a recent study tour undertaken by CEC and CCL representatives to Brussels were presented on the subject of regional tripartite good practices and strategies for national input.
Chen summed up the meeting by saying, The mood of the forum was positive and optimistic. But more importantly, the firm commitment by the national organizations to doing the hard and sustained work augurs well for employers having a more influential voice in our region's integration and development."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Havana to be home port of Italian cruise line in the Caribbean</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Havana-to-be-home-port-of-Italian-cruise-line-in-the-Caribbean-26805.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Havana to be home port of Italian cruise line in the Caribbean
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- With Cuban tourism growing over 15 percent annually, Italys MSC cruise line has announced that Havana will be its home port as of December for its winter operations in the Caribbean.
The initiative changes the original program for the winter season of MSC in the Mediterranean, South Africa and Brazil, as its Opera MSC ship will now visit another 16 destinations in the Caribbean area, before returning to Europe in April 2016.
The new itinerary includes Jamaica, Cayman Islands and Mexico, two nights in Havana. The MSC Opera cruise ship will travel to Havana in December to start its Caribbean program and to become the first of its kind to operate from the Cuba destination.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>JetBlue connects New York and Havana</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-JetBlue-connects-New-York-and-Havana-26806.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
JetBlue connects New York and Havana
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- The first flight by JetBlue from New York to Havana took place on Friday in what has been described as one of the steps adopted over the past few months towards the resumption of relations between Cuba and the United States.
With a weekly flight between the two cities, JetBlue becomes the first US airline to open this route since the US travel restrictions to Cuba were eased earlier this year.
The New York-based airline had announced on May 5 its intentions to connect both cities through a weekly flight for which tickets can be purchased at Cuban Travel Services agency.
Since JetBlue is the largest US airline operating in the Caribbean, Cuba will someday play a significant role in the companys regional network, read a release by JetBlue.
Charter flights to Cuba have thus far been offered by smaller companies and with a limited number of passengers authorized to travel to Cuba, given the US-Cuba travel ban.
The New York-Havana route is one of the five weekly flights between the US and Cuba by JetBlue, the others depart from Tampa and Fort Lauderdale-Hollywood, in Florida.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Surinam Airways launches direct Guyana-Orlando flight with connecting flights to Suriname</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Surinam-Airways-launches-direct-Guyana-Orlando-flight-with-connecting-flights-to-Suriname-26807.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Surinam Airways launches direct Guyana-Orlando flight with connecting flights to Suriname
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Surinam Airways crew and airport team with General Manager Henk Fitz-Jim, ready for departure from Sanford International Airport
ORLANDO, USA -- Surinam Airways officially launched service with an inaugural non-stop flight on July 2 between Cheddi Jagan International Airport (CJIA) in Georgetown, Guyana, and the Orlando Sanford International Airport. The return flight left on July 3 from Orlando Sanford to CJIA with continuing service to Johan Adolf Pengel International Airport in Paramaribo, Suriname.
This service will initially operate with weekly flights during July, August and September; arriving on Thursday afternoons at 3:30 pm in Sanford and departing from Sanford airport on Friday afternoons at 1:30pm. Surinam Airways will use a 737-300 aircraft with 126 seats. It will operate once weekly for three months, after which an evaluation of the operation will be done to ascertain the way forward, said the airlines local manager Rudi Westerdorg.
Currently, Surinam Airways offers two weekly nonstop flights from Georgetown to Miami. The airlines officials are buoyant of the success of the new route since feasibility studies signal Guyanese travelers are desirous of better arrival and departure times and also visiting the US city at an affordable price.
We work closely with travel agents, so we have a good idea of the travelers needs, Westerdorg said.
Minister of public infrastructure, David Patterson, who, along with minister of governance, Raphael Trotman, were on the inaugural flight, stated that the introduction of the new route is great and exciting news.
He added, This initiative is a clear indication of the confidence Surinam Airways has in the volume of passenger traffic in Guyana, and by extension our aviation sector.
Patterson also stated that he was impressed with CJIAs management strategy to attract other airlines to fly the GEO route.
He noted that Guyana is truly the gateway to many other countries, and its potential in the aviation sector is boundless. To this end, he intends to actively engage CJIAs chief executive officer, Ramesh Ghir, on the untapped opportunities available to explore.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A vital reference tool that educates about Haiti</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-A-vital-reference-tool-that-educates-about-Haiti-26808.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
A vital reference tool that educates about Haiti
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
MAITLAND, USA -- J.R. Gelins new book, Haiti Once Again, ($11.99, paperback, 9781622300327) serves to present, discuss, and promote Haiti using concepts and ideas from historical research, biblical theology, and contemporary science. The text offers an analysis of relevant points in the countrys history, and makes the connection with the AIDS stigma and its religious counterpart -- the myth of the divine curse.
Readers will gain a comprehensive understanding of the first black republic of the world, whether they read it for leisure or in search of educational materials, states the author. The book connects the countrys glorious past with its current challenges, so the readers can understand why Haiti is great yet small, strong yet weak, and rich yet poor.
Gelin holds a PhD in plant sciences, and has published several scientific articles in peer-reviewed journals. A former minister of the Church of God, he served for several years as assistant pastor in a small, but vibrant, Haitian church. Gelin is a native of Haiti, and resides in the United States with his family.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: How can we finance sustainable development?</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-How-can-we-finance-sustainable-development%3F-26809.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: How can we finance sustainable development?
Published onJuly 6, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Alicia Brcena
The Third International Conference on Financing for Development, which will be held from July 13 to July 16 in Addis Ababa, represents a unique opportunity to overcome the challenges that middle-income countries face, to procure effective financing at all income levels, and to fulfill the transformative objectives of the post-2015 agenda and the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), which will be presented in September in the framework of the United Nations General Assembly.
Alicia Brcena is Executive Secretary of the Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC)
To this end, the financing architecture for development must mobilize a large quantity of resources and change the way in which they are obtained, organized and allocated.
The internal mobilization of resources is at the center of financing in the post-2015 agenda. But this runs up against domestic and international obstacles.
The governments of Latin America and the Caribbean have made significant efforts to increase fiscal revenue collection; however, they have been limited by tax evasion and fiscal avoidance. According to official estimates, evasion rates on the Value-Added Tax (VAT) in Latin America range from 17.8% to 37% of total collection, figures that are much higher than those in countries belonging to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), where rates oscillate between 3% and 22%. The rates of evasion on personal income and corporate taxes are even higher, surpassing 40% of total income in some cases.
The governments of the region also face new challenges in the international arena, such as the need to combat illicit flows that, according to Global Financial Integrity (2014), exceed $150 billion dollars, which represents more than ten times the official development assistance, or ODA (10 billion dollars in 2013) and is similar to what the region receives in terms of foreign direct investment (158 billion dollars in 2014).
That is why I have insisted that to promote the mobilization of internal resources international cooperation on fiscal policies must be multilateralized to the point where major tax accords and fiscal rules have been established at a global level. This should be complemented by the active role of development banks, which are a significant source of financing for productive development.
These challenges are compounded by others related to sovereign debt and the need for restructuring. Due in large part to their structural vulnerability to natural disasters, the small island States of the Caribbean make up one of the most indebted regions of the world: in 2014 their total public debt reached an average of about 80% of GDP, dragging down the sub-regions development.
For this reason, I am calling for the exploration of routes that would lead to pardoning part of these countries external debt.
The mobilization of internal resources should be complemented by private flows. A key challenge consists in finding a way to channel these resources towards development objectives, taking into account that private capital is motivated primarily by economic benefit.
But national strategies to mobilize internal and external resources, by themselves, are insufficient. That is why I argue that there is an urgent need to address the asymmetries in the governance mechanisms of the international financial architecture and allow developing and middle-income countries to take advantage of the benefits of technology transfer and knowledge acquisition.
I hope that in Addis Ababa a broad global consensus is reached. The new development agenda can and should become a powerful catalyst for a new equation between the State, the market and society, in which all actors can establish new rules and complementary alliances for the sake of the common good.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
