<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Kitts-Nevis PM champions reform for good governance in CARICOM</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Kitts-Nevis-PM-champions-reform-for-good-governance-in-CARICOM-26693.html</Link>
        <Description>BASSETERRE, St Kitts (SKNIS) -- Some of the major challenges confronting Caribbean governments in relation to good governance and electoral reform, were placed in context by St Kitts and Nevis Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris at a recent regional forum in Antigua.</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Kitts-Nevis PM champions reform for good governance in CARICOM
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
BASSETERRE, St Kitts (SKNIS) -- Some of the major challenges confronting Caribbean governments in relation to good governance and electoral reform, were placed in context by St Kitts and Nevis Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris at a recent regional forum in Antigua and Barbuda.
The multifaceted issues surrounding good governance touched on the move by some administrations to operate outside of the constitution as well as the ability of citizens to question and challenge representatives for unseemly behaviour.
Motions of no confidence, integrity in public life, tenders boards and freedom of information legislation were highlighted as instruments to promote transparency, true democracy and were described as hallmarks of good governance.
In the case of electoral reforms, the voters list was described as the heart of the electoral process. The importance of cleaning the list periodically to remove names of the deceased, campaign finance rules, the rights of voters residing abroad and support for the Electoral Commission were all mentioned.
Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris
These are some of the issues which we in St Kitts and Nevis have to place before our citizens for their consideration and input, Harris revealed, while addressing delegates at the one-day forum dubbed CARICOM Overcoming Challenges: Pathway to Development.
We the servants of the people must have a clear sense of the reform in which we must engage and plan the way forward to guarantee a true democracy, he said.
Ambassador Dr Clarence Henry of Antigua and Barbuda played a key role in the forums staging. He praised Harris for capturing the imagination of persons regarding his vision of CARICOM (Caribbean Community) today and beyond.
He was often passionate, stirred and excited a grateful audience who applauded his powerful statements, Henry stated. I am grateful that the prime minister came and shared with the people of Antigua and Barbuda and by extension the entire region. Both he and [host] Prime Minister Gaston Browne make a powerful force as demonstrated during the opening ceremony and will continue their collaboration during the forthcoming meeting of the regular conference of CARICOM heads of government ...
The meeting is scheduled for July 2 to 4 in Barbados.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reparations on CARICOM heads of government agenda</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Reparations-on-CARICOM-heads-of-government-agenda-26694.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Reparations on CARICOM heads of government agenda
Published onJune 27, 2015
Prime Minister Freundel Stuart
By Sharon Austin
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados (BGIS) -- When the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) heads of government gather in Barbados early next month for their 36th regular meeting, they are expected to continue fleshing out the initiatives that have to be taken to push the reparations agenda forward.
This disclosure has come from Barbados Prime Minister Freundel Stuart, who acknowledged that progress was being made towards reparations for native genocide and slavery and that there was consensus across the region that leaders must go in that direction.
Stuart, who chairs the reparations sub-committee, said the heads viewed it as necessary to have talks with those former slave trading countries, England, France and Holland.
This is not a diplomacy of protest; it is a diplomacy of engagement because most of those countries are now our friends and who better to discuss issues like this with than friends.
There are some developmental, educational and health issues that we face that we think these countries can contribute a lot more to. So, we are not in a position where we are looking to quantify damages and say you owe this amount of money. That is for the law courts. What we want is to sit and discuss a way forward in terms of the development of this region in the context of an under development that has resulted from slavery itself, he stated.
The prime minister reiterated that such discussions were necessary so there could be a sharing of views on both sides, so as to see where the scope for some kind of agreement and consensus exist. He said, however, that it should not be argued that those countries had not contributed to the region in significant ways.
The European Union, through its series of development funds, has been contributing significantly to countries in the Caribbean. The British has its own aid packages for these countries. But, we are saying you can do better and that a lot of what you need to do needs to be more targeted he stressed.
Stuart expressed the view that the effects of slavery continue to be felt in the region and that it had affected the economies and societies.
The configuration of slavery is still evident in a few Caribbean countries, where you have a sociological minority being at the same time an economic majority and the numerical majority being an economic minority. These are facts that result from slavery and colonialism, he stated.
He opined that the region had done well in trying to bounce back from slavery and colonialism, but stressed that the stage had been reached across the Caribbean and the black world that there was some unfinished business in relation to how black people had been affected by the slave experience.
Stuart noted that the president of France, Francois Hollande, recently spoke about slavery and its effects on countries like ours and highlighted the challenges being faced by Haiti.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cayman Islands opposition leader targets governor in legal battle with premier</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cayman-Islands-opposition-leader-targets-governor-in-legal-battle-with-premier-26695.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cayman Islands opposition leader targets governor in legal battle with premier
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
GEORGE TOWN, Cayman Islands (CNS) -- The Cayman Islands opposition leader McKeeva Bush has filed a response to a defamation lawsuit filed by the territorys premier that outlines his claims of a conspiracy led by the former governor, Duncan Taylor, to topple him from office, rather than make a direct response to what Premier Alden McLaughlin has said are damaging untruths about him.
Leader of the Opposition McKeeva Bush
Bushs defence against the damages suit has been filed in the Grand Court but the documents are not public and CNS was refused access when it attempted to see the files.
Sources close to the premier confirmed that on Monday his attorneys received the documents responding to the suit filed by him in early May. It is understood that the focus of the response is on Taylor and the alleged conspiracy rather than the premiers defamation allegations. The opposition leader is understood to have claimed that the premier, when he was opposition leader, was involved in secret meetings with the police and the governor, where a plan to remove Bush was hatched in the wake of his arrest.
CNS contacted Bush, who is currently overseas, and his attorney, Michael Alberga, to ask about the defence to the suit but has not received a response regarding the release of the documents.
The premier filed suit against Bush after the opposition leader refused to apologise to him for accusing McLaughlin in a parliamentary motion and at a press briefing of being directly involved in what Bush claims was his unlawful removal from the leadership. Bush called for an independent enquiry into his arrest and subsequent charges for the alleged misuse of his government credit card, for which he was acquitted.
Cayman Islands Premier Alden McLaughlin
Since the trial in October last year, when the extent of Bushs gambling while he was the leader of the country was revealed, the veteran politician has threatened to take legal action against the former governor, the police commissioner, the auditor general and others in relation to what he says were the trumped up charges to undemocratically boot him out of office.
But instead, Bush filed a private members motion in the LA, making allegations and pointing the finger at the premier in an effort to force his legislative colleagues to debate what happened to him under cover of parliamentary privilege. The motion has not been withdrawn and remains with the speaker.
Bush called a press conference to reveal the motion and detailed his belief that the case against him was a British-led conspiracy. It was then that he made specific allegations against McLaughlin. The premier immediately demanded an apology but when none was forthcoming, he filed suit.
Republished with permission of Cayman News Service

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN urges that deportations do not result in statelessness of people born in Dominican Republic</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-UN-urges-that-deportations-do-not-result-in-statelessness-of-people-born-in-Dominican-Republic-26696.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
UN urges that deportations do not result in statelessness of people born in Dominican Republic
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Approximately 200,000 Haitian migrants live in bateyes  communities located on or near to sugar cane plantations in the Dominican Republic. Photo: UNHCR/Jason Tanner
PORT AU PRINCE, Haiti -- Amid ongoing concern about the status of thousands of immigrants living in the Dominican Republic, Sandra Honor, the special representative for Haiti of the United Nations secretary general, said that deportations carried out by Santo Domingo authorities should not result in statelessness of people of Haitian descent.
Honor also considered that such acts should be consistent with the dignity, human rights and international humanitarian law.
This call comes as the Office of the UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) last Friday appealed to the government of the Dominican Republic to ensure that people who were arbitrarily deprived of their nationality as a result of a 2013 ruling of the Dominican Constitutional Court would not be deported.
According to UNHCR, in May 2014, the Dominican Republic adopted a naturalization law which provided for the re-issuance of nationality documents for some individuals born in the Dominican Republic and gave others the possibility to apply for special registration until February 2015, opening a path to eventual citizenship.
In a welcome development, the agency said, the Dominican authorities have concluded an audit of the first group whereby some 57,000 individuals could be reasonably presumed to have found a solution, but tens of thousands of people who were born in the Dominican Republic and are of Haitian descent remain stateless. The consequences of their eventual expulsion to Haiti could be devastating.
In an interview with UN Radio, Honor said that in a recent meeting with the foreign minister and the immigration authorities in the Dominican Republic, those officials explained to her that during the process they would take all necessary measures so that there was full respect for the basic guarantees of the people.
Honor, who is also head of UN Stabilization Mission in Haiti (MINUSTAH), said that, to date, there has been an increase in the flow of returnees and that both governments have decided that there would be two official points for carrying out deportations.
We encourage the dialogue recently begun at the level of foreign ministers of both countries to continue, to agree on the best way to address these measures, she said.
She said that at several points along the border where people have gathered, the Haitian government does not have the capability to receive or process them.
This will, in fact, be a challenge for the government, she acknowledged, and added that, in response, Haitian authorities have established a committee of national solidarity to deal with the question of returnees from the Dominican Republic.
In addition, Honor said the government of Haiti does have a contingency plan that it has developed to deal with the return of large numbers of Haitian citizens and the government is working with UN agencies, funds and programmes regarding the support it needs to enact the plan.
Our mandate for stabilization in Haiti dictates that we support the government as best we can and within the resources that are available to us, she said, explaining that two rounds of elections  legislative and presidential  are scheduled to take place in Haiti over the coming months.
The UN would aim to maintain support for the government to ensure that the climate surrounding these elections would be a serene as possible, and we would do everything that we possibly can to ensure that the challenges posed by this situation do not translate into any undesirable effects on the overall election process, concluded Honor.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CARICOM rejects tax haven listings</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-CARICOM-rejects-tax-haven-listings-26697.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
CARICOM rejects tax haven listings
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
GEORGETOWN, Guyana -- The Caribbean Community (CARICOM) has stated its strong objection to the recent decision by the European Commission to blacklist a number of CARICOM member states for allegedly not co-operating on tax law enforcement with European Union countries.
The Community, in a statement issued Thursday, described the Commissions assertion as patently false in view of the continued efforts by CARICOM member states to comply with the onerous and unilaterally imposed regulatory measures.
The Commission earlier this month named Anguilla, Antigua and Barbuda, The Bahamas, Barbados, Belize, Bermuda, British Virgin Islands, Cayman Islands, Grenada, Montserrat, St Kitts and Nevis, St Vincent and the Grenadines and the Turks and Caicos Islands on its list of non-co-operative tax jurisdictions and counties.
The Turks and Caicos Islands (TCI) and St Vincent and the Grenadines (SVG) have also both added their objections to their inclusion on the EU list.
The TCI is compliant with the Global Forums standards on exchange of tax information said its minister of finance Washington Misick on Thursday.
The Turks and Caicos was commended by the Global Forum for the tremendous progress that we have made in improving international tax transparency, Misick pointed out. The Global Forum considers the TCI as co-operative.
Indeed, following the UKs G8 presidency, we were early adopters of the automatic exchange of tax information, committing to share information with our partners by 2017.
I assure the international community that we remain committed to and actively involved in achieving these ideals.
Despite the ECs claims, the Global Forum believes that countries identified are either fully or largely compliant, and have committed to Automatic Exchange of Information, sometimes even as early adopters, such as the TCI.
Misick also noted that the EC list appears to deal only with corporate tax and does not contain any lists from larger EU jurisdictions like Germany, France or the United Kingdom.
The TCI will now work with the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), the Global Forum and its sister territories to express collective concern to the EC.
The SVGs Financial Services Authority (FSA) said in a release that there appears to be no rationale or at best, no reasonable rationale for the blacklisting of St Vincent and the Grenadines save for the fact that this country operates an international financial services industry, albeit very small.
The EU process of blacklisting seems to be that countries were blacklisted that were found by at least ten of their EU members to be non- cooperative in relation to tax matters. Eleven EU countries named SVG as being non cooperative  Bulgaria, Croatia, Estonia, Greece, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Portugal, Slovenia and Spain.
SVG has never had a request for tax information or any other information from any of those countries, nor refused any international request for tax information whatsoever, the FSA said.
Methodology
The countries blacklisted were apparently assessed on two limbs  good governance (transparency and exchange of information) and fair tax competition. The EU may have possibly categorized SVG under the latter limb  by reason of operating an offshore financial industry with tax benefits. The same would have applied to the other Caribbean territories but, unsurprisingly, it is not a clean sweep of all international finance centres (IFCs) or offshore jurisdictions, as many powerful IFCs jurisdictions, which by the same token ought to be have been blacklisted, have not been (e.g. Jersey, Switzerland, Luxembourg). This is so even though the Netherlands, Ireland and Luxembourg are under investigation by the EU Competition authorities for facilitating aggressive tax avoidance, the FSA noted.
No information or evidence has been provided to SCG upon which a conclusion can be drawn that this country has been or is non-compliant, non-receptive or non-cooperative with any international tax initiative or any specific request for information or case for tax avoidance by any of the named countries, or from the EU for that matter. No information has been provided that persons from the named countries are hiding assets in this country.
OECD Position
SVG has queried this blacklisting with the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), the international tax standard setter, which is the relevant international body for tax compliance issues. SVG has been a member of the OECD Global Forum since 2009 and, prior to that, been actively involved in OECD initiatives since 2002.
In a formal statement by the Global Forum issued to its members on June 19, 2015, the OECD Global Forum has in effect disassociated itself with the action of the EU and underscored the fact that it is their own assessment which is the relevant assessment for the purposes of determining a countrys cooperation in tax matters. An excerpt from the statement is reproduced below:
As the OECD and the Global Forum we would like to confirm that the only agreeable assessment of countries as regards their cooperation is made by the Global Forum and that a number of countries identified in the EU exercise are either fully or largely compliant and have committed to AEOI, sometimes even as early adopters. Without prejudice to countries' sovereign positions, we are happy to confirm that these jurisdictions are cooperative and we would like to commend the tremendous progress made over the past years as well as the cooperation and integrity of the Global Forum process.
We have already expressed our concerns and stand ready to further clarify to the media the position of the affected jurisdictions with regard to their compliance with the Global Forum standards.
From the above, it is clear that the EUs conclusions do NOT correspond with those of the Global Forum and that the Global Forum is willing to extend support, as described, to countries like SVG, which they have already rated as fully or largely compliant, through their own processes.
SVG Position
In view of the extensive work undertaken and full cooperation given by SVG internationally over the years, the relevant authorities in SVG, including the FSA, consider the present blacklisting by the EU Commission to be arbitrary and not supported by any objective or transparent process. The blacklisting is considered unjust, amounting to an abuse of process/power. This country has amended its laws and implemented a tax information exchange system to conform to international standards and built a successful tax information exchange regime.
Of absolute significance is that SVG has already been assessed as NOT being a tax haven by the OECD, the responsible international body for international tax compliance purposes. SVG is also white listed by the OECD, having very successfully completed its mandatory 2 phased assessments (Phase 1 and 2 Peer Reviews). SVG is rated Largely Compliant by the OECD Global Forum in relation to its tax compliance regime, which is globally accepted as a very positive rating.
SVG intends to object to the blacklisting on an individual basis and from a unified Caribbean front.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guyana prime minister promises to professionalise state media entities</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Guyana-prime-minister-promises-to-professionalise-state-media-entities-26698.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Guyana prime minister promises to professionalise state media entities
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Prime Minister and First Vice-President Moses Nagamootoo, who holds responsibility for public information, making his presentation in the National Assembly
GEORGETOWN, Guyana (GINA) -- Addressing Guyanas National Assembly on Thursday, prime minister and first vice president Moses Nagamootoo pledged the new administrations support for true press freedom. The prime minister, who also holds the responsibility of minister of information, said that the new administration will make no attempt to curb the constitutional right of freedom of any media, including that of the state.
He however urged that information must be disseminated in a responsible manner that will help, not destroy Guyana. Moreover, the prime minister said that the right of reply must be catered to for persons who come under assault and attack for their character or who suffer threats of victimisation.
This is the kind of professional journalism and journalists that the new administration is seeking to promote, and in the state media, Nagamootoo said. He promised that if this type of journalism is done, then the state media, will see less, and perhaps ideally no interference from him, as the minister responsible for public information.
He noted the already bipartisan turnaround of sections of the state in taking up this mandate of professionalism, adding that Guyana is witnessing what appears to be a magical transformation of public information. He described as amazing the transformation in the Guyana Chronicle.
He pointed out that this state paper used to be saturated with editorial pieces that sought to divide and set Guyanese against each other. He noted that this paper which was used as a partisan propaganda rod has now turned a bastion of public information that is credible.
We have revolutionised this newspaper, he said.
In moving forward, in further professionalising the state paper and television, the PM promised major shakeup at these entities and at the Government Information Agency (GINA). He said that National Communications Network (NCN) and the Guyana Chronicle will soon be getting new boards with professional representatives.
He explained that these boards will be staffed by persons committed to professional standards, who will ensure that both the Chronicle and the NCN as public information media, not only carry out the function of informing, educating and entertaining people, but are also accountable and reliable.
He warned that the new administration expects that its state media will be viable business entities.
If you are not viable you will be pushed to the wall and where the chips fall, they fall, he said.
He explained that the complete shake-up at GINA will ensure that the entity functions as it should; as it was set up to, and that is as a small professional body to tell Guyana and the world, what government, ministers, public servants are doing for the people, he said.
what should be placed in the public domain is information so that you have an informed public, that would make better choices and not fall prey to stigma of racism and the appeal to ethnicity and all other-side agendas that are not healthy for the forward movement of Guyana, the prime minister explained..
He further stated that GINA must no longer be an agency that does things that are not in the domain of public information and that are within the narrow confines of political vendetta or political agenda to harass persons who do not share the opinion and the views of those in leadership.
He said too that the new administration will ensure that the advertisements that entities pay for GINA to place into the larger media are not sidelined to pay propaganda ads for political parties. He explained that this is the reason for the poor performance of GINA and why it has become a heavy lead pulling down NCN and Chronicle. The money paid to GINA to remit to the television and state newspaper has never been paid over, the PM said.
He explained further that an investigation is underway as to these outstanding payments including the huge sum owed to the Chronicle alone.
Meanwhile, the prime minister announced that the administration will be moving to correct expeditiously the subject of the issuing of television licences.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jamaican police investigating hacking of government websites</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Jamaican-police-investigating-hacking-of-government-websites-26699.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Jamaican police investigating hacking of government websites
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
The JIS web-team is assisted by the cybersecurity team from the Jamaica Constabulary Force (JCF), following the attack on the JIS website late Monday night. From left are: Andre Allen, Systems Administrator; Detective Inspector, Patrick Linton from the Major Organised Crime and Anti-Corruption Agency; Oneil Morgan, Computer Services Manager and Constable Jouvan Murray of the Communication Forensics and Cybercrime Unit. Photo: Dave Reid
By Douglas McIntosh
KINGSTON, Jamaica (JIS) -- Science, technology, energy and mining state minister, Julian Robinson, says the Jamaican police have commenced investigations into the hacking of the Jamaica Information Service (JIS) website, and those of five other entities, which the JIS hosts.
These are: Culture, Health, Arts, Sports, and Education (CHASE) Fund; G.C. Foster College; Social Development Commission (SDC); Houses of Parliament; and Jamaica National Commission for UNESCO.
Speaking on Thursday, Robinson said that the Jamaica Constabulary Force (JCF) has committed resources to try and identify the source of this cybercriminal activity, which occurred on June 22.
We dont know (as yet) whether its local (or) whether (it emanated from) overseas. (But) there were certain things that were posted, which we have to treat with seriously, as a country, he said.
Robinson also advised that the Cyber Incidents Response Team (CIRT), which responded when the breach was identified, is continuing work to ensure that all potential loopholes are closed, so that we can prevent future attacks.
CIRT is comprised of technical officers from several ministries, departments and agencies, including the JCF.
The state minister, again, expressed satisfaction with the extent of work undertaken by the personnel involved, which ensured that the six sites were restored within a couple of hours.
The reality of what we are dealing with is very clear. As a country and as a government, we are the target of cybercriminals, and we are moving to ensure that we can implement common standards and measures to address the issue, he stated.
In addition to the establishment of CIRT, comprising persons with extensive training and experience in cybersecurity, there are also the pending amendments to the Cybercrimes Act, acquisition of equipment, training of officers, and ensuring that systems are resilient and robust in the face of threats. Alerts and advisories are issued regularly as part of a set of established protocols.
A chief information officer has been appointed to ensure that standards will be maintained across the government and this would help with best practices.
Robinson also advised that a public education campaign is to be undertaken, to heighten awareness about cybersecurity.
The JIS website began to experience difficulties between 9:02 pm and 9:38 pm on June 22. It was taken offline for maintenance shortly thereafter and was restored by the JIS web team, which conducted recovery procedures within four hours.
Preliminary findings revealed that the attempts of the hactivists at breaching the system did not result in access to sensitive information, but was constrained to surface defacement, and no data was corrupted.
The CIRT team said that it has seen a number of activities from more than 500 blacklisted IP addresses used by cyberterrorists. They span several countries and took place within an hour.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>USVI delegate calls for inclusion in affordable healthcare programme</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-USVI-delegate-calls-for-inclusion-in-affordable-healthcare-programme-26700.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
USVI delegate calls for inclusion in affordable healthcare programme
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Delegate to the US House of Representatives from the US Virgin Islands at-large congressional district, Stacey Plaskett
WASHINGTON, USA -- Following Thursdays announcement of the US Supreme Courts decision to uphold the provision allowing the federal government, through the Affordable Care Act, to subsidize health insurance costs for low-income and middle class individuals, US Virgin Islands delegate to Congress, Stacey Plaskett, drew attention to the four million residents living in Americas island territories that remain ineligible to participate in the affordable healthcare programme.
Today, in a 6-3 split, the US Supreme Court has once again upheld the validity of the Affordable Care Act (ACA). As we celebrate this measure which is a victory for the millions of Americans who prior to this law, were without affordable healthcare; we draw attention to the four million citizens and nationals living in Americas Island territories that remain ineligible to participate in a federal exchange and are unable to establish their own state exchange, Plaskett said.
Almost a third of the residents in the US Virgin Islands live below the federal poverty line, with nearly a quarter of the general population lacking health insurance of any kind, she pointed out.
Our being excluded from the ACA, coupled with these staggering statistics is yet another example of the benign neglect, to which we in the Virgin Islands and the other four territories are subjected. Todays decision keeps this important legislation intact and affords the four million citizens and nationals in Americas island territories a glimmer of hope for future inclusion in the law, Plaskett said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Coast Guard repatriates Cuban and Haitian migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-US-Coast-Guard-repatriates-Cuban-and-Haitian-migrants-26701.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
US Coast Guard repatriates Cuban and Haitian migrants
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Eighteen Cuban migrants aboard a fishing vessel were interdicted south of Key West, Florida, June 23, 2015. All 18 of the migrants were later repatriated to Cuba. US Coast Guard photo
MIAMI, USA -- Crewmembers aboard the US Coast Guard Cutter Charles David Jr. repatriated 55 Cuban migrants to Bahia de Cabaas, Cuba, on Thursday and the crew of the Cutter William Trump repatriated 18 Haitian migrants to Cap Haitian, Haiti, also on Thursday.
These repatriations are the result of separate migrant interdictions at sea. Four of these events were Cubans trying to illegally enter the United States on unseaworthy vessels commonly called "rustics" or "chugs." In these instances the Coast Guard not only helped secure the US border, but they also prevented these perilous ocean voyages from ending in tragedy.
"Homemade vessels with no navigation or lifesaving equipment trying to cross these dangerous waters is a recipe for disaster," said Cmdr. Jeff Swanson, commanding officer of the Coast Guard Cutter Tampa.
On Sunday, the US Customs and Border Protection Office of Air and Marine assisted the Coast Guard in safely interdicting a non-compliant Cuban fishing vessel with 18 Cuban migrants aboard approximately 12 miles south of Key West, Florida. The Office of Air and Marine agents then transferred those individuals to the Coast Guard Cutter Tampa.
"This case is a great example of how the US Coast Guard works with its Department of Homeland Security partner agencies to protect and secure our maritime border," said Cmdr. Tim Cronin, Coast Guard Seventh District deputy chief of law enforcement. "There is a legal way to enter the United States...this is not it. We will seek to hold smugglers accountable and quickly repatriate migrants to their country of origin."
On Monday, a Customs and Border Protection Office of Air Marine (CPB-OAM) boat interdicted a 28-foot non-compliant vessel suspected of migrant smuggling near Palm Beach Gardens, Florida. The CBP-OAM boat crew disabled the vessel's engines and detained a suspected smuggler. Aboard the vessel were one Jamaican migrant, one Dominican migrant and 18 Haitian migrants.
The Coast Guard Cutter William Flores arrived on scene and safely embarked the Haitian migrants, later transferring them to the William Trump for repatriation. The suspected smuggler, Jamaican and Dominican were transferred ashore for further investigation.
Once aboard a Coast Guard cutter, migrants receive food, water and basic medical attention.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grenada's unemployment falls</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Grenada%27s-unemployment-falls-26702.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Email To Friend  Print Version
ST GEORGES, Grenada -- Grenadas unemployment rate has fallen by 3.6 percent, the Central Statistical Division with the ministry of finance has announced.
A labour survey done in October last year showed a drop in unemployment rate from 32.5 percent in 2013 to 28.9 percent in 2014.
Officials also report that wholesale and retail sectors continue to employ the most people.
The sectors that showed increase were education, agriculture, forestry, fisheries, said Timon Charles, senior statistician, central statistical office, ministry of finance.
We also saw an increase in the health sector and public administration and defence sector, Charles noted.
Assistant statistician Rachel Jacob reported that the highest unemployment rate was among persons between the ages of 15 to 24.
Governments share of employment rose from 19.1 percent in 2013 to 24.4 percent in 2014, largely because of the Imani Programme.
Of the 3,517 persons interviewed in the survey, 1,795 were males and 1,722 females.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Montserrat progresses with development of climate change policy and action plan</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Montserrat-progresses-with-development-of-climate-change-policy-and-action-plan-26703.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Montserrat progresses with development of climate change policy and action plan
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
BRADES, Montserrat -- Stakeholders in Montserrat are aiming to achieve climate resilient development through an integrated and coordinated response prioritising climate change responses across all sectors and society.
This was the goal proposed by stakeholders for Montserrats new national climate change policy during a workshop held on June 18 in Little Bay.
The ministry of agriculture, trade, land, housing and the environment is leading the collective effort to prepare a national climate change policy and action plan for Montserrat. This is being supported under the climate change adaptation and sustainable land management project in the Eastern Caribbean, which is managed by the Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States (OECS) on behalf of participating members. The Caribbean Natural Resources Institute (CANARI) is facilitating the process.
Climate change will have serious impacts across all sectors and facets of life in Montserrat and stakeholders are developing a national policy and action plan. These will lay out a framework for an integrated and coordinated response that engages all stakeholders in collaborative actions for adaptation (via building resilience to negative impacts) and mitigation (via low carbon development).
The unusually dry season Montserrat experienced this year is likely to be more frequent and more intense as a result of climate change. The average annual rainfall is expected to decrease and temperatures to increase. More intense storms and hurricanes with heavier rainfall and higher winds can cause flooding and landslides. Bigger storm surges alongside sea level rise will threaten Little Bay and other coastal developments.
The recent workshop was the second in the consultation process for stakeholders to analyse impacts and decide on priorities. Priority areas for urgent action include making energy and water infrastructure (including generation systems, distribution lines and storage systems) able to withstand the projected extreme weather events. Critical infrastructure such as the hospital, airport, seaport and roads, and buildings will also need to be enhanced to ensure that they can also withstand the stronger storms and hurricanes.
Management strategies will need to be put in place to protect ecosystems and biodiversity. New agricultural methods and crops will be needed to ensure food production can continue, and increase, given drought and high temperatures. Health systems will need to be put in place to address the projected increase in diseases which are anticipated with changes in rainfall and higher temperatures.
In the workshop, stakeholders noted that the action plan needs to be realistic given the capacity constraints in Montserrat. It will clearly identify short, medium and long-term actions to guide responses by all sectors. But they were positive in recognising that addressing climate change issues and climate proofing sectors will build on much of the work already being done in developing renewable energy and the new energy policy, the new building code, conservation of biodiversity, and agricultural extension.
The draft policy and action plan are available from the Department of Environment or CANARI for comment until June 30.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Public health policymaking to get new life with help from CARPHA</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Public-health-policymaking-to-get-new-life-with-help-from-CARPHA-26704.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Public health policymaking to get new life with help from CARPHA
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
ST GEORGES, Grenada -- A study conducted by one of the former regional health institutions found that governments generally lack the capacity to assess and use research to make health policy decisions. Furthermore, the type of research needed to inform health decisions in the region is not necessarily the type that is being conducted.
Understanding the impact that these situations can have on public health in the region, the Caribbean Public Health Agency (CARPHA), has launched an initiative called the Evidence Informed Decision Making Network of the Caribbean (EvIDeNCe).
One of the functions of CARPHA is the provision of accurate, reliable, timely and relevant public health information. Through the EvIDeNCe, CARPHA will be able to adhere to this mandate, as policy-makers and researchers will be able to access information and services relevant to their work. Policy-makers will be provided with easy access to Caribbean research evidence to support their decision-making needs.
CARPHA will also host regular dialogues on pressing health policy issues. During these dialogues, Researchers, policy-makers and stakeholders will have an opportunity to share their knowledge and experience. In this way, solutions that are based on the best available scientific evidence but which also fit the unique social and political context of the Caribbean could be found. It is envisaged that by bringing together a diverse group persons with interest in the topic, new insights about solving the problems can be sparked.
Additionally, CARPHA will provide training to help build the required capacity in the region so as to enable all member states to have the tools needed to make more informed health decisions.
According to Dr Andrea Yearwood, the senior health policy analyst at CARPHA, the benefits of the initiative to the region are many.
CARPHA will work with countries to develop evidence briefs for a particular health problem that ministries may be grappling with, and when requested will summarize what is scientifically known about the problem, and identify context specific policy and program options to address them, she said.
The Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), McMaster University, Health Forum and the University of the West Indies have provided considerable support to this initiative, as they believe that it is necessary and important and will be of great benefit to the ministries of health in the region. Representatives from these organizations, including Nickolas Steele, the minister of health Grenada, were on hand for the launch of the network.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hostile climate for Dominican Republic media since start of 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Hostile-climate-for-Dominican-Republic-media-since-start-of-2015-26705.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Hostile climate for Dominican Republic media since start of 2015
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PARIS, France (RSF) -- The first half of 2015 has been arduous for journalists in the Dominican Republic, with physical attacks, threats, prosecutions and a murder. Freedom of information is also weakened by continuing impunity for crimes of violence against media personnel and the concentration of media ownership in few hands.
Journalists who cover sensitive stories such as corruption or drug trafficking are exposed to the possibility of threats or violent reprisals by government officials or organized crime.
Progress was initially slow in the investigation into the murder of Blas Olivo, the press director of the Dominican Agribusiness Association (JAD), whose body was found 80 km (50 miles) north of Santo Domingo on 13 April. When his family and friends staged a demonstration on 18 May to press the police to solve his murder, the national police chief said the leading suspects would soon be arrested.
At a news conference on 3 June, the police said he was murdered by members of the Latin King gang on the orders of Jos Miguel Rodrguez Almonte, an already imprisoned gang leader accused of more than 100 murders. However, Rodrguez Almonte was mysteriously gunned down in his cell by police on 12 June, depriving the investigation of a key witness for confirming this theory and for identifying the masterminds.
Since the start of the year, Reporters Without Borders (RSF) has registered two cases of media personnel being physically attacked by police officers or soldiers to prevent them from continuing to do some potentially embarrassing reporting.
In the latest case, members of the National Directorate for Drug Control (DNCD) attacked Fausto Garca as he was trying to film a DNCD operation in Navaratte, in the northern province of Santiago, on 27 March.
Telefuturo Canal 23 cameraman Eduard Gonzlez was assaulted by soldiers while filming incidents outside an electoral commission office in the Santo Domingo district of Trianitos on 14 January.
We are very concerned about abusive treatment of the media and we condemn all forms of violence designed to censor media coverage or punish journalists who are just trying to do their work, said Claire San Filippo, the head of the Reporters Without Borders Americas desk.
The Dominican authorities should concentrate on combating impunity for violence against journalists and set an example by pressing ahead with the decriminalization of media offences begun in 2012.
Smear and hate campaigns
Four journalists  Juan Bolvar Daz, Huchi Lora, Amelia Deschamps and Roberto Cavada  announced on 2 February that they were the targets of a hate campaign for showing support for Haitians resident in the Dominican Republic.
This is a sensitive issue since the adoption of Law 169/14 in May 2014, a law that is said to violate the American Convention on Human Rights because it denies Dominican citizenship to many persons of Haitian descent born in the Dominican Republic.
The four journalists filed a complaint about the public humiliation and threats they had received in January and February, which they said had been orchestrated by a group called the Independent Patriotic Movement.
A few days later, TV reporter Salvador Holgun said he had been the target of death threats and a social network smear campaign since an interview in which a former drug trafficker and army captain, Quirino Paulino Castillo, claimed to have lent 200 million pesos to former president Leonel Fernndez of the ruling PLD party.
The Dominican Association of Journalists (CDP) reported in April that Holgun had been told by TeleRadioAmerica Canal 45 not to broadcast the interview during his programme and that, according to Holgun, the orders came from persons close to Fernndez.
This is not the first time that Fernndez associates have censored a TV station in this manner. In 2010, officials ordered the closure of privately-owned Canal 53-Cibao TV Club after one of its presenters made critical comments about Fernndez.
Threats and acts of violence against journalists are all the more worrying because they are rarely solved.
Reporters Without Borders has nonetheless noted some significant court rulings in favour of media personnel. On 18 April, the supreme court threw out a defamation case against journalists Hector Tineo, Guillermo Tejeda and Hector Herrera Cabral.
And on 9 April, a court threw out a government officials claim that his constitutional rights were violated by a journalist who criticized the way the Development and Cooperative Credit Institute (IDECOOP) was being run. The case was rejected on the grounds that the officials goal was to obtain the right of reply.
Precarious employment
At a news conference on 7 April, celebrated as Day of the Journalist, the Dominican Association of Journalists painted a grim picture of journalism in the Dominican Republic, blaming the concentration of media ownership for the lack of job security and the high level of self-censorship.
According to the association, journalists have to choose between covering frivolous subjects that do not threaten the interests of advertisers and doing serious investigative reporting with the accompanying risk of losing their jobs.
Legislative progress is also needed because journalists continue to be exposed to the possibility of prison sentences or heavy fines in connection with their work. Progress has been made in recent years on the decriminalization of media offences but it has yet to be completed.
The protection of journalists source has been guaranteed since a constitutional amendment in 2009. And a major step was taken in 2013, when the supreme court ruled that article 46 of Law 6132 on the Expression and Dissemination of Thought was unconstitutional. The article listed professions whose members could be convicted of press offences.
The Dominican Republic is ranked 63rd out of 180 countries in the Press Freedom Index that Reporters Without Borders released in February.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Vincent PM to deliver Emancipation Day lecture in St Martin</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Vincent-PM-to-deliver-Emancipation-Day-lecture-in-St-Martin-26706.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Vincent PM to deliver Emancipation Day lecture in St Martin
Published onJune 27, 2015
GREAT BAY, St Martin -- Prime minister of St Vincent and the Grenadines, and a campaigner for reparatory justice, Dr Ralph Gonsalves, will deliver a guest Emancipation Day lecture organized by the Independence for St Martin Foundation, on Saturday.
Dr Ralph Gonsalves
The lecture, on the topic of Reparations, will be held at the University of St Martin.
Gonsalves, known as Comrade Ralph, is the longest-serving prime minister in the Caribbean, having been elected to office in 2001 and winning re-election at two subsequent general elections. He is a proponent of Caribbean unity, and an advocate of reparatory justice.
We have to be very focused so that the new colonialism and imperialism now being practiced by Western nations cannot pick us off one-by-one, he told a gathering of ambassadors, politicians, and activists in Brooklyn, New York, recently.
Speaking before the UN General Assembly a couple of years ago, Gonsalves alerted the international community regarding the 14-nation Caribbean Community (CARICOM) plans to pursue reparations. He informed the personalities gathered in Brooklyn that the lawsuit against the United Kingdom, France, and the Netherlands was going forward; however, he said, It needs to move faster.
The legacy of the crimes against humanity (committed by these and other European nations during centuries of slavery) -- a legacy that exists today in our Caribbean -- should be repaired for the development of our Caribbean peoples and societies, Gonsalves said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>USVI music fest set for St Thomas</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-USVI-music-fest-set-for-St-Thomas-26707.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
USVI music fest set for St Thomas
Published onJune 27, 2015
The USVI's Pressure Busspipe to perform at summer music festival
ST THOMAS, USVI -- Music will be in the air in the US Virgin Islands this summer.
On the heels of the St John Festival carnival celebration to be held over the July 4th holiday weekend, its sister island St Thomas will take its turn to host America's Paradise USVI Music Festival, featuring top tier musicians and entertainers, from July 16 to 19.
The summer festival features the likes of Barrington Levy, Destra, Don Omar, Third World, Cedric the Entertainer, Future, and the US Virgin Islands' own reggae musician Pressure Busspipe.
"Special events such as Music Fest help to drive business throughout the summer months," said Beverly Nicholson-Doty, Commissioner of Tourism for the USVI.
"We are looking forward to, not only enjoying some great music and entertainment, but also welcoming many visitors and festival goers to Charlotte Amalie next month," she added.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: The View from Europe: Education innovation and the future</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-The-View-from-Europe%3A-Education-innovation-and-the-future-26708.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: The View from Europe: Education innovation and the future
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By David Jessop
For many years now, the Caribbean has been able to cultivate a generally positive image of high literacy levels and academic achievement. It has given the world Nobel laureates and has demonstrated a capacity for intellectual rigour and debate that makes it among the more interesting regions of the world with which to engage. It has used this to promote itself as a location for foreign investment and as an indicator of its identity and culture.
David Jessop is the Director of the Caribbean Council and can be contacted at david.jessop@caribbean-council.org . Previous columns can be found at www.caribbean-council.org
However, look more closely at what is happening on the ground in many states and it becomes clear that away from a small elite group of schools, the regions secondary education system is failing to turn out students with the type of qualifications or skills that will enable the Caribbean to succeed in the highly competitive services-based industries that its future rests upon.
Moreover, while there are a growing number of publicly and privately funded centres of excellence within higher education in the region, it is clear that there is much more that needs to be done to adapt tertiary education to the globally competitive academic environment in which all higher academic institutions now operate. Put more simply, if Caribbean universities are to attract the best undergraduates, researchers and faculty they need to do so based on a reputation for rigour, educational outcomes that are more than satisfactory, and new sources of income.
Two years ago, Saint Lucias Prime Minister, Dr Kenny Anthony, speaking largely in the context of secondary education, spelt out where declining educational standards and poorer quality schools might lead the region. He said that there was a need to place greater emphasis on developing citizens who can make a contribution otherwise (his country) was in danger of becoming uncompetitive. Concerning numbers of young people, he said, were leaving school unready for the world of work, and did not have any marketable, technical or vocational skills.
Recently produced figures appear to support this. While there has been a slow upward trend in exam results for the Caribbean Secondary Education Certificate (CSEC) and Caribbean Certificate of Secondary Level Competence (CCSLC), a December 2014 Caribbean Exams Council (CXC) report suggested that from 2012 to 2014 the number of candidate entries for January exam sittings declined by 25 percent, while the May/June entries fell by 4.5 percent. The reasons given were economic considerations, declining birth rates, policy decisions, and general low interest.
What is apparent is that there is a pressing need to redefine the regions approach to education to ensure it is producing individuals with competencies that place the region on a path to sustainable development. As many Caribbean educators point out, education in the Caribbean may not be fit for this purpose as it has largely been based on adapting a colonial inheritance.
What is needed, they suggest, is a new educational philosophy appropriate to the contemporary Caribbean, a Caribbean-led assessment of the regions key competencies, a focus on the economic areas where the region might hope in future to have global competitive advantage, and an approach more closely related to the digital world.
Speaking about this recently to the chief executives of two major Caribbean companies, one from Trinidad, the other from Jamaica, it is clear that the matter is becoming serious. They noted that companies are having to start their own skills development programmes. One cited the example of Trinidad, where labour shortages in the construction, hospitality and the garment industry are growing, and pointed to a report produced by the Trinidad and Tobago Chamber of Commerce that suggests that poor attitudes, absenteeism, indiscipline, illiteracy, a disdain for service industries, and a lack of continuous skills training, were starting to damage key sectors.
This is concerning, as there are multiple studies that indicate knowledge-based economies represent the only realistic long-term future for most resource-poor small states and, for this reason, education in nations such as those in the Caribbean has to be transformational, technology-driven and relevant to national development.
Across the world, new technologies are now disrupting the way in which in which government and business is organised, threatening to leave much of the Caribbean behind. At the same time, high speed broadband, total connectivity, and the offer of low cost or even free Wi-Fi is opening the world of ideas and opportunity potentially to everyone, making size and location less relevant.
This means that trained and educated individuals can creatively apply and ally their skills to income without leaving to work overseas; offering opportunity in everything from computer animation, to back office services, design, three dimensional printing applications, and the many the new ideas that are emerging in the world beyond the region.
What is now happening globally begs the question as to whether the skills and forms of thinking that much of the Caribbean has previously encouraged will still be relevant in ten years time.
The region is not short of ideas about how to advance changes in education. Taken at random recent reports suggest schools and the classrooms need to be modernised and new technology introduced; distance learning needs facilitating; consideration needs to be given to future labour force demands in priority sector such as tourism, financial services, and light manufacturing; foreign language teaching needs expanding; schools need to be better managed and more accountable; models like the Caribbean Science Foundation (CSF) that encourage innovation should be more widely applied; university research needs to be related to private sector needs; and new sources of financing for education are required.
Given that in most Caribbean states educational spending is falling and having to compete with other social priorities including healthcare and housing, the starting point ought to be finding new funding for education.
Here there is a wealth of external experience. In North America, Europe and in states like Singapore, community colleges and tertiary education establishments have been created through foundations; corporate money is used for public/private educational partnerships; there are commercially-led research parks around universities; and fee-paying summer schools support full- time education. There are also many other ways.
For example, large regional and hemispheric multinationals engaged in the region, including those from China, should be encouraged to invest in schools and local education out of self-interest and to demonstrate their corporate social responsibility.
If innovation and entrepreneurship are to thrive in the Caribbean, it will require both a change in thinking and an equally radical change in education from the primary school level upwards.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Montserrat remains a land that has not lost touch with its most endearing qualities</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Montserrat-remains-a-land-that-has-not-lost-touch-with-its-most-endearing-qualities-26709.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Montserrat remains a land that has not lost touch with its most endearing qualities
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Jeevan A. Robinson
Resilience in the face of tragedy is an admirable quality. The people of Montserrat, in their collective entirety, throughout these past 20 years of volcanic discourse, have often been described as such  resilient.
Jeevan Robinson is founder and editor-in-chief of the global Caribbean marketing, news and information media house, MNI Alive.com. He can be reached at jeevan@mnialive.com
On June 25, 1997, 19 lives were lost as a direct result of the volcanic devastation that has impacted the island these almost 20 years. The loss of life was, and still is a solemn occasion for all the island's people; for as the echoes go, it could have possibly been avoided.
But today was neither the day nor the moment for recriminations as to who was neglectful, too political, too gung-ho or anything of that nature. Today has been a day for Montserrats reflection to be considered in the light of what the island has endured, and where the island has come to thus far in its rebirth.
Of the 19 lives lost, I know of friends who lost parents and other loved ones. On a personal level, our family too suffered a loss on that day, with an uncle, Phillip Robinson losing his life in the volcanic tragedy of June 25, 1997. My neighbour also, Joseph Greenaway aka Shortman, also lost his life on that fateful day.
A community as small as Montserrat could have been broken irreparably from such a massive blow to the national psyche. Sometimes I wonder frankly if this volcanic devastation  even though it has presented much opportunity for the island in many regards  if it has not also shifted a section of the national psyche in ways that only professional assessors can ascertain whether this has been good, or fundamentally bad for the islands future prospects. In time to come we shall all see, I suppose, where this all bears fruit for the island and her people.
Despite all the questions that remain, and the fights that have ensued during these years of regrowth, Montserrat still remains a land that has not lost touch with its most endearing qualities. As big a demographic shift as the island has had with some changes noticeable socially  the overriding theme for Montserrat is one of peace and an enduring non-violent commune.
For this, after 20 years, visitors can still come and walk amongst residents and, within a few hours, feel as if they have always lived with the island's people. This is strength of purpose, a fashionable and commendable display of resilience with quality in the face of gigantic odds. If for peace and relaxation only, then all visitors should afford themselves even a day walking the soil of Montserrat.
After today is done, and these 20 years have been observed, Montserrat will continue on. The lives of those 19 lost along the flanks of the Soufriere Hills Volcano will be remembered for even 100 years on from today, for their sacrifice is Montserrats sacrifice. A sacrifice of resilience and hope.
It is within the island's remit to not only remember those lost lives just for one day, and then tomorrow relegate them back to collateral loss to be expected from natures fury.
More so, as the island grapples with politics, economics, personalities, cultural shifts and social transformation, amidst all of its redevelopment tasks  there should be an all-encompassing legacy to never forget why Montserrat's people, both on the ground and throughout the Diaspora, fight for Montserrat.
It is who we are as a people together that will make history record this volcanic tragedy as a uniting force, and not as a detriment and an instrument of division, loss and stagnation.
We respect those lives lost by paying homage to them all, and offering our deepest regards to their families who remember them and mourn them today and always. Montserrat remembers, and she moves forward in observance.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Kaiso! Kaiso! Vincy Kaiso 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Kaiso%21-Kaiso%21-Vincy-Kaiso-2015-26710.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Kaiso! Kaiso! Vincy Kaiso 2015
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
Its Vincy Mas time again in St Vincent and the Grenadines (SVG) and 2015 is no different; boy, the emails, texts and calls about calypsos ah fill up me smartphone. As usual yo know me ears ah tuned to the ground in Vincyland and as I-Madd said,  I Love This Land .
For a second year in ah row, no Ex-tempo (the step-up, put on yo big undies, high jump competition) and another reprieve have been granted to me partner Ras Boo! No annual spanking again this year for Ras Boo from Blakey. Well, last year I sent yo coach Ras Bucket out of Anguilla. But it seems like yo opted for me old Spanish teacher and former colleague at the St Vincent Grammar School Man CP and the Drinkers Anthem for Christmas 2014.
However, the goal is still to dethrone the venerable step-up, put on yo big undies, high jump champion, Blakey. Therefore, yo ha fo get wid the program and do the Fosbury Flop! Ah told yo already, it may take two Ras to bring down Blakey because two Ras are better than one! So yo cant get as Poorsah said,  Rumified .
Boy, the Carnival Development Corporation (CDC) started off on the wrong foot in 2015. The first Vincy Mas ad from the CDC left out one of the pillars of Vincy Mas! Can yo believe it? Calypso was left out! I guess CDC is as Denis Bowman said,  Calypso Best Friend . Well, I aint leaving out Calypso that is why each year I write the Kaiso! Kaiso! Vincy Kaiso letter.
Next, ah see Hero kick off the Kaiso Kallaloo by capturing the new song competition with the 3D Woman! Hero boy, 3D printers are very expensive man! Maybe, yo could win some ah dat 3D lotto money and buy one, man!
Well, John The Truth Dougan and his inquiring mind is asking, what kind of  Secret Weapon  the man bringing to Vincyland? But please tell the people the truth! Maybe The Truth could ask Brother Ebony for some  Sign Language  lessons.
Yo done know I love me social commentary kaiso and with elections due in less than nine months, this year was no letdown. Fabulous T sound off by stating a  Changes is Coming ! But me old geography teacher, Lord Have Mercy said,  This One Will Be Tight ! Nevertheless, Bob MC followed up with  Comrade  boy you have to go!
On the other hand, as the social melee got into full swing, the annual heavy hitters from the Ontour Calypso Tent were in fine form. Its a brand new day and the Ring the Bell man burning fire because the days of slavery gone. So, Patches telling all them Uncle Toms plain and flat, Comrade aint going back dey,  Massa Days Done !
Who other than Abijah could tell you about the  Monkey Man ? After all, last year he brought us the Invisible Man and sitting up on Monkey Hill, he could see all the monkey business. Kaiso, Kaiso, Abijah! Yeah, too much monkey business in SVG.
Tell me again, they bribing (toilets and baths) just to get votes. Therefore, the Bad John kaiso man is spelling them out. Well, who tell he do dat;  Not a Cent  for Zion-I under this government. However, Zion-I have no fear! So, if yo think yo more than me! Yo lie! You could  Never  be more than Zion-I! Word like raaain, from the Bad John kaiso man!
Exposer was in vintage form with Gun no ha no brain. So too was Rejector with  That is Why . Boy, ah need to call on the Stinger from yesteryears and Allyo Stop De Killing, Killing because the Master coming, coming! For that reason and more Papa Iston is saying  We want back we country !
Kaiso, Kaiso, Lexi lamenting, sorry, we aint have that here in Our Story Book! Now GC is saying Dont do me that! So, Shaunelle keeping her Ears to the Ground as SVG crumbles and they scorn her! Parry boy, are you sure you have named all the Enemies of the State?
Brother Ebony says things in SVG High except Lowmans Hill and yo salary. Futhermore, Johnny Rebel says hard times as Life Getting Hard and he wishes money could grow on trees, so it can rain pennies! According to Kahalia aka Queen B, cost of living getting out of hand but Salary  Nah Grow At All  until you see the doctor!
Blackman be proud to be black says Ninja! Consequently, Isahjah say we Voting for the Blackman! Call the elections and see Vibrating Scakes Dancing at 64 for true democracy! Well Bump-I telling everyone, Ah Voting early election morning and he cant wait for the election date! Boy, Bump-I voting them out! Call it, call it, because as Brother Dan says, Poor People Tired!
Sir D says take yo hands out of the Sugar Pan because its not yours and I dont want any nolle prosequi! Saharro with his Roll Call number says: One by one by one; Two by two; Three by three; E.G., call them by their number! RIP  Lord Teach, gone but not forgotten!
In this day and age, Chico B needs to stay out from  Under the Bed  unless he has a  Chronic Disorder  like Jamesy P and as De Man Age said some years ago Them Fellers Smoking Too!
However, Maddzart says yo ha-fe  Go Hard ! But Maffie is  Addicted to Soca  and Problem Child states thats  So Amazing ! Therefore, Skinny Fabulous declares,  Argument done !
Tourism and Culture Minister Ces, wazzup fo Jouvert man? Is it the HMS Providence? Ces boy, the people would prefer to see the HMS Bounty and a little mutiny! Then yo could bring back the classic mas Sailor overboard from famed Vincy masman Junior Melbourne Constance. At the same time yo could be dancing to the classic TnT calypso Captain the ship is sinking (The Trinidad) by Gypsy. Ces, Jouvert ah ole Mas and all ah dat ah Mas in SVG fo 2015 and as Ellis Darkchild said,  Carnival we love yo !
Peace and justice and enjoy Vincy Mas 2015.
Lenford OGarro
Washington
P.S. Seems like Old Age really caught up with I-Pa! Or is it that he doesnt want another Jumbie Police Slap? I-Pa boy, stay sober!

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Classism oftentimes a mask for silent wrongs in Jamaica</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Classism-oftentimes-a-mask-for-silent-wrongs-in-Jamaica-26711.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Classism oftentimes a mask for silent wrongs in Jamaica
Published onJune 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
As the ongoing debate and discourse about class, colour, identity and ethnicity continued to be debated, as the discourse continues on social media, on the streets, on verandahs, in the printed media such as the numerous letters to the editor in the Jamaica Observer, the Jablogz blog and electronic media such as CVM with Mr Simon Croskill, we realized how entrenched these issues have become and have no intention of going away.
Any postcolonial society, in which people are marginalized, worse, looked down as inferiors, will be divided to the point of resistance and possible rebellion. Power, whether economic, social or cultural in the hands of a few people can be disastrously devastating. A house that is divided will soon tumble down. Interestingly it will tumble down or gravitate towards indiscipline when one side gets away with atrocities, corruption or injustices, as is the case with many countries where people of Afro origin find themselves as the others.
But lets look at a serious issue that is a feature of Jamaica and those who are the privileged classists. I am referring to wrongdoings or crimes in which those of a silent hue or colour get away because of the silence in that sphere, in the space of Uptown.
For several decades uptown or classist people have a way of decriminalizing crimes that, if happened in the wider society, result in imprisonment and ostracizing of its people.
First, incest. Incest has always been a big issue in uptown. How do they deal with it? They ship out the aggrieved party to Miami, and frequently the culprit. Many of us have heard in hushed tones of the evil committed against daughters and stepdaughters, yet the law has never been able to take its course because the hegemony of a particular class has allowed the culprits to get away by their ability to finance the aggrieved party in apartments and lodgings in South Florida.
The next big issue is crimes of gun impropriety  many young men, including sons of prominent light skinned politicians, have been caught with guns, either illegal guns or guns destined for bird shooting. Four years ago a prominent JLP MPs son pleaded guilty to possession of his having his fathers shotgun at a bird shooting fiesta. In our corrupt society, he only paid a fine and was given a warning. Talking confidentially to several high ranking high colour MPs and lawyers stopped the cops from taking his son, who was found with an illegal gun, by paying millions. Again, there is silence because the general media are oblivious to this, as money is used to hush up the crime.
Then we have crimes against humanity  the flooding of our shores with hard drugs from Colombia. Power, colour and money allow riches to be made from illicit drugs that destroy peoples lives while the perpetrators sleep without conscience. There are lurid stories of hardware being stashed with drugs, escorted by crooked cops and eyes turned in the opposite direction, as so called decent people indulge in destruction while profiling as good and upstanding citizens.
On a personal note, at university years ago, an accounting student was fired by a Jewish bigwig because he refused to write off millions of damages to packed goods at a Jamaican port. Again silence as a criminal act was committed, defrauding the Insurance company back then of millions. As is usual for us, the black majority, he had to pack his bag, protecting his dignity but not succumbing to the evil of those who pretend to be honest and decent.
Who then expects a clean society with values when those who say they are the upper class are in contempt of the law, instead of with their power, intelligence and education striving for a solid society of virtue, ethics and morality?
Maurice Christie
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Privy Council affirms no trial by jury in Turks and Caicos corruption cases</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Privy-Council-affirms-no-trial-by-jury-in-Turks-and-Caicos-corruption-cases-26677.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Privy Council affirms no trial by jury in Turks and Caicos corruption cases
Published onJune 26, 2015
Former Turks and Caicos Islands premier Michael Misick
By Caribbean News Now contributor
LONDON, England -- On Thursday, the Judicial Committee of the Privy Council (JCPC) in London handed down its written judgment in relation to and appeal former Turks and Caicos Islands (TCI) premier Michael Misick seeking to enforce his right to trial by jury instead of by judge alone as requested by the prosecution in the ongoing corruption trials in the British territory.
In addition to Misick, the case involves a number of other citizens and former ministers of the TCI, who are charged with corruption and other offences in the TCI, following an investigation subsequent to a Commission of Inquiry led by Sir Robin Auld. The appellants challenged the impartiality and independence of Justice Paul Harrison, a former president of the Court of Appeal of Jamaica, who was appointed to hear their case.
Ironically, the impracticability of finding jurors with no prior knowledge or opinions on the issues at stake given the very small pool (of approximately 6,000) to choose from in the TCI; and the inevitability that such jurors would be exposed to extra-evidential opinions and information, prompted Misick to submit forcefully to Auld at the Commission of Inquiry that trial by jury could not be fair to him.
The appeal now arguing to the contrary was heard by the JCPC on May 11, 2015, when the court indicated at the time that the appeal would be dismissed.
In relating the background to the appeals in its written judgment, the JCPC noted that from 2008 to 2009 there was a constitutional crisis in the TCI, then self-governing under a constitution of 2006. Following concerns about the administration of the TCI, a Commission of Inquiry was appointed into possible corruption or other serious dishonesty in relation to past and present elected members of the Legislature in recent years.
The Commissioner, Sir Robin Auld, published a report (the Report) recommending, amongst other things, the partial suspension of the 2006 Constitution, the creation of a special prosecution team to investigate evidence of corruption and dishonesty and the suspension of the absolute right to trial by jury.
The 2006 Constitution had provided for government by a Governor, acting on the advice of the Premier and his cabinet. However, following the Report and the effect given to the Report by the UK government, temporary direct rule by the Governor was instituted. The legislature was dissolved, the cabinet ceased to exist and the principal offices of government and legislature, such as the Premier and Speaker of the Assembly, were declared vacant.
After two years, self-government was restored and a new 2011 Constitution inaugurated. Similar to the 2006 Constitution, Section 6(1) of the 2011 Constitution affords those charged with a criminal offence the right to a fair hearing within a reasonable time by an independent and impartial court established by law. Unlike the 2006 Constitution, however, the 2011 Constitution does not contain an unqualified right to jury trial upon a criminal charge. Even though trial by jury is the norm, section 4 of the Trials Without a Jury Ordinance 2010 (TWAJO) allows a trial to be heard by a judge alone if the interests of justice so require.
A Special Investigation Team was created and it was this body that brought charges of conspiracy to accept bribes in public office, conspiracy to defraud and associated money laundering against Misick, other government ministers and their associates (the Appellants). Harrison J, an experienced judge in his mid-seventies from Jamaica, was appointed on 26 February 2015 for the specific purpose of presiding over these cases. The appointment was made for a fixed period of three years. Pursuant to section 4 of TWAJO, Harrison J directed that the interests of justice required trial by himself without a jury.
The Appellants challenged the lawfulness of their proposed trial on the grounds that: (1) contrary to section 6(1) of the 2011 Constitution, Harrison J did not have sufficient security of tenure and, thus, was not independent; and, (2) Harrison J failed to ask whether there was no reasonable doubt (the criminal standard of proof) that the interests of justice required a trial without jury before deciding so. The Appellants' claim was rejected by Harrison J himself and, subsequently, by the Court of Appeal.
The JCPC (with Lord Hughes giving its judgment) dismissed the appeal.
Reasons for the Judgment
On the first ground, Lord Hughes recalled that in the present case: (a) the Constitutional guarantee of judicial independence, remuneration, allowances and terms of service apply to Harrison J as they do to any other judge; (b) Harrison J has been appointed on the recommendation of the independent Judicial Service Commission; and, (c) Harrison J is guaranteed security of tenure during his appointment, except in the case of cause shown to this Board.
As for the limited term of his appointment, no objective observer would fear that Harrison J would entertain any sense of lack of independence in trials which he has been specifically asked to take on, outside his home territory and in his retirement. Far from a danger of lack of independence, his appointment has been made precisely to bring to locally highly controversial cases an independent outsider.
The Board does not need to decide whether other Supreme Court judges in the Turks and Caicos Islands lack sufficient security of tenure and has insufficient evidence of practice to do so  they are routinely appointed for an initial period of three years subject to renewal by agreement, but appointments are subject to the independent Judicial Service Commission. Whatever may be the practice as to their situation, it cannot affect Harrison J. He has been brought in ad hoc from outside and there is no sensible prospect that a judge who enjoys sufficient security of tenure to maintain his independence might lose it on the grounds that others lack his advantages.
On the second ground, not every decision which has to be made by a judge during or in preparation for a criminal trial is susceptible to analysis in terms of burden and standard of proof. Here, there is no doubt that the decision required by TWAJO  where, in relation to predictive conditions, a judge is required to weigh different factors and make a judgment as to necessity  is not susceptible of analysis in terms of proof or the standard of it. This applies to both the finding of facts and the evaluation of the interests of justice in light of those findings. Indeed, in this case there were no significant disputed primary facts according to Harrison J.
Harrison J recalled the fundamental importance of jury trials before working through the factors relevant to the interests of justice test. He was entitled to come to the conclusion he did. This was particularly the case in light of: (a) the complexity of the trial issues; (b) the impracticability of finding jurors with no prior knowledge or opinions on the issues at stake given the very small pool (of approximately 6,000) to choose from; and, (c) the inevitability that such jurors would be exposed to extra-evidential opinions and information, which had led the Appellants to submit forcefully to Sir Robin Auld that trial by jury could not be fair to them. In any event, even if Harrison J ought to have applied the criminal standard of proof, he could not realistically have reached any conclusion other than the one he did.
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trinidad opposition candidates under investigation by Integrity Commission</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Trinidad-opposition-candidates-under-investigation-by-Integrity-Commission-26678.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Trinidad opposition candidates under investigation by Integrity Commission
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- The opposition People's National Movement (PNM) in Trinidad and Tobago is going into the September 7 general election with two of its candidates now before the Integrity Commission, the Voice newspaper reported.
Marlene McDonald
In the first case, opposition leader Dr Keith Rowleys right hand, Marlene McDonald, is under investigation by the Integrity Commission over contracts given out to Calabar Foundation, while she was minister of community development in the previous PNM administration.
McDonalds husband, Michael Carew, and his brother, Lennox, are listed as directors of Calabar Foundation, which received $375,000 from the ministry of community development, even before their company had been registered.
Victor McEachrane is also listed as a director.
McEachrane is also listed as a director of Waterwheel Foundation, which received large contracts from the ministry during McDonalds tenure at the ministry.
Faris Al Rawi
McEachranes name has cropped up on several contracts received from the ministry of community development, culture and gender affairs.
In the second matter, Faris Al Rawi, the PNM candidate for the San Fernando West constituency, is also under investigation by the Integrity Commission for a conflict of interest. Faris allegedly tried to raise an issue concerning a client of his and the Trinidad and Tobago Electricity Commission (TTEC) during a debate in the Senate.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Answers sought regarding legal cost to St Lucia of controversial oil exploration agreement</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Answers-sought-regarding-legal-cost-to-St-Lucia-of-controversial-oil-exploration-agreement-26679.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Answers sought regarding legal cost to St Lucia of controversial oil exploration agreement
Published onJune 26, 2015
RSM Production Company (RSM) president Jack J. Grynberg (L) and Prime Minister Dr Kenny Anthony
By Caribbean News Now contributor
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- Saint Lucias prime minister, Dr Kenny Anthony, has been called on to apprise the nation of the legal costs involved in the governments ongoing efforts to settle an ill-fated agreement purporting to grant oil exploration rights over some eight million acres of Saint Lucias maritime territory.
In or about February 2000, Anthony, as then minister of finance, planning and sustainable development, signed a contract with RSM Production Company (RSM), a Texas company, along with its president Jack Grynberg, that purported to grant the company an Exploration License in respect of territorial maritime resources belonging to Saint Lucia amounting to 8,726,263 acres.
An ongoing claim by RSM in relation to the agreement is currently before the International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes in Washington, DC, but the matter was deferred again in April following RSMs failure to put up US$750,000 security for Saint Lucias legal costs.
On Thursday, the Lucian Peoples Movement (LPM) said that Anthony is obligated to offer the people of Saint Lucia an open and full disclosure regarding this matter.
Furthermore, in doing so, he would finally ensure his governments full compliance with the true meaning and ideals of accountability and transparency, which he has often maintained are the hallmarks of good governance, the LPM said in a press release.
According to the LPM, in addition to being a lesson for Anthony, who signed an agreement with Grynberg for oil exploration in Saint Lucia without any prior consultation with the citizens of Saint Lucia, the Grynberg affair highlights the painful repercussions that result when leaders with autocratic tendencies make ill-conceived decisions which could well saddle an entire nation with insurmountable financial debt.
Saint Lucia is currently being represented in the matter by a total of five lawyers, all of whom are employed by the law firm Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer, which operates in both the United States and the United Kingdom.
In late 2013, a complaint was filed with the US Department of Justice stating that the following facts, among others, established probable cause that a crime had been committed in relation to the RSM contract to warrant investigation and possible prosecution under the US Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA):
1. The contract was signed by Anthony purportedly as a Saint Lucia government minister but who was not in fact legally authorised or empowered to do so;
2. The contract was approved neither by parliament nor the governor general of Saint Lucia;
3. Royalty payments under the contract were to be made directly to a public official, not the Saint Lucia government itself;
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean integrity commissions form new Commonwealth body to fight corruption</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-integrity-commissions-form-new-Commonwealth-body-to-fight-corruption-26680.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean integrity commissions form new Commonwealth body to fight corruption
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
(L-R) Justice Dame Monica Joseph, Chairperson of the Integrity Commission of Grenada; Dr Keith Mitchell, Prime Minister of Grenada; Dame Cecile La Grenade, the Governor-General of Grenada; and Roger Koranteng, Governance and Anti-Corruption Adviser at the Commonwealth Secretariat
ST GEORGES, Grenada -- National authorities from 12 Commonwealth countries in the Caribbean have joined forces to establish a new regional body to enhance transparency and help fight corruption.
The Association of Integrity Commissions and Anti-Corruption Bodies in the Commonwealth Caribbean was formed at an international conference convened by the Commonwealth Secretariat in Grenada and hosted by the Integrity Commission of Grenada.
It was launched at the first Commonwealth regional conference for heads of integrity commissions and anti-corruption bodies in the Caribbean, taking place between 22-26 June 2015, and inaugurated by Dame Cecile La Grenade, the governor-general of Grenada, and Dr Keith Mitchell, the prime minister of Grenada.
The association, made up of the heads of national commissions, will help Caribbean countries to cooperate across borders, exchange best practices and develop regional anti-corruption initiatives.
Commonwealth Deputy Secretary-General Deodat Maharaj, welcoming its formation, expressed his hope that the new body will help to further strengthen public confidence in cross-border initiatives to enhance accountability.
Maharaj said: The formation of this new association represents a major step forward in regional efforts to support integrity and address corruption. We have high hopes for the future of this network of national agencies, which will deliver practical benefits to members as a forum for knowledge sharing and coordination. The intention is also to help countries learn and exchange with other Commonwealth countries and regions.
Justice Dame Monica Joseph, chairperson of the Integrity Commission of Grenada, said: The fact that we, in the Caribbean, will be forming ourselves into a regional association is recognition by us as a body that we consider it vital for the persons who serve us in public life, to function honestly, free of corruption and corrupt practices. We hope that, with that step, the peoples of the region would have confidence in the several commissions and anti-corruption bodies that form the association.
The establishment of the Caribbean body follows the similar formation, in 2011, of the Association of Anti-Corruption Agencies in Commonwealth Africa, spearheaded and supported by the Commonwealth Secretariat. The African association has helped improve the performance of national authorities through information exchanges, peer learning and by becoming a launch pad for bilateral agreements between countries.
The countries belonging to the new Association of Integrity Commissions and Anti-Corruption Bodies in the Commonwealth Caribbean are Antigua and Barbuda, The Bahamas, Barbados, Belize, Dominica, Grenada, Guyana, Jamaica, Saint Lucia, St Kitts and Nevis, St Vincent and the Grenadines, and Trinidad and Tobago.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean banks respond to EU tax haven blacklist</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-banks-respond-to-EU-tax-haven-blacklist-26681.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean banks respond to EU tax haven blacklist
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- The release of the Action Plan for Fair and Efficient Corporate Taxation in the EU by the European Commission on June 17, 2015, which included 15 Caribbean countries in a blacklist of non-cooperative jurisdictions, has caused the Caribbean Association of Banks (CAB) grave concern.
Notwithstanding that the European Union has now clarified that the final decision regarding which countries should be on the list has not been made, it is considered that the timing of this publication and its general perception as a new blacklist could have far-reaching effects on the Caribbeans financial services sector.
Indigenous banks in the region are currently being challenged with the threat of loss of correspondent banking relationships that are provided by international banks. An additional blacklist, based on unclear criteria, may serve to exacerbate the perception of the region as a high risk area and, consequently, negatively impact the risk rating profile of financial institutions by correspondent banks.
The financial services industry cannot survive without correspondent banking relationships and as a result, neither can regional economies.
The CAB said it was pleased to note the response of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) and the Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes which confirmed that the only agreeable assessment of countries as regards their cooperation is made by the Global Forum and that a number of countries identified in the EU exercise are either fully or largely compliant and have committed to AEOI (automatic exchange of information), sometimes even as early adopters.
It is noteworthy that the eight Caribbean Community (CARICOM) countries and five associated members that are named in the EUs report are all included in the OECDs list of members that have committed to automatic exchange of information.
The CAB therefore called upon the EU to carefully review the criteria used by its member states to assess and determine the countries that are non-compliant in tax matters. Additionally, the CAB strongly recommended greater collaboration between the EU, the OECD and the Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes before blacklist reports are issued.
The CAB also urged regional governments to act together to ensure that the region is represented in such key decision-making processes that can impact the growth and development of regional economies.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commonwealth secretary-general to visit Guyana</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commonwealth-secretary-general-to-visit-Guyana-26682.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commonwealth secretary-general to visit Guyana
Published onJune 26, 2015
GEORGETOWN, Guyana -- Commonwealth Secretary-General Kamalesh Sharma will arrive in Guyana on Saturday for a three-day visit, to gain a clear understanding of the regions concerns and priorities.
Commonwealth Secretary-General, Kamalesh Sharma
Sharma will call on recently elected President David Granger, and some of the members of his coalition government. He will also meet with the speaker of parliament and other key stakeholders in the country.
The visit will continue a series of high-level engagements in the Caribbean. Last week the secretary-general met with recently elected St Kitts and Nevis prime minister, Dr Timothy Harris, and attended the Commonwealth conference of education ministers in The Bahamas. From Guyana Sharma will travel to the CARICOM heads of government conference in Barbados.
The trip to the region and consultation with heads of government is part of the secretary-generals preparations for the next Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting (CHOGM), in Malta on 27-29 November 2015.
The aim is to meet with as many Commonwealth leaders in the Caribbean as possible to ensure their concerns and priorities are reflected in the CHOGM agenda, Sharma said.
The secretary-general will also address key issues affecting small states in the region, including ocean governance, climate change, education and youth empowerment, debt, trade, natural disaster management and access to development finance.
He said: In addition to our advocacy work to raise the Caribbeans concerns and needs on the global stage, the Commonwealth Secretariat is leading a number of cutting-edge initiatives that offer practical solutions to the challenges facing the Caribbean.
For example, our debt management software, which is used in 60 countries worldwide, manages a global portfolio of more than US$ 2.5 trillion of public debt, including approximately US$ 50 billion in the Caribbean.
Our Commonwealth 2013 debt restructuring exercise in Jamaica resulted in annual savings of approximately J$17 billion and a projected reduction of 8.8 per cent of debt-to-GDP by 2020.
The secretary-general will also discuss the ground-breaking Building the Resilience of Small States: A Strategic Vision for the Caribbean 2050 project.
The initiative examines the underlying reasons for slow economic growth in the region and its findings were dubbed a wake-up call for governments.
The project proposes a set of decisive actions, including empowering the youth with creative and interpersonal skills through revamped curriculums; reinvigorating the spirit of entrepreneurship; political reform; utilising local resources to achieve 100 per cent renewable energy; improving employment opportunities for young people in the private and public sectors and securing access to development of finance.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
