<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sugar fund millions paid to former St Kitts-Nevis ambassador, PM reveals</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Sugar-fund-millions-paid-to-former-St-Kitts-Nevis-ambassador%2C-PM-reveals-25915.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Sugar fund millions paid to former St Kitts-Nevis ambassador, PM reveals
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Caribbean News Now contributor
BASSETERRE, St Kitts -- At his monthly press conference on Tuesday, Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris revealed that millions of dollars were paid to former St Kitts and Nevis Ambassador to the UN, Delano Bart QC from the Sugar Industry Diversification Foundation (SIDF).
Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris
According to Harris, in response to a question, Bart was paid millions in legal fees for services allegedly provided to the SIDF, which some have described as a slush fund. Harris declared that Bart had been paid in excess of a whopping $3 million in legal fees from the SIDF. All this while functioning and operating as St Kitts-Nevis permanent representative to the United Nations.
The payments to Bart appear not to have been made with the oversight, direction or consent of the director of audit. Harris also questioned why Bart had to be retained and at such a high cost, when the Attorney General's Chambers is staffed with competent lawyers who are already on the government's payroll.
Harris outlined some of these disbursements to Bart as US$134,550; EC$1.79 million; EC$126,389.25; EC$2,201,635.80; EC$1.61 million; EC$ 351,000 and EC$ 315,900. Harris said that these payments were made between 2013 and 2014.
Harris also disclosed that the SIDF's records reveal that the Foundation received an income of $1.4 billion, but has spent monies totalling $1.26 billion.
Delano Bart QC
In addition to providing legal services to the SIDF, Delano Bart QC is also listed on the SIDFs website as a service provider authorised to represent applicants for citizenship by investment.
Harris said the government considers this concrete proof that the SIDF funds were abused by the former administration.
The prime minister said there had been a serious lack of accountability in relation to the funds of the Foundation.
The Foundation in a very real sense operated in the eyes of many as a slush fund, and an alternative government of the ex-regime, Harris said.
According to the prime minister, an estimated $200 million is currently available in the Foundation.
Against these cash resources now available, are commitments against that fund of EC$126 million in what has been described as one-off commitments, and it has ongoing commitments of approximately $75 million including commitments to sustain the PEP programme you see we not talking about many things left. That is the situation that we met, he explained.
Harris said the former government had ignored the advice of the IMF on how to appropriately use SIDF funding.
The government almost in an insane act of desperation figured that the money either shouldn't last, or the new government must not have any access to resources, and it went on a spending fantasy. And so for example in 2013, the government spent out of that fund $419.4 million, aggregate expenditure. The income for 2013 into the Foundation was 337.5 million. The government was prepared to bankrupt the fund if that trajectory continued, he noted.
Harris said available data reveals a pattern of abnormal expenditure by the former administration relative to the inflows into the Foundation.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barbados signs offshore exploration licences</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Barbados-signs-offshore-exploration-licences-25914.html</Link>
        <Description>BRIDGETOWN, Barbados (BGIS) -- Barbados on Wednesday took a step towards securing its energy future by signing two offshore exploration licences with the international oil company BHP Billiton. Prime Minister Freundel Stuart and vice president of exploration for BHP Billiton...</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Barbados signs offshore exploration licences
Published onMay 1, 2015
Prime Minister Freundel Stuart and Vice President of Exploration for BHP Billiton, Dr Niall McCormack signing the two offshore exploration licences on Wednesday morning. (A. Miller/BGIS)
By Sharon Austin
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados (BGIS) -- Barbados on Wednesday took a step towards securing its energy future by signing two offshore exploration licences with the international oil company BHP Billiton.
Prime Minister Freundel Stuart and vice president of exploration for BHP Billiton, Dr Niall McCormack, signed the documents during a brief ceremony at Government Headquarters.
The two blocks  Carlisle Bay and Bimshire  are approximately 40 kilometres southeast of the island, and total about 5,000 square kilometres.
They are located in waters ranging from approximately 1,200 to 2,000 metres in depth. And, Stuart said that every Barbadian was a stakeholder in the offshore petroleum programme.
He promised that government would ensure the benefits derived from offshore exploration and production activities were spread evenly across the economic and social spectra for present and future generations.
Signing these two exploration licences will send a clear message to the industry that Barbados is open for business and is serious about the development of its offshore petroleum sector.
"In addition, Barbadian nationals stand to reap early benefits on execution of the licences through the negotiated provisions for annual training, scholarships, local content, coastal and marine environment research and the acquisition of critical equipment and software, he said.
Stuart stressed that government had taken great care in formulating a robust regulatory regime and legislative framework that would ensure all offshore exploration and production activities were undertaken in accordance with the highest industry standards.
The prime minister stated: The government will expect no less than the highest commitment to the preservation and protection of our coastal and marine environment, as well as the communities in which BHP will operate.
He disclosed that the division of energy was working closely with local stakeholders to formulate a comprehensive long-term petroleum development strategy that would inform this islands future offshore petroleum policies.
Barbados had launched its first offshore licensing round in 2007 and the offshore territory was subdivided into 26 blocks, with 24 being made available for bidding. On conclusion of the process, BHP Billiton, headquartered in Australia, had emerged as the only successful bidder and was awarded the two blocks in 2008.
Stuart said that since then, government and BHP Billiton had engaged in intense, yet fruitful negotiations to finalise the exploration.
He stated: Today, Barbados offshore petroleum acreage remains largely underexplored with both local and international geological experts agreeing that all the necessary elements for a productive petroleum system are present in the offshore.
He noted that Woodbourne Oil Field was showing signs of steady decline, producing about 700 barrels of crude oil and 1.9 million cubic feet of natural gas per day.
He added that during the period 2003 to 2013, Barbados average annual fuel import bill stood at BDS$542.306 million, and in 2012, it reached a staggering peak of BDS$807.813 million, which equated to 9.6% of GDP.
Expending such significant amounts of capital on the importation of fossil fuels has impacted governments ability to allocate the desired level of financial resources across other areas of critical national importance such as education, health and social development.
It is in this context that the signing of the offshore exploration licences for the Carlisle Bay and Bimshire blocks becomes increasingly important to Barbados energy future and the development of its people, goods and services, he stressed.
The islands history of onshore oil and gas production dates back to the 1800s and BHP Billiton is optimistic about its chances of discovering hydrocarbons within the Carlisle Bay and Bimshire blocks.
McCormack explained that the exploration process would proceed in phases, with each building on the other and dependent on the previous phase.
We will begin to augment our understanding of this complex geology through a new 2D seismic survey programme of over 3,200 line kilometres. This survey will be conducted during the initial 3-year phase of the licence.
If the results of this initial survey are promising, BHP Billiton may then elect to proceed into the next exploration phase to acquire and process approximately 1,500 square kilometres of 3D seismic covering both blocks. Given further encouragement, the next step will be the drilling of at least one exploration well in each block, he said.
He pointed out that this incremental process was highly effective, and one that the industry had used successfully in oil and gas exploration and development around the world.
McCormack stressed that the benefits to communities where BHP Billiton worked went beyond revenue.
We are proud as a company that where BHP Billiton is successfully producing oil and gas, we work to ensure these benefits are shared between our shareholders, our partner nations and their people, he said.
He pointed out that BHP Billiton was considered one of the safest oil and gas companies in the industry, with a focus on environmental responsibility and the communities in which they work.
The breadth of our resources portfolio, our historical operational performance and our long-term approach to resource development distinguish us from most other companies in this industry. And, we feel this strategic partnership with BHP Billiton provides the Government of Barbados with a distinct advantage," he added.
The BHP Billiton energy portfolio includes oil, gas, coal and uranium, while the metal portfolio includes those used in energy infrastructure and renewables.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Royal visit to Curacao Museum leads to censorship controversy</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Royal-visit-to-Curacao-Museum-leads-to-censorship-controversy-25916.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Royal visit to Curacao Museum leads to censorship controversy
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
WILLEMSTAD, Curacao -- Princess Beatrix of the Netherlands on Saturday, May 2, will open the exhibition Guera na Krsou War in Curacao 1940-1945 at the Curacao Museum. However, one part of the exhibition, sponsored by the Foundation for Rehabilitation of War Victims Curacao (SEOC) has been rejected by the museum. According to chairman of SEOC, Nizaar Makdoembaks, censorship is covering up a painful event in Dutch history.
Princess Beatrix of the Netherlands
The SEOC wanted to include a list of names of 15 victims of war on a board and place this on the route for Princess Beatrix to see. The organization working group Guera na Krsou indicated to the SEOC many times that this has met internal resistance. They did not want to run the risk of the princess seeing these 15 names. This matter is still politically very sensitive in the Netherlands.
The Netherlands was guilty of war crimes in Curacao during World War II. That offence disappeared under the carpet. On April 20, 1942, Dutch authorities in Curacao stationed in Suffisant shot 15 employees of Chinese origin, who worked for Shell, dead and seriously injured 44 more. The dead were buried anonymously in the Kolebra Berde cemetery, among criminals and prostitutes. The news about it was concealed by censorship.
The family / relatives of these war victims have not yet been informed to date about this tragedy, said Makdoembaks.
Since 2003, the SEOC has been actively working to make the 15 murdered workers of Chinese descent recognized as war victims. The government of Curacao did this already in 2012 as a proclamation.
Minister Plasterk (Kingdom Relations) refuses to follow the example of Curacao. The Dutch government refuses to help the SEOC to inform the families of these victims of war over the fate of their loved ones. The visit of Princess Beatrix to the exhibition could bring possible change to that, Makdoembaks added.
Republished with permission of the Curacao Chronicle

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ECLAC praises Cuba for opening-up to foreign investment</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-ECLAC-praises-Cuba-for-opening-up-to-foreign-investment-25917.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
ECLAC praises Cuba for opening-up to foreign investment
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- The case of Cuba must be distinguished because it has opened up to foreign investment but selects important items for the country and protects national jobs, Alicia Barcena, executive secretary of the Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC) highlighted on Tuesday in Havana.
Alicia Barcena, executive secretary of the Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC)
The health of the economy in the West Indies and Central America is something that the country should take into account, because in that area competitors in terms of attracting foreign capital are located, she told ACN, while participating in the First International Seminar on Opportunities and Challenges for the development of Latin America and Cuba, held this week in Havana.
Although for 2015 Latin America's Gross Domestic Product as a whole should not increase by more than 1%, in the Caribbean area it could grow to 1.9%, Barcena said.
That situation should be used so that, rather than opponents, these nations become allies, she explained, because simultaneous investment may occur, where every economy contributes its best, especially in nautical tourism and maritime transport, which are lines that are likely to be exploited given the natural conditions of the region.
I think that the Special Development Zone of Mariel is an example of the use of competitive advantages in the process of foreign investment, because distance makes the export of Latin American products to other continents becomes more expensive, but the Cuban port could be used as stopover and platform for shipments, she predicted.
Parallel to the injection of foreign capital, I consider it to be an appropriate strategy to continue promoting the export of health services and cultural consultancy, she said.
Even in the future, when the country's infrastructure problems are resolved, Cuba could also export products related to information technology and communications, Barcena stressed, because it has the staff with the training and qualifications necessary to create them.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faster internet coming to Belize</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Faster-internet-coming-to-Belize-25918.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Faster internet coming to Belize
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Signing the agreement for the Belize Internet exchange point at University of Belize, Belize City on April 16 are, left to right, Internet service provider representatives Rafael Marin, Belize Telemedia Limited, Etienne Sharp, Alternative Networks, and Jose Urbina, Speednet (SMART) Communications. Standing at left is Kingsley Smith, Belize Public Utilities Commission
By Gerard Best
BELIZE CITY, Belize -- Sometimes the best solution to a technical problem is social engineering. After a journey of two years, thats exactly how Belize has come to a major milestone in its technological development.
The countrys Internet service providers (ISPs) have committed to set up Belizes first-ever Internet exchange point (IXP), a piece of critical Internet infrastructure through which they can exchange local Internet traffic between their networks. The process was as simple -- and as difficult -- as getting nine Internet service providers (ISPs), all fierce competitors, to agree to work together for the greater good.
Belize Telemedia, Speednet, BroadBand Belize, and Network Solutions signed the historic agreement on April 16 at the University of Belizes (UB) Belize City campus, clearing the way for the establishment of the regions latest IXP, called Belize IX or BIX.
As with all things important and meaningful, it was not an easy task to get to this point. However, the journey of the negotiating the pathway to this agreement for the Belize Internet exchange (BIX) was in indeed rewarding, said Michael Kong, owner and CEO at NetKing Solutions, who spoke at the signing on behalf of the ISPs.
Other signatures to the memorandum of understanding (MOU) include Centaur Communications Corporation, Alliance IP Belize and NetKing Solutions.
I speak on behalf of all providers when I say that determined team effort and collaboration for the greater good made this historic day a reality. We can all be happy and proud to know we are part of a milestone that will go down in ICT history in Belize, Kong said.
The agreement marks a significant moment for Belize. It is the first time that the country's ISPs put aside their differences to work together to address a challenge that affects them all -- bandwidth.
The upcoming launch of BIX will put an end to a costly and inefficient situation whereby data and access to other critical local services has to be routed internationally just to get back to a local customer, who could be only a few feet away from the person who sent it. In other words, we were using expensive international Internet connections to exchange domestic traffic, said Bevil Wooding, Internet strategist with international non-profit Packet Clearing House, speaking in an interview following the signing.
Packet Clearing House, a non-profit organisation, plays a key role in implementing IXPs around the world. In the Caribbean, Wooding and his team have worked closely with the Caribbean Telecommunications Union, regulators and local ISPs to set up IXPs across the region.
Faster Net
Traditionally, local internet traffic would need to leave Belize to an ISP in the United States and then get rerouted back to Belize. Once BIX is set up, that local traffic will no longer have to leave the country. That means better speeds for local Internet users.
Establishing a local IXP brings benefits not only to local consumers but also to the ISPs bottom line, Wooding explained.
A local IXP improves the quality and cost effectiveness of delivering local Internet-enabled services to citizens and businesses. Thats a major benefit for local ISPs. The IXP also enables new forms of local innovation and entrepreneurship, as Internet users benefit from greater opportunities for e-commerce and local content development, including online education, he noted.
Alan Slusher, president of the University of Belize, said the university is looking forward to greatly expanding its capacity to deliver training across the length and breadth of the country and directly into the homes and workplaces of our work people. Thus greatly reducing the costs of education while expanding its availability. We are looking for a great leap forward as a result of this corporation.
The soon-to-be established IXP will not only address the inefficiency of local Internet traffic exchange. It will also allow other important Internet infrastructure to be located in Belize, such as domain name root services and content delivery caches from major content networks like Google, Netflix and Yahoo.
Roosevelt Blades, chair of the ISP working group, is already looking ahead. He announced at the signing there are plans to have a similar facility built in Belmopan, once the Belize City IX is up and running.
Technical discussions about how to set up the IXP started two years ago, with a working group that included ISPs, the Belize Public Utilities Commission, government ministries, Packet Clearing House with support from other regional stakeholders, including the Caribbean Telecommunications Union, and the Caribbean Network Operators Group (CaribNOG).
Speaking at an October 2013 CaribNOG event at which the plans to establish BIX were announced, Kingsley Smith, then director of telecommunications at the Belize Public Utilities Commission said, This development is expected to provide significant benefits to local ISPs and the Internet users in Belize.
With the signing finally becoming a reality, Belizean Internet users are one step closer to a faster, stronger and more secure Internet.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jamaica to expand trade with Cuba and Costa Rica</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Jamaica-to-expand-trade-with-Cuba-and-Costa-Rica-25919.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Jamaica to expand trade with Cuba and Costa Rica
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Industry, Investment, and Commerce Minister, Anthony Hylton (left), listens to a point being made by Jamaica Promotions Corporations (JAMPRO) Chairman, Milton Samuda (2nd right), during Wednesdays media briefing in New Kingston, to provide details of two recent trade missions to Cuba and Costa Rica. Also sharing in the discussions are: Jamaica Exporters Association (JEA) President, Marjory Kennedy (2nd left); and JAMPRO President, Diane Edwards. Photo: Donald Delahaye
By Douglas McIntosh
KINGSTON, Jamaica -- The government of Jamaica is moving to strengthen and deepen trade relations with Cuba and Costa Rica.
The move follows the successful outcomes of trade missions to the countries earlier this month, which were led by industry, investment, and commerce minister, Anthony Hylton.
The minister outlined details of the trips during a media briefing at JAMPROs corporate office in New Kingston, on Wednesday.
Hylton, who led a 18-member public-private sector group to Cuba, from April 19 to 23, said the island stands ready to cooperate fully in developing bilateral trade with its Caribbean neighbours, particularly Jamaica.
To this end, he said Jamaica and Cuba have agreed to establish working groups on both sides comprising inter-ministerial and private sector representatives, to begin preparatory work in the areas of trade, investment, and transport.
The minister said he has invited Cubas trade and investment minister, Rodrigo Malmierca to visit Jamaica in September for further discussions.
The thinking is that Minister Malmiercas visit will launch the working group discussions for the strategic partnership, in September, he noted.
Additionally, the minister said a framework agreement is being targeted for signing between Jamaicas Special Economic Zone (SEZ), and Cubas Mariel Special Economic Development Zone (ZEDM), which both come into play later this year.
He pointed out that the Cuban government has established the ZEDM, which has the port of Mariel as the nucleus. This, he informed, is supported by two cargo airports, and the Jos Marti International Airport.
As Jamaica continues work towards the development of our own Special Economic Zone regime, we are well placed to take advantage of the opportunities for inter-SEZ trade, the minister contended.
Hylton said revision and upgrading of existing maritime and aviation agreements between Jamaica and Cuba will also be considered, pointing out that the opportunities facing us today warrants us to (revisit) those critical agreements.
The minister said other opportunities for cooperation in areas such as tourism, trade, finance, and manufacturing, will also be explored.
Hylton said the discussions yielded key outcomes relating to Jamaica forging a strategic partnership with the Cuban government and its economic entities.
Notable among these were: proposed establishment of a joint Jamaica-Cuba Business Council to foster and facilitate the development of economic relations between the countries; the need identified to increase the performance and utilization rate of the existing line of credit through the Export/Import (EXIM) Bank of Jamaica, in collaboration with Banco Nacional de Cuba; and the Cuban governments expressed support for Jamaicas Logistics Hub Initiative, and the medium to long-term benefits anticipated for both countries.
In this regard, Hylton concluded that: what is clear is that Cuba sees the value of working collaboratively with its closest neighbour.
In relation to Costa Rica, where Hylton led a five-member delegation from April 12 to 16, he said a memorandum of understanding (MoU) was signed, with the countrys foreign trade minister, Alexander Mora, to supplement the free trade agreement between the Central American nation and the Caribbean Community (CARICOM).
The MoU symbolizes the partnership between Jamaica and Costa Rica. It will enhance existing ties and provide an opportunity for more cooperation in trade administration as well as exchange of valuable trading information, he stated.
The minister advised that Costa Rica, like Cuba, is anticipating Jamaicas fulfilment of its goal of becoming the fourth node in global logistics. As such, he said, the country is focussed on expanding Port Limon which, he pointed out, is well positioned to become a spoke that routes cargo into Jamaica, and from Jamaica into Central America.
Additionally, Hylton said further opportunities exist for both countries to collaborate on investments as well as tourism and culture.
In this regard, the minister said the administration anticipates re-activation of the Jamaica-Costa Rica Joint Commission, as the appropriate vehicle to advance bilateral cooperation between the two countries.
The government of Jamaica, through the ministry of industry, investment, and commerce, will continue to engage with the Cuban and Costa Rican governments to ensure that the commercial and bi-lateral relations are strengthened and maximized for the growth if the Jamaican economy, Hylton stated.
Wednesdays briefing was also attended by JAMPROs president, Diane Edwards, who provided an overview of the Cuba engagements.
Also attending were the presidents of the Jamaica Chamber of Commerce (JCC), Warren McDonald, and Jamaica Exporters Association (JEA), Marjory Kennedy, who accompanied Hylton to Cuba, and who provided positive feedback from their perspectives, on the outcomes of the visit, and prospects for trade between both countries.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A new tourism era begins in the BVI</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-A-new-tourism-era-begins-in-the-BVI-25920.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
A new tourism era begins in the BVI
Published onMay 1, 2015
The opening of the new cruise pier ended with a ceremonial anchor drop by government officials
By Nekita Turnbull
ROAD TOWN, BVI -- A new beginning for the tourism industry in the British Virgin Islands was declared on Wednesday, as the newly expanded cruise pier was officially opened.
On Wednesday morning at 7:30 am, the Norwegian Getaway made its inaugural call to the Port of Road Town; on time for the opening ceremony.
Premier and minister of finance, Dr Orlando Smith, minister for communications and works, Mark Vanterpool and other dignitaries were on the dock to welcome the Norwegian Getaway cruise ship to the port, as well as award a couple with a dream vacation package.
This gesture symbolised a new beginning for the territory in opening its shores to more tourists and developing stronger international relationships.
Governor John Duncan expressed his congratulations to the BVI government and its vision in making the pier a reality. He added that British Virgin Islanders should be proud and that the pier profiles the territorys high quality culture.
Duncan said, As a gateway to our territory, (the cruise pier) will play an important role in maintaining tourism as a key pillar in the Virgin Islands economy. A shop window to Natures Little Secrets, where the type and quality of customer services offered are not only friendly and welcoming but amongst the best in the region.
Smith in remarks said that the government is strengthening the BVIs tourism product and providing training to accommodate the growing sector.
We are improving our customer service experience by training our frontline Customs and Immigration staff, as well as our taxi operators. We have partnered to strengthen the core of the BVIs tourism product and its reputation by ensuring that our people are ready to respond to the rapid growth of commerce, and deliver excellent customer service at all levels, Smith said.
The cruise pier expansion and landside development project is placed under the portfolio of the ministry of communications and works, and the minister, Vanterpool stated that his goal is to develop the territory to help secure a brighter future for all.
Vanterpool said, We have worked extremely hard to ensure that the infrastructure of the Virgin Islands is maintained and improved according to international standards.
He added, With that will come the necessary amenities and facilities, to ensure that our cruise ship passengers are properly welcomed and entertained here, hence the landside development.
Leader of the opposition, Ralph ONeal was also present to give his remarks for the historic occasion. ONeal provided a brief history lesson on the Road Harbour and what it means for the territory today.
He said, What we see here today is a continuation of what started many years ago and from what I have been reading about the other islands, we have to catch up, otherwise we will find ourselves lagging. So I am very glad to see what has been done here today and a time will come when we have to do more because tourism is growing.
The opening ceremony ended with an anchor drop by government officials and a plaque presentation to the captain of the Norwegian Getaway.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Diversifying the EU-CARIFORUM trade dynamic</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Diversifying-the-EU-CARIFORUM-trade-dynamic-25921.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Diversifying the EU-CARIFORUM trade dynamic
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
MONTEGO BAY, Jamaica -- The recently concluded third CARIFORUM-EU Business Forum in Jamaica succeeded in strengthening Caribbean-EU trade relations. Over a two-day period, well over 100 representatives and entrepreneurs took part in focused meetings to discuss the potential of Caribbean foods, the regions pulsating musical creative products and its growing higher education sector.
The gathering was the third in a series dedicated to discovering the possibilities offered by the Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) between the European Union and the CARIFORUM-states and presenting a unique platform to facilitate dialogue between entrepreneurs and investors from the Caribbean and Europe.
The rich interchange in the business sessions underscored the high quality and availability of raw material inputs and services in the region, but also the need for a greater number of trade modalities and for training in sustainable practices.
European businessman Eldar Astthorsson welcomed the opportunity to do business in the Caribbean.
Im grateful for the opportunity and to learn more about the creative industries in the Caribbean and the prospects the sector has to offer. I can see business opportunities arise from this, and Im already connecting people from my sector with individual talent and companies in the CARIFORUM area, noted Astthorsson, who is the senior PR manager-Europe of CCP Games in Iceland.
One of the topics discussed was the cocoa industry, and a significant number of European chocolatiers crossed the Atlantic to make a new foray into the Caribbeans high-flavour cocoa market. The conversations revolved around how to brand and build a viable cocoa product that can fetch premium prices in international markets. In response, designates from the Dominican Republic, Jamaica, Trinidad and Tobago, and Suriname explained how their countries have actively been rebuilding their cocoa production to develop high-quality chocolate to meet growing demand in Europe.
Bejamin Figarede, representative of the French chocolaterie Valrhona, agreed that the EU-CARIFORUM Business Forum was a unique exchange platform.
The diverse and detailed business examples given by all the speakers should stimulate the export offer within the Caribbean and strengthen trade opportunities, said Figarede.
From the Caribbean, Norman Wright, a research chemist turned tea entrepreneur for the TOPs brand, is excited to show off his packaged product and to allow curious noses to sample whiffs of his range of peppermint teas.
I would never make this opportunity pass me by. My teas are on supermarket shelves in the USA, Canada, the UK and across the Caribbean. I am here to break into Continental Europe, Wright explained.
We cant compete on volume, so we are going to have to compete on price, on quality, and on niche marketing, noted Pamela Coke Hamilton, the executive director of Caribbean Export Development Agency (CEDA), which together with the ACP Business Climate Facility (BizClim) organised the conference.
The ultimate purpose, said Jesus Ors Bguena, head of cooperation in the Delegation of the EU to Jamaica, Belize, The Bahamas, Turks and Caicos Islands, and Cayman Islands, is to ensure that trade is not only freer but fairer!

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cuba has the oldest population in Latin America</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cuba-has-the-oldest-population-in-Latin-America-25922.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cuba has the oldest population in Latin America
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
HAVANA, Cuba (ACN) -- In Cuba there are more than two million people over 60 years of age, 19 percent of the total population, and is the Latin American country with the oldest population, announced an expert in Havana on Tuesday.
Doctor Alberto Fernandez, head of the National Group for the Care of the Elderly, of the ministry of public health (MINSAP) told ACN in an exclusive interview that the rapid population aging is largely due to the low birth rate, the increase of life expectancy and social development.
Cuba has indicators of the first world and the only population that is increasing hereinafter are senior citizens, said Fernandez, who participates in the 13th International Seminar on Longevity that wound up on Thursday at Havana's Convention Center, attended by 300 delegates from various nations.
Since 2010, people arriving to the sixth decade intersect which those who are 15, and hence hereinafter only the first group only increases and those who are 15 years of age decreases, emphasized Fernandez.
Guideline 144 of the Economic and Social Policy of the Party and the Revolution reads: "to give special attention to the study and implementation of strategies in all sectors of society to address the high levels of population aging.
Among the actions in this regard, the ministry of public health is working to strengthen the primary health care, for which it gives training for family doctors and nurses and graduates in geriatrics and gerontology, and courses for care at the end of life, in a way that health professionals are provided with the necessary tools to address this age bracket, Fernandez said.
It also includes the strengthening of grandparents homes and old people's homes on the island, for which there is a rehabilitation program backed by a budget that in 2014 amounted to 66 million pesos allocated for this purpose by the ministry of finance and prices.
Today, thanks to the development of education, 57 percent of the people that are between 60 and 74 years of age are medium level of university graduates, and in old age they also have the opportunity to continue studying at the university departments for the elderly, from which, in their fifteen years of existence, more than 15,000 people have benefited, Fernandez highlighted.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman's work: Birthing Caribbean entrepreneurs</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Woman%27s-work%3A-Birthing-Caribbean-entrepreneurs-25923.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Woman's work: Birthing Caribbean entrepreneurs
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Fifteen Caribbean woman entrepreneurs taking part in the first-ever facilitators training for the Women's Innovation Network of the Caribbean (WINC) program, a World Bank project funded via the Canada Development Bank and coordinated by the Enterprise Hub, take a photo call on April 21. Front row, left to right, are Nerissa Golden (Montserrat), Simmone Bowe (The Bahamas), Donna Every (Barbados), Barbara Innocent-Charles (St Lucia), Cecile Watson (Jamaica), Jenni Headlam (Jamaica), Sandra Baptist (Antigua and Barbuda), Glenda Joseph-Dennis (Trinidad and Tobago), Aine Brathwaite (Grenada). Back row, left to right, are Telojo Onu (St Kitts and Nevis), Reina Kolf (Suriname), Danalyn Myvette (Belize), Virginia Riviere (Dominica), Georgina Terry (T&amp;T), Valrie Grant (Guyana), and Ashley Mitchell (Head of The Enterprise Hub, T&amp;T). Photo: Gerard Best
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- You really dont know what to expect when you put a dozen-plus Caribbean entrepreneurs in one room for a week.
But one thing was clear when 15 entrepreneurs -- all women -- came together in Port of Spain, Trinidad, in April. It was the start of something good.
The ladies gathered to share experiences and build strategies for future collaboration. Besides their Caribbean heritage and passion for productivity, these go-getters had something else in common. Each had been competitively selected to take part in the first-ever facilitators training for the Women's Innovation Network of the Caribbean (WINC) program. The initiative is a World Bank project to support woman entrepreneurs in the region. It is funded via the Canada Development Bank.
The one-week workshop focused on teaching participants how to run courses targeted at other goal-oriented women in their home territory. Up to 10 of the 15 would receive funding to run the course for one year. For Nerissa Golden, though, the big win wasnt in the funding but the friendships.
This has been an incredible opportunity to connect with other women who share this same passion for entrepreneurship and empowering others to launch and grow a business, she said.
Goldenmedia, the company that she started 12 years ago in Montserrat, is a small business rooted primarily in the cultural and technology industries, and specialising in publicity and multimedia content creation for brands and entrepreneurs.
The other ladies and I decided even before arriving in Port of Spain that the greater gift was in having this new connection and awareness that we weren't alone in our desire to serve our communities with business growth programmes. Were already exploring ways that we can work together to help each other achieve our business goals long after the project funding runs out. Each woman is a professional in various disciplines and so the opportunity to learn from them has been quite a gift. We've all been strengthened by being able to connect and find common ground on which we want to build future collaborations, Golden explained.
Breeding enterprise
WINC is part of the Entrepreneurship Program for Innovation in the Caribbean (EPIC), which is being implemented by infoDev, a global multidonor program in the Trade and Competitiveness Global Practice of the World Bank Group, with support from Canada's Foreign Affairs, Trade and Development (DFATD).
The program is being implemented across the region by Enterprise Hub a Trinidad and Tobago-based company specialising in providing support services to a wide range of start-ups and established entrepreneurs. Enterprise Hub founder and lead consultant Ashley Mitchell, himself an entrepreneur, said that "intermediary agencies," such as the World Bank's infoDev, can be a significant source of financial support for budding businesses.
Beyond simply acting as a bridge to start-up financing, Enterprise Hub works alongside the business owners to open their eyes to fresh opportunity, enhance their ability for innovation and increase their tolerance for risk-taking. Encouraging people to take initiative and challenge received wisdom -- even within the constraints of a full-time job -- is crucial to unlocking the region's entrepreneurial potential, Mitchell said.
"Our young people have been conditioned and sheperded over time to simply get on a track of academic pursuit. There's nothing wrong with that but it's not for everyone. Some of our Caribbean people are very willing to take entrepreneurial risks but that ability is not being harnessed in a constructive way by our formal education systems, he added.
Entrepreneurship, said Mitchell, is a mindset. And you can act entrepreneurially even without ever leaving your job, he said.
Nor should local entrepreneurship depend on foreign agencies or even national governments, Golden underscored.
Entrepreneurship is still one of the sexy topics for governments and international donor agencies. However, we have to see it not as a hot topic but essential to how every nation is going to grow its economy, she said.
More cohesion is needed in how programs are implemented across the Caribbean, as many have the similar goals but resources are not used efficiently, she said.
I would like to see more entrepreneurs being given the capacity to unleash their ideas by having the financial support they need, the theoretical knowledge and the access to markets. Bottom line is entrepreneurship challenges won't be solved by governments, only entrepreneurs can do that, Golden said.
A life's work
Golden participated in the Grow Your Business boot camp, another WINC project, in 2013 and 2014, and before that had been working with entrepreneurs for more than 10 years, through Goldenmedia.
My vision is to create opportunities for the Caribbean to grow and an important way to do this is through the media. Most of what will generate revenue and transform our nations are the ideas inside of us waiting to be unleashed. I like being a part of providing the platforms as well as guiding how these messages can connect with the people ready to hear it, she continued.
She said she saw WINC as a way to continue with her lifes work.
Much of the work I do is centered on job creation and empowerment, so this is an extension of that. I began hosting my own entrepreneurship conferences in 2006 simply because I realised other people had the same need as I did to learn about starting a business, she said.
The latest WINC initiative, coordinated by the Enterprise Hub, covered eight subject areas including marketing, technology, networking and financial management, giving Golden and others rich resource from which to draw for future growth.
I am looking forward to first implementing the new ideas I learned or were reinforced this week to help my company continue along a growth path, then it will be extended out to Montserrat and neighbouring islands, she said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vessel with 149 pounds of cocaine intercepted near Puerto Rico</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Vessel-with-149-pounds-of-cocaine-intercepted-near-Puerto-Rico-25924.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Vessel with 149 pounds of cocaine intercepted near Puerto Rico
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
AGUADILLA, Puerto Rico -- US Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Office of Air and Marine agents, and Puerto Rico Police Department Joint Forces of Rapid Action (FURA, for its Spanish acronym) officers seized 149 pounds (67.6 kilos) of cocaine after intercepting a wooden vessel, with one man on board, near the island of Desecheo in the west coast. The seized cocaine shipment was estimated to have a street value of approximately $1.9 million dollars.
Sixty bricks were found inside the vessel fenders
Bartolome Barber-Bracero, 43, was arrested and charged in a criminal complaint authorized by US Magistrate Judge Sylvia Carreo Coll with possession with intent to distribute cocaine.
Our collective effort and resolve is key to secure the Caribbean borders from attempts to smuggle narcotics into the region, stated Johnny Morales, director of air operations at the CBP Caribbean Air and Marine Branch.
A CBP UH-60M Blackhawk helicopter conducting a patrol along the Mona Passage detected a vessel, navigating east, approximately ten nautical miles west of Desecheo Island.
The vessel was described as a yola type, single engine, 20 feet in length, single outboard engine with one person on board and the name "FOX" labeled on each side.
The CBP helicopter requested the assistance of a Puerto Rico Police Department FURA marine unit nearby to conduct a boarding.
The vessel was escorted to the Mayaguez pier for inspection by CBP agents and PRPD officers, who discovered a total of 60 bricks hidden within three vessel fenders, which later testing positive to cocaine.
Barber-Bracero and the contraband were transferred to the custody of US Immigrations and Customs Enforcement (ICE) Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) Special Agents for further investigation.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New report unveils far-reaching policy agenda to transform economies and gender equality</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-New-report-unveils-far-reaching-policy-agenda-to-transform-economies-and-gender-equality-25925.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
New report unveils far-reaching policy agenda to transform economies and gender equality
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- UN Women has launched its flagship report Progress of the Worlds Women 2015-2016: Transforming Economies, Realizing Rights, which highlights how economies have failed to guarantee women's empowerment and the full exercise of their economic and social rights, in rich countries and poor countries.
At the same time, however, it demonstrates that the transformation of economies to ensure that women's rights become a reality is possible by constructing economic and human rights policies that promote far-reaching changes.
Progress sets out a vision of a global economy fit for women, where they have equal access to productive resources and social protection, which provides them with sufficient income to support an adequate standard of living. In such an economy, the work that women do would be respected and valued; stereotypes about what women and men can and should do would be eliminated; and women would be able to work and live their lives free from violence and sexual harassment.
However, the data and analysis presented show that this vision is still far from reality. Globally, only half of all women in the world are part of the labour force, compared to three-quarters of all men. The participation of women in the Latin America and the Caribbean labour market experienced the largest increase compared to all global regions  from 40 to 54 percent between 1990 and 2013; but it is still far below the participation of men (80%).
The UN Women report also highlights the persistent gaps in the salaries of men and women: worldwide, women earn on average 24 percent less than men; in Latin America and the Caribbean this figure is 19 percent.
Additionally, in the region, 59 percent of womens jobs are located in the informal sector without labour legislation and social protection. Paid domestic work, which is usually informal and not protected by labour laws, accounts for 17 out of every 100 economically active Latin American and Caribbean women. While Guyana is the only Caribbean country to have ratified the ILO Convention 189 on Decent Work, the UN Women report also notes that Trinidad and Tobago and Chile are among the countries that have recently extended national minimum wages to domestic workers who are often informally employed.
Women still carry the burden of unpaid care work in the home. In those countries in the region with time use surveys, it is evident that women perform two to five times more unpaid domestic and care work than men, which limits their educational and employment opportunities, and leaves them less time for rest, leisure or political participation.
While there is evidence according to a recent ILO report of Caribbean women in seven countries holding above 40% of management positions, it is noted that these positions are largely concentrated in areas such as human resources, communications and administration. The UN Women Progress report probes womens economic progress encouraging countries to better understand the challenges and opportunities that women face in attainting their full economic potential.
One significant challenge in the Caribbean is lack of data on these issues. UN Women MCO Caribbean is working to support countries to address their data gaps on gender disparities to more efficiently measure progress on womens economic empowerment and programme effectively to build on womens economic potential.
Our public resources are not flowing in the directions where they are most needed: for example, to provide safe water and sanitation, quality health care, and decent child- and elderly-care services. Where there are no public services, the deficit is borne by women and girls, said UN Women executive director Phumzile Mlambo-Ngcuka.
This is a care penalty that unfairly punishes women for stepping in when the state does not provide resources and it affects billions of women the world over. We need policies that make it possible for both women and men to care for their loved ones without having to forego their own economic security and independence, she added.
Through case studies and concrete examples of change, the report introduces 10 key recommendations to move towards an economy that ensures women's empowerment and the exercise of their rights and that is also beneficial for society as a whole and for the sustainable development of each country.
In the report, UN Women points out that an economy designed with womens needs in mind would give them an equal voice in economic decision-making: from the way in which time and money are spent in their households, to the ways in which resources are raised and allocated at the national level, to how broader economic parameters are set by global institutions.
If the economy worked for women, their life choices would not be constrained by gender stereotypes, stigma and violence; women could carry out their work without fear of sexual harassment or violence; and the paid and unpaid work that they do would be respected and valued, said Luiza Carvalho, regional director of UN Women for the Americas and the Caribbean.
We urgently needed a transformative agenda that allows greater equality and redistribution to build economies that work for women and men equally. Our region is moving forward, but we need to accelerate the pace towards substantive equality.
Macroeconomic policies can and should support the realization of womens rights, by creating dynamic and stable economies, generating decent work and mobilizing sufficient resources to fund vital public services, continued Carvalho.Governments must move beyond old metrics of growth such as GDP and low inflation, and instead, they need to quantify the growth in terms of compliance with human rights.
To access the executive summary as well as the complete report, visit: http://caribbean.unwomen.org

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alaska Airlines adds new flights from Los Angeles to Costa Rica</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Alaska-Airlines-adds-new-flights-from-Los-Angeles-to-Costa-Rica-25926.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Alaska Airlines adds new flights from Los Angeles to Costa Rica
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Alaska Airlines will start new Costa Rica flights October 31
SEATTLE, USA -- Alaska Airlines will chart new territory this fall when it adds new service between Los Angeles and Costa Rica's two major international airports, further strengthening its southern California focus city. The eight weekly flights from Los Angeles to San Jose (SJO) and Liberia/Guanacaste (LIR), Costa Rica, are scheduled to begin October 31 and November 1 respectively.
Liberia is the gateway to the Guanacaste region in the western part of the country, renowned for surfing and sport fishing. While the capital city of San Jose, located about 130 miles from Liberia, boasts museums and historic Spanish colonial architecture.
"As the most popular Central American tourist destination for US travelers, Costa Rica is a Mecca for eco-tourism, surfing and sport fishing and has been a top request from our customers who enjoy outdoor adventure," said John Kirby, Alaska Airlines' vice president of capacity planning. "Our new Costa Rica flights are well timed for Los Angeles travelers and offer convenient roundtrip connections for our Anchorage and Seattle customers, while our new Baltimore service provides passengers greater access to the nation's capital, complementing our daily nonstop service to Reagan National Airport."
Flights will be available for purchase for the new Costa Rica routes starting May 21, pending approval by Costa Rican civil aviation authorities.
The new flights will be operated with fuel-efficient, next generation Boeing 737 aircraft.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Baltimore apes worst of Ferguson</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Baltimore-apes-worst-of-Ferguson-25927.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Baltimore apes worst of Ferguson
Published onMay 1, 2015
By Anthony L Hall

Violence and looting overtook much of West Baltimore on Monday, seriously injuring several police officers and leaving a store and several vehicles in flames.
At least seven police officers were injured in a clash that began near Mondawmin Mall and spread toward downtown
Demonstrators pelted officers with rocks, bricks and bottles and assaulted a photojournalist
(The Baltimore Sun, April 27, 2015)
Anthony L. Hall is a Bahamian who descends from the Turks and Caicos Islands. He is an international lawyer and political consultant - headquartered in Washington DC - who also publishes a current events weblog, The iPINIONS Journal, at http://ipjn.com
The above describes the still-unfolding fallout from the killing of Freddie Gray, a black man who died last week, after having his spine nearly severed, while in police custody in Baltimore, Maryland.
But Ive written too many instructive commentaries on the fallout from the killing of Michael Brown in Ferguson, Missouri, to count. Therefore, I fear writing another on this latest outbreak of misguided violence would be tantamount to beating the proverbial dead horse.
No case of police brutality justifies looting and vandalism. Period. Not least because the anger and frustration among blacks today pale in comparison to that which simmered among blacks during the Civil Rights Movement. Yet the only barbarism on display during their protests came not from black marchers looting and vandalizing stores, when they werent taunting the police, but from white cops willfully attacking them as they marched peacefully and non-violently.
Is there any wonder that people (black and white) have as much contempt for these marauding black protesters today as they had for those mauling white cops back then?
(Killing of Michael Brown: as much about Resisting Arrest as about Police Brutality, The iPINIONS Journal, August 12, 2014)
Not to mention that, far from having anything to do with outrage over police brutality, the violence in this case was orchestrated  through social-media clarion calls  to act out scenes from The Purge, a movie about what happens when people are given free rein to commit any crime without fear of arrest.
But imagine the mentality of knuckleheads using the menace of police brutality as a pretext to menace their own neighborhoods  by, among other things, looting and torching pharmacies and other businesses.
Worse still, imagine the state of anarchy when you have a mayor responding to their wanton destruction as follows:
We gave those who wish to destroy space to do so.
(WJZ Baltimore, April 27, 2015)
This, believe it or not, is how Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake responded. Hell, one could be forgiven the suspicion that it was she who initiated that clarion call to purge. Talk about the insane running the asylum. Nothing indicates how surreal/absurd things have become in this respect quite like black leaders propagating the fiction that its racist to refer to the thugs who looted stores and assaulted the police as  thugs.
I fear that the lesson most young black men are learning from this tragedy is that they can resist arrest -- so long as they shout the newfangled slogan, hands up, dont shoot while doing so. Clearly, this will only lead to more of them ending up like Michael
Instead of doublespeak that would make him a saint, those eulogizing Michael would honor his death far more by admonishing young black men against the deadly hazards of resisting arrest and defying authority  merely as a misguided badge of honor or rite of passage.
(Why Chastise the Times for Describing Michael Brown as No Angel? The iPINIONS Journal, August 26, 2014)
But am I the only one who wonders how the parents of these wilding kids are going to feel when it dawns on them that their prescriptions  for hypertension and other stress-related maladies  went up in flames with that CVS Pharmacy? I cannot lament too often this self-immolating feature of the violence and looting these so-called civil rights protesters are perpetrating.
In any event, God help Baltimore: save it from its lawless youth  and clueless mayor.
Related commentaries:
* This commentary was originally published at The iPINIONS Journal on Monday, April 27.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Misfeasance and malfeasance</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Misfeasance-and-malfeasance-25928.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By G. A. Dwyer Astaphan
The last week or so has been filled with revelations from the new Team Unity administration.
Dwyer Astaphan is a lawyer and former St Kitts-Nevis minister of national security and tourism
First, Attorney General Vincent Byron shared some juicy (pun intended) information on the squandermania of the now dismantled Department of Constituency Empowerment.
He told us about $250,000 spent to build a fence and $200,000 spent to paint a wall, $18,000 to build a hard court in Keys Village (where there has been a hard court for many, many years), $143,000 for a space adoption project in Hermitage, Cayon, but there seems to be no sight or sign of it at that Hermitage, or at Hermitage Road, Old Road, or at any place named Hermitage anywhere on planet Earth, etc.
One million dollars spent in January 2015 alone on these things! Remember, elections were in February.
Weve also heard of the Government Assistance Program (GAP), purportedly designed for people at and below the poverty line, although people earning $2,000, $3,000, $4,000, and more, monthly were the happy recipients of vouchers from the government, using taxpayers money, to pay for fridges, stoves, furniture and other goodies, leading up to the election.
I know one office worker who was, and is, close to a particular candidate who got her voucher for $2,900 and bought herself a nice appliance with it.
And weve begun hearing of stories of PEP.
One of the many things that have to be explained to the public is how and why certain employers were able to put their regular, permanent workers of long standing on the PEP program. A business owned by my family had its three workers, ranging in experience on the job from ten to thirty years, put on the program and their wages paid by PEP.
How can that be right? Who could have allowed or countenanced this?
What could be more wrong than taxpayers being asked to subsidize businesses by paying those businesses wage and salary bills?
Im not talking about apprentices, engaged in a specified, short-term basis. No, Im talking about full-time seasoned workers.
This is not an assault on the workers. They are by no means to be blamed for this.
But subsidizing good and successful businesses in this manner, that is to say, paying the wages and salaries of their permanent employees, is nothing short of an abomination. It is a misuse and abuse of public funds.
And subsidizing bad businesses in this open-ended way is a disincentive to those businesses improving, and is also a sinful waste and abuse of public money. Its like pouring water into a bucket that has no bottom.
Then in his press conference on April 28, Prime Minister Harris told us about the Sugar Industry Diversification Foundation (SIDF), among other things.
He said it earned $1.47 billion between 2007 and 2014, and during that time it spent $1.26 billion.
In a different world, this would mean that the SIDF should have a surplus, even after all of the squandermania, of $200 million. But as the PM said, pretty much all of that $200 million is committed to payment obligations.
So, in effect, Douglas has dried out the SIDF. And while drying it out, he put the economic citizenship program at risk with all of these undesirables who got passports and diplomatic passports, bringing the country to the point where the US issued an advisory and Canada ended the visa-free entry for our citizens. (When was the last time you checked to see how easy it is to get a Canadian visa?)
Meanwhile, can you tell me what we have to show for the spending of $1.26 billion of SIDF money? Could some of that money have been used to properly develop the jobless among us, and graduate them to a more sustainable and independent existence? Could he have fixed the Basseterre High School and all of our other schools and government facilities that need to be fixed? Could he have made our hospitals more modern and efficient? Could more lives have been saved? Could he have given public servants a better deal? Could he have reduced the VAT and removed it from food, medicine and funerals as Team Unity just did? Could he have simply exempted those things from VAT from the very beginning? Could he have reduced the high rents that government has been paying? Could more people have gotten their own homes?
Was spending in the best and sustainable interests of the people his number one priority, or was he more concerned with travelling the world and having people run up cell phone bills of up to $30,000 a month, paid for by the people of St Kitts and Nevis, who he is now pleading with to march with him on Labour Day?
Could the $4.74 million in legal fees that were allegedly paid to a person who was at the same time serving as our permanent ambassador to the United Nations have been better spent for the people of this country?
Is any of this related to the fact that the people of St Kitts and Nevis were robbed of the right to see the annual financial statements of the SIDF and the Social Security Board since 2011? What will happen when we see these reports? What more will be revealed?
Without accusing anybody of anything, let me tell you that theres a Belize legal case in which it was decided ultimately by the Caribbean Court of Justice, that an attorney general can take legal action against former government ministers, not only for misfeasance in public office (misfeasance is a civil wrong, a tort) but also, through a DIRECTOR OF PUBLIC PROSECUTIONS, for malfeasance in public office (malfeasance is a crime).
The CCJ, in strongly making to point that governments have to act, said this:
The failure to detect, investigate, prosecute and punish corruption has a corrosive impact on democracy and the rule of law. We underestimate, at our peril, the degree to which such failure affords encouragement to the criminal elements in society and contributes to a burgeoning crime rate.
And the court went on to say that the misfeasance route is a less painful one for the perpetrators than the malfeasance route, because, to use a well known saying, in the case of malfeasance jail could be in that.
Go and accuse the Caribbean Court of Justice of looking to victimize anyone because it has ruled that a government has an obligation to detect, investigate, prosecute and punish corruption!
And if youve heard it from me once, youve heard it from me a hundred times: Corruption in high places contributes to increased so-called blue collar crime. Now youve heard that the Caribbean Court of Justice says the same thing.
I say: let the processes continue, and let the chips fall where they may. The government must discharge its obligation to democracy, to the rule of law, to the people, and to the good name of St Kitts and Nevis. It must, and if it fails to do so, it is just as guilty as the perpetrators of misfeasance or malfeasance.
So if any wrongdoing is discovered, whether it be tantamount to misfeasance in public office or misfeasance in public office, the perpetrators and beneficiaries must be made to pay.
Doing that will not only send the right message to anyone who has acted corruptly in public office in the past, but it will serve as a warning to todays, and tomorrows incumbents that they must conduct themselves, and the affairs of government, in a proper manner.
Or else!
We have a new government that has a glorious opportunity to start clean, continue clean, and, eventually, to end clean. Our hopes rest on that. No selfishness, no my constituency first, no piling up of cronies on boards, etc.
Years ago, a friend of mine said that persons elected to public office must be paid fairly, and if theyre caught stealing a pencil, they should go to jail.
I agree.
The case is: Attorney General of Belize vs Marin and Coye. Check it out.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: False patriotism and deceitful promises at Argyle</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-False-patriotism-and-deceitful-promises-at-Argyle-25929.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: False patriotism and deceitful promises at Argyle
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
Except for unfortunate gaps and unintentional errors here and there, which I hope others will address or correct, finding the data for these essays was a simple tap on my iPad in this Internet age. Critiquing the never-ending construction of Argyle International Airport (AIA) has been even easier given the project's long list of glaring shortcomings, even for an airline, airport, and travel industry novice like myself (whose only credentials for writing these pieces is a PhD in one of the social sciences and 45 years of holiday travel to 15 different destinations throughout the Caribbean archipelago, and whose only motives have been intellectual curiosity, a desire to engage the public in a long needed evidence-based debate about AIA, and a sense of patriotic duty).
It is regrettable, though not unexpected, that many readers have found my comments overly "negative," even "unpatriotic." As a professional academic, I tried to present my findings as accurately and dispassionately as I could to counter the many false, silly, and deceitful assertions made by members of our tourism establishment and their politically-motived or uninformed sycophants. Yes, the truth often hurts -- especially for a people who have been conditioned to view all public policy through the distorted lens of party politics or who have been socialized to interpret any criticism of their party or country, however valid or well intentioned, as an assault on their sense of national identity -- but it can also be wonderfully liberating.
As for my lack of patriotism, the concept has been termed "the last refuge of the scoundrel" (Samuel Johnson, April 7, 1775) when referring to a false patriotism lacking grounded conviction or thoughtful contemplation. What I take from Samuel Johnson (a British slavery abolitionist well ahead of his time) is that those who stubbornly and mindlessly reject any negative assessment of their homeland regardless of its accuracy or motivation are not true patriots at all but people who either suffer from some sort of national inferiority complex, or have something to gain (politically, socially, or economically) from supporting the status quo, or who can only blindly love their country because, well, its the only country they have. This is an empty even dangerous "patriotism" that can lead to self-deception, censorship, victimization, xenophobia, or worse.
Not unexpectedly, so-called negativism and presumed anti-patriotism are differentiated in our small land on the basis of socio-economic position: the have-nots are much more realistic about our country's limitations simply because they have to cope with them day in and day out; the various elites, being the main beneficiaries of our grossly unequal distribution of wealth, power, and privilege, are naturally our main cheerleaders.
What many of these false or blind patriots would refuse to acknowledge most of all is that the criticisms that I and others have levelled against the AIA project are just the tip of an unprecedented tropical iceberg, one that deliberately hides from view so much more damning truths that will eventually sink us with debts, despair, and lost opportunities.
But not everything can be hidden. A drive out to Argyle or a visit to our mainland tourist sites, beaches, and recreational venues should immediately tell all with eyesight -- if not vision -- and a bit of international holiday travel experience that AIA is nothing more than a graveyard of deceitful promises.
The most recent of these deceitful promises is a claim by Sabato Caesar , minister of agriculture and fisheries, that "The new international airport currently under construction at Argyle in St Vincent and the Grenadines is expected to play a critical role in enhancing the viability of the local fishing industry.... The minister said that investors are likely to be more inclined to get involved in fish exports, once the issue of market access is addressed".
The minister knows full well that: the tonnes of fish caught by Japanese trawlers in our waters are shipped thousands of miles home to Japan by refrigerated ships (as in commercial fisheries all over the world); no other foreign interests are going to invest in our local fishery when they can continue to steal from our waters at will; we can barely satisfy our domestic needs, especially for large species, due to overfishing; transporting most sea products by air is prohibitively expensive; fish shipped by air or boat from SVG to North America or Europe could never compete with cheaper fish shipped there from Asia and Africa; and we don't have enough live crustaceans (lobsters, crayfish, conchs, etc.) left in our waters or rivers to export anywhere outside the country.
The beach bar at Layou
If deceit and deception were not the political order of the day with this airport folly, we would also have known by now which of the airlines the prime minister claims the government has been "in touch with" -- American Airlines, JetBlue, Delta, Spirit, WestJet, British Airways and Caribbean Airlines -- have made even a tentative commitment to fly here once the airport is open for business; we would have known by now which international or regional hotel chains, even the smallest ones, have the slightest interest in building a resort hotel on the leeward coast or elsewhere on the mainland; we would have known by now which regional or local entrepreneurs or existing hotel owners were planning to substantially expand our boutique resort offerings or build new ones; we would have know -- and seen -- by now what non-airport infrastructure and facilities were been planned or enhanced to meet the requirements of mass international tourism; and we would have known by now, even actually seen with our own eyes by now, which new and exciting tourist facilities were being built, which were being significantly expanded or altered, and which were being renovated to meet the high standards of our neighbours.
Famous Basil's Bar on Mustique, packed with tourists, as usual
As Sabato Caesar's and other equally deceitful comments from regime members illustrate, none of this has happened or will happen because AIA was never conceived or constructed to bring thousands of passengers to our country from foreign destinations; it was conceived and constructed only to bring thousands of voters to the polling booth on election day to mark their "X" for the ULP as a sign of their "patriotism."
Perhaps the best evidence for this assertion is two recent bold-faced Dr Gonsalves flip-flops.
First, we have the about-turn on revealing the identity of the airlines that we have supposedly been "in touch with." At a November 8, 2011, AIA symposium, the prime minister said that: We have airlines who [sic] have already indicated their interest and none wants us to mention their names, because, obviously, they dont want their competitors to know until quite late what they are engaged in ().
Suddenly, either secrecy has been abandoned or we have entered the "quite late" phase with the publication of the above-listed names of seven airlines, most of which would never fly here for economic reasons, as I will show in my last essay.
Second, at the same symposium, the honourable prime minister defended his governments decision to out-source the management of AIA because the skills needed were not available locally. Dr Gonsalves even ridiculed the comments of those who questioned bringing foreigners in to manage AIA as reflecting a " ... kind of bogus, superficial nationalism, which has no depth.... They know that  we dont have the skilled personnel now to do it. We have to train them and we have to make sure that the requisite experience is developed and we have that as a process... That is part of our decolonisation; because the same bogus nationalists who parrot these inanities, they are the ones who are among the most backwards, colonised and unemancipated minds in the country".
Now, in a dramatic 180-degree turn, the prime minister has apparently yielded to a "superficial nationalism which has no depth" by surrendered to "the most backwards, colonised and unemancipated minds in the country" by setting up a new locally run government-owned company to manage the airport once it is completed.
Many Vincentians were pleasantly surprised and heartened by the 2011 out-sourcing announcement, given the public perception of poor and indifferent performance by the current government bureaucracy running E. T. Joshua International Airport. So how are we to interpret the dramatic decision that airport management will now be in the hands of "... a new wholly owned government company ... staffed by a number of suitably trained and qualified persons," none of whom appear to have been selected, let alone trained, on the eve of the airport's newly promised June 2015 completion?
What really happened between 2011 and 2015 ? In particular, what happened to the "... arrangement with the Boyd Group International Inc., an aviation consulting, forecasting, and research firm from the United States.... The group will assist with the development and execution of air service recruitment strategies for this country, especially the AIA.... The recruitment strategies include developing an air service blue print for the AIA and building airline awareness through meetings at international conferences... It will also speak to arranging guided tours of the AIA, key resorts and other attractions for airlines and tour operators and assisting with negotiations of air service agreements with targeted airlines"?
What became of these laudable and necessary objectives?
Perhaps the prime minister, the International Airport Development Company, and the Boyd Group were unable to attract qualified and seasoned outsiders to manage the airport because all those invited to do so recognized a boondoggle when they saw one (a remote possibility); perhaps Boyd Group advised the government to manage the airport and the other tourism activities mentioned above on its own (an unlikely possibility given that the privatization of airport and allied administration has been going on all over the world for decades for reasons of accountability, transparency, efficiency, and integrity); maybe the prime minister feared surrendering decision making to an impartial entity which would be quick to expose the airport's failings, perhaps even the entire project's imminent demise (a real possibility).
The most frightening possibility, at least for "patriotic" AIA boasters, is that the honourable prime minister simply does not want to waste money, time, and effort on professional managers he cannot easily control when he knows full well that the AIA project is bound to fail.
But there is nothing to gain by limiting blame to deliberate political deceit for this would only lead to an even more destructive self-deception. "Be not deceived; God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap" (Galatians 6:7). Not long from now, we will be taught this painful Bible lesson when we reap the awful truth of what we ourselves have wilfully and democratically sown with our AIA "patriotism."
Among the many examples of this awful truth is our inability to ever remotely compete with places like the much bigger country of the Dominican Republic which saw its visitor numbers increase by a whopping 45 percent in 2014 from the year before while our numbers declined during the same period.
Nor can we ever hope to come close to matching tiny places like the Turks and Caicos Islands (TCI) which received a whopping 1.4 million cruise ship passenger and overnight guests in 2014. This was a 32 percent increase over the year before , or nearly ten times our number of cruise ship and stay-over arrivals, a figure that decreased last year and has been stagnant or in decline for previous years.
The TCI has also just signed two agreements totalling US$450 million for lavish new resort projects. One of these is with the prestigious Ritz Carlton hotel chain. No wonder one of the TCI, Providenciales, has just been declared " the world's best [tourist] island " (after scoring second last year) by TripAdvisor based on reviews by the travel site's visitors.
Meanwhile, we are struggling even to get a single "approval in principle" with some no-name -- perhaps imaginary -- group of Canadian investors to build a US$ 200 million hotel in the Mt Wynne area. Rest assured, so desperate in this government to show that AIA is a potentially worthwhile project, if any agreement is ever reached it would be bound to include one-sided interest-free loan guarantees and other potentially damaging concessions.
Again, before anyone counters that we cannot compete with the small Turks and Caicos island chain mainly because it has two international airports and we have none, they should note the following: twice as many visitors arrive there by ship than by plane; only one of these international airports receives most of the overseas traffic; the other "international" airport services mainly the Turks and Caicos and other nearby tourism islands; and many of the Turks and Caicos tourist islands are accessible only by boat.
So why are the Turks and Caicos Islands such a popular tourist destination and St Vincent Island is not? Everything I have written in these essays and the photo below gives the answers.
A typical Turks and Caicos beach, hotel, and resort area
But "negatively" and "unpatriotically" comparing ourselves to the TCI, the Dominican Republic, and the many other holiday destinations I have referred to in this series also has an important positive lesson to teach us. Rather than trying to emulate places our mainland can't possibly compete with or pray for economic salvation at the phony shrine at Argyle we can't possibly afford, isn't it high time that we more fully recognized, embraced, and fostered the fact that our "Gem of the Antilles," to use another tourism motto, also consists of a chain of wondrous Grenadines island jewels of incredible beauty and charm, a perfect complement to our big island in so many ways?
The Grenadines -- a magical TCI-like string of pearls in a part of the Caribbean Sea that so many holidayers have always yearned to visit and slowly travel through by all manner of vessel -- have long been the heart and soul of our tourist industry and will always remain the main source of its future development.
Why do we need to genuflect to the deceitful development proclamations of our self-aggrandizing political class when we have long known what visitors and many of our own people love most about our country?
***
ENDNOTE
This is the 14th in a series of 15 essays on the folly of the proposed Argyle International Airport.
My other AIA essays may be found at:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Time for new diversified blood in Guyana's parliament</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Time-for-new-diversified-blood-in-Guyana%27s-parliament-25930.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Time for new diversified blood in Guyana's parliament
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
I would like to share my personal video message with the people of Guyana encouraging you get ready and head out to vote on May 11. I endorse the Independent Party to bring new, fresh and diversified ideas and people into Parliament. It is time the infighting stops and the focus on real issues begin. If is like our homes, if there is infighting in our homes, no matter how strong we are, how much money we have, how big our houses and how expensive our cars are, we will lose it all because we simply cannot get along. Exercise your right to chose who you want to represent you. It does not have to the same party you chose before. You can change. You can change your support at each election depending of what each party has to offer.
I am encouraging all Guyanese to come out in numbers and vote at this upcoming election. Use your voice and your vote to ensure the best party is placed in parliament to represent YOUR interests. Think of this like a business. You wouldnt just hire anyone to run your business if you want that business to grow and become successful right? Likewise, show that you can make wise decisions by casting your vote for the Independent Party come May 11. If they have a chance to secure a few seats, they will echo your voice in government and ensure your quiet voice is heard. Dont be a follower. Be your own leader. You do not have to support who your parents or their parents supported. This is your voice. You are the best person to make the choice best for you. You have the power to make a change, infuse fresh ideas and come out of just settling. Be the voice of your future and your childrens future. If you keep voting for the same party, you will get what you have always gotten. You want change? Vote for those who will hear you, speak for you and respect you. Vote Independent Party on May 11.
I am Sukree Boodram. I make a difference. I am the power of ONE standing with the power of MANY. Thank you and good luck to everyone.
Sukree Boodram
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Permaul added to West Indies squad for third Test match</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Permaul-added-to-West-Indies-squad-for-third-Test-match-25931.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Permaul added to West Indies squad for third Test match
Published onMay 1, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados  The West Indies Cricket Board announced on Thursday that left-arm spinner Veerasammy Permaul has been added to the Test squad for the third and final match against England.
The West Indies will now have a 15-member squad for the third Test against England, starting on Friday at the Kensington Oval. Leg-spinner Devendra Bishoo suffered a cut to his ring finger in the right hand and is being treated by the medical staff.
Permaul, 25, made his debut in 2012 and has played four Test matches so far. He has 12 wickets at an average of 37 runs per wicket. He was the leading wicket-taker in the WICBs Professional Cricket League Four-Day Tournament this year with 67 wickets at 14 runs each.
Commenting, head coach Phil Simmons said: Bishoo did well for us in the second Test in Grenada but he has a finger injury so we decided to call-up Permaul. He (Permaul) was among the best bowlers in the four-day cricket earlier this season, and he also bowled well in the camp ahead of this series  so hes in good shape.
FULL SQUAD
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lay Day at Antigua Sailing Week</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Lay-Day-at-Antigua-Sailing-Week-25932.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Lay Day at Antigua Sailing Week
Published onMay 1, 2015
Teams compete in the Nonsuch Bay RS Elite Challenge on Lay Day at Antigua Sailing Week. Photos: Paul Wyeth/pwpictures.com
By Louay Habib
ST JOHNS, Antigua -- The Nonsuch Bay RS Elite Challenge started at 1pm on Wednesday with eight international teams vying for the winner takes-all-prize of a one-week bed and breakfast stay at the outstanding award winning Nonsuch Bay Resort. Hundreds of people watched the racing from the beach and enjoyed a sumptuous barbecue prepared by 2011 Caribbean Chef of the Year, Mitchell Husbands. Sailing Anarchy's Mr Clean, Smile and Wave's Jaime Torres and Antigua Sailing Week 's Louay Habib provided race commentary and the occasional competition for a cold Presidente Beer.
Team CSA, Team Phaedo3, Team Kick 'em Jenny. Photo: Ted Martin/Photofantasyantigua.com
In the first flight defending champion Peter Holmberg, racing with his brother John and nephew Kai on Team CSA, showed their intent breezing into the final. Marc Fitzgerald's Team Sojana also made the final after a great battle with Team Phaedo skippered by Brian Thompson and St Martin's own, Kick 'em Jenny. In the second flight, the Italian team At Last... skippered by Pietro Corbucci showed their amazing skills. The Italian stallions won all three flights. Lucy Jones' Performance Yacht Charter team won an intense battle for second place, deposing Nicole Lameter, a long-time Antigua Sailing Week bareboat participant with KH+P yachtcharter from Germany and also Nonsuch Bay resident, Martin Beck's all Antiguan team, Sheer Madness.
Pietro Corbucci's winning Team - At Last... in action at the Nonsuch Bay RS Elite Challenge on Lay Day. Photo: Paul Wyeth/pwpictures.com
The final was thrilling right from the start. An eager defending champion, Peter Holmberg was called over the line and despite returning to start correctly, the Olympic and America's Cup helmsman was never going to catch the others. Pietro Corbucci's Team At Last... won the final with a race to spare beating Team CSA into second with Lucy Jones' Team Performance Yacht Charter completing the podium.
Mark Whinney, sales and marketing director at Nonsuch Bay Resort was happy to see so many people turning out to watch this popular Lay Day event, now in its third year: "We at Nonsuch Bay are passionate about sailing and love holding events, so the RS Elite Challenge works well for us. We were looking for a way of getting the Elites involved in Antigua Sailing Week and this stadium event was the perfect fit. It's great to see so many international sailors taking part this year and congratulations to Pietro Corbucci from Team At Last...for such a decisive win. They will be able to enjoy their week at Nonsuch Bay, which includes use of all the water sports equipment and we have seven types of sailboats including other watersports: kayaks, SUPs and kitesurfing.
"We look forward to welcoming the Italians back and certainly they've already expressed interest in coming to race in some of our other regattas at Nonsuch next year," Whinney concluded after another successful and popular Nonsuch Bay RS Elite Challenge.
Nicole Lameter's Team KH+P yachtcharter. Photo: Paul Wyeth/pwpictures.com
Marc Fitzgerald's Team Sojana. Photo: Paul Wyeth/pwpictures.com
Click here for the full event programme visit, Facebook ( AntiguaSailingWeek ) or download the new APP on iTunes or Google Play by searching for Antigua Sailing Week by ASW 2015

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Kitts-Nevis to implement citizenship programme reforms</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Kitts-Nevis-to-implement-citizenship-programme-reforms-25894.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Kitts-Nevis to implement citizenship programme reforms
Published onApril 30, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Caribbean News Now contributor
BASSETERRE, St Kitts -- The government of St Kitts and Nevis has accepted the recommendations of an international risk management firm to implement reforms in its citizenship by investment (CBI) programme, bolstering security aspects and increasing attractiveness to investors.
Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris
At a press conference on Tuesday, Prime Minister Dr Timothy Harris said that the services of IPSA International Inc. based in the United States were secured in the last quarter of 2014 by the previous administration to make an independent comprehensive evaluation of the CBI.
This review was inspired by serious concerns raised by foreign governments, including the United States, United Kingdom and Canada, which subsequently led to the imposition of visas on St Kitts and Nevis citizens traveling to Canada.
The [then] government by and large had gotten in an election mode and had paid very little attention to IPSAs recommendation, Harris revealed. I can say today that this government has reviewed the report and after consultations with a wide cross section of persons representing developers, agents, service providers, lawyers, ordinary citizens and workers, we have decided that it is in the best interest of our country that we implement the 20 recommendations proposed by IPSA International.
Among the recommendations that have been accepted is the implementation of a case management tool to streamline the application management process within the CBI unit; changes to the units organizational structure to enhance processing capabilities and mitigate risk; an improved risk assessment process; and a review of previously approved applicants.
These will form the basis to restructure reform and reposition the CBI programme and unit in particular to restore it to its former glory, Harris emphasized. Not just to become known as a programme which is the oldest, but a programme which is the best and which will become a leader in best practices in (similar) programmes.
IPSA will be working closely with the government in these areas. These measures are expected to promote greater transparency and efficiency in the work at the CBI unit.
The world's oldest citizenship programme, and for years regarded as the best programme of its kind, was dealt a heavy blow to its reputation when Iranian sanctions evaders began showing up all over the world with St Kitts-Nevis passports. Some even carried diplomatic passports. This created concern on the part of US and Canadian authorities, among others.
In particular, the arrival of an Iranian in Canada with a St Kitts-Nevis diplomatic passport for which he claimed to have paid one million dollars resulted in outrage locally, and in advisories from foreign countries. Some months later, the Canadian government put an end to the visa-free access that had been previously enjoyed for decades by St Kitts-Nevis passport holders entering Canada.
Harris acknowledged that there had been damage done to the reputation of the programme due to its less than appropriate management by the former administration.
In giving his guarantee of improvements to the programme, Harris outlined:
As the new prime minister of the country, responsibility for our citizenship-by-investment, one of the mainstays of the economy, rests with me. I guarantee the following:
1. To our partner governments across the world, I pledge my word that no undesirables will be allowed to take advantage of our programme. We shall work actively with you to make this happen. We shall not issue any diplomatic passports to people who are neither citizens nor residents of St Kitts and Nevis. Our reputation is not for sale at any price. We shall be revoking any passports that were issued fraudulently. We will not allow our good name to be traduced. We shall also make provision to revoke the citizenship of any citizen-by-investment who within five years of the certificate of registration commits a serious crime, appears on an international sanctions list or on the wanted list of any country or international body, or is named in any scandal that might bring St Kitts and Nevis into disrepute. Anybody who made false claims or provided us with misleading information at the time of making the application will have their citizenship revoked. We are very serious about this.
2. To genuine investors, I apologise for any delay in the processing of your application. We welcome your interest and investment in our beautiful islands. We are working hard to ensure that the procedure becomes more efficient and transparent. IPSA International, a consultancy that specializes in due diligence and works for many governments around the world, prepared a report for us just before Christmas on the citizenship programme.
It said that The St Kitts and Nevis Citizenship Investment Programme has been successfully run for the last 30 years but with higher volumes, changing regulations and increased focus on anti-money laundering and counter terrorist funding, further improvements would enhance the governments continued initiatives to protect the integrity and security of the programme. It concluded that Together with the good practices in place, the proposed policy initiatives and the implementation of the recommendations, the CIU will continue to be strengthened while ensuring efficiency, integrity and transparency in its activities.
These recommendations include establishing a commission for the oversight of the citizenship by investment programme; reviewing the regulations for the establishment of escrow accounts and amending the policies accordingly; and conducting a look back of approved and reviewed applications, as well as conducting periodic reviews of approved applicants thereafter. In total, there are 20 recommendations. My cabinet agreed this week to adopt all these 20 recommendations with immediate effect.
3. To developers who are creating projects that will bring employment and investment to our country, we say: You are most welcome. We understand that citizenship-by-investment is a useful source of income. Legitimate developers who create a positive economic impact on our islands will continue to enjoy the benefits of the programme as a funding source. Tourism is a great source of income for this country, and we have a shortage of hotel beds. However, we are looking carefully at those projects that are only benefitting the individuals who are building empty boxes. Not only is this of no benefit to the citizens of St Kitts and Nevis, but also it has a negative impact on the beauty of the landscape and we shall be reviewing some of the schemes that are being proposed. Genuine developers need have no concerns. In fact we shall work tirelessly to ensure your projects proceed in a timely manner.
4. And finally, to the citizens of St Kitts and Nevis, I can assure you that not only are we working to protect and safeguard your travel rights to more than 140 countries, but that we are adding to the list. Brazil has just announced that it will now allow our citizens to enter its borders without the hassle of first applying for a visa. We are in consultation with other countries, and the success of these talks will be announced in due course.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Lucia opposition declines to debate budget estimates</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Lucia-opposition-declines-to-debate-budget-estimates-25895.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Lucia opposition declines to debate budget estimates
Published onApril 30, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Caribbean News Now contributor
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- Following the presentation to parliament of the 2015/16 estimates of revenue and expenditure by Saint Lucias prime minister and minister for finance, Dr Kenny Anthony, opposition members declined to open the customary debate on the estimates.
Prime Minister Dr Kenny Anthony
In a subsequent press release, Anthony explained that, after the presentation of the estimates of revenue and expenditure, it is usual practice for the opposition to lead off the debate. The same procedure applies after the presentation of the budget statement. Thereafter, other parliamentarians intervene and make their presentations.
Prior to the presentation of the estimates, the government and opposition agreed that each speaker would be allowed one hour to speak, if they so chose.
When the House convened on Wednesday, four opposition members: leader of the opposition Gale Rigobert; Arsene James; Edmund Estaphane; and Guy Joseph were present. Towards the end of the prime ministers presentation, Joseph left the Chamber.
At the end of the prime ministers presentation, the speaker put the question to the House in the customary manner. There was a period of silence and no member turned on the microphone to signal an intent to speak. The speaker put the question again and another period of silence ensued. At that point, the speaker of the House proceeded to present the motion for approval. No member of the House voted against the motion. The prime minister then moved for the adjournment of the House of Assembly, sine die.
Oppostition Leader Gale Rigobert
This is unprecedented, unfortunate and disappointing. The government of Saint Lucia will not accept any responsibility for the failure of the opposition to manage its affairs in the House of Assembly, Anthony said.
On a midday radio talk show, Philip J Pierre, minister for infrastructure, port services and transport, added, The real losers are the people who voted for the opposition.
Another local observer commented that the United Workers Party (UWP) opposition disrespected the taxpayers and the voters of Saint Lucia: In short, the people of Saint Lucia were deprived and short changed.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CSM, private sector engagement, Cuba feature prominently at COTED</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-CSM%2C-private-sector-engagement%2C-Cuba-feature-prominently-at-COTED-25896.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
CSM, private sector engagement, Cuba feature prominently at COTED
Published onApril 30, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Delegates at the Opening Ceremony of the 40th Meeting of the Council for Trade and Economic Development in Georgetown, Guyana, on Thursday, 23 April, 2015
GEORGETOWN, Guyana -- Action to ensure that the CARICOM Single Market (CSM) is placed on a more efficient footing to benefit Caribbean Community nationals; the importance of standards and consumer protection; and the role of the private sector in regional development, were among the key matters trade ministers took decisions on when they met in Georgetown, Guyana, 23-24 April, 2015.
CSME
Ministers, at the fortieth meeting of the Council for Trade and Economic Development (COTED) placed special emphasis on consolidating the work of the CARICOM Single Market and Economy (CSME) to boost regional development.
They held extensive discussions on procedures related to the Single Market, particularly with respect to establishing fully web-based, harmonised administrative procedures that would reduce the time and challenges associated with applying for documentation under the five core regimes of the CSME. The harmonization also has positive implications for e-governance in the Community.
The meeting was held against the background of a continuing volatile global economic environment, and CARICOM Secretary-General Irwin LaRocque reminded delegates that utilising the provisions of the CSME to its fullest, was the best option. The CSME, he said, would allow us to exploit the full potential of our human resources as our skilled personnel move freely throughout the Community. The easier movement of capital would help to generate much needed investment. Our trade in goods and services can only be enhanced by the removal of whatever restrictions still remain.
The ministers considered work to be completed towards harmonization and standardization of administrative practices and procedures; enhancing the effective functioning of the services and labour markets through standardized licensing, certification and mutual recognition of licences and certificates; and widening the scope of participation by stakeholders and beneficiaries in the process of decision-making, implementation and operation of the Single Market. This process is supported by the CARICOM Trade and Competitiveness Project (CTCP) funded by the government of Canada.
The Council also paid attention to Communitys development, adoption and implementation of regional standards. In this regard, roles for the Council, the Caribbean Regional Organisation for Standards and Quality (CROSQ) and member states have been clearly identified.
Placing emphasis on the critical importance of the services sector to the regions economy, the Council welcomed the announcement by Suriname of the establishment of the Coalition of Services Industries.
Underscoring the significance of intra-regional trade to the Communitys development, the ministers welcomed the assurance by sugar producing countries, Guyana and Belize, supported by the Sugar Association of the Caribbean (SAC) that they were gearing to provide sustained supplies to the regional market. The ministers mandated the CARICOM Secretariat to collaborate with the SAC and regional sugar-producing member states to compile a paper within three months, on regional demand, supply and global trade issues related to the commodity.
The meeting approved the revised procedures and forms that would facilitate smoother functioning of the system for requests for suspensions of the Common External Tariff (CET).
Ministers also agreed to a special session of the COTED to pay attention to the supply of petroleum products.
The challenges member states encountered in intra-regional trade were also a point of focus at the meeting and ministers agreed on steps to be taken at the bilateral level to resolve some of those issues.
With respect to the COTEDs engagement with the regional private sector, which has implications for the conduct of business in the region, strides have been made since the last meeting of COTED in November 2014. An examination of the findings of a consultancy on the role of the private sector was concluded earlier this year and it was determined that the Caribbean Business Council (CBC) remained the best vehicle to effect the public-private structured interaction. The CBC is expected to be operational by the end of September, 2015.
The private sector is a critical partner in the regions quest for economic resilience, which is a key element of the Communitys five-year strategic plan.
External Economic Relations
Special attention was paid to relations with Cuba. Ministers underlined the strong bonds between CARICOM and Cuba, and acknowledged Cubas generous offer of duty-free access for a wide range of CARICOM products into the Cuban market. They agreed to review urgently outstanding requests from Cuba for additional preferential access to CARICOM more developed countries which will pave the way for a joint commission meeting between the two sides to be held by July 2015.
The COTED also reviewed member states preparation for implementation of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) trade facilitation agreement which was adopted at the ninth WTO ministerial meeting in Bali.
On Thursday, the first day of the ministerial meeting, the ministers received a delegation from Kazakhstan, which will be hosting an international exposition under the theme Future Energy in its capital Astana in 2017. Yerzhan Ashikbayev, deputy minister of foreign affairs of Kazakhstan, in addressing the COTED, called for participation by all CARICOM member states and the CARICOM Secretariat in the exposition.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trinidad and Tobago signs shipbuilding contracts for new coast guard vessels</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Trinidad-and-Tobago-signs-shipbuilding-contracts-for-new-coast-guard-vessels-25897.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Trinidad and Tobago signs shipbuilding contracts for new coast guard vessels
Published onApril 30, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- On Wednesday, the ministry of national security and Damen Shipyards signed shipbuilding contracts and an overall agreement for the construction of naval vessels for the Trinidad and Tobago Defence Forces Coast Guard.
Trinidad and Tobago has ordered the vessels covered by the contract to enhance the countrys maritime security and to establish the foundations of a maritime security wall, which will create and sustain an effective presence at all levels of Trinidad and Tobagos maritime domain.
The vessels include:
1. Four Damen coastal patrol vessels:
 51 metres long, 9 metres wide
 Speed is in excess of 28 knots
 Range exceeds 2,500 nautical miles
 Equipped with an advanced surveillance system
 Deploys an on-board 11m interceptor plus a short-range 7.5m rigid hull inflatable boat (RHIB)
 Will patrol coastal waters but is capable of operating in Trinidad and Tobagos EEZ
 Uses a unique Sea-Axe design to dramatically enhance seakeeping in rough waters
2. Two Damen fast crew supply utility vessels:
 54 metres long, 10 metres wide
 Speed is in excess of 20 knots
 Range exceeds 3,000 nautical miles
 Can be used for a variety of roles  support of interceptor operations, disaster relief, search and rescue as well as limited coastal patrol
3. Six Damen interceptors:
 11 metres long, 2 meters wide
 Speed is in excess of 53 knots
 Capable of being embarked on and deployed from the coastal patrol vessels and utility vessels
Since 1927, Damen Shipyards have built high quality vessels for civil, military and paramilitary purposes. Such vessels are in service with the coast guards of the United States, Canada, Mexico, Venezuela, The Bahamas, Jamaica and Barbados, among other countries.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Renewed law enforcement partnerships are a win for USVI, says senator</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Renewed-law-enforcement-partnerships-are-a-win-for-USVI%2C-says-senator-25898.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Renewed law enforcement partnerships are a win for USVI, says senator
Published onApril 30, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
ST THOMAS, USVI -- US Virgin Islands Senator Novelle Francis on Wednesday commented on what he called a fresh start in the relationship between federal and local law enforcement agencies. A career law enforcement professional and former police commissioner, he presently serves as the chair for the legislatures Committee on Homeland Security, Public Safety and Justice.
Senator Novelle Francis
Francis commended Governor Kenneth Mapp on his positive and timely efforts to restore the territorys relationships with federal law enforcement agencies, to include the Drug Enforcement Administration, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms and US Customs and Border Patrol. He considers the ability to fully utilize the resources of federal law enforcement partners a win in the territorys fight against crime and gun violence.
He appreciated that the governor, VIPD Acting Commissioner Delroy Richards and US Attorney Ronald Sharpe have worked to overcome previous issues created by a lack of trust and transparency between the federal and local agencies.
This renewed partnership will have a critical impact on local initiatives, as it will provide immediate force and resource multipliers to support our men and women in blue, Francis stated. Our geographic location and open borders have historically been significant challenges for the VIPD, who work hard every day to keep guns, drugs and other contraband off of our streets. Our federal partners provide valuable resources such as training, equipment and manpower which are crucial to winning this war on crime.
Francis commended Richards, Sharpe and the members of the newly formed coalition for working together to craft a holistic approach to law enforcement in the territory. This marks a new start that can only carry us forward in ensuring a safer Virgin Islands for all.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bermuda ratings lowered as weak economic performance continues; outlook stable</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bermuda-ratings-lowered-as-weak-economic-performance-continues%3B-outlook-stable-25899.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bermuda ratings lowered as weak economic performance continues; outlook stable
Published onApril 30, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
NEW YORK, USA -- On Tuesday, Standard &amp; Poor's Ratings Services lowered its long-term issuer credit and senior unsecured debt ratings on Bermuda to 'A+' from 'AA-'. At the same time, Standard &amp; Poor's lowered its short-term rating on Bermuda to 'A-1' from 'A-1+'. The outlook is stable.
Finance Minister Bob Richards
Key drivers stated as the reasons for the downgrade are continuing weak economic performance and weak public finances which is not surprising, explained minister of finance, Bob Richards. Ministry of finance recognized that continuing government deficits and weak economic growth could put Bermudas sovereign rating at risk of a downgrade by one notch. We are pleased, however, that S&amp;P has attached a stable outlook to the rating.
The stable outlook reflects S&amp;Ps expectation that Bermuda's economy will grow in the next two years, which in turn will reduce fiscal deficits and stabilize gross government debt.
While the ratings adjustment is discouraging news, the minister of finance noted that the lower rating remains in the upper medium investment grade, with a stable outlook.
S&amp;P continues to endorse the governments effective policymaking and political stability. It is also pleasing to note that S&amp;P recognized that the hosting of the 2017 America's Cup yachting race will raise the island's profile as a high-end tourist destination, spurring investment in the hospitality sector, which is exactly what the Government is anticipating, Richards explained.
The government will continue to press ahead with our two track strategy that strikes a balance between responsible growth and disciplined financial management. We will continue work to restore investor confidence to attract foreign dollars back to our shores, opening the island to job and revenue creating activities, creating new possibilities for Bermudians to make a living. As the minister of finance, I remain committed to creating an economy that works for everyone and returning our public finances to a sustainable position, he concluded.
Shadow Finance Minister David Burt
According to shadow finance minister David Burt of the opposition Progressive Labour Party (PLP), Bermuda's latest downgrade by Standard &amp; Poor's should come as no surprise to Richards.
"Over the last 30 months he has been warned by the PLP and by ratings agencies that failure to diversify our economy would impact future ratings, he said.
Thirty months of austerity, lack of transparency, inaction on diversification and lack of planning have moved the Bermuda economy in the wrong direction. We cannot build an economy for the future with ideas from the last century; Bermuda needs new and innovative ideas to create jobs and build a secure economic future for Bermudians, Burt added.
S&amp;P provided the following rationale for its ratings action:
The downgrade reflects our assessment of Bermuda's continuing weak economic performance, persistent government deficits, and increases in debt burden, which we expect will continue through our forecast horizon.
The country's economy remains in recession: Real GDP contracted in 2014 for the sixth consecutive year. The Ministry of Finance believes that the contraction in real GDP could be as much as 1.5% in 2014. Real GDP fell 18% by 2014 from the 2008 peak and nominal GDP declined 8%. Labor market results were also weak in 2014. Bermuda's unemployment rate rose to 9% in 2014 from 7% in 2013 (compared with 8% in 2012). Employment fell in both 2013 and 2014, as it has since each year 2009. By 2014, employment had fallen 16% from its 2008 peak.
Despite the poor economic performances of recent years, GDP per capita remains what we consider very strong, at about US$88,000. We believe that real GDP growth will be flat in 2015 but increasing to about 1% growth in 2016. Weak economic performances have resulted in declining revenues and fiscal deficits. Bermuda recorded a general government deficit of 5% of GDP in fiscal 2014 (year ended March 31), which was unchanged from that of the previous fiscal year but much greater than those prerecession.
Fiscal results were near balance for most of 2001 through 2006, but fiscal deficits began to widen in 2007. The deficit peaked in 2009 at 6.5% of GDP and then fell to about 4.5% of GDP in 2010 and 2011, only to rise again to about 5.4% for both 2013 and 2014. The current governing party and its predecessor have made some progress toward reducing expenditures in the past five years. However, declining revenues have undone efforts to achieve balance. From 2009 to 2014, revenues fell 7%.
The 2015 budget imposed modest increases in payroll, air passenger, commercial property, corporate services, and fuel taxes. The government forecasts its fiscal deficit to improve to 3.9% of projected GDP in fiscal 2015 and 2.1% by fiscal year 2017. The annual change in government debt should be 1.8% of GDP for 2015-2017.
Bermuda's gross general government debt stood at 39% of GDP in fiscal 2014. Thanks to substantial fiscal assets, we estimate the government to be a net creditor of about 6% of GDP at fiscal year-end 2014. Despite our expectation of slow and modest economic and fiscal recoveries, respectively, we still expect Bermuda to remain a net creditor through the end of 2017 as gross government debt reaches 41% of GDP. The gross interest burden, however, will represent more than 11% of projected general government revenues from 2015-2017. The interest burden has been on the rise since fiscal 2008 with the debt-financing of deficits.
As with all sovereigns, we consider the local banking sector the principal contingent risk to the government. We place Bermuda's banking sector in group '5', on our Banking Industry Country Risk Assessment scale from '1' to '10', '1' being the best. We believe the sector poses a limited contingent liability to the government as our criteria defines the term.
HSBC Holdings PLC owns the largest bank, HSBC Bank Bermuda Ltd, with about a 50% market share. The second-largest bank, Bank of N.T. Butterfield &amp; Son Ltd, with a somewhat smaller market share, is mostly locally owned. Bermuda operates a currency board arrangement. Deposits at the Bermudian banks are more than 70% denominated in foreign currency, mostly the US dollar, against which the Bermudian dollar is pegged at 1-to-1. Both circumstances mean that external factors beyond the control of Bermudian authorities largely determine monetary conditions, contributing to our view that the island lacks monetary flexibility.
We view Bermuda's policymaking as largely effective and predictable and its political institutions stable. It is the largest of the UK's 14 overseas territories. The assessment also incorporates our view that public sector transparency (which we measure with indicators such as the timeliness, frequency, and completeness of statistics and public sector financial reporting) trails that of many higher rated governments.
Bermuda's size and lack of natural resources make it depend almost entirely on imported goods. As a result, the island consistently registers a large trade deficit. However, foreign earnings from financial services and tourism more than offset this, consistently generating a substantial current account surplus. (Bermuda classifies its world-class reinsurance sector as nonresident companies.)
We estimate the current account surplus will be close to 15% of GDP range from 2015-2017. By our estimate, the island is a substantial external creditor, with external debt net of public and financial sector assets nearly twice as high as current account receipts. However, because of its large banking sector, its gross external financing needs are very high.
In December 2014, Bermuda was named host for the 2017 America's Cup yachting race. We believe that this event will raise the island's profile as a high-end tourist destination, spurring investment in the hospitality sector. The government will spend BM$37 million on race-related infrastructure and BM$15 million in direct sponsorship, as well as provide a BM$25 million sponsorship guarantee. We believe the event will help increase growth in the latter years of the forecast horizon. However, our forecasts do not incorporate a direct boost to government net revenues from the race.
Outlook
The stable outlook reflects our expectation that Bermuda's economy will grow in the next two years, which in turn will trim fiscal deficits and stabilize gross government debt at slightly more than 40% of projected GDP. Should the economy continue to contract and government revenues in tandem, downward pressure on the ratings could emerge. On the other hand, should government measures, including the hosting of America's Cup, place Bermuda back on a higher growth plane that resulted in a steady decline in the government debt burden, we could consider a positive outlook revision or upgrade.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
