<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Privy Council affirms no trial by jury in Turks and Caicos corruption cases</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Privy-Council-affirms-no-trial-by-jury-in-Turks-and-Caicos-corruption-cases-26677.html</Link>
        <Description>LONDON, England -- On Thursday, the Judicial Committee of the Privy Council (JCPC) in London handed down its written judgment in relation to and appeal former Turks and Caicos Islands (TCI) premier Michael Misick seeking to enforce his right to trial by jury instead of by&amp;nbsp;judge alone.</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Privy Council affirms no trial by jury in Turks and Caicos corruption cases
Published onJune 26, 2015
Former Turks and Caicos Islands premier Michael Misick
By Caribbean News Now contributor
LONDON, England -- On Thursday, the Judicial Committee of the Privy Council (JCPC) in London handed down its written judgment in relation to and appeal former Turks and Caicos Islands (TCI) premier Michael Misick seeking to enforce his right to trial by jury instead of by judge alone as requested by the prosecution in the ongoing corruption trials in the British territory.
In addition to Misick, the case involves a number of other citizens and former ministers of the TCI, who are charged with corruption and other offences in the TCI, following an investigation subsequent to a Commission of Inquiry led by Sir Robin Auld. The appellants challenged the impartiality and independence of Justice Paul Harrison, a former president of the Court of Appeal of Jamaica, who was appointed to hear their case.
Ironically, the impracticability of finding jurors with no prior knowledge or opinions on the issues at stake given the very small pool (of approximately 6,000) to choose from in the TCI; and the inevitability that such jurors would be exposed to extra-evidential opinions and information, prompted Misick to submit forcefully to Auld at the Commission of Inquiry that trial by jury could not be fair to him.
The appeal now arguing to the contrary was heard by the JCPC on May 11, 2015, when the court indicated at the time that the appeal would be dismissed.
In relating the background to the appeals in its written judgment, the JCPC noted that from 2008 to 2009 there was a constitutional crisis in the TCI, then self-governing under a constitution of 2006. Following concerns about the administration of the TCI, a Commission of Inquiry was appointed into possible corruption or other serious dishonesty in relation to past and present elected members of the Legislature in recent years.
The Commissioner, Sir Robin Auld, published a report (the Report) recommending, amongst other things, the partial suspension of the 2006 Constitution, the creation of a special prosecution team to investigate evidence of corruption and dishonesty and the suspension of the absolute right to trial by jury.
The 2006 Constitution had provided for government by a Governor, acting on the advice of the Premier and his cabinet. However, following the Report and the effect given to the Report by the UK government, temporary direct rule by the Governor was instituted. The legislature was dissolved, the cabinet ceased to exist and the principal offices of government and legislature, such as the Premier and Speaker of the Assembly, were declared vacant.
After two years, self-government was restored and a new 2011 Constitution inaugurated. Similar to the 2006 Constitution, Section 6(1) of the 2011 Constitution affords those charged with a criminal offence the right to a fair hearing within a reasonable time by an independent and impartial court established by law. Unlike the 2006 Constitution, however, the 2011 Constitution does not contain an unqualified right to jury trial upon a criminal charge. Even though trial by jury is the norm, section 4 of the Trials Without a Jury Ordinance 2010 (TWAJO) allows a trial to be heard by a judge alone if the interests of justice so require.
A Special Investigation Team was created and it was this body that brought charges of conspiracy to accept bribes in public office, conspiracy to defraud and associated money laundering against Misick, other government ministers and their associates (the Appellants). Harrison J, an experienced judge in his mid-seventies from Jamaica, was appointed on 26 February 2015 for the specific purpose of presiding over these cases. The appointment was made for a fixed period of three years. Pursuant to section 4 of TWAJO, Harrison J directed that the interests of justice required trial by himself without a jury.
The Appellants challenged the lawfulness of their proposed trial on the grounds that: (1) contrary to section 6(1) of the 2011 Constitution, Harrison J did not have sufficient security of tenure and, thus, was not independent; and, (2) Harrison J failed to ask whether there was no reasonable doubt (the criminal standard of proof) that the interests of justice required a trial without jury before deciding so. The Appellants' claim was rejected by Harrison J himself and, subsequently, by the Court of Appeal.
The JCPC (with Lord Hughes giving its judgment) dismissed the appeal.
Reasons for the Judgment
On the first ground, Lord Hughes recalled that in the present case: (a) the Constitutional guarantee of judicial independence, remuneration, allowances and terms of service apply to Harrison J as they do to any other judge; (b) Harrison J has been appointed on the recommendation of the independent Judicial Service Commission; and, (c) Harrison J is guaranteed security of tenure during his appointment, except in the case of cause shown to this Board.
As for the limited term of his appointment, no objective observer would fear that Harrison J would entertain any sense of lack of independence in trials which he has been specifically asked to take on, outside his home territory and in his retirement. Far from a danger of lack of independence, his appointment has been made precisely to bring to locally highly controversial cases an independent outsider.
The Board does not need to decide whether other Supreme Court judges in the Turks and Caicos Islands lack sufficient security of tenure and has insufficient evidence of practice to do so  they are routinely appointed for an initial period of three years subject to renewal by agreement, but appointments are subject to the independent Judicial Service Commission. Whatever may be the practice as to their situation, it cannot affect Harrison J. He has been brought in ad hoc from outside and there is no sensible prospect that a judge who enjoys sufficient security of tenure to maintain his independence might lose it on the grounds that others lack his advantages.
On the second ground, not every decision which has to be made by a judge during or in preparation for a criminal trial is susceptible to analysis in terms of burden and standard of proof. Here, there is no doubt that the decision required by TWAJO  where, in relation to predictive conditions, a judge is required to weigh different factors and make a judgment as to necessity  is not susceptible of analysis in terms of proof or the standard of it. This applies to both the finding of facts and the evaluation of the interests of justice in light of those findings. Indeed, in this case there were no significant disputed primary facts according to Harrison J.
Harrison J recalled the fundamental importance of jury trials before working through the factors relevant to the interests of justice test. He was entitled to come to the conclusion he did. This was particularly the case in light of: (a) the complexity of the trial issues; (b) the impracticability of finding jurors with no prior knowledge or opinions on the issues at stake given the very small pool (of approximately 6,000) to choose from; and, (c) the inevitability that such jurors would be exposed to extra-evidential opinions and information, which had led the Appellants to submit forcefully to Sir Robin Auld that trial by jury could not be fair to them. In any event, even if Harrison J ought to have applied the criminal standard of proof, he could not realistically have reached any conclusion other than the one he did.
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trinidad opposition candidates under investigation by Integrity Commission</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Trinidad-opposition-candidates-under-investigation-by-Integrity-Commission-26678.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Trinidad opposition candidates under investigation by Integrity Commission
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- The opposition People's National Movement (PNM) in Trinidad and Tobago is going into the September 7 general election with two of its candidates now before the Integrity Commission, the Voice newspaper reported.
Marlene McDonald
In the first case, opposition leader Dr Keith Rowleys right hand, Marlene McDonald, is under investigation by the Integrity Commission over contracts given out to Calabar Foundation, while she was minister of community development in the previous PNM administration.
McDonalds husband, Michael Carew, and his brother, Lennox, are listed as directors of Calabar Foundation, which received $375,000 from the ministry of community development, even before their company had been registered.
Victor McEachrane is also listed as a director.
McEachrane is also listed as a director of Waterwheel Foundation, which received large contracts from the ministry during McDonalds tenure at the ministry.
Faris Al Rawi
McEachranes name has cropped up on several contracts received from the ministry of community development, culture and gender affairs.
In the second matter, Faris Al Rawi, the PNM candidate for the San Fernando West constituency, is also under investigation by the Integrity Commission for a conflict of interest. Faris allegedly tried to raise an issue concerning a client of his and the Trinidad and Tobago Electricity Commission (TTEC) during a debate in the Senate.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Answers sought regarding legal cost to St Lucia of controversial oil exploration agreement</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Answers-sought-regarding-legal-cost-to-St-Lucia-of-controversial-oil-exploration-agreement-26679.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Answers sought regarding legal cost to St Lucia of controversial oil exploration agreement
Published onJune 26, 2015
RSM Production Company (RSM) president Jack J. Grynberg (L) and Prime Minister Dr Kenny Anthony
By Caribbean News Now contributor
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- Saint Lucias prime minister, Dr Kenny Anthony, has been called on to apprise the nation of the legal costs involved in the governments ongoing efforts to settle an ill-fated agreement purporting to grant oil exploration rights over some eight million acres of Saint Lucias maritime territory.
In or about February 2000, Anthony, as then minister of finance, planning and sustainable development, signed a contract with RSM Production Company (RSM), a Texas company, along with its president Jack Grynberg, that purported to grant the company an Exploration License in respect of territorial maritime resources belonging to Saint Lucia amounting to 8,726,263 acres.
An ongoing claim by RSM in relation to the agreement is currently before the International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes in Washington, DC, but the matter was deferred again in April following RSMs failure to put up US$750,000 security for Saint Lucias legal costs.
On Thursday, the Lucian Peoples Movement (LPM) said that Anthony is obligated to offer the people of Saint Lucia an open and full disclosure regarding this matter.
Furthermore, in doing so, he would finally ensure his governments full compliance with the true meaning and ideals of accountability and transparency, which he has often maintained are the hallmarks of good governance, the LPM said in a press release.
According to the LPM, in addition to being a lesson for Anthony, who signed an agreement with Grynberg for oil exploration in Saint Lucia without any prior consultation with the citizens of Saint Lucia, the Grynberg affair highlights the painful repercussions that result when leaders with autocratic tendencies make ill-conceived decisions which could well saddle an entire nation with insurmountable financial debt.
Saint Lucia is currently being represented in the matter by a total of five lawyers, all of whom are employed by the law firm Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer, which operates in both the United States and the United Kingdom.
In late 2013, a complaint was filed with the US Department of Justice stating that the following facts, among others, established probable cause that a crime had been committed in relation to the RSM contract to warrant investigation and possible prosecution under the US Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA):
1. The contract was signed by Anthony purportedly as a Saint Lucia government minister but who was not in fact legally authorised or empowered to do so;
2. The contract was approved neither by parliament nor the governor general of Saint Lucia;
3. Royalty payments under the contract were to be made directly to a public official, not the Saint Lucia government itself;
Related article:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean integrity commissions form new Commonwealth body to fight corruption</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-integrity-commissions-form-new-Commonwealth-body-to-fight-corruption-26680.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean integrity commissions form new Commonwealth body to fight corruption
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
(L-R) Justice Dame Monica Joseph, Chairperson of the Integrity Commission of Grenada; Dr Keith Mitchell, Prime Minister of Grenada; Dame Cecile La Grenade, the Governor-General of Grenada; and Roger Koranteng, Governance and Anti-Corruption Adviser at the Commonwealth Secretariat
ST GEORGES, Grenada -- National authorities from 12 Commonwealth countries in the Caribbean have joined forces to establish a new regional body to enhance transparency and help fight corruption.
The Association of Integrity Commissions and Anti-Corruption Bodies in the Commonwealth Caribbean was formed at an international conference convened by the Commonwealth Secretariat in Grenada and hosted by the Integrity Commission of Grenada.
It was launched at the first Commonwealth regional conference for heads of integrity commissions and anti-corruption bodies in the Caribbean, taking place between 22-26 June 2015, and inaugurated by Dame Cecile La Grenade, the governor-general of Grenada, and Dr Keith Mitchell, the prime minister of Grenada.
The association, made up of the heads of national commissions, will help Caribbean countries to cooperate across borders, exchange best practices and develop regional anti-corruption initiatives.
Commonwealth Deputy Secretary-General Deodat Maharaj, welcoming its formation, expressed his hope that the new body will help to further strengthen public confidence in cross-border initiatives to enhance accountability.
Maharaj said: The formation of this new association represents a major step forward in regional efforts to support integrity and address corruption. We have high hopes for the future of this network of national agencies, which will deliver practical benefits to members as a forum for knowledge sharing and coordination. The intention is also to help countries learn and exchange with other Commonwealth countries and regions.
Justice Dame Monica Joseph, chairperson of the Integrity Commission of Grenada, said: The fact that we, in the Caribbean, will be forming ourselves into a regional association is recognition by us as a body that we consider it vital for the persons who serve us in public life, to function honestly, free of corruption and corrupt practices. We hope that, with that step, the peoples of the region would have confidence in the several commissions and anti-corruption bodies that form the association.
The establishment of the Caribbean body follows the similar formation, in 2011, of the Association of Anti-Corruption Agencies in Commonwealth Africa, spearheaded and supported by the Commonwealth Secretariat. The African association has helped improve the performance of national authorities through information exchanges, peer learning and by becoming a launch pad for bilateral agreements between countries.
The countries belonging to the new Association of Integrity Commissions and Anti-Corruption Bodies in the Commonwealth Caribbean are Antigua and Barbuda, The Bahamas, Barbados, Belize, Dominica, Grenada, Guyana, Jamaica, Saint Lucia, St Kitts and Nevis, St Vincent and the Grenadines, and Trinidad and Tobago.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caribbean banks respond to EU tax haven blacklist</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Caribbean-banks-respond-to-EU-tax-haven-blacklist-26681.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Caribbean banks respond to EU tax haven blacklist
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- The release of the Action Plan for Fair and Efficient Corporate Taxation in the EU by the European Commission on June 17, 2015, which included 15 Caribbean countries in a blacklist of non-cooperative jurisdictions, has caused the Caribbean Association of Banks (CAB) grave concern.
Notwithstanding that the European Union has now clarified that the final decision regarding which countries should be on the list has not been made, it is considered that the timing of this publication and its general perception as a new blacklist could have far-reaching effects on the Caribbeans financial services sector.
Indigenous banks in the region are currently being challenged with the threat of loss of correspondent banking relationships that are provided by international banks. An additional blacklist, based on unclear criteria, may serve to exacerbate the perception of the region as a high risk area and, consequently, negatively impact the risk rating profile of financial institutions by correspondent banks.
The financial services industry cannot survive without correspondent banking relationships and as a result, neither can regional economies.
The CAB said it was pleased to note the response of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) and the Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes which confirmed that the only agreeable assessment of countries as regards their cooperation is made by the Global Forum and that a number of countries identified in the EU exercise are either fully or largely compliant and have committed to AEOI (automatic exchange of information), sometimes even as early adopters.
It is noteworthy that the eight Caribbean Community (CARICOM) countries and five associated members that are named in the EUs report are all included in the OECDs list of members that have committed to automatic exchange of information.
The CAB therefore called upon the EU to carefully review the criteria used by its member states to assess and determine the countries that are non-compliant in tax matters. Additionally, the CAB strongly recommended greater collaboration between the EU, the OECD and the Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes before blacklist reports are issued.
The CAB also urged regional governments to act together to ensure that the region is represented in such key decision-making processes that can impact the growth and development of regional economies.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commonwealth secretary-general to visit Guyana</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commonwealth-secretary-general-to-visit-Guyana-26682.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commonwealth secretary-general to visit Guyana
Published onJune 26, 2015
GEORGETOWN, Guyana -- Commonwealth Secretary-General Kamalesh Sharma will arrive in Guyana on Saturday for a three-day visit, to gain a clear understanding of the regions concerns and priorities.
Commonwealth Secretary-General, Kamalesh Sharma
Sharma will call on recently elected President David Granger, and some of the members of his coalition government. He will also meet with the speaker of parliament and other key stakeholders in the country.
The visit will continue a series of high-level engagements in the Caribbean. Last week the secretary-general met with recently elected St Kitts and Nevis prime minister, Dr Timothy Harris, and attended the Commonwealth conference of education ministers in The Bahamas. From Guyana Sharma will travel to the CARICOM heads of government conference in Barbados.
The trip to the region and consultation with heads of government is part of the secretary-generals preparations for the next Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting (CHOGM), in Malta on 27-29 November 2015.
The aim is to meet with as many Commonwealth leaders in the Caribbean as possible to ensure their concerns and priorities are reflected in the CHOGM agenda, Sharma said.
The secretary-general will also address key issues affecting small states in the region, including ocean governance, climate change, education and youth empowerment, debt, trade, natural disaster management and access to development finance.
He said: In addition to our advocacy work to raise the Caribbeans concerns and needs on the global stage, the Commonwealth Secretariat is leading a number of cutting-edge initiatives that offer practical solutions to the challenges facing the Caribbean.
For example, our debt management software, which is used in 60 countries worldwide, manages a global portfolio of more than US$ 2.5 trillion of public debt, including approximately US$ 50 billion in the Caribbean.
Our Commonwealth 2013 debt restructuring exercise in Jamaica resulted in annual savings of approximately J$17 billion and a projected reduction of 8.8 per cent of debt-to-GDP by 2020.
The secretary-general will also discuss the ground-breaking Building the Resilience of Small States: A Strategic Vision for the Caribbean 2050 project.
The initiative examines the underlying reasons for slow economic growth in the region and its findings were dubbed a wake-up call for governments.
The project proposes a set of decisive actions, including empowering the youth with creative and interpersonal skills through revamped curriculums; reinvigorating the spirit of entrepreneurship; political reform; utilising local resources to achieve 100 per cent renewable energy; improving employment opportunities for young people in the private and public sectors and securing access to development of finance.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Kitts-Nevis disability associations visit Montserrat</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Kitts-Nevis-disability-associations-visit-Montserrat-26683.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Kitts-Nevis disability associations visit Montserrat
Published onJune 26, 2015
By Cathy Buffonge
Caribbean News Now contributor
BRADES, Montserrat -- Recently Montserrat was blessed with a visit from two special visitors from St Kitts. They were Anthony Mills, president of the St Kitts-Nevis Association for Persons with Disabilities, and Rockliffe Bowen, president of the St Kitts Society for the Blind. Both of these associations have been in existence for over 30 years.
They came at the invitation of the Montserrat Association of Persons with Disabilities (MAPD) through its president Joseph King Kirwan, with the highlight of their visit being the annual general meeting of MAPD.
In addition they took part in radio programmes, met with the minister of health Delmaude Ryan and other top officials and socialized with MAPD members.
In his feature address, Mills, who is in a wheelchair, stressed that people with disabilities are willing and able to be treated like anyone else, hold jobs and make their contribution to society. He explained that the first business venture of the St Kitts Association was a jewelry making business, which was successful. He himself has a job in an electrical company.
Bowen, who is blind, revealed that his wife is also blind but between them they lead an active and useful life, and encouraged the community to treat blind people with the respect they deserve. He was one of a family of ten, and has been blind since he was 11 years old, but his mother was determined that he should be treated the same as the other children in the family.
Kirwan emphasized the slogan Nothing about us without us, which illustrates that things should not be done for persons with disabilities unless they themselves are involved, as they know their needs best. They should be involved in every project or plan for their benefit,
In addition the speakers stressed that national plans should always include provision for persons with disabilities, for example building plans should include accessibility, so that those in wheelchairs or otherwise disabled can enter the building. They should be part of the process, not a separate or different issue.
Ryan, in her review, took on the expectations of the speakers and was enthusiastic about involving them in ongoing and new projects. She spoke about the need for a special bus that would make it easier for people with disabilities to get on and off.
Kirwan was re-elected as president of the Montserrat Association, with Thomas OGarro as vice president. The visit from the two St Kitts Associations was a tremendous boost and encouragement to the local Association.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BVI shell company allegedly used to steal US and Chinese shareholder interests in energy firm</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-BVI-shell-company-allegedly-used-to-steal-US-and-Chinese-shareholder-interests-in-energy-firm-26684.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
BVI shell company allegedly used to steal US and Chinese shareholder interests in energy firm
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
NEW YORK, USA -- Robert Seiden, the court-appointed receiver of Sino Clean Energy, Inc. (SCEI) filed criminal charges with the Hong Kong Police Commercial Crimes Bureau on May 22, 2015 alleging that SCEI's chairman, Baowen Ren, undertook a fraudulent backdated-transfer of shares in the Hong Kong subsidiary of the company, Wiscon Holdings Limited (WHL) to a shell company in the British Virgin Islands that he controls, Dacona Limited, thereby stealing the shareholders' interest (including the shares held by many US and Chinese citizens).
The forms memorializing these actions were filed in November 2014, which was six months after the receiver's appointment and were filed secretly without the receiver's knowledge or approval and after the receiver had effectively taken control over WHL.
Seiden, a former Manhattan prosecutor and president of the global firm Confidential Security Investigations filed the police report after his auditors in Hong Kong uncovered the fraud on WHL.
The Hong Kong criminal complaint states in part that: [t]he alleged share allotment is a willful attempt by Mr Ren to steal WHL, hence all the operating companies in China, from SCEI.... [and] is a blatant and illegal act of Mr Ren to embezzle the entire assets of SCEI.
The 2nd Judicial District Court of Nevada appointed Seiden as receiver on May 13, 2014, to hold SCEI accountable and act to maximize the value of SCEI on behalf of all shareholders after the company abruptly stopped filing its required forms with the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in May 2012, failed to convene required annual shareholders' meetings and elections of directors under Nevada statutes, and was sanctioned and de-listed by the NASDAQ.
The receiver's agents in China have conducted a series of meetings with Ren in China since October 2014 in an effort to settle these issues and to have Ren account for SCEI's finances, but Ren has consistently rebuffed these entreaties and violated the court's orders.
As a result, on June 4, 2015, the receiver, through his US lawyers, filed a rarely used motion for civil and criminal contempt with the court against Ren to have Ren ordered to be jailed and fined for his willful violations of the court's orders.
SCEI was previously reported to be one of the largest producers of clean energy fuel in China when it entered the US equity market via a reverse merger and its stock reached a high of $9.40 per share in April 2010.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bermuda targets US corporations with captive insurance webinar</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bermuda-targets-US-corporations-with-captive-insurance-webinar-26685.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bermuda targets US corporations with captive insurance webinar
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Rochelle Simons, of BCOA; Butch Agnew of Dyna Management Services; Joe DaSilveira of Liberty Mutual Management Bermuda and Leslie Robinson of the BMA
HAMILTON, Bermuda -- The Bermuda Business Development Agency (BDA) is teaming with industry partners to host a webinar next week spotlighting the advantages to US corporations of setting up a captive insurance company in Bermuda.
The hour-long webinar, to be broadcast on Tuesday, will highlight the regulatory, legal and tax issues as well as the substantial benefits of establishing a Bermuda captive -- including risk management, asset protection, and efficient access to the global reinsurance market via Bermuda-based companies.
"This is our second BDA webinar, following a successful debut we hosted earlier this year," said BDA business development manager Jereme Ramsay. "Our focus is US businesses that could benefit from setting up a Bermuda captive insurance company, including those in the growing healthcare sphere. We thank our industry colleagues for sharing their expertise to heighten the visibility of Bermuda's thriving captive insurance business."
The healthcare industry -- which will be the sole focus of a third BDA webinar in September -- is a growing sector in Bermuda's captive insurance field, driven by rapidly changing regulation and the need for coverage capacity. Bermuda captives and insurance carriers support a quarter of the US medical insurance and reinsurance market.
The BDA webinar guides registrants through the basics of what a captive is -- a vehicle to finance the risk of its owners -- as well as the captive regulation process and tax benefit details. Registrants will receive online access to the live webinar of speaker presentations followed by a question-and-answer session.
Featured speakers are: Rochelle Simons, of the Bermuda Captive Owners Association (BCOA), who will moderate the discussion; Butch Agnew, Vice President, Dyna Management Services Ltd.; Joe DaSilveira, Senior Vice President, Liberty Mutual Management (Bermuda) Ltd.; Leslie Robinson, Assistant Director, Corporate Authorisations for the Bermuda Monetary Authority; and William McCallum, Managing Director, Tax, at KPMG Bermuda.
"We have an excellent panel of experts lined up for this event," said Rochelle Simons, of the Bermuda Captive Owners Association (BCOA), who will moderate the discussion. "We intend for it to be informative and useful to any executives who may be considering setting up a captive insurance company, and offer details on why Bermuda can best suit their needs."

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European low-cost airline launches flights from US to the Caribbean</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-European-low-cost-airline-launches-flights-from-US-to-the-Caribbean-26686.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
European low-cost airline launches flights from US to the Caribbean
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
NEW YORK, USA -- Norwegian, deemed the worlds best low-cost long-haul airline and also Europes best low-cost airline for the past three consecutive years by SkyTrax, has announced it will launch flights from Boston, Baltimore/Washington, DC, and New York City to two beautiful and unspoiled Caribbean destinations: the Guadeloupe islands and Martinique.
Only two years after launching service to New Yorks John F. Kennedy International Airport (JFK), Norwegian will be the largest foreign airline at JFK in terms of number of routes. Norwegian will offer a total of seven nonstop routes to Bergen, Copenhagen, Guadeloupe, London, Martinique, Oslo and Stockholm. Overall, Norwegian will operate 31 routes from ten US airports.
With the new service, Norwegian will offer US-based customers some of the lowest fares to the Caribbean, with an introductory fare starting at $79 one way, valid from all three US airports and starting at $99 one way from Guadeloupe and Martinique in the French Caribbean, also known as the French West Indies.
Norwegians new seasonal service to the French West Indies will launch on December 3, 2015, with three flights per week from JFK to Guadeloupes Pointe--Pitre International Airport (PTP) on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays, and from JFK to Martiniques Aim Csaire International Airport (FDF) on Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays.
From Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport (BWI) and Boston Logan International Airport (BOS), Norwegian will operate twice weekly service to both Guadeloupe and Martinique. Flights between Baltimore-Washington and Guadeloupe will operate on Tuesdays and Saturdays, and Martinique on Mondays and Fridays. From Boston flights to Guadeloupe will operate on Thursdays and Sundays, and to Martinique on Wednesdays and Sundays.
Norwegian operates one of the worlds most modern and eco-friendly fleets. On the US-Caribbean routes, the airline will fly its new Boeing 737-800s with 186 comfortable, leather seats and it will be the first airline to offer free Wi-Fi on flights to the Caribbean. Norwegian will also offer customers the option to rent movies and TV shows on their personal devices.
The airline currently offers 25 nonstop routes from the US to London and Scandinavia, providing more European routes than any other European airline. Service from San Juan, Puerto Rico, will commence on November 1, 2015; and service from St Croix, USVI, will commence on November 5, 2015.
With these new and exciting routes, Norwegian will offer customers in the Northeast nonstop flights to two of the most idyllic islands in the Caribbean, said Norwegians CEO Bjrn Kjos. Norwegian is fully committed to the US market and we will continue to expand by offering more great nonstop destinations to American travelers and growing our US crew bases, said Kjos.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EarthTalk: Is there potential for kinetic energy to provide significant amounts of electricity?</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-EarthTalk%3A-Is-there-potential-for-kinetic-energy-to-provide-significant-amounts-of-electricity%3F-26687.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
EarthTalk: Is there potential for kinetic energy to provide significant amounts of electricity?
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Uncharted Play's Soccket soccer ball doubles as a kinetic energy power source for an integrated high-efficiency 3-LED lamp
Dear EarthTalk: I recently heard about a cafe in the Netherlands that harvests so-called kinetic energy from its revolving door to power its interior lights. Is there potential for kinetic energy to provide significant amounts of electricity to help replace fossil fuels?  Doug Mola, Boise, ID
Physicists define kinetic energy as the energy of motion (as opposed to potential energy, which represents an objects stored energy). While there is not much that is practical that we can do with potential energy, kinetic energy is another matter. We can capture energy from all sorts of everyday activities, and entrepreneurs around the world are working hard on ways to make kinetic energy more accessible.
But we may be decades from realizing any serious fossil fuel displacement from this age-old energy source, and by then other alternative energy sources may have already made coal, oil and natural gas things of the past.
While the cutting edge revolving door at Natuurcaf La Port in Beerschoten, Netherlands (about 30 miles southeast of Amsterdam) may be one of the best examples of repurposing the kinetic energy that humans generate through their movement into electricity to power their stuff -- the door connects the cafe to an adjoining train station and generates some 4600 kWh of electricity annually -- its far from the only one.
The Soccket is a soccer ball that was designed by Harvard undergraduates for a class project -- and since incorporated as the company Uncharted Play -- that harvests energy when it is kicked around and can then be used to power an included energy efficient 3-LED lamp that runs for up to three hours after just 20 minutes or so of soccer.
The more the ball rolls, the more power thats generated, reports Uncharted Play, which got the idea for the ball as a way to help eliminate the use of kerosene.
The company also makes the Pulse, a portable, emergency battery charging jump rope designed to promote physical activity and spread awareness about the global energy problem. While the Pulse is a jump rope just like any other, it is also a portable battery charger that can be powered up from a power outlet or even better from using it.
For every Soccket or Pulse purchased ($99/each), Uncharted Play donates one to a kid in a developing country who might not otherwise have access to electricity to provide a light to read at night.
Another innovative application of kinetic energy is from Pavegen, which produces floor tiles that absorb kinetic energy when people walk on them. The tiles are made with recycled materials and contain small LEDs that light up to show they are working.
Meanwhile, KinergyPower is applying the same principal to harnessing the kinetic energy from vehicles through designed road surfaces that turn vehicle motion into electricity.
But while kinetic energy shows lots of potential for helping transition away from fossil fuels, it may never become more than a novelty if we continue to focus our energy resources on other proven clean renewables like solar arrays and wind farms.
Regardless, get used to seeing more and more kinetic energy harvesting from flooring, sidewalks, soccer balls, jump ropes and who knows what else. Going through a revolving door never felt so good.
EarthTalk is produced by Doug Moss &amp; Roddy Scheer and is a registered trademark of Earth Action Network Inc. View past columns at: www.earthtalk.org . Or e-mail us your question: earthtalk@emagazine.com

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analysis: Cuban president summons Curacao's prime minister? Curubacao Part1</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Analysis%3A-Cuban-president-summons-Curacao%27s-prime-minister%3F-Curubacao-Part1-26688.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>josefina@caribbeannewsnow.com
WILLEMSTAD, Curacao -- Cuban President Raul Castro summons Curacao's Prime Minister Asjes?
This could be interpreted as a headline, depending on how much information was released from that four-man private meeting in Havana, Cuba, or that the general public is led to believe or understand.
In the atmosphere of dynamic interaction, macroeconomics and pico-politics, could PM Asjes have gone on an official visit to Cuba to support the Curacaleno soccer team? Or was he "unofficially" summoned by the former commander of the Cuban military? Or was it simply just something else?
On a macroscopic view by coincidence:
October 2014: Curacaleno student contacts Cuban embassy and ambassador about studying in Cuba. Cuban embassy and ambassador never responded
November 2014 (Curacao Chronicle): PM Asjes visits Washington, USA but unable to speak directly with President Barack Obama
February 2015 (Curacao Chronicle): Fermin Garbiel Quiones Snchez made an introductory visit to the Minister Plenipotentiary of Curacao in the Netherlands, Marvelyne Wiels
March 2015 (Reuters): USA declared Venezuela a national security threat and ordered sanctions against seven officials
March 2015: Cuba gives its unconditional support to Venezuela against USA
March 16, 2015: Cuban former president Fidel Castro Ruiz writes a letter glorifying the efforts of Venezuelan president on continuing the dream of sharing Venezuela's natural resources with the world [see Fidel Castro's letter to President Maduro]
March 2015 (Curacao Chronicle): PM Asjes summons Venezuela consul general, Marisol Gutierrez de Almeida, to cease and desist her actions to gather signatures and support from within the Curacao populace to possibly cause a rift in the US-Curacao foreign international diplomatic lines (policy programme)
Asjes stated that Curacaos neutrality in the diplomatic conflict between Venezuela and the US and that the friendly relationship with both countries shall not be put in jeopardy.
April 2015 (Curacao Chronicle): President Obama said that the nations must get rid of all disputes and added that he has asked the US Congress to lift the economic, commercial and financial embargo of Cuba. The US president said, "If the US-Cuba bilateral dialogue keeps advancing, there will be progress despite deep differences," furthermore he noted that this change in US policy represents an inflection point towards the whole region, and that this change is accompanied by a compromise with the Americas
Early June 2015 (personal Facebook page): MP Sulvaran [PAR] posted that there is a change in the air, but it would not be by his hands... indicating that the coalition government is being stressed to breaking point
Mid June 2015 (Curacao Chronicle): Minister Nelson Navarro [PAIS] speaks on justice, national security legislative concerns and the debate on CCTV implementation and that the coalition government is at a melting point and could vaporize at any point or time, leading to a change of the guards at Curacao's political borders
*Sources say that the communist controlled paradise of Raul Castro, brother of Fidel Castro Ruiz, is governed by CCTV at just about every main street, which have high definition cameras for surveillance atop of numerous roofs. But sources also point out that Amnesty International has constantly raised the argument of the human rights and rights to privacy of the Cuban people. This maybe something that not too many Curacalenos will appreciate having their privacy invaded.
Gerrit Schotte has been in the news for travelling to Venezuela to attend former leader Hugo Chavezs funeral on supposedly diplomatic status in 2013.
ALBA (the Bolivarian Alliance for the Peoples of Our America) was formed in 2004 initially by Cuba and Venezuela as an intergovernmental organization based on the idea of the social, political and economic integration of the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean.
PetroCaribe was formed in 2005 and in 2013 formed an alliance with ALBA.
Oil prices continued to go down with possible effects shimmering on the Venezuelan economy becoming evident. Based on a simple economic view that: (1) Low Supply + High Demand = High Prices; and (2) High Supply + Low Demand = Low Prices. In addition, from financial budgeting, we know that to control the purse or the economy of a country is to control the country. Interesting point: Netherlands has the financial control of the autonomous island of Curacao.
There is probably no doubt that an economic overview study of Curacao had already been in place before the Havana visit of the PM and the finance minister of Curacao, thinking about the coalition government which, if the pressure point is correct, may side with one or the other, therefore shifting the balance of power in favour of a "favour for a favour".
Less than three weeks ago there was a green residue, purportedly a carcinogenic substance, covering the outside fixtures and homes of the people in the Isla oil refinery area of Curacao. This substance is presumably from the "lesser" quality oil being refined supplied by the PDVSA from the Venezuelan oil fields to the Curacao refinery. This may then sound like a "non-favour for a non-favour", or better yet put, "if you don't support us, suffer economic hikes and not the benefits but the consequences" mentality.
But while there is the talk about the green residue, which some report as probably a transitional /heavy metal-based compound, in the Wishi Marchena area, no one has stopped to think about that substance falling on the ground and seeping into the underground water supply or that of Aqualectra, not to mention how much rain has fallen since the start of the hurricane season.
How many persons in Curacao felt that their water had a more metallic-like taste some weeks ago?
What is more interesting is what are the short term and long term effects of this exposure to the people of that area and of course to the people of Curacao?
What is the fertility rate of the women whom have lived in that area?
What has been the average birth rate and weight, the morbidity rate, spontaneous abortion rate, the incidence and prevalence of cancer, testicular cancer, liver disorders and kidney disorders and diabetes for the persons in that area and the island wide?
On reflection, as we consider the events that are developing before us today, MP Constancia of the opposition MFK is being brought before the courts and then, in September, former PM and MFK MP, Gerrit Schottes day in court will undoubtedly squash any possibility of an ouster or vote of no confidence in PM Asjes.
How quickly the tides change when the magical trip to Cuba and the Castro brothers magical land of "free" doctors, communist health care and socialist health tourism, always come at a heavy price. In the spiritual realm, "magic" that powerful always comes with a heavy price load.
Lets just look at so much coincidence that transpired. The former minister of public health Constancia was brought up on charges that stem from transactions apparently mainly of Venezuelan origination. How quickly the tides change when we seek to hide and deceive. That was a trump card that was being held close to probably Cuba's financial auditors in communication with the Venezuelan sources.
The old proverb of what is done in the darkness will come to light seems so appropriate. Its just a matter of time.
Please go back and read above that there are two countries that share one of the closest Latin American relationships, even the Bolivian president once studied in Cuba. Former president Hugo Chavez's charge to recapture the presidency after the coup attack is even reminiscent of what happened to his mentor, Fidel Castro, in which he purged his cabinet of those that threatened his life and vision of a better Cuba and better world.
Could you have imagined all of this just from the economic control of the oil economy in Curacao, which has a GDP of 3 billion dollars and a debt of approximately 1 billion dollars, 10.3% unemployment rate (2008 estimates) and our largest import partner is Venezuela at 57.13%.
Cuba's relationship with Venezuela, whose population is about 30.41 million, is well documented and Fidel Castro himself has tooted the horn of the Venezuelan army being one of the best trained in the Caribbean, ready and willing to sacrifice their last drop of blood. Cuba has supplied Bolivia and Venezuela with medical human resources and with St Elisabeth Hospital Curacao (SEHOS) and the new SEHOS director, chances are that Cuba's 12 million populace and graduating medical class of 10,000 medical professionals could be added benefits to convince any small country that "one hand scratches the other".

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: UN peacekeepers preying on helpless Haitians? Yes</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-UN-peacekeepers-preying-on-helpless-Haitians%3F-Yes-26689.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: UN peacekeepers preying on helpless Haitians? Yes
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Anthony L Hall
There have been many reports over the years on peacekeepers standing by and watching warring factions kill each other  as they did, to the UNs eternal shame, in Rwanda.
Anthony L. Hall is a Bahamian who descends from the Turks and Caicos Islands. He is an international lawyer and political consultant - headquartered in Washington DC - who also publishes a current events weblog, The iPINIONS Journal, at http://ipjn.com
There have not been nearly as many reports, however, on peacekeepers exacerbating the scourge of civil strife by preying on people who depend on them for protection.
This is why it might surprise you to learn that UN peacekeepers have a reputation for preying on helpless girls that rivals the reputation Catholic priests have for preying on little boys. More to the point, the United Nations has shown even less interest in protecting helpless girls from predatory peacekeepers than the Catholic Church has shown in protecting little boys from predatory priests.
In fact, I was so dismayed by the UNs betrayal of trust in this respect that I wrote The United Nations: Corrupt from Head to Toe? June 17, 2005, which begins as follows:

The leadership of UN Secretary General Kofi Annan was severely compromised earlier this year, when reports revealed that he did little to prevent UN foot soldiers from inflicting widespread abuses upon those they were deployed to protect. That many of these abuses occurred in refugee camps in Africa, where rape and molestation rivaled the horrors of war and starvation these refugees were trying to escape, made his failure all the more shameful.
Folks, that was ten years ago this week. Therefore, it speaks volumes that the UN has allowed peacekeepers to continue their predatory exploits with impunity  as a June 11 report in the Washington Post makes patently clear:
The UNs Office of Internal Oversight Services -- a UN watchdog within the UN -- said members of a peacekeeping mission had transactional sex with more than 225 Haitian women. The women traded sex for basic needs, including food and medication.
For rural women, hunger, lack of shelter, baby care items, medication and household items were frequently cited as the triggering need, the report said. In exchange for sex, women got church shoes, cell phones, laptops and perfume, as well as money from peacekeepers.
Women in Haiti sometimes protested when peacekeepers who said they would pay for sex did not, but most were unaware the United Nations prohibited sexual exploitation and has a hotline to report it.
Given this report and my analogy to priests above, I feel obliged to clarify that these peacekeepers target little boys too. Reports in early 2012 on the contingent of Pakistani peacekeepers who raped a mentally disabled 14-year-old Haitian boy in Gonaives threw this into stark relief. And, yes, the UN shielded them with its blanket of immunity
Meanwhile, I fear the UNs Internal Oversight Services (with its Orwellian name) will have cause to draft a report about peacekeepers perpetrating similar abuses on some other peacekeeping mission ten years from now.
But Im all too mindful that my feelings of frustration and fecklessness pale in comparison to the feelings of desperation and hopelessness victims of these abuses must suffer. Therefore, before I wax too indignant, I shall end by confessing that, despite my informed cynicism, even I was shocked in one respect by this UN report.
I have always felt (and in fact wrote in Haitis Living Nightmare Continues, March 7, 2005) that Haiti looms amidst the islands of the Caribbean, just as Africa does amidst the continents of the world: as a dark, destitute, diseased, desperate, disenfranchised, dishonest, disorganized, disassociated, dangerous and, ultimately, dysfunctional mess. Therefore, I was hardly surprised in 2004, when the UN launched its mission:
to restore a secure and stable environment, to promote the political process, to strengthen Haitis Government institutions and rule-of-law-structures, as well as to promote and to protect human rights.
(United Nations.org/peacekeeping/missions/minustah)
But I never imagined peacekeepers would dare perpetrate the kinds of abuses they got away with in distant Africa so close to home (i.e., UN headquarters in New York City), especially with reporters foraging all over Haiti looking for stories in the aftermath of the 2010 earthquake. Yet, dare they did
Haitians have become a migration menace throughout the Caribbean for some of the same understandable reasons Africans have throughout Europe. Fear of UN peacekeepers raping them, however, should not be one of those reasons.
In any event, this Post report is only the latest indication that my abiding prayers for the godforsaken people of Haiti are all in vain.
Related commentaries:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: The Commonwealth's future - Part 1</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-The-Commonwealth%27s-future---Part-1-26690.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: The Commonwealth's future - Part 1
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Sir Ronald Sanders
Questioning the relevance and value of the Commonwealth of Nations is nothing new  for such has occurred ever since the modern Commonwealth was created in 1949. However, doubts have intensified in recent time about the voluntary association of now 53 countries. Claims are repeatedly made that the organisation is no longer relevant or useful. Its persistent portrayal is that of a relic of Britains colonial past or a hypocritical grouping that declares commitments to shared values but fails to uphold them.
Sir Ronald Sanders is a Senior Fellow at the Institute of Commonwealth Studies, University of London and at Massey College, University of Toronto. He is also a candidate for the post of Commonwealth Secretary-General. Reponses to:
www.sirronaldsanders.com
The Commonwealth is now, once again, at a crossroads. Its member states can allow it to continue a slow march to oblivion, or they can rejuvenate and re-energise it to make it work in their mutual interest and for the benefit of the global community. While the heads of Commonwealth governments are at the centre of these options, the organisations secretary-general and the Secretariat have very special roles.
Heads of government are busy managing the affairs of their own countries, and responding to pressing challenges within their regions and internationally. Therefore, the task of creating a vision and purposes for the Commonwealth that would appeal to leaders of the Commonwealth and invoke their support falls substantially on the secretary-general.
If the secretary-general does not proffer a vision of the Commonwealth that is politically appealing to, and motivational for heads of government, and if the Secretariat does not deliver work that excites the imagination of governments, non-governmental organisations, the media, academia and the people of Commonwealth countries, the association could wither and die.
For Britain, the single largest contributor to the budget of the Commonwealth Secretariat and its technical assistance arm, the Commonwealth Fund for Technical Co-operation (CFTC), the Commonwealth will have to find a broader base of relevance  other than an association of Britain and its former colonies  to sustain commitment.
As for its former dominion members  Canada, Australia, New Zealand and India  the Commonwealth, as it now stands, holds little attraction for advancing their interests in todays major issues  such as increasing trade, enhancing security, safeguarding against terrorism, and managing the challenges of climate change.
Largely, this is because, apart from climate change, the Commonwealth has not taken on these issues  not even as a facilitator of inter-governmental discussion and a catalyst for international initiatives. Even on climate change, the effort made to focus attention at the 2009 Summit in Trinidad and Tobago has not been followed-up in ways that stimulated governments to see the Commonwealth as a beneficial forum.
The governments of bigger developing Commonwealth countries in Africa and Asia are also struggling to find meaning for their priorities in the work of the Commonwealth. With the exceptions of South Africa and India, they continue to be sidelined in the major economic and financial decision-making bodies of the world and they have had to engage non-Commonwealth countries, such as China, to progress their development agendas.
The small member states of the Commonwealth  now numbering 31 and defined as having populations of 1.5 million or less  increasingly question the attentiveness of larger Commonwealth countries to their severe challenges. Low attendance by heads of government and ministers of the big Commonwealth countries at meetings creates misgivings in the minds of leaders of small states about the usefulness of the Commonwealth as a mechanism for addressing their concerns.
Small states are at a critical juncture in their history. Increasingly, they are marginalised in the international community. Both large developed countries and international financial institutions behave as if small nations are not only irrelevant, they are a nuisance. Hence the concerns of small states are either ignored or barely tolerated.
Development assistance is drying-up; terms of trade are worsening; access to concessional financing has virtually disappeared. This is occurring at a time when climate change and sea level rise are threatening the existence of some small states and materially affecting the economic life of others. In these circumstances, it is urgent that the causes of small states be advocated strongly and effectively in the Commonwealth and the wider international community.
The Commonwealth Secretariat must, therefore, become machinery for such strong and effective advocacy. For the Secretariat to do so, the secretary-general must be someone who has fought in the diplomatic and negotiating front line for small states and who has not only the sensitivity to their plight, but the knowledge of their circumstances born of experience.
The Commonwealth is the most important of all multilateral organisations for small states because it is the only forum which provides the opportunity for leaders of small states to meet regularly (and as equals) with leaders of larger and more powerful countries.
No other organisation provides the chance for the head of government of small Caribbean states, for instance, to meet the head of government of Britain, Australia, India and South Africa as an equal to discuss frankly and openly his/her countrys challenges and opportunities.
That is why small states cannot allow the Commonwealth to wither and die. Small states need the Commonwealth to be vibrant and effective so that it can advance their interests.
In recent years, an increasing focus by Australia, Britain and Canada (ABC) on democracy, human rights and the rule of law in Commonwealth countries, has led to a widening division within the organisation. The argument is raised continuously by representatives of developing countries that the ABCs emphasis on these matters is at the expense of economic development upon which the governments of developing countries place high importance. While this perception is mistaken, there have been inadequate efforts to demonstrate that the great portion of resources is indeed spent on development.
These fractious and divisive conditions have arisen from years of neglect in which the Commonwealth could have been reformed and inspired by its leadership. Its slide away from its fundamental purposes should have been arrested and new ways created to maintain its collegiality. The absence of vibrant initiatives to keep heads of government fully engaged in preserving and strengthening the association has led to the inertia and lack of enthusiasm in which it now languishes.
(The Commonwealth  Part 2 will deal with the role of the Commonwealth and the Secretary-General)
 Copyright to this article is held by Sir Ronald Sanders and its reproduction or republication by any media or transmission by radio or television without his prior written permission is an infringement of the law. Republished with permission.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: People of SVG, say NO to the Dominican Republic participation in Miss Carival 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-People-of-SVG%2C-say-NO-to-the-Dominican-Republic-participation-in-Miss-Carival-2015-26691.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: People of SVG, say NO to the Dominican Republic participation in Miss Carival 2015
Published onJune 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
I am making an appeal to prime minister of St Vincent and the Grenadines, Dr Ralph Gonsalves to withdraw the invitation from the Dominican Republic contestant, Ms Lesley Bell Troncoso Rijo, who is slated to participate in the Miss Carival competition to be held in St Vincent and the Grenadines on Friday, July 3, 2015.
The government and people of St Vincent and the Grenadines should not promote a country as the Dominican Republic, which by a decision of the Supreme Court stripped our black brothers and sisters of Haitian descent who were born in the Dominican Republic their right to citizenship in the Dominican Republic.
What the government of the Dominican Republic is doing amounts to "a crime against humanity, which is obviously based on racism. How could women and children be sent out of a country where they were born without their belongings, and with no place to live in Haiti, where they don't know anyone? This is an act of evil and should be condemned by everyone in our "Caribbean civilization".
St Vincent and the Grenadines and the Dominican Republic are members of the Community of Latin American Caribbean States (CELAC), a regional organization that aims to unite, strengthen and promote the interests of Latin America and Caribbean States. Dr Gonslaves recently attended a EU/CELAC meeting where, among other things, the mass deportation of people of Haitian descent was discussed, and he said, "A lot of people ask me, 'Why are you, Ralph, so strong on this matter? I say, 'I am strong on this in the same way that I am strong on other things," and he gave examples of reparation for native genocide and slavery and the further enoblement of the Caribbean civilization.
Dr Gonsalves also said at the EU/CELAC meeting, "It is unacceptable to have a public policy in relation to citizenship, grounded in ethnicity or your national origins... He went on to say, "Persons of Haitian descent born in the Dominican Republic, they are denied citizenship and they are denied citizenship on ethnic grounds or grounds of national origins."
The reason why I am making this appeal to Dr Gonsalves is because he said, "These persons don't have anybody to talk for them so I have to be their voice." He also said, "I have to do it because I know Jesus would have done it."
Dr Gonsalves, I am begging you on behalf of Vincentians and the people of our Caribbean civilization, lead the way by saying to the Dominican Republic it cannot participate in our festivities and be a part of our Caribbean civilization until it does the right thing by stopping this mass deportation of our brothers and sisters to Haiti.
Amory Lashley
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Offended</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Offended-26692.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
I am moved to pen a few words following your publication of a letter by one Helen Grenade a couple days ago.
I read your news site each day to keep abreast of what's happening in the region and I'm aware that you have a disclaimer on the site.
However, sometimes you need to be more responsible. I am neither interested in the body parts nor alleged sexual leanings of Mr Derrick James' wife. That letter is downright "unprofessional", extremely nasty and reflects the nature of its author and the individual(s) manning the site's content.
I am deeply offended as I am not only selective about what I read but never personally disrespectful with others on a professional level.
If this is what caribbeannewsnow offers to readers I will prefer to use my choice of getting worthy news and opinions elsewhere.
Cyrilla R. Steele
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murders up 16 percent in Bahamas</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Murders-up-16-percent-in-Bahamas-26665.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Murders up 16 percent in Bahamas
Published onJune 25, 2015
By Royston Jones Jr.
Nassau Guardian Staff Reporter
NASSAU, Bahamas -- Murders in The Bahamas increased by 16 percent between January 1 and June 22, 2015, compared to the same period in 2014.
There were 72 murders recorded during this period compared to the 62 murders recorded last year.
There were ten murders in January, 15 in February, 12 in March, 11 in April, 15 in May and nine this month.
The most recent victim, who was out on bail on a murder charge and being electronically monitored, was shot dead on Sunday night, police said.
Yesterday, police classified the death of a woman, who was struck by a vehicle outside a bar she worked at on Saturday, as a murder.
National Security Minister Dr Bernard Nottage
National Security Minister Dr Bernard Nottage was expected to speak about crime trends and the governments crime fighting efforts during the budget debate.
But he never spoke, as the government aborted the debate early last Wednesday.
What the minister did say about crime on June 10 in response to Montagu MP Richard Lightbourn, who said the murder rate today is worse than it ever was, caused controversy.
Nottage, who rose on a point of order, said, The murder rate today is no worse; in fact, less than it was in 2011, their last year in office.
But police data showed that the murder count was 17 percent higher that it was in 2011.
The murder count when Nottage made the statement was 68.
Up to June 10, 2011, the murder count stood at 58.
Nottage did admit that the murder count is higher than it was in 2014.
He has not since made a public address about crime or the governments efforts to reduce crime.
On June 4, Prime Minister Perry Christie pointed to some discord between the Royal Bahamas Police Force and Defence Force when he spoke about crime at the Caribbean-US High-Level Citizen Security Dialogue.
Six months ago, Christie said he has confidence in the police force and its efforts in combatting crime.
While Commissioner of Police Ellison Greenslade said earlier this month that serious crimes with the exception of murder are down, he admitted that the public does not want to hear that.
He said murders continue to challenge the police and called on all stakeholders, and the wider public to do more in the fight against crime.
Republished with permission of the Nassau Guardian

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Warner's latest antics trigger defamation claim</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Warner%27s-latest-antics-trigger-defamation-claim-26664.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Warner's latest antics trigger defamation claim
Published onJune 25, 2015
Former FIFA vice president Jack Warner
By Caribbean News Now contributor
PORT OF SPAIN, Trinidad -- A combination of false statements by disgraced former FIFA vice president Jack Warner and blind acceptance on the part of a Trinidad journalist that what Warner had said was true has resulted in the issue of a letter before action to the head of news at local television station CCN TV6.
The letter was written by attorney Ravi Rajcoomar to CCN TV6's head of news Dominic Kallipersad on Tuesday afternoon on behalf of Jitnarine Hardeen, who was the subject of an in-depth news report entitled The Hardeen Expos by CCN TV6 journalist Mark Bassant, which aired on Monday during the stations 7pm newscast.
According to the attorney, Hardeen is not featured on a voice recording released to the media by Warner and the CCN TV6 report had "improperly, wrongfully and/or illegally named him and/or referred to him being the source of information on a purported audio recording held by Mr Jack Warner MP."
It continued: "My client has listened to your broadcast and instructs us that he is not the person on the tape as alleged by you, your reporters and Mr Warner, MP. In fact, he has no knowledge of the matters that were aired on your station and ascribed to him.
"My client further instructs me that he has no knowledge of its contents. My client is of the view that the tape is malicious and false, and Mr Warner, MP is well aware that the tape is false untrue and that the person on the tape is not him."
CCN TV6 has been required to respond within 28 days, failing which proceedings may be commenced in the High Court.
TV6 is owned by Caribbean Communications Network Ltd (CCN), publishers of the Trinidad Express newspaper, which in turn is a subsidiary of ONE Caribbean Media Limited (OCM), chaired by prominent Barbados attorney Sir Fred Gollop and run by CEO Dawn Thomas.
ONE Caribbean Media Limited chairman Sir Fred Gollop (L) and CEO Dawn Thomas
Warner seems to be determined to cause problems for OCM, since the Trinidad Express reported that a director of its ultimate parent company is the owner of a Trinidad-based business that laundered money through illegal currency trades for Warner, who is one of 14 senior FIFA officials and others indicted in New York on multiple counts of racketeering, corruption and money laundering.
According to the indictment, Warner used almost half of a US$10 million bribe he is alleged to have received from South Africa to promote its successful bid to host the 2010 World Cup in black market currency trades through JTA Supermarkets in Trinidad.
The funds in question were paid from FIFA accounts into Confederation of North, Central American and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF) accounts in Trinidad controlled by Warner.
OCM Director Carl Mack
JTA Supermarkets subsequently received $4,860,000 from the CONCACAF accounts, paid in installments from January 2008 to March 2009. The largest payment was $1,350,000 paid in February 2008.
According to US prosecutors, the money was mostly paid back to Warner in local currency. How the remaining money was disbursed is currently unknown.
Carl Mack, owner and executive chairman of the JTA Group, is also a director of OCM. Mack has denied any knowledge of the substantial transactions passing through his business, apparently in contravention of local exchange control laws.
OCM and CCN management have consistently declined to respond to requests for comment on these and other issues.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exploration to continue in Guyana's exclusive economic zone, says president</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Exploration-to-continue-in-Guyana%27s-exclusive-economic-zone%2C-says-president-26666.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Exploration to continue in Guyana's exclusive economic zone, says president
Published onJune 25, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
GEORGETOWN, Guyana (GINA) -- President David Granger has assured US oil company Exxon Mobil that it has nothing to fear in terms of its current operations in Guyanas waters, as the company has the backing of the Guyana government and international law as it continues exploration in Guyanas exclusive economic zone.
President David Granger
In a recent interview, the head of state said that he met with officials from the exploration company and assured them that ExxonMobil has nothing to fear in terms of the present operations in Guyanas waters.
In the interim, Granger said the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) has been notified, and he is confident that the Secretary General Irwin LaRocque has provided some information to the heads of government.
However, the president noted that CARICOM heads would be formally briefed on the situation at the upcoming 36th heads of government meeting, which is slated for July 1 to 5 in Barbados. The president will be heading a delegation for that meeting. In addition, all the countries of the Organisation of America States (OAS) and Union of South American Nations (UNASUR) have already been notified of Venezuelas claim.
Meanwhile, the president, in response to Venezuelas claim, described it as a legal absurdity, stating that it is the worst intrusion on Guyanas sovereignty.
It is an affront to the nation and it collides with internal maritime law; it is completely in breach of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea, Granger said.
Venezuelas President Nicholas Maduro issued a decree on May 25, claiming sovereignty over Guyanas territorial waters in the Essequibo region of the Atlantic Ocean.
Maps created after the decree by Venezuelas National Organisation for Rescue and Maritime Safety (ONSA), indicate that the claim would include a large part of the Stabroek Block, where ExxonMobil discovered oil recently.
ExxonMobil, on May 20 disclosed that it found a deposit of a 'significant' amount of oil in the Stabroek Block, about 120 nautical miles offshore Guyana. The company said this discovery was made in one of the two wells it dug, in the Liza-1 drill site, which realised more than 295 feet of high-quality oil-bearing sandstone.
ExxonMobil, the largest public trading international company in the world, is an industry that is the leading inventory of oil and gas projects, and the worlds largest refiner of petroleum products.
The total area allotted to Exxon for exploration (the Liza Area or the Stabroek Block) covers 26,806 square kilometers. It has a long history of using science and innovation to find safer and cleaner ways of bringing energy to the world.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Antigua-Barbuda PM calls on EU Commission to apologize and withdraw tax haven list</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Antigua-Barbuda-PM-calls-on-EU-Commission-to-apologize-and-withdraw-tax-haven-list-26667.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Antigua-Barbuda PM calls on EU Commission to apologize and withdraw tax haven list
Published onJune 25, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
ST JOHNS, Antigua -- In a strongly worded letter to Ambassador Mikael Barford, head of the Delegation of the European Union to Barbados and the Eastern Caribbean, Prime Minister Gaston Browne has documented his governments impassioned objection to Antigua and Barbuda being named by the European Commission as a tax haven in a list published on June 17.
Prime Minister Gaston Browne
Calling the inclusion on the list unjust, Browne said that his government totally objects to the implication by Pierre Moscovici, the EU Commissioner for Economic and Financial Affairs, Taxation and Customs, that Antigua and Barbuda is a non-cooperative jurisdiction. The countrys leader further stated that the EU Commission and Moscovici have done considerable harm to Antigua and Barbuda and many other countries named on the list in flagrant disregard of known facts about the jurisdictions.
In the case of Antigua and Barbuda, the jurisdiction has been found to be in compliance with the highest international standards of transparency and exchange of information as set by the Global Forum of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) of which EU countries are members. Indeed, since the publication of the EU list, the OECD Global Forum has disassociated itself from the action of the EU and underscored the fact that it is their assessment which is the relevant assessment for the purposes of determining a countrys cooperation in tax matters, Brownes letter read.
It was also made clear that Antigua and Barbuda has been found to be fully compliant and cooperative with international standards established by the Financial Action Task Force on whose decision-making councils EU countries sit. The letter also pointed to the fact that Antigua and Barbuda has signed tax information exchange agreements with a significant number of EU members and that no request for information by an EU member state has ever been declined.
In the circumstances, my government regards the criteria by which Antigua and Barbuda has been named on the EU list of tax havens as fatally flawed, Browne outlined in his letter.
According to the EU Commission, Antigua and Barbuda was included on its arbitrary list because ten EU members named the jurisdiction as non- cooperative. The ten EU countries have been identified as: Bulgaria, Croatia, Estonia, Greece, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Portugal and Spain.
These are countries with which Antigua and Barbuda does little or no business. Antigua and Barbuda has not received any requests for information from these ten countries that it has refused. It is also significant that the EU countries, such as Britain and France, with which Antigua and Barbuda does significant transactions, did not name our jurisdiction, Browne pointed out.
The countrys leader, while asking for his governments objection to be made to the EU Commission by the swiftest means, said, In damaging the reputation of Antigua and Barbuda  and many other Caribbean countries that appear on the extremely defective list  the EU Commission may well have infringed the terms of the Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) between the EU and Caribbean countries.
In registering his governments strongest objection to the EU list, Browne called on the EU Commission to apologize for the damage it has done to the jurisdiction of Antigua and Barbuda and to publicly rescind the flawed and injurious list.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bahamas demands retraction of EU tax blacklist</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bahamas-demands-retraction-of-EU-tax-blacklist-26668.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bahamas demands retraction of EU tax blacklist
Published onJune 25, 2015
By K. Quincy Parker
Nassau Guardian Business Editor
NASSAU, Bahamas -- Minister of Financial Services Hope Strachan has confirmed that the government is moving to have The Bahamas removed from a new European Union (EU) tax blacklist.
Minister of Financial Services Hope Strachan
The minister told Guardian Business on Tuuesday that The Bahamas has demonstrated its overall dedication to ending cross-border tax evasion by its implementation of the US Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) and by pledging to facilitate the automatic exchange of information (AEOI) under the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Developments (OECD) Common Reporting Standard (CRS), beginning in 2018.
We are a jurisdiction that is considered a leader when it comes to compliance, represented by a professional compliance body supported by the Bahamas government, Strachan said.
It is unfortunate that during a time when global taxation initiatives are progressively underway and many Caribbean nations listed have made great strides using large financial and human resources to comply, the EU published a blacklist that compromises that progress. The list published by the EU should be retracted immediately, as it is unfounded, procedurally unfair and insults the progress made by the OECD on international tax initiatives of which many of the countries listed are a part.
The Bahamas has already begun communications with the OECD and the EU and will continue to press this issue as we join with other nations in the Caribbean to resolve this matter.
Strachan noted that the 12 EU countries responsible for naming The Bahamas are Belgium, Bulgaria, Croatia, Estonia, Greece, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Portugal, Slovenia and Spain.
She said it was uncanny, given that The Bahamas does very little to no business with these countries with the exception of Italy and Spain, with whom The Bahamas signed tax information exchange agreements (TIEA) with in March of 2010.
Meanwhile, the director of the OECDs Centre for Tax Policy and Administration (CTPA), and the head of the Secretariat of the Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes  reacting to the new blacklist  have jointly asserted that the only agreeable assessment of countries as regards their cooperation is made by the Global Forum and a number of countries identified in the EU exercise are either fully or largely compliant and have committed to AEOI, sometimes even as early adopters.
Strachan, who spent the day behind closed doors in Cabinet meetings on Tuesday, promised a more complete response in due course, but assured Guardian Business that the governments intention is to ensure that The Bahamas is removed from the list.
The Bahamas is among those countries that have  as the OECD notes  automatic exchange of information. The standard for automatic exchange of financial account information in tax matters was presented by the OECD to the G20 finance ministers in 2013. It provides for exchange of all financial information on an annual basis, automatically.
Fifty-one jurisdictions signed the multilateral competent authority agreement that will activate automatic exchange of information, based on the Multilateral Convention on Mutual Administrative Assistance in Tax Matters. Others, including The Bahamas, have chosen to adopt the standard for automatic exchange of financial account information in tax matters without adopting the convention, preferring instead to implement exchange of information on a strictly bilateral basis, similar to the FATCA intergovernmental agreement.
The Bahamas has agreed to implement the standard by 2018.
The Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes has been the multilateral framework within which work in the area of transparency and exchange of information has been carried out by both OECD and non-OECD economies since 2000.
The forum lists The Bahamas as largely compliant overall, with specific ratings for availability of information, access to information and exchange of information.
In an open letter to Global Forum members, CTPA director Pascal Saint-Amans and Global Forum head Monica Bhatia assured members that they had already expressed concerns  presumably to the EU Commission, which released the list  and said they stand ready to further clarify the position of the affected jurisdictions with regard to their compliance with the Global Forums standards.
On June 17, the EU Commission released the comprehensive Action Plan for Fair and Efficient Corporate Taxation in the EU. The plan includes five key areas for action, including item four, Further Progress on Tax Transparency.
As an immediate first step as part of this item, Saint-Amans and Bhatia noted that the commission has released what is essentially a compilation of a pan-EU list of third country, non-cooperative tax jurisdictions, which is based on member states' independent national lists.
In their background document, the EU has indicated that they have not decided which countries should be listed; rather it is relaying decisions taken at a national level by their members. It is very unfortunate that this exercise has looked like the establishment of a list. Our EU colleagues have confirmed that this is not their intent, Saint-Amans and Bhatia said.
Both the Bahamas Financial Services Board (BFSB) and Strachan expressed disappointment that The Bahamas is on the EU list, despite a raft of tax information exchange agreements (TIEAs), the signing of an intergovernmental agreement (IGA) with the US on implementation of the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (FATCA) and the decision by The Bahamas to adopt the standard as outlined above.
The OECD points out that the EU list is made up of jurisdictions that appear on at least ten EU member states national blacklists. Some information is provided as to what factors go into making the national blacklists  they include compliance with transparency and exchange of information standards; absence of harmful tax measures, other criterion.
Still, Saint-Amans and Bhatia insist that the EU Commission has incorporated the Global Forums terms of reference into its principles of good governance in tax matters and so supports a clear link between compliance with the Global Forum standard and inclusion on a national blacklist.
However, it is not clear how this aspect is factored into either the national blacklists or the ECs list. In addition, the inclusion of harmful tax practices or other criterion in determining inclusion in a national blacklist makes it impossible to determine how this independently reflects on a jurisdictions compliance with the Global Forum standards.
As the OECD and the Global Forum we would like to confirm that the only agreeable assessment of countries as regards their cooperation is made by the Global Forum and that a number of countries identified in the EU exercise are either fully or largely compliant and have committed to AEOI, sometimes even as early adopters.
Without prejudice to countries' sovereign positions, we are happy to confirm that these jurisdictions are cooperative and we would like to commend the tremendous progress made over the past years as well as the cooperation and integrity of the Global Forum process, the OECD says.
Reacting to the publication of such a list  and the inclusion of The Bahamas on it  BFSB CEO Aliya Allen said, Given the full cooperation of many countries like The Bahamas on tax transparency it is highly disappointing that these types of blacklists exist today. The Bahamas has moved, in line with the rest of the world, to adopt the OECD Standard on the Automatic Exchange of Information.
The Bahamas is white-listed by the OECD and its 4th round mutual evaluation indicated that it was either wholly compliant or largely compliant with the criteria on tax information exchange.
We believe this type of a consolidated list means nothing if it fails to take into account the assessments of the true standards setting bodies. A consolidation of countries blacklists says nothing of the reasonableness of the criteria involved in creating them."
Republished with permission of the Nassau Guardian

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Curacao minister's detention extended</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Former-Curacao-minister%27s-detention-extended-26669.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Former Curacao minister's detention extended
Published onJune 25, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Jacintha Constancia
WILLEMSTAD, Curacao -- Former minister of public health and member of parliament for the opposition party MFK, Jacintha Constancia, will remain behind bars in Curacao pending the investigation into the so-called Dubnium case.
Her detention has been extended by eight days, the Public Prosecutor reported.
The magistrate will probably rule on Thursday if the detention is lawful. After eight days, the magistrate must decide whether a defendant should be held longer.
The former minister is accused of fraud, misappropriation of public funds, money laundering and forgery. She was arrested last Monday by order of the Public Prosecution.
The Dubnium case is the investigation into the Foundation for Medical Services Agency, which placed an order in 2012 for 40,000 facemasks. Some 365,000 guilders (US$204,900) were paid for these masks that were actually worth only US$4,000, but the products were never delivered.
Republished with permission of the Curacao Chronicle

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CDF funds renewable energy project in St Lucia</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-CDF-funds-renewable-energy-project-in-St-Lucia-26670.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
CDF funds renewable energy project in St Lucia
Published onJune 25, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Prime Minister of St Lucia, Dr Kenny Anthony (right) with CDF's CEO, Lorne McDonnough, at the signing ceremony
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- The government of Saint Lucia has signed a grant agreement with the CARICOM Development Fund (CDF) for funding of the St Lucia National Trust (SLNT) renewable energy project in the sum of 71,749 Euros.
The agreement was signed by prime minister, Dr Kenny Anthony, and Lorne McDonough, chief executive officer of the CDF and the fund will provide lighting solutions for the Pigeon Island National Park, in keeping with one of the CDFs principal themes  environmental preservation.
The lighting solutions were designed to run strictly on Solar PV modules backed up by 12/24VDC battery banks. The use of solar lighting was initiated by the SLNT and the funding would contribute to the expansion of the use of PV lighting.
At the signing ceremony, McDonough announced his departure from the post of CEO of the CDF at the end of the month and thanked the prime minister and the government of Saint Lucia for their support over the years during his tenure as head of the CDF.
I am especially pleased to sign this agreement as it reflects the philosophy of the CDF to tenaciously wrestle a problem until a solution within the rules and consistent with good governance practices is found. I am optimistic about this facility for the SLNT.
This along with other agreements signed between the government of Saint Lucia and the CDF for projects totaling EC$16.43 million or US$6.09 million (EC$1=US$2.70) means that in total the government of Saint Lucia, with a contribution of US$2.4 million, was able to obtain for projects it prioritized, an additional US$2.54 for every US$1.00 contributed making good the promise of returning to disadvantaged countries interest free all of their contributions and then some.
Anthony thanked McDonough for his leadership at the CDF and for his support of the CAP for Saint Lucia and wished him the very best in his future endeavours.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Let's Talk Business: Stop blaming your employees for bad customer service</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Let%27s-Talk-Business%3A-Stop-blaming-your-employees-for-bad-customer-service-26671.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Let's Talk Business: Stop blaming your employees for bad customer service
Published onJune 25, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Billie Bowe
One of the first articles I published in this column was regarding customer service. Unfortunately, my feelings on the subject have not changed since then. Bad customer service still equals bad business. One thing has changed and that is the gloves are off, no more subtlety around this vexing issue. Employers need to stop blaming their employees for poor customer service delivery, period.
Billie Bowe has been a successful senior manager in human resources for the private sector for more than ten years and is the president and CEO of Benchmark Consulting Services Ltd , a management consulting firm, in Freeport, Grand Bahama. Email: bbowe@bcsbahamas.com
Customer service is an experience. Consumers are less tolerant when they receive bad service. This can be catastrophic for companies that heavily rely on recurring, loyal customers to keep their businesses alive. Sadly, companies still drop the ball, miss the mark or are just plain blind to the fact that it is the way in which they treat their internal customers, their employees, that determines the quality of customer service the external customers receives. Bad service practices are like chain reactions. Once it starts off bad, it almost always ends that way.
The statistics are staggering around how customer service impacts a companys brand and profitability among other things; therefore I need not regurgitate them here. At the end of the day, when sales lag and a slew of customer complaints starts rolling in, take a hard look on how you are treating your employees.
As a management consultant with expertise in human resources, I have conducted numerous customer service trainings for small and medium sized businesses. My requirements are simple, and it is that there are no executive exemptions. Customer service is not a department and all employees, especially the leaders at the top, need to understand their role in the customer service delivery process hence their presence in the training is crucial.
More often than not, leaders are totally opposed to this approach. In their minds, the employees on the front lines are the ones who require training. These are the jobs I turn down for obvious reasons, but this was not always the case.
Admittedly, I have conducted customer service training for companies who touted their commitment to delivering exceptional customer service, only to find out the opposite. What they really wanted was a shot in the arm, feel-good seminar for their employees. I akin this approach to truly putting your number one assets on the frontlines of the battle field without any armour or weapons to defend themselves. Ask any customer service provider what its like dealing with irate customers and the horror stories will likely make you cringe.
The brunt of the customer service experience rests on the shoulders of the employees who are in direct contact with the consumers so when complaints do arise they are the ones who take the blame. What a shame.
When an employer totally disregards their role and responsibility when it comes to customer service, they are not serious about changing what they have identified as a customer service problem. It became abundantly clear that the true audience of any customer service training must be the top tier leaders of the organization.
Here is a scenario that plays out probably on a daily basis in businesses with a skewed view of what customer service is really about.
Nancy walks into Acme Goods and Gadgets, Inc., in search of the perfect sectional sofa for her newly renovated apartment. It was her first time visiting the store. She decided to check the store out only after receiving information from a friend about the great prices. What Nancys friend failed to tell her was how poor the service was.
Nevertheless, when Nancy entered the store there was not one employee smiling. She received no warm welcome or greeting. Undeterred by the coldness that emanated from the employees on the floor, she proceeded to search the furniture section and within minutes she spotted the perfect sectional! With the enthusiasm of a kid in a candy store, Nancy found the nearest sales person to inquire about the sofa. Her smile quickly faded when she asked for assistance. The body language, tone and overall demeanor of the sales rep were poor. Let me interject here what is so sad about this part of Nancys experience.
Here you have a motivated customer willing to spend money at this business yet the employee responsible for closing the sale was just rude. What would make an employee, whose pay is dependent upon customers spending money, treat their bread and butter in such a way?
It is very easy for us to blame the employee for displaying such poor and unfriendly behaviour. But are they truly to blame? I dare say no! Lets see what may have impacted the sales rep, who we will call Jennifer, appear as though the last place she wanted to be was in that store selling Nancy a sectional sofa.
Earlier that morning Jennifer arrived to work 20 minutes early to prepare her aisle and be ready for when the store opened. She too was enthusiastic and ready to do what she loved, which ironically had nothing to do with selling furniture, and more to do with interacting with people and the satisfaction she received when the customers she served left happy.
Jennifers enthusiasm was dashed the moment she clocked in. Her manager aggressively spoke to her about a matter that occurred the day before. Jennifer received an onslaught of criticism without ever getting a word in to answer to what she was being accused of. What made matters even worse, as other employees entered they witnessed this embarrassing scenario play out.
Lets pause here and reflect on what may have caused the manager, Michael, to berate Jennifer first thing in the morning.
You see, Michael was in a management meeting the day before. The sales were down in the furniture department and upper management wanted answers. His superior, Linda, the VP of Sales and Marketing, didnt want to hear excuses, she wanted results. Michael never had a chance to share that over the last two months the recent shipments from their suppliers had been significantly delayed, resulting in low stock. After Michael left that management meeting he was frustrated, demotivated, and outright angry.
We can trace back even further into this fictitious story to find out what may have caused Linda to handle Michael in such an unprofessional manner.
A few days prior to Nancys visit to the store, Linda sat in a meeting with her CEO who proceeded to harshly criticize and express his utter disappointment with her performance. If youre thinking, well, it comes with the job so Linda should just suck it up, dont. Linda is an employee first and the VP of sales and marketing second.
The chain reaction was in full swing and its origin started with the CEO. He created the negative reaction which, if we fast forward to Nancy, we can see how her experience when she engaged Jennifer, was so poor.
Again I ask who is really to blame for the poor service Nancy received?
Employers, wake up and smell the coffee. Treating your employees poorly and then expecting them to exhibit exceptional customer service is just plain ridiculous. Stop blaming your employees for poor customer service. It all starts with you and from within the companys culture.
So the next time, dear CEO, you ask your training manager to find someone to conduct customer service training for your employees, make sure your name is on the list of participants. If you are thinking of engaging Benchmark Consulting Services, think twice because if youre not genuine and dont truly want to see change in a significant, sustainable way, dont be offended if we refuse your business. We suggest you find another trainer.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: How much do you love your country?</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-How-much-do-you-love-your-country%3F-26672.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: How much do you love your country?
Published onJune 25, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Youri Kemp
Times are dark. The saying goes: "Tings red!" But, while things are challenging, does it necessarily mean that everything must be complained about and one must be upset every living day of one's life? Certainly not. So, how does one shake off that miasmal thinking of ubiquitous melancholy and pervasive angst against any and all things? One word: Love.
Youri Kemp is president and CEO of Kemp Global, a management consultancy firm, based in The Bahamas, which serves all markets. Email: globalviewtoday@gmail.com
Now, before you call me a peacenik-ing do-gooding, lovey-dovey pacifist beyond all sense and sensibilities, let me say quite clearly: There are not all things in The Bahamas I love. In fact, some things that happen in my country I abhor with a disdain so great that if my thoughts can burn holes through those partaking in the so-called debauchery and wickedness, I would do so and take the charge from the judge. Plead guilty if the judge allows the amount of time I need and require to read my version of a country manifesto for righting these disgusting wrongs!
However, it's not my world. I don't have superpowers. I can't wave a magic wand and make things appear great when they may be worse than bad. I was told that I can if I really tried hard enough, but I think folks were fooling me into thinking that. Possibly! Let's just say my attempts have been fruitless up to this point, with a slim chance they may work in the future. Good? Good!
Now, let me state emphatically: I love my country! Can you say that with me? I love The Commonwealth of The Bahamas for which it stands. One people united in love and service.
Now, that wasn't so hard to do now was it? Especially out of the season of independence celebrations, where outward displays of national affection would be considered normal, saying I love this country on a cool morning in January is just as easy as saying it on a boring day in mid-August.
I reject, wholeheartedly, this notion that in order to say you love this country, you have to show up and be front and centre at every independence celebrations, at every national event, stay draped in your flag every day of your waking life, or call in every talk-show for every day for the rest of your life and recite the pledge of allegiance in the most dramatic and passionately frothy manner as that of a grassroots Baptist preacher deep into his Sunday morning sermon about how you are all going to hell if you don't repent, making parishioners fall into the full spirit (not half spirit, but full spirit), turning the church auditorium into a violent sea of glory with the choir and band in the background sending them higher and higher. No!
In fact, while I appreciate those that have the time, inclination and energy to show this affection at every day of their waking life, I am not a fan of those that say that one must have this zeal on tap because they say so. I'm also not a fan of those that say: "Oh, you don't go on our little protests and marches and rallies. You are not serious about this country, because if you were, you would show up with us and show people how serious you are!"
Yeah, the emotional politicking and grandstanding goes very, very deep indeed. They almost make you feel guilty for not being a part of their cause of the day.
My thing is, and I speak for myself and maybe for a small-faction of intellectual dissidents that don't appreciate being "goosied" into the self-righteous indignations of the day: Don't judge me, and do not question anyone's love or heart based on what you feel it is. I love my country, and I show it in my own way when I want to. Fair? Fair!
Why do I love this country, one may ask? What's so great about this country that you love it with a burning fire deep down in your soul? Well, the obvious answer to it is: What other country was I born in, a country that is mine and that I would most likely be buried in? If you don't like where you are, or at least make the best of life where you are, then what good is life to you and this country to you? Consider it.
Also, what's not to love about it? Joblessness, crime and the political and governmental inertia aside, the people are cool people, if I may say so myself. I have no true problem with the lot of you, to be quite honest.
Bahamians are nice to a fault at times, however. Overly nice to the point where some would mistake that for foolish. Seriously. But that is not an overwhelmingly bad thing, it's just that we need to find ways to love in different ways that shows our strength and decency than just laying down, flat on our back, like a puppy looking for a doggie snack and a belly rub from their master.
I feel we owe it to ourselves to love our country a little more than what we do. That love does not mean we kiss, hug and look the other way when things are going on that affect our lives. It means the exact opposite, quite frankly.
How can one say that one loves their country and see a violation taking place, but say nary a word let alone do something about it? That doesn't mean you have to march on parliament, but every day acts of acknowledgement for the good and the bad works just as well. In fact, private rebuke, in significant times and places, works just as well as open rebuke and public shaming.
Also, there is nothing in this country that should be seen as a sacred cow. Absolutely nothing. No one person, from the governor general to the young toddler in the inner city, deserves a pass off-top because they feel, or some feel, they deserve it this one time.
On the contrary, this forgive them now, this one time, or let's have pity on this one now because we feel he is sorry, works out to the detriment in more instances than it helps. There must be accountability at all levels. If you can't hold your brother, cousin, mother, father, wife, husband, etc... to account, then you serve us and this country no use whatsoever.
What happens is, and this is one of the faults of our overly loving and understanding people, is that when we show that blind-eye to wickedness under the rubric of being caring and loving, or show that understanding for behaviour and acts that are deleterious to the fabric of our society and small enclaves as being "just that incident", it continues more often than not.
What happens is the worst of the worst amongst us, from the criminals with the handguns and knives to the other criminals with their pen and paper, from the street corner to the government to the church hall, game your emotions and get away with the most egregious forms of debauchery and wickedness because you like them and can't separate their penchant for anti-social behaviour from their person.
My call to all saints and aints: If you love your country as you say you do, always do the right thing. Always love it from the position that if it were me, what would I want done? If it were my life, name, family, etc... on the line, then how should this be dealt with?
Show love. True love. I love The Bahamas!

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
