<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="caribbeannewsnow">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cuba visit would be great pleasure for Obama, says White House</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cuba-visit-would-be-great-pleasure-for-Obama%2C-says-White-House-26282.html</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, USA (ACN) -- A visit to Cuba would give President Barack Obama, and especially Havana, great pleasure, White House spokesman, Josh Earnest, stated at a press conference in Washington. &amp;quot;I know a visit to Cuba would give him great pleasure and especially Havana...</Description>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cuba visit would be great pleasure for Obama, says White House
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
White House spokesman, Josh Earnest
WASHINGTON, USA (ACN) -- A visit to Cuba would give President Barack Obama, and especially Havana, great pleasure, White House spokesman, Josh Earnest, stated at a press conference in Washington.
"I know a visit to Cuba would give him great pleasure and especially Havana," Earnest told Cuban television journalist Cristina Escobar in the last question granted by the official, after Oliver Knox, accredited correspondent for Yahoo News, highlighted the presence of the island's press delegation in Washington to cover the third round of negotiations between the two countries.
The spokesman welcomed the press group to Washington, something unprecedented in recent decades at the headquarters of the executive.
In his regular meeting with dozens of reporters at the White House, the spokesman commented some issues of the bilateral dialogue process.
Earnest assured in relation to the talks that the president declared in December, when changes toward Cuba were announced, his intention to work with the Cuban government to open a US embassy on the island and in the United States.
"This is the intention," he pointed out.
He said that the rapprochement between the two nations would benefit his country from the commercial point of view since business opportunities could increase.
Julia Sweig, former director for Latin American Studies at the Council on Foreign Relations, a US think tank, told reporters that the change in policy toward the island is one of the five most successful initiatives developed by Obama in his two terms and will contribute to his legacy in international affairs.
US public opinion, even in Florida, has changed in favour of improved relations between the United States and Cuba.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guyana's new president should avoid being baited by Chinese investors, says author</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Guyana%27s-new-president-should-avoid-being-baited-by-Chinese-investors%2C-says-author-26283.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Guyana's new president should avoid being baited by Chinese investors, says author
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
NEW YORK, USA -- Citing several instances of Chinese corrupt practices, and accusing them of being guilty of seriously compromising the Guyanese citizenship process, Guyana born author, researcher and international journalist Dennis Adonis has urged the countrys newly sworn in head of state, Brigadier (ret.) David Granger, not to be baited by a Chinese invitation to speak at a conference organized by a trade organization that is representing their interest in Guyana.
Dennis Adonis
Adonis suggested that, if the head of state accepts such an invitation, it would amount to a presidential endorsement of Bai Shan Lin, and all of the other Chinese operations that had mercilessly raped Guyana under the recently defeated PPP/C government.
As such, Adonis urged the recently elected Guyanese president to use his better judgment and send some other lower ranking official to the event to simply give them a hearing, rather than putting himself there.
He was at the time facilitating a Skype opinion interview on judicial corruption with the New York Times, in which a few other international media houses were allowed to listen in.
According to the sometimes controversial author, it is public knowledge that hundreds of foreign nationals, mainly Chinese, Indians and Brazilians are in possession of Guyanese passports that were obtained by barefaced underhand dealings and which would deny them the right to even be sitting in the same room with a Guyanese head of state.
He stated that, should Granger attend the conference, he would be rolling himself in flour that is overwhelmingly mixed with corruption.
He added that, after that proverbial flour stage, the president would be repeatedly fried by these people without even realizing it.
While agreeing that there may be a few genuine Chinese investors in Guyana, he labeled most of them as commercial exploiters who have no other objective than to extensively enrich themselves at the expense of the poor.
As such, he added that any meeting with them would mean sitting invitingly in bed with the people who are plundering the country.
If the president speaks at that conference, he would be sitting in bed with a group of people who have plundered our countrys natural resources, exploited our people, and are responsible for the loss of thousands of jobs that belongs to the Guyanese people, he said.
Adonis is of the view that the president should first meet with the local business community to hear their story, and organizations that represents the ordinary citizens before he adheres to any request to speak to a group of foreign nationals who are fully aware that they will soon be targeted for corrupt practices and past indiscretions that they have committed against the country.
Guyana is believed to have the largest population of migrating Chinese in the Caribbean, and similarly the largest working population of Brazilians, Russians and Indian nationals for any Caribbean Community (CARICOM) member state.
The countrys citizens and businesses have repeatedly accused Chinese investors of exploiting their economic generosity and continue to blame them for Guyanas growing unemployment crisis.
The then opposition APNU+AFC, led by now elected President Granger, had long promised to tackle corrupt practices involving a number of Chinese owned entities in Guyana.
Granger became head of state after defeating the PPP/C at the recently held May 11 general elections, on a platform to tackle corrupt practices that were allegedly flourishing under the previous administration.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OAS congratulates people of Suriname for exemplary civic spirit in 2015 general elections</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-OAS-congratulates-people-of-Suriname-for-exemplary-civic-spirit-in-2015-general-elections-26284.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
OAS congratulates people of Suriname for exemplary civic spirit in 2015 general elections
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
PARAMARIBO, Suriname -- The electoral observation mission of the Organization of American States (OAS/EOM) has congratulated the citizens of Suriname for their exemplary civic spirit and active participation in the electoral process, reflected in the voter turnout in Mondays general elections.
The 24-member team comprised of 13 nationalities, headed by Chilean international expert Irene Klinger, observed the elections in 61% of polling stations in all ten districts of the country and was pleased to witness that the process was carried out in an orderly, peaceful and even festive manner.
The OAS/EOM thanked the government of Suriname for the invitation to observe this process and recognizes the efforts undertaken by the ministry of home affairs, the Central Polling Authority and the Independent Electoral Council to prepare and conduct the 2015 general elections.
The OAS team reported that the polling stations observed opened on time, were adequately staffed and fully equipped with all the materials required for the election. The mission highlighted the extraordinary commitment and diligence of polling station members, oversight personnel and security agents in the exercise of their duties and commends political parties for the camaraderie shown throughout the day at polling stations.
The OAS/EOM was pleased to verify that some of the recommendations made by the OAS in 2010 have been adopted for this electoral process. These include the introduction of separate ballot boxes (stembuzen) for the local and national elections, which facilitated the ballot counting after the closing of the polls, and the increase in the political representation of women in political party candidate lists.
In the spirit of further assisting Suriname in its efforts to continue strengthening its electoral process, the electoral observation mission offered the following preliminary findings and recommendations, which are based on a thorough analysis of the electoral legal framework, and on the information gathered by the delegation as a result of exchanges with national and electoral authorities, as well as with the Surinamese civil society, political parties and the international community in the pre-electoral phase and during election day.
1. The OAS/EOM noticed that the average number of people represented in each electoral district varies significantly. A seat in one district can represent almost ten times more voters than in another. Suriname could explore mechanisms to remedy these disparities to ensure a more balanced representation of inhabitants per district while at the same time securing representation for all regions.
2. The mission noted that Suriname has limited regulations regarding political-campaign financing and information disclosure on sources of funding. In addition, no form of political party direct or indirect public financing exists. The OAS/EOM identified the need for Suriname to discuss and incorporate regulations regarding political-campaign financing and to consider introducing some sort of public funding scheme for political parties.
3. The OAS electoral observation mission was pleased to observe the increased number of female candidates and the progress seen in their ranking in higher positions in party lists as a result of the efforts made by the National Assembly and civil society organizations. On this occasion 128 candidates, or 33% of the total number, were women compared to 90 in the last election. The mission urged parties to continue providing women with more favorable positions within party structures and in the candidate lists in order to enhance their possibilities of being elected. Affirmative action measures, such as quotas and alternation mechanisms, could be introduced to promote gender equality in electoral competition.
4. The OAS/EOM welcomes the efforts made to improve the access to polling stations for persons with disabilities, including the introduction of special voting booths. However, throughout the country OAS observers noticed that there were discrepancies in the procedures used to assist the elderly and persons with disabilities. In some polling stations family members accompanied them, while in others assistance was provided by polling station personnel and party representatives. The mission suggested that electoral authorities consider drafting a uniform procedure for assisting those voters who require additional help.
The mission reminded the public that official results of the National Assembly and regional and local council elections will be provided by the Central Polling Authority and certified by the Independent Electoral Council in accordance with the national legislation.
The EOM thanked the governments of Canada, Chile, France, Italy, the United Kingdom, the United States and Spain for their contributions that made this mission possible.
In the coming weeks Klinger will present a detailed report on the observations and recommendations of the OAS electoral observation mission to the OAS Permanent Council in Washington, DC.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bahamas AG won't comment on power company bribe before end of June</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bahamas-AG-won%27t-comment-on-power-company-bribe-before-end-of-June-26285.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bahamas AG won't comment on power company bribe before end of June
Published onMay 27, 2015
By Travis Cartwright-Carroll
Nassau Guardian Staff Reporter
NASSAU, Bahamas -- It remains unclear when Bahamians will receive answers over the report that a Bahamian official accepted $325,000 in bribes to swing Bahamas Electricity Corporation (BEC) contracts to a French company over a decade ago.
Attorney General Allyson Maynard-Gibson
Attorney General Allyson Maynard-Gibson said she wont say anything on the matter until the end of next month.
She told The Guardian that the investigation is still ongoing.
We are taking this matter very seriously. As soon as I have something to report I will do so, she said when contacted for comment.
The public has a right to know. There has been movement on the matter.
Last month, Maynard-Gibson told The Guardian that answers are imminent.
The allegations were made on December 22, 2014, when the US Department of Justice reported that Alstom SA agreed to pay $772 million to resolve allegations that it bribed high-ranking foreign government officials for lucrative projects.
Federal prosecutors said Alstom falsified its records and paid tens of millions of dollars in bribes for help in obtaining more than $4 billion in projects in countries including Indonesia, Saudi Arabia, Egypt and The Bahamas.
As part of the plea agreement, the company paid a fine of nearly $780 million and also detailed its corrupt practices.
The agreement said that in connection with the bidding on power projects, Alstom retained Consultant I who, as certain Alstom employees knew, was a close personal friend of Official 8, a board member of BEC.
The names of Consultant I and Official 8 were omitted from the recorded agreement.
According to court documents, the incident happened between 1999 and 2003.
Maynard-Gibson previously said The Bahamas has requested information from the United States regarding the allegations, including the identity of the alleged bribe taker.
Former BEC chairman J. Barrie Farrington has described the bribe taker as a traitor who must be revealed and made to pay a price for this unforgiveable transgression.
After the matter became public, Farrington called on Prime Minister Perry Christie to appoint a non-partisan commission to investigate and to make recommendations on how to bring conclusion to this unwanted stain on the countrys reputation.
Former Prime Minister Hubert Ingraham has said the matter should be turned over to the police.
In January, Christie said the bribe claim is a very serious matter and assured that the government will deal with it accordingly.
Republished with permission of the Nassau Guardian

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>St Lucia explores legal framework for establishing medical research facility</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-St-Lucia-explores-legal-framework-for-establishing-medical-research-facility-26286.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
St Lucia explores legal framework for establishing medical research facility
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- Invest Saint Lucia last week hosted a series of consultations with relevant stakeholders to determine the way forward for establishing Saint Lucia as a preferred location for investments in medical research and education, with downstream opportunities for health tourism and other economic activities.
As cited in the 2015 Throne Speech by Governor General Dame Pearlette Louisy, the government has engaged the British law firm of Clifford Chance LLP to review the legislative and regulatory framework needed to transform Saint Lucia into a world class medical research centre.
Accordingly, a number of local stakeholders, as well as relevant government officials, are expected to meet with the representatives of Clifford Chance LLP over the next few days to present their respective inputs into the consultative process designed to facilitate the regulatory framework for developing Saint Lucia as a preferred location for medical research.
Emma Hippolyte
In explaining the rationale behind the consultative process, the minister responsible for commerce, business development, investment and consumer affairs, Emma Hippolyte, said: The ultimate goal of this venture is to support the development of a clinical research environment in Saint Lucia through modular steps, and to establish clinical research in line with high legal and ethical international standards, in order to further develop the island as a recognized location for medical research.
"In so doing, she continued, it is our hope that this would enhance Saint Lucia's attractiveness for foreign investments in the medical sector.
During the Senate debate on Friday, independent senator Dr Stephen King acknowledged that the establishment of a medical research sector would have a far-reaching impact.
There is revenue, infrastructure development and process improvements to be generated [through this initiative]," he said, adding that it would also provide major job opportunities for young persons in Saint Lucia.
"This is going to be transformational because it will create another industry within the health field, he noted.
It is anticipated that the outcome of this initiative will help develop a clinical research environment that would attract international research institutions and researchers, thus promoting subsequent economic benefits for Saint Lucia through additional demand for goods and services such as real estate, food and beverage services, office space, skilled labour and transportation.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bahamas signs on to major agreements at COFCOR meeting</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bahamas-signs-on-to-major-agreements-at-COFCOR-meeting-26287.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bahamas signs on to major agreements at COFCOR meeting
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Fred Mitchell, Foreign Minister of The Bahamas (C) signs three agreements during the COFCOR meeting in St Lucia. COFCOR Chairman and Minister of Foreign Affairs of St Lucia Alva Baptiste (L) and CARICOM Secretary-General Irwin LaRocque witnessed the signing
CASTRIES, St Lucia -- The Bahamas used the occasion of the just-ended 18th meeting of the Council for Foreign and Community Relations (COFCOR) in Saint Lucia to sign instruments of accession to three agreements.
Bahamian minister of foreign affairs Fred Mitchell signed on to the:
 Agreement establishing the CARICOM Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (IMPACS);
 Memorandum of understanding for the sharing of intelligence among member states of the Caribbean Community; and
 Memorandum of intent between the government of the United States and member states of the Caribbean Community on co-operation regarding the development of an advance passenger information system (APIS).
The signing was witnessed by Saint Lucias minister of foreign affairs and chair of COFCOR, Alva Baptiste, and secretary-general of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) Irwin LaRocque.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seaborne and JetBlue to become codeshare partners across the Caribbean</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Seaborne-and-JetBlue-to-become-codeshare-partners-across-the-Caribbean-26288.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Seaborne and JetBlue to become codeshare partners across the Caribbean
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
SAN JUAN, Puerto Rico -- Seaborne Airlines and JetBlue Airways, the largest carrier in San Juan, have finalized terms to begin a codeshare marketing relationship, expanding upon the carriers' successful interline agreement in place since 2013. The codeshare will help facilitate improved connectivity between two of the top airlines in the Caribbean, subject to receipt of all regulatory approvals.
"We are excited to expand our partnership with JetBlue. Providing improved connectivity in our common hub of San Juan will add tremendous value to Caribbean residents, visitors, and businesses," said president and CEO of Seaborne Airlines Gary Foss.
"We are honored that JetBlue, known for outstanding customer service, would recognize the same that Seaborne employees are providing throughout the Caribbean," he added.
Seaborne, the largest regional operator, and JetBlue, the number one carrier by flights and seats at San Juan Luis Munoz Marin International Airport, offer a combined 50 daily flights that connect 22 destinations. Seaborne will expand the JetBlue network to multiple new destinations, including Anguilla, Dominica, Guadalupe, Martinique, Nevis, St Kitts, and Tortola. In addition, the Seaborne Airlines network will also provide JetBlue customers access to an expanded presence throughout the US Virgin Islands and the Dominican Republic.
"Our codeshare agreement with Seaborne makes traveling to the Caribbean easier than ever, and that's the way a beach vacation or family visit should feel," said Scott Laurence, senior vice president airline planning, JetBlue. "Between JetBlue's leading position as San Juan's largest and most customer friendly airline, and Seaborne's extended local reach, this is a win-win partnership for customers and tourism."
"The Puerto Rico Tourism Company welcomes this new partnership that supports and strengthens our efforts to increase air access to the Island. This new codeshare marketing relationship between Jet Blue and Seaborne facilitates the entrance of more visitors and positively impacts the economic development in the Island", said Ingrid Rivera Rocafort, executive director of the Puerto Rico Tourism Company.
Along with JetBlue, Seaborne operates as a codeshare partner of American Airlines and Air Europa of Spain. Seaborne offers interline connecting agreements with Delta Airlines and United Airlines as well. In aggregate, Seaborne and the carrier's partners offer non-stop service to 32 destinations in the Americas and Europe from San Juan. Seaborne's expanding network out of San Juan has helped solidify San Juan's position as the Caribbean's largest hub.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Guyana: The new cabinet resembles a thrown together group rather than a team</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Guyana%3A-The-new-cabinet-resembles-a-thrown-together-group-rather-than-a-team-26289.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Guyana: The new cabinet resembles a thrown together group rather than a team
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Dr David Hinds
Its been quite a first week for Guyanas new coalition government. They are still basking in the sunlight of an unexpected victory. Their supporters, including this writer, are still celebrating. In such a situation, any criticism of the government is not likely to go down well with the supporters.
Dr David Hinds, a political activist and commentator, is an Associate Professor of Political Science and Caribbean and African Diaspora Studies at Arizona State University. More of his writings and commentaries can be found on his Youtube Channel Hinds Sight: Dr. David Hinds Guyana-Caribbean Politics and on his website .
The new rulers initial missteps -- and there have been some -- would be excused. It is always tempting after the ousting of a discredited government to go easy on the successor. Such is the nature of politics in a complex country like Guyana. But we have to call a spade a spade, even if it offends friends and supporters.
By the end of the week we learned that there are 26 ministers in the Cabinet -- quite large by Caribbean standards. It was always going to be a tough job to put together a cabinet that represents six parties, while at the same time satisfying ethnic, gender and generational quotas.
But my own initial response is that the Cabinet could have been more balanced. With some more consultations and strategic thinking they could have put together a Cabinet that better combined party representation, gender, ethnicity and the expertise available to the Coalition.
Given the pressures that I am sure he was faced with, I sympathize with Mr Granger. But in the end he has to bear responsibility for the finished product, if he, as reported by some, did not properly consult his partners in the APNU and the AFC. So its his Cabinet.
In this regard WPAs Tacuma Ogunseyes revelations that the APNU leadership is yet to meet following the elections should not be brushed aside. You cant be too busy with government business to meet with the parties that are forming the government. That should not be comforting news for the country.
As it stands, the Cabinet resembles a thrown together group of individuals rather than a team that reflects a sense of collective purpose. It seems more like a job for the boys and girls situation. Twenty-six ministers are about six too many. One can hardly make sense of some of the portfolios and their functions. Some ministries seem more like departments of a ministry.
I hear, Mr President, but Cabinet is not a place for apprenticeship. This is in no way a criticism of the men and women in the Cabinet -- all of whom are accomplished individuals.
Let me end with this. Our support for a government should not blind us to the shortcomings of that government. Its a tragic flaw in our political culture that has in the past hurt our nation. What we often call government over-reach is the end product when its too late to reverse it. The way to prevent government over-reach is to identify it early and nip it in the bud.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Grenada jab jab mas and music culture origin is West Africa</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Grenada-jab-jab-mas-and-music-culture-origin-is-West-Africa-26290.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Grenada jab jab mas and music culture origin is West Africa
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Hudson George
I have done some research on African culture and found out that our Grenadas jab jab masquerade culture has its origins in West Africa. Therefore, as Grenadians, we should be very proud to know that we have some West African traditions as part of our culture and as long as we exist as a people and nation, the tradition must continue, as long as we protect and preserve it.
Hudson George has a BA in Social Science from York University, Toronto, Canada. He has been writing since his early teenage years and now contributes letters and articles to a number of Caribbean newspapers
Basically, our Jab Jab mas and music is always a major highlight during Grenadas carnival celebration .As a matter of fact, since the days of slavery on the plantation, when Grenada was under French rule. However, the tradition continued after the British took control from the French as our last coloniser up to 1974, when Grenada became an independent country.
The jab jab mas and music always attract the majority of citizens to come out on the street during carnival celebration. The build up to carnival starts when jab jab mas players organised themselves throughout the different villages and practice to dance and compose songs for the two days carnival celebration on the streets. For example, Skinny Banton jab jab song,  Soak It " shows how organised the jab jab culture is. His lyrics in the songs tell a story about the jab jab culture.
However, based on my research looking at video documents on West African cultural festivals and the various traditions they portray, I saw this video from Cameroon .It is very similar to our jab jab mas culture. Therefore, I come to the conclusion that our jab jab culture definitely has its origins in West Africa and it has to remain as it is, on the street of Grenada, Carriacou and Peite Martinique during our carnival celebration. There is nothing else that can change in the jab jab culture because it is historical.
In addition, in my research, I came to realise that Africans on Cape Verde Islands carnival and their version of masquerade is very similar to Grenada jab jab. This is a video of Cape Verde Carnival. For example this video tells it all . Basically, this is the same cultural expression we participate in on the streets throughout our tri island state.
Additionally, I was in Grenada for the entire year 2007 and I used travel from my village Hermitage and go to Sauteurs town, which is about four miles in distance inside the northern parish, St Patrick, on a regular basis. I travelled to Sauteurs to just to go sit down on the incomplete jetty and look at the activities on the sea water, where the fishermen anchor their boats. The environment on the jetty was peaceful and the breeze coming from the sea was an enjoyment to me.
Most of the time I visited the jetty, there was an elderly man from Prospect village, who used to come on the jetty to catch fish as a form of recreation. One day the elderly man told me some stories about the jab jab culture and how Grenadian drummers made a fusion from the different style of drumming during national dance celebrations to create a new version of jab jab music that we enjoy today. Based on the story he told me, this video is evidential proof of the fusion of jab jab music. (Green House Jab Jab @Grenada Day Brooklyn NY 2014)
As a matter of fact, the elderly man told me he is a Spiritual Baptist priest. He told me that some of the biggest national dance festivals used to take place on Isle de Ronde, which is a small island outside Sauteurs town, where people do farming and fishing for their livelihood.
The reason why I wrote this article is to make Grenadians aware that we must not divert from our culture and follow what is popular in the other Caribbean countries that have bigger populations than us. We must protect and preserve our culture.
The roots of jab jab culture in the rural communities is very important as the La Fillette jab jab band portrays .
However, I end this article with this video of jab jab masquerades dancing street theatre during the carnival. Indeed, they beat traditional jab jab drum that can move the soul of Grenadians. And I know they are the Tivoli Drummers moving the biggest Jab Jab band in the heart of St Georges. Therefore, it is very important to keep the jab jab culture deep within its roots that lies in West Africa.
So let us continue to play a wicked jab .It is very important to keep it real.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Allen Chastanet's 'rotten borough'</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Allen-Chastanet%27s-%27rotten-borough%27-26291.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Allen Chastanet's 'rotten borough'
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
Rocking away with my Habanos cigars watching the news last week made me feel uncomfortable in full view of the Caribbean Sea. I have not felt this way in a long time.
The newspapers came in for equal treatment from my wife, mocking the aristocrat Allen Chastanet screwed-out, rightly so, from Soufriere for another lover in Micoud South. So she says, never mind what the operatives say, the salon and a stop at the supermarket have all the juicy details.
On the next page she says take a look, its a picture of the hungry Arsene James and the desperate aristocrat Allen Chastanet. My wife went hysterical, take a look at two capital As; they think voters in Micoud South stupid to follow blindly.
My wife still has some wit, pulling-up a line from the aristocrat Kenny Anthony to remind me next election is between the economic power on the RED left and the YELLOW right, so watch the little bread (our savings) we have left, eh; the three percent increase in our pension is not enough to pay 50 percent increase in vehicle registration and buy a bottle of Bounty, the Spirit of Saint Lucia.
There were more surprises to come. The wifes pressure running in overdrive, face pink, I had to sit back for a history lesson on the classical political happenings in Saint Lucia and a history lesson in rotten boroughs. Fatal, she said, on your computer search rotten boroughs and read. Take your time. You will notice how similar the rotten politics of today is as before.
And so I started reading how rotten boroughs were a product of a system in England that did not want change, where fathers passed on constituencies (and the power of MPs that went with them) to their sons as if they were personal property. In many such boroughs the very few electors could not vote for whom they truly wanted due to the lack of a secret ballot or simply due to the lack of a candidate desirable to their political philosophy. The term rotten borough came into use in the 18th century, and was used to mean a parliamentary borough with a tiny electorate, so small that voters were susceptible to control in a variety of ways. The word "rotten" had the connotation of corruption as well as that of long-term decline.
Onto Arsene James, his given name is unforgiving on street vibes and in village gossip, so he done tarnished his character long before he opened his mouth, to understand why many such rotten boroughs were controlled by landowners who gave the seats in parliament to their politically like-minded friends or relations, or even to sell them for money or other favours.
In the 80s Neville Cenac (cross over park) and Peter Josie (Judas) played games with Saint Lucians. Cenac has received forgiveness and taken absolution in retirement. Up to now Judas in his sunset years talks a lot of foolishness and writes likewise for his Massa leader about persons of vision and integrity (by his standards that is), who once conducted the affairs of state and are now vagabonds habituating parliament. But he conveniently forgot his episodes: his government car; a blue Korean Pony licence plate PA 1  Political Ass Number One. Thanks to memory lapse, Judas is in good company with desperate Allen and hungry Arsene.
Together the politics of Saint Lucia has the established dual capital As and a PA1 sealed with proven distinction of the greatest Judas in the history of UWP and SLP politics.
Thanks to the desperate aristocrat Allen Chastanets rotten boroughs and associates, Saint Lucia has taken another turn of the century with worse consequences.
 Seat sale is legitimate business @ EC$5 million;
 Voter buying is no big deal @ EC$250;
 Conference of delegates is pay-per-vote by invitation only @ EC$500 and a gift basket;
 Blatantly lying is legitimate for politicians and aristocrats, but the poor and defenceless do time in prison;
 So called intellectuals sit by and allow their intelligence to be insulted as long as their pay cheques keep rolling in;
 There is an established protocol for dishonesty, a new benchmark for integrity and ethics for those with ways and means, the greedy and powerful;
 Human trafficking in Gros Islet and Micoud South is alive and well, as long as the price is right;
 The integrity commission has no integrity;
 The Castries mulatto dictators can do no wrong.
Hoo- ray, I can now offer my rich friends a Saint Lucian passport for a contribution no less than EC$250,000 under the citizenship by investment program.
Before the Gods call upon me; welcome to Saint Lucia.
All the very best!
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: A poem: 'On Peter Binos from Liemost'</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-A-poem%3A-%27On-Peter-Binos-from-Liemost%27-26292.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Captain Peter Binos from Liemost got in his ship
And with orders from his superiors prepared for his trip.
Headed for a land that Liemost claims
They would love to add to their Imperial gains.
(Every year Liemost carries out the Imperial games of Lies, and dispatches armies of liars
to corrupt the people of Truthmost" their fiercest enemy, and bring back heads as trophies
they could be referred to as Head Hunters.)
Wrought with envy, anger, greed and lies,
Captain Binos from Liemost sets out to claim his prize.
For Prosperity, Empire, King and Queen
To weaken his victims, with his liars beam.
Like a Behemoth from Hell his engines did scream
Up! Up! and away, galloping at full steam.
Rise up you wretched beast, for tis the land I see
Make haste my stealthy lover on to lie to thee.
As he flew up to mingle but only with a few
He came upon The Gate he already knew
Roaring with thundering words magnificently displayed
Watch your mouth when you enter, liars beware!
Reggie "Vinciman" Wright
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barbados Rally Club celebrates 25th anniversary in style</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Barbados-Rally-Club-celebrates-25th-anniversary-in-style-26293.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Barbados Rally Club celebrates 25th anniversary in style
Published onMay 27, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- The final running order for Sol Rally Barbados 2015 (May 29-31), published by the Barbados Rally Club (BRC) in advance of Tuesday evenings briefing meeting, lists competitors from 15 nations among the 90 crews for the Caribbeans biggest annual motor sport International.
As the BRC celebrates the 25th Anniversary of its premier event, records have been broken  overseas entries (44), total of overseas participants (89), first-time overseas participants (40), cars in the 4wd classes (27) and the number of female competitors (16), while the quality of the entry across the board means all bets are off.
BRC chairman Mark Hamilton said: It would seem that there are many in the rallying fraternity across the world who want to help the Barbados Rally Club celebrate the first 25 years of special stage rallying in the island. We are overwhelmed by the support shown this year, not only by our long-term repeat visitors, but also by the record number of newcomers. We welcome them and thank them all for their support and it is now up to us, and that special vibe that rally in Barbados creates, to ensure that our first-time participants come back year after year as well.
Sundays LIME King of the Hill has truly set us up for an amazing weekend of competition  overall victory was decided by just five-hundredths of a second, and four classes were settled by less than a second, too! This is unheard of I believe that next weekend will be something very special.
With seeding based on the results of last Sundays LIME King of the Hill, 13-time winner Roger Skeete and Louis Venezia (Sol/LIME/Simpson Motors/Automotive Art Subaru Impreza WRC S12) will start at number one. Jamaicas Jeffrey Panton  he won the International All-Stage Rally in 1998  and Michael Fennell Jnr are at two, in the Rubis/Total/Sandals Barbados Ford Focus WRC06, with 2012 &amp; 13 winner Paul Bird and Aled Davies at three in the Rubis/Cockspur/Frank Bird Poultry/Hager/Mac Tools/Elas/Pirelli/C4L Focus WRC08.
Also in contention are former World Rally Championship contender, Finlands Toni Gardemeister, who will campaign the Red Bull Global Rallycross/Simpson Motors/Bushy Park Barbados Suzuki SX4 WRC with countryman Timo Alanne, and double European Rally Champion, Frances Simon Jean-Joseph, who will be partnered in Trinidad ace John Powells Intercontinental Shipping/Trinidad Mooring &amp; Launch Services Focus WRC08 by Jack Boyere, who shared both his ERC titles in 2003 &amp; 07.
Josh Read and Mark Jordan are top 2wd seeds for the first time, starting at eight in the Stihl/Gliptone/Sprite/Hankook/Weetabix/Chutneys/Royal Purple/EZone Toyota Starlet, with Neil Armstrong and Barry Ward (Rubis/Chefette/Hankook/Nassco/GUNK Starlet) at 11, Roger Mayers and Sean Corbin (Chefette/Sol/Digicel/DHL/Hankook/Illusion Graphics WR Starlet) at 12, and the highest-placed 2wd overseas newcomers Simon Mauger and Melanie Holmes (Major Motorsport/Smith and Jones Engines/Ravenol/Virgin Atlantic Airways/Redline Fuels/Accra Beach Hotel/Stoutes Car Rentals Ford Escort MkII) at 14.
In addition to the battle for overall and 2wd supremacy, there will be 15 separate classes contested, in all but two of which island competitors will enjoy the challenge of pitting their skills against regional or international entries.
Sol RB15 will start and finish on the unique Race Of Champions Parallel Track at Bushy Park Barbados; on Friday night, the facility will play host to the first two of 22 special stages, while Sundays SuperSpecial will give drivers the chance to let their hair down head-to-head, safe in the knowledge that the times are not included in the results.
On the other side of the island, the Vaucluse Raceway (VRW) will be the focal point of the Saturday of Sol RB15, with four runs southbound through the facility, followed by a further two northbound runs on Sunday morning. The introduction of the ROC track and new sections of VRW combined with the reconfiguration of other familiar stages present a refreshed challenge for competitors, while seeding arrangements change, too: in addition to the traditional Sunday morning re-seed based on overnight classification, the same will happen on Saturday morning.
Sol Rally Barbados 2015 statistics:
 90 crews on the final running order
 a record 27 entries in the 4wd classes
 a record 44 overseas entries
 competitors from 15 nations (including Barbados)
 a record 89 overseas drivers and co-drivers, 40 new to the event (also a record)
 46 local entries
 a record 16 female competitors, two drivers (for the first time), 14 co-drivers
 cars from 13 manufacturers, Ford best-represented with 26, followed by Toyota (15), Mitsubishi (13) and Subaru (9)
 120 entries received on-line  30 withdrawn (20 International, 1 Regional, 9 Local)

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Financial journalists bullish on outlook for economy and financial services industry</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Financial-journalists-bullish-on-outlook-for-economy-and-financial-services-industry-26275.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Financial journalists bullish on outlook for economy and financial services industry
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
NEW YORK, USA -- Financial journalists are increasingly bullish on the economy and the prospects for the US financial sector and, while they are growing a little less concerned, they have mixed views on the outlook for their own profession, according to a new report based on the results of the 2015 Gorkana Survey of Financial Journalists.
The survey of more than 400 US-based financial journalists, which was conducted in partnership with professors Matt Ragas, PhD and Hai Tran, PhD of DePaul University, represents one of the largest studies of the opinions and practices of financial journalists. It provides unique insight into changing perspectives and industry trends, and follows prior studies in 2014 and 2012.
The 2015 Gorkana Financial Journalists Survey Report shows that nearly three out of four (74%) of the financial journalists who responded have a positive outlook for the next year for the US economy. This is the most optimistic financial journalists have been about the health of the US economy in the three years this survey has been conducted.
In 2012, the year the survey was first conducted, only 18% held a positive view, almost half were neutral (46%), and more than a third (36%) were negative, underscoring a dramatic turn-around in perceptions.
Financial journalists are also optimistic about the health of the US financial services sector over the next year, with a solid majority (57%) feeling positive. Underscoring the dramatic difference in sentiment over the last three years, in 2012 only 15% were positive about the financial services sector, with 44% negative and 41% neutral.
This years survey results represent the most bullish perspective on the economy and financial services industry by financial journalists since 2012, said Jeni Chapman, managing director, Gorkana US. After so much bad news, it is significant that financial journalists, who do so much to shape perceptions of the economy and have the benefit of talking to a broad range of informed commentators and business leaders, have a broadly positive outlook for the economy and sector.
Financial journalists have a decidedly more mixed outlook for their own profession. While many are positive (44%), most are neutral (28%) or negative (28%). These numbers reflect a significant improvement over the 2014 survey, in which only one in three (32%) were positive, four out of ten (42%) were neutral, and around a quarter (27%) of respondents were bearish. These results reflect not only an improved economic environment, but arguably the perception of a more stable environment for financial journalism overall.
The survey also shows financial journalists trust in the credibility of key sources is improving. Financial journalists perception of the credibility of company CEOs was 61%, an increase from 51% in the 2012 survey. Similarly, journalists sense of the credibility of company technical experts (58%) and financial/industry analysts (53%) has improved and is the highest it has been since the first survey was conducted in 2012. Of concern for those in the public relations profession, few financial journalists consider company PR professionals (13%) to be highly credible sources.
It is clear that the trust in CEOs and other key sources that was lost during the financial crises in financial institutions is slowly returning, added Chapman. But there remains a significant gap in credibility and an opportunity for the corporate communications and public relations industry to strengthen relationships with financial media.
The survey shows an evolution in sources for story ideas since 2012. The most often cited source of stories are subject matter experts (71%), reading newspapers or other publications (67%), and research studies from public or private institutions (60%). The study reveals an increasing number of journalists both drawing upon their own personal interests when it comes to writing, along with a greater use of press releases (46%), corporate newsrooms (26%), and corporate social media sites (16%) as a news sources. The survey also shows an increase in mentions of PR professionals pitches (21%) as a story source.
The survey also provides perspective from financial journalists on what corporate communications and public relations professionals need to do to build better relationships with them. The most frequently cited areas included, first, the need to tell the truth (90%), second, to have a better understanding of journalists beats, publications and audiences (88%), and, third, to develop greater knowledge of the subjects, companies and industries they (PR professionals) represent (84%).

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bouterse wins general elections in Suriname</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Bouterse-wins-general-elections-in-Suriname-26269.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Bouterse wins general elections in Suriname
Published onMay 26, 2015
Suriname President Desi Bouterse holds a baby after casting his ballot in Monday's general elections in Suriname. With his National Democratic Party, Bouterse secured at least a 26-seat majority in the 51-seat National Assembly
By Ivan Cairo
Caribbean News Now contributor
PARAMARIBO, Suriname -- President Desi Bouterse (69) and his National Democratic Party (NDP) won the general elections held on Monday in Suriname. With over 80 percent of the votes counted preliminary results indicate that NDP won27 of the 51 seats in parliament. V7, a coalition of six parties, secured 17 seats. Five seats go to Alternative Combination of former guerilla Ronnie Brunswijk, while the remaining two seats went to DOE and PALU respectively.
It is the first time in Surinames political history that a party that participated on its own has won the election. Final results are expected on Tuesday and an official declaration of the results in at least two weeks.
Our social programme and the determination of our supporters has paid off, said NDPs campaign leader and former minister of public works, Ramon Abrahams after it was clear that his party had a comfortable lead.
Highly controversial due to his military dictatorship during the 80s and a drug sentence in Holland, Bouterse, who is also the main suspects for the murder of 15 opponents in 1982, remains popular due to his social policies.
After he came into power in 2010 by forging a coalition with several parties, he embarked upon an ambitious program to increase old-age pensions and other social benefits. In 2014, parliament also passed the Minimum Wage Act, a basic health insurance scheme and introduced a general pension.
Bouterse also cancelled school tuition fees for elementary education, while his administration built numerous new schools and affordable housing for scores of citizens. For the last two years government has been paying for the health insurance of nationals from 0-16 years and senior citizens from 60 years and up.
Meanwhile, several leaders of the V7-block have conceded defeat.
We did what we had to, but the Surinamese people have spoken and we have to accept that, said Gregory Rusland, one of the leaders of the opposition.
A disappointed former minister of police and justice, Chandrikapersad Santokhi, said that although the NDP is set to win the elections he is still waiting for the official results.
While the NDP has secured a 27-seat majority, the president must be elected by at least 34 legislators. If parliament fails to elect the new head of state and vice president, these officials will be elected by the Peoples Assembly  parliament and local councils combined  by a simple majority.
The formal process to have a new government in power could therefore take several weeks. After the elections on May 25, 2010, Bouterse was inaugurated as president on August 12, 2010.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Netherlands Antilles prepares for cyber attacks</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Netherlands-Antilles-prepares-for-cyber-attacks-26270.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Netherlands Antilles prepares for cyber attacks
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Dennis Adonis
WILLEMSTAD, Curacao -- Citing renewed evidence that cyber terrorists and hackers are now heavily targeting the Caribbean region, a three-man team of ethical hackers and cyber security trainers are expected to fly into the Netherlands Antilles next month to hold a two-day training workshop in Curacao, Aruba, and Bonaire to better prepare those countries to deal with the threat.
The training program, which is part of a Caribbean-wide cyber security project, will also include similar workshops in The Bahamas, St Kitts, Turks and Caicos Islands, Cayman Islands and Bermuda among others. However, the Dutch Caribbean Islands of Curacao, Aruba, and Bonaire will lead that list for the month of June, with St Maarten and several others being scheduled for August.
The three-member team, which is made up of a retired FBI trained cyber security and ethical hacking specialist, a Caribbean-based attorney on cyber laws, and a regional ethical hacker, who also works as a technology writer, has successfully held similar training programs in other jurisdictions.
In an earlier interview with the Los Angeles Post-Examiner, head of the team Michael Denny had explained that cyber security incidents in the Caribbean are more widespread than is actually known. He was at the time referring to a major cyber attack in The Bahamas, which saw some government websites being manipulated by Islamist hackers.
As for Curacao, Aruba and Bonaire, he indicated that they are not immune either to these types of threats, and must be engaged in continuous training exercises in order to stay ahead of potential hackers.
The ethical hacking and cyber security program offered by Denny and his team usually helps companies and countries to create a stronger cyber security interception and response unit. Upon completion of the program, participants are empowered with greater knowledge on the various advanced forms of cyber security threats, and are also able to identify, intercept, remove, destroy, deter or block such security threats via advanced ethical hacking and technological engineering techniques.
The ethical hackers and cyber security training program is scheduled to be held at the University of Curacao on June 8 and 9, and at the University of Aruba on June 11 and 12, 2015.
Several major technology companies in Curacao are also widely expected to be a part of the forum, which will also see the subsequent establishment of a Netherlands Antilles Ethical Hackers and Cyber Security Society.
Attendance is free, but all participants must be registered in advance to be admitted. An ethical hackers software suite and reference guidebook may be required for those who were unable to obtain sponsored copies.
While the Caribbean has a team of qualified programmers and cyber security analysts, many in the industry are of the view that the region is not properly equipped to independently deal with real covert and brutal cyber attacks from terrorist groups such as Hezbollah or ISIS or from other countries such as Iran, Russia and China, all of whom are known to maintain well trained cyber armies.
Related articles:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Panama businessman claims to have delivered millions in kickback cash to former president</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Panama-businessman-claims-to-have-delivered-millions-in-kickback-cash-to-former-president-26271.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Panama businessman claims to have delivered millions in kickback cash to former president
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Kenneth Rijock
PANAMA CITY, Panama -- Evidence of massive corruption committed by former Panamanian president Ricardo Martinelli while in office continues to stun Panamanians.
Martinelli allegedly buying a Lexus in North Miami
Cristbal Tobin Salerno Balestra, who ran Cobranzas del Istmo, SA, a Panamanian company that collected delinquent taxes on behalf of the General Revenue Department, has testified that he delivered bags of cash, each containing $400-$600,000, every three months to the offices of Martinelli's Super 99 supermarket chain.
Salerno's company earned an estimated $45m during a four-year period; he is being held under house arrest, on order of the Corruption Prosecutor's Office.
Salerno also testified that he gave Martinelli a check for $900,000, as a kickback for the lucrative business, awarded to him by Martinelli in a no-bid contract.
Martinelli's present location is unknown, though his publicists swear that he is living in the United States. He even has posted "evidence" of his purchase of a luxury automobile in Miami, though most believe he is in hiding on an estate he purchased in Paraguay.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cuba welcomes Caribbean, Latin American Internet community</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cuba-welcomes-Caribbean%2C-Latin-American-Internet-community-26272.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cuba welcomes Caribbean, Latin American Internet community
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Jorge Villa, manager of the national university network at the Cuban Ministry of Higher Education, left, and Oscar Robles, executive director of the Internet Addresses Registry for Latin America and the Caribbean (LACNIC), at LACNIC 23, Lima, Peru, May 22. Photo: Gerard Best
By Gerard Best
LIMA, Peru -- Cuba will host a significant gathering of the regional Internet community next year.
The Havana Convention Centre will host the 25th meeting of the Internet Addresses Registry for Latin America and the Caribbean (LACNIC) from May 2 to 6, 2016.
"Havana will be the capital of the Latin American and the Caribbean Internet Community in May 2016," said Jorge Villa, manager of the national university network at the Cuban ministry of higher education.
The Cuban State Telecommunications Company ETECSA will be the official host of the event.
Cuba hosted the fifth LACNIC meeting in 2003.
"This will be the second time that LACNIC flies to Havana for its meetings. It will be a great opportunity for the Caribbean community to participate in a better way in this community," Villa noted.
LACNIC executive director Oscar Robles made the official announcement at the end of LACNIC 23, held in Lima, Peru from May 18 to 22. The news was greeted with loud applause by hundreds of delegates, who had gathered for the weeklong conference to discuss questions of Internet governance and other issues affecting the evolution of the regional Internet.
For Cuba, it comes as the latest in a series of significant developments in its nascent telecommunications sector. Until 2012, most Internet users on the Caribbean's largest island had only had limited bandwidth via satellite connection.
The Geneva-based International Telecommunications Union (ITU) ranks Cuba lowest in the Americas in telecommunications development. It says about 25 percent of Cubans have access to the Internet.
In early 2013, the Cuban government opened several cyber-cafes, which have become the primary point of access to the Internet for local users. The Cuban public mostly has state-controlled Internet access in schools and workplaces.
Cuban officials have been promising better Internet service for years but have cited the US economic embargo and political aggression as reasons for its stunted development.
The US rapprochement toward Cuba in late 2014 came with added pressure for the island to hasten the modernisation of its telecommunications infrastructure. The US made telecommunications equipment, technology and services among the first exemptions to the embargo after Washington and Havana announced last December that they would restore diplomatic relations.
In February, Cuba's First Vice President Miguel Diaz-Canel pledged online access for all, and acknowledged that the country cannot develop without better connectivity to the Internet.
Following the vice president's speech, there have been several positive developments in the form of digital literacy training centres, wireless hotspots and a project to increase access to fixed and mobile telecommunications services, Villa said.
In March, New Jersey-based IDT Corp. became the first US company to strike a long-distance deal with Cuba since the Obama administration's rapprochement. Previously, US carriers were unable to make direct calls to Cuba and had to use a non-US carrier for the final connection.
Later that month, a US delegation travelled to Havana to explore business opportunities for US telecommunications companies.
In May, French companies, including telecommunications corporation Orange, accompanied President Francois Hollande on the first visit by a European leader since Spanish Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez visited in 1986.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jamaican citizens' rights group welcomes coroner's verdict in police killing</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Jamaican-citizens%27-rights-group-welcomes-coroner%27s-verdict-in-police-killing-26273.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Jamaican citizens' rights group welcomes coroner's verdict in police killing
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
KINGSTON, Jamaica -- Jamaicans for Justice (JFJ), a non-profit, non-partisan, non-violent volunteer citizens' rights action group, has welcomed the jury verdict of the Special Coroners Court in the inquest into the death case of Neville Lemmon.
On May 20, 2015, a coroners jury handed down a verdict of manslaughter by gross negligence against unnamed police officers who were responsible for the shooting death of Lemmon on August 4, 2005. The matter now proceeds to the director of public prosecutions, who is responsible for initiating a prosecution in the Circuit Court.
Lemmon, a carpenter, was shot dead by police officers while on his roof, allegedly smoking a ganja spliff. A group of over 20 officers descended on Lemmons home, purportedly as part of an unrelated operation in the area.
Upon seeing him on his roof, they ordered him to freeze, at which point they claim that he attempted to pull a gun at the 20-plus strong group of officers. The police opened fire, lodging three bullets in Lemmons chest. The gun that Lemmon is alleged to have had was never placed before the court, and the police maintain that they cannot locate it.
After he had been shot, Lemmon was dragged by his feet, off the roof to the ground, and placed in a police car. His family requested to take him to the Kingston Public Hospital, which was five minutes away. The police denied their request. When they attempted to follow the officers, the police blocked their path with a vehicle.
It took approximately half-an-hour for the police to transport Lemmon to the Kingston Public Hospital.
The post-mortem revealed that Lemmon had by that time received a total of eight gun-shot wounds, an additional five to the shooting at his home.
After his death, the DPP declined to press charges against the officers, and referred the matter to the Coroners Court. It is now again in the hands of the DPP to continue the process towards justice.
JFJ calls for a thorough and timely prosecution of this matter. Neville Lemmons family has already waited ten long years for justice. We thank the Special Coroner and the Coroners Jury for their work over the past four years to inquire into Mr Lemmons death at the hands of the police, said Rodje Malcolm, advocacy manager at JFJ.
JFJ provided legal representation on behalf of Lemmons family and it is his elderly mothers wish to see justice for her sons death before she dies.
Like for many Jamaican families, access to justice for abuse at the hands of the police has been a long and frustrating journey. This small victory is still only one step in holding those responsible for this violation of the right to life accountable. Justice delayed is truly justice denied, Malcolm added.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cayman Islands premier applauds new hospital</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Cayman-Islands-premier-applauds-new-hospital-26274.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Cayman Islands premier applauds new hospital
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Cayman Islands Premier Alden McLaughlin (right) and Dr Chandy Abraham of Health City Cayman Islands
GEORGE TOWN, Cayman Islands -- The premier of the Cayman Islands believes a new Caribbean hospital's accreditation will stimulate interest in the Caribbean destination as a premier location for world-class healthcare and medical tourism.
Speaking at a press conference marking the award of the Joint Commission International's (JCI) Gold Seal of Approval to Health City Cayman Islands, Cayman Islands Premier Alden McLaughlin said the award meant Health City was now on the map for potential patients from all over the globe and particularly the United States where the JCI accreditation is highly regarded as one that ensures the highest quality of services within a healthcare environment.
"It means that Health City now operates on par with its peers in the United States, offering the same level of top quality healthcare as some of the best hospitals in the world. It means that overseas patients are safe in the knowledge that they will receive excellent healthcare," the premier noted.
A little more than year after it opened its doors to patients, Health City Cayman Islands, located in Grand Cayman, earned the designation from JCI, the worldwide leader in accrediting the quality of hospitals.
McLaughlin pointed to the wider linkages of the hospital's success: "A strong economy is the lifeblood of our country, and Health City is doing its part to ensure Cayman's economy is robust. Not only will we see the number of tourists significantly increasing as patients and their families come to the Cayman Islands for healing and care, but ancillary services have already felt economic benefits. I am talking here of (national airline) Cayman Airways, hotels, hire car businesses, restaurants, shops and others who cater to those seeking out the excellent services of Health City."
Dr Chandy Abraham, Health City's facility director and head of medical services, is gratified that Health City met the highest expectations and delivered on its promises.
"This accreditation also lets our target population know that we are tested and have passed with flying colours. It is a recognition of Health City Cayman Islands being a centre of excellence across the globe, he said.
John Doyle, president and CEO of Ascension Holdings, saw synergies being created from Ascension's partnership with Health City: "We know that Dr (Devi) Shetty and Narayana (Health) have introduced new health care methods in their communities in India. It is our hope that their knowledge, combined with our experience, will produce new models that make high-quality, low-cost care accessible for all the people of this region, and in fact around the world."
JCI is the international arm of the Joint Commission, the leading health care accreditor in the United States. JCI has accredited and certified 725 public and private health care organizations in 62 countries since accrediting its first hospital in 1999.
The Joint Commission International hospital standards aim to stimulate continuous, systematic and organization-wide improvements in daily performance and in the outcomes of patient care.
JCI will continue to monitor Health City Cayman Islands for compliance with all of the JCI hospital standards on an ongoing basis throughout the three year accreditation cycle.
Health City Cayman Islands , the vision of top heart surgeon and humanitarian Dr Devi Shetty, is supported by two major healthcare organizations, Narayana Health and the US-based Ascension which is one of the nation's largest faith-based and nonprofit health systems, providing the highest quality care to all with special attention to those who are poor and vulnerable. Health City Cayman Islands provides compassionate, high-quality, affordable healthcare services for all in a world-class, comfortable, patient-centered environment. Offering healthcare to international, regional and local patients, Health City Cayman Islands delivers excellence in adult and pediatric cardiology, cardiac surgery, medical oncology, orthopedics, pediatric endocrinology, and pulmonology.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Trinidad and Tobago presages transformation</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Trinidad-and-Tobago-presages-transformation-26276.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Trinidad and Tobago presages transformation
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Melanius Alphonse
Accepting recurring themes of low growth and a downturn in oil prices as the new normal in world economy, and activities in China that slowed marginally to 7.4 percent in 2014 compared to growth of 7.8 percent in 2013, places Trinidad and Tobago to endure alternatives to supplement revenue returns.
Melanius Alphonse is a management and development consultant. He is an advocate for community development, social justice, economic freedom and equality; the Lucian Peoples Movement (LPM) spokesman on youth initiative, infrastructure, economic and business development. He can be reached at malphonse@rogers.com
Granted, there is external pressure on state resources and the recommendation for change of use to the Heritage and Stabilisation Fund, the Central Bank position is quite clear on this and has drawn the line. The fund is not a petty cash account! Further, it is not a situation where public finances are under unbearable pressure, neither is the financial sector starving for funds, nor are pensions and civil servants pay, due at the end of the month, in jeopardy. Otherwise, journalists and clever columnists masquerading as economists talking up politically sponsored spin would be all over this.
Weathering the outlook to improvements, leaders and government have the opportunity to reboot policy frameworks, incorporate fresh ideas, new engagements, innovation and knowledge that are more diverse to influence the future of the region and build stronger economies.
Delivering opening remarks at the forum on the future of the Caribbean, Senator Vasant Bharath, minister of trade, industry, investment and communications acknowledged that finding common ground for collaboration begins with partnership; partnership empowers political will; political will motivates action; and confidence enlivens political will.
This is encouraging in the context of political change in St Kitts and Nevis, and recently Guyana, with an abundance of resources. Up and down the region there is the capability to consolidate politically and economically, to project growth, return to stability, maximize capital and liquidity. This would strengthen credit profiles, revise international assessments and return capital generation to impact more broad based development for jobs and wealth creation.
Repeatedly, it has been said the region needs leadership. Thats a fact. The region has resources. Thats also a fact. We are a diverse people rich in culture, fashion and music. That goes without saying; however, the platform so eloquently produced in Trini mas is also replicated in political and economic exuberance in the context of regional integration.
The opportunity to summon the will to act for the long term global challenges has gone wanting before in favour of binding constraints that placates voting blocs and preferred rhetoric that proves regrettable today. But this time, the sophistication is much more astute to managing headlines and the use of clever politics.
Thus, the recovery from Moodys downgrade and IMF low growth projections affecting the region may well serve as measurements to achieve the objectives of strong monetary policy to gain real assets, consistent purchasing power, maintain prudent fiscal initiatives and keep the lid on inflation.
Revolving matters of increased efficiency and profitability verses profitability at any cost will remain a constant balancing act; however, new solutions, technology and appreciation to gain industrial advantage in the light of the energy industrys current projections has certainly broadened the need to strengthen strategic, managerial, and functional preparedness to respond in a swift and decisive manner to global events.
Chinas economy is expected to expand by 6.8 percent this year, by IMF forecast, the slowest pace since 2008. China, the second largest economy, purchased 7.4 million barrels of oil a day in April. Compared to 7.2 million barrels purchased by the US: "Overtaking the United States means China is the top user of almost all commodities, including coal, iron ore, and most metals, with far-reaching implications for markets which continue to shift from West to East," Reuters reported.
In 2014, the global economy grew by 3.4 percent. Economic growth in the United States was particularly strong at 2.4 percent, the highest since the 2008 financial crisis. The Eurozone recorded growth of 0.9 percent. Jamaicas economy grew marginally by 0.5 percent. In Guyana, increased production of rice, sugar and forest products contributed to growth of 3.8 percent.
When compared to global economic growth, the IMFs recently released Regional Economic Outlook for the western hemisphere projects growth in Latin America and the Caribbean at 0.9 percent in 2015, down from 1.3 percent last year; projecting GDP growth for Trinidad and Tobago at 1.2 percent for 2015 and 1.5 percent for 2016. These numbers, although preferred at higher projections, show no need for scaremongering down Frederick Street, with alarm bells, on the eve of the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries, (OPEC), meeting in Vienna June 5, to assess the market that supplies about 40% of the worlds oil.
In fact, there is great potential for the region to become the supplier of choice for oil and gas, even as price is dropping. Exxon Mobil Corporation recently reported a significant oil discovery on the Stabroek Block, located approximately 120 miles offshore Guyana. Stabroek Block is 6.6 million acres (26,800 square kilometers).
Haitis new findings indicate the existence of three million barrels of oil in a shallow formation offshore the island. Cuba, Haiti, the Dominican Republic, Puerto Rico and their offshore waters probably hold at least 142 million barrels of oil and 159 billion cubic feet of gas, according to a 2000 report by the US Geological Survey. Undiscovered amounts may be as high as 941 million barrels of oil and 1.2 trillion cubic feet of gas, according to the report.
Trinidad and Tobago can be the catalyst with its accessibility and production capabilities in stabilizing the region, taking into consideration that 92 percent of Venezuela's oil is exported to US refineries along the Gulf Coast, with the ability to handle the extra heavy crude oil from Venezuela's Orinoco Belt. In addition to that, the Gulf Coast is also the destination for approximately 600,000 barrels per day of Saudi exports to the United States.
With this transformation change taking place in the region, strong, inspired leaders, business leaders and major companies are essential to strengthen economic globalization and bridge the divide to provide a better appreciation to micro and macro drivers of corporate investments.
As price stabilizes, the region has the opportunity to become a leader in the game change of events politically and economically, in the formulation of key strategies to drive investment in labour, the production of material in non-energy sectors such as construction, manufacturing and distributive trades. Thus enhancing the whole value chain in a bid to overcome enduring challenges in employment creation, income generation and economic growth.
Achieving this will need a new mindfulness to find that solid path of well-being. The government of Trinidad and Tobago seems on the road in making progress towards better governance that unlocks a new approach to doing business, diversifying the economy and remaining bullish on fiscal stability that is guided by data in the national interest.
Evidence of this is reinforced by Senator Vasant Bharaths focus on collaboration in energy, broadband and knowledge, noting that the benefits to be gained from breaking the mold of the natural evolution of things and replacing it with disruptive new ideas for a new kind of engagement are clear. And nothing moves without political will. The very basis of innovation, entrepreneurship and change comes alive by deciding that we will adapt vulnerability to influence  and risk to opportunity.
With optimism rising, these ideas mean that the governments strategic foresight is both transactional and relational in nature, on the components of expansion, with the view to stimulate fiscal targets and the continuance of positive change.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Fuzzy financing in Bermuda</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Fuzzy-financing-in-Bermuda-26277.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Fuzzy financing in Bermuda
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Christopher Famous
Recently it has been revealed, via 2,000 pages of *documents supplied by the government of Canada, that the One Bermuda Alliance (OBA) minister of finance of Bermuda has allegedly been involved in a number of questionable activities surrounding the OBAs plans for the airport.
*Documents may be found at Airportemails.tumblr.com
Transparency?
Christopher Famous is a Caribbean real estate developer and business owner. Raised in various Caribbean islands such as; Bermuda, Jamaica, St Eustatius and St Kitts and Tortola. He has a weekly social and political column in The Royal Gazette. Feedback to: carib_pro@yahoo.com
On November 10, 2014, at the press conference announcing the signing of the MOU, the minister of finance Bob Richards stated that the model to be used by CCC ...demands total transparency adhering to international best practices.
Ironically, on November 10, 2014, Wendy Dempsey assistant general counsel at CCC wrote an internal email relating to the deal stating:
This should be a lesson to stop using the word transparency as CCC is not transparent in its contracting.
Competitive Sourcing?
On February 27, 2015, MP Bob Richards said in the House of Assembly:
The point is this, that the Bermuda government didnt choose Aecon -- CCC chose Aecon -- not the Bermuda government.
In contrast, on November 14, 2014, in an email from CCCs director of business development and sales, Don Olsen to Susannah Denovan, CCCs director strategic business development and marketing:
Yes, Aecon brought this project to CCC that was last winter and we first saw the minister of finance from Bermuda at the office of Aecon.
This was mirrored in a statement made on May 12, 2015, to the Royal Gazette, by CCCs president and CEO Martin Zablocki:
The Canadian Commercial Corporation (CCC), a Canadian Crown corporation, through discussions with Aecon was alerted to the exciting opportunity to redevelop the L.F. Wade International Airport.
Privatization?
On March 31, 2015, MP Bob Richards stated in the St Georges town hall:
The next issue is that weve heard people say that this is privatization of the airport. No, it is not privatization.
These statements are contradicted in an email correspondence dated April 15, 2014, from Andrew Shisko to Luc Allary (both of CCC) which states:
I received a call from Steve Nackan of AeconIntent is to privatize the airport operation.
Supplied Talking Points?
It seems that perhaps the OBA has had their MPs following a concerted communication strategy suggested by Wendy Dempsey, assistant general counsel at CCC, in putting out talking points to convince the people of Bermuda that this Aecon airport deal is in the best interest of Bermuda.
On December 2, 2014, she wrote to Steve Nackan, president of Aecon Concessions:
Steve yes I am following this we have put our communications people on this.
 December 1, 2014, OBAs Jeff Sousa had an opinion piece in local media stating:
Far from a slap in the face to good governance, it is a creative method of making sure Bermuda gets the best value for money.
There have been no other competitive bids put forth. So it is impossible to know that this was the best value for money.
 December 15, 2014, OBA MP Leah Scott had an opinion piece put out stating:
The government has entered into a non-binding memorandum of understanding with the Canadian Commercial Corporation (CCC).
Steve Nackan, president of Aecon Concessions, in an email to Wendy Dempsey, assistant general counsel at CCC, stated:
I am working on a capabilities document that can serve as part of a paper trail on your selection of Aecon. A draft is attached.
 On January 9, 2015, OBA MP Cole Simons also had an opinion piece put out stating:
Privatisation is the transfer of ownership of a property or a business from the public sector to the private. Thats not whats happening here at all.
 On April 7, 2015, OBA MP Sylvan Richards also had an opinion piece put out stating:
Far from a failure of good governance, this project is a creative and timely way of working around our debt-created challenges to make sure Bermuda gets the custom-built airport it can afford.
Creative? On November 8, 2014, Minister Bob Richards sent an email correspondence to Laurie Mahon of CIBC stating:
Ive fuzzied up the no new debt part in view of the funding gap.
Just coincidence, eh?
Accounting practices that mislead investors
Company accounting practices designed to inflate earnings or earnings estimates in order to attract investors
Many Bermudians are now asking themselves and each other these two questions:
A. How can a minister of finance fuzzy up any official government figures?
B. What other figures may Minister Bob Richards have fuzzied up?
Wocka Wocka Wocka!
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commentary: Pope Francis and the Catholic Church</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Commentary%3A-Pope-Francis-and-the-Catholic-Church-26278.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Commentary: Pope Francis and the Catholic Church
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
By Arley Gill
March 19 this year would have marked the second anniversary of the 266th Pontiff of the Roman Catholic Church. In other words, Pope Francis have served just over two years as the head of the Catholic Church and it is my respectful view, it has been a remarkable two years.
Lawyer Arley Gill is a magistrate and a former Grenada minister of culture
From the outset he brought a fresh sense of humility to the office and he sort to ground the church in that humility and to create a greater focus on the mission of the church. He once declared that, he wished for a poor church for the poor. He practiced what he preached with his simple living in the Vaticans guest house rather than the Papal palace; and eats with Vatican workers in the cafeteria. There is no doubt that Pope Francis is a humble man.
I must confess, however, that it is his astute political work that I am most impressed with. Both Presidents Raul Castro and Barack Obama credit the Pope for brokering the deal which resulted in the normalization of diplomatic ties between the United States and Cuba. This situation, between Washington and Havana, was arguably the biggest hangover from the Cold War era, resulting in years of suffering for millions of innocent Cuban people. Pope Francis used his good offices to assist. That is worthy of high praise.
Secondly, the Vatican is due to sign an agreement with the State of Palestine, thus effectively recognizing a Palestinian state; thereby, joining many nations around the world in doing so. Indeed, to the Jews, the Vatican is not just any other state and they are visibly upset. However, the Vatican is doing the right thing. The right thing, I contend, is the core of righteousness. It is righteous to be fair and to be just. It is righteous for the Palestinians to have their own state. This is a bold undertaking.
The Holy Father established the sex abuse commission to combat the sexual abuse of children by clerics. Whilst this problem may yet to be eradicated, it is fair to say that the church, under the leadership of Pope Francis, has made a more concerted effort to deal with that demon in the church.
On the issue of gay rights, the Pope once famously said, If someone is gay and he searches for the Lord and has good will, who I am to judge? Coming from him, this speaks volume to sexual tolerance globally and would have gone some way to easing discrimination against gay persons.
The Pope has spoken to world leaders, especially the Europeans, on the issue of thousands of migrants trying to reach their shores and he has admonished Catholics to help. This is admirable; especially where, often times, religious leaders are stuck with teaching the scriptures rather than speaking out on current social issues.
Of course, his training and life as a Jesuit make Pope Francis a natural ally to the poor. He has invited vagrants for a meal and has consistently spoken out and stood alongside the poor and downtrodden in the society. I would like to see more bishops, priests, deacons and nuns doing the same. Some are simply too stuck up, and when they do stand up with the downtrodden and marginalized, it does not come across as sincere. Needless to say, this does not stop with the Catholic Church; some other religious leaders in Grenada and elsewhere also walk with their heads in the air as if they are already in heaven and do not spare sufficient thought to the poor and the homeless.
I observed that recently the preaching, the singing and the dancing in the Catholic Church look more and more evangelical. I dont know if Pope Francis has anything to do with that; but yes, you guess right, I will attribute that to him, regardless.
President Raul Castro said after his most recent visit with the Pontiff, said of Pope Francis: I read all the speeches of the Pope, his commentaries, and if the Pope continues his way, I will go back to praying and go back to the church. Im not joking. It is an acknowledgement of the Popes sincerity and his work.
I suspect, though, that President Raul Castro may not be the only person thinking that way.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Is the boy really that big a twerp?</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Is-the-boy-really-that-big-a-twerp%3F-26279.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Is the boy really that big a twerp?
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
When I read the Vincentian news online a couple of weeks ago, I was interested that once again Luke Browne was displaying infantile behaviour, hence the boy label.
The New Democratic Party had a rally on the weekend May 9 at Sion Hill, the biggest crowd ever, multi thousands of people attended, dressed mainly in yellow, the NDP colours, some neutral colours. But the boy Browne turned up in a red shirt with ULP signage plastered front and back. He obviously thought that provoking a reaction from an NDP crowd of supporters would be rather clever.
But when you analyze that and what possible reaction that may well have provoked, you can understand why I call him a twerp. Because only an idiot would do such a thing, he would have cried to his daddy, to the PM, even the police if someone had given him a slap [or thrown stones ULP style]. Thank God the NDP are well behaved, a reflection of their leaders behaviour. The Honourable Arnhim Eustace is a man steeped in genuine decency and social honesty.
My question is if the boy does such silly things before he is elected, how will he behave if he is ever elected? God help even the thought of that.
Has the boy got too big for his shoes? Or is he just genuinely stupid insensitive? Perhaps both! I believe that some of his silly behaviour comes from the influence Prime Minister Gonsalves has over him.
Other things that I consider silly from the past:
PM Gonsalves in the bigging up process took Browne on a trip to Libya, where he attended the annual revolution party held by Muammar Gaddafi. There this wimpish looking boy was out of place and overshadowed by PM Gonsalves.
Luke Browne received an upper class second class degree from his university; thinking he deserved better he then demanded a first class degree and threatened to sue the university. Today he is still the recipient of a second class degree; his threats came to nothing, and the university refused to budge.
Remember the boy was employed by the ministry of finance, as such some may consider he should not have been making unofficial statements to the press or public about the Building and Loan finances [or perhaps it was authorized by someone above him], when he gave information about the status in such a way as it caused a serious run on withdrawals and BLA almost collapsed right there and then.
It turned out a few weeks before Brownes disclosures the prime ministers mother had withdrawn a million dollars from BLA, so at the time I asked if they were acting on inside information, but in hindsight I would now enquire if he advised the PM or the PMs family to withdraw their savings from B&amp;L before he went public? [Thats a question not an allegation.]
In my view his actions made the Comrade look dishonest and stupid. The Gonsalves then deposited $20,000 to demonstrate confidence in the financial institution after the family has taken out over $1 million? Had it not been for Lukes rash conduct, Vincentians would have never known that the family of the PM had withdrawn so much money from BLA ($1 million plus). Perhaps one day this whole matter will be investigated and we will get to see the reported results.
In 2010, Patricia Chance, a resident of East Kingstown, brought four private criminal complaints against Browne in a voter fraud registration case. The Chief Magistrate Sonia Browne ruled an offence is not committed until an illegally registered voter actually votes. http://www.iwnsvg.com/2010/12/11/lawyers-to-appeal-in-luke-browne-voter-fraud-case/
In 2011, before the matter comes back to court the DPP nolle prosequi the case. The DPP dismissed the case, not allowing it to go forward in the courts.
Most recently the boy has what appears to me attempting to use strong arm tactics on the famous Vincentian columnist and social writer Patrick Ferrari, telling him to remove his trailers from a green at Walvaro, which Ferrari has been renting for some years. I am not sure with what or by whose authority that Browne made the approach to Patrick. Browne says he has a social project earmarked for the ground. Mr Ferrari shared some of that with us some weeks ago in one of his writings.
Luke Browne has a social project and wants to interfere with a rental contract by ordering Ferrari off of government land [was it bordering on, if not an illegal eviction?] when he is not even the area representative, a minister or anything whatsoever to do with land in question? I do not know what the outcome of that was, because Mr Ferrari has never mentioned the subject again. But it would be nice if he updated us.
The views in this letter are my own and not necessarily the same as Lukes, the cream puff brigade [Cooeeeeeeeee! dearies], his mummy, daddy, the comrade and his dynasty, I may be wrong in at least one of those classifications or persons afore mentioned. I may be the only person in the world to think this way, so I will leave it to the readers to make their own comments.
I am not alleging any act of criminality or implying in this letter that anyone mentioned herein did anything wrong or illegal, but I must ask again, is the boy really that big a twerp?
This letter was self edited for the removal of profanities [replaced with the word twerp]. Except in one case I have also removed all references to the word honourable, because I regard that word applied anywhere else herein as a profanity also.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Letter: Let's preserve our legacy by rejecting reparations</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Letter%3A-Let%27s-preserve-our-legacy-by-rejecting-reparations-26280.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Letter: Let's preserve our legacy by rejecting reparations
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
Dear Sir:
While the reasons for considering the calls for reparations for the so-called crime of slavery as ridiculous are well-known and well-grounded, there is one important reason why we must end this nonsense call for slavery compensation. Demanding reparations is a good reason for our descendants to condemn us for so-called crimes that we may be doing today.
I know that it is hard for most of us to correctly contextualize and thus understand history. As such, it is easy for those who dont understand history to condemn the actions of past generations for their involvement in slavery.
However, we must understand that the average person at the time saw the institution of slavery as moral, socially acceptable and legal. As such, those of us who continue to condemn slavery are doing so at great risk. What is this risk, you may ask? It is the risk of giving more sustenance to this wrong habit of allowing each succeeding generation the right to condemn past ones for their supposed sins. In other words, we are helping our own descendants to condemn us in the future.
It is hard for us to conceive of supposed crimes that our descendants, centuries from now, may condemn us for in the future. However, history is replete with many examples  including this claim for slavery reparations. However, I can think of a few.
For one thing, the constant debate over the relevance and morality of the death penalty. Another is our unequal treatment of minorities like homosexuals and immigrants. A third may be our treatment of people based on class. Who knows, maybe a fourth could be our perceived need to kill animals for food. Many of our societies take these actions for granted as morally acceptable. But will future generations be so kind to us in this respect?
Just as we would not want our future descendants to condemn us for supposed crimes that we may be committing now, so too should we today not condemn our ancestors  both European and African  for so-called crimes that they have committed. We, today, can do our part in helping to end this inter-generational condemning by rejecting this call for slavery reparations.
Humans are very interesting creatures. One of the reasons why humans are superior is the fact that their moral structures are not static  we evolve. Evolution, including moral evolution, is indeed a learning process. All societies are structured to solve particular problems  including slave societies. Therefore, no one has any right to condemn these past societies.
Let us therefore help stop this cycle of condemnation-madness with our generation and demonstrate our desire to promote inter-generational understanding by rejecting this claim for reparations.
Michael A. Dingwall
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thrilling King of the Hill competition plays out in front of huge crowds in Barbados</title>
        <Link>http://www.caribbeannewsnow.com/headline-Thrilling-King-of-the-Hill-competition-plays-out-in-front-of-huge-crowds-in-Barbados-26281.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>All of our news services are free. A donation will help keep our service running and your support will keep Caribbean News Now fully independent. Please chip in to help support our work this year.
News from the Caribbean:
Thrilling King of the Hill competition plays out in front of huge crowds in Barbados
Published onMay 26, 2015
Email To Friend  Print Version
BRIDGETOWN, Barbados -- Roger The Sheriff Skeete (Sol/LIME/Simpson Motors/Automotive Art Subaru Impreza WRC S12) won an action-packed LIME King of the Hill on Sunday, as a record number of overseas competitors made their final preparations for Sol Rally Barbados next weekend, when the Barbados Rally Club (BRC) celebrates the 25th Anniversary of its premier event.
Skeete is the first driver to win KotH a third time and by the closest margin, just five-hundredths of a second. Jamaicas Jeffrey Panton (Rubis/Total/Sandals Barbados Ford Focus WRC06) and last years winner Paul Bird (Rubis/Cockspur/Frank Bird Poultry/Hager/Mac Tools/Elas/Pirelli/C4L Focus WRC08) finished second and third.
Skeete said: It was quite difficult, with the others being so quick; we experimented with tyres in the earlier runs and found the right set for the last two. Panton added: I had an anti-lag issue on the practice, but got a decent run in for the first official, which stood as fastest until the last. The flat in the second broke the momentum, in the third run we thought we had it but Roger did better. Next weekend is all-out battle.
By the time the 10.00 am practice run started, huge crowds had gathered inside the Vaucluse Raceway (VRW), with hundreds more spectators lining other popular spots on Hangmans Hill, Dukes and Lion Castle. An intricate sequence of corners within VRW contributed significantly to the longest stage distance in KotH history, 4.6 kilometres.
Twice European Rally Champion Simon John-Joseph was fastest in practice in John Powells Intercontinental Shipping/Trinidad Mooring &amp; Launch Services Focus WRC08, clocking 3m 10.27s, ahead of Skeete (3:11.13), the Nassco/Esso/Pennzoil/MotorMac Toyota Corolla WRC of Roger Hill (3:17.68), Panton (3:18.09) and Englands Roger Duckworth (3:18.14, Intrinsys Impreza WRC S6). Roger Mayers topped the 2wd runners, sixth on 3:18.91 in the Chefette/Sol/Digicel/DHL/Hankook/Illusion Graphics WR Starlet.
Jean-Joseph said: This event was like a practice for me, as my last 4wd tarmac drive was in 2000. This events atmosphere is quite different it is like Christmas in May.
There was never a dull moment once the official timed runs got under way  the fastest of three would decide the results. Panton was ahead after the first run, with a stunning 3:03.51, more than three-and-half seconds quicker than Jean-Joseph (3:07.26), with a flamboyant Rob Swann third (3:07.86, Waves Hotel and Spa Barbados/Terra Caribbean/Cygnet Plant/R A Swann Impreza WRC S11) and Duckworth fourth (3:10.70). Josh Read (Stihl/Gliptone/Sprite/Hankook/Weetabix/Chutneys/Royal Purple/EZone Toyota Starlet) was fifth and top 2wd, exactly 1sec up on Neil Armstrong (Rubis/Chefette/Hankook/Nassco/GUNK Starlet), Mayers now with alternator problems.
Bird ran off just a few yards into the stage, with no injury to driver or co-driver Aled Davies, but the incident prompted a long delay while the Focus was removed from its resting place against a well. Skeete had problems, too, with a stall on the start-line: We tried leaving the line with the handbrake up . . . which didn't work too well.
While Skeete was fastest on the second run, 3:03.71 was still two-tenths off Panton, who spun entering VRW, then limped out of the arena with a puncture. Jean-Joseph found more than two seconds to lie third (3:04.59), with Bird slotting into fourth (3:04.96), ahead of Duckworth, Swann and Hill. The leading 2wd runners completed the top 10, Read (3:11.90) ahead of Armstrong (3:12.49) and Mayers (3:14.10), who entertained the crowd with a dramatic spin at VRW.
On the final run, Jean-Joseph failed to improve, slipping to fourth, while half-a-second covered the top three after a thrilling competition; all improved on their final run, Skeete (3:01.54) pipping Panton by five-hundredths, with Bird third (3:02.03). Swann found nearly 2secs to leapfrog WRC-2 winner Duckworth to fifth, while Hill slipped to eighth. Read chipped another 3secs off for seventh overall, to claim his first KotH 2wd win, also SuperModified 10, with Armstrong and Mayers ninth and 10th. Read said: I am really happy. The team needed a boost, having done lots of hard work to get the car right. I didnt have any real expectations, but I knew I had to be clean.
There were some very close finishes in the classes, too: the smallest margin was just 4/100ths in Modified 7, where Daryl Clarke (Honda Civic) beat Paul Horton (Ford Escort MkI) from the Turks &amp; Caicos Islands, finishing 24th overall. In Group A, Welshman Rupert Lomax (Mitsubishi Lancer Evo VI) led after the first run, but Joe McQuillan (Evo IX) turned the tables on run two, the Irishman 7/100ths to the good and 17th overall.
There was an overseas victory in SM11, too, where Sol RB newcomer Simon Mauger (Escort MkII) pulled out all the stops on the final run, finishing 11th, with Dane Skeete (Peugeot 306 Maxi) just one place and quarter of a second behind him. GpN also provided a close finish, Andrew Mallalieu (Impreza N10) finishing 15th overall to beat Mark Thompson (Evo IX) by just under eight-tenths.
Rhett Watson (BMW M3) was 13th overall for a commanding victory in SM12, Neil Corbin (Starlet) 19th and winner of M6, while the Escort MkIIs of first-time visitors Pete Rayner and Peter Shaun Sinclair won Group B and International Historic respectively. Sol RB debutante Mark Kinch (Startlet) won SM9 and Jeremy Croney (Peugeot 206XS) the Clubman category, while English newcomer Marcus Tinsley was on his own in M5.
Of the 87 listed on the running order, there were seven non-starters; casualties included Nick Marshall from New Zealand, who ran off the road in his Peugeot 206 GTi 180 on the exit of the bridge at VRW  he did, however, return for the final run  while a number of wrong-slots kept the spectators attention focussed.
Sol Rally Barbados (May 29-31) and LIME King of the Hill (May 24) are organised and promoted by the Barbados Rally Club, which celebrated its 55th Anniversary in 2012; title sponsors are the Sol Group and LIME.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
