<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Selling your home? Today may be the best day to do it this year</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/may-1-the-best-day-to-sell-a-house-in-toronto-theredpin-com-says-1.3054103?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Real estate commissions could fall as new competition heats up
If you're thinking of selling your house and want to get the best price, today might be your best bet for doing it, a Toronto real estate company says.
According to alternative realtor websiteTheRedPin.com, Friday, May 1, is likely to be the best day to sell your home this year, in terms of getting the most for it.
The real estate company has tabulated sales data from the past five years and calculated that the entire month of May is one of the most popular months to buy a home, with 20,809 homes changing hands across the Greater Toronto Area during the month last year  more than any other month.
January 20 the best day to buy a house, TheRedPin says
All those home sales to eager buyers have a habit of driving up prices, too.
"May not only sees more homebuyers out on the market, but homebuyers are also willing to pay more," the company says.
How much more? The company calculates the premium to be on average $18,650 more than the priceyou'd get during the rest of the year.
Over the past five years, homes sold in May have average selling prices more than $5,000 higher than the next most expensive month (October) and a full $60,000 more than the cheapest month to buy a home, which is January . And homes listed in the spring tend to sell much faster than those listed in the winter months, the company says.
"Year after year, May has blown away sales expectations," company founder Rokham Fard said. "With the year's sales so far, we're expecting the market to explode over the next few weeks."
Fridays are typically the best day of the week to sell a home, becausepotential buyers are looking at listings in advance of weekend open houses, and newer listings have the greatest appeal.
Add it all up, and the company calculates that this Friday, May 1, is the best day to maximize the selling price of a home.
If you're reading this now, it'sprobably too late for anyone who hasn't already listed their home for sale, but the company says the rest of the month is typically an excellent time to sell.
Toronto house prices have increased by 31.5 per cent since 2010, with the average selling price across all housing types in the GTA hitting $566,648 last month, according to data from the Toronto Real Estate Board. That's up from just over $431,000 five years ago.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:35:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The energy revolution has begun? Tesla officially launches home battery</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/tesla-launches-powerwall-home-battery-with-aim-to-revolutionize-energy-consumption-1.3056587?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tesla launches Powerwall home battery with aim to revolutionize energy consumption
Larger version of battery has been tested in pilot program
The Associated Press Posted: May 01, 2015 12:35 AM ET Last Updated: May 01, 2015 7:33 AM ET
Tesla Motors CEO Elon Musk unveils large utility scale home batteries at the Tesla Design Studio in Hawthorne, Calif. on Thursday night.   (David McNew/AFP/Getty Images)
Related Stories
The race to capture solar energy at U of T
Tesla CEO Elon Musk is trying to steer his electric car company's battery technology into homes and businesses as part of an elaborate plan to reshape the power grid with millions of small power plants made of solar panels on roofs and batteries in garages.
Musk announced Tesla's expansion into the home battery market amid a party atmosphere at the company's design studio near Los Angeles International Airport. The festive scene attended by a drink-toting crowd of enthusiasts seemed fitting for a flashy billionaire renowned for pursuing far-out projects. For instance, colonizing Mars is one of Musk's goals at Space X, a rocket maker that he also runs.
Listen toThe Currentsegment on the possible energy revolution
Now, he is setting out on another ambitious mission. "Our goal here is to fundamentally change the way the world uses energy," Musk told reporters gathered in Hawthorne, Calif.
Although Tesla will make the battery called "Powerwall," it will be sold by a variety of other companies. The list of partners includes SolarCity, a solar installer founded by Musk's cousins, Lyndon and Peter Rive. Musk is SolarCity's chairman and largest shareholder.
I don't believe this product in its first incarnation will be interesting to the average person.
- Peter Rive, CTO of Tesla partner SolarCity
As with Tesla's electric cars, which start around $70,000 US, the battery might be too expensive for most consumers.When it goes on sale, the system will carry a suggested price of $3,000 to $3,500, depending on the desired capacity. That could discourage widespread adoption, especially for a product that may only have limited use.
"I don't believe this product in its first incarnation will be interesting to the average person," conceded Peter Rive, SolarCity's chief technology officer. Rive, though, still expects there to be enough demand to substantially increase the number of batteries in homes.
Hopes to ship internationally next year
Musk is so encouraged by the initial demand that he believes Tesla and other future entrants in the market will be able to sell two billion battery packs around the world  roughly the same number of vehicles already on roads. Although that may sound like a "super crazy" goal, Musk insisted it "is within the power of humanity to do."
Tesla Energy batteries for businesses and utility companies are pictured providing energy for the Tesla Motors Powerwall Home Battery on Thursday. (Patrick T. Fallon/Reuters)
It will take a long time to get there. Tesla hopes to begin shipping a limited number of Powerwall batteries this summer in the U.S. before expanding internationally next year.
The long-term goal is to reduce the world's reliance on energy generate from fossil fuels while creating regional networks of home batteries that could be controlled as if they were a power plant. That would give utilities another way to ensure that they can provide power at times of peak demand.
For now, the battery primarily serves as an expensive backup system during blackouts for customers like David Cunningham, an aerospace engineer from Foster City, California. He installed a Tesla battery late last year to pair with his solar panels as part of a pilot program run by the California Public Utilities Commission to test home battery performance.
Can be recharged with solar panels
Although Cunningham's home has not endured a blackout in the six months that he has had the battery, it's capable of running critical home appliances like lights and refrigeration and can be recharged by solar panels during the day.
"As long as a person has solar panels, it's just a natural fit for the two to go together," Cunningham, 77, said. "I consider it to be a whole power system right here in my home."
In this April 20, 2015 photo, David Cunningham shows a prototype Tesla battery system that powers his Foster City, Calif. home. Cunningham installed the battery late last year to pair with his solar panels as part of a pilot program run by the California Public Utilities Commission. (Jeff Chiu/The Associated Press)
The battery Cunningham got had a whopping sticker price of $18,300, but hetook advantage of state incentives that reduced the battery'sprice to $7,500.
"The value proposition now is around reliability and backup power more than it is around savings, but over time that may change," said Shayle Kahn, an analyst at GTM Research.
The batteries are likely to become more useful if, as expected, more utilities and regulators allow power prices to change throughout the day based on market conditions. That way, the software that controls the solar and battery system will allow customers to use their home-generated power  and not expensive grid power  when grid prices spike.
Many commercial customers already buy power this way, and Tesla also announced battery systems designed for them, along with bigger battery packs that utilities can use to manage their grids. Analysts say these utility and commercial markets will probably be more promising for Tesla during the next few years than residential customers.
Several businesses, including Amazon.com and Target, plan to use Tesla's battery storage system on a limited basis. Southern California Edison is already using Tesla batteries to store energy.
Tesla is building a giant factory in Nevada that will begin churning out batteries in 2017, so Musk needs to begin drumming up customers now. The spotlight may help Musk push policy makers and utilities to consider reshaping regulations so solar and battery storage could be more easily incorporated into the larger electric system, Kahn said.
Tesla's ambitions already have intrigued homeowners like Mike Thielen, who installed one of the prototype batteries with SolarCity panels on his Redondo Beach, Calif., home last year. Although he hasn't needed the backup power yet, he has embraced the concept.
"I think it's brilliant," he said. "I would consider upgrading to a more powerful home battery if they could figure out a way to get me totally off the grid."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:58:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Google is spending $160M to woo European media</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/google-s-160m-bid-to-woo-european-media-1.3052813?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Google's $160M bid to woo European media
Search giant's gift an investment from 'a frenemy' amid EU probe
ByMatt Kwong, CBC News Posted: May 01, 2015 4:58 AM ET Last Updated: May 01, 2015 8:48 AM ET
The Google logo is seen at the Google headquarters in Brussels. Google said in a statement Tuesday it is establishing the $198 million Digital News Initiative together with eight leading publishers, including the Financial Times and the Guardian.  (Virginia Mayo/Associated Press)
Related Stories
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
They quarrel. They keep secrets. And they depend on each other.
At times, the complicated relationship betweenGoogleand European news publishers is like a schoolyard feud.
Even the parents have stepped in, in the form of stern European regulators who have accused the U.S. giant of cheating consumers by fudging web searches to favour its own services.
Facebook, New York Times deal could change news business
Now, though, Google's recent announcement of 150 million euros ($162 million) to fund digital newsroom strategies in Europe has media observers seeing this as Google's attempt to play nice.
A man reads the front page of Spanish newspaper 'El Pais' at a bar in Pamplona northern Spain. Google closed Google News in Spain in 2014 due to a new Spanish law requiring aggregators to pay if they posted any snippets of Spanish news content. (Alvaro Barrientos/Associated Press)
"For the publishers, they're realizing that fighting Google is not the strategy for success because Google is not going to go away," says Vancouver-based media commentator Alfred Hermida, author of Tell Everyone: Why We Share and Why it Matters, which tracks the evolving digital media landscape.
"Google is what a news audience is using to find information. In some ways, Google is not an enemy [to publishers], and it's not a friend," he says. "It's a frenemy."
News companies have long complained that aggregators like Google News siphon clicks, and therefore potential ad money, from content producers.
But now Google looks like it wants to pour some of this back.
EU pressure
As part of its Digital News Initiative, Google and eight European newspapers, including The Guardian and The Financial Times, announced on Tuesday a partnership "to support quality journalism."
Google announced Tuesday a $162-million partnership with eight major European news organizations to support journalism development initiatives. (CBC)
Journalism training, product development and investment in innovative digital storytelling techniques are among the shared goals.
Noble as that sounds, C.W. Anderson, an associate professor of media studies at New York's City University, takes a more cynical view.
"I think it's obvious Google's under a tremendous amount of pressure from regulators in the European Union, and they're looking to put their best foot forward as a kind of public-relations strategy," Anderson said.
That doesn't necessarily mean the initiative is a bad thing, he added, noting it's always good when serious money is being spent on research in the news.
Even so, Anderson points out that $162 million for journalism development represents a drop in the ocean for a multibillion-dollar firm like Google.
Media ecosystem
As Anderson sees it, some insight into Google's proprietary data or search results "would be even more valuable than money in many ways," though those kinds of trade secrets are highly unlikely to be shared.
'I'm sure there's a bit of pride involved in accepting money from the company that has stolen so much of their revenue over the past years.'
- Tim Currie, University of King's College journalism professor
For his part, Hermida says that Google may not see itself as being in the journalism business, but it is a "gateway" company, even if it doesn't produce anything original.
"A significant portion of people around the world use it to go find news and information, so it's part of the media ecosystem," he says.
At a time when large media organizations like New York's Daily News are losing an estimated $20 million a year, Google's olive branch is nothing to sniff at, says Tim Currie, who teaches online journalism at the University of King's College.
"I'm sure there's a bit of pride involved in accepting money from the company that has stolen so much of their revenue over the past years," Currie said. "But we've moved past that."
Google's Digital News Initiative
Currie pointed to other digital players such as Facebook and Snapchat, which have formed official partnerships with news organizations to host journalism on their platforms.
"Unless news companies have some secret technology up their sleeve, they have to work with these new platforms," he says.
Pride swallowing
According to reports, Carlo D'Asaro Biondo, head of Google's strategic relationships in Europe, was expected to acknowledge that "mistakes" had been made when it came to forming friendly ties with the news industry.
Relations became so fraught last year that Google News shut down in Spain, following the passage of a "Google Tax" law requiring news aggregators to pay up if they showed any content from a Spanish publisher.
Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg's social media platform was reportedly in talks with major media brands such as The New York Times, National Geographic and BuzzFeed to host content natively inside Facebook. (Reuters, Wikimedia Commons)
The Digital News Initiative is one way to make good, says Toronto-based SEO expert Marc Nashaat.
"While this is certainly a means to help appease some of the tensions, it's also advantageous to Google in the long run," says Nashaat, a marketing manager with the SEO agency Powered By Search .
By providing big-name publishers with the means to create shareable online content with the kind of "social signals" that make the content friendly for sharing, Googleserving as a distribution platform  will generate more queries, clicks, ad impressions and revenue for everyone, Nashaat points out.
Anderson believes the partnership can also be viewed as a tacit acknowledgment by news organizations that they are no longer in command of their own fortunes, as was the case only a decade ago.
"I'm sure there is a huge amount of pride- and ego-swallowing on the part of publishers to even take this money," he said.
"At the same time, though, they need the money. It cannot be easy for a news organization to acknowledge their futures are now in the control of companies that don't always think about news in the same ways that they do."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:11:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>May Day protests around the world</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/may-day-protests-around-the-world-1.3056784?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>May Day marches, protests for better wages around the world
Marches, parades begin in Asia, clamouring for fair wages and better work conditions
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:21:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why the dream of hydrogen fuel cell cars is still alive</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/hydrogen-fuel-cells-find-a-niche-despite-doubts-of-tesla-s-elon-musk-1.3054628?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Hydrogen fuel cells find a niche, despite doubts of Tesla's Elon Musk
Canadian firm Ballard finds paying customers for fuel cell emergency power systems
ByGreg Rasmussen, CBC News Posted: Apr 30, 2015 2:21 PM PT Last Updated: Apr 30, 2015 5:25 PM PT
From the outside, the fuel cell electric Mercedes looks like any other car in its class and accelerates smoothly. (CBC)
Related Stories
Electric cars get NB Power boost
For years car companies have been promising thata little magic box known as the hydrogen fuel cell would revolutionize transportation.
Proponents were exhaustive on the subject of exhaust.Clean water would be the only thing flowing from the tailpipe. It would be an emissions-free panacea.
The hype has been toned down recently, but those who have spent years working on fuel cells continue to promise that hydrogen has a future.
A fuel cell turnsthe chemical energy inhydrogen or other fuels directly into electricity. They werefirst discovered in 1838, but havefaced significant technological challenges.
Klaus Berger, vice-president of the fuel cell division for Mercedes-Benz, says the vehicles can be refuelled quickly, but the necessary infrastructure is not yet in place. (CBC)
At a conference this week in Vancouver, hydrogen boosters met to talk up the technology, and theCBC went for a ride in a hydrogen fuel cell vehicle with Klaus Berger, the vice-president of the fuel cell division for Mercedes-Benz.
Berger points out that unlike electric vehicles that rely on energy stored in batteries, electric vehicles powered by fuel cells can be replenished as quickly as those powered by gasoline. Just pop open the fuel cap, attach a nozzle and fill it up in a few minutes.
Berger does admit one problem though a lack of friendly neighbourhood hydrogen stations.
"The major obstacle is availability of an acceptable infrastructure where customers can just fill up hydrogen powered cars like they do with their gas or diesel cars."
Smooth acceleration
A test drive in the fuel cell electricMercedesshowed the technology has come a long way.
From the outside, itlookslike any other car in its class. It can't tear away from the stop line like a high-performance Tesla, but it accelerates smoothlywith adequate power for city driving, and handling seemed fine on a short spin through Vancouver's downtown.
Battery-electric cars take time to recharge, but a fuel cell electric can be topped up quickly with hydrogen. (CBC)
Berger points out that Mercedes, Hyundai, Ford, GM, Toyota and others all have hydrogen fuel cell programs and costs are coming down as they focus on moving into production.
"It's not based on some technology and dreams, it's based in the meantime on real business, real customers, and that will lead us and all of those in the hydrogen industry in the right direction," he says.
Elon Musk calls hydrogen fuel cells 'bullshit'
Recently, Elon Musk, founder ofSpaceX and the Tesla line of battery-electric cars, suggested hydrogen fuel cells are a dead end, calling them "silly" and "bullshit."
Tesla chairman Elon Musk says there's no future for fuel cell vehicles, citing the difficulty of creating, transporting and storing hydrogen. (Paul Sancya/Associated Press)
"The best-case hydrogen fuel cell doesn't win against the current-case batteries, so obviously it doesn't make sense," Musk told reporters ata news conferencein January.
He argues that hydrogen is difficult to make, transport, store and use in a vehicle, whilerechargeable batteries are packing more power and charging times have been greatly reduced.
Not surprisingly, those who have spent years working on the fuel cell strongly disagree.
Toyota, which is now selling its first production hydrogen vehicle , shot back with a short film showing bull manure being turned into hydrogen, which is then used topowera fuel cell Toyota.
Hope and hype?
In Canada, Ballard power systems was once the darling of the tech world, with a sky-high valuation on the stock market.
It's since returned to earth both in price and outlook. Recently, Randy MacEwen , who has a decade in the clean power industry, took the helm.
Randy MacEwen, who has a decade in the clean power industry, recently took the helm at Ballard. (CBC)
"One analyst 10 years ago characterized Ballard as based on hope and hype, not on fundamentals. I think that was an accurate assessment," MacEwen told CBC.
His focus is continuing a corporate pivot that began several years before thatmaking products with potential now rather than far in the future.
"I don't think you're going to see, in the very near term, home energy systems or fuel cell powered vehicles. I think those are longer-term plays."
'Actual paying customers'
But at a tour of the Ballard facility in Burnaby, B.C., MacEwen talked about fuel cell products that have found wide acceptance in certainmarkets.
He says Ballard has sold about 3,000emergency power systems, largely to the telecom sector. The units kick in to support cellular systems if grid power fails.
A hydrogen fuel cell is on display at Ballard's facility in Burnaby, B.C. (CBC)
MacEwensays telecomcompanies are willing to pay a premium to ensure cell systems can survive outages that might result froman earthquake or a hurricane.
In addition to backup power, he says, fuel cells to powerelectric forklifts and for military applications are also promising.He believes fuel cell power forbuses, trains and tramswill make increasing sense in the years ahead.
Ballard's chief technology officer, Chris Guzy, says it's now less about government subsidies and more about bringing down costs and increasing power output.
"From a commercial product standpoint there are actually paying customers, that out of purely economicalself-interest are purchasing fuel cells, and you could not have said that 10 years ago."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain's bumpy, fractious, as hated as Marmite election: Nahlah Ayed</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-k-election-2015-bumpy-fractious-as-hated-as-marmite-1.3056391?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>There is something that doesn't quite add up about Ed Miliband, surely one of Britain's most awkward politicians, suddenly emerging as the darling of thousands of fawning young women in the dying days of a lacklustre national election campaign.
Then again, there have been even odder moments surrounding this whole campaign.
U.K. election: Seven party leaders debate
Britons apparently stack two of the parties on offer Nigel Farage's UKIP and David Cameron's Conservativesas among the country's most hated brands, ahead even of Marmite, a questionably palatable spread made of yeast extract.
Of course, with more parties now vying for votes, it was inevitable that the lead-up to Britain's May 7 election would be as unpredictable and messy as the anticipated outcome.
The latest BBC "Poll of Polls" shows no party anywhere near a majoritythe ruling Conservatives are at 34 per cent, Labour at 33, UKIP at 13, and the Liberal Democrats at nine.
If those numbers hold as expected, the fractured post-election landscape will be unlike anything modern Britain has ever seen. And the campaign will be just as memorable.
Who could have imagined, for instance, the Scottish National Party's Nicola Sturgeon, pictured as Princess Leia of Star Wars fame, on the front page of the supportive Scottish Sun, while its sister paper backed the Tories?
Or that Miliband, who once infamously looked anything but ordinary trying to tackle a bacon sandwich (in an effort to look ordinary), would trend on Twitter, thanks to the "Milifans" who call him a "cutie" fit for a crown of flowers?
Conservative Leader David Cameron campaigning in West Yorkshire on Thursday. A much different British election than in years past.  (Getty Images)
Who could have anticipated his campaign bus being mobbed by a hen party demanding Miliband (who looked terrified) emerge for selfies?
Not bad, though, for a politician who was recently described, together with his Tory rival, David Cameron, as "drabness personified."
For Cameron, that description was inadvertently underlined in a photo-op gone awry when a young schoolgirl did a face plant as the prime ministerwas reading her a story.
Cameron, however, might at least derive some satisfaction that his party is not Britain's most hated brand.
The euro-skeptic UKIP, as the topper in that peculiar contest, has arguably had the bumpiest campaign of all.
Farage's bumpy ride
The UK Independence Party's Farage has long raised eyebrows here with his smokes, pints and pointed barbs.
But he also raised alarm bells among the traditional parties when UKIP managed to win two national byelections last fall; and grabbed 27.49 of the vote for the European Parliament earlier in the year.
In this campaign, he's had to contend with lower numbers, but many more mishaps.
One of his candidates described Islam as an "evil cult." Another  prior to the campaign  admitted to "having a problem" with people of African origin.
It also emerged that the party's vice-chairman moonlighted as a porn star and as a porn promoter known as "Johnny Rockard" in a firm reportedly specializing in the "British girl next door."
UKIP Leader Nigel Farage celebrates St George's Day, for England's patron saint, on April 23. His one-of-the-blokes persona has kept him in the national spotlight. (Getty Images)
With only a week left before the vote, Farage, who once met with former Reform Party leader Preston Manning in a bid to emulate that party's successful anti-Conservative Party insurgency, hasn't quite lived up to the hype he generated at the outset of this campaign.
He is apparently even battling for his own riding of Thanet South in what's being described as an uncomfortably close race.
Frankenstein?
Each of the leaders has detractors. Early in the campaign Cameron was serenaded by a ukulele player who sang "F*** off back to Eton."
But unlike the other leaders, Farage also has the unique challenge of an unflattering, constant critique coming from the founder of his relatively new party.
"I've compared myself to Dr. Frankenstein, with his monster on the rampage," Alan Sked, who founded UKIP in 1993, told CBC News. "I feel a responsibility for what the monster does.
"And I want to point out it wasn't always like that."
"He [Farage] doesn't talk about the democratic deficithe doesn't talk about patterns of trade. All he says is 'we have to get our country back, we have to control our borders.'"
UKIP's current leadership insists it is not racist as Sked and others allege  Farage argues Britain should adopt a points system for immigrants like Australia has. And UKIP defenders point to a clause in its constitution that says the party does not discriminate on the grounds of race or religion.
Farage's anti-immigration vitriol, however, has landed him in some awkward spots, like that moment when he was captured laughing nervously as he was being photographed with a Hungarian man who barely spoke English.
Mostly controversially, Farage said that the EU's asylum policy was a "direct threat to our civilization."
The immigration debate he sparked has spawned a backlash in some quarters, generating protests, crowd-funded anti-UKIP campaigns, even a parody band.
The kingmaker? Nicola Sturgeon's Scottish National Party is expected to sweep much of Scotland next Thursday, possibly putting her in position to decide which party will rule at Westminster in the event of a hung parliament.  (Getty Images)
One Pakistan-born comic, who came to Britain as a teenager, organized a comedy evening last week to try to counter the renewed negativity about immigrants.
"What I'm worried about is after the seventh of May, what we're going to wake up to," says Sajeela Kershi.
According to analysts, UKIP's support is highest in communities that actually have the lowest numbers of immigrants  like Thanet South.
And yet, he's had to spend quite a lot of time there to shore up support. Farage has promised that if he can't manage to win his own seat, he will quit as party leader.
Farage is adamantit won't come to that. And whileUKIP and the Tories came ahead of Marmite in the ranking of hated brands, the others weren't far behind: Labour and the Liberal Democrats were in the fifth and sixth positions respectively.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:46:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal to compensate those who lost loved ones in earthquake</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/nepal-earthquake-death-toll-hits-6-260-as-government-plans-to-compensate-families-1.3056817?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal earthquake death toll hits 6,260 as government plans to compensate families
The equivalent of $1,000 US for each victim killed, plus $400 for funeral costs
The Associated Press Posted: May 01, 2015 4:46 AM ET Last Updated: May 01, 2015 8:56 AM ET
A man walks along the street in Kathmandu on Friday near a collapsed house levelled by the April 25 earthquake in Nepal.  (Navesh Chitrakar/Reuters)
Related Stories
Are you in the earthquake zone?
Submit your news, stories, photos and videos.
Sign Up now.
Fresh croissants emerged from a popular bakery and were quickly snapped up. Farmers delivered fresh produce and lines disappeared at gasoline stations. Slowly, life edged back toward a semblance of normal in Nepal's quake-hit capital Kathmandu onFriday as residents packed up tents and moved indoors.
"People are looking for the necessities of life. The stores are starting ot open. These are the kinds of things that are happening," said CBC News correspondent Sasa Petricic.
"At the same time, there are some areas where the searchers are still going in, still looking for people," he said.
As rescue workers continued to comb the rubble in the cityfor survivors, the government said it was handing out the equivalent of $1,000 US to families for each victim killed in Saturday's earthquake, and another $400 for funeral costs, according to state-run Nepal Radio.
The death toll from the mammoth quake climbed to 6,260including those who died in an avalanche on Mount Everest, plus more than 60 elsewhere in the region. The city got a lift Thursday when two survivors, including a 15-year-old boy, were rescued after being buried in debris for five days.
DART, Canadian Red Cross relief efforts ramp up
Although poorer sections of the city remained strewn with collapsed buildings, there were visibly fewer tents standing in a central part of Kathmandu that had been packed with people in the first few days after the magnitude 7.8 quake hit amid repeated aftershocks.
Krishna Maharjan, a farmer on the outskirts, brought green onions and cauliflower on his bicycle into the city.
"We are trying to get as much fresh food to the people as possible," he said. "I feel it is our small contribution. But that's what we can do and every little bit helps."
More than 130,000 houses are reportedly destroyed, according to the UNhumanitarian office. Its chief, Valerie Amos, landed in Nepal for a three-day visit to meet victims and local leaders. She plans to visit areas outside the Kathmandu Valley, according to the deputy spokesman for the UNsecretary-general, Farhan Haq.
Earthquake survivors board an Indian helicopter to be evacuated from their village, at Sirdibas Village, in Gorkha on Friday.   (Athit Perawongmetha/Reuters)
"Inaccessibility to some remote areas, the lack of helicopters, poor communication and security concerns remain the main challenges in delivering relief," Haq said. In the past 48 hours, the UNChildren's Fund, or UNICEF, has delivered nearly 30 tonnesof supplies, including tents, water purification tablets, and first aid and hygiene kits.
Rescuers are moving into the country's more remotevillages as quickly as they can, but face an incredible task, Petricic said.
"There are thousands and thousands of people expected to be found dead in those areas," he said.
The World Health Organization saida quick assessment of Nepal's worst-hit districts has found some hospitals damaged or destroyed but most are coping well with no extra staff or beds required. However, they are in need of essential medicines, equipment and materials.
The WHO says the Nepalese health system took measures to prepare for such emergencies.
The agency says it is focused on preventing the possible spread of diarrhoeal diseases among at least 2.8 million displaced people, especially those living in 16 makeshift camps in Kathmandu. So far, the number of cases has not exceeded expectations and no camps have reported an increase in disease or any outbreaks.
A group of Nepal's Gurkhas serving the British army have rushed back home to help their quake-hit countrymen get some clean drinking water. The soldiers from the Queen's Gurkha Engineers Unit on Thursday set up a portable water purification unit on the Kathmandu grounds of the old royal palace.
"I am just glad I could serve my countrymen when they really needed something so necessary like clean drinking water," said Corporal Bhesh Gurung, 34. "I have been away for 13 years serving in a foreign land and finally I can do something for my motherland."
Gurung and his fellow Gurkha soldiers, helped by some Nepalese soldiers, are pumping ground water, filtering it in a purification unit and storing it in a 5,000-litretank.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:00:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alberta NDP campaign has 'shades of Jack Layton'</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/elections/alberta-votes/rachel-notley-campaign-has-shades-of-jack-layton-1.3056425?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Rachel Notley campaign has 'shades of Jack Layton'
Orange wave could be seen on election day in Alberta, according to polls
CBC News Posted: Apr 30, 2015 8:00 PM MT Last Updated: Apr 30, 2015 10:01 PM MT
Alberta NDP Leader Rachel Notley scrums during a campaign stop in Calgary on Thursday. (Jeff McIntosh/Canadian Press)
Alberta election: Rob Brown talks with CBC's political panel ramping up to Tuesday's election. 6:27
Related Stories
Nenshi predicts PC minority government in Alberta election
The Alberta NDP ispoised for a historic breakthrough, and a lot of that momentum can be credited to the party's leader Rachel Notley .
An exclusive CBC poll suggestsNotley, who was first elected to the Alberta Legislature in 2008, is driving the party's surge with astrong campaign. She was giventhe highest approval rating at 53 per centwhenAlbertanswere polled by Return On Insight (ROI).
Advance polls in Alberta's election now open
"Rachel Notley has built this campaign around her. It has shades of Jack Layton, in that she is quite popular and she has a lot of energy," said ROI president Bruce Cameron.
"Most Albertans, regardless of who they are voting for, would acknowledge the NDP has run the best campaign so far."
WildroseParty Leader Brian Jean received a 34 per cent approval ratingwhile Progressive Conservative Leader Jim Prentice sits at 31per cent.
Live operator telephone surveys were conducted for the ROI poll from April 25 to 28 with a representative cross-section of adult Albertans in Calgary, Edmonton and areas outside the two major cities in Alberta.  (ROI)
Prentice going in wrong direction?
Notley is the only leader with a positive net score, meaning her disapproval rate of 22 per cent does not factor out the positive ratingshe received in the latest polling.
Every other party leader has a negative net score, with Prenticeat -22.
A new poll from ROI says Rachel Notleys personal popularity is driving the NDP momentum, with over half of Albertans expressing approval and only 22 per cent expressing disapproval. (ROI poll)
"Half of Albertans think Jim Prentice has led the province in the wrong direction since becoming Premier," according to ROI.
Cameron thinks thePCs will focuson oneclearquestion for the rest of the campaign: How do you feel about the NDP running the economy here?
The rhetoric from Prentice leading up to Tuesday'svote has mainly focused on the NDP, which led Notley to say the PC leader was fear-mongering  something that could be seen in the last provincial election.
If the early polls in 2012 were to be believed, Alberta was in for political upheaval unlike anything the province had seen in four decades.
In the end, the Progressive Conservative dynasty remainedintact , afterconcerns about social conservatism and controversial statements from Wildrose candidates pushed progressive voters to cast ballots for the PCs.
Final data was computer-weighted to reflect the correct proportion of respondents by age, gender, and region based on Statistics Canada data.  (ROI poll)
Notley encouraged, but not bankingon polls
Notley is taking the latest poll results in stride.
"People are looking for something different. They're looking for an alternative," she said."They're looking for a government that will reflect their opinions on issues of fairness, on protecting our education and our health care and protecting jobs, so I'm encouraged by what the polls show, but Idon't bank on them and Idon't think most politicians do these days."
Jean also weighed in on the several polls released in the last 24 hours, while on a campaign stop in Calgary.
"It's not going to change our principles, which is really the key to this race, because we are the only party that stands up for Alberta's principles and priorities," said Jean.
PC Leader Jim Prentice hasn't commented on the poll results, but used a major fundraising speech Thursday evening to attack the NDP as potential killers of jobs and investment.
ROI tookasample size of 758 Albertansfor its approvalpoll, whichhas a margin of error of plus or minus 3.6percentage points, 19times out of 20.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Apr 24 21:24:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Simple iPad app turning hearing tests on their ear</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/health/canadian-hearing-test-app-for-third-world-finding-new-uses-here-1.3046345?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
An iPad app to diagnose hearing loss in children in the developing world has come full circle.
Developed for use in impoverished countries like Uganda, the app has now come back home to Canada where its creators realize it would save Western health-care systems both time and money.
"It's cheap, accurate, validated and easy to use," says Dr. Matthew Bromwich, an ENT surgeon at the Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario in Ottawa who oversaw the development of the app.
Newborn hearing screening 'insufficient' in most provinces
Called ShoeBox, the app allows users to perform a hearing test with nothing more than an iPad. It was initially developed for CanHEAR Uganda, a long-running, mostly Canadian program to screen Ugandan children for hearing loss.
But even in Canada screening children for hearing loss is difficult and expensive. The bulky machines used in hospitals cost up to $35,000. Compare that to an iPad that costs roughly $400 and fits in a backpack.
Dr. Bromwich first realized he had a problem when he started making twice a year trips to Uganda to screen children for hearing loss.
Dr. Matthew Bromwich, an ENT surgeon at the Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario in Ottawa, oversaw the development of the ShoeBox app. (Courtesy of Dr. Matthew Bromwich)
Before the trip he and his team would try to raise money for testing equipment that they would then leave behind for the local clinics to use.
But with each return trip he realized that the equipment would often end up broken and piled in a corner of the room.
Even the equipment that was still working would often go unused because there simply weren't enough trained personnel.
Bromwich realized the equipment he was bringing with him was expensive, bulky, complicated to use, hard to maintain and prone to breaking down.
So his research team at CHEO came up with the iPad app, in the process winning a 2014 Research Canada award for mobile health innovation.
The next time he went to Uganda, "we just took 10 iPads and screened 800 kids," Bromwich says. Unlike standard audiometry equipment, the iPads were considerably cheaper and much easier to use.
The app itself "takes five minutes to learn for people comfortable with the iPad," Bromwich says. It's also much quicker.
With the iPad app a hearing test can be performed in about five minutes whereas it would take up to 15 minutes with the conventional machine.
Like a game
The other bonus is that the app is formulated as a game, which makes it particularly attractive to kids.
Rather than sitting at a machine and raising their hands when they hear a tone, as with traditional hearing tests, kids have to sort brightly coloured animals and objects based on whether they make a noise.
"They just play with the iPad," says Bromwich.
After using the app in Uganda, he and his team realized the app had applications and benefits here in Canada.
A young girl in Iqaluit, Nunavut, has her hearing tested in 2013. (Courtesy of Dr. Matthew Bromwich)
Instead of flying children down from Iqaluit for hearing tests, which typically costs the government $7,500 in transportation and housing, they could send people up there with an app that requires little special training to use.
By using the app to screen children for hearing loss, only the children who have a problem need to be sent down to Ottawa for further testing and treatment.
Bromwich calls it "intelligent triage." It has spared Iqaluit families an unnecessary multi-day trip to Ottawa and eased an already overtaxed health system.
"You don't want to send kids with normal hearing to get tests," he says. "If you send everyone down, it overwhelms the system."
Schools the next frontier
The app then ended up having yetanother use much closer to home.
David Chan, a medical student at the University of Ottawa, was working with Bromwich analyzing data from the Iqaluit project when he had an Aha! moment.
"Honestly, I was just going to be bed and right before I fell asleep I was like, 'Oh my God!' This app would be perfect just to bring it to screen in schools," Chan says.
He brought the idea to Bromwich and he loved it too.
Both Canadian and American medical guidelines say that all children in Canada should be screened for hearing loss, but because of budget constraints, few ever are.
"People just don't have access," Chan says. That prompted him to launch iHEAR, a program of 27 medical student volunteers who took the app into eight Ottawa elementary schools in February 2015 to screen children for hearing loss.
Since February, they found three cases of hearing loss that would otherwise have gone undiagnosed.
The key to treating hearing loss is to diagnose it early; otherwise it can cause learning difficulties, language problems and behavioural issues later in life.
Since access to formal hearing testing is so difficult, most children have their hearing tested manually.
A doctor will rub her fingers next to a child's ear and ask if the youngster heard the sound.
"It's 2015," Chan says, "We can come up with a better solution. That's the purpose of the project."
As Bromwich puts it, it's a perfect example of reverse engineering. "A Third World solution is being put to use for a first world problem."
Christopher Labos is a cardiologist and epidemiologist at the McGill University Health Centre. He is currently a fellow in global journalism at the Munk School of Global Affairs at the University of Toronto.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drop your defences to enjoy Avengers: Age of Ultron </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/avengers-age-of-ultron-director-joss-whedon-improves-on-the-formula-1.3055708?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Spider-Man, Avengers film deal defeats mighty legal woes
The interesting thing about the first Avengers film, the most successful Marvel movie ofall time,is thatdirector and writer Joss Whedon considers it a failure.
Taking in an estimated $1.5 billion at the global box office, Avengerswas the third-biggest-grossing film in cinematic history, behind Titanic and Avatar.Butwhen Whedon looks at it, all he sees is "flaw, flaw, flaw, compromise, laziness, mistake," the filmmaker told Vulture.com . 
The reason Whedon, the showrunner behind fan favourites such as Buffy the Vampire Slayer and Firefly, committed to make the second Avengers film, he says, was to address his mistakes.
For his troubles, Whedonsays, the experience nearly killed him, and it's easy to see why.
The Avengers: Age of Ultron is not about forming the superhero team, but finding a reason to justify its existence while simultaneously tying up the loose ends of three film franchises and their ancillary TV shows. Whew. (Disney/Marvel/Associated Press)
The first film was a delicate balancing act, but there was a firm template anchored by anorigin story abouta team of heroes unitingto stop pesky God Loki.By comparison,Avengers: Age of Ultron has a much more difficult mission.
It's not about forming the team, but finding a reason to justify its existence while simultaneouslytying up the loose ends of three film franchises and their ancillary TV shows.
Darker subtext
The highly anticipatedsequel, which opens in theatres on Friday,starts at a sprint pace, as if Whedon is eager to apply the lessons he's learned.The action is tight and dynamic as the team springs into action and attacksa base of the world-wide terrorist organization, Hydra.
The Avengers get some new, hostile company in Age of Ultron in a pair of mysterious and enhanced twins, played by Elizabeth Olsen, right, and Aaron Taylor-Johnson. (Jay Maidment/Disney/Marvel/AP Photo)
But there's a darker subtext in the air.When Robert Downey Jr.'sIron Man summons an army of robot dronescalled the Iron Legion, the crowd pelts them with garbage as the camera lingers on Banksy-style graffiti where Iron Man's head is replaced by dollar signs. 
Building on that sense of resentment, Captain America (Chris Evans)and friends soon meet two new enhanced opponents: Quicksilver, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson, and Scarlet Witch, played by Elizabeth Olsen.
Chris Evans and Jeremy Renner say sorry for calling Black Widow a 'whore'
The orphans,who speak with aSlavic snarl, are looking to teach Tony Stark a lesson.They were raised in the fictional eastern European country of Sokovia, "a place that's nowhere special on the way to everywhere special,"asMaria Hill describes it.
It's a throwaway line, but also an example of why Whedon's deft dialogue is his super power.
Best Hulk ever
While Avengers: Age of Ultron threatens to sag under the strain of the various strands of the story, it's the little moments that make the Avengers seem real. 
In a movie with 10 major characters, Whedon almost manages to give everyone a moment, and if you're a fan of ol' Greenjeans (that's the Hulk for non-comic nerds) you are in for a treat.
Mark Ruffalo plays The Hulk in a scene from Avengers: Age of Ultron. (Disney/Marvel)
Keep your eyes peeled during the party scene at Avengers headquarters for a film noir throwback.
Mark Ruffalo's Bruce Banner sidles up to Scarlett Johansson's Natasha Romanoff at the bar with the old "What's a nice girl like you doing in a dump like this?" line.
"Fella did me wrong," she replies, and we're off to the races with a wonderful variation on a classic Whedon theme: the Beauty and the Geek. 
The Hulk and Black Widow are just two tragic heroes trying to find a little solace in the gamma-charged heart of this film, and Ruffalo has created the best version of the Hulk we've seen.
Smug super villain
While we're on the topic of characterization, Marvel fans should get ready for a different type of super-villain: Ultron.
Voiced by James Spader, the sinister robot with delusions of grandeuris smug, sarcastic and practically jocular.
Ultron, a product of Tony Starks artificial intelligence program run amok, makes for a different type of super-villain with his smug sarcasm.   (Disney/Marvel)
And while an android this amusing strains believability, the result is a hoot and a major improvement on dull world-destroying despots. (I'm looking at you, Ronan.)
While Hulk and Ultron shine in this sequel, not everything is perfect. Whedon's first cut of Avengers: The Age of Ultron was an epic 3  hours. The final version runs two hours and 22 minutes. That's over an hour of footage gone, and it shows.
Been there, done that
There is also a niggling sense of the familiar to this tale.For the plethora ofnew characters and a more global setting (South Korea, Wakanda and more) the finale finds the Avengers once again buzzing around trying to protect a city from a faceless horde. 
It's Captain Americauliflower to the rescue in Sesame Street's Avengers parody
Sure,Ultron's robot army is an upgrade over the alien Chitauri, but there is stilla feeling of been there, done that.
Zoom out to the bird's-eye view andyou'll recognize another pattern:Massive action scenes followed bycasual moments where we get to see Avengers relating on a more human level.
We see themjokingabout trying to lift Thor's hammer at a party, and sitting down for a home-cooked meal in another scene.As much as I revel in the action  likeIron Man and Hulk going at it in a stunning slugfest  it's still the quiet moments, likeThor sheepishly stepping on a toy, that are most endearing.
The key to enjoying Avengers: Age of Ultron is just accepting what it is. This is not Whedon'sTheEmpire Strikes Back  afilm that had the courage to leave the audience in a dark place, desperate for more.
If anything, this is Whedon's Return of the Jedi.
Avengers: Age of Ultronishis swan song,achance to play the hits one more time, improve on the formula and leave the pieces on the table for the next iteration.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 18:34:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ontario law passes to let asthmatic kids carry inhalers in school</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/ontario-law-passes-to-let-asthmatic-kids-carry-inhalers-in-school-1.3055534?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Ontario law passes to let asthmatic kids carry inhalers in school
Ryan Gibbons died of an asthma attack at school in 2012
The Canadian Press Posted: Apr 30, 2015 11:34 AM ET Last Updated: May 01, 2015 7:58 AM ET
Ryan Gibbons died in October 2012, following an asthma attack he suffered during recess. He was 12 years old. (CBC)
Related Stories
Asthma likely to be a lifetime condition
Ontario has made it illegal for schools to keep inhalers away from kids suffering from asthma with legislation crafted following the death of a 12-year-old boy.
Ryan's Law is named for Ryan Gibbons, who died Oct. 9, 2012, after suffering an asthma attack during recess. His school in Straffordville, southeast of London, did not allow him to keep his puffer with him, despite repeated efforts by his mother and a doctor's note.
"You would give him an inhaler but then he would get caught with the inhaler and then it would be taken away," Sandra Gibbons said Thursday. "Then I'd get a phone call. So it was actually very frustrating. I didn't understand why. I didn't realize that the policy actually stated that the prescribed medication needed to be in the office."
Asthma likely to be a lifetime condition
Gibbons said her son was an energetic boy who loved motorbikes and hiking with her in the woods.
"There's so much I can say about him and it's just really hard because it's just  you miss him," she said through tears.
It seems like a matter of common sense that kids would have access to their life-saving medication, said Progressive Conservative MPP Jeff Yurek, who introduced the private member's bill passed unanimously Thursday.
Patchwork policies
School boards across the province had a patchwork of policies on inhalers and though some provinces have policies similar to Ryan's Law, the Asthma Society of Canada's president and CEO said he believes Ontario will be the first to enact a law.
"There are still school boards all across this country and schools within those boards that don't allow children to carry their puffers," said Rob Oliphant.
"It's usually part of a blanket understanding of medications, so they say medications are unsafe, they have that idea in their head, so they lock them up in the principal's office."
An asthma sufferer himself, Oliphant said it's stressful to not have his inhaler nearby.
"It is exactly the same with children," he said.
"Children need to have the confidence that their medication is near them, that if they have an exacerbation, if they're out running in a playground they have something with them. Not only do their triggers actually affect their lungs...but the stress of not having a puffer available can actually exacerbate it and make it a worse feeling."
1 in 5 Ontario kids have asthma
Once the bill receives royal assent every school in Ontario will be required to allow a student to carry asthma medication with the permission of their parent or guardian and doctor.
It will also require schools to develop ways to reduce exposure to asthma triggers and that every principal develop an individual plan for each student who has asthma with the child's doctor.
George Habib, president and CEO of the Ontario Lung Association, said about 570,000 children and teens in the province have asthma  about one in five.
"It's because asthma is so common, we can easily forget it's a very dangerous disease and it can be fatal," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:26:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy, 11, detained at Lego Store for shopping alone</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/lego-store-detains-11-year-old-boy-for-shopping-without-an-adult-1.3054467?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Everything could be awesome: LEGO store coming to Winnipeg?
A Calgary father says he is shocked his 11-year-old son was detained by a security guard at the Chinook Centre Lego Store because the boy was shopping alone.
Doug Dunlop's son, Tadhg (pronounced Tige), had $200 of his own moneyon Sunday and was looking to add to his vast Lego collection.
Dunlop says hebicycled most of the way to the mall withTadhg, leaving him to shop at the Lego store. The two planned to meetlater at the mall for lunch.
In the store, Tadhgwas asked his age.
After he told the store manager he was 11, a security guard was called and the boy was asked to stay in a certain area until his father arrived.
It turns out Lego has a rule that childrenunder 12 should not be left unattended in its stores.
The boy had shopped at the store alone many times without incident, said his father, and hadspent thousands of dollars there  he earned the moneyshovelling snow and babysitting.
Tadhg had even been asked his age before on several occasions, and the store employees would joke that it wouldn't be long before he could work there.
Dunlop was upsetto discover his son had been detained in the store.
"I was, of course, shocked," he said.
When he walked into the store, he thought that Tadhg might haveknocked over a display, but not that he had done anything wrong, said Dunlop.
"Why would you detain a good customer? It's bad business."
'Utmost concern is for child safety'
The store policy was not visible inside the store at the time. But Dunlop, who posted his letter to Lego in a blog about the incident, asked the store manager why the policy existed. The store manager cited safety concerns such as child predators or the possibility of an evacuation from the mall.
Doug Dunlop wants an apology from the Lego Store for detaining his son. (Doug Dunlop)
Dunlopsaid he was called a "bad parent" while questioning the store manager and the security guard about thepolicy.
As of Wednesday, the store has posted a sign in the window that reads: "To ensure that your child has a safe and enjoyable experience in our store, please do not leave them unattended."
Amanda Santoro,a Lego brand relations manager, told CBC News in an email the companystands by the policy.
"As a toy company,our utmost concern is for children's safety, and as such we have a policy in place regarding unaccompanied minors.As this customer was under the age of 12 and alone, we followed our protocol and stand by our policy."
Dad calls policy 'age discrimination'
In a lengthy letter to Lego, Dunlop says he wantsan apology from the store for detaining his son and for being called a "bad parent" by letting himshop alone.
Nowthe Dunlops say they will never shop in the Calgary Lego store again.
"My son loves Lego. It's his favourite store," he said. "This policy doesn't make sense; it's arbitrary age discrimination where they decided that children under 12 are inconvenient."
Tadhg has also been telling his friends about the incident, saidDunlop."And they are incensed. Being 11 years old is not a crime."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Montreal Canadiens fan warns others to 'be aware' of fake jerseys</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/locker-room-to-stop-selling-some-jerseys-after-counterfeit-found-1.3055775?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Locker Room to stop selling some jerseys after counterfeit found
NHL confirms Reebok jersey bought at store in Bubba Ray's not official gear
ByCatharine Tunney, CBC News Posted: May 01, 2015 6:00 AM AT Last Updated: May 01, 2015 9:31 AM AT
Locker Room owner Brad Hartlin says he stands by the autographs in his memorabilia store, but he'll stop selling unsigned jerseys because things can 'fall through the cracks.' (CBC)
About The Author
First generation Maritimer. Email: catharine.tunney@cbc.ca Twitter: @cattunneycbc
Related Stories
Fake jerseys hit Calgary ahead of Heritage Classic
A sports memorabilia store in Halifax says it's getting out of the jersey game after a CBC Nova Scotia investigation found it wasselling counterfeit NHLjerseys.
There's no denying Patrick Voyer's love for the Montreal Canadiens is real  but he doubts two jerseys he bought at the Locker Room are authentic.
Voyer is from Montreal and has been working in Halifax for the past few months. When he saw a signed Guy Lafleur Habs jersey displayed in the store, he was willing to open his wallet.
He later returned to the store  located inside Bubba Ray's Sports Bar on Spring Garden Road  and bought another Habs jersey, spending close to $400 in total.
"I'm very superstitious, so I really feel that if I have some gear, or some hockey stick or puck that a real Canadiens player has touched, I feel we always have a chance to win," Voyer said.
"Makes me feel like I'm a part of the game."
It wasn't until he checked the official Canadiens site on counterfeit jerseys that he realized the jerseys he bought might not be authentic.
"This store is right next to a popular bar. You wonder with a few drinks during a good game, someone could fall in love with one of these pieces, it's easy for them to not ask questions and just pay the price," he said.
"I'm really pissed off. Down the line, I do this for my team."
Counterfeit jersey sold
Equipped with a hidden camera, CBC News returned to the store to buy another jersey. A Washington Capitals jersey, with a Reebok logo stitched on the back, cost $80.
'Advanced athletic pereormance,' reads the tag. After reviewing photos of the jersey, a representative for the NHL points out the front wasn't sewn on properly and there were spelling errors. (CBC)
When questioned, the clerk reassured us it was an authentic jersey.
The NHL doesn't think so.
After reviewing photos of the jersey, a representative for the corporation points out the front wasn't sewn on properly and there werespelling errors.
"Advanced athletic pereormance," reads the tag.
The jersey is also missing an NHL hologram.
"In identifying counterfeits, the best defence for fans is a good offence," said Tom Prochnow, vice-president of legal and business affairs at NHL Enterprises. "Most important is the NHL hologram that is affixed to all licensed NHL products."
A spokesperson wouldn't comment on individual enforcement matters, but said the NHL is involved in hundreds of enforcement actions each year against counterfeiters.
'We made a mistake'
Brad Hartlin, owner of the Locker Room, said he didn't know the jersey was fake.
"We made a mistake," he said.
Hartlin says he hasbuilt a business on authenticity.
Brad Hartlin, owner of the Locker Room, stands by the signatures in his store. (CBC)
The former Quebec Major Junior Hockey League player sells signed memorabilia, most of it sports related. But take a look around the store and you'll see a James Dean-signed cheque and a Charles Schulz-signed cartoon.
Hartlin said he buys hundreds of jerseys from trusted collectors every year. Now and then, unsigned jerseys are thrown into the collection, according to Hartlin.
He stands firmly by the signatures, but said the store will stop selling unsigned jerseys because the risk is too great.
"Going forward, after you brought this to our attention, it's just not worth it for us to do that. We can give them away, throw it out, whatever it is. Even if it is authentic, it's not worth it," he said.
"You assume the jerseys are real jerseys. But we don't know. It's almost impossible to tell the difference without doing some major research into it."
He compares it to fake IDs.
"On a weekend we can confiscate 100 IDs a night. It's absolutely insane what goes on out there. Every now and then one is going to slip through the cracks," Hartlin says.
'Slip through the cracks'
The Locker Room has a money-back guarantee.
"That kind of goes in itself, to say we stand by everything we sell," said Hartlin. "Things can slip through the cracks."
Voyer said it wasn't made clear to him the jerseys might not be authentic.
"Who can we trust now? We shouldn't be asking ourselves if it's real or not," he said.
Voyersays he now will gethis Habs gear from the official Canadiens store. He wants other sports fans in Halifax to be wary.
"It's not a fun shopping experience," he said. "Be aware when you buy. Now before I buy these types of stuff, autographs, I want to make sure it's a real one. You need experts sometimes."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:48:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CBC At Issue panel on potential upset in Alberta </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/cbc-at-issue-panel-upset-ahead-in-alberta-election-1.3056908?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>CBC At Issue panel: Upset ahead in Alberta election?
Peter Mansbridge talks with Andrew Coyne,  Bruce Anderson, Chantal Hbert and Kathleen Petty
CBC News Posted: May 01, 2015 8:48 AM ET Last Updated: May 01, 2015 8:48 AM ET
The Alberta Election | At Issue 13:15
Alberta election: Rob Brown talks with CBC's political panel ramping up to Tuesday's election. 6:27
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 20:45:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Muslim teen in France banned from class for long skirt</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/trending/french-teen-s-skirt-deemed-too-long-for-her-to-attend-school-1.3055606?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>French teen's skirt deemed too long for her to attend school
Online backlash sparks 'I wear my skirt as I please' Twitter trend
CBC News Posted: Apr 30, 2015 1:45 PM ET Last Updated: Apr 30, 2015 2:18 PM ET
Related Stories
Theinternetresponded by deeming the decision ridiculous and the ensuing outragespawned thehashtag#JePorteMaJupeCommeJeVeux, translated into English as "I wear my skirt as I please."
French Muslim student kept from class over long skirt http://t.co/0KWaCmixsH #JePorteMaJupeCommeJeVeux pic.twitter.com/o2kACg3Tiz
 @AJStream
The school is standingby itsdecision, arguing that the plain black skirt "conspicuously" showed religious affiliation, AFP reported.
According to the 2004 law that governs secularity in schools, veils, the Jewish kippa or large Christian crosses are all banned in educational establishments, but "discreet religious signs" are allowed.
The student, who removes her head scarf daily before entering school, was quoted by a local newspaper as saying the skirt was "nothing special, it's very simple, there's nothing conspicuous. There is no religious sign whatsoever."
Kenneth Roth, a U.S. attorney who is the executive director of Human Rights Watch, tweeted that the decision was "carrying secularism too far."
He wasn't alone. Ranging from angry to dripping with sarcasm, online reactionto the school's decision has been overwhelmingly negative.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
