<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:39:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suspended NDP rookie apologizes to LGBT community for 'homophobic' image</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/deborah-drever-apologizes-to-lgbt-community-vows-to-gain-calgary-bow-s-trust-1.3088381?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Deborah Drever's Facebook page
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
Deborah Drever, who was suspended from the Alberta NDP caucus last week after a series of social media gaffes, has apologized for her "problematic" posts.
MLA Deborah Drever expresses regret over offensive photo
"I am sorry that my actions were hurtful," the 26-year-old political rookie posted to her Facebook page Tuesday.
"My flippant attempt at humour backfired and I sincerely apologize to my constituents and to all Albertans for that. I am also sorry that I was the source of significant distraction from what should have been a time of celebration for Premier [Rachel]Notley and the NDP caucus."
Drever's troubles started almost immediately after winning her northwest Calgary seat onMay 5when controversialphotos emerged of her posing next to a T-shirt emblazoned with marijuana leaves and posing as a victim of asexual assault for a heavy metal band's album cover.
Deborah Drever appears on the album cover of the metal band Gatekrashor. (Gatekrashor/Facebook)
Then another image, featuringformer premierJim Prenticeand interim Alberta PC leader Ric McIver, led to her suspension from the NDP caucus.
"I apologize to allAlbertansfor the homophobic statements contained in this image, which are completely contrary to the views of our party and our future government," said premier-designate RachelNotleyin a statement last week.
Dreversaid the image was a screen capture of her Instagram account from over a year ago.
'Never intended to convey an insult'
"I want to stress in the strongest possible terms that my comment was never intended to convey an insult to LGBTQI* people," she wrote in her statement."I also want to make it perfectly clear that I know now that my intent doesn't matter. When it comes to discriminatory language or actions, intent is irrelevant when it causes harm to another person or persons."
An NDP spokesperson says the above image came from a closed Instagram account called 'drevfever.' (Instagram)
Drever says she is a strong supporter of equal rights for all Albertans, and understands the need for gay-straight alliances in all schools around the province.
She says she is dedicated to the job and plans to win the trust of her constituents in Calgary-Bow.
"I intend to serve as the MLA for Calgary-Bow, as I was elected to do, and I will sit as an Independent MLA. I am ready to work hard to ensure my constituents are well-represented and I will continue to promote the core NDP values of inclusion and fairness upon which I ran."
Members of the legislative assembly will be sworn in at a ceremony in Edmonton on June 1.
Notley says she will review whether Drever has a future in the NDP caucus next year. She askedthe young politician tospeak out clearly on issues of violence against womenand homophobia, in the meantime.
"I appreciate the premier's past advice and will live up to the expectations she has set out for me over the coming months," saysDrever in her statement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Auditor general says he'll recommend RCMP investigate 10 senators</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/10-senators-to-be-referred-to-rcmp-auditor-general-michael-ferguson-says-1.3088542?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>10 senators to be referred to RCMP, Auditor General Michael Ferguson says
Audits have found questionable spending in 30 expense cases
CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 5:37 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 7:44 PM ET
AG says he'll recommend RCMP investigate senators 2:35
Ian Binnie, ex-Supreme Court justice, to arbitrate Senate expense claims
Auditor General Michael Ferguson says he will recommend that 10 of the senate expense cases investigated by his office be referred to the RCMP.
Ferguson told Evan Solomon, host of CBC News Network's Power &amp; Politics, in an interview Tuesday that his office has turned up 30 cases of problematic spending  and that some of those cases should be investigated by the RCMP.
Ian Binnie, ex-Supreme Court justice, to arbitrate Senate expense claims
Ferguson later clarified to CBC News that the number of senators facing possible investigation by the RCMP is 10.
Ferguson's much-anticipated report into senate expenses will be released next week. His office has been conducting a review of current and former senators' expenses over the past two years.
Auditor General Michael Ferguson says he will recommend 10 senators to the RCMP  following his office's audit of senator's expenses.  (Adrian Wyld/Canadian Press)
"We'll deliver the report later next week then the Senate will have to go through their process," Ferguson told CBC News after his Power &amp; Politics interview.
"It may be the week after before they actually get it tabled and before we can speak to it."
Officials from Senate Speaker Leo Housakos' office agreed it could take anywhere from hours to days before the report is ready to be made public. That can only be done after it has been tabled in the Senate.
Ghislain Desjardins, a spokesman for Ferguson, could not confirm whether or not names of specific senators would be presented in the report.
Earlier Tuesday, Senate Speaker Housakos announced Ian Binnie, the retired supreme court justice, as the special arbiter between the Auditor General and Senators.
He'll be responsible with negotiating any disputes that come out of Ferguson's report. Housakos confirmed that all cases can be brought to the new arbiter.
"Arbitration will be available to senators, both current and former, who disagree with the findings of the auditor general," Housakos told reporters.
"Any case where there are disagreements will have the arbitration, including those referred to the RCMP."
Senators have been preparing themselves for the results of the audit since RCMP launched investigations into the spending habits of suspended Senator Mike Duffy and three of his Senate colleagues: suspended senators Patrick Brazeau and Pamela Wallin and retired senator Mac Harb.
Duffy's trial is currently on three-week break. He is facing 31 charges of fraud, breach of trust and bribery. Duffy has pleaded not guilty to the charges.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I'm not a quitter,' says ex-cop trying to crack Highway of Tears cases on his own time</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/aboriginal/ex-rcmp-officer-probes-highway-of-tears-leads-on-own-time-1.3087350?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Ex-RCMP officer probes Highway of Tears leads on own time
P.I. Ray Michalko on a mission to solve cases of missing and murdered in northern B.C.
ByNick Purdon, CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 5:00 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 6:33 PM ET
Ex- Cop Probes Missing Women Cases (Excerpt) 2:21
Related Stories
Highway of Tears investigation yields 'strong suspects' but no charges
For 10 years,private investigator Ray Michalkohas been trying to solve British Columbia's infamous Highway of Tears cases but nobody pays him to determine what may have happened to themurdered and missing women along that800-kilometrestretch.
RCMP say the route alongHighway 16 thatwinds between Prince George and Prince Rupertis whereat least 18 women have gone missing or been murdered since 1969. Seventeen of thosecases remain unsolved.
"I'm disappointed that some of these cases haven't been solved," says Michalko, 67."I'm stubborn. I'm not a quitter. And I like to help people."
Michalkowasan RCMP officer, but leftthe force after nine years because he prefers to work alone.
INTERACTIVE: The unsolved cases of missing and murdered indigenous women
"I remember once counting the number of side roads that a killer could drive off to dispose of a body in an hour, and there were a hundred maybe more," Michalko says. "It's the perfect place to go missing forever."
Whenever he gets a chance,Michalko drives north from his home in Vancouver and follows his leads. Over the past decade, he estimates, he hasput in a year of 40-hour weeks.
Hitting the streets for answers
The killings of teenagers Roxanne Thiara, pictured, and Leah Germaine brought private investigator Ray Michalko to Prince George, B.C., recently.  (CBC)
In May,Michalko was in Prince George following up on a lead in the killingsof teenagers Leah Germaine and Roxanne Thiara apparentmurders that happened in 1994.
Michalko believes the cases are linked and the killer lived near the now-abandoned elementary school where Germaine's body was dumped after she hadbeen stabbed to death.
"This theory has been with me since I started,"Michalkosays "and I keep coming back to it."
BothGermaineandThiarawere involved in drugs and prostitution,Michalkosaid. The women had something else in commonboth had said they wanted to clean up andget out.
'I didn't expect quite the resistance to what I was doing.'
- RayMichalko, private investigator
"It makes me wonder if the people responsible for running that business,using them, like their pimps, had something to do with it,"Michalkosaid, adding that he`s tracking down who the players in that trade were back then.
Michalko's investigation technique is simple: He walks the streets of Prince George and talks to as many street-involved people as he can. He hands out dozens of business cards.
"I still believe there are people out there that know something," Michalko says. "It's just getting them to come forward that is the biggest problem."
Hope for families
Over the years,Michalkohas grown close to a few of the familiessearching for answers to what happened to their lovedones.
Sixteen-year-old Ramona Wilson went missing in June 1994. Her body was found 10 months later.  (CBC)
Sixteen-year-oldRamonaWilson went missing in June1994. Her body was found 10 months later. TheRCMPhasinvestigatedRamona'smurder,but hasbeen unable to solve it.
"Ray's been a really good friend to us and has inspired us in some different ways when we did feel hopeless,"said Brenda Wilson,Ramona'ssister."He always seems to show up when we feel that way. And it's been good."
'Thorn in side' for RCMP
Michalko's investigations haven't been popular with the RCMP over the years. In 2008, the Mounties sent him a letter warning that he could be charged with obstructing justice if he wasn't careful.
Michalkosays theRCMPwants him to go home and forget about the women's deaths."I didn't expect quite the resistance to what I was doing.I am a thorn in their side, to put it politely," Michalko says.
The case ofRamonaWilson
"You know,the RCMP is very territorial and I am sticking my nose in what they see as their business," he says. "I would have felt the same back in the day myself. I can understand that. I didn't expect quite the resistance to what I was doing."
Watch The National tonight for more on RayMichalkoand his quest to crack theHighway of Tears cases.
CBC News continuesto investigate Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women and Girls by exploring the stories of these women, their families and their communities.
If you have any information on these cases please contact mmiw@cbc.ca.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:35:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida tornado blows bouncy castle away with 3 kids inside</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/trending/florida-tornado-blows-bouncy-castle-away-with-3-kids-inside-1.3088259?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Florida tornado blows bouncy castle away with 3 kids inside
Children injured falling out of airborne bouncy castle after waterspout rocks Memorial Day beach party
ByLauren O'Neil, CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 4:35 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 5:20 PM ET
Bounce house blows away in Florida 1:28
Related Stories
Bouncy castle rules introduced in Cornwall
Three childrenwere injured at a Memorial Day eventinFlorida onMondayafter unexpectedly taking one very dangerousbouncy castle ride.
According to the Fort Lauderdale Police Department ,two inflatable bounce houses were uprooted from a localbeachMonday afternoon when a waterspout came on shore  one of them, with three kids inside.
Waterspouts become tornadoes when they cross onto land.
The twister, which has since been classified as an EF-0 tornado by the National Weather Service,hurled both castlesabove the tree line, across four lanes of traffic, and into a nearby parking lot,shocking sunbathers andattendees of the city-sponsored Memorial Day family activity zone as it flew overhead.
Fortunately, all three children were ejected from thehousebefore it left the beach area,droppingfrom the airborne inflatable onto sand.
Five-year-old Shadaja Bryant broke her arm falling from a bouncy castle that was sent airbone by a tornado in Florida on Monday. (Brandon Burchett/Facebook)
But they were not without injury.
NBC Miami reports that a five-year-old girl, a six-year-old girl, and an 11-year-old boy were transported toBroward Health Medical Center following the incident.
"I was thinking I was about to die,"Shadaja Bryant,5, told NBC Miami."I was in the bounce house and then it flew while I was in there, then I fell in the dirt."
Shadaja and the 11-year-oldwere treated for minor fractures and released from hospital, while the six-year-old girl was listed as stable, but held overnight for observation.
Shadaja sustaineda broken arm in the incident as her father watched feeling "helpless."
"I was crying all the way there and from the time I saw the bounce house to the hospital I was crying, I was shaken real bad," said Ryan Howard. "I thought it was safe."
'It kept spinning and that's when the little girl fell on the concrete.'
 Jammelia Wrap, eyewitness
Howard is not the first parent to learn the hard way thatinflatable bounce houses aren't as safe as they seem.
Justone year ago this month, a bounce house at a New Yorkapartment complex carried three children more than 15 metres into the air, leaving two of them with serious injuries.
A 2014 study conducted at Toronto's Ryerson University found that inflatable bounce houses account for 42 per centof amusement park injuries in all age groups, with more than half of theinjuries in kids aged 15 and under.
As video captured by a beachgoer who witnessed thebouncy castle incidentin Floridaon Monday shows,the sight of such aseemingly tame children's attraction taking flight could be enough to scare some people away from them for good.
"It was like spinning around, broke the basketball goal, it broke the light poles,"Jammelia Wrap told NBC. "It kept spinning and that's when the little girl fell on the concrete."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 18:19:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Joe Oliver to consult on 'voluntary' Canada Pension Plan boost</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/joe-oliver-to-consult-on-voluntary-canada-pension-plan-boost-1.3087896?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Joe Oliver to consult on 'voluntary' Canada Pension Plan boost
Mandatory increase in CPP still considered 'payroll tax' by Conservative government
CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 11:19 AM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 6:41 PM ET
Finance Minister Joe Oliver told the House of Commons Tuesday that consultations will begin soon for a 'voluntary' enhancement of the Canada Pension Plan. (Sean Kilpatrick/Canadian Press)
Related Stories
Voluntary target benefit pension scheme proposed by Ottawa
Finance Minister Joe Oliver says his government is ready to start consulting Canadians on allowing larger, "voluntary," contributions to the Canada Pension Plan.
"We are open to giving Canadians the option to voluntarily contribute more to the Canada Pension Plan to supplement their current retirement savings,"he told the House of Commonson Tuesday.
Analysis: Canadian pensions: Should we be forced to save?
Oliver said the move would build on the Harper government's record of creating more options for retirement savings, including the pooled pension plans and tax-free savings account alternatives championed by the Conservatives. A statement released by his office said that "by providing voluntary, flexible savings tools,Canada's retirement system is, in fact, now among the best in the world."
No more details wereprovided in his brief answer to a planted question from a Conservative caucus colleague. It's unclear how the voluntary contributions would work, or what limits would apply.
But Oliver reiterated his government's position on hiking basic premiums, something federal government talking points have called a "mandatory, job-killing, economy-destabilizing, pension-tax hike on employees and employers."
"What we will not do isreach into the pockets of Canadians with a mandatory payroll tax, like the Liberals and the NDP would do," Oliver said in question period.
"Aone-size fits all pensiontax hike is not what Canadians want, nor what they need," Oliver's release said.
Policy reversal?
This is the second time in two years the government has seemingly done an about-face on the CPP issue.
In 2010, then-finance minister Jim Flaherty announced consultations had begun to expand CPP, calling the program "the envy of the world."
He said the expansion should be "modest and phased in," and that provinces were on board.
Then, in 2013, he abruptly backtracked and started referring to the CPP as a "payroll tax" that the country couldn't afford until there was more economic growth.
Employees and employers are each required to contributeup to almost $2,480 annually on income up to $53,600.
This year, the CPP pays out a maximum benefit of $12,780.
Past proposals have suggested doubling both the contribution cap and the maximum payout. Although Flaherty had made it clear he wasn't in favour of going that high, he never publicly outlined what numbers he had in mind.
Oliver now intends to spend the summer months ahead of a coming election consulting with "experts and stakeholders," on what voluntary contributions to the CPP might look like.
Finance critic NDP MP Nathan Cullen questioned what he called theConservatives' "death-bed conversion" to CPP enhancement.
"It's incredibly vague. It's a non-announcement today. This is at the very last minute. If they were serious about this, we would have seen something a lot sooner," he said.
Ontario Liberal MPPMitzieHunter, the associate minister of finance, dismissed the announcement, saying the federal government "has made it clear they have no real interest in enhancing CPP."
"It's disappointing that the federal government is only concerned with their short-term election prospects instead of providing a secure retirement for millions of Canadians."
Canada's most populous province recently passed a bill approving the creation of a provincial pension plan that would start in 2017. Ontario's plan, which would be phased in over a two-year period, would be for those who don't have a workplace plan.
With a file from The Canadian Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:39:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ontario high school teachers' strikes illegal, labour board rules</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/ontario-high-school-teachers-strikes-illegal-labour-board-rules-1.3088550?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Ontario high school teachers' strikes illegal, labour board rules
Students, teachers in Peel, Durham to return to class on Wednesday
CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 5:39 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 7:37 PM ET
About 250 striking English public high school teachers rally outside a Sudbury, Ont., hotel.  (Olivia Stefanovich/CBC)
Related Stories
Janet McDougald's statement
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
The strikes by Ontario high school teachers in the school board districts of Durham, Rainbow and Peel are illegal, the Ontario Labour Relations Board ruled on Tuesday.
The labour board determined that the local strikes at the three school boards are in contravention of the School Boards Collective Bargaining Act.
Is there a better way than strikes to resolve labour disputes in education?
The labour board also askedthe Ontario Secondary School Teachers' Federation, the union representing the teachers in the three boards, to "cease and desist their unlawful strike" starting from Tuesday. 
Following the ruling, Peel and Durham school boards said students and teachers will return to schools on Wednesday. Students at Sudbury'sRainbow District School Board will also return to class .
The strikes have keptmore than 70,000 high school studentsout of class for six weeks.
Precedent-setting ruling
Janet McDougald, chair of the Peel District School Board, calledthe labour board's decision a "precedent-setting ruling."
"We're pleased that the OLRB's ruling supports what we've believed all along  that provincial OSSTF began an unlawful strike in Peel to put pressure on provincial negotiations," she said in a statement .
Because the labour board's decision was announced late in the day, reopening school would be a complex process,McDougaldadded.
"We know that with this little notice it won't be a perfect return to school tomorrow, but our incredible staff will make sure it is the best possible one for our students," she said.
The Ontario Ministry of Education said it is currently reviewing the ruling and will be determining next steps.
"Part of the determination will be hearing how OSSTF responds to the ruling," Education Minister Liz Sandals said in a statement.
Read the labour board's decision below
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:26:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Student wearing ripped jeans, tank top, sent home for breaking dress code </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/windsor/london-student-in-jeans-tank-top-sent-home-for-breaking-dress-code-1.3088412?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>London student in jeans, tank top sent home for breaking dress code
Students to show support for Laura Anderson by wearing ripped jeans, tank tops Wednesday
CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 4:26 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 4:42 PM ET
Laura Anderson was sent home to change by her vice-principal after showing up to school in ripped jeans and a tank top, stating she failed to follow the school's dress code. (Sophie McGregor/Facebook)
A London, Ont., teen says she was sent home from school for wearing ripped jeans and a tank top to class on Monday.
Laura Anderson said thevice-principal at A.B. Lucas called the clothes "inappropriate" and in violation of the school's dress code.
"They just said that what I was wearing was not appropriate for school and that I should not be able to be seen in school until I change," said Anderson. "I went home and changed into regular jeans and a baggy t-shirt, but felt very sad about the incident and very degraded by the incident."
Anderson said she's not a troublemakerand, at the time, accepted what the vice-principaltold her to do.
"My intention was not for it to be sexual...I have the right as an individual to wear what makes me feel comfortable."
- Laura Anderson, Student
The Grade 12 student who will be attending Queens University next year for literature, is on student council and saidshe has respect for the administration at the school.
"My intention was not for it to be sexual.I don't put on shorts or tank tops so I get sexual attention from men or other people at my school," she said. "I put it on because it's hot outside and I think I have the right as an individual to wear what makes me feel comfortable."
Students to wear ripped jeans, tank tops
On Wednesday high school students from A.B. Lucas as well other schools in London will dress in support of Anderson bywearing tank tops and ripped jeans.
They will also be usinga hashtag saying #mybodymybusiness.
"This incident has given people a chance to really open up their voices, and really give themselves confidence in what they belive inand what they think they should be allowed to do," said Anderson.
Anderson wants to sit down with administration, the superintendent and student council at Lucasand discuss whetherthe rules regarding dress code need to be evaluated.
"As educators I understand that they care about us, but believing that they'rewrong about this, I really want to work with them to redefine what they think about dress code," she said.
Dress code petition started
Classmates have rushed to defend Anderson's choice of clothing.
In a Facebook post, Sophie McGregor said"what is most amazing about this whole thing is the fact that I was wearing a short sleeve t-shirt and short shorts."
"I am revealing more skin than my friend," McGrergor continued.
Ashlyn Nicolle started an online petition at change.org in support of Anderson.
"To ask female students to put sweaters on and 'cover up' to ensure the male students are not distracted or exposed to female sexuality is sexist and outdated," Nicolle wrote. "This standard presumes that female students are considered a distraction and therefore its a females actions that must be policed.
"The sexualization of a teenage girls body is not her problem, it is the problem of those who choose to sexualize a 17-year-old's body."
Nicolle wants wording in the school's dress code reworked.
"A.B. Lucas seriously needs to take another look at their dress code and reconsider the lines: "clothing must not be inappropriately revealing" and "administration will determine what is considered to be appropriate dress for school", because they are imprecise, unjustified, and resulting in the punishment of students for the administration's ambiguity," the petition reads.
The petition has been digitally signed by 1,500 people.
School superintendent weighs in
Lucas principal Tom McLeod declined to speak with CBC. However, Sheila Powell, the school's superintendent spoke with CBC's Gary Ennett.
Powell said she cannot comment on Anderson's specific case, but added that each school has a specific dress code.
The dress code is reviewed every year with students and parents, she said.
"Student protests always offer opportunity to engage in dialogue and discussion about what's appropriate and why there may be rules, if they need to be changed."
-SheilaPowell, Lucassuperintendent
"When concerns arose yesterday about a student's attire, the school code was followed, and the student was given an opportunity to address the concerns and comply with the dress code that is outlined for them," said Powell.
She said administrators will enforce the dress code when the students dress in solidarity with Anderson on Wednesday.
"Student protests always offer opportunity to engage in dialogue and discussion about what's appropriate and why there may be rules. If they need to be changed and if the protest raises the opportunity for discussion with students, the principal very much welcomes that opportunity," said Powell.
The school has its "dress expectations" online:
Clothing must not be inappropriately revealing and free of profane or vulgar language. Shirts must cover the midriff and the back.
No references to drugs, alcohol, sex, demeaning or offensive slogans.
All shorts and skirts should be past the fingertips of your outstretched hands.
Skirts, shorts and pants should completely cover undergarments.
Pants must be able to stay up at the waist.
No hats or head wear. Hats may be confiscated if worn in school. Only head wear worn for religious or medical reasons is exempt.
Administration will determine what is considered to be appropriate dress for school.
Students who do not conform to this guideline will not be allowed to attend classes and will be sent home to change.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:03:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baja berry pickers work for as little as $1 US an hour</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/photos/baja-berry-pickers-work-for-as-little-as-1-us-an-hour-1.3088300?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Baja berry pickers work for as little as $1 US an hour
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:48:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Environment minister's briefing to MPs lacks key carbon emissions figures</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/leona-aglukkaq-official-can-t-do-the-math-on-climate-targets-for-mps-1.3088256?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Leona Aglukkaq official 'can't do the math' on climate targets for MPs
New targets would cut carbon emission to 30 per cent below 2005 levels by 2030
ByMargo McDiarmid, environment reporter, CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 3:48 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 3:48 PM ET
Environment Minister Leona Aglukkaq was grilled over her recently announced climate targets in a parliamentary committee on Tuesday. (Adrian Wyld/Canadian Press)
Related Stories
The federal environment minister and her top officials were unable to provide concrete numbers on Canada's new plan to cut greenhouse gasemissions to a parliamentary committee.
Leona Aglukkaq's appearance created some sparks at a normallylow-key Commons environment committee meeting.
She was grilled on her recent announcement Canada will cut carbon emissions by 30 per cent below 2005 levels by 2030.
That target has been submitted to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change asCanada's intended, nationally-determined contribution. It's part of the international effort to keep global temperatures from rising more than two degrees.
Aglukkaq called the targets "fair and ambitious," but didn't say whatthe 30 per centreduction actually means in tonnes of carbon pollution that would have to be cut annually.
Liberal MP John McKaywent after Aglukkaq's deputy minister, Michael Martin, for the answer.
"What is it in terms of megatonnes?" he asked.
"Actually I can't do the math off the top offthe top of my head but would happy to provide the number to the committee," said Martin.
It clearly took McKay by surprise.
"Really?" he asked. "Ifind itquite remarkable that you should state the target for 2030 of 30 per cent and not know what that is in megatonnes."
Martin promised to provide numbers to the committee members at some pointlater.
When ministers appear at committee they are accompanied by their top bureaucrats and a herd of staff lugging heavy binders of information. But none of those binders appeared to contain the number Canada will strive to reach.
McKay found it all veryodd.
"I would have thought if you had a percentage reduction you would know what the bottom line is," he said in an interview outside the committee hearings.
"They just want to have a press release a talking point, but no real number."
Aglukkaq's staff denies avoiding question
Aglukkaq wouldn't talk about the target number with reporters either, but said her government is reducing the country's carbon footprint by bringing in rules for individual sectors.
"The sector-by-sector approach that we have taken reflects Canada's footprintand we are proud of those accomplishments and initiatives that we have taken," she said.
An hour later,Aglukkaq'sdirector of communications, Ted Laking,called CBC to sort out the confusion.
Canada has committed to a 30 per cent reduction of 2005 levels by 2030, ahead of an international climate change conference later this year.  (Frank Gunn/Canadian Press)
"I did the calculations on my way back to work," Laking said.
"The 2005 levels were 749megatonnes. Multiply that by 0.3 and you get 224, so it would be 224 megatonnes [reduction] by 2030," he said.
When asked why a deputy minister couldn't have easily done that too, Laking said:"That was cheesy question. He didn't have the numbers off the top of his head, he was not avoiding the question."
Laking later emailed a further clarification:"Canada's greenhouse gas emissions in 2005 were 749 MT. A 30 per centreduction of this is 225 MTs. The minister was happy to once again highlight Canada's ambitious target to reduce our emissions by 30 per centof 2005 levels by 2030," said the email.
Aglukkaq also told the committee she hasn't discussed details of Canada's new climate goal with the provinces, including Ontario, the largest jurisdiction in the country. The federal government had said provinces and territories must play a big part in helping Canada reaching its goal to cut carbon pollution.
"In the case of Ontario, I have not received the details of Ontario's plan in terms of their initiatives as to how it translates to actual GHG reductions," said Aglukkaq.
But a spokesman for Ontario's environment minister said the sum total of the consultation with his government was being asked to fill out a form detailing its goals.
"Demanding that provinces fill out a template form does not constitute sufficient consultation on behalf of the federal government, especially given the severity of the climate change problem," said Lucas Malinowski in an email.
"In developing its [intended, nationally-determined contribution], the federal government did not carry out a robust or genuine consultation with the province of Ontario," he added.
Aglukkaq says she plans to have detaileddiscussions on climate change and Canada's targetswith all the provinces at a meeting of Canadian Council of Ministers of the Environment next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 19:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Telecoms, governments keep Canadians in dark about rampant surveillance</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/rampant-telecom-surveillance-conducted-with-little-transparency-oversight-1.3087934?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Rampant telecom surveillance conducted with little transparency, oversight
Canadian governments, telecoms lag other countries when it comes to transparency about surveillance
ByEmily Chung, CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 12:49 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 1:52 PM ET
Outdated laws require government departments and agencies to report telecommunications interceptions, but not access to stored communications such as emails and text messages. (Igor Stevanovic/Shutterstock)
Related Stories
Citizen lab
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
Canadian telecommunications providers have been handing over vast amounts of customer information to law enforcement and government departments and agencies with little transparency or oversight, a new report says.
"We conclude that serious failures in transparency and accountability indicate that corporations are failing to manage Canadians' personal information responsibly," says the report released by Citizen Lab today that examineshow Canadiantelecommunications data ismonitored, collected andanalyzedby groups such as police, intelligence andgovernment agencies.
Blog post featuring report highlights
The report also criticizes the government's "irresponsibility surrounding accountability" with respect to telecommunications surveillance. It warns that that could endanger the development of Canada's digital economy and breed cynicism among citizens.
"Access to our private communications is incredibly sensitive," said Christopher Parsons, lead author of the study and a postdoctoral researcher at Citizen Lab, which conducts research on information technology in the context of human rights and global security.
New tool helps Canadians find out if telecoms are collecting their info
The report,funded by the Canadian Internet Registration Authority, showed Canadians recognize this and are very concerned.
"It raises real questions about the appropriateness of the powers or perhaps the appropriateness of the mandates or aggressiveness of the agencies that currently look to keep Canadians safe," Parsons said.
Outdated laws
He noted there's no way to know what the requests were about, how many there were or whether any one person's data was requested, as Canadian law doesn't require police to record or report any of that information.
'Access to our private communications is incredibly sensitive,' said Christopher Parsons, lead author of the study and a postdoctoral researcher at Citizen Lab. (Courtesy Christopher Parsons)
Outdated laws require government departments and agencies to report telecommunications interceptions, but not access to stored communications such as emails and text messages, nor "non-sensitive" information such as records of calls dialed and received.
The Canada Border Services Agency is one of the few government departments that tracks such requests. In 2012 and 2013, it made 18,849 requests for telecommunications information. None were interceptions, the study found.
"That really indicates that the interception reports, while they're very rigorous, they're such a limited data set that they really don't explain to parliamentarians or the public the extent or kind of surveillance that are commonplace in Canada today," Parsons said.
A Supreme Court decision last year has forced police to start getting a warrant before requesting subscriber information from telecoms . While that has slashed the number of police requests for data , Parsons warns that new legislation that is currently before the Senate could make it easy for telecom data to be shared among police and government agencies.
Supreme Court ruling hobbles pursuit of child predators, police say
New bill a concern
Bill C-51 would allow, for example, the Canada Revenue Agency to request information about a telecom customer related to a tax issue, then pass it on to the CBSA, RCMP or CSIS to probe something only marginally related, Parsons said.
Anti-terror Bill C-51 to be changed as Tories respond to criticism
Meanwhile, oversight bodies such as the privacy commissioner of Canada have no way to share information with other oversight bodies, such as the Security Intelligence Review Committee, which oversees CSIS.
And while the privacy commssioner can go to court to force private companies to comply with Canadian privacy laws, it can't do that with government departments or agencies under the Privacy Act, Parsons said.
Another concern cited in the report is that governments and telecommunications companies have spent the past decade or so negotiating behind closed doors about technology to allow interceptions and the types of interceptions that should be mandated into law.
"I think that's incredibly inappropriate," Parsonssaid. Such interceptions are "something that we just need to do in contemporary law and order environment, but doesn't have to take place in secretive back rooms." He believes discussions about it should involve the public. 
The report offers a long list of recommendations for corporations and government as to how they can become more transparent and accountable about telecommunications surveillance.
For example, Parsons hopes that Canadian telecommunications companies, which have just started releasing transparency reports about requests for customer data, will begin to issue more standardized and detailed reports as they do in the U.S.
He added, "I think we're absolutely behind."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:39:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Phone booth destroyed in bizarre B.C. feud to be replaced</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/coalmont-b-c-phone-booth-destroyed-in-bizarre-feud-to-be-replaced-1.3088357?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
Coalmont, B.C., phone booth destroyed in bizarre feud to be replaced
Telus initially said it would not replace the phone booth  but residents refused to take no for an answer
ByDaybreak South, CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 3:39 PM PT Last Updated: May 26, 2015 4:24 PM PT
Coalmont's public phone booth was destroyed in March after this vehicle crashed into it as part of what police claim was a feud between two residents. (Ole Juul)
Coalmont BC loses its only phone boot in allegedly homicidal feud. 6:05
Related Stories
Coalmont, B.C., loses its only public phone to bizarre feud
After the destruction of Coalmont's only phone booth in May during a bizarre feud and alleged murder attempt, residents of the tiny B.C. town found themselves facing another fight with Telus.
At stake? The phone booth itself. Telus declined to replace the wreckedpayphone,but Bob and Diane Sterne wouldn't take no for an answer.
Roland Giroux runs a makeshift shelter for lambs and goats. He is charged with attempted murder in the phone booth incident. (Jennifer Thuncher)
While the Sternes' social media campaign and petition garnered little attention, it was a direct email to a Telus executive that got things moving.
"My wife kind of did a Hail Mary play and she put out an email to all of the Telus executives that she could find names for," Bob Sterne told Chris Walker, the host of CBC Radio One's Daybreak South.
"A week later  they decided that they were going to install a new pay phone that was publicly accessible in the area."
The phone booth was destroyed at the beginning of May after a long-simmering feud between Roland Giroux and Warren Spence boiled over.
Giroux is alleged to have crashed his car into the phone booth in an attempt to killSpence, who was using it at the time. Spence managed to get out of the phone booth before the car hit, but he was still injured.
The result? Spence is in physiotherapy, Giroux is charged with attempted murder, and Coalmont's lone public phone booth was in pieces.
Telus initially said it wouldn't replace the demolished phone booth, but has since changed its mind.  (Ole Juul)
Located in rugged mining country 20 kilometres west of Princeton, Coalmont has a population of roughly 100 full-time residents. Cellphone coverage is spotty.
Sterne said his biggest concern was that withouta payphone, Coalmonthad lost its only public access to 911.
"There's a lot of tourist traffic here in the summer time particularly, and some in the winter as well, and the booth was right by the Trans Canada Trail,and there's a lot of other heavier-used tourist trails in the area, so it was very important."
It's not yet known when the phone will be replaced.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:01:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kids' motor, social skills improve when cord cutting delayed</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/health/kids-motor-and-social-skills-improve-when-cord-clamping-delayed-at-birth-1.3088257?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Kids' motor and social skills improve when cord clamping delayed at birth
Boys, more prone to iron deficiency after birth than girls, showed more improvements
CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 3:01 PM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 3:01 PM ET
Delayed umbilical cord clamping can have quite an effect on the amount of iron in the blood, which is important for brain development just after birth. (iStock)
Related Stories
Long-term Follow-up of Placental Transfusion in Full-term Infants
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
Children developed better fine-motor skills when the clamping of their umbilical cord at birth was delayed several minutes compared with just seconds, according to a new randomized trial.
Delaying clamping allows fetal blood circulating in the placenta to be transfused to the infant, which has been shown to reduce iron deficiency at four to six months of age. Now thelonger term benefits of a delayare becoming clearer.
Delaying umbilical cord clamping better for baby: McMaster expert
Researchers in Sweden randomly assigned 382 full-term infants born after low-risk pregnancies to be clamped at least three minutes after delivery or within 10 seconds of birth.
When the children were four, a psychologist assessed them on standard tests of IQ, motor skills and behaviour. The parents also filled in questionnaires about their child's communication and social skills.
"Delayed cord clamping compared with early cord clamping improved scores and reduced the number of children having low scores in fine-motor skills and social domains," the study's lead author, Dr. Ola Andersson of Uppsala University in Sweden, and his co-authors said in Tuesday's issue of JAMA Pediatrics.
The fine-motor skill tests showed those in the delayed clamping group had a more mature pencil grip.
There was also a difference in boys, who researchers said are generallymore prone to iron deficiency than girls. Boysshowed more improvements in fine-motor skills with delayed clamping.
Andersson said delayed cord clamping can have quite an effect on the amount of iron in the blood, which is important for brain development just after birth.
Simple, no-cost intervention
In 2013, the respected Cochrane Collaboration , an international network of scientists who regularly review medical research, concluded: "A more liberal approach to delaying clamping of the umbilical cord in healthy term infants appears to be warranted."
In a journal editorial published with the new study, Dr. Hieki Rabe of the Brighton and Sussex Medical School in England and her co-authors concluded "the potential benefit of improving maternal and neonatal care by a simple no cost intervention of delayed [cord clamping]should be championed by the international community."
So far, Canadian midwives commonly delay cord clamping . The World Health Organization recommends waiting at least one minute after birth, or until visible pulsing stops, to clamp the umbilical cord. In 2012, the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists opinion, said it supports delayed cord clamping for premature infants, but said there is insufficient evidence to prove a benefit for full-term babies.
In medical circles, cord clamping has been common for about 60 years under the mistaken belief it could reduce the risk of hemorrhage. It's a psychological hurdle for doctors to change the practice, Rabe said.
The researchers noted the results applied to a low-risk population of children born in a high-income country.
"If you did the same study in India you might see a marked difference, the reason is that there is excellent nutrition in Sweden," Rabe said.
There are still questions about cord clamping, such as the ideal time to wait, best position to hold the infant and the role of milking the cord as an alternative, the editorial writers said.
A limitation of the study is the drop out, or attrition, rate among participants was relatively high at about 31 per cent.
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:03:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's deadly heatwave kills 750 as temperature nears 50 C</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/india-heat-wave-death-toll-climbs-to-750-1.3087648?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>India heat wave death toll climbs to 750
Daily temperatures in states of Andhra Pradesh and Telengana hit between 45 and 48 C
The Associated Press Posted: May 26, 2015 9:03 AM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 9:17 AM ET
More than 750 people have died in southern India since the middle of April as soaring summer temperatures scorch the country, officials said Tuesday.
The southeastern states of Andhra Pradesh and Telengana have been hit the hardest.
More than 550 people have died from the unrelenting heat in Andhra Pradesh since May 13, state Deputy Chief Minister Nimmakayala Chinna Rajappa said.
A top state official in Telangana, Bhambal Ram Meena, said about 215 heat-related deaths have been reported since April 15.
Daily temperatures in both states have hit between 45 and 48 Celsius. Officials have urged people to stay hydrated and remain indoors as much as possible.
A child cools off in a pond near India Gate amid soaring temperatures in New Delhi on May 24, 2015. The temperature in New Delhi hit 45.5 C, according to the meteorological department. (Sajjad Hussain/AFP/Getty Images)
Blistering hot, dry winds have also swept across most parts of north and central India, wilting plants and forcing people to avoid the outdoors. In the cities, large crowds of office workers gather around stalls selling cold fruit drinks.
Weather officials say the sweltering temperatures are likely to continue in southern India for at least another week. Monsoon rains, expected to arrive in the southern state of Kerala in the first week of June, should bring some respite. The monsoon season runs through September as the rains gradually cover the entire country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 17:42:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Economist magazine calls Vancouver 'mind-numbingly boring'</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/vancouver-mind-numbingly-boring-economist-magazine-says-1.3087742?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Vancouver 'mind-numbingly boring,' Economist magazine says
Travel columnist says the B.C. city may be nice, but where is the fun in that?
ByMike Laanela, CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 7:42 AM PT Last Updated: May 26, 2015 10:50 AM PT
Vancouver is a popular tourist destination, but doesn't seem to agree with one Economic magazine travel writer, who calls the city 'mind-numbingly boring.'
Related Stories
Top 10 most livable cities include Vancouver, Calgary and Toronto
A columnist with The Economist magazine has taken another pot shot at Vancouver and its c onsistently high rankings on livability indexe s  but the city remains in great company it would appear.
The writer, who pens a business travel column under the name Gulliver , makes the argument that the more cities strive to be nicer places to live, the less interesting they become.
Top 10 most livable cities include Vancouver, Calgary and Toront o
For instance, he writes that New York has lost its edge since yuppies pushed the street prostitutes out of the Meat Packing District.
Similarly, London's Tube is now safe and one need not look over one's shoulder while walking the city's dark streets at night, he concludes.
All these improvements make for nice places to live and work, he says.
"But, here's the thing," he asks, "where's the fun in nice?"
Gulliver says livability indexes, which he used to compile for corporations, don't include the fun factor inherent in living in a dangerous, or at least slightly unsavoury metropolis.
"The trouble was," he writes,"measuring things such as crime levels, transport efficiency and housing stock, meant that the most anodyne cities inevitably rose to the top.
"Vienna, Vancouver and Geneva always seemed to do well. Pleasant cities, yes, but mind-numbingly boring.
"What right-minded person would rank Vienna a better city than Rio, or Vancouver preferable to Paris?"
Marks missed?
There is no evidence that the writer has visited Vancouver for the article, or how exciting he might consider dropping into a double-black diamond run at Whistler, meeting a bear while taking out the garbage, or jogging with a cougar in the Capilano watershed. But clearly, many of the exciting aspects of life valued by residents of the West Coast city are lost on him.
It may not be the Louvre, or Times Square, but a hike through cougar country on the outskirts of Vancouver can hardly be described as boring. (Getty Images/Flickr RF)
But The Economist does have a track record of missing the mark when it comes to Vancouver.
In 2011, the magazine's intelligence unit downgraded Vancouver's ranking on its own livability index because of traffic congestion.
The demotion was blamed on a crash thatclosed a nearby highway for 22 hours. The problem was the highway was the Malahat on Vancouver Islandabout 60 kilometres and a 95-minute ferry ride away.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 16:54:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RCMP conduct Montreal raids linked to radicalization investigation</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/montreal/rcmp-conduct-montreal-raids-linked-to-radicalization-investigation-1.3087704?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>RCMP conduct Montreal raids linked to radicalization investigation
Police seen removing boxes and computers from home in St-Leonard borough
CBC News Posted: May 26, 2015 9:54 AM ET Last Updated: May 26, 2015 5:23 PM ET
A home in St-Leonard, Que., was searched on Tuesday morning, linked to a police investigation into youth suspected of trying to go overseas to join jihadists. (Radio-Canada)
Related Stories
Quebec to table anti-radicalization bill after 10 teens arrested at Trudeau airport
RCMP and Montreal police carried out several raids around the city today linked to a radicalization investigation.
At least two of the raids were connected with the 10 Montreal youth recently arrested on suspicion of trying to leave the country to join jihadists in Turkey and Syria, the RCMP confirmed.
10 Montreal young people arrested on suspicion of wanting to join jihad
Police officers were seen removing boxes and computers from a home intheborough of St-Leonard, in the city's east end.
Investigators obtained a search warrant, but did not say what they are looking for. RCMP said it was the first time they had raided the residence.
Alberto Teixeira, a longtime resident in the area, said he woke to the sight of several RCMP officers on his streetknocking on an apartment door.
"Officers were going in and out since 7 a.m.," Teixeira said.
Just a block away, another raid took place at a semi-detached home where a teenager was arrested about a week ago.The raid there also lasted several hours.
The 10 teenagers arrested in mid-May were released without charges, but their passports were confiscated.
RCMP said at the time the investigation was continuing.
A lawyer for one of the people arrested told Radio-Canada his client is a "victim" who was approached online and promised "a better life."
Some of those arrested have ties to the sixQuebecers who are thought to have left for Turkey, en route to Syria, in January.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
