<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:17:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isère, France attack: 1 beheaded, 2 injured at gas factory</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/is%C3%A8re-france-attack-1-beheaded-2-injured-at-gas-factory-1.3128657?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. local timewhen a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
Notre rponse, c'est l'action, la prvention, la dissuasion et donc la ncessit de porter des valeurs et de ne pas cder  la peur, jamais.
 @fhollande
"Islamist terrorism has struck once again in France," said FrenchPrime Minister Manuel Valls.
Authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.A local media outlet, Ledauphine.com, said the victim was a manager with a transportation company who was on the site to make a delivery.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
Ledauphine.com said anotherperson, who was seen driving back and forthin front of the Air Products factory,wasarrested at their residence inSaint-Quentin-Fallavier.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, in central eastern France on Friday. An attacker carrying an Arabic banner killed one person at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a security official. (Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images)
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Penn. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
The attack occurred in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, in the Isre region between Grenoble and Lyon. (CBC)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obamacare support grows amid latest Supreme Court win</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/obamacare-support-grows-amid-latest-supreme-court-win-1.3128170?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Obamacare support grows amid latest Supreme Court win
King v. Burwell decision allows millions to keep federal subsidies, many in Republican states
ByMatt Kwong, special to, CBC News Posted: Jun 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 6:16 AM ET
Picketers, both for and against Obamacare, rallied outside the U.S. Supreme Court back in 2012 when the first case against it was being heard. Now, with two Supreme Court wins, Americans seem to be coming around to the reforms.  (The Associated Press)
Related Stories
Crowded Republican presidential field ramps up the paranoia
Manuel Camacho doesn't have many flattering words for Obamacare.
"Ridiculous," the New Jersey resident says. "A headache," he says. "We were pretty much forced to get it," he says.
And yet, even before the U.S. Supreme Court ruled Thursday on the legality of the provision in the Affordable Care Act that gives federal subsidies to people in the Garden State, the 33-year-old security guard sounded an almost appreciative tone.
Like Obamacare or not, Camarcho's $75-a-month premium for basic health insurance definitely beats the roughly $200 he says he'd be billed monthly without the federal discount.
"There's no way I could afford that," he said, conceding the Obamacare tax credits are what's keeping him afloat.
The nanny-state lie behind Obamacare
Fortunately for Camacho and an estimated 6.4 million Americans across 34 mostly Republican-led states, the status quo prevailed on Thursday.
In the case known as King v. Burwell, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled 6-3 that subsidies under the Affordable Care Act are legal for all low- and middle-income Americans, regardless of whether a state chose to create its own "exchange," or online insurance marketplace.
Manuel Camacho, a security guard in N.J., is no fan of Obamacare. But he says he wouldn't be able to afford health care without the federal subsidies for low- and middle-income Americans. (Matt Kwong / CBC)
Those largely "red" states  New Jersey among them had opted to have the federal government step in and set up an official health-insurance marketplace through HealthCare.gov.
But Obamacare opponents had challenged that, claiming a provision in the health-care act is worded in such a way that subsidies should only be available to Americans on exchanges established by the state. That would exclude subsidies for purchases on exchanges created by the federal government.
Had the Supreme Court struck down the subsidies for those holdout states, the lives of millions would have been affected by enormous insurance price hikes.
Opinion shifting
In New Jersey, where the average credit is $306 a month, some 170,000 people can now breathe a little easier, said Maura Collinsgru, the health-care program director for the advocacy group New Jersey Citizen Action.
"That's how many people in our state would have lost credits and likely would have lost their coverage because it would have become unaffordable," she said.
"Hopefully we can now move forward in making what we started under the ACA reform even better."
That's a big hope. So far, the Republican-controlled Congress has voted nearly 60 times to repeal, tweak or undermine the Affordable Care Act.
But with each deflected anti-Obamacare attack, like Thursday's second win in the Supreme Court, sentiment supporting the president's signature legislative achievement is growing, Collinsgru believes.
"All those repeal efforts and now this Supreme Court case has, on the flip side, done a service to people trying to raise awareness of the benefits and protections of the ACA," she said.
Recent polls suggest she could be right.
A CBS-New York Times survey on Monday found that for the first time in their polling, more people supported the health-care law (47 per cent) than opposed it (44 per cent).
Although still short of a majority in favour, the gains are notable considering its unpopularity among Americans since it became law in 2010.
According to the CBS-NYT poll, many who weren't sold on Obamacare nevertheless found something to approve of: for example, 70 per cent were in favour of letting people retain their federal subsidies, a pillar of the reform program.
Christie off the hook
Collinsgru expects Thursday's outcome was good news for New Jersey Governor Chris Christie, even if he's loath to admit as much.
"I would imagine he's relieved of the decision because he will not now have to take a proactive step to secure tax credits for more than 170,000 New Jerseyians," she said.
The Republican governor has admitted he was reaping the budgetary benefits of the Medicaid expansion under Obamacare, and had called it "the right decision" for his state during a March town hall meeting.
The 2013 Medicaid expansion, which some observers saw as a tacit acceptance of Obamacare by mostly Republican legislatures, has helped save New Jersey $150 million, according to the state's treasurer, with a projected $417 more to be saved in fiscal 2016.
Christie, however, has been mum about those savings, parroting Republicans who have condemned the health-care law.
In fact, minutes after the Supreme Court decision declaring the tax credits legal, Christie tweeted that "leaders must turn our attention to making the case that Obamacare must be replaced."
Moving on
In the meantime, the continuation of those federal subsidies should allow Teresa Brooks, a 63-year-old retiree in Jersey City, to keep paying the $95 a month for her daughter's health insurance while she attends college.
"But that's just for my daughter  that's not for us," Brooks said.
Teresa Brooks, a retiree in Jersey City, says she wouldn't be able to afford her daughter's health insurance while at college without the federal subsidies. (Matt Kwong / CBC)
Without the discount? "Definitely we'd be out. She just would not have health insurance. And in college, you need to have health insurance."
Collinsgru is now looking forward to bringing in more people in the next open enrolment period for coverage in November.
She believes there's been enough affirmation around the program.
"It's time to quit the repeal attempts," she said. "They've tried 54 times to undermine it. Now, this Supreme Court decision says the ACA is here to stay, it will stay, and it's time to move forward."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:21:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>8 cruise ship tourists, pilot die in plane crash on Alaska cliff</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/alaska-plane-crash-8-cruise-ship-tourists-pilot-dead-1.3128570?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Alaska plane crash: 8 cruise ship tourists, pilot dead
DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop found 240 metres above Ella Lake
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 7:21 PM PT Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 2:39 AM PT
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam remains docked in Ketchikan, Alaska.  (Taylor Balkom/Ketchikan Daily News/Associated Press)
Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot who were killed when their sightseeing plane crashed in a remote and rugged area of southeastern Alaska.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery after the wreckage of the aircraft was found Thursday against a granite rock face, 240 metresabove a lake.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down, killing the nine people during the sightseeing excursion. No names have been released.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down."
He earlier confirmed the deaths: ""We have nine fatalities."
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 1,3000 kilometressoutheast of Anchorage.
Ella Lake, east of Ketchikan, Alaska marks the spot where searchers found the aircraft on a cliffside 240 metres above the lake. (Google maps)
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to traveling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 809,000-hectareMisty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Haiti sees progress, with Canada's help - but when can it stand on its own?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/haiti-s-health-gains-at-risk-without-ongoing-assistance-from-canada-1.3124034?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Haiti's health gains at risk without ongoing assistance from Canada
Canadian development runs into roadblocks in country still rebuilding from 2010's earthquake
ByLaura Payton, CBC News Posted: Jun 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET
Children wait at a community meeting in Terre Neuve, Haiti. Community health workers at the meeting will weigh every child and update their vaccinations. (Laura Payton/CBC)
Related Stories
Read Laura Payton's blog
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
The hospital in Gonaves feels like it's sitting in the middle of a desert, even though the community is on Haiti's west coast. It's hard to see anything but dull beige sand and the muted brown hills beyond as the sun bakes it all dry and dusty.
The hospital is well-designed: Canada contributed $29 million so it could be built to withstand earthquakes and hurricanes. The green and white facility lets air and light flow through to keep energy costs low. Mexico and the U.S. kicked in an additional US$6.1 million for equipment, including solar panels, and management costs.
More stories in the 2015 Travers Fellowship series
The hospital is at about 35 to 40 per cent of capacity, with a plan to gradually ramp up over the next two years, says Jean-Franois Laurent, director of the health unit for the UN's Office for Project Services in Haiti.
Laurent's role is scheduled to end next month, but that doesn't mean a clean hand-off to Haiti's health ministry, which goes by the French acronym MSPP.
The $29-million Canadian-funded hospital in Gonaives, Haiti was overseen by the UN Office for Project Services. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"Of course once we're done, I hope it's not the end," said Laurent, a Canadian.
"The Haitian government will find other donors or support...There's a very strong will at the governmental level, at the ministry level, to make this hospital a model in the country.
"But on the other hand, there's so many variables that we cannot control."
Over the past five years, Canadian-funded programs in Haiti have helped educate people on the need for proper hygiene and clean water, trained technicians to build and fix water filters and provided money to buildanew hospital and new clinics.
But below the shiny surface of brand-new facilities lurks the shadow of uncertainty. When will the country be able to take over running the facilities and paying the salaries of the people who staff them? Will there be enough staff to put them to full use? What shape will these buildings be in five years from now? Twenty years from now?
Right now, more than 60 per cent ofHaiti'shealth budget comes fromdonors like Canada. Another29 per cent is covered by patients through user fees, and only seven per cent comes from the state.
That's barely enough for salaries.
At risk of losing ground
Haiti is an interesting place to be a Canadian. The $1billion provided to the Caribbeancountry since the 2010 earthquakegives Canada an unusually high profile. The ambassador's namecarries a lot of weight. The British have a small office inCanada's embassy,rather than the other way around.
2015 Travers Fellowship series
The CBC's Laura Payton is this year's R. James Travers Fellow. The Travers Fellowship provided $25,000 in funding for her pitch to look at whether Canada's maternal, newborn and child health program was working. Read more about the project here .
Yesterday: Canada's family planning problem
Tomorrow:What'snext?
And, local officials still talk about a suggestion two years ago by former international development minister Julian Fantino that Canada could freeze aid to Haiti .
But despite the years of co-operation and hundreds of millions of dollars invested,a recently released evaluation of Canada's work in Haiti from 2006 to 2013 found that the future could see a troubled transition.
Community health workers supported by Quebec-based NGO CCISD measure and weigh children at a gathering in Terre Neuve, Haiti. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"The almost exclusive reliance on executing agencies (the United Nations, the private sector, universities, NGOs, and so on), meant the opportunity to strengthen government systems was missed," said the external report prepared for the Canadian government.
The evaluation found several reasons to praise Canada, including for improving co-ordination between donors to eliminate duplicated efforts and helping more people castballots in elections.
But it warned Haiti's health sector might not be able to take on the management and staffing of new infrastructure.
"The MSPP lacks both the resources (funding, staff, medication, equipment, etc.) and the management capacity to support existing programs, even in the capital region... Canada should carefully consider whether to contribute to the further expansion of infrastructure and health programs, and what the capacity constraints of doing so might be."
It also foundproblems related to Canada's development workand emergency humanitarian assistance:
Several programs, especially in health and education, were at risk of "not sustaining results" because of insufficient funding from the Haitian government.
The lack of a proper strategy for transferring knowledge and skills to Haitians, which diminished the prospects for sustainability.
And agencies providing assistance programs offered salaries and working conditions the government of Haiti couldn't match, "robbing the civil service of staff."
'Come a long way'
Paula Caldwell St-Onge, Canada's ambassador to Haiti, exudes warmth across a boardroom table at the embassy in Port-au-Prince. She's popular in the community of non-governmental organizations in Haiti and seems to have a close relationship with the country's health minister.
But Caldwell St-Onge is clear: the embassywon't simply hand overcheques, even though the external evaluation found Canada is losing a chance to build local expertise when it doesn't let Haiti itself handle donor funds for development.
A nurse fills out paperwork at a newly built Canadian-funded hospital in Gonaives, Haiti. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"We [are helping] them create better management structures and better strategic plans with a budget attached to it, which is not the case right now," Caldwell said.
"So I think when we get to that point and we can see some transparency with the strategic plans and where we're going, that will be for the Canadian government to decide when that time comes."
CaldwellSt-Onge, who previously worked in Brazil and Mexico, knows Haiti well: she partly grew up there while her father worked for the Royal Bank. She says the earthquake set back the country dramatically, with nearly one fifth of the civil service killed that day.
"People are always saying 'geez, there's so much more left to do.' But the thing is we've come a long way, so yeah, I think there is a difference. It's not like we've stayed at zero and not gone forward. So I think all of that gives us hope for the future."
'Keep being positive'
International development is complex. Issues intermingle.
Canada is focusing on maternal, newborn and child health. That ties into economic development because poor families need jobs to pay for food, and it ties into governancebecause countries losing money to corruption can't provideservices.
Haiti's health ministry has plans to cut corruption by introducing standard accounting practices and to increase revenue by opening up hospitals to doctors performing private services.
Budget pressures, time crunches limit progress in Tanzania 
But HealthMinisterFlorenceDupervalGuillaume admits she can't imagine a day when Haiti won't need Canada, though she hopes to move beyond the basic assistance that sees NGOsinstructing people on the need to wash their hands or use a toilet instead of defecating near water sources.
"We need to get rid of this type of package of assistance one day and to have really a partnership for development  where we can decrease poverty everywhere, [where] we can also give technical assistance one day to some other countries," she said.
"I'm a very positive person and I keep being positive."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:27:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait City Shia mosque bombed after prayers, reportedly killing 2</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/kuwait-city-shia-mosque-bombed-after-prayers-reportedly-killing-2-1.3128713?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait City Shia mosque bombed after prayers, reportedly killing 2
ISIS claims responsibility after blast strkes Imam Sadiq Mosque in city's al-Sawabir district
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 26, 2015 7:27 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 7:44 AM ET
A witness who was at Kuwait City's Imam Sadiq Mosque at the time said the explosion took place on the grounds after Friday prayers. (Saudi Gazette)
Related Stories
What happened after the Arab Spring?
A deadly explosion ripped through a Shia mosque in a busy neighbourhood of Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers, witnesses said, reportedly killing two.
Mohammed al-Faili, 32, told The Associated Press that his 70 year-old father was killed in what appeared to be a bombing attack. Two of his brothers were also wounded by the explosion. Speaking to The Associated Press by telephone, he said he was not at the mosque at the time of the explosion but was heading to the morgue to identify his father's body.
ISIS allies in Libya post purported beheadings video
ISIS claimed responsibility for the mosque bombing in a statement, Reuters reported.
The official Kuwait News Agency reported that an explosion struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque, which is located in the neighbourhood of al-Sawabir, a residential and shopping district of Kuwait City. The agency confirmed that there were multiple casualties and injuries, but did provide any figures.
Paramedics at the mosque say at least two people were killed. Police formed a cordon around the mosque's complex immediately after the explosion, banning people from entering or gathering near the area. Ambulances could be seen ferrying the wounded from the site.
Abdullah al-Saffar, who was at the mosque, said the explosion took place just after midday Friday prayers.
The extremist group Islamic State in Iraq and Syria, which regards Shia Muslims as heretics, has claimed responsibility for bombings at two different Shia mosques in neighbouring Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
Friday midday prayers are typically the most crowded of the week, and attendance increases during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, which started last week.
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:09:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU leaders agree to settle 40,000 migrants after fractious debate</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/migrant-crisis-in-europe-leaders-agree-to-relocate-40-000-migrants-1.3128646?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>IN DEPTH | Migrants at unprecedented numbers in Calais
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended, describing the migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor."
That is a striking statement considering the euro zone debt crisis and confrontation with Russia during her decade in power.
Expressing his frustration, Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker described the plan as one of "modest ambition" and said at one point in the meeting he had told EU leaders "I don't give a damn" about objections to the plan's underlying methodology.
"We have to find out if the system works. It doesn't matter if it is voluntary or mandatory, it is whether it can help 60,000 refugees," Juncker told a news conference in the early hours of Friday.
However, the EU's chief executive had been hoping to set a precedent for Europe-wide action that limited national opt-outs.
British interlude
During the summit dinner, Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi rebuked his fellow leaders for their reluctance to support a plan that was meant as an emergency response to the tragedy of 2,000 migrant deaths in the Mediterranean year but has been overshadowed by divisions, particularly in eastern Europe.
"If we think Europe is only about budgets, it is not the Europe we thought of in 1957 in Rome," Renzi said, referring to the European Union's founding treaty.
The summit became so tense that a speech by British Prime Minister David Cameron served as an interlude to cool tempers, with the much awaited address to pitch for a new deal for Britain in the European Union reduced to barely tenminutes.
The mood was a long way from the unity showed by EU ministers in April immediately after the deaths of 900 migrants off the Libyan coast in a single weekend.
'Much more argument to come'
While the political deal was a breakthrough, implementing the plan still faces hurdles. The criteria to share migrants among member states must be decided by the end of July. Such factors as the size of a member state's economy and population must be considered.
"There's much, much more argument to come," said one senior EU diplomat. "I don't yet see the full way forward."
The criteria system replaces unpopular proposals for mandatory quotas on each country, which Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and others fought against, arguing their ex-Communist economies still lacked the capacity to cope.
The debate has also strained the EU's commitment to its Schengen agreement on passport-free travel.
This week, Austria threatened to reimpose controls on its border with Hungary and Britain called for more security around the French port of Calais. Britain and Spain want a bigger focus on returning migrants to countries of origin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:02:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate monuments graffitied in 6 states as protest movement grows</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/confederate-monuments-the-target-of-graffiti-in-6-states-1.3128648?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate monuments the target of graffiti in 6 states
Lawmakers in several states moving to remove Confederate symbols from capitol grounds
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 26, 2015 3:02 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 3:02 AM ET
A monument paying homage to Jefferson Davis on the campus of the University of Texas was among the first to be scrawled with "Black Lives Matter."  (Deborah Cannon/Austin American-Statesman/AP)
Related Stories
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
Vandals have targeted monuments dedicated to the leaders and soldiers of the Confederacy, painting the slogan "Black lives matter" on memorials in a half-dozen states where the landmarks stand tall in parks and outside government buildings.
The graffiti reflects the racial tension that permeates post-Ferguson America, more than a week after a white gunman shot and killed nine black congregants at a Charleston, South Carolina, church.
Michael Allen, a lecturer in American culture studies at Washington University in St. Louis, Mo., compared the vandalism to the toppling of statues in Russia at the end of the Soviet empire.
"If the monuments are strong statements of past values, defacing them is the easiest and loudest way to rebuke those statements," Allen said.
The historical significance of Charleston's 'Mother Emanuel' church
Confederate symbols including the rebel battle flag have been the subject of resentment for years. The anger boiled over after last week's massacre at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church. The suspect, Dylann Roof, posed in photos with the Confederate flag.
Politicians throughout the South are taking steps to remove the flag from public places. Black activists say the monuments should meet the same fate.
One of the defaced monuments was the Confederate Memorial in St. Louis' Forest Park, 16 kilometresfrom Ferguson. The same graffiti was reported on memorials in Charleston; Baltimore; Austin, Texas; Asheville, North Carolina; and Richmond, Virginia. No arrests have been made.
A rallying call
Racial wounds in the U.S. were torn open last August, when a white police officer in the St. Louis suburb of Ferguson, Missouri, fatally shot 18-year-old Michael Brown, who was black and unarmed. Officer Darren Wilson was cleared of any wrongdoing, but the shooting raised new awareness about the treatment of blacks.
"Black lives matter" became a rallying call in protests that followed police shootings of black men in other cities, too. With the Charleston shooting refocusing attention on Confederate symbolism, experts said, it isn't surprising that some people would take out their anger on monuments to those who fought on the side of slavery.
Alabama removed four Confederate battle flags from the state capitol grounds earlier this week. (Martin Swant/Associated Press)
Elizabeth Brondolo, a psychology professor at St. John's University in New York who studies the effects of race on mental and physical health, said the defacing of memorials reflects a "consensus that there's been a very serious failure of empathy, a failure to understand what these symbols might mean to people who suffered from slavery and ongoing aggression."
Defaced monuments at the University of Texas in Austin and in Richmond honour Confederate President Jefferson Davis. The Asheville monument pays homage to Zebulon Vance, a Confederate officer and later a governor and senator. Others, like the St. Louis memorial, are more generic tributes to those who fought for the South.
Monumental debate
The future of the 32-foot-tall, 101-year-old statue in St. Louis was already in doubt. In April, Mayor Francis Slay ordered a study of what to do with it and asked for the review to be complete by the end of the summer. Options include altering the wording of the plaque, moving the monument out of Forest Park or removing it entirely.
The University of Texas in Austin is weighing options for its statues of Davis and other Confederate war heroes, with a decision expected by Aug. 1. Three of those statutes were damaged this week.
In Kentucky, both candidates for governor, along with other prominent political leaders, are calling for the Jefferson Davis statue to be removed from its prominent place in the statehouse rotunda and placed in a museum.
Efforts have also begun to seek removal of Confederate monuments in Nashville, Tennessee; Shreveport, Louisiana; Orlando, Florida; Portsmouth, Virginia; and Birmingham, Alabama.
Darrell Maples, commander of the Missouri chapter of the Sons of Confederate Veterans, said the "citizen-soldiers who fought for the Confederacy personified the best qualities of America."
He said altering or removing monuments is "divisive and unnecessary."
Brandi Collins of the civil rights group ColorOfChange.org said the effort isn't about revising history.
"It's about saying that if we are truly about equity, about moving forward, we have to respect everybody who lives in and built this country," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:04:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Arrested New York jail guard denies knowing of escape plan </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/gene-palmer-arrested-jail-guard-denies-knowing-of-prisoner-escape-plan-1.3128281?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Gene Palmer, arrested jail guard, denies knowing of prisoner escape plan
Palmer is 2nd Clinton Correctional Facility employee to be charged since prison break
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 6:04 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 6:04 PM ET
New York State Police officers escort suspended Clinton Correctional Facility guard Gene Palmer from court in Plattsburgh, N.Y., on Wednesday.  (Keshia Clukey/Albany Times-Union via AP)
Related Stories
New York prison escape: Police look into possible sightings
A U.S. prison guard charged in connection with the escape of two killers admitted providing them with tools, paint, frozen hamburger meat and access to a catwalk electrical box, but claims he never knew they planned to bust out, authorities say.
As the search for the convicts entered its 20th day Thursday, Gene Palmer was released on $25,000 bail after his arrest on charges of promoting prison contraband, tampering with evidence and official misconduct. His arraignment was postponed until Monday.
Palmer is the second Clinton Correctional Facility employee to be charged since two convicted murderers, Richard Matt and David Sweat, cut their way out of the maximum-security prison in far northern New York, close to the Canadian border, on June 6. A prison tailor shop instructor Joyce Mitchell, 51, is charged with helping them break out.
But in contrast to the allegations against Mitchell, Palmer said he was an unwitting helper.
New York State Police have been searching for escaped killers David Sweat and Richard Matt since June 6. (New York State Police/Getty Images)
"I did not realize at the time that the assistance provided to Matt or Sweat made their escape easier," he told authorities in a signed statement.
District Attorney Andrew Wylie said that based on Palmer's statements and a polygraph test, investigators have no reason to believe he was knowingly involved in the escape.
In the statement, Palmer admitted providing Matt with paint and paintbrushes. On four occasions over eight months, he supplied Sweat with needle-nose pliers and a screwdriver. He said he gave Sweat access to the catwalk later used in the escape to change the wiring on electrical boxes as "a favour" to make it easier for them to cook in their cells. And a week before the escape, he delivered to Matt a pound of frozen ground beef in a package left by Mitchell.
Palmer told investigators that he agreed to help the pair in return for information about some illegal acts the other inmates were engaged in.
Wylie said Mitchell told investigators she smuggled hacksaw blades, a screwdriver and other tools into the prison by hiding them in the frozen meat.
She then put the meat in a refrigerator in the tailor shop, and Palmer took the meat to Sweat and Matt, who were housed in a section where inmates are allowed to cook their meals, according to the district attorney.
Palmer to plead not guilty
Wylie said Thursday that investigators have no proof Palmer knew hacksaw blades were embedded in the meat.
Palmer, who has been suspended, will plead not guilty, according to his lawyer.
Authorities say the inmates cut through the steel wall at the back of their cells, crawled down a catwalk, broke through a brick wall, cut their way into and out of a steam pipe and then emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
Sweat, 35, was serving a life sentence without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy. Matt, who turned 49 on Thursday, was doing 25 years to life in the kidnapping, torture and hacksaw dismemberment of his former boss.
Palmer had worked at the prison in Dannemora for more than 27 years and had known Sweat and Matt for at least five years.
In a 2000 interview with a local radio station, Palmer portrayed his job as highly stressful.
"With the money that they pay you," he said, "you'll go bald, you'll have high blood pressure, you'll become an alcoholic, you'll divorce, and then you'll kill yourself."
About 1,100 law enforcement on Thursday continued their search for the escaped convicts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:08:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iranian foreign minister to join nuclear talks on Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iranian-foreign-minister-to-join-nuclear-talks-on-friday-1.3128514?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
Iranian foreign minister to join nuclear talks on Friday
CBC's Nahlah Ayed talks to Masoumeh Ebtekar, a vice-president in Iran, about nuclear talks and ties to Canada
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 10:08 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 3:02 AM ET
U.S. and Iran: Then and now 3:24
Related Stories
Justin Trudeau: I'll end ISIS combat mission, restore relations with Iran
With significant gaps standing in the way of an Iran nuclear deal, foreign ministers at the seven-nation talks are adding their diplomatic muscle to the negotiations before a June 30 target date for an agreement.
France announced Thursday that Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius is joining the talks in Vienna on Saturday. Iranian media reported earlier that Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif will fly to Vienna on Friday. That's the day U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry departs Washington for the Austrian capital
Trudeau says Liberals would stop bombing ISIS, restore relations with Iran
Foreign ministers from the four other nations at the negotiating table  Russia, China, Britain and Germany  are also expected to join in as they try to bridge differences between the sides on the limits Tehran must accept on its nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions.
But with Iran apparently backtracking on key points of the emerging deal, the talks could go past the target date. In a speech on Tuesday, Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei rejected a long-term freeze on nuclear research and insisted that Iran will only sign a deal if international sanctions are lifted first.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif will join talks on a nuclear deal in Vienna on Friday. (Ivan Sekretarev/Associated Press)
He also repeated that military sites and Iranian nuclear scientists will be off limits to UNexperts, who would monitor Iranian compliance to any deal while trying to kick-start a moribund probe of suspicions that Tehran worked on atomic arms  allegations Iran denies.
Kerry said Khamenei's speech was for "domestic political consumption" and that there would not be a deal if Iran reneged on commitments made in an April outline.
'It could be a game changer'
Masoumeh Ebtekar, a vice-president in Iran, told CBC's Nahlah Ayed, that she doesn't think thespeech "was a hardening of his positions by any means."
"I think that he was very frank, he made it clear that there are concessions that Iran might need to make."
Ebtekar, who in 1979 wasan English-speaking spokeswoman forstudents who overtook and held hostages atthe U.S. Embassy in Tehran, later became Iran's first female vice-president.
"The history is thereit's not something that could be forgottenbut we look forward to this settlement as a turning point. I think that it could be a game changer," she told Ayed.
Though the official deadline is coming up, a delay up to July 9 is not a deal-breaker. If Congress receives an agreement by then, it has 30 days to review it before President Barack Obama could suspend congressional sanctions.
But postponement beyond that would double the congressional review period to 60 days, giving both Iranian and U.S. opponents more time to work on undermining an agreement.
U.S. House of Representatives Speaker John Boehner, a Republican critic of the deal, said even "a little more time" was too much of a concession to the Iranians.
"Giving Iran more flexibility will not lead to a good deal, it will only lead to more concessions for a regime that has no intention of giving up its desire for a nuclear weapon," he said. "We're about to get stuck with a bad deal with a bad regime."
With files from CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:37:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek bailout talks stall again as new deadline looms</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greece-still-deadlocked-with-creditors-as-tuesday-deadline-looms-1.3127431?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greece still deadlocked with creditors as Tuesday deadline looms
Pension reform and new sales taxes sticking points in talks as EU leaders gather in Brussels
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 11:37 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 3:48 PM ET
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, left, and Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi speak with German Chancellor Angela Merkel during a round table meeting at an EU summit in Brussels on Thursday.  (Geert Vanden Wijngaert/ Associated Press)
Related Stories
Greek crisis needs more than a Band-Aid solution: Don Pittis
Eurozone finance ministers ended their meeting Thursday without asolution to the Greece debt crisis after yesterday's talks between Athens and its creditors alsoended in deadlock.
Greece and its creditors  the International Monetary Fund, European Central Bank and the European Commission  had presented competing proposals to the finance ministers.
Greek crisis needs more than a Band-Aid solution: Don Pittis
They are still at an impasse at issues such as pension reform, including what year to move the retirement age to 67 and whether to continue to provide top-up funding to Greece's poorest pensioners.
Another sticking point has been the overhaul of the value-added tax system, with the EU wanting processed foods and restaurants taxed at a higher rate and insisting on removal of an exemption for the Greek islands.
The head of the IMF, Christine Lagarde, says Greece's creditors need more time to examine new offers Athens has made.
"We were given a proposal by the Greek parties at the last hour. We need to doso some more work to examine their proposals, to see how it can be reconciled," she said.
EU leaders meet
Greece's economy ministerGiorgos Stathakissaid concessions had been made on both sides.
As Europe's leaders arrived for asummit in Brussels, Germany's Angela Merkel warned talks were going nowhere.
Officials have "not yet made the necessary progress" in the talks to get Greece more financial aid, she told reporters and "in some places we even have the impression that we are falling back a bit."
Meanwhile, French President Francois Hollande is exhorting Greece and its international creditors to speed up talks on new loans for the country, as a default would affect the entire continent.
Greece faces default if it fails to make a 1.6 billion euro ($2.2 billion Cdn) IMF debt repayment by Tuesday.
And if it fails to make the payment, it may opt to withdraw from the euro, which could roil markets and affect the entire eurozone.
On the other hand, deep concessions by Greece could leave Tsipras in trouble, as he could face parliamentary defeat over heightened austerity. His Syriza party was elected in January on an anti-austerity platform geared at reviving the Greek economy.
Banks in trouble
Greek banks may lose their lifeline from the ECB and be forced to limit withdrawals as soon as Monday.
Worried Greeks have been withdrawing their money from their country's banks, fearing the imposition of restrictions on banking transactions. An estimated more than 4 billion euros ($4.5 billion) left Greek banks last week.
A Greek banking official says the European Central Bank has approved a request from Athens to increase the amount of emergency liquidity Greek lenders can tap from the country's central bank.
The ECB approved the request Thursday, as it has done every day since Friday as Greece headed into the final stretch of tough bailout negotiations with no clear solution in sight.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:26:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obamacare 'here to stay,'  president says in wake of U.S. Supreme Court decision</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-s-supreme-court-upholds-obamacare-tax-subsidies-1.3127306?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. Supreme Court upholds Obamacare tax subsidies
6-3 decision means Americans who get health insurance via federal exchanges can still get subsidies
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 10:26 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 8:09 PM ET
Obama reacts to health-care ruling 6:10
Related Stories
SCOTUS Blog
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
Ina major win for President Barack Obama, the U.S. Supreme Court has upheld a lower-court decision that allows the federal government to issue health care subsidies to states.
The 6-3 decisionmeans that Americans whoget their health insurance throughexchanges set up by the federal government will continue to be eligible for tax subsidies.
Obamacarecosting less than forecast
The plaintiffs in the case had argued that these subsidies were illegal becauseObama'sAffordable CareAct, widely known as Obamacare, stipulates that to be eligible for federal tax credits, insurance had to have beenpurchased through an exchange set upbya state, notthefederal government.
But the court sided with theObama administration'sinterpretation and found the language in the law sufficiently broad to apply to both state and federal exchanges.
The rulingis more confirmation that the law "is working exactly as it's supposed to," Obama said in reaction to the decision.
The HealthCare.gov serves as an insurance exchange where individuals whose states have not set up their own exchange can compare plans from competing providers. (Don Ryan/Associated Press)
"After more than 50 votes in Congress to repeal or weaken this law, after a presidential election based in part on preserving or repealing this law, after multiple challenges to this law before the Supreme Court, the Affordable Care Act is here to stay,"the president saidat a newsconference in the Rose Garden at the White House.
"This is not an abstract thinganymore. This is not a set of political talking points. This is reality," he said after listing off examples of how the law has made health care more accessible and affordable for millions of Americans.
"Thislaw is working, and it's going to keep doing just that," Obama said.
2nd high court ruling in favour of Obamacare
Thursday's decision marks the second time in three years that the high court has ruled against a major challenge to the law brought by conservatives seeking to gut it.
"We should start calling this law SCOTUScare," Justice Antonin Scalia wrote in his dissenting opinion, referring to the common abbreviation for the Supreme Court of the United States.
'This was a good day for America.'- U.S. President Barack Obama
The decision means the subsidies will remain not just in the 13 states that have set up their own exchanges and the three states that have state-federal hybrid exchanges, but also in the 34 states that use HealthCare.gov,the exchange run by the federal government.
"This was a good day for America," Obama said of the ruling, telling themedia that had the challenge been successful,millions of Americans would have lost thousands of dollars in tax subsidies and many would have become uninsured.
"America would have gone backwards, and that's not what we do," he said.
Federal insuranceexchange legitimate
The case centred on the tax creditsoffered under the law, passed by Obama's fellow Democrats in Congress in 2010 over unified Republican opposition, that help low- and moderate-income people buy private health insurance. The exchanges are online marketplaces that allow consumers to shop among competing insurance plans.
Since the federal government can't compel states to set up exchanges, in some cases where states failed to do so or had trouble running their own exchanges, it stepped in and created themon their behalf through HealthCare.gov and provided subsidies to low- and middle-income individualsnationwide, regardless of whether they enrolled in theirinsurance plan through a state-run or federally run exchange.
The point of the subsidies is to keep enough people in the pool of insured to avoid triggering aso-called deathspiral of declining enrolment, a growing proportion of less healthy people and premium increases by insurers.
The court itselfwrote in its decision that "the tax credits are among the act's key reforms, involving billions of dollars in spending each year and affecting the price of health insurance for millions of people."
In 2014, roughly87 per cent of people who bought insurance on a federal exchange did so withtax credits, the court noted.
Chief Justice John Roberts wrote the majority opinion in the U.S. Supreme Court's 6-3 decision backing Obama's Affordable Care Act. (Nati Harnik/Associated Press)
The question before the justices was whether a four-word phrase in the expansive law saying subsidies are available to those buying insurance on exchanges "established by the state" had been correctly interpreted by the administration to allow subsidies to be available nationwide.
While the plaintiffs argued for a strict interpretation of this part of the law,several states toldthe court that they had no inkling they had to set up their own exchange in order for their residents to get tax credits, and the court found that the structure of thelaw andseveral provisions within itassume that tax credits will be available on both state and federal exchanges.
Chief Justice John Robertswrote that although the conservative challengers' arguments about the plain meaning of the statute referring to exchanges being "established by the state"were "strong," the "context and structure of the act compel us to depart from what would otherwise be the most natural reading of the pertinent statutory phrase."
Adhering to the plaintiffs' narrow reading ofthe statute"would destabilize the individual insurance market in any state with a federal exchange, and likely create the very 'death spirals'that Congress designed the Act to avoid," he wrote in themajorityopinion.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care Act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," he wrote.
With files from Reuters and The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 12:30:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS launches twin attacks in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/isis-storms-northeast-syrian-city-of-hassakeh-attacks-kobani-1.3127007?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS storms northeast Syrian city of Hassakeh, attacks Kobani
Attacks come after ISIS suffered setbacks against Kurdish forces
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 5:30 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 12:19 PM ET
An explosion is captured on a closed-circuit video cam camera second after a car bomb detonated on Thursday in the Kurdish town of Kobani, Syria. ISIS militants staged a new attack on the town, which famously resisted a months-long assault by the Islamic militants. (Associated Press)
Related Stories
ISIS blows up ancient tombs in Palmyra,  2,000-year-old heritage site in Syria
Islamic State in Iraq and Syria (ISIS) militants launched major attacks in northern Syria on Thursday in a swift counter-offensive after recent battlefield setbacks, storming government-held areas in one mostly Kurdish city and setting off deadly car bombs as they pushed back into a border town they were expelled from earlier this year.
The ISIS offensive was two-pronged and left dozens of people dead or wounded. On one front, ISISfighters advanced early in the morning into the northeastern city of Hassakeh, long split between Syrian Kurds and government forces, capturing parts of it.
The other push was into the Syrian border town of Kobani, which famously resisted a months-long assault by the Islamic militants before they were driven out in January, and surrounding villages. An activist group said 12 people died in fighting Thursday in Kobani  the first time in six months the ISIS had managed to enter the town along the Syria-Turkey border  and that the militants had detonated three car bombs.
People mourn the death of a woman, who died from her wounds after she was injured during what activists said was an attack by ISIS fighters in Kobani, Syria on Thursday. (Rodi Said/Reuters)
In the Kobani attack, which was launched from the town's southern and western parts, the ISIS extremists donned Syrian rebel uniforms and carried flags of the mainstream Free Syrian Army to deceive the town's Kurdish defenders, said Redur Khalil, a spokesman for the Kurdish People's Protection Units, or YPG.
Speaking about Hassakeh, Khalil said ISIS militants attacked government-held neighbourhoods on the southern edge of the city, and captured some areas.
Syrian state TV reported intense clashes inside Hassakeh's southern neighbourhood of Nashawi. According to the report, ISIS fighters killed several people they captured in the city, including the head of a military housing institution. It said the militants sustained many casualties, including the commander of the group who is a foreign fighter. An activist group said many people in neighbourhoods engulfed in the fighting fled to safer areas in the city.
ISIS blows up ancient tombs in Palmyra, 2,000-year-old heritage site in Syria
ISIS tried to storm the city earlier this month and reached its southern outskirts before facing strong resistance from Syrian government troops who pushed them away.
The Hassakeh and Kobani attacks came just days after YPG fighters and their allies captured the Islamic State stronghold of Tal Abyad on the border with Turkey and the town of Ein Issa to the south. Kurdish fighters have been advancing since January under the cover of airstrikes by the U.S.-led coalition.
But in neighbouring Iraq, government forces and allied Shiamilitiamen have been slow in retaking IS-held territory. The Iraqis have also suffered occasional losses.
Iraqi troops drove ISIS militants from Saddam Hussein's hometown of Tikrit in April, but lost Ramadi, the capital of Anbar province west of Baghdad, last month.
In June last year, ISIS launched a blitz, capturing large parts of both Syria and Iraq and subsequently declared an Islamic caliphate on the territory it controls. A major IS attack was widely expected during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, which began last week.
In an audio message Tuesday, ISIS spokesman, Abu Muhammad al-Adnani, urged Sunni Muslims to use the time of piety and dawn-to-dusk fasting during Ramadan to wage jihad and seek martyrdom.
"Attack them everywhere and shake the ground beneath them," he said. It was not possible to verify the recording, but it resembled previous audio statements from the group.
Al-Adnani referred to the recent battlefield setbacks for ISIS, saying the faithful "may lose a battle or battles and may lose towns and areas, but will never be defeated."
A Syrian Kurdish sniper looks at the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, in this January 2015 photo. Turkish officials said Thursday, that ISIS has staged a new attack on the Kurdish town. (Associated Press)
In the Kobani attack, the Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, which tracks Syria's war, said three vehicles were detonated in the town. Ghalia Nehme, a commander with the Kurdish Women's Protection Units, told The Associated Press by telephone from inside the town that "a group of fighters deployed in some areas of Kobani."
"We are defending a position now," she added.
Another Kurdish official in Kobani, Idriss Naasan, said the fighting was intense in the morning but became more sporadic by midday. He said the extremists appear to have infiltrated from the villages south of Kobani.
"We hear cracks of gunfire every now and then," Naasan said from inside Kobani around noon. He added that some explosions could still be heard but that it was unclear what those were.
The Observatory said 12 civilians and Kurdish fighters were killed in Kobani on Thursday, and also eight IS extremists.
In Barkh Botan, not far from Kobani, ISIS fighters entered the village also on Thursday morning, opening fire on civilians and killing 20 residents, the Observatory said. Syria's state news agency SANA said 22 people were killed in the shooting, including women and children.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:20:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Univision drops Miss USA pageant over Donald Trump's 'insulting remarks' about Latino immigrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/univision-drops-miss-usa-pageant-over-donald-trump-s-insulting-remarks-about-latino-immigrants-1.3127510?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Univision drops Miss USA pageant over Donald Trump's 'insulting remarks' about Latino immigrants
Trump accused Mexicans of bringing drugs, crime and rapists to the U.S. during campaign speech
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 12:20 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 12:20 PM ET
FILE - In this June 16, 2013 file photo, Donald Trump, left, and Miss Connecticut USA Erin Brady pose onstage after Brady won the 2013 Miss USA pageant in Las Vegas, Nev. Univision says it is dropping the Miss USA Pageant and says it will cut all business ties with Donald Trump over comments he made about Mexican immigrants. The network said Thursday, June 25, 2015, it will not air the pageant on July 12, as previously scheduled, and has ended its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organization due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner.  (Jeff Bottari/AP File)
Related Stories
Donald Trump's run at the presidency: More than a stunt?
Univision is dropping the Miss USA pageant and says it will cut all business ties with Donald Trump over comments he made about Mexican immigrants.
The network said Thursday it will not air the July pageant and has ended its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organization, which produces the Miss USA pageant, due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner of Miss Universe.
Donald Trump's run at the presidency: More than a stunt?
During his presidential campaign kickoff speech last week, Trump accused Latino immigrants of bringing drugs, crime and rapists to the U.S. He called for building a wall along the southern border of the U.S.
Trump says he was only criticizing U.S. policies concerning Mexico, not its people. He says Univision is in default of a five-year contract.
Miss USA presenter pulled out
Univision's decision is the latest in the fallout over Trump's remarks: On Thursday, Puerto Rican actress and Miss USA presenter Roselyn Sanchez severed her ties with the pageant. And on Wednesday, Colombian singer J Balvin cancelled a planned performance.
A spokesman for Balvin said in a written statement that the singer's management told the Miss Universe organization to withdraw his name from an announcement about participants in the Miss USA broadcast.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:40:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I'm safer in Baghdad': Courtney Love says she was ambushed in Paris taxi protest</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/courtney-love-held-hostage-in-paris-taxi-protest-singer-says-1.3127565?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Courtney Love 'held hostage' in Paris taxi protest, singer says
'They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage,' tweeted the singer Thursday
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 1:40 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 1:40 PM ET
Courtney Love credits two men on a motorcycle for rescuing her from a violent taxi strike aimed at Uber in Paris on Thursday. The former Hole frontwoman says she was scared out of her wits when protesters ambushed her car and held her driver hostage.   (Ben Gabbe/Getty Images)
Related Stories
Two charged after Uber driver beaten, hospitalized
Courtney Love says she was scared out of her wits Thursday when thecar she was riding in was "destroyed" by protesting taxi drivers in Paris.
The 50-year-old former Hole frontwomanand widow of Nirvana's Kurt Cobain, says she wasambushed and "held hostage forabout an hour" whenpicketers, rallyingagainstthe mobile car-hailing serviceUber,attacked her car.
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 @Courtney
Love was among many travellers who got caught up in the protest in the French capital that sawtaxi drivers smashlivery cars, set tires ablaze and block traffic across the country.
An overturned car is pictured as French taxi drivers, who are on strike, demonstrate at Porte Maillot to block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against Uber. (Charles Platiau/Reuters)
The action was part ofa nationwide strike bydrivers who sayUber's lowest cost service is taking their livelihood away.
Love, who didn't specify what kind of car she was in, posted a barrage of messages on social media during the ordeal, calling the incident the "scariest day" of her life.
paid some guys on motorcycles to sneak us out, got chased by a mob of taxi drivers who threw rocks, passed two police and they did nothing
 @Courtney
The celebrity appeared to blameFranois Hollande, calling the French president a "libertine."
"I can't believe this really just happened, she wrote onInstagram . "[I]love French people but your government blows."
Rescued from the riot
The singer later posted a snapshotwearing a motorcycle helmet with two smiling men who appeared to haverescued her from the melee.
Courtney Love posted this picture of her apparent rescuers on her Instagram Thursday after she says she was 'held hostage' for an hour. (courtneylove/Instagram)
Riot police chased strikers from Paris' ring road, where protesters torched tires in the middle of the roadway and swarmed onto exit ramps at rush hour.
France's top security official said he had ordered an immediate ban on unlicensed services like UberPop in the Paris region but called for an end to violence against the service's drivers.
"We are calling for calm. We are in a state of law," Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said. "A state of law is not a state of violence."
Uber's more expensive livery service is still legal but a source of intense frustration for French taxi drivers, who pay tens of thousands of euros (dollars) for the equivalent of medallions and who face customer complaints that they are being resistant to changes such as credit cards and geolocation.
Two charged after Uber driver beaten, hospitalized
The French government, meanwhile, said nearly 500 legal cases have been filed across the country involving complaints about UberPop, the lowest cost service. Several drivers have had their cars impounded. The officials reiterated concerns about safety of passengers, insisting they are not protected in case of an accident by an UberPop driver.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From dodging shoes to throwing barbs: Politicians who got into it with hecklers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-s-president-barack-obama-just-the-latest-politician-to-go-head-to-head-with-heckler-1.3127437?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Video
U.S. President Barack Obama just the latest politician to go head-to-head with heckler
Obama part of a long line of politicians who engaged with hecklers who tried to throw them off course
ByJoe Pack, CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 5:00 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 8:36 AM ET
U.S. President Barack Obama and Vice-President Joe Biden react after a heckler was removed from a reception at the White House marking LGBT Pride Month. Obama is not the first politician to make headlines after going head-to-head with a heckler. (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Related Stories
Same-sex marriage ruling by U.S. Supreme Court within days
U.S. President Barack Obama verbally jousted with a heckler on Wednesday at a White House reception in honour of LGBTPride Monthand was widely praised for handling the incident withgrace and good humour, telling the heckler, "Hey, listen, you're in my house."
The heckler had interrupted Obama's remarks by protesting the detention and deportation of gay, lesbian and transgender immigrants.
"My attitude is, if you're eating the hors d'ouevres" he joked, alluding totheprivilege of attending a White House event.
Video:U.S. President Barack Obama scolds heckler at White House event
At a 2014Democratic National Committee convention in San Jose,Calif., Obama talked down another heckler calling for "freedom for Ethiopia" and yelling out "We love you."
"I love you back," Obama told the audience member. "You kind of screwed up my ending, but that's OK."
Handling surprise interruptions can improve or stain a politician's reputationdepending on whether their response comes acrossasgracefulor in bad taste.
Here are some other examples of how politicians have handled hecklers.
Jean Chrtien
Canada's former prime ministerJean Chrtienbarely deflecteda question asked by media personalityNardwuar the Human Servietteabout protesters and pepper spray at a 1997 meeting ofAPEC(Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) members in Vancouver.
"For me, pepper I put it on my plate," Chrtien famously said.
George W. Bush
Former U.S. President George W. Bush once deftly ducked two shoes thrown at him by a man at a press conference in Baghdad. His observation about attention-seeking protesters was refreshingly apt.
"I don't know what the guy's cause is, but one thing is for certain: he caused (the press)to ask me a question about it."
Hillary Clinton
Hillary Clinton, former U.S. Secretary of State and current Democratic presidential candidate,similarly had a shoe thrown at her at a 2014 speech in Las Vegas, leaving her visiblyperplexed.
"Was that a bat?," she asked at the time. "Was that somebody throwing something at me? Was that part of Cirque duSoleil?"
Rob Ford
Toronto's former mayor Rob Ford met with more than a fewdissenters during his four-year tenure. Onenotableencounter onCanada Day in2014 involved ashirtless jogger who showed up on the scene as Fordand his brother, Doug, were meeting with residents in East York.
Many will also remember how Ford nearly knocked Toronto councilwoman Pam McConnell to the floor in November2013as he ran after aheckler in city hall.
Rob Ford knocks over councillor2:28
Ronald Reagan
U.S. presidents have been comingup with memorable quips since before the age of social media and particularly since the advent of televised debates. At the 1984 presidential debate,Ronald Reagandeftly turned a question about his age fromBaltimore Sun reporter Henry Trewhittinto a jab about his opponent, Walter Mondale.
At a White House press conference in 1982, Reagan was equally quick in turning a serious question about his part in the recession into a slam against the Democrats.
Chris Christie
Not all politicians are savvy enough to defend themselves in public with tact. At a 2012town hall meeting in Roebling, N.J., Gov. Chris Christie lost his cool with a law school student who interrupted him, berating the former Navy Seal and calling him an "idiot."
Winston Churchill
Winston Churchill, whose silhouette is represented in a statue outside the Houses of Parliament in London, was known for his all-around verbal dexterity and had one particularly memorable exchange with member of parliament Nancy Astor. (Luke MacGregor/Reuters)
The formidable Winston Churchill, the former British prime ministerknown for his rousing speeches and radio broadcasts,doesn't need video evidence of his verbal prowess. He is alleged to have had this heated exchange with Nancy Astor, the first woman in the British Parliament, who once confronted him abouthis drunkennessand poor manners.
Astor: "Winston, if you were my husband, I'd put poison in your tea."
Churchill: "Nancy, if you were my wife, I'd drink it."
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank will maintain emergency credit to Greek banks</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-banks-granted-cash-flow-reprieve-amid-emergency-debt-talks-1.3131048?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greek banks granted cash flow reprieve amid emergency debt talks
European Central Bank head urges eurozone countries to 'address fragilities'
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 28, 2015 9:25 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 28, 2015 9:30 AM ET
People line up outside a bank which normally operates on Saturday but remained closed, in central Athens.  (Thanassis Stavrakis/Associated Press)
Greece's future in balance 1:57
Related Stories
Greek crisis needs more than a Band-Aid solution: Don Pittis
The European Central Bank has announced it is maintaining emergency credit to Greek banks at its current level, a day after the country's parliament approved holding a referendum next week on whether to accept creditors' financial proposals in return for bailout loans.
Greek parliament approves referendum on bailout deal
The ECB's decision keeps a key financial lifeline open but does not provide further credit to Greece's banks, which are seeing deposits drain away as anxious Greeks withdraw savings.
The ECB had said it was considering tightening assistance to the banks, but on Sunday said it was stillworking closely with the Bank of Greece to maintain financial stability and added it could reconsider its decision on credit levels.
"We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of member states in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies," ECB head Mario Draghi said.
Historically speaking, Germany a bigger deadbeat than Greece
Worried Greeks continued lining up at ATM machines Sunday morning. While some machines were running out of cash, others were being replenished.
Tsipras' move for a national vote on July 5 startled and angered Greece's European partners and threw the country's bailout negotiations with international lenders into turmoil. Parliament approved the referendum call in a majority vote on Saturday.
But Greece's international bailout with its European creditors and the International Monetary Fund expires Tuesday, and Greece's European partners said they would not accept an extension of the bailout until Sunday's referendum.
With Greece also facing a 1.6 billion-euro debt repayment to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday  one it will struggle to meet without bailout funds  the developments have thrown Greece's financial future and its continued membership in the 19-nation shared euro currency into question.
Alternate Greek Finance Minister Nadia Valavani said the government was "expecting the funding of Greek banks to continue normally via the ELA after Tuesday."
Bank customers urged to remain calm
Valavani urged Greeks themselves to show restraint, telling private Mega television the country's banks could see "business as usual" next week if they receive the emergency support "so long as there is calm" and Greeks don't attempt to withdraw all their savings.
The ECB's emergency liquidity currently stands at just under 90 billion euros ($100 billion US), a financial lifeline that has been keeping the country's four major banks going. The ECB has been slowly increasing the amount of emergency credit which has been compensating for the increase in withdrawals from Greek banks.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls on Sunday urged Greece and other nations to do whatever they can to keep Greece in the 19-nation bloc that uses the euro currency.
"We don't know, none of us, the consequences of an exit from the eurozone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the eurozone,"Valls said on France's i-Tele TV.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:06:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suspect in French beheading sent selfie to Canadian cellphone, report says</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/france-beheading-attack-suspect-took-selfie-with-decapitated-victim-1.3130934?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia hotel attacker kills at least 28, mostly tourists
Jean-Christophe de Le Rue, a spokesman for Public Safety Minister Steven Blaney, did not confirm to CBC News that the image was sent to a Canadian number, but did say Canadian authorities are involved in the case.
"While I cannot comment on operational matters of national security, we are assisting the French authorities with their investigation," he said in an email statement.
He declined to comment further on details of the investigation.
Police found the head of Herve Cornara, manager of the transport firm that employed Salhi, attached to a fence at the plant owned by U.S. group Air Products, framed by black and white flags bearing Islamic slogans.
No claim of responsibility for attack
President Francois Hollande, dealing with new security fears six months after Islamist gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish deli, said the incident clearly amounted to a terrorist attack.
Salhi, whose wife and sister are also being detained along with a fourth person, is known to have associated with Islamists over more than a decade and had previously been flagged as a potential risk.
But there has so far been no claim of responsibility for the attack.
The attack occurred in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, in the Isre region between Lyon and Grenoble. (CBC)
Paris public prosecutor Francois Molins said on Friday that investigators would take time to piece together the sequence of events at the plant in Saint Quentin-Fallavier, 30 kilometressouth of Lyon, and establish whether Salhi was acting alone.
The body of Cornara, 54, also bore signs of strangulation suggesting that he may have been killed at an unknown location prior to his decapitation.
Investigators searching his home in Saint-Priest, near Lyon, seized a laptop, a tablet computer and a fake pistol but found no trace of explosives or radical propaganda.
"We don't know whether we're dealing with a fundamentalist who just lost it or a real terrorist," the source said.
3 attacks on same day
The latest attack in France occurred on the same day that a gunman killed 39 people at a Tunisian beachside hotel and an ISISsuicide bomber killed two dozen and wounded more than 200 at a mosque in Kuwait.
French authorities said there was no connection between the attacks and nothing to indicate that the industrial site had been targeted because of its U.S. ownership.
"There is no other link other than to say that terrorism is our common enemy," said Hollande said after rushing back to Paris from an EU summit in Brussels.
Unlike two of the gunmen behind the January attacks, Salhi does not have a criminal record. But the fact he was flagged as a risk between 2006 and 2008 and known to have since maintained radical Islamist links is raising new questions about the security services and their effectiveness.
With files from The Associated Press and CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:38:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia puts 1,000 extra police at tourist sites</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tunisia-beach-hotel-attack-extra-security-aimed-at-tourist-sector-1.3131024?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia's prime minister announced on Saturday a string of new security measures, including closing mosques accused of citing violence.
About 80 mosques accused of "spreading venom" will close within a week, Prime Minister Habib Essid said.
This image taken from a militant website associated with Islamic State extremists, posted on Saturday purports to show the Tunisian gunman, identified as Seifeddine Rezgui. (Associated Press)
Essid said additional army reservists would be deployed at tourist sites around the country and inside hotels, while he called on the hotels themselves to do more to enforce security.
He also said that political parties and associations espousing radical ideas with suspicious funding would be closed down, and he promised financial rewards for information leading to arrests related to the attack.
A day after the attack, ISIS posted a photo of the alleged gunman. Authorities have identified him as a Tunisian, 24-year-old Seifeddine Rezgui, from the town of Gaafour, 160 kilometres northeast of Sousse. After shooting vacationers along the beach, the gunman wandered into nearby streets, where police shot and killed him.
Britain's Foreign Office on Sunday updated its travel advice to Tunisia, urging vigilance and warning that further attacks against foreigners are possible.
Injured people are treated on the beach in Sousse after a man in his 20s opened fire with a Kalashnikov, killing sunbathers at the resort, following a call to violence by ISIS. (Jawhara FM/Associated Press)

The ministry warned against all travel to Tunisia's militarized southern zone, all travel anywhere within five kilometres of Tunisia's border with Libya and all travel to the country's Chaambi Mountain national park area. It also advised against all but essential travel to much of Tunisia's south and along its western border with Algeria.
The ministry said possible attacks could stem from "individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
At least 15 Britons were among the 38 people killed at the Sousse beach resort.
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:42:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Major differences remain in Iran nuclear talks, U.K. says</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iran-nuclear-talks-require-give-and-take-says-u-k-foreign-secretary-1.3131035?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks require 'give and take,' says U.K. foreign secretary
Parties negotiating nuclear limits in exchange for easing sanctions
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jun 28, 2015 7:42 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 28, 2015 7:43 AM ET
Britain's Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said negotiators in Vienna still have 'major differences of interpretation' in detailing what was agreed to in April in the framework agreement. (Neil Hall/Reuters)
Related Stories
Wikileaks exposes reams of secret Saudi diplomatic files
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said on Sunday there were still major differences on a proposed nuclear deal between major powers and Iran and there would need to be concessions to reach an agreement.
"There a number of different areas where we still have major differences of interpretation in detailing what was agreed in (the) Lausanne (framework agreement)," Hammond told reporters on arrival in Vienna for the talks. He was referring to a framework deal agreed on April 2.
"There is going to have to be some give or take if we are to get this done in the next few days," he said, adding that there were red lines that could not be crossed. "No deal is better than a bad deal."
An accord to curb Iran's nuclear program remains elusive due to disagreements on fundamental issues, said Laurent Fabius, France's foreign minister in Vienna.
European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said on Sunday that a last-minute deal between Iran and world powers on Tehran's nuclear program was still possible.
"If all negotiating parties have strong political will in these last moments, we can make it," she said in a tweet from the negotiations in Vienna.
With the June 30 deadline looming, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry was meeting Sunday in Vienna with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, their third encounter since Saturday. Other foreign ministers are expected to join.
The goal of the talks involving Iran and the U.S., Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia is a deal that would crimp Tehran's capacity to make nuclear weapons in exchange for sanctions relief.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:31:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nearly 500 injured as explosion, fire hits Taiwan water park party</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/taiwan-water-park-fire-injures-nearly-500-1.3130513?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan water park fire injures nearly 500
Fire set off by accidental explosion of an unknown powder
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 1:31 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 11:40 PM ET
About 1,000 people were gathered for a concert at the water park when the explosion went off near a performance stage. (Associated Press)
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring nearly 500 people, including 141 in serious condition, authorities said.
The fire was sparked by an accidental explosion of an unknown powder near the stage in front of about 1,000 people, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Taiwan's Central News Agency on Sunday reported 474 have been injured, including 141 in serious condition. It quoted the New Taipei City health bureau. The injured included four mainland Chinese and two foreigners.
Witnesses said the fire spread quickly after the coloured powder was blown into the air. (Associated Press)
The fire erupted at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City near the island's capital and was quickly brought under control.
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
CNA reported witnesses as saying the fire spread quickly after the coloured powder was blown into the air.
It wasn't clear if the coloured powder was part of a performance. The cause of the fire is being investigated.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:47:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hunchbacked mutt Quasi Modo crowned World's Ugliest Dog</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/world-s-ugliest-dog-contest-crowns-hunchbacked-mutt-quasi-modo-1.3130675?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
World's Ugliest Dog contest crowns hunchbacked mutt Quasi Modo
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 3:47 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 7:50 PM ET
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix Quasi Modo and her owner took the $1,500 US prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that celebrates imperfection, organizers said. (Noah Berger/Associated Press)
Quasi Modo crowned World's Ugliest Dog 0:39
Related Stories
World's ugliest dog contest 2014
A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year's World's Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and her owner took the $1,500 US prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that celebratesimperfection, organizers said.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Fla., according to her biography posted on the contest's website.
"My appearance can be a little unsettling to some (I have had grown men jump on top of their cars to get away from me because they thought I was a hyena or Tasmanian devil) but once they get to know me I win them over with my bubbly personality," her biography said.
Sweepee Rambo, a 16-year-old Chinese Crested dog, won the runner-up award. (Noah Berger/Associated Press)
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
An 8-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the "spirit award," honouring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles or are providing service to the community. Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest, held at the Sonoma-Marin Fairgrounds in Petaluma, Calif., is in its 27th year.
The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:09:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate flag removed by South Carolina protester</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/confederate-flag-removed-by-south-carolina-protester-1.3130425?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag removed by South Carolina protester
Bree Newsome of Charlotte removes flag from front of statehouse
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 11:09 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 3:34 PM ET
Woman takes down Confederate flag 1:47
Related Stories
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
The Confederate flag was temporarily removed from the front of the South Carolina Statehouse on Saturday when a woman climbed the flagpole and  despite calls by police to get down  removed the banner.
BreeNewsome, 30, of Charlotte, N.C., was about halfway up the more than nine-metresteel flagpole just after dawn Saturday when officers of the South Carolina Bureau of Protective Services told her to get down. Instead, she continued climbing to the top and removed the banner.
She and a man who had climbed over a 1.2-metrewrought-iron fence to get to the flag were arrested.
The historical significance of Charleston's 'Mother Emanuel' church
The flag, which is protected by state law, was raised about 45 minutes later. Flag supporters planned a rally at the monument later on Saturday.
Sherri Iacobelli, a spokeswoman for the state Department of Public Safety, said that Newsome and James Ian Tyson, 30, also of Charlotte, have been charged with defacing monuments on state Capitol grounds. That's a misdemeanour that carries a fine of up to $5,000 US and a prison term of up to three years or both.
Bree Newsome of Charlotte, N.C., removes the Confederate battle flag at a Confederate monument at the statehouse. The flag was put back about 45 minutes later. (Bruce Smith/Associated Press)
A staff member at the Alvin Glenn Detention Center where the two were taken said she did not know if the two had attorneys. About the time of her arrest, Newsome released an email statement to the media.
'We can't wait any longer'
"We removed the flag today because we can't wait any longer. We can't continue like this another day," it said. "It's time for a new chapter where we are sincere about dismantling white supremacy and building toward true racial justice and equality."
Authorities said Newsome was from Raleigh. However, Mervyn Marcano, a spokesman for the small group of activists who worked together to take down the flag, said she had recently moved to Charlotte.
Tamika Lewis, another member of the group, said taking down the flag "was done because we were tired of waiting for the judicial system to make the decision they have been prolonging for a very long time."
Calls for removing the flag have been renewed since nine black churchgoers were killed in what police characterized as a racist attack at a Charleston, S.C.,church last week.
South Carolina lawmakers took the initial steps last Tuesday toward removing the Confederate battle flag from the Statehouse grounds by agreeing to allow discussion of the matter during the legislative session.
The agreement came a day after Republican Gov. Nikki Haley reversed course and called for the divisive symbol to come down. The flag has flown in front of the state Capitol for 15 years after being moved from atop the Statehouse dome.
The momentum in South Carolina sparked further calls from politicians across the state and country for flags and Confederate symbols to be removed from public displays in other states.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 20:46:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The week in pictures: From same-sex marriage in U.S. to Taylor Swift's battle with Apple</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/photos/the-week-in-pictures-from-same-sex-marriage-in-u-s-to-taylor-swift-s-battle-with-apple-1.3124496?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>The week in pictures: From same-sex marriage in U.S. to Taylor Swift's battle with Apple
Top images from around the world for June 20-26
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:06:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hunt for escaped N.Y. prisoner David Sweat intensifies after Richard Matt shot dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/hunt-for-escaped-n-y-prisoner-david-sweat-intensifies-after-richard-matt-shot-dead-1.3130402?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Hunt for escaped N.Y. prisoner David Sweat intensifies after Richard Matt shot dead
Helicopters, search dogs and hundreds of law enforcement officers converge on wooded area
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 11:06 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 6:38 PM ET
Police hold a morning strategy meeting at the Titus Mountain Ski Area in the town of Malone, N.Y.,before heading out to search for escaped inmate David Sweat. (New York State Police/Facebook)
New York prisoner manhunt 5:44
Related Stories
New York prison escape: Husband talks about threats from inmates
The shooting death of one escaped killer brought new energy to a weeks-long hunt for a second escaped murderer as helicopters, search dogs and hundreds of law enforcement officers converged on a wooded area 50 kilometres from the prison in Upstate New York.
Richard Matt, escaped N.Y. prisoner, shot dead
"Of course our preference would always be to capture them alive," New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico told a news conference as he announced late Friday the killing hours earlier of Richard Matt, one of two escaped killers from an upstate maximum-security prison.
New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico, left, and Gov. Andrew Cuomo speak to reporters on Friday in Malone, N.Y., after escaped prisoner Richard Matt was shot and killed by a border patrol agent in a wooded area about 50 kilometres from Clinton Correctional Facility. (Mary Altaffer/Associated Press)
He credited a tip from the public, one of over 2,300 received so far, for crucial information leading to the deadly confrontation in the town of Malone.
D'Amico said Matt was shot by a border patrol agent when he failed to comply with commands in the woods near a cabin where a shot had been fired earlier in the day at a camping trailer. A 20-gauge shotgun was found on him, though he did not fire it at officers, he added.
"They verbally challenged him, told him to put up his hands. And at that time, he was shot when he didn't comply," D'Amico said.
A second convicted murderer, David Sweat, has not been spotted since he escaped, though evidence was found a week ago indicating he was with Matt in a cabin that was burglarized about five kilometres from any paved roadway, the superintendent said.
David Sweat, left, and Richard Matt escaped June 6 after using tools that had been hidden in hamburger meat to cut their way out of the maximum-security prison. Matt was fatally shot Friday after refusing to surrender to border agents, police say. (New York State Police via AP)
An intense search of the area led to a discovery Friday morning of a camp where somebody apparently had laid down, leaving behind candy wrappers and other items, D'Amico said.
The breakthrough Friday came shortly before 2 p.m., when a person towing a camper heard a loud sound and thought a tire had blown. Finding the tires intact, the driver went another 13 kilometresbefore looking at the trailer and finding a bullet hole.
Authorities converged on the location where the sound was heard and discovered the smell of gunfire inside a cabin, where a weapon had been fired. D'Amico said there also was evidence someone recently had fled out the back door.
Prison escapes: Tools, tricks, helicopters or strolling out the door
"As we were doing the ground search in the area, there was movement detected by officers on the ground, what they believed to be coughs. So they knew that they were dealing with humans as opposed to wildlife," he said.
After Matt was killed, a 20-gauge shotgun that was believed to be missing from the cabin he broke into last weekend was recovered from his body, D'Amico said.
A corrections officer stands near a sign thanking law enforcement along County Route 41 during Saturday's search for David Sweat. (Chris Wattie/Reuters)
"Based on that, we continued to search. We have a lot of people in the area. We have canines and we have a decent perimeter set up and we're searching for Sweat at this time," he said.
D'Amico said he had no information that Sweat was not with or near Matt so a heavy search of the area would go on.
The pair escaped from the Clinton Correctional Facility together early June 6. Gov. Andrew Cuomo called them "dangerous, dangerous men."
'We have a lot of people in the area. We have canines and we have a decent perimeter set up and we're searching for Sweat at this time.'- New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico
Police blocked off roads officers hunted for Sweat in an area around Titusville Mountain State Forest in Malone and spanning 56 square kilometres.
Mitch Johnson said one of his best friends checked on his hunting cabin in Malone Friday afternoon and called police after noticing the scent of grape flavoured gin as soon as he stepped into his cabin and spotting the bottle that had gone untouched for years resting on a kitchen table.
Johnson said his friend, correction officer Bob Willett, told him he summoned police about an hour before Matt was fatally shot and then heard a flurry of gun blasts.
Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a 60-centimetre-thick brick wall, squirmed through pipes and emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
Slain prisoner had killed former boss
Sweat, 35, was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy in Broome County in 2002. Matt, 49, was serving 25 years to life for the killing and dismembering of his former boss. They were added to the U.S. Marshals Service's 15 Most Wanted fugitives list two weeks after getting away.
(Google)
A pair of prison workers has been charged in connection with the inmates' escape.
Prosecutors said Joyce Mitchell, a prison tailoring shop instructor who got close to the men while working with them, had agreed to be their getaway driver but backed out because she felt guilty for participating. Authorities also said Mitchell had discussed killing her husband, Lyle Mitchell, as part of the plot.
N.Y. prison employee arrested for allegedly helping inmates escape
Joyce Mitchell pleaded not guilty June 15 to charges including felony promoting prison contraband, which authorities said included hacksaw blades and chisels.
Authorities said the men had filled their beds in their adjacent cells with clothes to make it appear they were sleeping when guards made overnight rounds. On a cut steam pipe, the prisoners left a taunting note containing a crude caricature of an Asian face and the words "Have a nice day."
On June 24, authorities charged Clinton correction officer Gene Palmer with promoting prison contraband, tampering with physical evidence and official misconduct. Officials said he gave the two prisoners frozen hamburger meat Joyce Mitchell had used to hide the tools she smuggled to Sweat and Matt. Palmer's attorney said he had no knowledge that the meat contained hacksaw blades, a bit and a screwdriver.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:51:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gun culture runs deep in the U.S. and won't change soon</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/gun-culture-runs-deep-in-the-u-s-and-won-t-change-soon-1.3127809?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Analysis
Gun culture runs deep in the U.S. and won't change soon
And it is not just white males from the South who keep the gun culture alive, polls show
ByMark Gollom, CBC News Posted: Jun 27, 2015 5:51 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 5:22 PM ET
Whenever a high-profile shooting occurs, someone campaigns to tighten U.S. gun laws. But change doesn't come easy in a culture where the values of gun ownership run deep and cross so many demographic groups. (San Francisco Chronicle/Michael Macor/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Charleston mayor says US must do more to tackle gun control
Former CNN host and current gun law crusader Piers Morgan wants to remind the public that "it wasn't a flag that killed nine black Americans in their Charleston church. It was a gun."
Whileapplaudingthe decision to remove the Confederate flag from South Carolina'sStateHouse, the British journalist suggests thatcontroversyhasdistracted from the root cause of the deadly shooting.
He dusts off the familiar anti-gun arguments that pop up after any such mass killing, laying the blame on lax U.S.gun laws, the intransigent National Rifle AssociationandRepublicans who refuse to impose any kind of restrictions on weapons.

Nothing novel there in those arguments, nor in the arsenal of counterpointsthe gun rights advocates have been spouting don't blame the gun, don't blame the gun laws, blame the shooter and society's inability to deal with those suffering from mental health issues.

But these endless debates, pro- and anti-gun, mostlycentre on degrees of change in existing gun laws. Rarely are there suggestions or proposals tofundamentally overhaul the nature of gun ownership in the U.S.

President Barack Obama proposed all sorts of changes in 2013following the Sandy Hook school shooting  the reinstatement of a ban on assault-style rifles, a decrease in the size of ammo magazines, and an expansion of federal background checks on firearms buyers. But, as National Review writer Charles Cooke points out , none of those laws, had they been passed, would have made a fig of difference in the recent tragedy. For example, the suspect in Charleston shootingsdid not have an assault-style rifle but a .45-calibre Glock handgun.

So the next step, a gun control advocate might suggest, is to ban those guns too. But that just isn'tgoing to happen any time soon.And why?

The answer may have come from an unlikely source, former George W. Bush adviser Karl Rove, who on Fox News Sunday said this:"The only way to guarantee that we will dramatically reduce acts of violence involving guns is to basically remove guns from society, and until somebody gets enough "oomph" to repeal the Second Amendment, that's not going to happen. I don't think it's an answer."
It's not an answer because Americans,or at least a significant portion of the population, like orwant gunsit's in their cultural DNA.Americans will always have guns.Laws may come and go, banning thisweapon, or that, but there will always be some kind ofgunin the U.S.

While there has been some debate over whether gun ownership is declining in the U.S, it's stillestimated that thereare roughly 300 million guns in the country, which equates to nearly one gun per person.This suggests that any power ascribed to the NRA to quashgun lawsis power that is really derivedfrom the people.

A 2014Pew study looking into the demographics of gun ownership found thatabout a third of all Americans with children under 18 at home have a gun in their household.
And it's all types of Americans who have guns. Republican Americans andDemocratic Americans, male Americans and female Americans, blue state, red state a cross-section of Americans have guns.
Sure, guns aremuch more prevalent in some demographics(white, male, from the South,twice as manyRepublicans as Democrats, but a significant number of Independents.)
But Pew found that, regionally anyway, there wasn'tmuch difference. "Southerners werejust about as likely as those living in the Midwest or the West to have a gun at home (38 per cent35 per centand 34 per cent, respectively)," its study found.Men were more likely than women to be gun owners, but not by much(38 per cent vs. 31 per cent).
And even those who may nothave guns, support gun rights. A Gallup poll last year found that nearly three-quarters of the Americans surveyed said there should not be a ban on the possession of handguns.
Count retired Arizona Democratic congresswoman Gabby Giffords in that group. Giffordssurvived being shot in the headoutside a Tucson supermarket in 2011. Although a proponent for tougher gun laws, shestill considers herself a proud gun owner, asdoes herhusband astronaut Mark Kelly.( A recent CBS interview with her and Kelly showed the couple at a gun range, where Gifford, partially paralyzed in her right side because of the attack, was learningto shoot with her left hand.)
Gun culture in the U.S, may berooted in the days of the early settlers, given some impetusbythe American Revolution, andproliferatedduring and just after the Civil War. But political science professor at SUNYCortlandRobert Spitzer, who arguesthatgun use and ownership has been gradually declining since the1960s, stillsays"guns and the gun culture are deeply engrained in portions of American life."
"The gun culture has two partsthe hunting/sporting tradition, and the frontier/militia tradition,"said Spitzer, author ofGuns Across America."The former is recreational, the latter is political and ideological. Both of these contribute to the modern attachment to guns"
And all that means is that guns, in the U.S., aren't going to disappear.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:00:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Maternal health funding 'the right thing to do' - but what comes next?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/maternal-health-funding-the-right-thing-to-do-but-what-comes-next-1.3126531?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Yesterday: Haiti sees progress- but when can it stand on its own?
Stories like Peter's are what prompted former Canadian foreign affairs minister John Baird in 2012 to speak out against what's known variously as child, early and forced marriage. Last fall, Baird announced Canada would put $10 million toward programs to fight child marriage around the world.
Rob Nicholson has since replaced Baird at foreign affairs, but officials say the focus on ending child marriage continues.
It's an issue not unrelated to Canada's maternal, newborn and child health focus established at the 2010 G8 summit in Muskoka. Women who give birth before they turn 15 are five times more likely to die during delivery, according to British-based NGO Girls Not Brides. Young women, particularly those without medical care, can have serious complications.Giving birth too young also puts the baby at greater risk.
It's a horrifying reality in many countries, and one that's difficult to defend. But it makes up only a single target among dozens included in next set of global development goals.
Sustainability the new focus
The world has spent 15 years working to reach the UN's Millennium Development Goals. First set in 2000, they come to an end on Dec. 31, 2015. The next set of targets, the Sustainable Development Goals, or SDGs, will be set this fall at the UN.
The new regime will havehave twice as many goals and dozens moresubtargets.
It raises the question of whether the world is losing focus on women and children, and the number of preventable deaths: 6.3 million children and 289,000 women a year.
Guillermo Rishchynski,Canada'sambassador to the UN, acknowledges the challenge to keep the world focused on the needs of women and children.
Salome Pascale, 26, and her two-year-old son, at their home in Tanzania's Nzega district, in the region of Tabora. She is pregnant with her third child and says she doesn't know how to avoid getting pregnant other than that she has to speak to a doctor to find out. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"The challenge of course is to keep this as high a priority as possible. And I can tell you without any hesitation that that is the singular preoccupation for myself and our mission here in New York."
While it's hard to find an organization that won't praise Canada's work, some would like to see adjustments to the next round of funding, already announced at $3.5 billion for 2015-2020.
Shannon Kowalski, director of policy at the International Women's Health Coalition, says the Canadian government was a political leader on ending forcedmarriage, including on leading discussions at the UN, but some maternal health polices "undermine the goals that they're espousing internationally."
"One thing that we've noticed with Canada over the last several years is that they've really regressed on their commitments to addressing sexual health and rights, particularly in adolescent girls," Kowalski said in an interview.
"And you can't talk about ending child marriage without also talking about young women's access to sexual and reproductive health services and to comprehensive sexuality education," she said.
"So we feel that's a really missing element that's part of the Canadian response that could actually prevent them from achieving what they want to achieve."
'The right thing to do'
The Conservative government has pledged additional billions over the next five years. But it's also pulled back on overall international development funding, bringing it down to its lowest level since 2005. Official development assistance, or ODA, has fallen from $5.7 billion a year in 2011 to $5.4 billion in 2013 to $4.9 billion last year.
Mickey Chopra, UNICEF's chief of health, says the organization which receives millions in funding from Canada would like to see an increase.
This bed is from a small clinic in Tanzania's Nzega district in the Tabora region. That type of clinic is known as a dispensary. This bed is used for women who need to give birth at the dispensary. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"Not just because it's the right thing to do, but we also do feel it's a very efficient and effective investment to be made," he said.
"The investments that were made in the development of countries such as China, Malaysia and now India do reap benefits in the medium-to-long-term in increasing the market for Canadian goods or increasing the knowledge base for innovation."
Some money has already been allocated under the 2015-2020 funding, although there's been no announcement so far on the$370-million partnership program that gives money directly to NGOs.
With a federal election coming this fall, there's always thepossibility ofa new leadership, which could pull back, redirect or otherwise change Canada's development goals.
Prime Minister Stephen Harper and InternationalDevelopment Minister Christian Paradis turned down repeated requests for interviews on their signature policy.
Tom Mulcair, leader of the NDP, said last month the New Democrats would increase aid to 0.7 per cent of gross national income, which would nearly triple it from the current 0.24 per cent. That 0.7 per cent is a global target that few countries have actually met, although the UK reached it this year.
The NDP said it would also maintain the current focus on maternal, newborn and child health, but expand it to put more money toward family planning, including abortion.
Liberal Leader Justin Trudeau said he would keepmaternal, newborn and child health a priority, and expand the family planning element, including offering abortion. The party wouldreverse the cuts the Conservatives made, butisn't making any promises about hitting the 0.7 per cent target.
The organizations delivering aid around the world will be watching.
The CBC's Laura Payton is this year's R.JamesTravers Fellow. The Travers Fellowship provided $25,000 in funding for her pitch to look at whether Canada's maternal, newborn and child health program was working. Read more about the project here and read her entire series here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:04:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Supreme Court legalizes same-sex marriage in all 50 states</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-s-supreme-court-legalizes-same-sex-marriage-in-all-50-states-1.3127280?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Celebrities react to same-sex marriage decision
In a 5-4 decision released Friday, the court ruled that the amendmentobliges states to license marriages between people of the same sexand to recognize marriages lawfully performed outside of state. Thirty-seven of the 50 states and the District of Columbia already allow gay marriage, andFriday's ruling means the others will have to follow suit.
The ruling only affects state laws. Religious institutions can still choose whether or not to marry same-sex couples.
'[The decision] affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts.'- U.S. President Barack Obama
Obamacalled the decision"a victory for America"and said it "affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts."
"When all Americans aretreated equal, we are all more free,"hesaid from the White House Rose Garden.
He praised the perseverance of those who have fought for gay rights and marriage equality for decades "and slowlymade an entire country realize that love is love."
Aixa Adame, left, and Lacey Darcy exchange vows in front of Judge Laura Strathmann in the 388th District Courtroom in El Paso, Texas. They were the first female couple to be married in El Paso. (Victor Calzada/The El Paso Times/Associated Press)
"Change must have seemed so slow for so long," Obamasaid. "But compared to so many other issues, America's shift has been so quick."
Outside of the courtin Washington, D.C., gay couples and gay rights supporters erupted in cheers, whoops and cries ofU-S-A!" and "Love is love" when the ruling came down.
"I'm simply elated,"said Kenneth Barnes, waving a rainbow flag he's had for more than 20 years."I never thought I'd see this in mylifetime,"
Barnes and his partner married in California in 2008. "Now, everyone can do this," he said.
Manysame-sex couples living instates where gay marriage had been banned headed immediately to county clerks' offices to getmarriage licences as state officials issued statements saying they would respect the ruling. Technically, the losing side has three weeks to ask for reconsideration of the ruling, but many state officials and county clerks started issuing marriagelicences right away.
Some waived the usual waiting period between getting a licence and the marriage ceremony.
Equal protection for all
The 14th Amendment affords equal protection under the law to all citizensand was key in other landmark decisionson such divisiveissues as reproductive rights andracial and gender discrimination (for example, in Brown v. Board ofEducation, and Roe v. Wade).
Today is a big step in our march toward equality. Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else. #LoveWins
 @POTUS
The top court ruledit would be a violation of the amendment to grant marriagerights only to heterosexual couples.
"No union is more profound than marriage, for it embodies the highest ideals of love, fidelity, devotion, sacrificeand family. ... [The challengers] ask for equal dignity in the eyes of the law. The constitution grants them that right," Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote in the majority opinion.
 @WhiteHouse
Obamawelcomed the decisionwith a tweet and a phone call to the lead plaintiff in the case, James Obergefell.
"I'm really proud of you and just know that not only did you set a great example for people, but you're also going to bring about lasting change in this country," he told him in the call, whichObergefell took as he was celebratingin front of the Supreme Court andput on speaker so the crowd could lsiten in.
'From this day forward, it will simply be "marriage,"' James Obergefell, the lead plaintiff in the case, said after the landmark ruling. (Andrew Harnik/Associated Press)
Obergefell was in court when Kennedy read the decision and afterward held upa photo of his late spouse, John, outside the court building, saying the ruling establishesthat "our love is equal."
"This is for you, John." he said.
"From this day forward, it will simply be 'marriage.'"
TheWhite House donned rainbow colours, a symbol of the gay rights movement, on its Twitter and home page in celebration of the ruling.
In its ruling, the Supreme Court said the "long history of disapproval of their relationships" and thedenial of the right to marry has done a "grave and continuing harm" to same-sex couples.
Laurin Locke, 24, left, and her partner, Tiffany Brosh, 26, of Pearl, Miss., applied for a marriage licence at the Hinds County Circuit Clerk's office in Jackson, Miss., moments after the U.S. Supreme Court ruling came down. (Rogelio V. Solis/Associated Press)
"The imposition of this disability on gays and lesbians serves to disrespect and subordinate them,"Kennedywrote. "And the equal protection clause, like the due process clause, prohibits this unjustified infringement of the fundamental right to marry."
People are celebrating outside the Supreme Court, this pair came from Florida to be here #CBC pic.twitter.com/w8iUhNuFid
 @fitzpatrick_m
Kennedy, a conservativeappointed by Republican President Ronald Reagan in1988whooften casts the deciding vote inclose cases, hasauthored all four of the court's major gay rights rulings, with the first coming in 1996.
JusticeAntonin Scaliawrote the mostscathing of the four dissenting opinions, calling the decision a" threat to American democracy" and ridiculing the flowery language of the majority opinion.
Eric Braman, right, is hugged by his best man after registering for a marriage licence with his partner Kris Katkus, in Kalamazoo, Mich. (Mark Bugnaski/Kalamazoo Gazette-MLive Media Group/Associated Press)
"If, even as the price to be paid for a fifth vote, I ever joined an opinion for the court that began: 'The Constitution promises liberty to all within its reach, a liberty that includes certain specific rights that allow persons, within a lawful realm, to define and express their identity,'I would hide my head in a bag," Scalia wrote.
"The Supreme Court of the United States has descended from the disciplined legal reasoning of John Marshall and Joseph Story to the mystical aphorisms of the fortune cookie."
Scalia took strong issue with the majority interpretation of the 14th Amendment.
"The five Justices who compose today's majority are entirely comfortable concluding that every state violated the Constitution for all of the 135 years between the 14th Amendment's ratification and Massachusetts's permitting of same-sex marriages in 2003," he wrote. "They have discovered in the14th Amendment a 'fundamental right'overlooked by every person alive at the time of ratification, and almost everyone else in the time since."
Theotherdissenters were justices SamuelAlito, ClarenceThomas and John Roberts.
Crowd tears up at singing of anthem at steps of Supreme Court #CBCnews pic.twitter.com/9Sqy4ilZQo
 @kimbrunhuber
Roberts saidthere are compelling policy arguments for extending marriage tosame-sex couplesbut no legal argument to justify forcingstates to change their marriage laws.
"The fundamental right to marry does not include a right to make a state change its definition of marriage," he wrote. "Our constitution does not enact any one theory of marriage. The people of a state are free to expand marriage to include same-sex couples, or to retain the historic definition."
He said that while he doesn't begrudge supportersof gay marriage their celebrations, the court overstepped in handing down a ruling that"orders the transformation of a social institution that has formed the basis of human society for millennia, for the Kalahari bushmen and the Han Chinese, the Carthaginians and the Aztecs."
"Just who do we think we are?" he wrote.
Roberts and other dissenters predicted further legal wrangles fromthose opposed to same-sex marriage on religious grounds.
Political Conservatives also denounced the ruling.Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee called it "an out-of-control act of unconstitutional judicial tyranny."
Wisconsin Republican Governor Scott Walker, also running for president, called for amending the U.S. Constitution to allow states to again ban same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Governor Greg Abbott said, "Marriage was defined by God. No man can redefine it."
Plaintiffs' arguments
The court was examiningtwo key questions:
Whether states can ban same-sex marriage.
Whether states with gay marriage bans can refuse to recognize marriagesperformed in other jurisdictions where same-sex marriage is legal.
The plaintiffs hadargued that the court hadalready acknowledgedmarriage is a fundamental right in previous decisions and that they were merely seeking equal access to this right.
Jayne Rowse, left, and partner April DeBoer were among the five plaintiffs whose cases made up the challenge of gay marriage bans before the Supreme Court. (Bill Pugliano/Getty)
The challenge of state bans on gay marriagejoined together the cases ofObergefell, April DeBoer, Jayne Rowse, Ijpe DeKoeand Thomas Kostura.
DeKoe and Kosturalegally married in New Yorkbut then moved to Tennessee, where their marriage wasn't recognized.
Obergefell legally married his partner of 20 years,John Arthur, in Maryland, but was not recognized as his legal spouse when Arthur died a few months later in Ohio.
DeBoer and Rowse have three children together but were prevented from jointly adopting them or having them covered under each other's health insurance because they were not legally married, and couldn't get married because their home state ofMichigan doesn't recognize same-sex marriage.
Ruling follows other key victories in gay rights movement
The court's latest decision is themost important expansion of marriage rights in the United States since its landmark 1967 ruling in the case Loving v. Virginia that struck down state laws barring interracial marriages.
The ruling is the latest milestone in the gay rights movement in recent years. In 2010, Obama signed a law allowing gays to serve openly in the U.S. military. In 2013, the Supreme Court struck down a provision of the federal Defence of Marriage Act that defined marriage as a union between a woman and manandprevented same-sex couples married in states where such unions are legal from accessing certain federal programs and filing tax returns as a married couple, for example.
The U.S. is the latest of many Western countries to recognize same-sex marriage.Last month, voters in Ireland backed same-sex marriage by a landslide in a referendum that marked a dramatic social shift in the traditionally Roman Catholic country.
Gay marriageis also legal in Canada,South Africa, Brazil,Britain, France and Spain, but many parts of Africa and Asia consider it andhomosexuality in general taboo and often illegal.
With files from Reuters and The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:49:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia beach hotel attack: mosques closed, army reservists enlisted</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tunisia-beach-hotel-attack-mosques-closed-army-reservists-enlisted-1.3130343?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia museum attack: More than 20 arrested in nationwide crackdown
Tunisia's prime minister announced on Saturday a string of new security measures including closing renegade mosques and calling up army reservists as thousands of tourists fled the North African country in wake of its worst terrorist attack ever.
Tourists crowded into the airport at Hammamet near the coastal city of Sousse where a young man dressed in shorts on Friday pulled an assault rifle and grenades out of his beach umbrella and killed 38 people, mostly tourists.The Islamic State of Iraq and Syriagroup (ISIS) has claimed responsibility for the attack.
Essid announced the call-up of army reservists and said they would be deployed in tourist sites around the country and inside hotels, while he called on the hotels themselves to do more to enforce security.
He also said that political parties and associations espousing radical ideas with suspicious funding would be closed down and around 80 mosques known for extremist preaching would be shut. Hepromised financial rewards for information leading to arrests related to the attack.
"This is a decision the government has taken and we have assigned the minister of interior and all authorities involved to carry this out within the coming week," said Essid."It is not acceptable to have in Tunisia any mosques operating outside the rule of law."
The government has been criticized for its lacklustre anti-terror measures, especially since 22 people were killed by gunmen at the national museum in March. There was also been a failed suicide bomb attack in Sousse in 2013.
British death toll 'may well rise'
At least 15 British citizens were killed in the attack,most of them tourists, the U.K.'s foreign minister said Saturday.
Tunisia beach hotel attack leaves 38 dead, 36 wounded
Tobias Ellwood also said the British toll "may well rise" and referred to the assault as "the most significant terrorist attack on the British people" since July 7, 2005, when suicide bombers struck the London transport network, killing 52 people and wounding hundreds of others.
This image taken from a militant website associated with Islamic State extremists, posted on Saturday purports to show the Tunisian gunman, identified as Seifeddine Rezgui. (Associated Press)
Ireland's foreign minister says the government suspects that two other Irish citizens are among the dead, in addition to nurse Lorna Carty.
A spokesman for Tunisia's health ministry said a total of 39 people were wounded in the shooting, including 21 people who have now left the hospital. Chokri Nafi told The Associated Press that 18 are under observation, including two who are in critical condition.
He said the nationalities of the injured include seven Tunisians, 25 Britons, three Belgians, one German, one Ukrainian, one Russian and one who has not yet been identified. Nafi said the attack left 39 people dead, including the gunman.
Tunisian police arrest more than 20 in crackdown
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted around noon at the Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba near Sousse, 140 kilometres south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire left and right at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot. A spokesman for the interior ministry said the gunman was a student in his early 20s, but Tunisian authorities did not name him. Awebsite associated with ISIS on Saturday posted what it said was the gunman, a Tunisian identified asSeifeddine Rezgui.
The bodies of several tourists lay crumpled where they fell in the sand, covered with yellow towels and blankets among the plastic white sunbeds. Blood smeared stone steps leading from the hotel main area.
Thousands of tourists leave
At the Imperial Marhaba on Saturday,vans and buses were carrying tourists away. While the hotel wasn't actually closing down, the tour operators had urged everyone to leave, the director said.
"We may have zero clients today but we will keep our staff," said Mohammed Becheur, adding the 370-room hotel had been at 75 percent occupancy before the attack.
On the beach, there was as scattering of tourists while police on horses rode along the beach and their security boats patrolled along the coast.
Tourism is a key part of Tunisia's economy and had already fallen some 25 percent after the March museum attack.
"Since yesterday, there have been about 15 extra flights scheduled at the airport with nine already leaving carrying 1,400 passengers," said Mohamed Walid Ben Ghachem, director of the Enfidha-Hammamet Airport.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 13:23:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China cuts interest rates for 4th time since November to boost economy</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/china-cuts-interest-rates-to-boost-sluggish-economy-1.3130350?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
China cuts interest rates to boost sluggish economy
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 6:23 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 6:23 AM ET
The People's Bank of China will cut the rate on a one-year loan by commercial banks by 0.25 percentage point to 4.85 per cent, starting Sunday. (Frederic J. Brown/AFP/Getty)
Related Stories
China cuts interest rates for 3rd time in 5 months
The People's Bank of China said Saturday that it would cut the rate on a one-year loan by commercial banks by 0.25 percentage point to 4.85 per cent. The interest rate paid on a one-year deposit was lowered by 0.25 point to 2 per cent.
Rates were cut on Nov. 22, March 1 and then May 11. The new rates take effect Sunday.
The central bank also says the reserve requirement ratios to small businesses would be lowered by 50 points, a move that would boost lending.
Economic growth has slowed in China, and its stock markets plunged Friday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama leads mourners in Amazing Grace at funeral for Charleston shooting victim Rev. Pinckney</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/obama-eulogizes-charleston-shooting-victim-rev-clementa-pinckney-sings-amazing-grace-1.3128798?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Obama eulogizes Charleston shooting victim Rev. Clementa Pinckney, sings Amazing Grace
Overflow crowd of thousands at service attended by Obama and other politicians and dignitaries
CBC News Posted: Jun 26, 2015 10:32 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 5:28 PM ET
Obama eulogizes Charleston shooting victim Rev. Pinckney and leads mourners in singing Amazing Grace 2:50
Related Stories
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
U.S. President Barack Obama describedRev.ClementaPinckney as a kind, diligent man who was "able to walk in someone else's shoes, able to see through their eyes" at a funeral for the South Carolina pastor shot to death with eight others at aCharleston churchlast week.
Obama, who knew Pinckney personally,eulogized the pastor infront of a crowdof more than 5,000at an arena in downtown Charleston, recalling Pinckney'shumble influence on his communityand at one point leading the crowdin a chorus of thehymnAmazing Grace.
South Carolinalawmakers debate Confederate flag
"Even from a young age, people knew he was special," Obamasaid of Pinckney."He conducted himself kindly, quietly and diligently. He was full of empathy, able to walk in someone else's shoes, able to see through their eyes.That's the best thing to hope for when you're eulogized to just say somebody was a good man."
The late Rev. Clementa Pinckney's daughter, Malana, reaches up to U.S. President Barack Obama next to her sister Eliana, right, as their mother Jennifer hugs first lady Michelle Obama after the president eulogized Rev. Pinckney during funeral services at the College of Charleston TD Arena in Charleston, S.C., on Friday (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Pinckneyheadedthe historic African-American Emanuel AME Church and was also a state senator. He was takingpartin a bible study on June 17 whena gunman entered the church, joined the bible study for an hour before opening fire, killing Pinckney and seven other parishoners. One person died later in hospital.
Obama acknowledged those other victims in his eulogy.
"To the families of the fallen, our nation shares in your grief," he said.
'Aflag did not commit these murders'
Dylann Roof, 21, has been charged with nine counts of murder in connection with the shooting. He has been linkedto a website with numerous racist writings and images, including ones showing him holding a Confederate flag, a Civil War-era battle flagseen by many as a racist symbol of the slave-owning American South.
More than 5,000 mourners packed a downtown Charleston arena for the service. (Brian Snyder/Reuters)
Politicians and civil rights activists have called for the flag to be removed from governmentbuildings and other institutions in South Carolina and elsewhere in the wake of the shooting while other's have insisted it is an important part of the history of the American south. Obama alluded to that controversy at the funeral Friday.
"It's true a flag did not commit these murders" he said."Theflag has always represented more than ancestral pride. For many, black and white, that flag was a reminder of oppression and racial subjugation.
"For too long, we were blind to the pain that the Confederate flag stirred in too many of our citizens."
The president acknowledged that racism can't be solved by debate and thatsolutions will always be imperfect.
"There's no shortcut. We don't need more talk," Obama said. "Whatever solutions we find will be necessarily incomplete."
Joe Biden, HillaryClintonin attendance
Obamaarrived in Charleston Friday afternoon, several hoursafter addressing the nation from the White House Rose Garden about the U.S. Supreme Court's decision to legalize gay marriage in all 50 states.
Other speakers at the funeral praisedPinckney'spersonal touch andhis political reach.
The tone of Friday's funeral service was largely uplifting. The service included several musical numbers and humourous anecdotes about the beloved pastor. (Grace Beahm/Reuters)
"We will see the Confederate flag come down.You're the one who did it." said South Carolina statesenatorGerald Malloy. "Do not let race, religion or politics close the door that SenatorPinckney opened."
Bishop John Richard Bryant spoke to the congregation about Roofand his effect on the South Carolina community and the country at large.
"He wanted to start a race war, but he came to the wrong place," said Bryant. "Weeping may endure for the night, but joy comes in the morning."
MichelleObamaand Vice-President JoeBidenand his wife,Jill, also attended the service, as didHouse Speaker John Boehner,Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton and other state and federal politicians and civil rightsactivists, includingMartin Luther King III.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
