<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks extended </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iran-nuclear-talks-will-continue-through-friday-u-s-says-1.3140994?cmp=rss</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:17:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Isère, France attack: 1 beheaded, 2 injured at gas factory</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/is%C3%A8re-france-attack-1-beheaded-2-injured-at-gas-factory-1.3128657?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. local timewhen a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
Notre rponse, c'est l'action, la prvention, la dissuasion et donc la ncessit de porter des valeurs et de ne pas cder  la peur, jamais.
 @fhollande
"Islamist terrorism has struck once again in France," said FrenchPrime Minister Manuel Valls.
Authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.A local media outlet, Ledauphine.com, said the victim was a manager with a transportation company who was on the site to make a delivery.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
Ledauphine.com said anotherperson, who was seen driving back and forthin front of the Air Products factory,wasarrested at their residence inSaint-Quentin-Fallavier.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, in central eastern France on Friday. An attacker carrying an Arabic banner killed one person at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a security official. (Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images)
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Penn. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
The attack occurred in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, in the Isre region between Grenoble and Lyon. (CBC)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obamacare support grows amid latest Supreme Court win</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/obamacare-support-grows-amid-latest-supreme-court-win-1.3128170?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Obamacare support grows amid latest Supreme Court win
King v. Burwell decision allows millions to keep federal subsidies, many in Republican states
ByMatt Kwong, special to, CBC News Posted: Jun 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 6:16 AM ET
Picketers, both for and against Obamacare, rallied outside the U.S. Supreme Court back in 2012 when the first case against it was being heard. Now, with two Supreme Court wins, Americans seem to be coming around to the reforms.  (The Associated Press)
Related Stories
Crowded Republican presidential field ramps up the paranoia
Manuel Camacho doesn't have many flattering words for Obamacare.
"Ridiculous," the New Jersey resident says. "A headache," he says. "We were pretty much forced to get it," he says.
And yet, even before the U.S. Supreme Court ruled Thursday on the legality of the provision in the Affordable Care Act that gives federal subsidies to people in the Garden State, the 33-year-old security guard sounded an almost appreciative tone.
Like Obamacare or not, Camarcho's $75-a-month premium for basic health insurance definitely beats the roughly $200 he says he'd be billed monthly without the federal discount.
"There's no way I could afford that," he said, conceding the Obamacare tax credits are what's keeping him afloat.
The nanny-state lie behind Obamacare
Fortunately for Camacho and an estimated 6.4 million Americans across 34 mostly Republican-led states, the status quo prevailed on Thursday.
In the case known as King v. Burwell, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled 6-3 that subsidies under the Affordable Care Act are legal for all low- and middle-income Americans, regardless of whether a state chose to create its own "exchange," or online insurance marketplace.
Manuel Camacho, a security guard in N.J., is no fan of Obamacare. But he says he wouldn't be able to afford health care without the federal subsidies for low- and middle-income Americans. (Matt Kwong / CBC)
Those largely "red" states  New Jersey among them had opted to have the federal government step in and set up an official health-insurance marketplace through HealthCare.gov.
But Obamacare opponents had challenged that, claiming a provision in the health-care act is worded in such a way that subsidies should only be available to Americans on exchanges established by the state. That would exclude subsidies for purchases on exchanges created by the federal government.
Had the Supreme Court struck down the subsidies for those holdout states, the lives of millions would have been affected by enormous insurance price hikes.
Opinion shifting
In New Jersey, where the average credit is $306 a month, some 170,000 people can now breathe a little easier, said Maura Collinsgru, the health-care program director for the advocacy group New Jersey Citizen Action.
"That's how many people in our state would have lost credits and likely would have lost their coverage because it would have become unaffordable," she said.
"Hopefully we can now move forward in making what we started under the ACA reform even better."
That's a big hope. So far, the Republican-controlled Congress has voted nearly 60 times to repeal, tweak or undermine the Affordable Care Act.
But with each deflected anti-Obamacare attack, like Thursday's second win in the Supreme Court, sentiment supporting the president's signature legislative achievement is growing, Collinsgru believes.
"All those repeal efforts and now this Supreme Court case has, on the flip side, done a service to people trying to raise awareness of the benefits and protections of the ACA," she said.
Recent polls suggest she could be right.
A CBS-New York Times survey on Monday found that for the first time in their polling, more people supported the health-care law (47 per cent) than opposed it (44 per cent).
Although still short of a majority in favour, the gains are notable considering its unpopularity among Americans since it became law in 2010.
According to the CBS-NYT poll, many who weren't sold on Obamacare nevertheless found something to approve of: for example, 70 per cent were in favour of letting people retain their federal subsidies, a pillar of the reform program.
Christie off the hook
Collinsgru expects Thursday's outcome was good news for New Jersey Governor Chris Christie, even if he's loath to admit as much.
"I would imagine he's relieved of the decision because he will not now have to take a proactive step to secure tax credits for more than 170,000 New Jerseyians," she said.
The Republican governor has admitted he was reaping the budgetary benefits of the Medicaid expansion under Obamacare, and had called it "the right decision" for his state during a March town hall meeting.
The 2013 Medicaid expansion, which some observers saw as a tacit acceptance of Obamacare by mostly Republican legislatures, has helped save New Jersey $150 million, according to the state's treasurer, with a projected $417 more to be saved in fiscal 2016.
Christie, however, has been mum about those savings, parroting Republicans who have condemned the health-care law.
In fact, minutes after the Supreme Court decision declaring the tax credits legal, Christie tweeted that "leaders must turn our attention to making the case that Obamacare must be replaced."
Moving on
In the meantime, the continuation of those federal subsidies should allow Teresa Brooks, a 63-year-old retiree in Jersey City, to keep paying the $95 a month for her daughter's health insurance while she attends college.
"But that's just for my daughter  that's not for us," Brooks said.
Teresa Brooks, a retiree in Jersey City, says she wouldn't be able to afford her daughter's health insurance while at college without the federal subsidies. (Matt Kwong / CBC)
Without the discount? "Definitely we'd be out. She just would not have health insurance. And in college, you need to have health insurance."
Collinsgru is now looking forward to bringing in more people in the next open enrolment period for coverage in November.
She believes there's been enough affirmation around the program.
"It's time to quit the repeal attempts," she said. "They've tried 54 times to undermine it. Now, this Supreme Court decision says the ACA is here to stay, it will stay, and it's time to move forward."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:21:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>8 cruise ship tourists, pilot die in plane crash on Alaska cliff</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/alaska-plane-crash-8-cruise-ship-tourists-pilot-dead-1.3128570?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Alaska plane crash: 8 cruise ship tourists, pilot dead
DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop found 240 metres above Ella Lake
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 7:21 PM PT Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 2:39 AM PT
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam remains docked in Ketchikan, Alaska.  (Taylor Balkom/Ketchikan Daily News/Associated Press)
Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of eight cruise ship passengers and a pilot who were killed when their sightseeing plane crashed in a remote and rugged area of southeastern Alaska.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery after the wreckage of the aircraft was found Thursday against a granite rock face, 240 metresabove a lake.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down, killing the nine people during the sightseeing excursion. No names have been released.
Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office, said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down."
He earlier confirmed the deaths: ""We have nine fatalities."
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 1,3000 kilometressoutheast of Anchorage.
Ella Lake, east of Ketchikan, Alaska marks the spot where searchers found the aircraft on a cliffside 240 metres above the lake. (Google maps)
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to traveling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 809,000-hectareMisty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Haiti sees progress, with Canada's help - but when can it stand on its own?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/haiti-s-health-gains-at-risk-without-ongoing-assistance-from-canada-1.3124034?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Haiti's health gains at risk without ongoing assistance from Canada
Canadian development runs into roadblocks in country still rebuilding from 2010's earthquake
ByLaura Payton, CBC News Posted: Jun 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET
Children wait at a community meeting in Terre Neuve, Haiti. Community health workers at the meeting will weigh every child and update their vaccinations. (Laura Payton/CBC)
Related Stories
Read Laura Payton's blog
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
The hospital in Gonaves feels like it's sitting in the middle of a desert, even though the community is on Haiti's west coast. It's hard to see anything but dull beige sand and the muted brown hills beyond as the sun bakes it all dry and dusty.
The hospital is well-designed: Canada contributed $29 million so it could be built to withstand earthquakes and hurricanes. The green and white facility lets air and light flow through to keep energy costs low. Mexico and the U.S. kicked in an additional US$6.1 million for equipment, including solar panels, and management costs.
More stories in the 2015 Travers Fellowship series
The hospital is at about 35 to 40 per cent of capacity, with a plan to gradually ramp up over the next two years, says Jean-Franois Laurent, director of the health unit for the UN's Office for Project Services in Haiti.
Laurent's role is scheduled to end next month, but that doesn't mean a clean hand-off to Haiti's health ministry, which goes by the French acronym MSPP.
The $29-million Canadian-funded hospital in Gonaives, Haiti was overseen by the UN Office for Project Services. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"Of course once we're done, I hope it's not the end," said Laurent, a Canadian.
"The Haitian government will find other donors or support...There's a very strong will at the governmental level, at the ministry level, to make this hospital a model in the country.
"But on the other hand, there's so many variables that we cannot control."
Over the past five years, Canadian-funded programs in Haiti have helped educate people on the need for proper hygiene and clean water, trained technicians to build and fix water filters and provided money to buildanew hospital and new clinics.
But below the shiny surface of brand-new facilities lurks the shadow of uncertainty. When will the country be able to take over running the facilities and paying the salaries of the people who staff them? Will there be enough staff to put them to full use? What shape will these buildings be in five years from now? Twenty years from now?
Right now, more than 60 per cent ofHaiti'shealth budget comes fromdonors like Canada. Another29 per cent is covered by patients through user fees, and only seven per cent comes from the state.
That's barely enough for salaries.
At risk of losing ground
Haiti is an interesting place to be a Canadian. The $1billion provided to the Caribbeancountry since the 2010 earthquakegives Canada an unusually high profile. The ambassador's namecarries a lot of weight. The British have a small office inCanada's embassy,rather than the other way around.
2015 Travers Fellowship series
The CBC's Laura Payton is this year's R. James Travers Fellow. The Travers Fellowship provided $25,000 in funding for her pitch to look at whether Canada's maternal, newborn and child health program was working. Read more about the project here .
Yesterday: Canada's family planning problem
Tomorrow:What'snext?
And, local officials still talk about a suggestion two years ago by former international development minister Julian Fantino that Canada could freeze aid to Haiti .
But despite the years of co-operation and hundreds of millions of dollars invested,a recently released evaluation of Canada's work in Haiti from 2006 to 2013 found that the future could see a troubled transition.
Community health workers supported by Quebec-based NGO CCISD measure and weigh children at a gathering in Terre Neuve, Haiti. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"The almost exclusive reliance on executing agencies (the United Nations, the private sector, universities, NGOs, and so on), meant the opportunity to strengthen government systems was missed," said the external report prepared for the Canadian government.
The evaluation found several reasons to praise Canada, including for improving co-ordination between donors to eliminate duplicated efforts and helping more people castballots in elections.
But it warned Haiti's health sector might not be able to take on the management and staffing of new infrastructure.
"The MSPP lacks both the resources (funding, staff, medication, equipment, etc.) and the management capacity to support existing programs, even in the capital region... Canada should carefully consider whether to contribute to the further expansion of infrastructure and health programs, and what the capacity constraints of doing so might be."
It also foundproblems related to Canada's development workand emergency humanitarian assistance:
Several programs, especially in health and education, were at risk of "not sustaining results" because of insufficient funding from the Haitian government.
The lack of a proper strategy for transferring knowledge and skills to Haitians, which diminished the prospects for sustainability.
And agencies providing assistance programs offered salaries and working conditions the government of Haiti couldn't match, "robbing the civil service of staff."
'Come a long way'
Paula Caldwell St-Onge, Canada's ambassador to Haiti, exudes warmth across a boardroom table at the embassy in Port-au-Prince. She's popular in the community of non-governmental organizations in Haiti and seems to have a close relationship with the country's health minister.
But Caldwell St-Onge is clear: the embassywon't simply hand overcheques, even though the external evaluation found Canada is losing a chance to build local expertise when it doesn't let Haiti itself handle donor funds for development.
A nurse fills out paperwork at a newly built Canadian-funded hospital in Gonaives, Haiti. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"We [are helping] them create better management structures and better strategic plans with a budget attached to it, which is not the case right now," Caldwell said.
"So I think when we get to that point and we can see some transparency with the strategic plans and where we're going, that will be for the Canadian government to decide when that time comes."
CaldwellSt-Onge, who previously worked in Brazil and Mexico, knows Haiti well: she partly grew up there while her father worked for the Royal Bank. She says the earthquake set back the country dramatically, with nearly one fifth of the civil service killed that day.
"People are always saying 'geez, there's so much more left to do.' But the thing is we've come a long way, so yeah, I think there is a difference. It's not like we've stayed at zero and not gone forward. So I think all of that gives us hope for the future."
'Keep being positive'
International development is complex. Issues intermingle.
Canada is focusing on maternal, newborn and child health. That ties into economic development because poor families need jobs to pay for food, and it ties into governancebecause countries losing money to corruption can't provideservices.
Haiti's health ministry has plans to cut corruption by introducing standard accounting practices and to increase revenue by opening up hospitals to doctors performing private services.
Budget pressures, time crunches limit progress in Tanzania 
But HealthMinisterFlorenceDupervalGuillaume admits she can't imagine a day when Haiti won't need Canada, though she hopes to move beyond the basic assistance that sees NGOsinstructing people on the need to wash their hands or use a toilet instead of defecating near water sources.
"We need to get rid of this type of package of assistance one day and to have really a partnership for development  where we can decrease poverty everywhere, [where] we can also give technical assistance one day to some other countries," she said.
"I'm a very positive person and I keep being positive."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:27:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait City Shia mosque bombed after prayers, reportedly killing 2</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/kuwait-city-shia-mosque-bombed-after-prayers-reportedly-killing-2-1.3128713?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait City Shia mosque bombed after prayers, reportedly killing 2
ISIS claims responsibility after blast strkes Imam Sadiq Mosque in city's al-Sawabir district
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 26, 2015 7:27 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 7:44 AM ET
A witness who was at Kuwait City's Imam Sadiq Mosque at the time said the explosion took place on the grounds after Friday prayers. (Saudi Gazette)
Related Stories
What happened after the Arab Spring?
A deadly explosion ripped through a Shia mosque in a busy neighbourhood of Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers, witnesses said, reportedly killing two.
Mohammed al-Faili, 32, told The Associated Press that his 70 year-old father was killed in what appeared to be a bombing attack. Two of his brothers were also wounded by the explosion. Speaking to The Associated Press by telephone, he said he was not at the mosque at the time of the explosion but was heading to the morgue to identify his father's body.
ISIS allies in Libya post purported beheadings video
ISIS claimed responsibility for the mosque bombing in a statement, Reuters reported.
The official Kuwait News Agency reported that an explosion struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque, which is located in the neighbourhood of al-Sawabir, a residential and shopping district of Kuwait City. The agency confirmed that there were multiple casualties and injuries, but did provide any figures.
Paramedics at the mosque say at least two people were killed. Police formed a cordon around the mosque's complex immediately after the explosion, banning people from entering or gathering near the area. Ambulances could be seen ferrying the wounded from the site.
Abdullah al-Saffar, who was at the mosque, said the explosion took place just after midday Friday prayers.
The extremist group Islamic State in Iraq and Syria, which regards Shia Muslims as heretics, has claimed responsibility for bombings at two different Shia mosques in neighbouring Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
Friday midday prayers are typically the most crowded of the week, and attendance increases during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, which started last week.
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:09:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU leaders agree to settle 40,000 migrants after fractious debate</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/migrant-crisis-in-europe-leaders-agree-to-relocate-40-000-migrants-1.3128646?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>IN DEPTH | Migrants at unprecedented numbers in Calais
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended, describing the migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor."
That is a striking statement considering the euro zone debt crisis and confrontation with Russia during her decade in power.
Expressing his frustration, Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker described the plan as one of "modest ambition" and said at one point in the meeting he had told EU leaders "I don't give a damn" about objections to the plan's underlying methodology.
"We have to find out if the system works. It doesn't matter if it is voluntary or mandatory, it is whether it can help 60,000 refugees," Juncker told a news conference in the early hours of Friday.
However, the EU's chief executive had been hoping to set a precedent for Europe-wide action that limited national opt-outs.
British interlude
During the summit dinner, Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi rebuked his fellow leaders for their reluctance to support a plan that was meant as an emergency response to the tragedy of 2,000 migrant deaths in the Mediterranean year but has been overshadowed by divisions, particularly in eastern Europe.
"If we think Europe is only about budgets, it is not the Europe we thought of in 1957 in Rome," Renzi said, referring to the European Union's founding treaty.
The summit became so tense that a speech by British Prime Minister David Cameron served as an interlude to cool tempers, with the much awaited address to pitch for a new deal for Britain in the European Union reduced to barely tenminutes.
The mood was a long way from the unity showed by EU ministers in April immediately after the deaths of 900 migrants off the Libyan coast in a single weekend.
'Much more argument to come'
While the political deal was a breakthrough, implementing the plan still faces hurdles. The criteria to share migrants among member states must be decided by the end of July. Such factors as the size of a member state's economy and population must be considered.
"There's much, much more argument to come," said one senior EU diplomat. "I don't yet see the full way forward."
The criteria system replaces unpopular proposals for mandatory quotas on each country, which Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and others fought against, arguing their ex-Communist economies still lacked the capacity to cope.
The debate has also strained the EU's commitment to its Schengen agreement on passport-free travel.
This week, Austria threatened to reimpose controls on its border with Hungary and Britain called for more security around the French port of Calais. Britain and Spain want a bigger focus on returning migrants to countries of origin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:02:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate monuments graffitied in 6 states as protest movement grows</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/confederate-monuments-the-target-of-graffiti-in-6-states-1.3128648?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate monuments the target of graffiti in 6 states
Lawmakers in several states moving to remove Confederate symbols from capitol grounds
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 26, 2015 3:02 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 3:02 AM ET
A monument paying homage to Jefferson Davis on the campus of the University of Texas was among the first to be scrawled with "Black Lives Matter."  (Deborah Cannon/Austin American-Statesman/AP)
Related Stories
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
Vandals have targeted monuments dedicated to the leaders and soldiers of the Confederacy, painting the slogan "Black lives matter" on memorials in a half-dozen states where the landmarks stand tall in parks and outside government buildings.
The graffiti reflects the racial tension that permeates post-Ferguson America, more than a week after a white gunman shot and killed nine black congregants at a Charleston, South Carolina, church.
Michael Allen, a lecturer in American culture studies at Washington University in St. Louis, Mo., compared the vandalism to the toppling of statues in Russia at the end of the Soviet empire.
"If the monuments are strong statements of past values, defacing them is the easiest and loudest way to rebuke those statements," Allen said.
The historical significance of Charleston's 'Mother Emanuel' church
Confederate symbols including the rebel battle flag have been the subject of resentment for years. The anger boiled over after last week's massacre at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church. The suspect, Dylann Roof, posed in photos with the Confederate flag.
Politicians throughout the South are taking steps to remove the flag from public places. Black activists say the monuments should meet the same fate.
One of the defaced monuments was the Confederate Memorial in St. Louis' Forest Park, 16 kilometresfrom Ferguson. The same graffiti was reported on memorials in Charleston; Baltimore; Austin, Texas; Asheville, North Carolina; and Richmond, Virginia. No arrests have been made.
A rallying call
Racial wounds in the U.S. were torn open last August, when a white police officer in the St. Louis suburb of Ferguson, Missouri, fatally shot 18-year-old Michael Brown, who was black and unarmed. Officer Darren Wilson was cleared of any wrongdoing, but the shooting raised new awareness about the treatment of blacks.
"Black lives matter" became a rallying call in protests that followed police shootings of black men in other cities, too. With the Charleston shooting refocusing attention on Confederate symbolism, experts said, it isn't surprising that some people would take out their anger on monuments to those who fought on the side of slavery.
Alabama removed four Confederate battle flags from the state capitol grounds earlier this week. (Martin Swant/Associated Press)
Elizabeth Brondolo, a psychology professor at St. John's University in New York who studies the effects of race on mental and physical health, said the defacing of memorials reflects a "consensus that there's been a very serious failure of empathy, a failure to understand what these symbols might mean to people who suffered from slavery and ongoing aggression."
Defaced monuments at the University of Texas in Austin and in Richmond honour Confederate President Jefferson Davis. The Asheville monument pays homage to Zebulon Vance, a Confederate officer and later a governor and senator. Others, like the St. Louis memorial, are more generic tributes to those who fought for the South.
Monumental debate
The future of the 32-foot-tall, 101-year-old statue in St. Louis was already in doubt. In April, Mayor Francis Slay ordered a study of what to do with it and asked for the review to be complete by the end of the summer. Options include altering the wording of the plaque, moving the monument out of Forest Park or removing it entirely.
The University of Texas in Austin is weighing options for its statues of Davis and other Confederate war heroes, with a decision expected by Aug. 1. Three of those statutes were damaged this week.
In Kentucky, both candidates for governor, along with other prominent political leaders, are calling for the Jefferson Davis statue to be removed from its prominent place in the statehouse rotunda and placed in a museum.
Efforts have also begun to seek removal of Confederate monuments in Nashville, Tennessee; Shreveport, Louisiana; Orlando, Florida; Portsmouth, Virginia; and Birmingham, Alabama.
Darrell Maples, commander of the Missouri chapter of the Sons of Confederate Veterans, said the "citizen-soldiers who fought for the Confederacy personified the best qualities of America."
He said altering or removing monuments is "divisive and unnecessary."
Brandi Collins of the civil rights group ColorOfChange.org said the effort isn't about revising history.
"It's about saying that if we are truly about equity, about moving forward, we have to respect everybody who lives in and built this country," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:04:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Arrested New York jail guard denies knowing of escape plan </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/gene-palmer-arrested-jail-guard-denies-knowing-of-prisoner-escape-plan-1.3128281?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Gene Palmer, arrested jail guard, denies knowing of prisoner escape plan
Palmer is 2nd Clinton Correctional Facility employee to be charged since prison break
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 6:04 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 6:04 PM ET
New York State Police officers escort suspended Clinton Correctional Facility guard Gene Palmer from court in Plattsburgh, N.Y., on Wednesday.  (Keshia Clukey/Albany Times-Union via AP)
Related Stories
New York prison escape: Police look into possible sightings
A U.S. prison guard charged in connection with the escape of two killers admitted providing them with tools, paint, frozen hamburger meat and access to a catwalk electrical box, but claims he never knew they planned to bust out, authorities say.
As the search for the convicts entered its 20th day Thursday, Gene Palmer was released on $25,000 bail after his arrest on charges of promoting prison contraband, tampering with evidence and official misconduct. His arraignment was postponed until Monday.
Palmer is the second Clinton Correctional Facility employee to be charged since two convicted murderers, Richard Matt and David Sweat, cut their way out of the maximum-security prison in far northern New York, close to the Canadian border, on June 6. A prison tailor shop instructor Joyce Mitchell, 51, is charged with helping them break out.
But in contrast to the allegations against Mitchell, Palmer said he was an unwitting helper.
New York State Police have been searching for escaped killers David Sweat and Richard Matt since June 6. (New York State Police/Getty Images)
"I did not realize at the time that the assistance provided to Matt or Sweat made their escape easier," he told authorities in a signed statement.
District Attorney Andrew Wylie said that based on Palmer's statements and a polygraph test, investigators have no reason to believe he was knowingly involved in the escape.
In the statement, Palmer admitted providing Matt with paint and paintbrushes. On four occasions over eight months, he supplied Sweat with needle-nose pliers and a screwdriver. He said he gave Sweat access to the catwalk later used in the escape to change the wiring on electrical boxes as "a favour" to make it easier for them to cook in their cells. And a week before the escape, he delivered to Matt a pound of frozen ground beef in a package left by Mitchell.
Palmer told investigators that he agreed to help the pair in return for information about some illegal acts the other inmates were engaged in.
Wylie said Mitchell told investigators she smuggled hacksaw blades, a screwdriver and other tools into the prison by hiding them in the frozen meat.
She then put the meat in a refrigerator in the tailor shop, and Palmer took the meat to Sweat and Matt, who were housed in a section where inmates are allowed to cook their meals, according to the district attorney.
Palmer to plead not guilty
Wylie said Thursday that investigators have no proof Palmer knew hacksaw blades were embedded in the meat.
Palmer, who has been suspended, will plead not guilty, according to his lawyer.
Authorities say the inmates cut through the steel wall at the back of their cells, crawled down a catwalk, broke through a brick wall, cut their way into and out of a steam pipe and then emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
Sweat, 35, was serving a life sentence without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy. Matt, who turned 49 on Thursday, was doing 25 years to life in the kidnapping, torture and hacksaw dismemberment of his former boss.
Palmer had worked at the prison in Dannemora for more than 27 years and had known Sweat and Matt for at least five years.
In a 2000 interview with a local radio station, Palmer portrayed his job as highly stressful.
"With the money that they pay you," he said, "you'll go bald, you'll have high blood pressure, you'll become an alcoholic, you'll divorce, and then you'll kill yourself."
About 1,100 law enforcement on Thursday continued their search for the escaped convicts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:08:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iranian foreign minister to join nuclear talks on Friday</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iranian-foreign-minister-to-join-nuclear-talks-on-friday-1.3128514?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
Iranian foreign minister to join nuclear talks on Friday
CBC's Nahlah Ayed talks to Masoumeh Ebtekar, a vice-president in Iran, about nuclear talks and ties to Canada
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 10:08 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 3:02 AM ET
U.S. and Iran: Then and now 3:24
Related Stories
Justin Trudeau: I'll end ISIS combat mission, restore relations with Iran
With significant gaps standing in the way of an Iran nuclear deal, foreign ministers at the seven-nation talks are adding their diplomatic muscle to the negotiations before a June 30 target date for an agreement.
France announced Thursday that Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius is joining the talks in Vienna on Saturday. Iranian media reported earlier that Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif will fly to Vienna on Friday. That's the day U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry departs Washington for the Austrian capital
Trudeau says Liberals would stop bombing ISIS, restore relations with Iran
Foreign ministers from the four other nations at the negotiating table  Russia, China, Britain and Germany  are also expected to join in as they try to bridge differences between the sides on the limits Tehran must accept on its nuclear program in exchange for the lifting of economic sanctions.
But with Iran apparently backtracking on key points of the emerging deal, the talks could go past the target date. In a speech on Tuesday, Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei rejected a long-term freeze on nuclear research and insisted that Iran will only sign a deal if international sanctions are lifted first.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif will join talks on a nuclear deal in Vienna on Friday. (Ivan Sekretarev/Associated Press)
He also repeated that military sites and Iranian nuclear scientists will be off limits to UNexperts, who would monitor Iranian compliance to any deal while trying to kick-start a moribund probe of suspicions that Tehran worked on atomic arms  allegations Iran denies.
Kerry said Khamenei's speech was for "domestic political consumption" and that there would not be a deal if Iran reneged on commitments made in an April outline.
'It could be a game changer'
Masoumeh Ebtekar, a vice-president in Iran, told CBC's Nahlah Ayed, that she doesn't think thespeech "was a hardening of his positions by any means."
"I think that he was very frank, he made it clear that there are concessions that Iran might need to make."
Ebtekar, who in 1979 wasan English-speaking spokeswoman forstudents who overtook and held hostages atthe U.S. Embassy in Tehran, later became Iran's first female vice-president.
"The history is thereit's not something that could be forgottenbut we look forward to this settlement as a turning point. I think that it could be a game changer," she told Ayed.
Though the official deadline is coming up, a delay up to July 9 is not a deal-breaker. If Congress receives an agreement by then, it has 30 days to review it before President Barack Obama could suspend congressional sanctions.
But postponement beyond that would double the congressional review period to 60 days, giving both Iranian and U.S. opponents more time to work on undermining an agreement.
U.S. House of Representatives Speaker John Boehner, a Republican critic of the deal, said even "a little more time" was too much of a concession to the Iranians.
"Giving Iran more flexibility will not lead to a good deal, it will only lead to more concessions for a regime that has no intention of giving up its desire for a nuclear weapon," he said. "We're about to get stuck with a bad deal with a bad regime."
With files from CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:37:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek bailout talks stall again as new deadline looms</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greece-still-deadlocked-with-creditors-as-tuesday-deadline-looms-1.3127431?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greece still deadlocked with creditors as Tuesday deadline looms
Pension reform and new sales taxes sticking points in talks as EU leaders gather in Brussels
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 11:37 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 3:48 PM ET
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, left, and Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi speak with German Chancellor Angela Merkel during a round table meeting at an EU summit in Brussels on Thursday.  (Geert Vanden Wijngaert/ Associated Press)
Related Stories
Greek crisis needs more than a Band-Aid solution: Don Pittis
Eurozone finance ministers ended their meeting Thursday without asolution to the Greece debt crisis after yesterday's talks between Athens and its creditors alsoended in deadlock.
Greece and its creditors  the International Monetary Fund, European Central Bank and the European Commission  had presented competing proposals to the finance ministers.
Greek crisis needs more than a Band-Aid solution: Don Pittis
They are still at an impasse at issues such as pension reform, including what year to move the retirement age to 67 and whether to continue to provide top-up funding to Greece's poorest pensioners.
Another sticking point has been the overhaul of the value-added tax system, with the EU wanting processed foods and restaurants taxed at a higher rate and insisting on removal of an exemption for the Greek islands.
The head of the IMF, Christine Lagarde, says Greece's creditors need more time to examine new offers Athens has made.
"We were given a proposal by the Greek parties at the last hour. We need to doso some more work to examine their proposals, to see how it can be reconciled," she said.
EU leaders meet
Greece's economy ministerGiorgos Stathakissaid concessions had been made on both sides.
As Europe's leaders arrived for asummit in Brussels, Germany's Angela Merkel warned talks were going nowhere.
Officials have "not yet made the necessary progress" in the talks to get Greece more financial aid, she told reporters and "in some places we even have the impression that we are falling back a bit."
Meanwhile, French President Francois Hollande is exhorting Greece and its international creditors to speed up talks on new loans for the country, as a default would affect the entire continent.
Greece faces default if it fails to make a 1.6 billion euro ($2.2 billion Cdn) IMF debt repayment by Tuesday.
And if it fails to make the payment, it may opt to withdraw from the euro, which could roil markets and affect the entire eurozone.
On the other hand, deep concessions by Greece could leave Tsipras in trouble, as he could face parliamentary defeat over heightened austerity. His Syriza party was elected in January on an anti-austerity platform geared at reviving the Greek economy.
Banks in trouble
Greek banks may lose their lifeline from the ECB and be forced to limit withdrawals as soon as Monday.
Worried Greeks have been withdrawing their money from their country's banks, fearing the imposition of restrictions on banking transactions. An estimated more than 4 billion euros ($4.5 billion) left Greek banks last week.
A Greek banking official says the European Central Bank has approved a request from Athens to increase the amount of emergency liquidity Greek lenders can tap from the country's central bank.
The ECB approved the request Thursday, as it has done every day since Friday as Greece headed into the final stretch of tough bailout negotiations with no clear solution in sight.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:26:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obamacare 'here to stay,'  president says in wake of U.S. Supreme Court decision</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-s-supreme-court-upholds-obamacare-tax-subsidies-1.3127306?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. Supreme Court upholds Obamacare tax subsidies
6-3 decision means Americans who get health insurance via federal exchanges can still get subsidies
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 10:26 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 8:09 PM ET
Obama reacts to health-care ruling 6:10
Related Stories
SCOTUS Blog
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
Ina major win for President Barack Obama, the U.S. Supreme Court has upheld a lower-court decision that allows the federal government to issue health care subsidies to states.
The 6-3 decisionmeans that Americans whoget their health insurance throughexchanges set up by the federal government will continue to be eligible for tax subsidies.
Obamacarecosting less than forecast
The plaintiffs in the case had argued that these subsidies were illegal becauseObama'sAffordable CareAct, widely known as Obamacare, stipulates that to be eligible for federal tax credits, insurance had to have beenpurchased through an exchange set upbya state, notthefederal government.
But the court sided with theObama administration'sinterpretation and found the language in the law sufficiently broad to apply to both state and federal exchanges.
The rulingis more confirmation that the law "is working exactly as it's supposed to," Obama said in reaction to the decision.
The HealthCare.gov serves as an insurance exchange where individuals whose states have not set up their own exchange can compare plans from competing providers. (Don Ryan/Associated Press)
"After more than 50 votes in Congress to repeal or weaken this law, after a presidential election based in part on preserving or repealing this law, after multiple challenges to this law before the Supreme Court, the Affordable Care Act is here to stay,"the president saidat a newsconference in the Rose Garden at the White House.
"This is not an abstract thinganymore. This is not a set of political talking points. This is reality," he said after listing off examples of how the law has made health care more accessible and affordable for millions of Americans.
"Thislaw is working, and it's going to keep doing just that," Obama said.
2nd high court ruling in favour of Obamacare
Thursday's decision marks the second time in three years that the high court has ruled against a major challenge to the law brought by conservatives seeking to gut it.
"We should start calling this law SCOTUScare," Justice Antonin Scalia wrote in his dissenting opinion, referring to the common abbreviation for the Supreme Court of the United States.
'This was a good day for America.'- U.S. President Barack Obama
The decision means the subsidies will remain not just in the 13 states that have set up their own exchanges and the three states that have state-federal hybrid exchanges, but also in the 34 states that use HealthCare.gov,the exchange run by the federal government.
"This was a good day for America," Obama said of the ruling, telling themedia that had the challenge been successful,millions of Americans would have lost thousands of dollars in tax subsidies and many would have become uninsured.
"America would have gone backwards, and that's not what we do," he said.
Federal insuranceexchange legitimate
The case centred on the tax creditsoffered under the law, passed by Obama's fellow Democrats in Congress in 2010 over unified Republican opposition, that help low- and moderate-income people buy private health insurance. The exchanges are online marketplaces that allow consumers to shop among competing insurance plans.
Since the federal government can't compel states to set up exchanges, in some cases where states failed to do so or had trouble running their own exchanges, it stepped in and created themon their behalf through HealthCare.gov and provided subsidies to low- and middle-income individualsnationwide, regardless of whether they enrolled in theirinsurance plan through a state-run or federally run exchange.
The point of the subsidies is to keep enough people in the pool of insured to avoid triggering aso-called deathspiral of declining enrolment, a growing proportion of less healthy people and premium increases by insurers.
The court itselfwrote in its decision that "the tax credits are among the act's key reforms, involving billions of dollars in spending each year and affecting the price of health insurance for millions of people."
In 2014, roughly87 per cent of people who bought insurance on a federal exchange did so withtax credits, the court noted.
Chief Justice John Roberts wrote the majority opinion in the U.S. Supreme Court's 6-3 decision backing Obama's Affordable Care Act. (Nati Harnik/Associated Press)
The question before the justices was whether a four-word phrase in the expansive law saying subsidies are available to those buying insurance on exchanges "established by the state" had been correctly interpreted by the administration to allow subsidies to be available nationwide.
While the plaintiffs argued for a strict interpretation of this part of the law,several states toldthe court that they had no inkling they had to set up their own exchange in order for their residents to get tax credits, and the court found that the structure of thelaw andseveral provisions within itassume that tax credits will be available on both state and federal exchanges.
Chief Justice John Robertswrote that although the conservative challengers' arguments about the plain meaning of the statute referring to exchanges being "established by the state"were "strong," the "context and structure of the act compel us to depart from what would otherwise be the most natural reading of the pertinent statutory phrase."
Adhering to the plaintiffs' narrow reading ofthe statute"would destabilize the individual insurance market in any state with a federal exchange, and likely create the very 'death spirals'that Congress designed the Act to avoid," he wrote in themajorityopinion.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care Act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," he wrote.
With files from Reuters and The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 12:30:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS launches twin attacks in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/isis-storms-northeast-syrian-city-of-hassakeh-attacks-kobani-1.3127007?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS storms northeast Syrian city of Hassakeh, attacks Kobani
Attacks come after ISIS suffered setbacks against Kurdish forces
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 25, 2015 5:30 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 12:19 PM ET
An explosion is captured on a closed-circuit video cam camera second after a car bomb detonated on Thursday in the Kurdish town of Kobani, Syria. ISIS militants staged a new attack on the town, which famously resisted a months-long assault by the Islamic militants. (Associated Press)
Related Stories
ISIS blows up ancient tombs in Palmyra,  2,000-year-old heritage site in Syria
Islamic State in Iraq and Syria (ISIS) militants launched major attacks in northern Syria on Thursday in a swift counter-offensive after recent battlefield setbacks, storming government-held areas in one mostly Kurdish city and setting off deadly car bombs as they pushed back into a border town they were expelled from earlier this year.
The ISIS offensive was two-pronged and left dozens of people dead or wounded. On one front, ISISfighters advanced early in the morning into the northeastern city of Hassakeh, long split between Syrian Kurds and government forces, capturing parts of it.
The other push was into the Syrian border town of Kobani, which famously resisted a months-long assault by the Islamic militants before they were driven out in January, and surrounding villages. An activist group said 12 people died in fighting Thursday in Kobani  the first time in six months the ISIS had managed to enter the town along the Syria-Turkey border  and that the militants had detonated three car bombs.
People mourn the death of a woman, who died from her wounds after she was injured during what activists said was an attack by ISIS fighters in Kobani, Syria on Thursday. (Rodi Said/Reuters)
In the Kobani attack, which was launched from the town's southern and western parts, the ISIS extremists donned Syrian rebel uniforms and carried flags of the mainstream Free Syrian Army to deceive the town's Kurdish defenders, said Redur Khalil, a spokesman for the Kurdish People's Protection Units, or YPG.
Speaking about Hassakeh, Khalil said ISIS militants attacked government-held neighbourhoods on the southern edge of the city, and captured some areas.
Syrian state TV reported intense clashes inside Hassakeh's southern neighbourhood of Nashawi. According to the report, ISIS fighters killed several people they captured in the city, including the head of a military housing institution. It said the militants sustained many casualties, including the commander of the group who is a foreign fighter. An activist group said many people in neighbourhoods engulfed in the fighting fled to safer areas in the city.
ISIS blows up ancient tombs in Palmyra, 2,000-year-old heritage site in Syria
ISIS tried to storm the city earlier this month and reached its southern outskirts before facing strong resistance from Syrian government troops who pushed them away.
The Hassakeh and Kobani attacks came just days after YPG fighters and their allies captured the Islamic State stronghold of Tal Abyad on the border with Turkey and the town of Ein Issa to the south. Kurdish fighters have been advancing since January under the cover of airstrikes by the U.S.-led coalition.
But in neighbouring Iraq, government forces and allied Shiamilitiamen have been slow in retaking IS-held territory. The Iraqis have also suffered occasional losses.
Iraqi troops drove ISIS militants from Saddam Hussein's hometown of Tikrit in April, but lost Ramadi, the capital of Anbar province west of Baghdad, last month.
In June last year, ISIS launched a blitz, capturing large parts of both Syria and Iraq and subsequently declared an Islamic caliphate on the territory it controls. A major IS attack was widely expected during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, which began last week.
In an audio message Tuesday, ISIS spokesman, Abu Muhammad al-Adnani, urged Sunni Muslims to use the time of piety and dawn-to-dusk fasting during Ramadan to wage jihad and seek martyrdom.
"Attack them everywhere and shake the ground beneath them," he said. It was not possible to verify the recording, but it resembled previous audio statements from the group.
Al-Adnani referred to the recent battlefield setbacks for ISIS, saying the faithful "may lose a battle or battles and may lose towns and areas, but will never be defeated."
A Syrian Kurdish sniper looks at the rubble in the Syrian city of Ain al-Arab, also known as Kobani, in this January 2015 photo. Turkish officials said Thursday, that ISIS has staged a new attack on the Kurdish town. (Associated Press)
In the Kobani attack, the Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, which tracks Syria's war, said three vehicles were detonated in the town. Ghalia Nehme, a commander with the Kurdish Women's Protection Units, told The Associated Press by telephone from inside the town that "a group of fighters deployed in some areas of Kobani."
"We are defending a position now," she added.
Another Kurdish official in Kobani, Idriss Naasan, said the fighting was intense in the morning but became more sporadic by midday. He said the extremists appear to have infiltrated from the villages south of Kobani.
"We hear cracks of gunfire every now and then," Naasan said from inside Kobani around noon. He added that some explosions could still be heard but that it was unclear what those were.
The Observatory said 12 civilians and Kurdish fighters were killed in Kobani on Thursday, and also eight IS extremists.
In Barkh Botan, not far from Kobani, ISIS fighters entered the village also on Thursday morning, opening fire on civilians and killing 20 residents, the Observatory said. Syria's state news agency SANA said 22 people were killed in the shooting, including women and children.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:20:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Univision drops Miss USA pageant over Donald Trump's 'insulting remarks' about Latino immigrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/univision-drops-miss-usa-pageant-over-donald-trump-s-insulting-remarks-about-latino-immigrants-1.3127510?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Univision drops Miss USA pageant over Donald Trump's 'insulting remarks' about Latino immigrants
Trump accused Mexicans of bringing drugs, crime and rapists to the U.S. during campaign speech
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 12:20 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 12:20 PM ET
FILE - In this June 16, 2013 file photo, Donald Trump, left, and Miss Connecticut USA Erin Brady pose onstage after Brady won the 2013 Miss USA pageant in Las Vegas, Nev. Univision says it is dropping the Miss USA Pageant and says it will cut all business ties with Donald Trump over comments he made about Mexican immigrants. The network said Thursday, June 25, 2015, it will not air the pageant on July 12, as previously scheduled, and has ended its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organization due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner.  (Jeff Bottari/AP File)
Related Stories
Donald Trump's run at the presidency: More than a stunt?
Univision is dropping the Miss USA pageant and says it will cut all business ties with Donald Trump over comments he made about Mexican immigrants.
The network said Thursday it will not air the July pageant and has ended its business relationship with the Miss Universe Organization, which produces the Miss USA pageant, due to what it called "insulting remarks about Mexican immigrants" by Trump, a part owner of Miss Universe.
Donald Trump's run at the presidency: More than a stunt?
During his presidential campaign kickoff speech last week, Trump accused Latino immigrants of bringing drugs, crime and rapists to the U.S. He called for building a wall along the southern border of the U.S.
Trump says he was only criticizing U.S. policies concerning Mexico, not its people. He says Univision is in default of a five-year contract.
Miss USA presenter pulled out
Univision's decision is the latest in the fallout over Trump's remarks: On Thursday, Puerto Rican actress and Miss USA presenter Roselyn Sanchez severed her ties with the pageant. And on Wednesday, Colombian singer J Balvin cancelled a planned performance.
A spokesman for Balvin said in a written statement that the singer's management told the Miss Universe organization to withdraw his name from an announcement about participants in the Miss USA broadcast.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 20:40:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I'm safer in Baghdad': Courtney Love says she was ambushed in Paris taxi protest</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/courtney-love-held-hostage-in-paris-taxi-protest-singer-says-1.3127565?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Courtney Love 'held hostage' in Paris taxi protest, singer says
'They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage,' tweeted the singer Thursday
CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 1:40 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 25, 2015 1:40 PM ET
Courtney Love credits two men on a motorcycle for rescuing her from a violent taxi strike aimed at Uber in Paris on Thursday. The former Hole frontwoman says she was scared out of her wits when protesters ambushed her car and held her driver hostage.   (Ben Gabbe/Getty Images)
Related Stories
Two charged after Uber driver beaten, hospitalized
Courtney Love says she was scared out of her wits Thursday when thecar she was riding in was "destroyed" by protesting taxi drivers in Paris.
The 50-year-old former Hole frontwomanand widow of Nirvana's Kurt Cobain, says she wasambushed and "held hostage forabout an hour" whenpicketers, rallyingagainstthe mobile car-hailing serviceUber,attacked her car.
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 @Courtney
Love was among many travellers who got caught up in the protest in the French capital that sawtaxi drivers smashlivery cars, set tires ablaze and block traffic across the country.
An overturned car is pictured as French taxi drivers, who are on strike, demonstrate at Porte Maillot to block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against Uber. (Charles Platiau/Reuters)
The action was part ofa nationwide strike bydrivers who sayUber's lowest cost service is taking their livelihood away.
Love, who didn't specify what kind of car she was in, posted a barrage of messages on social media during the ordeal, calling the incident the "scariest day" of her life.
paid some guys on motorcycles to sneak us out, got chased by a mob of taxi drivers who threw rocks, passed two police and they did nothing
 @Courtney
The celebrity appeared to blameFranois Hollande, calling the French president a "libertine."
"I can't believe this really just happened, she wrote onInstagram . "[I]love French people but your government blows."
Rescued from the riot
The singer later posted a snapshotwearing a motorcycle helmet with two smiling men who appeared to haverescued her from the melee.
Courtney Love posted this picture of her apparent rescuers on her Instagram Thursday after she says she was 'held hostage' for an hour. (courtneylove/Instagram)
Riot police chased strikers from Paris' ring road, where protesters torched tires in the middle of the roadway and swarmed onto exit ramps at rush hour.
France's top security official said he had ordered an immediate ban on unlicensed services like UberPop in the Paris region but called for an end to violence against the service's drivers.
"We are calling for calm. We are in a state of law," Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said. "A state of law is not a state of violence."
Uber's more expensive livery service is still legal but a source of intense frustration for French taxi drivers, who pay tens of thousands of euros (dollars) for the equivalent of medallions and who face customer complaints that they are being resistant to changes such as credit cards and geolocation.
Two charged after Uber driver beaten, hospitalized
The French government, meanwhile, said nearly 500 legal cases have been filed across the country involving complaints about UberPop, the lowest cost service. Several drivers have had their cars impounded. The officials reiterated concerns about safety of passengers, insisting they are not protected in case of an accident by an UberPop driver.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From dodging shoes to throwing barbs: Politicians who got into it with hecklers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-s-president-barack-obama-just-the-latest-politician-to-go-head-to-head-with-heckler-1.3127437?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Video
U.S. President Barack Obama just the latest politician to go head-to-head with heckler
Obama part of a long line of politicians who engaged with hecklers who tried to throw them off course
ByJoe Pack, CBC News Posted: Jun 25, 2015 5:00 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 8:36 AM ET
U.S. President Barack Obama and Vice-President Joe Biden react after a heckler was removed from a reception at the White House marking LGBT Pride Month. Obama is not the first politician to make headlines after going head-to-head with a heckler. (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Related Stories
Same-sex marriage ruling by U.S. Supreme Court within days
U.S. President Barack Obama verbally jousted with a heckler on Wednesday at a White House reception in honour of LGBTPride Monthand was widely praised for handling the incident withgrace and good humour, telling the heckler, "Hey, listen, you're in my house."
The heckler had interrupted Obama's remarks by protesting the detention and deportation of gay, lesbian and transgender immigrants.
"My attitude is, if you're eating the hors d'ouevres" he joked, alluding totheprivilege of attending a White House event.
Video:U.S. President Barack Obama scolds heckler at White House event
At a 2014Democratic National Committee convention in San Jose,Calif., Obama talked down another heckler calling for "freedom for Ethiopia" and yelling out "We love you."
"I love you back," Obama told the audience member. "You kind of screwed up my ending, but that's OK."
Handling surprise interruptions can improve or stain a politician's reputationdepending on whether their response comes acrossasgracefulor in bad taste.
Here are some other examples of how politicians have handled hecklers.
Jean Chrtien
Canada's former prime ministerJean Chrtienbarely deflecteda question asked by media personalityNardwuar the Human Servietteabout protesters and pepper spray at a 1997 meeting ofAPEC(Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) members in Vancouver.
"For me, pepper I put it on my plate," Chrtien famously said.
George W. Bush
Former U.S. President George W. Bush once deftly ducked two shoes thrown at him by a man at a press conference in Baghdad. His observation about attention-seeking protesters was refreshingly apt.
"I don't know what the guy's cause is, but one thing is for certain: he caused (the press)to ask me a question about it."
Hillary Clinton
Hillary Clinton, former U.S. Secretary of State and current Democratic presidential candidate,similarly had a shoe thrown at her at a 2014 speech in Las Vegas, leaving her visiblyperplexed.
"Was that a bat?," she asked at the time. "Was that somebody throwing something at me? Was that part of Cirque duSoleil?"
Rob Ford
Toronto's former mayor Rob Ford met with more than a fewdissenters during his four-year tenure. Onenotableencounter onCanada Day in2014 involved ashirtless jogger who showed up on the scene as Fordand his brother, Doug, were meeting with residents in East York.
Many will also remember how Ford nearly knocked Toronto councilwoman Pam McConnell to the floor in November2013as he ran after aheckler in city hall.
Rob Ford knocks over councillor2:28
Ronald Reagan
U.S. presidents have been comingup with memorable quips since before the age of social media and particularly since the advent of televised debates. At the 1984 presidential debate,Ronald Reagandeftly turned a question about his age fromBaltimore Sun reporter Henry Trewhittinto a jab about his opponent, Walter Mondale.
At a White House press conference in 1982, Reagan was equally quick in turning a serious question about his part in the recession into a slam against the Democrats.
Chris Christie
Not all politicians are savvy enough to defend themselves in public with tact. At a 2012town hall meeting in Roebling, N.J., Gov. Chris Christie lost his cool with a law school student who interrupted him, berating the former Navy Seal and calling him an "idiot."
Winston Churchill
Winston Churchill, whose silhouette is represented in a statue outside the Houses of Parliament in London, was known for his all-around verbal dexterity and had one particularly memorable exchange with member of parliament Nancy Astor. (Luke MacGregor/Reuters)
The formidable Winston Churchill, the former British prime ministerknown for his rousing speeches and radio broadcasts,doesn't need video evidence of his verbal prowess. He is alleged to have had this heated exchange with Nancy Astor, the first woman in the British Parliament, who once confronted him abouthis drunkennessand poor manners.
Astor: "Winston, if you were my husband, I'd put poison in your tea."
Churchill: "Nancy, if you were my wife, I'd drink it."
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank will maintain emergency credit to Greek banks</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-banks-granted-cash-flow-reprieve-amid-emergency-debt-talks-1.3131048?cmp=rss</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks continue past Tuesday deadline
'More concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock,' U.S. spokeswoman says
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 07, 2015 8:50 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 9:25 AM ET
The deal under discussion between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy. (Carlos Barria/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Iran says nuclear deal could lead to co-operation in fight against extremism
Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a UNarms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," EU foreign policy chiefFedericaMogherinisaid outside the hotel where the talks between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States are taking place.
How an Iranian nuclear deal could reshape the Middle East
The spokeswoman for the U.S. delegation, MarieHarf, said the terms of an interim deal between Iran and the six would be extended through Friday to give negotiators a few more days to finish their work.
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time,"Harfsaid. "That is why we are continuing to negotiate."
Iranians await what could be "transformative" news from nuclear talks
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said there was "every reason" to believe a deal would be done within "a few days,"and that there was an "understanding" that most of the current sanctions against Iran would be lifted.
"There is only one big problem in terms of sanctions  it is the problem of a weapons embargo," he told journalists, according to the news agency Interfax.
He said it was important to reach agreement on this as soon as possible, telling journalists that "ending the bans on supplies to Iran of the weapons required to fight terrorism is a very, very relevant objective."
It is the fourth time the parties have extended the terms of the interim deal, which was struck in November 2013 and provided Iran with limited sanctions relief in exchange for a halt to the production of uranium enriched to a purity level of 20 percent.
2nd deadline passed
The comprehensive deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from economic sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalize the agreement," Mogherini said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve.
Among these, officials said, are Iranian demands for a UNarms embargo and ballistic missiles sanctions to be lifted, the timing of U.S. and EU sanctions relief, and disagreements over future Iranian nuclear research and development.
"We have entered the most difficult, but also the most real, part of the negotiations," Mogherini added.
"We knew it would be difficult, challenging and sometimes hard and some things get tense and others we make progress."
She said foreign ministers now in Vienna might come and go.
"Don't get too excited if you see ministers leaving. They might come back. They will come back. And it doesn't mean that we are stopping the work we are doing inside. On the contrary, on the contrary."
Easing decades of hostility
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius confirmed that he would leave, and return to Vienna on Wednesday night.
The United States and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear programme as a cover to develop a nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its programme is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the United States and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal would also reduce the chances of a U.S. military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington refuses to rule out, and of a wider regional war.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in eurozone as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-pm-alexis-tsipras-heads-to-brussels-meeting-with-financial-future-at-stake-1.3140890?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greek PM Alexis Tsipras heads to Brussels meeting with financial future at stake
18 eurozone leaders taking hardline approach to new proposals from Greece
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 07, 2015 3:39 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 7:05 AM ET
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras will bring new proposals for his country's future to a eurozone meeting Tuesday.  (Petros Karadjias/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Greece crisis: The sticking points that scuppered bailout talks
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is expected to present new proposals to an emergency eurozone summit on Tuesday, under pressure from European leaders to come up with credible ideas as his country's banks face potential meltdown.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must persuade the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to open negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
How Greece moves forward after the No vote
But Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labour reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the eurozone."
Greeks face further economic hardship, as banks will remain closed until later this week and limits on cash withdrawals remain in place. (Christopher Furlong/Getty Images)
He did not name names but may have been referring to German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his skepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the eurozone's economic output and population.
Concessions unclear
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the eurozone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 per cent No vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
"They [creditors] wanted a 'Yes' to prevail so they could humiliate the Greek prime minister, to go weakened, under these conditions of funding asphyxiation, and be a pushover. That didn't happen," Labour Minister Panos Skourletis told Antenna TV.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
But he gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply sceptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
His proposals were not expected to go much beyond a letter he sent to eurozone partners last week, acccepting most of the terms of a creditors' offer that was no longer on the table, but still seeking some loopholes for social or coalition reasons.
Confrontational approach criticized
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the eurozone.
Juncker told EU lawmakers in Strasbourg he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened but he chided the Greeks for their confrontational approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," said the EU's chief executive, who was heckled by leftists and Eurosceptics when he said Greeks hadn't been properly informed about what they were voting on.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Euclid Tsakalotos, seen Monday, is the new Greece finance minister, taking over from the oft-criticized Yanis Varoufakis. (Petr David Josek/The Associated Press)
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the centre-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras' games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
Greek newspapers said the proposals would be based on ideas that Juncker put forward at the end of June with a few tweaks and would not differ much from the last plans presented by Athens itself last week.
ANALYSIS I In rejecting austerity, Greek voters force Germany's hand
Euro zone national officials were irritated that Juncker had gone beyond the agreed negotiating mandate of the three creditor institutions in his last-ditch diplomacy, and it is not clear that they will be more receptive to his ideas now.
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favour a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they have to present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek newspapers reported the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 per cent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and protect defence spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines".
Follow the CBC News live blog for breaking news on the future of Greece:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:40:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'We will never be cowed': U.K. commemorates 10th anniversary of London bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/7-7-bombings-britain-honours-victims-on-10th-annivesary-of-transit-attacks-1.3140897?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>David Cameron and Barack Obama agree to right 'poisonous ideology' at home
Prime Minister David Cameron led sombre tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.
Relatives of the victims, survivors, and senior politicians gathered to remember those killed in the July 7, 2005 bombings with emotions still raw after a massacre in Tunisia last month, Britain's worst loss of life in a militant assault since London.
"Today the country comes together to remember the victims of one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain," Cameron said in a statement.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly - the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
George Psaradakis, second from the left, driver of the double decker bus that was targeted by bomber Hasib Hussain in 2005, bows his head during a remembrance ceremony on Tuesday. (Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images)
In the early hours of July 7 a decade ago, four young British Muslims travelled down to London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus during the morning rush-hour.
Inspired by al-Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others. Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
Cameron and London mayor Boris Johnson stood silently, heads bowed, before laying a wreath at the 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park. They will later join other senior figures, victims' families, survivors and members of the emergency services caught up in the bombings for a service of remembrance at St Paul's Cathedral.
This will include a national minute of silence, which comes just four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
Prince William to attend ceremony
A further service will be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives which Prince William, Queen Elizabeth's grandson, will attend.
Esther Hyman, 46, whose sister Miriam was killed on the Number 30 bus when it was blown up at Tavistock Square, told Reuters many young people seemed unaware of the bombings.
"The events of 7/7 do seem to have slipped out of public consciousness," said Hyman, who with her mother last week launched an educational programme to help teach school pupils about the attacks and to steer them away from violent extremism.
"It's worth remembering an event like 7/7 and learning lessons from it so that it didn't happen in vain."
A memorial plaque is attached to railings in Tavistock Square, in memory of those who lost their lives on a number 30 double-decker bus during the 7/7 attack. (Peter Nicholls/Reuters)
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe", meaning a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) fighters and Britons who have joined them.
Andrew Parker, head of Britain's domestic spy agency MI5, said only a "tiny fraction of the population" posed a threat.
"But the continuing fact that some people, born in the UK, with all the opportunities and freedoms that modern Britain offers, can nonetheless make those sorts of warped choices presents a serious societal and security challenge," Parker said in a rare public statement.
The government plans new measures to counter extremism and Mark Rowley, Britain's most senior counter-terrorism police officer, said the country was better prepared than 10 years ago, although the threat itself had morphed.
He said ISIS was creating an "enormous" list of potential targets, focused on propaganda value.
Members of the public and grounds staff and Wimbledon tennis fans observe a minute of silence to mark the 10th anniversary of the London bombings, at All England Lawn Tennis Club. (Sean Dempsey/EPA)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:33:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabaab claims responsibility for north Kenya attack that kills 14</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/kenya-attack-claimed-by-al-shabaab-leaves-at-least-14-dead-1.3140968?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Al-Shabaab attack leaves at least 147 dead at Kenyan university as siege ends
At least 14 people were killed in an attack early Tuesday in the country's north by al-Shabaab, Islamic extremist rebels from neighbouring Somalia, a Kenyan official said.
Eleven people were also wounded in the attack which took place in Soko Mbuzi village in Mandera County near Kenya's border with Somalia, said Mandera County Commissioner Alex Nkoyo.
The Somali-based militants, who are allied to al-Qaeda, have killed at least 85 people, all of them non-Muslims, in Mandera County in the last eight months.
Al-Shabab has vowed to carry out attacks in Kenya as retribution for the country sending troops to Somalia to fight the militants. Kenya sent its troops to Somalia in October 2011 following a series of cross-border attacks including kidnappings which the government blamed on al-Shabaab.
The Somali government, supported by the U.N. and backed by troops from African Union countries including Kenya, has pushed al-Shabaab out of Somalia's major cities but the rebels still control some rural areas and carry out bombings and attacks on the capital, Mogadishu, and attacks on Kenyan targets.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:45:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World's oldest man dies in Japan at 112</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/sakari-momoi-world-s-oldest-man-dead-at-112-1.3140855?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Sakari Momoi, world's oldest man, dead at 112
Momoi born in Fukushima in 1903
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 06, 2015 11:45 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 2:16 AM ET
Momoi, formerly Japan's oldest man, became the world's oldest at age 111 after Alexander Imich, also 111, died in New York on June 8, 2014. (Kyodo/Reuters)
Related Stories
Bowhead whales' genome may offer clues to aging gracefully
Sakari Momoi, who was recognised as the world's oldest man and credited healthy eating and getting plenty of sleep for his longevity, has died at the age of 112, Japanese media said on Tuesday.
Momoi was born in an area of Fukushima hit hard by the tsunami and nuclear meltdowns of four years ago in February 1903 the year the teddy bear was introduced and Orville Wright carried out the first powered, heavier-than-air flight.
Bowhead whalegenome may offer clues to aging gracefully
Named the world's oldest man in August 2014, Momoi, a former teacher who spent his days practicing calligraphy and taking part in recreational activities at the hospital where he lived, donned a suit and tie for a ceremony to receive a plaque from Guinness World Records.
"I want to live two more years," he said at the time.
The world's oldest man is now likely to be Japanese Yasutaro Koide, born in March 1903, a little over a month younger than Momoi. U.S. resident Susannah Mushatt Jones, 116, is the world's oldest person.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:08:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ice cave collapse kills 1, injures 3 in Washington state</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/big-four-ice-caves-collapse-kills-1-injures-3-in-washington-1.3140882?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Big Four Ice Caves collapse kills 1, injures 3 in Washington
Officials warned in May that caves were unsafe due to warm spring temperatures
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 07, 2015 2:08 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 2:08 AM ET
In this July 2010 photo, visitors examine the Big Four Ice Caves in the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest near Granite Falls, Wash. (Mark Mulligan/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Midland Ice Caves drawing hundreds to natural phenomenon
One person died and three were injured on Monday in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state that U.S. Forest Service officials had warned was too dangerous for exploration due to unseasonably warm weather.
A spokeswoman from the Snohomish County Sheriff's Office said the three injured people were airlifted from the Big Four Ice Caves near Granite Falls, 40 miles north of Seattle, to nearby hospitals with serious injuries.
PHOTOS| A rare look inside Apostle Islands ice caves
The person who died has not been identified. The Seattle Times reported the individual's body remained buried under debris.
Rescue teams were still determining how many hikers were in the cave when it gave way. The collapse occurred near the entrance, officials said.
The caves are home to a popular hiking trail and are part of the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest.
In May, the U.S. Forest Service warned hikers against entering the Big Four Ice Caves after several sections collapsed in unusually warm spring temperatures.
"The cave is in a condition that we would normally not see until at least September - large, inviting and collapsing," Lead Field Ranger Matthew Riggen said.
The area around the caves will be closed indefinitely, the sheriff's office said.
Falling ice has long been a danger to hikers in the region during warmer months, officials said. In 2010, an 11-year-old girl was killed near the caves when she was struck by a chunk of ice, forest officials said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Greece moves forward after the No vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-financial-crisis-how-the-country-moves-forward-after-the-no-vote-1.3140130?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Now, Greece still must deal with a financial crisis that includes adebt to Europe of over 320 billion, andthe need, according to the IMF, of at least another 60 billion more forrelief.
A sign of compromise?
Despite thestrong mandate the results gaveGreekPrime Minister AlexisTsipras, who had urged his citizens to vote No,the Greek leader signalled he may be willing to compromise with the Europeanswith the resignation of former finance minister Yanis Varoufakis. Varoufakis, an inflammatory figure,had suggested the European leaders were financial terrorists because of their demands.
But first things first. The banks.
But the most immediate threat facing Greece is the insolvency of its banking system, which is near collapse. Basically, it's almost out of cash. This has meant closed branches,long lineups at ATMs and a daily rationing of 60 per person.
"The first thing they need to decide iswhether they keep propping up the Greek banks whilethe Europeanleaders negotiate Greece's debt," said EvanDudley, anassistant professor atQueen's University School of Business.
"It's a tough decision because the Europeanleaders and the EuropeanCentral Bank havetakena tough stance up to the referendum. If they cave here and say they willsupport the banking system so we can promote furtherre-negotiations, then it kind of undermines that tough stand."
Some suggestthat July 20will be the day of reckoning, as that's the day Greece owes the ECB a 3.5 billion payment. It's at this point the ECB could cut off the flow of money, forcing Greece out of the eurozone.
On Monday, theECBsaidit was keeping the level of emergency credit to Greek banks unchanged.But Ian Lee, an assistant professor atCarletonUniversity'sSprottSchool of Business, said he believes the ECB will continue to give some money to Greece, while keeping it "on a very, very short leash."
"I think what they will probably do is keep the money trickling in just to keep the banks alive while the [European leaders]decidewhat the larger overall package is going to be."
Goodbye eurozone, hello drachma?
With thevery real chance that Greece may abandon (or be pushed out of)the eurozone altogether, this would mean the return ofits own currency.TheNovote has putpressure on Greeceto take control of its own money supply andgoingback to the drachma could solve some of those problems, Dudley said.
"They'd say, 'OK, we don'tneed the ECB, we'll meetall depositrequests, We can pay everythingout indrachmas instead of euros, All the currency transactions in Greece could be rewritten in drachmas. At the end of the day, Greece would be in full control, monetarily, of what's goingon initscountry." he said.
But that would come with its own set of complications. Greek businesses reliant on imports would now deal withsuppliers who wouldn'twant to be paid in drachmas. Goods cominginto the county would face hugeinflationary price increases. And contracts betweenGreek businesses, based on euros,would have to be renegotiated.
"It would be very difficult and chaotic in the short run. In the long runit would probably be best," Dudley said.
Market impact
While the markets fell following the referendum vote, it wasn't nearly as dramatic as some had feared.
"The stock exchangewill hurt for the next few days. Italways goes down when there's bad news, uncertainty and right nowthere's alot of uncertainty and bad news in Greece," Lee said."Then they'll come back up when the world is not coming to an end."
Europe prepared?
Europe is much better prepared than it was in 2012 when Greece was going to default, before a last-minute bailout package was agreed upon. In part, the country has been ring fenced, meaningthat measures have been put in place to protect other countriesfrom the possibilityof financialcontagion.
For example, Dudley said,the ECB has said it will not let the euro currency fall, at any cost, eliminating fears the currencycould collapse
Little effecton Canada
The Canadian economy is pretty much isolated from the Greek economy, with neither country engaging in a lot of trade with the other.
However,Canadian importers of olive oil, sea salt, preserved vegetables and other delicacies from Greece say they'vebeen stockpiling goods in their warehouses in anticipation that theeconomic turmoil overseas will get worse.
With files from The Associated Press and The Canadian Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:35:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bull-running festival takes off in Spain</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/photos/bull-running-festival-takes-off-in-spain-1.3139777?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Bull-running festival takes off in Spain
San Fermin Fiesta in Pamplona runs July 6-14
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:53:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barack Obama says ISIS will be defeated by ideas, not guns</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/barack-obama-says-isis-will-be-defeated-by-ideas-not-guns-1.3140231?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Barack Obama says ISIS will be defeated by ideas, not guns
U.S. president meets with Pentagon officials following weekend airstrikes in eastern Syria
CBC News Posted: Jul 06, 2015 3:53 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 5:47 PM ET
U.S. President Barack Obama, left, delivered remarks after a briefing on U.S. efforts against the Islamic State (ISIS), at the Pentagon in Arlington on Monday. He called the conflict a "generational struggle," one that will be defeated better through ideology than with guns. (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Related Stories
Barack Obama's string of political successes starts the legacy talk again
The complex threat of theISIS extremist group will not be ultimatelydefeated by guns but through ideology, BarackObamasays.
The U.S. president made theremarks Monday on the military campaign against the Islamic State group after being briefed by Pentagon officials earlier in the day.
He called for co-operation among countries in a fight he said spills over borders. Obama will look to partner with Muslim communities that he said are often the target of ISIS attacks.
"The battle for hearts and minds is going to be a generational struggle," he said.
Obama'slegacy: will string of successes leave positive impression?
Obamahas insisted he will not send U.S. troops into ground combat to fight the Islamic State in Iraq or Syria. However, he has acknowledged that the U.S. lacks a "complete strategy" for training Iraqi troops to carry out ground missions. He identified local authorities in targeted communities as essential to any kind of resolution.
"If [the U.S. military tries]to do everything ourselves, we'll be playing whack-a-mole," Obama said.
Republicans accused of obstructing
The president's meetings with top Pentagon officials and other national security advisersfollow a wave of weekend airstrikes by the U.S.-led coalition in eastern Syria. The coalition says it was one of the most sustained aerial operations carried out in Syria to date. Obamanoted that the total number of airstrikesduring thedeployment has surpassed 5,000.
Efforts to train Syrian rebels are also sputtering. Fewer than 100 rebels are being trained by the U.S., far fewer than the goal of producing 5,400 fighters a year.
Obamaacknowledged that the nationless ISIS group has been using technology to solicit Islamists around the world, some of whom end up launching attacks abroad,without military backing. He saidthe U.S. will continue to examine "what's working and what [the U.S.] can do better."
"The threat of lone wolves is complex. The small cells are becoming harder to detect," Obama said.
Ahead of the president's meetings, the White House sharply criticized U.S. Senate Republicans for failing to confirm Adam Szubin, Obama's nominee to be the Treasury undersecretary responsible for choking off funding to groups like ISIS.
White House spokesman Josh Earnest said Republicans had refused to "even give him the time of day for a hearing" since Obama nominated Szubin in April, adding that the Senate should confirm him before legislators go home for their annual August recess.
"It's time for Republicans in the Senate to do their jobs for a change," Earnest said.
Obama said that Szubin's appointment would significantly contribute to improvedforeign affairs.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:30:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston Marathon bomber seeks new trial after receiving death sentence</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/dzhokhar-tsarnaev-boston-marathon-bomber-seeks-new-trial-1.3140329?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, Boston Marathon bomber, seeks new trial
21-year-old was convicted of 30 charges in the bombings, and sentenced to death
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 06, 2015 5:30 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 7:46 PM ET
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev filed a motion for a new trial Monday, less than two weeks after being sentenced to death. The motion did not contain details regarding arguments the defence plans to use. (Jane Flavell/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Boston Marathon bombing timeline
Tsarnaev's lawyers filed a preliminary motion for a new trial Monday after his conviction and death sentence. The motion did not contain any details on what grounds they plan to argue, saying only that a new trial is "required in the interests of justice."
The 21-year-old Tsarnaev was convicted of 30 charges in the bombings, which killed three people and injured more than 260. The same jury that determined his guilt recommended the death penalty, and a federal judge on June 24 sentenced him to death.
Tsarnaev's lawyers call the motion a "placeholder" until they can file a more detailed motion next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:48:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>American Apparel to close stores, lay off workers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/american-apparel-to-close-stores-lay-off-workers-1.3140256?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>American Apparel to close stores, lay off workers
Cost-cutting measures will save U.S. retailer $30M over next 18 months
CBC News Posted: Jul 06, 2015 3:48 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 4:21 PM ET
American Apparel has lost $300 million since 2010 and its stock price has plummeted from a high of $15 in 2007 to less than a dollar. (Associated Press)
Related Stories
Dov Charney, Montreal-born founder of American Apparel, officially sacked
American Apparel plans to shutter some stores and lay off some of its staffas part of the next phase of its strategic turnaround, butwarns there's still a chance it will run out of money.
The U.S. retailer expects the new cost-cutting measures will save $30 million over the next 18 months. It did not say how many of its 239stores or 10,000 employees would be affected, but said the cuts were necessary in today's highly competitive and promotional retail environment.
In a statement, the company said "even ifAmerican Apparelincreases revenue and cuts costs, there can be no guarantee that the company will have sufficient financing commitments to meet funding requirements for the next 12 months."
"We are committed to turning this company around," said Paula Schneider, the newly appointed CEO. "Our primary focus is on improving the processes and product mix that have led to steep losses over the past five years."
American Apparel has accumulated more than $300 million in losses since 2010, mostly under the leadership of the retailer's controversial founder and former CEO Dov Charney, who was born in Montreal. He was ousted from the role last year amid allegations of sexual misconduct and misuse of funds.
In Monday's statement, the company said it also needs the extra cashto defend itself against approximately 20 lawsuits and administrative actions initiated by Charney.
The company added it will, for the first time, unveila new fallline, and announced the appointment of twoexecutives in its retail and wholesale divisionsto help with the turnaround.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caitlyn Jenner's 1984 Olympic Torch to hit auction block</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/caitlyn-jenner-s-1984-olympic-torch-to-hit-auction-block-1.3140878?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Caitlyn Jenner's 1984 Olympic Torch to hit auction block
Piece of Olympic memorabilia could fetch as much as $20K
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 07, 2015 1:49 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 1:49 AM ET
Related Stories
Bruce Jenner tells Diane Sawyer he's 'a woman for all intents and purposes'
The 1984 Summer Olympic Torch that CaitlynJennercarried through Lake Tahoe, Nev., is going on the auction block where it could fetch $20,000 or more.
It's the first major piece of Jenner memorabilia to go to auction since the winner of the 1976 Olympic Decathlon Gold Medal, formerly known as Bruce,became Caitlyn.
The 61 centimetretorch, featuring a brass finish and leather handle, is being offered by Heritage Auctions at its Platinum Night Sports Auction in Chicago on July 30. The seller is Bob Lorsch, a Los Angeles philanthropist and entrepreneur who orchestrated the Tahoe leg of the torch relay and secured Jenner's participation.
Winnipeg transgender woman calls Jenner a role model
"This torch serves as a wonderful symbol that masculinity and femininity are not mutually exclusive," said Chris Ivy, Heritage's director of sports auctions. "The decathlon has long been considered the ultimate athletic proving ground. Jenner has played both gender roles masterfully."
The torch is the first significant piece of Jenner memorabilia to go to auction since the winner of the 1976 Olympic Decathlon Gold Medal became Caitlyn Jenner. (Heritage Auctions/AP)
Jenner was approached to carry the torch as part of the Los Angles Summer Olympic Games to help support Caesars Tahoe's agenda of giving back to the local community and promoting area youth programs, said Lorsch. The hotel casino held a drawing for a chance to win a place in the relay and sponsored 50 kilometresof the Nevada route. Seven went to individuals and 42 to local organizations. Jenner was asked to run the remaining kilometre.
"Caesars saw it as a tremendous opportunity ... to do something more special, never realizing that we would be creating what is truly a piece of history that originated as a piece of sports history, then evolved as a piece of entertainment history through the Kardashian legacy and becoming a cultural phenomenon through the transition to Caitlyn," said Lorsch.
"Other than trinkets and signed memorabilia, this is the first piece of what I would consider significant Jenner memorabilia to reach the auction block," said Ivy.
Better known to a younger generation as the patriarch on Keeping up With the Kardashians,Jenner, 65, announced earlier this year that he was transitioning to become a woman. Vanity Fair ran glamour photos of him as Caitlyn.
A spokesman for Jenner didn't respond to a request for comment.
Caitlyn Jenner will receive the Arthur Ashe Courage Award at the upcoming ESPY Awards on July 15 for her bravery for publicly coming out as a transgender woman.
An E! Entertainment network documentary series I Am Cait,depicting Jenner's transition from a man to a woman, will debut July 26.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:51:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hollywood producer Jerry Weintraub dies at 77</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/jerry-weintraub-legendary-producer-dead-at-77-1.3140567?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Jerry Weintraub, legendary producer, dead at 77
Larry King, Arnold Schwarzenegger and others pay tribute to 3-time Emmy winner
CBC News Posted: Jul 06, 2015 10:51 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 10:59 PM ET
Film and TV producer Jerry Weintraub died Monday. The three-time Emmy winner is best known for his involvement with the Karate Kid and Ocean's Eleven franchises. (Danny Moloshok/Reuters)
Jerry Weintraub, the dynamic film producer and music manager who pushed the career of John Denver and produced such hit movies as Nashvilleand Ocean's Eleven,has died. He was 77.
Weintraub's representatives say he died Monday of cardiac arrest in Santa Barbara, Calif.
Weintraub became a top concert promoter in the 1970s, working with the likes of Elvis Presley and shaping John Denver's career. He then tackled the movie business and produced such films as Oh, God!;Diner;the remake of Ocean's Eleven and its sequels;and The Karate Kidand its sequels.
Though Weintraub's attempt to found his own studio, Weintraub Entertainment Group,ended in bankruptcy in 1990, his success as an independent producer spanned decades, including 2013's Emmy-winningBehind the Candelabra, a TV drama about Liberace.
He died with numerous projects in development, including the recently debuted HBO series The Brinkand an upcoming remake of Tarzan.
Weintraubwas also a close friend of former U.S. president George H.W. Bush.
"Jerry was an American original who earned his success by the sheer force of his instinct, driveand larger-than-life personality," Bush said Monday. "He had a passion for life, and throughout the ups and downs of his prolific career, it was clear just how much he loved show business."
So sad at loss of Jerry Weintraub, you were 1 of a kind, my friend. Last of a breed. So glad I got to be "that kid" pic.twitter.com/ebN7p8ptUL
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:19:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>20 riders fall in massive crash at Tour de France</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/sports/tour-de-france-20-riders-fall-in-massive-crash-1.3140094?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tour de France: 20 riders fall in massive crash
Spanish veteran Joaquim Rodriguez wins 3rd stage
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 06, 2015 2:19 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 2:19 PM ET
Big crash at Tour de France 1:51
Spanish veteran Joaquim Rodriguez won the crash-marred third stage of the Tour de France on Monday, with British rider Chris Froome finishing second to take the race leader's yellow jersey.
The crash happened with a little under 60 kilometres (37 miles) remaining, forcing the stage to be neutralized and then stopped altogether shortly after  for nearly 20 minutes  while organizers allowed those who fell to catch up.
With the race moving from neighbouring Netherlands into Belgium, stage three was 159.5 kilometres (99 miles) from Antwerp to Huy.
It featured four short and sharp climbs but the crash took place before any of these when Frenchman William Bonnet went down and several riders tumbled around him.
All of the main Tour contenders avoided the crash, unlike Fabian Cancellara, who started the day in the yellow jersey and ended it in agony after being one of some 20 riders who fell.
After taking chunks of time out of his Tour rivals Vincenzo Nibali and Nairo Quintana on Sunday's rain-soaked and wind-battered second stage, Froome did it again as he accelerated in the last climb. He almost caught up Rodriguez, but the Spanish rider held on with Froome closing in on him.
"It's never too early to take the yellow jersey," Froome said. "Really happy to come second and put more time on my GC (general classification) contenders. I was in front (of the crash) and just heard it about it on the radio."
Rodriguez and Froome clocked the same time of 3 hours, 26 minutes, 54 seconds. Frenchman Alexis Vuillermoz was third, four seconds behind them.
Froome, the 2013 Tour champion, leads German rider Tony Martin by just one second and is 13 seconds ahead of American rider Tejay Van Garderen.
The day's final two climbs  1.3 kilometres (0.8 miles)  up Cote de Cherave and the famed Mur de Huy featured on this year's Fleche Wallonne (Walloon Arrow) classic. That prompted Froome to ride the Wallonne this year, where he crashed toward the end.
He had better luck this time, gaining 11 seconds on Nibali and Quintana and 18 seconds on two-time Tour champion Contador.
"I lost quite a lot of time. I said before the stage that stages like this are often difficult," Contador said. "It was very hard in the end and I was lacking something. Froome is very strong and he's come here in good form."
Major impact
Monday's heavy crash took its toll.
Cancellara was one of the last to go down, leaping into the air with his bike attached to him, then landing with a thud  luckily on the grass  and skidding on his side. Escaping with a few cuts and bruises, Cancellara got back on his bike.
But others were not so lucky.
Bonnet was taken off on a stretcher with a brace around his neck. Dutch rider Tom Dumoulin  competing for the best young rider's white jersey  Australian veteran Simon Gerrans, and Russian Dmitry Kozontchuk also withdrew from the race.
During Sunday's trek along the Dutch coastline, time gaps were made when heavy side winds caused a split in the front of the peloton.
This time, the weather was not to blame.
Bonnet lost control and his bike slid forward and down.
The end result was a tangled mess of bikes, spewed in all directions on the side of the road, while some riders lay on their backs in the grass and others were curled up in agony on the hot tarmac.
The stage re-started for good at the top of the first climb, meaning there were about 50 kilometres (31 miles) remaining.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:53:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina senate advances bill to remove Confederate flag from capitol</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/south-carolina-senate-advances-bill-to-remove-confederate-flag-1.3140422?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>South Carolina senate advances bill to remove Confederate flag
Controversial bill passes a crucial 2nd reading by a 37-3 vote
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 06, 2015 4:53 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 6:38 PM ET
Robert Hayes, left, calls Tom Clements, right, a 'scallywag' as lawmakers vote on removing the Confederate flag from outside the South Carolina Statehouse in Columbia. Hayes is from Abbeville, S.C., and describes his hometown as 'The cradle and the grave of the Confederacy.' (Sean Rayford/Getty Images )
Related Stories
<<<<<<< HEAD
Obama eulogizes Charleston shooting victim Rev. Clementa Pinckney, sings Amazing Grace
South Carolina lawmakers took a step on Monday toward removing the Confederate battle flag that flies at the state house in Columbia, long denounced as a symbol of slavery by critics.
A bill to banish the flag from a Civil War memorial on the capitol grounds to a museum passed a crucial second reading in the state senate by an overwhelming vote of 37-3 after an emotional debate.
It faces a final reading on Tuesday before it is taken up by the lower House of Representatives.
Numerous elected officials, including Republican Gov.Nikki Haley, called for the flag's removal after the June 17 killings of nine African-American churchgoers during Bible study at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church in Charleston.
Charleston church shooting: Hate crime, gun crime? Does it matter?
Photos of the white man charged in the shootings showed him posing with the flag on a website that also carried a racist manifesto.
Among the victims was the church's pastor, Rev.Clementa Pinckney, who was also a state senator, and his senate desk was draped in black for Monday's debate.
The flag's defenders argue it is part of South Carolina's heritage, representing those who fought and died for the rebelling southern states in the Civil War.
A South Carolina state trooper stands at the bottom of a Confederate flag at the base of a confederate memorial in front of the South Carolina State House in Columbia, S.C. Republican Gov. Nikki Haley has called for the flag's removal. (Tami Chappell/Reuters )
They also worry that bringing down the flag, which has flown for more than 50 years at the capitol, could lead to calls for removing symbols from other monuments and changing street and place names honouring Confederate leaders.
The legislation appears to have a good chance of success and could be approved as early as Thursday. Haley has said she will have the flag removed immediately if the law is passed.
A recent poll by Charleston's Post and Courier newspaper showed it enjoys the support of a two-thirds majority in both houses as required under state law.
Several senators on Monday spoke of being moved and inspired by the Christian forgiveness displayed by relatives of the Emanuel ninefor the shooter, adding that removal of the flag was the proper way to honour them.
"If they could be peacemakers in those dire circumstances ... I determined I can be a peacemaker when it comes to a flag flying on our State House grounds," said Senator Chip Campsen, a Republican who represents Charleston.
Some senators argue flag should stay
At least three senators spoke in favour of keeping the flag flying.
"I do understand that what happened in Charleston got a lot of people's attention," said Republican Senator Lee Bright, who is white. "But I believe we're placing the blame of what one deranged lunatic did on people that hold their southern heritage high and I don't think that's fair."
Confederate flag: 10facts about the controversial symbol
Democrat Vincent Sheheen, who is white and introduced the bill, noted that he was mocked by politicians a year ago when he introduced similar legislation. He said the Charleston murders were a reminder that a racist cultural divide still existed in the state.
Removing the flag was "one small thing that we can do" to heal that divide, he said.
While some white people might have emotional ties to the Confederate flag, Senator Darrell Jackson, a black Democrat, reminded legislators that the descendants of slaves look at it differently.
"When I see a Confederate soldier, I don't get goosebumps and get all warm and fuzzy," he said. "All I'm saying is you can't force all of us to have the passion that some of you have about certain things."
The Confederate flag was raised atop the State House dome in 1961 as part of centennial commemorations of the Civil War. Critics said its placement was a sign of opposition by politicians to the black civil rights movement at the time.
In 2000, after the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People announced an economic boycott of South Carolina and protesters marched on the state capital, lawmakers agreed to a compromise, moving the flag to a monument to Confederate war dead on the capitol grounds.
=======
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
U.S. President Barack Obama describedRev.ClementaPinckney as a kind, diligent man who was "able to walk in someone else's shoes, able to see through their eyes" at a funeral for the South Carolina pastor shot to death with eight others at aCharleston churchlast week.
Obama, who knew Pinckney personally,eulogized the pastor infront of a crowdof more than 5,000at an arena in downtown Charleston, recalling Pinckney'shumble influence on his communityand at one point leading the crowdin a chorus of thehymnAmazing Grace.
South Carolinalawmakers debate Confederate flag
"Even from a young age, people knew he was special," Obamasaid of Pinckney."He conducted himself kindly, quietly and diligently. He was full of empathy, able to walk in someone else's shoes, able to see through their eyes.That's the best thing to hope for when you're eulogized to just say somebody was a good man."
The late Rev. Clementa Pinckney's daughter, Malana, reaches up to U.S. President Barack Obama next to her sister Eliana, right, as their mother Jennifer hugs first lady Michelle Obama after the president eulogized Rev. Pinckney during funeral services at the College of Charleston TD Arena in Charleston, S.C., on Friday (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Pinckneyheadedthe historic African-American Emanuel AME Church and was also a state senator. He was takingpartin a bible study on June 17 whena gunman entered the church, joined the bible study for an hour before opening fire, killing Pinckney and seven other parishoners. One person died later in hospital.
Obama acknowledged those other victims in his eulogy.
"To the families of the fallen, our nation shares in your grief," he said.
'Aflag did not commit these murders'
Dylann Roof, 21, has been charged with nine counts of murder in connection with the shooting. He has been linkedto a website with numerous racist writings and images, including ones showing him holding a Confederate flag, a Civil War-era battle flagseen by many as a racist symbol of the slave-owning American South.
More than 5,000 mourners packed a downtown Charleston arena for the service. (Brian Snyder/Reuters)
Politicians and civil rights activists have called for the flag to be removed from governmentbuildings and other institutions in South Carolina and elsewhere in the wake of the shooting while other's have insisted it is an important part of the history of the American south. Obama alluded to that controversy at the funeral Friday.
"It's true a flag did not commit these murders" he said."Theflag has always represented more than ancestral pride. For many, black and white, that flag was a reminder of oppression and racial subjugation.
"For too long, we were blind to the pain that the Confederate flag stirred in too many of our citizens."
The president acknowledged that racism can't be solved by debate and thatsolutions will always be imperfect.
"There's no shortcut. We don't need more talk," Obama said. "Whatever solutions we find will be necessarily incomplete."
Joe Biden, HillaryClintonin attendance
Obamaarrived in Charleston Friday afternoon, several hoursafter addressing the nation from the White House Rose Garden about the U.S. Supreme Court's decision to legalize gay marriage in all 50 states.
Other speakers at the funeral praisedPinckney'spersonal touch andhis political reach.
The tone of Friday's funeral service was largely uplifting. The service included several musical numbers and humourous anecdotes about the beloved pastor. (Grace Beahm/Reuters)
"We will see the Confederate flag come down.You're the one who did it." said South Carolina statesenatorGerald Malloy. "Do not let race, religion or politics close the door that SenatorPinckney opened."
Bishop John Richard Bryant spoke to the congregation about Roofand his effect on the South Carolina community and the country at large.
"He wanted to start a race war, but he came to the wrong place," said Bryant. "Weeping may endure for the night, but joy comes in the morning."
MichelleObamaand Vice-President JoeBidenand his wife,Jill, also attended the service, as didHouse Speaker John Boehner,Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton and other state and federal politicians and civil rightsactivists, includingMartin Luther King III.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
