<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:24:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>VIDEO: Texas family horrified as flood waters engulf their home</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/videos/video-texas-family-horrified-as-flood-waters-engulf-their-home-1.3092141?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>VIDEO: Texas family horrified as flood waters engulf their home
CBC News Posted: May 28, 2015 8:24 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 8:24 PM ET
Related Stories
Texas flood: Record rainfall eases long-running drought
The home video only lasts for 2 minutes and35 seconds, but captures in graphic detail the fear felt by a Texas couple as the Blanco River swept through their home in Wimberley, Texas, on Sunday.
Ernie and Sarah Perezwatched in horror from the second floor of their home as the river's record surge  which, at its peak reached the height of a four-storey building  roared through their home.
Texas flood: Record rainfall eases long-running drought
"Oh, no!" Sarah moans more than once as family photographs and furniture swirl beneath them, all captured on a mobile phone.
But the Perez family was lucky  they survived. Nine other people remain missing following the devastation of the "large wall of water that came down the Blanco River and destroyed everything in its path," Hays County Commissioner Will Conley said on Monday..
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:57:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Car bombs kill 10 near major Baghdad hotels</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/car-bombs-kill-10-near-major-baghdad-hotels-1.3092126?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Car bombs kill 10 near major Baghdad hotels
Thomson Reuters Posted: May 28, 2015 8:57 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 8:57 PM ET
Smoke and flames rise from the site of car bomb attack in Baghdad on Thursday night. (Ahmed Saad/Reuters)
Related Stories
Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
A further 30 people were wounded in the blasts, which were detonated about seven minutes apart.
Iraq lacks 'will to fight,' U.S. says
The first bomb targeted the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, and the second hit the Meridian.
Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew on Baghdad early this year, seeking to restore a sense of normality to the capital as security forces battle ISIS militants who have overrun large parts of the country.
However, the rate of bombings in Baghdad has increased since then.
In recent days, the insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, west of Baghdad,in the most significant military setback to the government since a U.S.-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against the jihadists last August.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:41:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin signs law banning publication of peacetime military casualties</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/putin-signs-law-banning-publication-of-peacetime-military-casualties-1.3091950?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Putin signs law banning publication of peacetime military casualties
Move comes as evidence mounts of Russian troops in Ukraine
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 6:41 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 6:41 PM ET
Russian President Vladimir Putin, seen addressing a business forum in Russia on Tuesday, signed a decree Thursday that makes it a crime to report Russian military losses in peacetime. (Alexei Nikolsky/RIA Novosti/ AP)
Related Stories
Russia's Vladimir Putin brandishes the nuclear option
President Vladimir Putin has signed a decree to make losses of Russian troops in peacetime a state secret.
The decree published on the official government website and signed by Putin on Thursday makes it a crime to publish information about peacetime losses of Russian troops in "special operations."
Russia's Vladimir Putin brandishes the nuclear option
The decree comes as evidence of Russian involvement in the conflict in eastern Ukraine is mounting.
Ukraine last week captured two men who it said were Russian officers operating on the side of the separatists in eastern Ukraine. The Russian defence ministry said the two are no longer active servicemen. However, the men insisted in several video interviews they were in Ukraine on their commanders' orders.
The measure brought strong criticism from Amnesty International and the United States.
"Not only is this decree a blatant attack on freedom of expression, it also has sinister undertones that will intensify speculation President Putin has something to hide  specifically losses incurred by Russia's military in Ukraine," John Dalhuisen, Amnesty's Europe and Central Asia director, said in a statement.
U.S. State Department spokesman Jeff Rathke said in Washington, "We see this as a misplaced effort to cover up what everyone knows, and that is that Russian active-duty military personnel are fighting and dying in eastern Ukraine and that the Russian government is denying it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:04:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS fighters fall back as Kurdish troops retake towns in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/kurdish-troops-retake-cities-in-syria-from-isis-1.3091682?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Kurdish troops retake cities in Syria from ISIS
Motivated by revolutionary fervour, Kurds succeed where Iraqi army fails
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 5:04 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 5:04 PM ET
A young Kurdish fighter battles last fall in the retaking of Kobani, Syria. The Kurds, motivated by a desire for their own homeland and backed by U.S.-led airstrikes, have now retaken more than 200 cities from ISIS fighters. (AP file photo)
Related Stories
Iraq lacks will to fight, U.S. says
In contrast to the Iraqi army's failures, Kurdish fighters in Syria are on the march against ISIS, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes.
As the Kurds close in on Tel Abyad, a major commercial centre on the Turkish border, their advance highlights the decisive importance of combining air power with the presence of a cohesive and motivated ally on the ground  so clearly absent in Iraq.
Iraq lacks will to fight, U.S. says
In Syria, a country now split mostly between al-Qaeda-style militants and forces loyal to embattled President Bashar al-Assad, the United States has found a reliable partner in the country's main Kurdish fighting force, known as the YPG. They are moderate, mostly secular fighters driven by revolutionary fervour and deep conviction in their cause.
Since the beginning of May, they have wrested back more than 200 Kurdish and Christian towns in northeastern Syria, as well as strategic mountains seized earlier by ISIS militants. Along the way, they have picked up ammunition, weapons and vehicles left behind by jihadists.
Key link
The push has got them closer to Tel Abyad, a major avenue for commerce for the extremist group through which it smuggles foreign fighters and sells black-market oil to help fund its conquests. The city is also a key link between Turkey and the northern Syrian city of Raqqa, the Islamic State group's de-facto capital in its self-declared caliphate.
"The YPG doesn't lack a will to fight, like soldiers in the Syrian army or soldiers in the Iraqi army who mostly fight for a salary," said Wladimir van Wilgenburg, a Middle East analyst at the Jamestown Foundation in Washington. "The YPG is much more motivated than other forces in the region, and doesn't lack cohesion and doesn't have co-ordination problems.
The Iraqi military has struggled to make gains after its humiliating defeats last year, when it virtually crumbled in the face of the militant onslaught in northern Iraq. Poor training, corruption and sectarian politics have all been cited as reasons for the military's shortcomings.
The U.S. spent billions of dollars training Iraqi forces from 2003 to 2011, but much of that training did not reach the foot soldiers battling the Islamic State group today.
Last week, U.S. Defence Secretary Ash Carter criticized the Iraqi army following the fall of Ramadi, the strategic capital of the country's largest Sunni province of Anbar, saying the Iraqi military lacked the "will to fight."
'The YPG doesn't lack a will to fight, like soldiers in the Syrian army or soldiers in the Iraqi army who mostly fight for a salary.'
- Wladimir van Wilgenburg, Middle East analyst
Within days, ISIS fighters had also dealt a major blow to Assad's forces in Syria, seizing the historic city of Palmyra, a major crossroads linking the capital, Damascus, with territory to the east and west. In images reminiscent of the Iraqi defeat in Ramadi, Syrian soldiers fled the city, leaving behind tanks and ammunition.
By contrast, Syria's Kurds have shown remarkable cohesiveness. Spurred by ideology and nationalistic fervour, they fought ferociously to claw back territory after ISIS fighters captured the Kurdish town of Kobani and dozens of surrounding villages last fall. The ISIS descent on Kobani led the U.S. to widen its air campaign from Iraq into Syria to assist the Kurds.
Despite the fact that ISIS had heavy weapons and far more fighters, the Kurds resisted the offensive on Kobani, conducting fierce street battles until the U.S. air-dropped weapons and intensified the airstrikes.
In January, the YPG liberated Kobani from the Islamic State militants and began a wide offensive in which they regained much of the territory they had lost.
On May 6, the Kurdish fighters and their allies launched an offensive from the northeastern province of Hassakeh and in less than three weeks captured the strategic Mount Abdul-Aziz along with 221 Kurdish and Christian villages that were held by ISIS.
The Kurds are now closing in on Tel Abyad with fighters moving east from Kobani and west from Hassakeh  an offensive that, if successful, would open a direct line between Kurdish-controlled territory along the border with Turkey. Such a move is likely to anger Turkey, which sees the YPG as part of the Kurdish PKK movement that has waged an anti-government insurgency in southeastern Turkey for years.
Kurdish troops were able retake Kobani, Syria, last year with the help of U.S.-led airstrikes. Now they're reclaiming more towns lost to ISIS fighters. (Associated Press file photo)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:40:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch up for sale at $100M</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/michael-jackson-s-neverland-ranch-valued-at-100m-1.3092190?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch valued at $100M
King of Pop's fantasy-land home goes up for sale
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 9:40 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 9:40 PM ET
In 1995, Michael Jackson and Lisa Marie Presley walk with children who were invited guests at his Neverland Ranch home, in Santa Ynez, Calif. He would move away from the playtime palace 10 years later following his acquittal on charges he sexually abused children there.  (Associated Press)
Related Stories
Michael Jackson: Recalling the King of Pop 5 years after his death
Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch is up for sale.
The Santa Ynez Valley property that once served as the late pop star's home and personal fantasy land is being listed at $100 million US, according to the Wall Street Journal.
Michael Jackson: Recalling the King of Pop 5 years after his death
The 1,100-hectare ranch, which features a train station, six-bedroom house and 50-seat movie theatre, has been in limbo since Jackson's death in 2009.
Jackson paid $19.5 million for the property in 1988 and rechristened it Neverland after Peter Pan's island dwelling.
The real estate company Colony Capital LLC bailed out Jackson in 2008 after he defaulted on the $24.5 million that he owed on the property.
Jackson distanced himself from Neverland after his 2005 acquittal on charges that he molested children at the ranch, opting to live elsewhere.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:50:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Girl, 6, just the right size to rescue kitten from storm drain</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/girl-6-just-the-right-size-to-rescue-kitten-from-storm-drain-1.3092044?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Girl, 6, just the right size to rescue kitten from storm drain
Firefighters lowered the kindergartner nearly a metre into a drain to coax the cat out
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 6:50 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 6:50 PM ET
Deputy Chief Glenn Usdin, left, of the Lancaster Township Fire Department holds the kitten Janeysha Cruz, 6, right, rescued. Firefighters lowered the Pennsylvania kindergartner nearly a metre into a storm drain to coax the kitten out.  (Brett J. Fassnacht/Lancaster Township Fire Department/AP)
Firefighters were too big to rescue a kitten from a storm drain in south-central Pennsylvania, but a six-year-old girl proved to be just the right size.
Lancaster Township firefighters responded when Janeysha Cruz and her friends saw the trapped kitten Tuesday afternoon.
The girl's mother called 911 and then gave firefighters permission to lower the kindergartner nearly a metre into the drain, which was too small for the firefighters to enter. The girl was able to coax the kitten to come to her and handed it to the firefighters.
The fire department reported the incident on its Facebook page, along with a picture of Janeysha, Deputy Chief Glenn Usdin and the kitten.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:39:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ukraine minister says fighting could resume in country's east</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/ukraine-minister-says-russian-troops-in-country-s-east-fighting-could-resume-1.3091540?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Ukraine minister says Russian troops in country's east, fighting could resume
Russia denies accusations it has sent soldiers, weaponry across border
Thomson Reuters Posted: May 28, 2015 3:39 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 3:39 PM ET
Ukrainian army soldiers prepare weapons against Russia-backed separatists in a front line near the Donetsk region in Ukraine on May 26, 2015. Ukraine's defence minister said Russia has moved units of armed forces into eastern Ukraine. (Petro Zadorozhnyy/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Russian officers captured, Ukraine says
Ukraine's defence minister said on Thursday Russia had moved forces into eastern Ukraine and there was a risk of fighting resuming between the army and pro-Russian separatists in coming months.
Violence has been less intense in Ukraine's east since a ceasefire was brokered in Minsk in February, but the two sides regularly accuse each other of violating the truce.
Russian officers captured, Ukraine says
Defence Minister Stepan Poltorak told a joint news conference with his Baltic counterparts in the Lithuanian city Panevezys the separatists were supported by Russia and their actions were difficult to predict.
"A large number of tanks and artillery systems have been moved into the territory, and in the territory of Luhansk and Donetsk there are units of Russian armed forces," Poltorak said. "That is why we see a risk fighting will restart."
Ukraine's Defence Minister Stepan Poltorak, seen on Feb. 13, 2015, said the Russian-supported separatists' actions are difficult to predict. (Andrew Kravchenko/Associated Press)
Russia denies accusations that it has sent serving soldiers or weaponry across the border to support the separatists.
Baltic states fearKremlin pressure
Baltic states Lithuania, Estonia and Latvia, all NATO members and with ethnic Russian minorities, fear they could become a target of Kremlin pressure after the pro-Moscow rebellion in Ukraine that has put Russia at loggerheads with the West.
The defence ministers of the three countries signed a memorandum of understanding on Thursday to consider joint procurement of medium-range air defence systems, which they currently lack.
"Today we had a very good discussion how we can develop our joint air defence system for the Baltic countries," Latvian Defence Minister Raimonds Vejonis told the news conference.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:12:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks promise bailout deal by Sunday, EU not so sure</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greeks-promise-bailout-deal-by-sunday-eu-not-so-sure-1.3091363?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greeks promise bailout deal by Sunday, EU not so sure
Government could run out of cash as soon as next week, with debt payment looming
CBC News Posted: May 28, 2015 3:12 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 3:14 PM ET
Greece's official government spokesman is saying there'll be a bailout deal by Sunday. But Eurozone officials aren't so sure. (Petros Giannakouris/ Associated Press)
Related Stories
Greece calls in cash from state agencies to help it stay afloat
Greece says it aims to clinch a deal with its creditors by Sunday, a development that would allow it to receive the desperately needed final installment of its international bailout plan and avoid a default.
But the optimism was dampened by the creditors, who warned an agreement remains elusive. Without one, Greece has no money to meet debt repayments as soon as next week. A default could eventually cause it to drop out of the euro, roiling European and global markets.
"Talks will continue in the coming days, and further progress is needed," said Annika Breidthardt spokeswoman for the European Commission. "We're not there yet. There are open issues which need to be resolved."
The Commission is one of the three institutions Greece is negotiating with, along with the European Central Bank and International Monetary Fund.
The Greek side insisted its optimism was not idle talk.
Hopes for deal
"It is based on very specific facts," government spokesman Gabriel Sakellaridis said Thursday. "We are going into these negotiations with the aim to have an agreement with our partners by Sunday."
"We believe conditions are now ripe for an agreement to be reached," he added.
A day earlier, Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had said a deal was near, and Greek officials said the text of an agreement was being written up. But German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, whose country is the largest single creditor in Greece's bailout program, said he did not share that view.
In Athens, the conservative opposition criticized the government's handling of the negotiation.
"It is obvious that the government is at a dead-end," said New Democracy party spokesman Kostas Karagounis. "It announces deals that don't exist, it presents its own positions as agreements, it is refuted by all foreign officials and meanwhile time has run out and the money has been exhausted."
Greece's new government, elected in January, has been in talks for four months on what reforms it should make to get the final bailout installment of 7.2 billion euros ($9.8 billion Cdn) from fellow eurozone states and the IMF.
Athens needs the funds to be able to repay an IMF loan installment of more than 300 million due June 5. The installment is just one of four due to the IMF in June, all repayments of loans that are part of Greece's 240 billion euro($327 billion)bailout, which began five years ago.
What sort of reforms?
The radical left Syriza party won the elections on promises to repeal deeply resented austerity measures that accompanied the country's bailout, arguing they had simply increased hardship and poverty and left the economy in a depression.
But Greece's creditors insist it must take measures to ensure its economy is reformed and doesn't slip back into the bad habits of the past, with reckless borrowing and an overinflated an inefficient public sector. Negotiations on what measures exactly Athens must take have dragged with little evidence of progress for months.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:09:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter says scandal brought shame and humiliation to soccer</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/fifa-president-sepp-blatter-says-scandal-brought-shame-and-humiliation-to-soccer-1.3090562?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>FIFA president Sepp Blatter says scandal brought shame and humiliation to soccer
Soccer world governing body reeling from arrests, indictments in U.S. racketeering case
Thomson Reuters Posted: May 28, 2015 6:09 AM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 2:04 PM ET
Sepp Blatter's address to FIFA 9:50
FIFA president defiant amid corruption allegations 3:11
Related Stories
Qatar World Cup sponsors targeted for improving workers' rights
Embattled FIFA president Sepp Blatter said on Thursday the corruption scandal surrounding the world soccer body has brought shame and humiliation to the sport.
In a defiant speech at the opening of a FIFA congress in Zurich at which he expects to be re-elected president for a fifth term, Blatter said there is no place for corruption of any kind in the game.
Seeking to distance himself from the scandal in which seven senior FIFA officials have been arrested in Switzerland on U.S. corruption charges, he said: "I cannot monitor everyone all the time. If people want to do wrong they will also try to hide it."
He added that FIFA had lost trust and must earn it back, starting tomorrow. More needs to be done to make sure everyone in football behaves responsibly and ethically, he said.
Qatar World Cup sponsors targeted over workers' rights
Earlier in the day,Blatter rejected an emotional plea to resign from one of the world's soccer greats as the corruption scandal engulfing the game's governing body drew warnings from sponsors and political leaders.
As FIFA faced the worst crisis in its 111-year history, Michel Platini, the former French international who now heads UEFA, Europe's soccer confederation, said he had told Blatter to go but the 79-year-old had refused.
UEFA president Michel Platini speaks to reporters after a UEFA meeting in Zurich on Thursday. A majority of UEFA's member associations will vote for Jordan's Prince Ali bin Al Hussein to succeed Sepp Blatter as the next FIFA president, he says. (Ruben Sprich/Reuters)
"I said, I'm asking you to leave, FIFA's image is terrible. He said that he couldn't leave all of a sudden," Platini told a news conference.
"I'm saying this with sadness and tears in my eyes, but there have been too many scandals, FIFA doesn't deserve to be treated that way," Platini said, speaking after an emergency FIFA meeting in Zurich.
Platini said 45 or 46 of UEFA's 53 eligible member associations would vote for Jordan's Prince Ali bin Al Hussein to succeed Blatter at an election on Friday.
But it appeared that Blatter still commanded enough of FIFA's 209 member associations and could expect to be anointed for a fifth term as president.
Despite FIFA assertions that it was business as usual following the arrest of seven senior officials on U.S. corruption charges, Blatterkept out of public view on Thursday until the opening of the congress
When Blatter failed to show up at a medical conference,FIFA's medical chief Michel D'Hooghe told the medical officers: "President Blatter apologizes for not being able to come today because of the turbulences you have heard about."
Those "turbulences" included a dawn raid by plainclothes police at one of Zurich's most luxurious hotels on Wednesday leaving seven of the most powerful figures in football in custody and facing extradition to the United States on corruption charges. They are all contesting extradition but lawyers said the process could be completed within months.
Criminal probe
Swiss authorities also announced a criminal investigation into the awarding of the next two World Cups being hosted in Russia in 2018 and Qatar in 2022.
U.S. authorities said nine soccerofficials and five sports media and promotions executives faced corruption charges involving more than $150 million USin bribes.
Blatter, who has denied allegations of involvement in corruption, said in a statement on Wednesday: "Let me be clear: such misconduct has no place in football and we will ensure that those who engage in it are put out of the game."
Former World Footballer of the Year Luis Figo, of Portugal, said the day the scandal erupted was "one of the worst days in the history of FIFA".
The FIFA congress gotunder way on Thursday evening with singers, dancers and a buffet.The serious business starts on Friday morning in Zurich's Hallenstadion, which is where the announcement of the 2018 and 2022 World Cup venues was made in 2010, decisions which lie at the very heart of most of FIFA's current malaise.
Splits in world game
With splits opening in the world game, the Asian and African confederations backed Blatter and said the election should go ahead as planned.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius disagreed, saying the vote should be delayed in light of the corruption investigation.
British Prime Minister David Cameron backed Prince Ali's candidacy and said there was a strong case for a change of leadership at FIFA.
Britain has long been a critic of FIFA and unsuccessfully bid for the 2018 World Cup which was awarded to Russia.
Les Murray of Australia, a former FIFA ethics committee member, called for Blatter to resign as have the FA chairmen of a number of leading European countries including England and Germany.
Russian President Vladimir Putin, left, speaks to FIFA president Sepp Blatter during the 2014 World Cup final between Germany and Argentina at the Maracana stadium in Rio de Janeiro in July 2014. (Dylan Martinez/Reuters)
Blatter did, however, receive endorsement from Russian President Vladimir Putin, who accused the United States of meddling outside its jurisdiction by arresting FIFA officials.
"This is yet another blatant attempt to extend its jurisdiction to other states," Putin said, adding the arrests were a clear move to prevent Blatter's re-election.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 10:15:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No relief from broiling temperatures expected for several days in southeast India</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/india-heat-wave-death-toll-climbs-above-1-400-1.3090546?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>India heat wave death toll climbs above 1,400
Most fatalities concentrated in Andhra Pradesh state
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 3:15 AM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 10:37 AM ET
Indian girls shield themselves with scarves as they ride a motorcycle on a hot summer day in Hyderabad, India on Wednesday.   (Mahesh Kumar A./The Associated Press)
Related Stories
Eating onions, lying in the shade and splashing into rivers, Indians were doing whatever they could Thursday to stay cool during a brutal heat wave that has killed more than 1,400 people in the past month.
However, some had no choice but to venture into the heat.
"Either we have to work, putting our lives under threat, or we go without food," farmer Narasimha said in the badly hit Nalgonda district of southern Andhra Pradesh state.
Why India matters to Canada
Meteorological officials have said the heat would likely last several more days  scorching crops, killing wildlife and endangering anyone labouring outdoors. Officials warned people to stay out of the sun, cover their heads and drink plenty of water. Still, poverty forced many to work despite the risks.
A woman walks along the road with her face covered to protect herself from sun stroke on a hot summer day in Chandigarh, India, on Thursday.   (Ajay Verma/Reuters)
"If I don't work due to the heat, how will my family survive?" said construction worker Mahalakshmi, who earns a daily wage of about $3.10 in Nizamabad, a city about 150 kilometresnorth of the state capital of Hyderabad.
Most of the 1,412 heat-related deaths so far have occurred in Andhra Pradesh state and neighbouring Telangana, where temperatures have soared up to 47 C, according to government figures.
"The rains which have eluded us for the last couple of years have created serious drought conditions," said State Minister K.T. Rama Rao in Telangana, which was carved out of Andhra Pradesh as a separate state last year.
"This is unprecedented  so there is a little bit of panic," he said. "Hopefully the monsoon will be on time. Hopefully we will receive rain very, very soon."
Streets nearly deserted
Among the most vulnerable were the elderly and the poor, many of whom live in slums or farm huts with no access to air conditioners or sometimes even shade-giving trees. Those who were able avoided the outdoors, leaving many streets in normally busy cities nearly deserted.
"With so many people dying due to the heat, we are locking the children inside," teacher Satyamurthy said in Khammam, which registered its highest temperature in 67 years on Saturday when the thermometer hit 48 C.
Cooling monsoon rains were expected to arrive next week in the southern state of Kerala and gradually advance north in coming weeks. Until then, volunteers were passing out pouches of salted buttermilk or raw onions  both thought to be hydrating. People used handkerchiefs and scarves to block searing winds and stifling air from their faces.
Across the country, teenagers flocked to water basins and rivers to cool off. Many adults took refuge atop woven cots in the shade.
Newspapers devoted full pages to covering the heat wave and its effects, with headlines saying "Homeless bake in tin shelters" and "birds &amp; animals drop dead."
In cities such as New Delhi, crowds of office workers gathered around stalls selling fruit drinks and iced water, while police officers wearing sweat-soaked shirts squinted into the sun while directing road traffic.
At the zoo, leopards and tigers lay panting in the shade until zoo keepers came by every two hours with hoses. One white tiger rolled around in obvious delight while being sprayed with water. Elephants drank thirstily and lolled in a pond.
"We are even spraying the reptiles," Delhi Zoo curator Riyaz Khan said, noting fans were also set up to keep enclosures cooler, while the animals were also receiving glucose in their drinking water.
Deadliest heat wave in at least 12 years
In the northern Indian states of Punjab and Haryana, Sikhs distributed free glasses of rose-scented milk to the public. Brief spurts of rain brought temporary relief to pockets of the nation, including the southern city of Chennai and the eastern city of Jharkhand.
Forecasting service AccuWeather described this as the most intense heat wave in India in recent years. The death toll for Andhra Pradesh alone, at 1,360, was higher than during a 2003 heat wave when 1,300 died in what was then a unified state including both Telangana and Andhra Pradesh.
Hyderabad resident Rajaiah, who goes by one name, was doing his newspaper delivery route at dawn to avoid peak temperatures.
"It is difficult to do this work in this harsh weather, but I have a family to take care of."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:45:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most new cars will have Apple or Android dashboards by end of 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/apple-carplay-or-google-android-auto-will-be-in-nearly-all-new-cars-by-end-of-2015-1.3090887?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
Apple CarPlay or Google Android Auto will be in nearly all new cars by end of 2015
GM announced both systems will be available in 7 of its 2016 Chevrolet models starting in the summer
The Associated Press Posted: May 28, 2015 10:45 AM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 1:57 PM ET
Starting with Chevrolet this summer, many General Motors models will offer Apple's CarPlay and Google's Android Auto systems that link smart phones with in-car screens and electronics. Here, an iPhone is connected to a 2016 Chevrolet Malibu equipped with Apple CarPlay apps, displayed on the car's MyLink screen. (Paul Sancya/The Associated Press)
Related Stories
Self-driving cars not as safe as human drivers  yet
By the end of the year, nearly every major automaker will begin offering Apple's CarPlay or Google's Android Auto, two systems that effectively turn a car's dashboard screen into a smartphone.
General Motors made the biggest move so far Wednesday, announcing that both systems will be available in seven 2016 Chevrolet models starting in the summer. The Apple system will appear in seven additional Chevy models. Earlier in the week, Hyundai announced the Android system in the Sonata midsize car.
Google conference unveils attempts to broaden focus
Experts say the move to systems devised in Silicon Valley is an admission by the automakers that people favour the way their smartphones work over the automakers' own touch screens and voice commands, which have been prone to glitches. The in-house systems have cost the car companies millions and dinged their quality ratings.
'We just want familiar'
People are familiar with smartphones and have music libraries, podcasts, social media contacts and other personal items on them, said Tim Bajarin, president of Creative Strategies, a technology research firm in San Jose, Calif. Automakers, he said, have realized that most drivers can't be bothered learning a whole new car-based system.
"We just want familiar. We want our content, our services that we already own on our phone. We just want the car to have the representation of that on demand," Bajarin said.
To get the systems, GM customers will have to purchase a new Chevrolet equipped with the brand's MyLinktouch screens, which are available on many entry-level models.
Once people plug into the car's USB port, the system will convert the screen to resemble the phone. The system will then be able to play a person's music library, log on to music apps with a touch, send and receive text messages by voice, and even call up Apple or Google Maps for navigation.
The number of available apps will be limited to avoid driver distraction, GM officials said. Many can be controlled by voice commands, and video won't be supported by the car system.
To work with MyLink, Android phones must have at least the Lollipop 5.0 operating system, while Apple CarPlay requires an iPhone 5 or newer model.
Automakers' systems still necessary
GM will provide CarPlay or Android Car for no additional cost. Although this might cause some drivers to shun MyLink, GM believes that ultimately giving consumers the choice will help it sell more cars, said Saejin Park, the company's director of innovation and portfolio planning.
Mark Boyadjis, senior analyst for infotainment at IHS Automotive, said the decision doesn't necessarily mean the death of MyLink, Ford's Sync and other systems. The automakers' systems have specific information about the car that Apple or Google can't duplicate  engine diagnostics, heating and air conditioning controls or even the ability to set up service appointments with dealerships, Boyadjis said.
GM officials also noted that some car owners might drive in areas without the cellular telephone coverage needed to run the Apple or Google systems. And others prefer not to plug anything in to their cars.
Initially both systems will be offered in the 2016 Spark mini car, Cruze compact, Malibu midisze car, Camaro and Camaro convertible, and the Silverado pickup, both regular and heavy-duty models.
If something goes wrong with the system under warranty, Apple and Google would be responsible if the problem originates with their software. GM would handle any problems on its end such as the MyLink hardware, GM said.
Apple and Android combined control about 95 per cent of the world's smartphone market, so having both systems is necessary. International Data Corp. is forecasting Android will have a 79 per cent share of the smartphone market this year with Apple (iOS) a distant second at 16 per cent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:23:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Toronto film shoot reveals Batman is in Suicide Squad after all</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/batman-appears-on-suicide-squad-film-set-in-toronto-1.3091116?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Batman appears on Suicide Squad film set in Toronto
Will the Dark Knight feature in David Ayers supervillain flick?
CBC News Posted: May 28, 2015 1:23 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 2:10 PM ET
Ben Affleck appears as Batman in a still from the trailer for Batman v. Superman: Dawn of Justice. Fans have long wondered if the Dark Knight would make an appearance in David Ayer's upcoming DC Comics supervillain flick.
Related Stories
Suicide Squad filming closes more streets downtown
Looks as ifBatmanwillbe in Suicide Squad after all.
Ever since Warner Bros. announcedDavid Ayer's upcoming DC Comicssupervillainflick, fans have wondered if the Dark Knight would appear to take on the cast of rogue villains.
Bystanders during one of Suicide Squad'snightly filmshoots in Toronto on Wednesdaywere given a big hint.
This can't go well for the Joker #SuicideSquad pic.twitter.com/NcZJwt0Fcj
 @sylvioso
One night after fans were treated to a first glimpse of the new Batmobile in action ,Batman himself made a surprise appearance.
Videotaken Wednesday nightappears to show a stunt double, wearing theiconic black suit (minus the cape), zipping around on the back of theJoker's sportscaras it raced though city streets.
The real MargotRobbie?
While neitherDark Knight actor Ben AfflecknorThe Joker'sJared Leto wasseenon set Wednesday night, therealMargotRobbiewas captured on camera byfew film buffs.
The Australian Wolf of Wall Streetactress,who plays theJoker's girlfriendHarleyQuinn, was spotted in thepassenger seat of the Jokermobile.
Porque voc  to linda @MargotRobbie pic.twitter.com/dcXGeULlRg
 @elecctrabitch
Suicide Squad, the first followto the upcomingBatman v Superman: Dawn of Justicemovie,also stars Will Smith as deadly assassin Deadshot andJoel Kinnamanas theleader of the Suicide Squad,elite soldier Rick Flagg.
Fans who can't wait for theAug.5, 2016, release date have been gathering at nightly movieshoots that have shut down some ofToronto's iconic landmarks.
Suicide Squad shuts down Yonge Street, yet again
Overthe weekend, the cast and crew filmed a helicopter crash in the city'sfinancial district, and earlier this month, a train scene shut down the Union Station bus terminal. Yonge Street was shut down last month for another chase scene and, prior to that, for a plane crash .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:44:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>MERS suspect case in South Korea travelled to China</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/health/mers-suspect-case-in-south-korea-travelled-to-china-1.3091050?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>MERS suspect case in South Korea travelled to China
Director of Korea's Centers for Disease Control 'deeply sorry' after man broke voluntary quarantine
Thomson Reuters Posted: May 28, 2015 12:44 PM ET Last Updated: May 28, 2015 12:44 PM ET
Related Stories
(Note: CBC does not endorse and is not responsible for the content of external links.)
A rise in MERS cases has stirred alarm in South Korea. (Kim Ju-sung/Yonhap/Associated Press)
South Korea's tally of patients of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) rose to seven on Thursday, with authorities saying one suspected victim skipped out of voluntary home quarantine to take a trip to China.
A rise in MERS cases has stirred alarm in South Korea, with health authorities being criticised for not moving quickly and effectively enough to quarantine suspected patients.
Two new victims are believed to have caught the virus from the first case confirmed last week, a 68-year-old man who had travelled to Bahrain in April and May, and returned to South Korea via Qatar.
MERS primer: what you need to know
The Health Ministry said the son of the second confirmed victim in the outbreak, who was himself being observed for possible infection, broke voluntary home quarantine and left South Korea on Tuesday for China.
"We should have checked more actively and broadly on family related issues. We are deeply sorry about that," Yang Byung-kook, director of the Korea Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, told reporters.
Chinese state broadcaster CCTV said that authorities in Guangdong province found the Korean man on Thursday and isolated him in a hospital for treatment. They also isolated 35 people who had come in close contact with him, though none has yet to show symptoms.
The man had not exhibited symptoms other than a fever and had not been confirmed as a MERS case.
First identified in humans in 2012, MERS is caused by a coronavirus from the same family as the one that triggered China's deadly 2013 outbreak of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome. There is no cure or vaccine.
Last week, South Korea's Health Ministry said there were 1,142 cases of MERS in 23 countries and 465 deaths had been reported by May 16. Of the total, 1,117 were in the Middle East.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
