<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks extended </title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iran-nuclear-talks-will-continue-through-friday-u-s-says-1.3140994?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks continue past Tuesday deadline
'More concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock,' U.S. spokeswoman says
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 07, 2015 8:50 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 9:25 AM ET
The deal under discussion between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy. (Carlos Barria/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Iran says nuclear deal could lead to co-operation in fight against extremism
Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a UNarms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," EU foreign policy chiefFedericaMogherinisaid outside the hotel where the talks between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States are taking place.
How an Iranian nuclear deal could reshape the Middle East
The spokeswoman for the U.S. delegation, MarieHarf, said the terms of an interim deal between Iran and the six would be extended through Friday to give negotiators a few more days to finish their work.
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time,"Harfsaid. "That is why we are continuing to negotiate."
Iranians await what could be "transformative" news from nuclear talks
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said there was "every reason" to believe a deal would be done within "a few days,"and that there was an "understanding" that most of the current sanctions against Iran would be lifted.
"There is only one big problem in terms of sanctions  it is the problem of a weapons embargo," he told journalists, according to the news agency Interfax.
He said it was important to reach agreement on this as soon as possible, telling journalists that "ending the bans on supplies to Iran of the weapons required to fight terrorism is a very, very relevant objective."
It is the fourth time the parties have extended the terms of the interim deal, which was struck in November 2013 and provided Iran with limited sanctions relief in exchange for a halt to the production of uranium enriched to a purity level of 20 percent.
2nd deadline passed
The comprehensive deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from economic sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalize the agreement," Mogherini said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve.
Among these, officials said, are Iranian demands for a UNarms embargo and ballistic missiles sanctions to be lifted, the timing of U.S. and EU sanctions relief, and disagreements over future Iranian nuclear research and development.
"We have entered the most difficult, but also the most real, part of the negotiations," Mogherini added.
"We knew it would be difficult, challenging and sometimes hard and some things get tense and others we make progress."
She said foreign ministers now in Vienna might come and go.
"Don't get too excited if you see ministers leaving. They might come back. They will come back. And it doesn't mean that we are stopping the work we are doing inside. On the contrary, on the contrary."
Easing decades of hostility
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius confirmed that he would leave, and return to Vienna on Wednesday night.
The United States and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear programme as a cover to develop a nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its programme is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the United States and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal would also reduce the chances of a U.S. military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington refuses to rule out, and of a wider regional war.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in eurozone as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-pm-alexis-tsipras-heads-to-brussels-meeting-with-financial-future-at-stake-1.3140890?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greek PM Alexis Tsipras heads to Brussels meeting with financial future at stake
18 eurozone leaders taking hardline approach to new proposals from Greece
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 07, 2015 3:39 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 7:05 AM ET
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras will bring new proposals for his country's future to a eurozone meeting Tuesday.  (Petros Karadjias/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Greece crisis: The sticking points that scuppered bailout talks
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is expected to present new proposals to an emergency eurozone summit on Tuesday, under pressure from European leaders to come up with credible ideas as his country's banks face potential meltdown.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must persuade the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to open negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
How Greece moves forward after the No vote
But Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labour reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the eurozone."
Greeks face further economic hardship, as banks will remain closed until later this week and limits on cash withdrawals remain in place. (Christopher Furlong/Getty Images)
He did not name names but may have been referring to German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his skepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the eurozone's economic output and population.
Concessions unclear
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the eurozone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 per cent No vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
"They [creditors] wanted a 'Yes' to prevail so they could humiliate the Greek prime minister, to go weakened, under these conditions of funding asphyxiation, and be a pushover. That didn't happen," Labour Minister Panos Skourletis told Antenna TV.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
But he gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply sceptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
His proposals were not expected to go much beyond a letter he sent to eurozone partners last week, acccepting most of the terms of a creditors' offer that was no longer on the table, but still seeking some loopholes for social or coalition reasons.
Confrontational approach criticized
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the eurozone.
Juncker told EU lawmakers in Strasbourg he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened but he chided the Greeks for their confrontational approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," said the EU's chief executive, who was heckled by leftists and Eurosceptics when he said Greeks hadn't been properly informed about what they were voting on.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Euclid Tsakalotos, seen Monday, is the new Greece finance minister, taking over from the oft-criticized Yanis Varoufakis. (Petr David Josek/The Associated Press)
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the centre-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras' games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
Greek newspapers said the proposals would be based on ideas that Juncker put forward at the end of June with a few tweaks and would not differ much from the last plans presented by Athens itself last week.
ANALYSIS I In rejecting austerity, Greek voters force Germany's hand
Euro zone national officials were irritated that Juncker had gone beyond the agreed negotiating mandate of the three creditor institutions in his last-ditch diplomacy, and it is not clear that they will be more receptive to his ideas now.
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favour a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they have to present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek newspapers reported the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 per cent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and protect defence spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines".
Follow the CBC News live blog for breaking news on the future of Greece:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:40:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'We will never be cowed': U.K. commemorates 10th anniversary of London bombings</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/7-7-bombings-britain-honours-victims-on-10th-annivesary-of-transit-attacks-1.3140897?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>David Cameron and Barack Obama agree to right 'poisonous ideology' at home
Prime Minister David Cameron led sombre tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.
Relatives of the victims, survivors, and senior politicians gathered to remember those killed in the July 7, 2005 bombings with emotions still raw after a massacre in Tunisia last month, Britain's worst loss of life in a militant assault since London.
"Today the country comes together to remember the victims of one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain," Cameron said in a statement.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly - the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
George Psaradakis, second from the left, driver of the double decker bus that was targeted by bomber Hasib Hussain in 2005, bows his head during a remembrance ceremony on Tuesday. (Peter Macdiarmid/Getty Images)
In the early hours of July 7 a decade ago, four young British Muslims travelled down to London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus during the morning rush-hour.
Inspired by al-Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others. Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
Cameron and London mayor Boris Johnson stood silently, heads bowed, before laying a wreath at the 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park. They will later join other senior figures, victims' families, survivors and members of the emergency services caught up in the bombings for a service of remembrance at St Paul's Cathedral.
This will include a national minute of silence, which comes just four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
Prince William to attend ceremony
A further service will be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives which Prince William, Queen Elizabeth's grandson, will attend.
Esther Hyman, 46, whose sister Miriam was killed on the Number 30 bus when it was blown up at Tavistock Square, told Reuters many young people seemed unaware of the bombings.
"The events of 7/7 do seem to have slipped out of public consciousness," said Hyman, who with her mother last week launched an educational programme to help teach school pupils about the attacks and to steer them away from violent extremism.
"It's worth remembering an event like 7/7 and learning lessons from it so that it didn't happen in vain."
A memorial plaque is attached to railings in Tavistock Square, in memory of those who lost their lives on a number 30 double-decker bus during the 7/7 attack. (Peter Nicholls/Reuters)
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe", meaning a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) fighters and Britons who have joined them.
Andrew Parker, head of Britain's domestic spy agency MI5, said only a "tiny fraction of the population" posed a threat.
"But the continuing fact that some people, born in the UK, with all the opportunities and freedoms that modern Britain offers, can nonetheless make those sorts of warped choices presents a serious societal and security challenge," Parker said in a rare public statement.
The government plans new measures to counter extremism and Mark Rowley, Britain's most senior counter-terrorism police officer, said the country was better prepared than 10 years ago, although the threat itself had morphed.
He said ISIS was creating an "enormous" list of potential targets, focused on propaganda value.
Members of the public and grounds staff and Wimbledon tennis fans observe a minute of silence to mark the 10th anniversary of the London bombings, at All England Lawn Tennis Club. (Sean Dempsey/EPA)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:33:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al-Shabaab claims responsibility for north Kenya attack that kills 14</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/kenya-attack-claimed-by-al-shabaab-leaves-at-least-14-dead-1.3140968?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Al-Shabaab attack leaves at least 147 dead at Kenyan university as siege ends
At least 14 people were killed in an attack early Tuesday in the country's north by al-Shabaab, Islamic extremist rebels from neighbouring Somalia, a Kenyan official said.
Eleven people were also wounded in the attack which took place in Soko Mbuzi village in Mandera County near Kenya's border with Somalia, said Mandera County Commissioner Alex Nkoyo.
The Somali-based militants, who are allied to al-Qaeda, have killed at least 85 people, all of them non-Muslims, in Mandera County in the last eight months.
Al-Shabab has vowed to carry out attacks in Kenya as retribution for the country sending troops to Somalia to fight the militants. Kenya sent its troops to Somalia in October 2011 following a series of cross-border attacks including kidnappings which the government blamed on al-Shabaab.
The Somali government, supported by the U.N. and backed by troops from African Union countries including Kenya, has pushed al-Shabaab out of Somalia's major cities but the rebels still control some rural areas and carry out bombings and attacks on the capital, Mogadishu, and attacks on Kenyan targets.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:45:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World's oldest man dies in Japan at 112</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/sakari-momoi-world-s-oldest-man-dead-at-112-1.3140855?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Sakari Momoi, world's oldest man, dead at 112
Momoi born in Fukushima in 1903
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 06, 2015 11:45 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 2:16 AM ET
Momoi, formerly Japan's oldest man, became the world's oldest at age 111 after Alexander Imich, also 111, died in New York on June 8, 2014. (Kyodo/Reuters)
Related Stories
Bowhead whales' genome may offer clues to aging gracefully
Sakari Momoi, who was recognised as the world's oldest man and credited healthy eating and getting plenty of sleep for his longevity, has died at the age of 112, Japanese media said on Tuesday.
Momoi was born in an area of Fukushima hit hard by the tsunami and nuclear meltdowns of four years ago in February 1903 the year the teddy bear was introduced and Orville Wright carried out the first powered, heavier-than-air flight.
Bowhead whalegenome may offer clues to aging gracefully
Named the world's oldest man in August 2014, Momoi, a former teacher who spent his days practicing calligraphy and taking part in recreational activities at the hospital where he lived, donned a suit and tie for a ceremony to receive a plaque from Guinness World Records.
"I want to live two more years," he said at the time.
The world's oldest man is now likely to be Japanese Yasutaro Koide, born in March 1903, a little over a month younger than Momoi. U.S. resident Susannah Mushatt Jones, 116, is the world's oldest person.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:08:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ice cave collapse kills 1, injures 3 in Washington state</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/big-four-ice-caves-collapse-kills-1-injures-3-in-washington-1.3140882?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Big Four Ice Caves collapse kills 1, injures 3 in Washington
Officials warned in May that caves were unsafe due to warm spring temperatures
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 07, 2015 2:08 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 2:08 AM ET
In this July 2010 photo, visitors examine the Big Four Ice Caves in the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest near Granite Falls, Wash. (Mark Mulligan/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Midland Ice Caves drawing hundreds to natural phenomenon
One person died and three were injured on Monday in the partial collapse of an ice cave in Washington state that U.S. Forest Service officials had warned was too dangerous for exploration due to unseasonably warm weather.
A spokeswoman from the Snohomish County Sheriff's Office said the three injured people were airlifted from the Big Four Ice Caves near Granite Falls, 40 miles north of Seattle, to nearby hospitals with serious injuries.
PHOTOS| A rare look inside Apostle Islands ice caves
The person who died has not been identified. The Seattle Times reported the individual's body remained buried under debris.
Rescue teams were still determining how many hikers were in the cave when it gave way. The collapse occurred near the entrance, officials said.
The caves are home to a popular hiking trail and are part of the Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest.
In May, the U.S. Forest Service warned hikers against entering the Big Four Ice Caves after several sections collapsed in unusually warm spring temperatures.
"The cave is in a condition that we would normally not see until at least September - large, inviting and collapsing," Lead Field Ranger Matthew Riggen said.
The area around the caves will be closed indefinitely, the sheriff's office said.
Falling ice has long been a danger to hikers in the region during warmer months, officials said. In 2010, an 11-year-old girl was killed near the caves when she was struck by a chunk of ice, forest officials said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Greece moves forward after the No vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-financial-crisis-how-the-country-moves-forward-after-the-no-vote-1.3140130?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Now, Greece still must deal with a financial crisis that includes adebt to Europe of over 320 billion, andthe need, according to the IMF, of at least another 60 billion more forrelief.
A sign of compromise?
Despite thestrong mandate the results gaveGreekPrime Minister AlexisTsipras, who had urged his citizens to vote No,the Greek leader signalled he may be willing to compromise with the Europeanswith the resignation of former finance minister Yanis Varoufakis. Varoufakis, an inflammatory figure,had suggested the European leaders were financial terrorists because of their demands.
But first things first. The banks.
But the most immediate threat facing Greece is the insolvency of its banking system, which is near collapse. Basically, it's almost out of cash. This has meant closed branches,long lineups at ATMs and a daily rationing of 60 per person.
"The first thing they need to decide iswhether they keep propping up the Greek banks whilethe Europeanleaders negotiate Greece's debt," said EvanDudley, anassistant professor atQueen's University School of Business.
"It's a tough decision because the Europeanleaders and the EuropeanCentral Bank havetakena tough stance up to the referendum. If they cave here and say they willsupport the banking system so we can promote furtherre-negotiations, then it kind of undermines that tough stand."
Some suggestthat July 20will be the day of reckoning, as that's the day Greece owes the ECB a 3.5 billion payment. It's at this point the ECB could cut off the flow of money, forcing Greece out of the eurozone.
On Monday, theECBsaidit was keeping the level of emergency credit to Greek banks unchanged.But Ian Lee, an assistant professor atCarletonUniversity'sSprottSchool of Business, said he believes the ECB will continue to give some money to Greece, while keeping it "on a very, very short leash."
"I think what they will probably do is keep the money trickling in just to keep the banks alive while the [European leaders]decidewhat the larger overall package is going to be."
Goodbye eurozone, hello drachma?
With thevery real chance that Greece may abandon (or be pushed out of)the eurozone altogether, this would mean the return ofits own currency.TheNovote has putpressure on Greeceto take control of its own money supply andgoingback to the drachma could solve some of those problems, Dudley said.
"They'd say, 'OK, we don'tneed the ECB, we'll meetall depositrequests, We can pay everythingout indrachmas instead of euros, All the currency transactions in Greece could be rewritten in drachmas. At the end of the day, Greece would be in full control, monetarily, of what's goingon initscountry." he said.
But that would come with its own set of complications. Greek businesses reliant on imports would now deal withsuppliers who wouldn'twant to be paid in drachmas. Goods cominginto the county would face hugeinflationary price increases. And contracts betweenGreek businesses, based on euros,would have to be renegotiated.
"It would be very difficult and chaotic in the short run. In the long runit would probably be best," Dudley said.
Market impact
While the markets fell following the referendum vote, it wasn't nearly as dramatic as some had feared.
"The stock exchangewill hurt for the next few days. Italways goes down when there's bad news, uncertainty and right nowthere's alot of uncertainty and bad news in Greece," Lee said."Then they'll come back up when the world is not coming to an end."
Europe prepared?
Europe is much better prepared than it was in 2012 when Greece was going to default, before a last-minute bailout package was agreed upon. In part, the country has been ring fenced, meaningthat measures have been put in place to protect other countriesfrom the possibilityof financialcontagion.
For example, Dudley said,the ECB has said it will not let the euro currency fall, at any cost, eliminating fears the currencycould collapse
Little effecton Canada
The Canadian economy is pretty much isolated from the Greek economy, with neither country engaging in a lot of trade with the other.
However,Canadian importers of olive oil, sea salt, preserved vegetables and other delicacies from Greece say they'vebeen stockpiling goods in their warehouses in anticipation that theeconomic turmoil overseas will get worse.
With files from The Associated Press and The Canadian Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:35:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bull-running festival takes off in Spain</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/photos/bull-running-festival-takes-off-in-spain-1.3139777?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Bull-running festival takes off in Spain
San Fermin Fiesta in Pamplona runs July 6-14
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:53:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barack Obama says ISIS will be defeated by ideas, not guns</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/barack-obama-says-isis-will-be-defeated-by-ideas-not-guns-1.3140231?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Barack Obama says ISIS will be defeated by ideas, not guns
U.S. president meets with Pentagon officials following weekend airstrikes in eastern Syria
CBC News Posted: Jul 06, 2015 3:53 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 5:47 PM ET
U.S. President Barack Obama, left, delivered remarks after a briefing on U.S. efforts against the Islamic State (ISIS), at the Pentagon in Arlington on Monday. He called the conflict a "generational struggle," one that will be defeated better through ideology than with guns. (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Related Stories
Barack Obama's string of political successes starts the legacy talk again
The complex threat of theISIS extremist group will not be ultimatelydefeated by guns but through ideology, BarackObamasays.
The U.S. president made theremarks Monday on the military campaign against the Islamic State group after being briefed by Pentagon officials earlier in the day.
He called for co-operation among countries in a fight he said spills over borders. Obama will look to partner with Muslim communities that he said are often the target of ISIS attacks.
"The battle for hearts and minds is going to be a generational struggle," he said.
Obama'slegacy: will string of successes leave positive impression?
Obamahas insisted he will not send U.S. troops into ground combat to fight the Islamic State in Iraq or Syria. However, he has acknowledged that the U.S. lacks a "complete strategy" for training Iraqi troops to carry out ground missions. He identified local authorities in targeted communities as essential to any kind of resolution.
"If [the U.S. military tries]to do everything ourselves, we'll be playing whack-a-mole," Obama said.
Republicans accused of obstructing
The president's meetings with top Pentagon officials and other national security advisersfollow a wave of weekend airstrikes by the U.S.-led coalition in eastern Syria. The coalition says it was one of the most sustained aerial operations carried out in Syria to date. Obamanoted that the total number of airstrikesduring thedeployment has surpassed 5,000.
Efforts to train Syrian rebels are also sputtering. Fewer than 100 rebels are being trained by the U.S., far fewer than the goal of producing 5,400 fighters a year.
Obamaacknowledged that the nationless ISIS group has been using technology to solicit Islamists around the world, some of whom end up launching attacks abroad,without military backing. He saidthe U.S. will continue to examine "what's working and what [the U.S.] can do better."
"The threat of lone wolves is complex. The small cells are becoming harder to detect," Obama said.
Ahead of the president's meetings, the White House sharply criticized U.S. Senate Republicans for failing to confirm Adam Szubin, Obama's nominee to be the Treasury undersecretary responsible for choking off funding to groups like ISIS.
White House spokesman Josh Earnest said Republicans had refused to "even give him the time of day for a hearing" since Obama nominated Szubin in April, adding that the Senate should confirm him before legislators go home for their annual August recess.
"It's time for Republicans in the Senate to do their jobs for a change," Earnest said.
Obama said that Szubin's appointment would significantly contribute to improvedforeign affairs.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:30:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston Marathon bomber seeks new trial after receiving death sentence</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/dzhokhar-tsarnaev-boston-marathon-bomber-seeks-new-trial-1.3140329?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, Boston Marathon bomber, seeks new trial
21-year-old was convicted of 30 charges in the bombings, and sentenced to death
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 06, 2015 5:30 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 7:46 PM ET
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev filed a motion for a new trial Monday, less than two weeks after being sentenced to death. The motion did not contain details regarding arguments the defence plans to use. (Jane Flavell/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Boston Marathon bombing timeline
Tsarnaev's lawyers filed a preliminary motion for a new trial Monday after his conviction and death sentence. The motion did not contain any details on what grounds they plan to argue, saying only that a new trial is "required in the interests of justice."
The 21-year-old Tsarnaev was convicted of 30 charges in the bombings, which killed three people and injured more than 260. The same jury that determined his guilt recommended the death penalty, and a federal judge on June 24 sentenced him to death.
Tsarnaev's lawyers call the motion a "placeholder" until they can file a more detailed motion next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:48:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>American Apparel to close stores, lay off workers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/american-apparel-to-close-stores-lay-off-workers-1.3140256?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>American Apparel to close stores, lay off workers
Cost-cutting measures will save U.S. retailer $30M over next 18 months
CBC News Posted: Jul 06, 2015 3:48 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 4:21 PM ET
American Apparel has lost $300 million since 2010 and its stock price has plummeted from a high of $15 in 2007 to less than a dollar. (Associated Press)
Related Stories
Dov Charney, Montreal-born founder of American Apparel, officially sacked
American Apparel plans to shutter some stores and lay off some of its staffas part of the next phase of its strategic turnaround, butwarns there's still a chance it will run out of money.
The U.S. retailer expects the new cost-cutting measures will save $30 million over the next 18 months. It did not say how many of its 239stores or 10,000 employees would be affected, but said the cuts were necessary in today's highly competitive and promotional retail environment.
In a statement, the company said "even ifAmerican Apparelincreases revenue and cuts costs, there can be no guarantee that the company will have sufficient financing commitments to meet funding requirements for the next 12 months."
"We are committed to turning this company around," said Paula Schneider, the newly appointed CEO. "Our primary focus is on improving the processes and product mix that have led to steep losses over the past five years."
American Apparel has accumulated more than $300 million in losses since 2010, mostly under the leadership of the retailer's controversial founder and former CEO Dov Charney, who was born in Montreal. He was ousted from the role last year amid allegations of sexual misconduct and misuse of funds.
In Monday's statement, the company said it also needs the extra cashto defend itself against approximately 20 lawsuits and administrative actions initiated by Charney.
The company added it will, for the first time, unveila new fallline, and announced the appointment of twoexecutives in its retail and wholesale divisionsto help with the turnaround.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:49:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Caitlyn Jenner's 1984 Olympic Torch to hit auction block</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/caitlyn-jenner-s-1984-olympic-torch-to-hit-auction-block-1.3140878?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Caitlyn Jenner's 1984 Olympic Torch to hit auction block
Piece of Olympic memorabilia could fetch as much as $20K
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 07, 2015 1:49 AM ET Last Updated: Jul 07, 2015 1:49 AM ET
Related Stories
Bruce Jenner tells Diane Sawyer he's 'a woman for all intents and purposes'
The 1984 Summer Olympic Torch that CaitlynJennercarried through Lake Tahoe, Nev., is going on the auction block where it could fetch $20,000 or more.
It's the first major piece of Jenner memorabilia to go to auction since the winner of the 1976 Olympic Decathlon Gold Medal, formerly known as Bruce,became Caitlyn.
The 61 centimetretorch, featuring a brass finish and leather handle, is being offered by Heritage Auctions at its Platinum Night Sports Auction in Chicago on July 30. The seller is Bob Lorsch, a Los Angeles philanthropist and entrepreneur who orchestrated the Tahoe leg of the torch relay and secured Jenner's participation.
Winnipeg transgender woman calls Jenner a role model
"This torch serves as a wonderful symbol that masculinity and femininity are not mutually exclusive," said Chris Ivy, Heritage's director of sports auctions. "The decathlon has long been considered the ultimate athletic proving ground. Jenner has played both gender roles masterfully."
The torch is the first significant piece of Jenner memorabilia to go to auction since the winner of the 1976 Olympic Decathlon Gold Medal became Caitlyn Jenner. (Heritage Auctions/AP)
Jenner was approached to carry the torch as part of the Los Angles Summer Olympic Games to help support Caesars Tahoe's agenda of giving back to the local community and promoting area youth programs, said Lorsch. The hotel casino held a drawing for a chance to win a place in the relay and sponsored 50 kilometresof the Nevada route. Seven went to individuals and 42 to local organizations. Jenner was asked to run the remaining kilometre.
"Caesars saw it as a tremendous opportunity ... to do something more special, never realizing that we would be creating what is truly a piece of history that originated as a piece of sports history, then evolved as a piece of entertainment history through the Kardashian legacy and becoming a cultural phenomenon through the transition to Caitlyn," said Lorsch.
"Other than trinkets and signed memorabilia, this is the first piece of what I would consider significant Jenner memorabilia to reach the auction block," said Ivy.
Better known to a younger generation as the patriarch on Keeping up With the Kardashians,Jenner, 65, announced earlier this year that he was transitioning to become a woman. Vanity Fair ran glamour photos of him as Caitlyn.
A spokesman for Jenner didn't respond to a request for comment.
Caitlyn Jenner will receive the Arthur Ashe Courage Award at the upcoming ESPY Awards on July 15 for her bravery for publicly coming out as a transgender woman.
An E! Entertainment network documentary series I Am Cait,depicting Jenner's transition from a man to a woman, will debut July 26.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:51:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hollywood producer Jerry Weintraub dies at 77</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/arts/jerry-weintraub-legendary-producer-dead-at-77-1.3140567?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Jerry Weintraub, legendary producer, dead at 77
Larry King, Arnold Schwarzenegger and others pay tribute to 3-time Emmy winner
CBC News Posted: Jul 06, 2015 10:51 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 10:59 PM ET
Film and TV producer Jerry Weintraub died Monday. The three-time Emmy winner is best known for his involvement with the Karate Kid and Ocean's Eleven franchises. (Danny Moloshok/Reuters)
Jerry Weintraub, the dynamic film producer and music manager who pushed the career of John Denver and produced such hit movies as Nashvilleand Ocean's Eleven,has died. He was 77.
Weintraub's representatives say he died Monday of cardiac arrest in Santa Barbara, Calif.
Weintraub became a top concert promoter in the 1970s, working with the likes of Elvis Presley and shaping John Denver's career. He then tackled the movie business and produced such films as Oh, God!;Diner;the remake of Ocean's Eleven and its sequels;and The Karate Kidand its sequels.
Though Weintraub's attempt to found his own studio, Weintraub Entertainment Group,ended in bankruptcy in 1990, his success as an independent producer spanned decades, including 2013's Emmy-winningBehind the Candelabra, a TV drama about Liberace.
He died with numerous projects in development, including the recently debuted HBO series The Brinkand an upcoming remake of Tarzan.
Weintraubwas also a close friend of former U.S. president George H.W. Bush.
"Jerry was an American original who earned his success by the sheer force of his instinct, driveand larger-than-life personality," Bush said Monday. "He had a passion for life, and throughout the ups and downs of his prolific career, it was clear just how much he loved show business."
So sad at loss of Jerry Weintraub, you were 1 of a kind, my friend. Last of a breed. So glad I got to be "that kid" pic.twitter.com/ebN7p8ptUL
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:19:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>20 riders fall in massive crash at Tour de France</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/sports/tour-de-france-20-riders-fall-in-massive-crash-1.3140094?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tour de France: 20 riders fall in massive crash
Spanish veteran Joaquim Rodriguez wins 3rd stage
The Associated Press Posted: Jul 06, 2015 2:19 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 2:19 PM ET
Big crash at Tour de France 1:51
Spanish veteran Joaquim Rodriguez won the crash-marred third stage of the Tour de France on Monday, with British rider Chris Froome finishing second to take the race leader's yellow jersey.
The crash happened with a little under 60 kilometres (37 miles) remaining, forcing the stage to be neutralized and then stopped altogether shortly after  for nearly 20 minutes  while organizers allowed those who fell to catch up.
With the race moving from neighbouring Netherlands into Belgium, stage three was 159.5 kilometres (99 miles) from Antwerp to Huy.
It featured four short and sharp climbs but the crash took place before any of these when Frenchman William Bonnet went down and several riders tumbled around him.
All of the main Tour contenders avoided the crash, unlike Fabian Cancellara, who started the day in the yellow jersey and ended it in agony after being one of some 20 riders who fell.
After taking chunks of time out of his Tour rivals Vincenzo Nibali and Nairo Quintana on Sunday's rain-soaked and wind-battered second stage, Froome did it again as he accelerated in the last climb. He almost caught up Rodriguez, but the Spanish rider held on with Froome closing in on him.
"It's never too early to take the yellow jersey," Froome said. "Really happy to come second and put more time on my GC (general classification) contenders. I was in front (of the crash) and just heard it about it on the radio."
Rodriguez and Froome clocked the same time of 3 hours, 26 minutes, 54 seconds. Frenchman Alexis Vuillermoz was third, four seconds behind them.
Froome, the 2013 Tour champion, leads German rider Tony Martin by just one second and is 13 seconds ahead of American rider Tejay Van Garderen.
The day's final two climbs  1.3 kilometres (0.8 miles)  up Cote de Cherave and the famed Mur de Huy featured on this year's Fleche Wallonne (Walloon Arrow) classic. That prompted Froome to ride the Wallonne this year, where he crashed toward the end.
He had better luck this time, gaining 11 seconds on Nibali and Quintana and 18 seconds on two-time Tour champion Contador.
"I lost quite a lot of time. I said before the stage that stages like this are often difficult," Contador said. "It was very hard in the end and I was lacking something. Froome is very strong and he's come here in good form."
Major impact
Monday's heavy crash took its toll.
Cancellara was one of the last to go down, leaping into the air with his bike attached to him, then landing with a thud  luckily on the grass  and skidding on his side. Escaping with a few cuts and bruises, Cancellara got back on his bike.
But others were not so lucky.
Bonnet was taken off on a stretcher with a brace around his neck. Dutch rider Tom Dumoulin  competing for the best young rider's white jersey  Australian veteran Simon Gerrans, and Russian Dmitry Kozontchuk also withdrew from the race.
During Sunday's trek along the Dutch coastline, time gaps were made when heavy side winds caused a split in the front of the peloton.
This time, the weather was not to blame.
Bonnet lost control and his bike slid forward and down.
The end result was a tangled mess of bikes, spewed in all directions on the side of the road, while some riders lay on their backs in the grass and others were curled up in agony on the hot tarmac.
The stage re-started for good at the top of the first climb, meaning there were about 50 kilometres (31 miles) remaining.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:53:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Carolina senate advances bill to remove Confederate flag from capitol</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/south-carolina-senate-advances-bill-to-remove-confederate-flag-1.3140422?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>South Carolina senate advances bill to remove Confederate flag
Controversial bill passes a crucial 2nd reading by a 37-3 vote
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jul 06, 2015 4:53 PM ET Last Updated: Jul 06, 2015 6:38 PM ET
Robert Hayes, left, calls Tom Clements, right, a 'scallywag' as lawmakers vote on removing the Confederate flag from outside the South Carolina Statehouse in Columbia. Hayes is from Abbeville, S.C., and describes his hometown as 'The cradle and the grave of the Confederacy.' (Sean Rayford/Getty Images )
Related Stories
Obama eulogizes Charleston shooting victim Rev. Clementa Pinckney, sings Amazing Grace
South Carolina lawmakers took a step on Monday toward removing the Confederate battle flag that flies at the state house in Columbia, long denounced as a symbol of slavery by critics.
A bill to banish the flag from a Civil War memorial on the capitol grounds to a museum passed a crucial second reading in the state senate by an overwhelming vote of 37-3 after an emotional debate.
It faces a final reading on Tuesday before it is taken up by the lower House of Representatives.
Numerous elected officials, including Republican Gov.Nikki Haley, called for the flag's removal after the June 17 killings of nine African-American churchgoers during Bible study at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church in Charleston.
Charleston church shooting: Hate crime, gun crime? Does it matter?
Photos of the white man charged in the shootings showed him posing with the flag on a website that also carried a racist manifesto.
Among the victims was the church's pastor, Rev.Clementa Pinckney, who was also a state senator, and his senate desk was draped in black for Monday's debate.
The flag's defenders argue it is part of South Carolina's heritage, representing those who fought and died for the rebelling southern states in the Civil War.
A South Carolina state trooper stands at the bottom of a Confederate flag at the base of a confederate memorial in front of the South Carolina State House in Columbia, S.C. Republican Gov. Nikki Haley has called for the flag's removal. (Tami Chappell/Reuters )
They also worry that bringing down the flag, which has flown for more than 50 years at the capitol, could lead to calls for removing symbols from other monuments and changing street and place names honouring Confederate leaders.
The legislation appears to have a good chance of success and could be approved as early as Thursday. Haley has said she will have the flag removed immediately if the law is passed.
A recent poll by Charleston's Post and Courier newspaper showed it enjoys the support of a two-thirds majority in both houses as required under state law.
Several senators on Monday spoke of being moved and inspired by the Christian forgiveness displayed by relatives of the Emanuel ninefor the shooter, adding that removal of the flag was the proper way to honour them.
"If they could be peacemakers in those dire circumstances ... I determined I can be a peacemaker when it comes to a flag flying on our State House grounds," said Senator Chip Campsen, a Republican who represents Charleston.
Some senators argue flag should stay
At least three senators spoke in favour of keeping the flag flying.
"I do understand that what happened in Charleston got a lot of people's attention," said Republican Senator Lee Bright, who is white. "But I believe we're placing the blame of what one deranged lunatic did on people that hold their southern heritage high and I don't think that's fair."
Confederate flag: 10facts about the controversial symbol
Democrat Vincent Sheheen, who is white and introduced the bill, noted that he was mocked by politicians a year ago when he introduced similar legislation. He said the Charleston murders were a reminder that a racist cultural divide still existed in the state.
Removing the flag was "one small thing that we can do" to heal that divide, he said.
While some white people might have emotional ties to the Confederate flag, Senator Darrell Jackson, a black Democrat, reminded legislators that the descendants of slaves look at it differently.
"When I see a Confederate soldier, I don't get goosebumps and get all warm and fuzzy," he said. "All I'm saying is you can't force all of us to have the passion that some of you have about certain things."
The Confederate flag was raised atop the State House dome in 1961 as part of centennial commemorations of the Civil War. Critics said its placement was a sign of opposition by politicians to the black civil rights movement at the time.
In 2000, after the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People announced an economic boycott of South Carolina and protesters marched on the state capital, lawmakers agreed to a compromise, moving the flag to a monument to Confederate war dead on the capitol grounds.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
