<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbc">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank will maintain emergency credit to Greek banks</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/greek-banks-granted-cash-flow-reprieve-amid-emergency-debt-talks-1.3131048?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Greek banks granted cash flow reprieve amid emergency debt talks
European Central Bank head urges eurozone countries to 'address fragilities'
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 28, 2015 9:25 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 28, 2015 9:30 AM ET
People line up outside a bank which normally operates on Saturday but remained closed, in central Athens.  (Thanassis Stavrakis/Associated Press)
Greece's future in balance 1:57
Related Stories
Greek crisis needs more than a Band-Aid solution: Don Pittis
The European Central Bank has announced it is maintaining emergency credit to Greek banks at its current level, a day after the country's parliament approved holding a referendum next week on whether to accept creditors' financial proposals in return for bailout loans.
Greek parliament approves referendum on bailout deal
The ECB's decision keeps a key financial lifeline open but does not provide further credit to Greece's banks, which are seeing deposits drain away as anxious Greeks withdraw savings.
The ECB had said it was considering tightening assistance to the banks, but on Sunday said it was stillworking closely with the Bank of Greece to maintain financial stability and added it could reconsider its decision on credit levels.
"We continue to work closely with the Bank of Greece and we strongly endorse the commitment of member states in pledging to take action to address the fragilities of euro-area economies," ECB head Mario Draghi said.
Historically speaking, Germany a bigger deadbeat than Greece
Worried Greeks continued lining up at ATM machines Sunday morning. While some machines were running out of cash, others were being replenished.
Tsipras' move for a national vote on July 5 startled and angered Greece's European partners and threw the country's bailout negotiations with international lenders into turmoil. Parliament approved the referendum call in a majority vote on Saturday.
But Greece's international bailout with its European creditors and the International Monetary Fund expires Tuesday, and Greece's European partners said they would not accept an extension of the bailout until Sunday's referendum.
With Greece also facing a 1.6 billion-euro debt repayment to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday  one it will struggle to meet without bailout funds  the developments have thrown Greece's financial future and its continued membership in the 19-nation shared euro currency into question.
Alternate Greek Finance Minister Nadia Valavani said the government was "expecting the funding of Greek banks to continue normally via the ELA after Tuesday."
Bank customers urged to remain calm
Valavani urged Greeks themselves to show restraint, telling private Mega television the country's banks could see "business as usual" next week if they receive the emergency support "so long as there is calm" and Greeks don't attempt to withdraw all their savings.
The ECB's emergency liquidity currently stands at just under 90 billion euros ($100 billion US), a financial lifeline that has been keeping the country's four major banks going. The ECB has been slowly increasing the amount of emergency credit which has been compensating for the increase in withdrawals from Greek banks.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls on Sunday urged Greece and other nations to do whatever they can to keep Greece in the 19-nation bloc that uses the euro currency.
"We don't know, none of us, the consequences of an exit from the eurozone, either on the political or economic front. We must do everything so that Greece stays in the eurozone,"Valls said on France's i-Tele TV.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:06:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suspect in French beheading sent selfie to Canadian cellphone, report says</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/france-beheading-attack-suspect-took-selfie-with-decapitated-victim-1.3130934?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia hotel attacker kills at least 28, mostly tourists
Jean-Christophe de Le Rue, a spokesman for Public Safety Minister Steven Blaney, did not confirm to CBC News that the image was sent to a Canadian number, but did say Canadian authorities are involved in the case.
"While I cannot comment on operational matters of national security, we are assisting the French authorities with their investigation," he said in an email statement.
He declined to comment further on details of the investigation.
Police found the head of Herve Cornara, manager of the transport firm that employed Salhi, attached to a fence at the plant owned by U.S. group Air Products, framed by black and white flags bearing Islamic slogans.
No claim of responsibility for attack
President Francois Hollande, dealing with new security fears six months after Islamist gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish deli, said the incident clearly amounted to a terrorist attack.
Salhi, whose wife and sister are also being detained along with a fourth person, is known to have associated with Islamists over more than a decade and had previously been flagged as a potential risk.
But there has so far been no claim of responsibility for the attack.
The attack occurred in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, in the Isre region between Lyon and Grenoble. (CBC)
Paris public prosecutor Francois Molins said on Friday that investigators would take time to piece together the sequence of events at the plant in Saint Quentin-Fallavier, 30 kilometressouth of Lyon, and establish whether Salhi was acting alone.
The body of Cornara, 54, also bore signs of strangulation suggesting that he may have been killed at an unknown location prior to his decapitation.
Investigators searching his home in Saint-Priest, near Lyon, seized a laptop, a tablet computer and a fake pistol but found no trace of explosives or radical propaganda.
"We don't know whether we're dealing with a fundamentalist who just lost it or a real terrorist," the source said.
3 attacks on same day
The latest attack in France occurred on the same day that a gunman killed 39 people at a Tunisian beachside hotel and an ISISsuicide bomber killed two dozen and wounded more than 200 at a mosque in Kuwait.
French authorities said there was no connection between the attacks and nothing to indicate that the industrial site had been targeted because of its U.S. ownership.
"There is no other link other than to say that terrorism is our common enemy," said Hollande said after rushing back to Paris from an EU summit in Brussels.
Unlike two of the gunmen behind the January attacks, Salhi does not have a criminal record. But the fact he was flagged as a risk between 2006 and 2008 and known to have since maintained radical Islamist links is raising new questions about the security services and their effectiveness.
With files from The Associated Press and CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:38:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia puts 1,000 extra police at tourist sites</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tunisia-beach-hotel-attack-extra-security-aimed-at-tourist-sector-1.3131024?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia's prime minister announced on Saturday a string of new security measures, including closing mosques accused of citing violence.
About 80 mosques accused of "spreading venom" will close within a week, Prime Minister Habib Essid said.
This image taken from a militant website associated with Islamic State extremists, posted on Saturday purports to show the Tunisian gunman, identified as Seifeddine Rezgui. (Associated Press)
Essid said additional army reservists would be deployed at tourist sites around the country and inside hotels, while he called on the hotels themselves to do more to enforce security.
He also said that political parties and associations espousing radical ideas with suspicious funding would be closed down, and he promised financial rewards for information leading to arrests related to the attack.
A day after the attack, ISIS posted a photo of the alleged gunman. Authorities have identified him as a Tunisian, 24-year-old Seifeddine Rezgui, from the town of Gaafour, 160 kilometres northeast of Sousse. After shooting vacationers along the beach, the gunman wandered into nearby streets, where police shot and killed him.
Britain's Foreign Office on Sunday updated its travel advice to Tunisia, urging vigilance and warning that further attacks against foreigners are possible.
Injured people are treated on the beach in Sousse after a man in his 20s opened fire with a Kalashnikov, killing sunbathers at the resort, following a call to violence by ISIS. (Jawhara FM/Associated Press)

The ministry warned against all travel to Tunisia's militarized southern zone, all travel anywhere within five kilometres of Tunisia's border with Libya and all travel to the country's Chaambi Mountain national park area. It also advised against all but essential travel to much of Tunisia's south and along its western border with Algeria.
The ministry said possible attacks could stem from "individuals who are unknown to the authorities and whose actions are inspired by terrorist groups via social media."
At least 15 Britons were among the 38 people killed at the Sousse beach resort.
With files from Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:42:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Major differences remain in Iran nuclear talks, U.K. says</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iran-nuclear-talks-require-give-and-take-says-u-k-foreign-secretary-1.3131035?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuclear talks require 'give and take,' says U.K. foreign secretary
Parties negotiating nuclear limits in exchange for easing sanctions
Thomson Reuters Posted: Jun 28, 2015 7:42 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 28, 2015 7:43 AM ET
Britain's Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said negotiators in Vienna still have 'major differences of interpretation' in detailing what was agreed to in April in the framework agreement. (Neil Hall/Reuters)
Related Stories
Wikileaks exposes reams of secret Saudi diplomatic files
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said on Sunday there were still major differences on a proposed nuclear deal between major powers and Iran and there would need to be concessions to reach an agreement.
"There a number of different areas where we still have major differences of interpretation in detailing what was agreed in (the) Lausanne (framework agreement)," Hammond told reporters on arrival in Vienna for the talks. He was referring to a framework deal agreed on April 2.
"There is going to have to be some give or take if we are to get this done in the next few days," he said, adding that there were red lines that could not be crossed. "No deal is better than a bad deal."
An accord to curb Iran's nuclear program remains elusive due to disagreements on fundamental issues, said Laurent Fabius, France's foreign minister in Vienna.
European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said on Sunday that a last-minute deal between Iran and world powers on Tehran's nuclear program was still possible.
"If all negotiating parties have strong political will in these last moments, we can make it," she said in a tweet from the negotiations in Vienna.
With the June 30 deadline looming, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry was meeting Sunday in Vienna with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, their third encounter since Saturday. Other foreign ministers are expected to join.
The goal of the talks involving Iran and the U.S., Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia is a deal that would crimp Tehran's capacity to make nuclear weapons in exchange for sanctions relief.
With files from The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:31:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nearly 500 injured as explosion, fire hits Taiwan water park party</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/taiwan-water-park-fire-injures-nearly-500-1.3130513?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan water park fire injures nearly 500
Fire set off by accidental explosion of an unknown powder
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 1:31 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 11:40 PM ET
About 1,000 people were gathered for a concert at the water park when the explosion went off near a performance stage. (Associated Press)
A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring nearly 500 people, including 141 in serious condition, authorities said.
The fire was sparked by an accidental explosion of an unknown powder near the stage in front of about 1,000 people, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Taiwan's Central News Agency on Sunday reported 474 have been injured, including 141 in serious condition. It quoted the New Taipei City health bureau. The injured included four mainland Chinese and two foreigners.
Witnesses said the fire spread quickly after the coloured powder was blown into the air. (Associated Press)
The fire erupted at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City near the island's capital and was quickly brought under control.
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
CNA reported witnesses as saying the fire spread quickly after the coloured powder was blown into the air.
It wasn't clear if the coloured powder was part of a performance. The cause of the fire is being investigated.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:47:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hunchbacked mutt Quasi Modo crowned World's Ugliest Dog</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/world-s-ugliest-dog-contest-crowns-hunchbacked-mutt-quasi-modo-1.3130675?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
World's Ugliest Dog contest crowns hunchbacked mutt Quasi Modo
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 3:47 PM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 7:50 PM ET
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix Quasi Modo and her owner took the $1,500 US prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that celebrates imperfection, organizers said. (Noah Berger/Associated Press)
Quasi Modo crowned World's Ugliest Dog 0:39
Related Stories
World's ugliest dog contest 2014
A 10-year-old mutt named Quasi Modo, whose spinal birth defects left her a bit hunchbacked, is the winner of this year's World's Ugliest Dog contest.
The pit bull-Dutch shepherd mix and her owner took the $1,500 US prize Friday night, besting 25 other dogs competing in the contest that celebratesimperfection, organizers said.
Quasi Modo was abandoned at an animal shelter before being adopted by a veterinarian in Loxahatchee, Fla., according to her biography posted on the contest's website.
"My appearance can be a little unsettling to some (I have had grown men jump on top of their cars to get away from me because they thought I was a hyena or Tasmanian devil) but once they get to know me I win them over with my bubbly personality," her biography said.
Sweepee Rambo, a 16-year-old Chinese Crested dog, won the runner-up award. (Noah Berger/Associated Press)
Two Chinese crested and Chihuahua mixes named Sweepee Rambo and Frodo took the second- and third-place prizes, respectively.
An 8-year-old Chihuahua named Precious received the "spirit award," honouring a dog and owner who have overcome obstacles or are providing service to the community. Precious, who is blind in one eye, is trained to monitor smells related to low blood sugar levels and alert her owner, a disabled veteran, of the problem, her biography said.
The contest, held at the Sonoma-Marin Fairgrounds in Petaluma, Calif., is in its 27th year.
The dogs are scored by a three-judge panel in several categories, including special or unusual attributes, personality and natural ugliness.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:09:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate flag removed by South Carolina protester</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/confederate-flag-removed-by-south-carolina-protester-1.3130425?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Confederate flag removed by South Carolina protester
Bree Newsome of Charlotte removes flag from front of statehouse
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 11:09 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 3:34 PM ET
Woman takes down Confederate flag 1:47
Related Stories
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
The Confederate flag was temporarily removed from the front of the South Carolina Statehouse on Saturday when a woman climbed the flagpole and  despite calls by police to get down  removed the banner.
BreeNewsome, 30, of Charlotte, N.C., was about halfway up the more than nine-metresteel flagpole just after dawn Saturday when officers of the South Carolina Bureau of Protective Services told her to get down. Instead, she continued climbing to the top and removed the banner.
She and a man who had climbed over a 1.2-metrewrought-iron fence to get to the flag were arrested.
The historical significance of Charleston's 'Mother Emanuel' church
The flag, which is protected by state law, was raised about 45 minutes later. Flag supporters planned a rally at the monument later on Saturday.
Sherri Iacobelli, a spokeswoman for the state Department of Public Safety, said that Newsome and James Ian Tyson, 30, also of Charlotte, have been charged with defacing monuments on state Capitol grounds. That's a misdemeanour that carries a fine of up to $5,000 US and a prison term of up to three years or both.
Bree Newsome of Charlotte, N.C., removes the Confederate battle flag at a Confederate monument at the statehouse. The flag was put back about 45 minutes later. (Bruce Smith/Associated Press)
A staff member at the Alvin Glenn Detention Center where the two were taken said she did not know if the two had attorneys. About the time of her arrest, Newsome released an email statement to the media.
'We can't wait any longer'
"We removed the flag today because we can't wait any longer. We can't continue like this another day," it said. "It's time for a new chapter where we are sincere about dismantling white supremacy and building toward true racial justice and equality."
Authorities said Newsome was from Raleigh. However, Mervyn Marcano, a spokesman for the small group of activists who worked together to take down the flag, said she had recently moved to Charlotte.
Tamika Lewis, another member of the group, said taking down the flag "was done because we were tired of waiting for the judicial system to make the decision they have been prolonging for a very long time."
Calls for removing the flag have been renewed since nine black churchgoers were killed in what police characterized as a racist attack at a Charleston, S.C.,church last week.
South Carolina lawmakers took the initial steps last Tuesday toward removing the Confederate battle flag from the Statehouse grounds by agreeing to allow discussion of the matter during the legislative session.
The agreement came a day after Republican Gov. Nikki Haley reversed course and called for the divisive symbol to come down. The flag has flown in front of the state Capitol for 15 years after being moved from atop the Statehouse dome.
The momentum in South Carolina sparked further calls from politicians across the state and country for flags and Confederate symbols to be removed from public displays in other states.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 20:46:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The week in pictures: From same-sex marriage in U.S. to Taylor Swift's battle with Apple</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/photos/the-week-in-pictures-from-same-sex-marriage-in-u-s-to-taylor-swift-s-battle-with-apple-1.3124496?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>The week in pictures: From same-sex marriage in U.S. to Taylor Swift's battle with Apple
Top images from around the world for June 20-26
Stay Connected with CBC News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:06:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hunt for escaped N.Y. prisoner David Sweat intensifies after Richard Matt shot dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/hunt-for-escaped-n-y-prisoner-david-sweat-intensifies-after-richard-matt-shot-dead-1.3130402?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Hunt for escaped N.Y. prisoner David Sweat intensifies after Richard Matt shot dead
Helicopters, search dogs and hundreds of law enforcement officers converge on wooded area
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 11:06 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 6:38 PM ET
Police hold a morning strategy meeting at the Titus Mountain Ski Area in the town of Malone, N.Y.,before heading out to search for escaped inmate David Sweat. (New York State Police/Facebook)
New York prisoner manhunt 5:44
Related Stories
New York prison escape: Husband talks about threats from inmates
The shooting death of one escaped killer brought new energy to a weeks-long hunt for a second escaped murderer as helicopters, search dogs and hundreds of law enforcement officers converged on a wooded area 50 kilometres from the prison in Upstate New York.
Richard Matt, escaped N.Y. prisoner, shot dead
"Of course our preference would always be to capture them alive," New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico told a news conference as he announced late Friday the killing hours earlier of Richard Matt, one of two escaped killers from an upstate maximum-security prison.
New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico, left, and Gov. Andrew Cuomo speak to reporters on Friday in Malone, N.Y., after escaped prisoner Richard Matt was shot and killed by a border patrol agent in a wooded area about 50 kilometres from Clinton Correctional Facility. (Mary Altaffer/Associated Press)
He credited a tip from the public, one of over 2,300 received so far, for crucial information leading to the deadly confrontation in the town of Malone.
D'Amico said Matt was shot by a border patrol agent when he failed to comply with commands in the woods near a cabin where a shot had been fired earlier in the day at a camping trailer. A 20-gauge shotgun was found on him, though he did not fire it at officers, he added.
"They verbally challenged him, told him to put up his hands. And at that time, he was shot when he didn't comply," D'Amico said.
A second convicted murderer, David Sweat, has not been spotted since he escaped, though evidence was found a week ago indicating he was with Matt in a cabin that was burglarized about five kilometres from any paved roadway, the superintendent said.
David Sweat, left, and Richard Matt escaped June 6 after using tools that had been hidden in hamburger meat to cut their way out of the maximum-security prison. Matt was fatally shot Friday after refusing to surrender to border agents, police say. (New York State Police via AP)
An intense search of the area led to a discovery Friday morning of a camp where somebody apparently had laid down, leaving behind candy wrappers and other items, D'Amico said.
The breakthrough Friday came shortly before 2 p.m., when a person towing a camper heard a loud sound and thought a tire had blown. Finding the tires intact, the driver went another 13 kilometresbefore looking at the trailer and finding a bullet hole.
Authorities converged on the location where the sound was heard and discovered the smell of gunfire inside a cabin, where a weapon had been fired. D'Amico said there also was evidence someone recently had fled out the back door.
Prison escapes: Tools, tricks, helicopters or strolling out the door
"As we were doing the ground search in the area, there was movement detected by officers on the ground, what they believed to be coughs. So they knew that they were dealing with humans as opposed to wildlife," he said.
After Matt was killed, a 20-gauge shotgun that was believed to be missing from the cabin he broke into last weekend was recovered from his body, D'Amico said.
A corrections officer stands near a sign thanking law enforcement along County Route 41 during Saturday's search for David Sweat. (Chris Wattie/Reuters)
"Based on that, we continued to search. We have a lot of people in the area. We have canines and we have a decent perimeter set up and we're searching for Sweat at this time," he said.
D'Amico said he had no information that Sweat was not with or near Matt so a heavy search of the area would go on.
The pair escaped from the Clinton Correctional Facility together early June 6. Gov. Andrew Cuomo called them "dangerous, dangerous men."
'We have a lot of people in the area. We have canines and we have a decent perimeter set up and we're searching for Sweat at this time.'- New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico
Police blocked off roads officers hunted for Sweat in an area around Titusville Mountain State Forest in Malone and spanning 56 square kilometres.
Mitch Johnson said one of his best friends checked on his hunting cabin in Malone Friday afternoon and called police after noticing the scent of grape flavoured gin as soon as he stepped into his cabin and spotting the bottle that had gone untouched for years resting on a kitchen table.
Johnson said his friend, correction officer Bob Willett, told him he summoned police about an hour before Matt was fatally shot and then heard a flurry of gun blasts.
Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a 60-centimetre-thick brick wall, squirmed through pipes and emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
Slain prisoner had killed former boss
Sweat, 35, was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy in Broome County in 2002. Matt, 49, was serving 25 years to life for the killing and dismembering of his former boss. They were added to the U.S. Marshals Service's 15 Most Wanted fugitives list two weeks after getting away.
(Google)
A pair of prison workers has been charged in connection with the inmates' escape.
Prosecutors said Joyce Mitchell, a prison tailoring shop instructor who got close to the men while working with them, had agreed to be their getaway driver but backed out because she felt guilty for participating. Authorities also said Mitchell had discussed killing her husband, Lyle Mitchell, as part of the plot.
N.Y. prison employee arrested for allegedly helping inmates escape
Joyce Mitchell pleaded not guilty June 15 to charges including felony promoting prison contraband, which authorities said included hacksaw blades and chisels.
Authorities said the men had filled their beds in their adjacent cells with clothes to make it appear they were sleeping when guards made overnight rounds. On a cut steam pipe, the prisoners left a taunting note containing a crude caricature of an Asian face and the words "Have a nice day."
On June 24, authorities charged Clinton correction officer Gene Palmer with promoting prison contraband, tampering with physical evidence and official misconduct. Officials said he gave the two prisoners frozen hamburger meat Joyce Mitchell had used to hide the tools she smuggled to Sweat and Matt. Palmer's attorney said he had no knowledge that the meat contained hacksaw blades, a bit and a screwdriver.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:51:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gun culture runs deep in the U.S. and won't change soon</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/gun-culture-runs-deep-in-the-u-s-and-won-t-change-soon-1.3127809?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Analysis
Gun culture runs deep in the U.S. and won't change soon
And it is not just white males from the South who keep the gun culture alive, polls show
ByMark Gollom, CBC News Posted: Jun 27, 2015 5:51 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 5:22 PM ET
Whenever a high-profile shooting occurs, someone campaigns to tighten U.S. gun laws. But change doesn't come easy in a culture where the values of gun ownership run deep and cross so many demographic groups. (San Francisco Chronicle/Michael Macor/Associated Press)
Related Stories
Charleston mayor says US must do more to tackle gun control
Former CNN host and current gun law crusader Piers Morgan wants to remind the public that "it wasn't a flag that killed nine black Americans in their Charleston church. It was a gun."
Whileapplaudingthe decision to remove the Confederate flag from South Carolina'sStateHouse, the British journalist suggests thatcontroversyhasdistracted from the root cause of the deadly shooting.
He dusts off the familiar anti-gun arguments that pop up after any such mass killing, laying the blame on lax U.S.gun laws, the intransigent National Rifle AssociationandRepublicans who refuse to impose any kind of restrictions on weapons.

Nothing novel there in those arguments, nor in the arsenal of counterpointsthe gun rights advocates have been spouting don't blame the gun, don't blame the gun laws, blame the shooter and society's inability to deal with those suffering from mental health issues.

But these endless debates, pro- and anti-gun, mostlycentre on degrees of change in existing gun laws. Rarely are there suggestions or proposals tofundamentally overhaul the nature of gun ownership in the U.S.

President Barack Obama proposed all sorts of changes in 2013following the Sandy Hook school shooting  the reinstatement of a ban on assault-style rifles, a decrease in the size of ammo magazines, and an expansion of federal background checks on firearms buyers. But, as National Review writer Charles Cooke points out , none of those laws, had they been passed, would have made a fig of difference in the recent tragedy. For example, the suspect in Charleston shootingsdid not have an assault-style rifle but a .45-calibre Glock handgun.

So the next step, a gun control advocate might suggest, is to ban those guns too. But that just isn'tgoing to happen any time soon.And why?

The answer may have come from an unlikely source, former George W. Bush adviser Karl Rove, who on Fox News Sunday said this:"The only way to guarantee that we will dramatically reduce acts of violence involving guns is to basically remove guns from society, and until somebody gets enough "oomph" to repeal the Second Amendment, that's not going to happen. I don't think it's an answer."
It's not an answer because Americans,or at least a significant portion of the population, like orwant gunsit's in their cultural DNA.Americans will always have guns.Laws may come and go, banning thisweapon, or that, but there will always be some kind ofgunin the U.S.

While there has been some debate over whether gun ownership is declining in the U.S, it's stillestimated that thereare roughly 300 million guns in the country, which equates to nearly one gun per person.This suggests that any power ascribed to the NRA to quashgun lawsis power that is really derivedfrom the people.

A 2014Pew study looking into the demographics of gun ownership found thatabout a third of all Americans with children under 18 at home have a gun in their household.
And it's all types of Americans who have guns. Republican Americans andDemocratic Americans, male Americans and female Americans, blue state, red state a cross-section of Americans have guns.
Sure, guns aremuch more prevalent in some demographics(white, male, from the South,twice as manyRepublicans as Democrats, but a significant number of Independents.)
But Pew found that, regionally anyway, there wasn'tmuch difference. "Southerners werejust about as likely as those living in the Midwest or the West to have a gun at home (38 per cent35 per centand 34 per cent, respectively)," its study found.Men were more likely than women to be gun owners, but not by much(38 per cent vs. 31 per cent).
And even those who may nothave guns, support gun rights. A Gallup poll last year found that nearly three-quarters of the Americans surveyed said there should not be a ban on the possession of handguns.
Count retired Arizona Democratic congresswoman Gabby Giffords in that group. Giffordssurvived being shot in the headoutside a Tucson supermarket in 2011. Although a proponent for tougher gun laws, shestill considers herself a proud gun owner, asdoes herhusband astronaut Mark Kelly.( A recent CBS interview with her and Kelly showed the couple at a gun range, where Gifford, partially paralyzed in her right side because of the attack, was learningto shoot with her left hand.)
Gun culture in the U.S, may berooted in the days of the early settlers, given some impetusbythe American Revolution, andproliferatedduring and just after the Civil War. But political science professor at SUNYCortlandRobert Spitzer, who arguesthatgun use and ownership has been gradually declining since the1960s, stillsays"guns and the gun culture are deeply engrained in portions of American life."
"The gun culture has two partsthe hunting/sporting tradition, and the frontier/militia tradition,"said Spitzer, author ofGuns Across America."The former is recreational, the latter is political and ideological. Both of these contribute to the modern attachment to guns"
And all that means is that guns, in the U.S., aren't going to disappear.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:00:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Maternal health funding 'the right thing to do' - but what comes next?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/maternal-health-funding-the-right-thing-to-do-but-what-comes-next-1.3126531?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Yesterday: Haiti sees progress- but when can it stand on its own?
Stories like Peter's are what prompted former Canadian foreign affairs minister John Baird in 2012 to speak out against what's known variously as child, early and forced marriage. Last fall, Baird announced Canada would put $10 million toward programs to fight child marriage around the world.
Rob Nicholson has since replaced Baird at foreign affairs, but officials say the focus on ending child marriage continues.
It's an issue not unrelated to Canada's maternal, newborn and child health focus established at the 2010 G8 summit in Muskoka. Women who give birth before they turn 15 are five times more likely to die during delivery, according to British-based NGO Girls Not Brides. Young women, particularly those without medical care, can have serious complications.Giving birth too young also puts the baby at greater risk.
It's a horrifying reality in many countries, and one that's difficult to defend. But it makes up only a single target among dozens included in next set of global development goals.
Sustainability the new focus
The world has spent 15 years working to reach the UN's Millennium Development Goals. First set in 2000, they come to an end on Dec. 31, 2015. The next set of targets, the Sustainable Development Goals, or SDGs, will be set this fall at the UN.
The new regime will havehave twice as many goals and dozens moresubtargets.
It raises the question of whether the world is losing focus on women and children, and the number of preventable deaths: 6.3 million children and 289,000 women a year.
Guillermo Rishchynski,Canada'sambassador to the UN, acknowledges the challenge to keep the world focused on the needs of women and children.
Salome Pascale, 26, and her two-year-old son, at their home in Tanzania's Nzega district, in the region of Tabora. She is pregnant with her third child and says she doesn't know how to avoid getting pregnant other than that she has to speak to a doctor to find out. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"The challenge of course is to keep this as high a priority as possible. And I can tell you without any hesitation that that is the singular preoccupation for myself and our mission here in New York."
While it's hard to find an organization that won't praise Canada's work, some would like to see adjustments to the next round of funding, already announced at $3.5 billion for 2015-2020.
Shannon Kowalski, director of policy at the International Women's Health Coalition, says the Canadian government was a political leader on ending forcedmarriage, including on leading discussions at the UN, but some maternal health polices "undermine the goals that they're espousing internationally."
"One thing that we've noticed with Canada over the last several years is that they've really regressed on their commitments to addressing sexual health and rights, particularly in adolescent girls," Kowalski said in an interview.
"And you can't talk about ending child marriage without also talking about young women's access to sexual and reproductive health services and to comprehensive sexuality education," she said.
"So we feel that's a really missing element that's part of the Canadian response that could actually prevent them from achieving what they want to achieve."
'The right thing to do'
The Conservative government has pledged additional billions over the next five years. But it's also pulled back on overall international development funding, bringing it down to its lowest level since 2005. Official development assistance, or ODA, has fallen from $5.7 billion a year in 2011 to $5.4 billion in 2013 to $4.9 billion last year.
Mickey Chopra, UNICEF's chief of health, says the organization which receives millions in funding from Canada would like to see an increase.
This bed is from a small clinic in Tanzania's Nzega district in the Tabora region. That type of clinic is known as a dispensary. This bed is used for women who need to give birth at the dispensary. (Laura Payton/CBC)
"Not just because it's the right thing to do, but we also do feel it's a very efficient and effective investment to be made," he said.
"The investments that were made in the development of countries such as China, Malaysia and now India do reap benefits in the medium-to-long-term in increasing the market for Canadian goods or increasing the knowledge base for innovation."
Some money has already been allocated under the 2015-2020 funding, although there's been no announcement so far on the$370-million partnership program that gives money directly to NGOs.
With a federal election coming this fall, there's always thepossibility ofa new leadership, which could pull back, redirect or otherwise change Canada's development goals.
Prime Minister Stephen Harper and InternationalDevelopment Minister Christian Paradis turned down repeated requests for interviews on their signature policy.
Tom Mulcair, leader of the NDP, said last month the New Democrats would increase aid to 0.7 per cent of gross national income, which would nearly triple it from the current 0.24 per cent. That 0.7 per cent is a global target that few countries have actually met, although the UK reached it this year.
The NDP said it would also maintain the current focus on maternal, newborn and child health, but expand it to put more money toward family planning, including abortion.
Liberal Leader Justin Trudeau said he would keepmaternal, newborn and child health a priority, and expand the family planning element, including offering abortion. The party wouldreverse the cuts the Conservatives made, butisn't making any promises about hitting the 0.7 per cent target.
The organizations delivering aid around the world will be watching.
The CBC's Laura Payton is this year's R.JamesTravers Fellow. The Travers Fellowship provided $25,000 in funding for her pitch to look at whether Canada's maternal, newborn and child health program was working. Read more about the project here and read her entire series here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:04:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Supreme Court legalizes same-sex marriage in all 50 states</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/u-s-supreme-court-legalizes-same-sex-marriage-in-all-50-states-1.3127280?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Celebrities react to same-sex marriage decision
In a 5-4 decision released Friday, the court ruled that the amendmentobliges states to license marriages between people of the same sexand to recognize marriages lawfully performed outside of state. Thirty-seven of the 50 states and the District of Columbia already allow gay marriage, andFriday's ruling means the others will have to follow suit.
The ruling only affects state laws. Religious institutions can still choose whether or not to marry same-sex couples.
'[The decision] affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts.'- U.S. President Barack Obama
Obamacalled the decision"a victory for America"and said it "affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts."
"When all Americans aretreated equal, we are all more free,"hesaid from the White House Rose Garden.
He praised the perseverance of those who have fought for gay rights and marriage equality for decades "and slowlymade an entire country realize that love is love."
Aixa Adame, left, and Lacey Darcy exchange vows in front of Judge Laura Strathmann in the 388th District Courtroom in El Paso, Texas. They were the first female couple to be married in El Paso. (Victor Calzada/The El Paso Times/Associated Press)
"Change must have seemed so slow for so long," Obamasaid. "But compared to so many other issues, America's shift has been so quick."
Outside of the courtin Washington, D.C., gay couples and gay rights supporters erupted in cheers, whoops and cries ofU-S-A!" and "Love is love" when the ruling came down.
"I'm simply elated,"said Kenneth Barnes, waving a rainbow flag he's had for more than 20 years."I never thought I'd see this in mylifetime,"
Barnes and his partner married in California in 2008. "Now, everyone can do this," he said.
Manysame-sex couples living instates where gay marriage had been banned headed immediately to county clerks' offices to getmarriage licences as state officials issued statements saying they would respect the ruling. Technically, the losing side has three weeks to ask for reconsideration of the ruling, but many state officials and county clerks started issuing marriagelicences right away.
Some waived the usual waiting period between getting a licence and the marriage ceremony.
Equal protection for all
The 14th Amendment affords equal protection under the law to all citizensand was key in other landmark decisionson such divisiveissues as reproductive rights andracial and gender discrimination (for example, in Brown v. Board ofEducation, and Roe v. Wade).
Today is a big step in our march toward equality. Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else. #LoveWins
 @POTUS
The top court ruledit would be a violation of the amendment to grant marriagerights only to heterosexual couples.
"No union is more profound than marriage, for it embodies the highest ideals of love, fidelity, devotion, sacrificeand family. ... [The challengers] ask for equal dignity in the eyes of the law. The constitution grants them that right," Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote in the majority opinion.
 @WhiteHouse
Obamawelcomed the decisionwith a tweet and a phone call to the lead plaintiff in the case, James Obergefell.
"I'm really proud of you and just know that not only did you set a great example for people, but you're also going to bring about lasting change in this country," he told him in the call, whichObergefell took as he was celebratingin front of the Supreme Court andput on speaker so the crowd could lsiten in.
'From this day forward, it will simply be "marriage,"' James Obergefell, the lead plaintiff in the case, said after the landmark ruling. (Andrew Harnik/Associated Press)
Obergefell was in court when Kennedy read the decision and afterward held upa photo of his late spouse, John, outside the court building, saying the ruling establishesthat "our love is equal."
"This is for you, John." he said.
"From this day forward, it will simply be 'marriage.'"
TheWhite House donned rainbow colours, a symbol of the gay rights movement, on its Twitter and home page in celebration of the ruling.
In its ruling, the Supreme Court said the "long history of disapproval of their relationships" and thedenial of the right to marry has done a "grave and continuing harm" to same-sex couples.
Laurin Locke, 24, left, and her partner, Tiffany Brosh, 26, of Pearl, Miss., applied for a marriage licence at the Hinds County Circuit Clerk's office in Jackson, Miss., moments after the U.S. Supreme Court ruling came down. (Rogelio V. Solis/Associated Press)
"The imposition of this disability on gays and lesbians serves to disrespect and subordinate them,"Kennedywrote. "And the equal protection clause, like the due process clause, prohibits this unjustified infringement of the fundamental right to marry."
People are celebrating outside the Supreme Court, this pair came from Florida to be here #CBC pic.twitter.com/w8iUhNuFid
 @fitzpatrick_m
Kennedy, a conservativeappointed by Republican President Ronald Reagan in1988whooften casts the deciding vote inclose cases, hasauthored all four of the court's major gay rights rulings, with the first coming in 1996.
JusticeAntonin Scaliawrote the mostscathing of the four dissenting opinions, calling the decision a" threat to American democracy" and ridiculing the flowery language of the majority opinion.
Eric Braman, right, is hugged by his best man after registering for a marriage licence with his partner Kris Katkus, in Kalamazoo, Mich. (Mark Bugnaski/Kalamazoo Gazette-MLive Media Group/Associated Press)
"If, even as the price to be paid for a fifth vote, I ever joined an opinion for the court that began: 'The Constitution promises liberty to all within its reach, a liberty that includes certain specific rights that allow persons, within a lawful realm, to define and express their identity,'I would hide my head in a bag," Scalia wrote.
"The Supreme Court of the United States has descended from the disciplined legal reasoning of John Marshall and Joseph Story to the mystical aphorisms of the fortune cookie."
Scalia took strong issue with the majority interpretation of the 14th Amendment.
"The five Justices who compose today's majority are entirely comfortable concluding that every state violated the Constitution for all of the 135 years between the 14th Amendment's ratification and Massachusetts's permitting of same-sex marriages in 2003," he wrote. "They have discovered in the14th Amendment a 'fundamental right'overlooked by every person alive at the time of ratification, and almost everyone else in the time since."
Theotherdissenters were justices SamuelAlito, ClarenceThomas and John Roberts.
Crowd tears up at singing of anthem at steps of Supreme Court #CBCnews pic.twitter.com/9Sqy4ilZQo
 @kimbrunhuber
Roberts saidthere are compelling policy arguments for extending marriage tosame-sex couplesbut no legal argument to justify forcingstates to change their marriage laws.
"The fundamental right to marry does not include a right to make a state change its definition of marriage," he wrote. "Our constitution does not enact any one theory of marriage. The people of a state are free to expand marriage to include same-sex couples, or to retain the historic definition."
He said that while he doesn't begrudge supportersof gay marriage their celebrations, the court overstepped in handing down a ruling that"orders the transformation of a social institution that has formed the basis of human society for millennia, for the Kalahari bushmen and the Han Chinese, the Carthaginians and the Aztecs."
"Just who do we think we are?" he wrote.
Roberts and other dissenters predicted further legal wrangles fromthose opposed to same-sex marriage on religious grounds.
Political Conservatives also denounced the ruling.Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee called it "an out-of-control act of unconstitutional judicial tyranny."
Wisconsin Republican Governor Scott Walker, also running for president, called for amending the U.S. Constitution to allow states to again ban same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Governor Greg Abbott said, "Marriage was defined by God. No man can redefine it."
Plaintiffs' arguments
The court was examiningtwo key questions:
Whether states can ban same-sex marriage.
Whether states with gay marriage bans can refuse to recognize marriagesperformed in other jurisdictions where same-sex marriage is legal.
The plaintiffs hadargued that the court hadalready acknowledgedmarriage is a fundamental right in previous decisions and that they were merely seeking equal access to this right.
Jayne Rowse, left, and partner April DeBoer were among the five plaintiffs whose cases made up the challenge of gay marriage bans before the Supreme Court. (Bill Pugliano/Getty)
The challenge of state bans on gay marriagejoined together the cases ofObergefell, April DeBoer, Jayne Rowse, Ijpe DeKoeand Thomas Kostura.
DeKoe and Kosturalegally married in New Yorkbut then moved to Tennessee, where their marriage wasn't recognized.
Obergefell legally married his partner of 20 years,John Arthur, in Maryland, but was not recognized as his legal spouse when Arthur died a few months later in Ohio.
DeBoer and Rowse have three children together but were prevented from jointly adopting them or having them covered under each other's health insurance because they were not legally married, and couldn't get married because their home state ofMichigan doesn't recognize same-sex marriage.
Ruling follows other key victories in gay rights movement
The court's latest decision is themost important expansion of marriage rights in the United States since its landmark 1967 ruling in the case Loving v. Virginia that struck down state laws barring interracial marriages.
The ruling is the latest milestone in the gay rights movement in recent years. In 2010, Obama signed a law allowing gays to serve openly in the U.S. military. In 2013, the Supreme Court struck down a provision of the federal Defence of Marriage Act that defined marriage as a union between a woman and manandprevented same-sex couples married in states where such unions are legal from accessing certain federal programs and filing tax returns as a married couple, for example.
The U.S. is the latest of many Western countries to recognize same-sex marriage.Last month, voters in Ireland backed same-sex marriage by a landslide in a referendum that marked a dramatic social shift in the traditionally Roman Catholic country.
Gay marriageis also legal in Canada,South Africa, Brazil,Britain, France and Spain, but many parts of Africa and Asia consider it andhomosexuality in general taboo and often illegal.
With files from Reuters and The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:49:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia beach hotel attack: mosques closed, army reservists enlisted</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tunisia-beach-hotel-attack-mosques-closed-army-reservists-enlisted-1.3130343?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia museum attack: More than 20 arrested in nationwide crackdown
Tunisia's prime minister announced on Saturday a string of new security measures including closing renegade mosques and calling up army reservists as thousands of tourists fled the North African country in wake of its worst terrorist attack ever.
Tourists crowded into the airport at Hammamet near the coastal city of Sousse where a young man dressed in shorts on Friday pulled an assault rifle and grenades out of his beach umbrella and killed 38 people, mostly tourists.The Islamic State of Iraq and Syriagroup (ISIS) has claimed responsibility for the attack.
Essid announced the call-up of army reservists and said they would be deployed in tourist sites around the country and inside hotels, while he called on the hotels themselves to do more to enforce security.
He also said that political parties and associations espousing radical ideas with suspicious funding would be closed down and around 80 mosques known for extremist preaching would be shut. Hepromised financial rewards for information leading to arrests related to the attack.
"This is a decision the government has taken and we have assigned the minister of interior and all authorities involved to carry this out within the coming week," said Essid."It is not acceptable to have in Tunisia any mosques operating outside the rule of law."
The government has been criticized for its lacklustre anti-terror measures, especially since 22 people were killed by gunmen at the national museum in March. There was also been a failed suicide bomb attack in Sousse in 2013.
British death toll 'may well rise'
At least 15 British citizens were killed in the attack,most of them tourists, the U.K.'s foreign minister said Saturday.
Tunisia beach hotel attack leaves 38 dead, 36 wounded
Tobias Ellwood also said the British toll "may well rise" and referred to the assault as "the most significant terrorist attack on the British people" since July 7, 2005, when suicide bombers struck the London transport network, killing 52 people and wounding hundreds of others.
This image taken from a militant website associated with Islamic State extremists, posted on Saturday purports to show the Tunisian gunman, identified as Seifeddine Rezgui. (Associated Press)
Ireland's foreign minister says the government suspects that two other Irish citizens are among the dead, in addition to nurse Lorna Carty.
A spokesman for Tunisia's health ministry said a total of 39 people were wounded in the shooting, including 21 people who have now left the hospital. Chokri Nafi told The Associated Press that 18 are under observation, including two who are in critical condition.
He said the nationalities of the injured include seven Tunisians, 25 Britons, three Belgians, one German, one Ukrainian, one Russian and one who has not yet been identified. Nafi said the attack left 39 people dead, including the gunman.
Tunisian police arrest more than 20 in crackdown
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted around noon at the Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba near Sousse, 140 kilometres south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire left and right at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot. A spokesman for the interior ministry said the gunman was a student in his early 20s, but Tunisian authorities did not name him. Awebsite associated with ISIS on Saturday posted what it said was the gunman, a Tunisian identified asSeifeddine Rezgui.
The bodies of several tourists lay crumpled where they fell in the sand, covered with yellow towels and blankets among the plastic white sunbeds. Blood smeared stone steps leading from the hotel main area.
Thousands of tourists leave
At the Imperial Marhaba on Saturday,vans and buses were carrying tourists away. While the hotel wasn't actually closing down, the tour operators had urged everyone to leave, the director said.
"We may have zero clients today but we will keep our staff," said Mohammed Becheur, adding the 370-room hotel had been at 75 percent occupancy before the attack.
On the beach, there was as scattering of tourists while police on horses rode along the beach and their security boats patrolled along the coast.
Tourism is a key part of Tunisia's economy and had already fallen some 25 percent after the March museum attack.
"Since yesterday, there have been about 15 extra flights scheduled at the airport with nine already leaving carrying 1,400 passengers," said Mohamed Walid Ben Ghachem, director of the Enfidha-Hammamet Airport.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 13:23:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China cuts interest rates for 4th time since November to boost economy</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/china-cuts-interest-rates-to-boost-sluggish-economy-1.3130350?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Photo Galleries
China cuts interest rates to boost sluggish economy
The Associated Press Posted: Jun 27, 2015 6:23 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 27, 2015 6:23 AM ET
The People's Bank of China will cut the rate on a one-year loan by commercial banks by 0.25 percentage point to 4.85 per cent, starting Sunday. (Frederic J. Brown/AFP/Getty)
Related Stories
China cuts interest rates for 3rd time in 5 months
The People's Bank of China said Saturday that it would cut the rate on a one-year loan by commercial banks by 0.25 percentage point to 4.85 per cent. The interest rate paid on a one-year deposit was lowered by 0.25 point to 2 per cent.
Rates were cut on Nov. 22, March 1 and then May 11. The new rates take effect Sunday.
The central bank also says the reserve requirement ratios to small businesses would be lowered by 50 points, a move that would boost lending.
Economic growth has slowed in China, and its stock markets plunged Friday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama leads mourners in Amazing Grace at funeral for Charleston shooting victim Rev. Pinckney</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbc.ca/news/world/obama-eulogizes-charleston-shooting-victim-rev-clementa-pinckney-sings-amazing-grace-1.3128798?cmp=rss</Link>
        <Description>
        
                        </Description>
        <MainBody>Obama eulogizes Charleston shooting victim Rev. Clementa Pinckney, sings Amazing Grace
Overflow crowd of thousands at service attended by Obama and other politicians and dignitaries
CBC News Posted: Jun 26, 2015 10:32 AM ET Last Updated: Jun 26, 2015 5:28 PM ET
Obama eulogizes Charleston shooting victim Rev. Pinckney and leads mourners in singing Amazing Grace 2:50
Related Stories
Charleston church shooting: Confederate flag belongs only in museum
U.S. President Barack Obama describedRev.ClementaPinckney as a kind, diligent man who was "able to walk in someone else's shoes, able to see through their eyes" at a funeral for the South Carolina pastor shot to death with eight others at aCharleston churchlast week.
Obama, who knew Pinckney personally,eulogized the pastor infront of a crowdof more than 5,000at an arena in downtown Charleston, recalling Pinckney'shumble influence on his communityand at one point leading the crowdin a chorus of thehymnAmazing Grace.
South Carolinalawmakers debate Confederate flag
"Even from a young age, people knew he was special," Obamasaid of Pinckney."He conducted himself kindly, quietly and diligently. He was full of empathy, able to walk in someone else's shoes, able to see through their eyes.That's the best thing to hope for when you're eulogized to just say somebody was a good man."
The late Rev. Clementa Pinckney's daughter, Malana, reaches up to U.S. President Barack Obama next to her sister Eliana, right, as their mother Jennifer hugs first lady Michelle Obama after the president eulogized Rev. Pinckney during funeral services at the College of Charleston TD Arena in Charleston, S.C., on Friday (Jonathan Ernst/Reuters)
Pinckneyheadedthe historic African-American Emanuel AME Church and was also a state senator. He was takingpartin a bible study on June 17 whena gunman entered the church, joined the bible study for an hour before opening fire, killing Pinckney and seven other parishoners. One person died later in hospital.
Obama acknowledged those other victims in his eulogy.
"To the families of the fallen, our nation shares in your grief," he said.
'Aflag did not commit these murders'
Dylann Roof, 21, has been charged with nine counts of murder in connection with the shooting. He has been linkedto a website with numerous racist writings and images, including ones showing him holding a Confederate flag, a Civil War-era battle flagseen by many as a racist symbol of the slave-owning American South.
More than 5,000 mourners packed a downtown Charleston arena for the service. (Brian Snyder/Reuters)
Politicians and civil rights activists have called for the flag to be removed from governmentbuildings and other institutions in South Carolina and elsewhere in the wake of the shooting while other's have insisted it is an important part of the history of the American south. Obama alluded to that controversy at the funeral Friday.
"It's true a flag did not commit these murders" he said."Theflag has always represented more than ancestral pride. For many, black and white, that flag was a reminder of oppression and racial subjugation.
"For too long, we were blind to the pain that the Confederate flag stirred in too many of our citizens."
The president acknowledged that racism can't be solved by debate and thatsolutions will always be imperfect.
"There's no shortcut. We don't need more talk," Obama said. "Whatever solutions we find will be necessarily incomplete."
Joe Biden, HillaryClintonin attendance
Obamaarrived in Charleston Friday afternoon, several hoursafter addressing the nation from the White House Rose Garden about the U.S. Supreme Court's decision to legalize gay marriage in all 50 states.
Other speakers at the funeral praisedPinckney'spersonal touch andhis political reach.
The tone of Friday's funeral service was largely uplifting. The service included several musical numbers and humourous anecdotes about the beloved pastor. (Grace Beahm/Reuters)
"We will see the Confederate flag come down.You're the one who did it." said South Carolina statesenatorGerald Malloy. "Do not let race, religion or politics close the door that SenatorPinckney opened."
Bishop John Richard Bryant spoke to the congregation about Roofand his effect on the South Carolina community and the country at large.
"He wanted to start a race war, but he came to the wrong place," said Bryant. "Weeping may endure for the night, but joy comes in the morning."
MichelleObamaand Vice-President JoeBidenand his wife,Jill, also attended the service, as didHouse Speaker John Boehner,Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton and other state and federal politicians and civil rightsactivists, includingMartin Luther King III.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
