<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:29:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/france-terror-attack-saint-quentin-fallavier/</Link>
        <Description>An attack on a gas factory near the eastern city of Lyon left at least one person dead</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Terror attack
At least one assailant rammed a car onto the premises of a U.S. gas company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast France, June 26, 2015, causing oxygen containers to explode. A decapitated head with Arabic writing on or near it was found at the site.
Here, French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
Terror attack
The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, southeastern France, after an assault June 26, 2015, in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates.
One person was killed and several others were injured.
Credit: Jean-Philippe Ksiazek/AFP/Getty Images
Terror attack
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
One of the attackers reportedly waved an Islamic  State of Iraq and Syria flag.
Credit: Emmanuel Foudrot/Reuters
Terror attack
French security and emergency services gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, southeastern France, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
Terror attack
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Credit: REUTERS
Terror attack
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve gives a press conference near the entrance of the Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier near Lyon, southeastern France, June 26, 2015.
A suspect arrested in connection with the attack on a French gas factory was investigated nine years ago for radicalization and has links to the Salafist movement, Cazeneuve said.
Credit: Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
President Francois Hollande
French President Francois Hollande gives a statement at the European Council headquarters in Brussels, June 26, 2015. Hollande said an attack that morning in southeast France was of "a terrorist nature" and that a suspect had been arrested and identified.
Credit: Yves Herman/Reuters
Terror attack
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Emmanuel Foudrot/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:01:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly attack targets tourists in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/tunisia-hotel-attack-in-tourist-resort-town-of-sousse/</Link>
        <Description>Officials confirm multiple fatalities as gunmen attack popular resort area on Tunisia's northeast coast, just months after museum massacre</Description>
        <MainBody>Twenty people, mostly tourists, were killed by gunmen at the National Bardo Museum in Tunis
Tunisia, a popular destination for European and Tunisian travelers, has been on high alert since a deadly assault on the famed Bardo museum in March by a pair of gunmen who killed 22 people at the tourist attraction in the capital city of Tunis.
The gunmen opened fire on tourists getting out of buses and then entered the museum, apparently unimpeded, and fired on more tourists inside. Two gunmen were killed in a shootout with police. Four Italians were among the dead.
The Islamic State in Iraq and Syria ( ISIS ) claimed responsibility for the Bardo attack.
This is a developing story, please check back for updates.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 20:33:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks to break June 30 deadline</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/iran-nuclear-talks-to-break-june-30-deadline/</Link>
        <Description>With pressure on Sec. Kerry to deliver a deal for Obama, dispute over nuclear site access appears to be halting progress</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APJune 28, 2015, 9:33 AM
Iran nuclear talks to break June 30 deadline
From left, U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry and U.S. Under Secretary for Political Affairs Wendy Sherman meet with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, second from right, at a hotel in Vienna, Austria, Saturday, June 27, 2015.
Carlos Barria/AP
More +
VIENNA - A senior U.S. official acknowledged Sunday that Iran nuclear talks will go past their June 30 target date, as Iran's foreign minister prepared to head home Sunday for consultations before returning to push for a breakthrough.
Iranian media said Mohammed Javad Zarif's trip was planned in advance. Still, the fact that he was leaving the talks so close to the Tuesday deadline reflected his need to get instructions on how to proceed on issues where the sides remain apart - among them how much access Tehran should give to U.N. experts monitoring his country's compliance to any deal.
The United States insists on more intrusive access than Iran is ready to give. With these and other disputes still unresolved the likelihood that the Tuesday target deadline for an Iran nuclear deal could slip was increasingly growing even before the U.S. confirmation.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry was in Vienna again for the talks. CBS News correspondent Margaret Brennan reports Kerry is under pressure to deliver President Obama's chief foreign policy goal - a nuclear accord with Iran.
Several former Obama aides warned in a recent letter that the emerging deal "may fall short of meeting the administration's own standard of a 'good' agreement."
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier and French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius are currently in Vienna, and their Russian and British counterparts are to join later. China was sending a deputy foreign minister in a building diplomatic effort to wrap up the negotiations.
For weeks, all seven nations at the negotiating table insisted that Tuesday remains the formal deadline for a deal. But with time running out, a senior U.S. official acknowledged that was unrealistic.
"Given the dates, and that we have some work to do ... the parties are planning to remain in Vienna beyond June 30 to continue working," said the official, who demanded anonymity in line with State Department practice.
Asked about the chances for a deal, Federica Mogherini, the European Union's top diplomat, told reporters: "It's going to be tough ... but not impossible."
Steinmeier avoided reporters but told German media earlier: "I am convinced that if there is no agreement, everyone loses."
"Iran would remain isolated. A new arms race in a region that is already riven by conflict could be the dramatic consequence."
Both sides recognize that there is leeway to extend to July 9. As part of an agreement with the U.S. Congress, lawmakers then have 30 days to review the deal before suspending congressional sanctions.
But postponement beyond that would double the congressional review period to 60 days, giving both Iranian and U.S. critics more time to work on undermining an agreement.
Arguing for more time to allow the U.S. to drive a harder bargain, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu - a fierce opponent of the talks - weighed in on Sunday against "this bad agreement, which is becoming worse by the day."
"It is still not too late to go back and insist on demands that will genuinely deny Iran the ability to arm itself with nuclear weapons," he said.
The goal of the talks involving Iran and the U.S., Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia is a deal that would crimp Tehran's capacity to make nuclear weapons in exchange for sanctions relief.  Iran insists it does not want such arms but is bargaining in exchange for sanctions relief
On Saturday, diplomats told The Associated Press that Iran was considering a U.S.-backed plan for it to send enriched uranium to another country for sale as reactor fuel, a step that would resolve one of several outstanding issues.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 18:33:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nervous Greeks crowd ATMs awaiting ECB decision</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/nervous-greeks-crowd-atms-awaiting-european-central-bank-decision/</Link>
        <Description>Greece's European partners debate whether or not to let the country's banks run out of cash after new prime minister threw bailout negations into turmoil</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece says it will not be able to make the 1.7 billion dollars in payments it owes this month as it tries to strike a deal with lenders. CBS New...
Parliament approved Tsipras' referendum call early Sunday, with the national vote set for July 5.
The ECB has said it can only continue its current assistance if the banks are basically solvent. A failure by Greece's government to get more aid before its bailout ends Tuesday and a big payment to the International Monetary Fund is due could prompt the ECB to decide the Greek banks are not financially solid any more.
Capping the aid would quickly force Greek banks to limit withdrawals - but such controls could take Greece a step closer to leaving the 19-nation eurozone.
ECB President Mario Draghi has said it's up to elected officials to decide Greece's fate . Analysts say the central bank wants to give politicians every chance to negotiate a deal.
Two opinion polls indicate most Greeks want to keep using the shared euro currency and would prefer a deal with Greece's European partners rather than a rupture.
The polls published Sunday were both conducted before Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras declared early Saturday that he was calling a referendum on financial proposals made by Greece's creditors in return for continuing to fund the country with bailout loans. Still, they provide an indication of public sentiment.
In the poll by Alco for the Proto Thema Sunday paper, 57 percent said they believed Greece should make a deal with its EU partners while 29 percent wanted a rupture. A separate poll by Kapa Research for the To Vima newspaper found 47.2 percent of respondents would vote in favor of a new, painful agreement with Greece's creditors, compared to 33 percent who would vote no and 18.4 percent undecided.
Both nationwide polls were conducted from June 24-26. The Alco poll had a margin of error of 3.1 percent while Kapa Research's was 3.09 percent.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:39:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens killed as Kurds answer latest ISIS offensive</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/isis-attacks-on-kobani-hasskeh-leave-hundreds-dead-thousands-displaced/</Link>
        <Description>Thousands flee Hassakeh while activists says dozens of bodies left in streets after 2 days of fighting in Kobani</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS fighters advanced into the south west of the Syrian Kurdish town of Kobani overnight
The Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said on Friday that the attack on Kobani and its suburbs left 120 civilians dead.
Bali said more than 100 civilians were killed in Kobani as well as 40 ISIS fighters whose bodies were still in the streets.
Kobani, on Syria's border with Turkey, had become a symbol of Kurdish resistance against the ISIS extremists.
On Thursday, ISIS fighters also attacked the town of Hassakeh in northeast Syria.
According to a Reuters report, 60,000 people were displaced due to the fighting.
Reuters reported that 200,000 people in Hassakeh eventually could try and escape north toward the Turkish border.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 18:05:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sudden inferno at Taiwan water park injures hundreds</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/sudden-inferno-taiwan-water-park-injures-hundreds/</Link>
        <Description>An accidental explosion of an unknown powder sets hundreds of people on fire at once during concert; cause still a mystery</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APJune 28, 2015, 7:11 AM
Sudden inferno at Taiwan water park injures hundreds
Silhouettes of people running from a blaze are seen at the Formosa Fun Coast water park, on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei in this still image taken from video shot on June 27, 2015 and provided by Apple Daily Taiwan.
REUTERS/Ms. Huang/Apple Daily Taiwan
More +
TAIPEI, Taiwan - A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring about 500 people, including 141 in serious condition, authorities said.
The fire was sparked by an accidental explosion of an unknown powder that was fired from a stage in front of about 1,000 people, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Taiwan's Central News Agency on Sunday reported 474 have been injured, including 141 in serious condition. It quoted the New Taipei City health bureau. The injured included four mainland Chinese and two foreigners. Other news sources put the injured count at over 500.
The fire erupted at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City near the island's capital and was quickly brought under control.
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City on June 27, 2015.
AFP/Getty Images
CNA reported witnesses as saying the fire spread quickly after the colored powder was blown into the air.
It wasn't clear if the colored powder was part of a performance. The cause of the fire is being investigated.
The event manager and several park employees were detained and questioned after the incident, the BBC reports. There are also reports of at least one person arrested for looting among the victims.
Taiwan News reports the the company owner in charge of the show, Lu Chung-ji, offered a public apology following the incident, and said he takes responsibility.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man decapitated in apparent France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/man-decapitated-in-apparent-france-terror-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A suspected terror attack may have targeted an American gas company. Police say two attackers set off an explosion at the gates of an industrial complex near Lyon. They also found a severed head at the scene and banners with Islamist messages on them. Elizabeth Palmer reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in apparent France terror attack
June 26, 2015, 7:02 AM
|A suspected terror attack may have targeted an American gas company. Police say two attackers set off an explosion at the gates of an industrial complex near Lyon. They also found a severed head at the scene and banners with Islamist messages on them. Elizabeth Palmer reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:49:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Philippine official: China island-building in full swing</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/philippines-official-china-constructing-islands-reclamation-south-china-sea/</Link>
        <Description>10 days after Beijing said land reclamation in disputed South China Sea territory was near complete, local mayor sees "full-blast construction"</Description>
        <MainBody>There are growing tensions between China, its neighbors and the U.S. over disputed waters in the South China Sea. The Chinese military is racing ...
CBS News correspondent Seth Doane was on the Philippines' Pag-Asa Island earlier this month, where he reported that the Chinese have filled in enough of the South China Sea to create 2,000 acres of artificial islands in just the last 18 months.
In the mid-portion of the emerging island, a 1.9-mile-long landfill is taking the shape of a runway, Bito-onon said.
His comments followed similar findings by the U.S. military and independent defense analysts.
Two senior Philippine military officials, speaking on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to talk to the media, said that aside from Subi Reef, China's island-building has also continued on Mischief Reef, also in the Spratlys, based on recent military surveillance.
Chinese Embassy officials in Manila did not comment immediately.
The Chinese Foreign Ministry said on June 16 that the land reclamation projects on some islands and reefs "will be completed in upcoming days." However, in a sign that the developments were far from over, the ministry also said on its website that China would follow up by building infrastructure for operations ranging from maritime search and rescue to environmental conservation and scientific research.
The U.S. and the Philippines, its defense treaty ally, have expressed concern that China's island-building on at least half a dozen features in the South China Sea could be used for positioning military planes and navy ships to intimidate other claimants, reinforce China's claim over virtually the entire sea and threaten freedom of navigation in one of the world's busiest shipping lanes.
China's Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang said in the statement that the projects "do not affect the freedom of navigation and overflight enjoyed by all countries in accordance with international law in the South China Sea."
A U.S. Navy plane flying near one of the artificial islands last month was told to leave the area by the Chinese military . In a separate incident, a Philippine air force plane was similarly ordered by the Chinese navy several weeks ago to leave the area. The incidents raised fears that China was preparing to enforce an air defense identification zone over the South China Sea, similar to one it declared over disputed Japanese-held islands in the East China Sea in 2013.
The U.S. argues that China can't use artificially constructed islands to expand its sovereignty. U.S. officials have said they were considering stepping up patrols to ensure free navigation in the contested region.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:20:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man found decapitated in France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/reports-of-terror-attack-in-eastern-france/</Link>
        <Description>President Hollande confirms 1 suspect in custody after attempt to blow up gas factory near Lyon that also left 2 injured; officials say more detained</Description>
        <MainBody>ByTucker RealsCBS NewsJune 26, 2015, 5:26 AM
Man found decapitated in France terror attack
Shares
More +
Last Updated Jun 26, 2015 8:20 AM EDT
One person was found decapitated and two others injured Friday after an assailant -- with a possible accomplice -- drove a vehicle onto an industrial complex near the eastern city of Lyon and tried to blow up a gas factory.
An attack on a gas factory near the eastern city of Lyon left at least one person dead
"The intent was without doubt to cause an explosion. It was a terrorist attack," President Francois Hollande said at a news conference in Belgium.
The attack targeted a chemical factory in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, about 20 miles southeast of Lyon. The plant is owned by the U.S. firm Air Products .
Witnesses said a man drove into the forecourt of the gas supply company, spun his car around in the yard, reports CBS News' Elaine Cobbe. Then they heard an explosion and saw fire.
The slain victim's head was found yards away from the body, stuck on a perimeter fence, with Arabic writing on or near it. There were also flags or banners bearing Arabic writing found at the scene.
The newspaper Le Dauphine libere reports that the decapitated victim was the manager of a transport company who happened to be at the site for a delivery.
French Defense Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian declared the attack an "act of terrorism," and said the national Defense Council was to convene at the presidential Elyse Palace at 3 p.m. local time (9 a.m. Eastern).
CBS News correspondent Elizabeth Palmer reports the factory was locked down along with other businesses in the area during the police investigation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 08:46:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paraglider landing on cable car breaks the Internet</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/paraglider-landing-on-cable-car-breaks-the-internet/</Link>
        <Description>A paraglider was filmed launching off a cliff and landing on a cable car. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has the wild video.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paraglider landing on cable car breaks the Internet
June 25, 2015, 9:35 PM
|A paraglider was filmed launching off a cliff and landing on a cable car. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has the wild video.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 08:38:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Luhu, the sad cat goes viral</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/luhu-the-sad-cat-goes-viral/</Link>
        <Description>An instagram featuring a cat's perpetually sad expressions has gone viral. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has more on the fussy feline.</Description>
        <MainBody>Luhu, the sad cat goes viral
June 25, 2015, 9:26 PM
|An instagram featuring a cat's perpetually sad expressions has gone viral. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has more on the fussy feline.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 08:24:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Queen unimpressed with her portrait</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/queen-unimpressed-with-her-portrait/</Link>
        <Description>The Queen of England had a lackluster response to an illustration of her as a child. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers describes her underwhelmed reaction</Description>
        <MainBody>Queen unimpressed with her portrait
June 25, 2015, 9:13 PM
|The Queen of England had a lackluster response to an illustration of her as a child. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers describes her underwhelmed reaction
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:29:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taxi drivers protest in France over Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/taxi-drivers-protest-in-france-over-uber/</Link>
        <Description>Taxi drivers in France took to the streets to protest Uber's presence in the country. The cabbies say the company is killing their business. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taxi drivers protest in France over Uber
June 25, 2015, 6:48 PM
|Taxi drivers in France took to the streets to protest Uber's presence in the country. The cabbies say the company is killing their business. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:15:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber French taxi drivers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/french-taxi-drivers-protest-uber/</Link>
        <Description>French taxi drivers created chaos in Paris and other cities protesting the U.S. online ride service's European service - UberPOP</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
France Uber strike
French taxi drivers smashed cars, set tires ablaze and blocked traffic across the country on June 25, 2015 in a nationwide strike aimed at Uber after weeks of rising, sometimes violent tensions over the U.S. ride-hailing company's booking service, known in France as UberPOP. The angry taxi drivers say Uber's lowest cost service is taking their livelihood away.
French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Here, smoke rises from a fire, as a French riot police officer keeps watch next to an overturned car during protests by taxi drivers at Porte Maillot in Paris, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Thomas Samson/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
The sign on the wall reads "Death to Uber."
French riot police secure the Porte Maillot during a demonstration by French taxi drivers, who are on strike,  during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris on June 25, 2015.
Access to three terminals at Paris-Charles de Gaulle airport and in a number of areas of Paris, especially Porte Maillot, were blocked.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
Taxis gather at a major Paris traffic artery, Thursday, June 25, 2015.
French taxis are on strike around the country, snarling traffic in major cities and slowing access to Paris' Charles de Gaulle airport after weeks of rising and sometimes violent tensions over Uber.
UberPOP, the popular taxi app, is facing fierce opposition from traditional cab drivers.
Credit: Michel Euler/AP
France Uber strike
During a strike by French taxi drivers on Thursday, June 25, 2015, travelers going to and from the airport walked alongside highways with their bags or got caught in ambushes, like U.S. singer Courtney Love, who was rescued by two men on a motorcycle.
"They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage," Love tweeted. "They're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France- I'm safer in Baghdad."
Here, a man looks at an overturned car, allegedly used by an UberPOP driver, at Porte Maillot in Paris on June 25, 2015, as taxi drivers demonstrated nearby.
Credit: Thomas Samson/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
Riot policemen deploy through the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout, with The Arc de Triomphe in Paris, as taxi drivers stage a demonstration/blockade, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Loic Venance/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
French taxi drivers burn tires during a protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against UberPOP, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Anne-Christine Poujoulat/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
Riot police stand by an overthrown car during a taxi drivers demonstration, in Paris, Thursday, June 25, 2015.
Credit: AP Photo/Michel Euler
France Uber strike
French riot police stand in front of the Tour Oxygene as taxi drivers take part in a protest against car-sharing service Uber in Lyon, France, June 25, 2015. French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Credit: Emmanuel Foudrot/Reuters
France Uber strike
A taxi driver waves a French flag inscribed with the words "Uber, here it's  France" during a demonstration in Paris, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Michel Euler/AP
France Uber strike
A taxi with a banner that reads, "Uber get out" is seen during a protest in the southern city of Marseille as taxi drivers demonstrate against UberPOP, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Anne-Christine Poujoulat/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
French taxi drivers, who are on strike, block traffic on the city ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Paris, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
French riot police stand next to an overturned car as striking French taxi drivers demonstrate at the Porte Maillot, blocking traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in France, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
Taxi drivers on strike burn tires during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Marseille, France, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Jean-Paul Pelissier/Reuters
France Uber strike
The inscription "Death to Uber" is tagged onto a wall at the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout in Paris, as taxi drivers stage a demonstration/blockade, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Loix Venance/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
An overturned car is seen in the distance as French taxi drivers demonstrate at Porte Maillot to block traffic on the city ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, June 25, 2015. French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP on Thursday, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
Passengers drag their suitcases as they make their way towards Orly airport as striking taxi drivers block access roads south of Paris during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Christian Hartmann/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:08:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean soccer player investigated for intimate touch of opponent</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/chile-soccer-player-investigated-for-provoking-opponent/</Link>
        <Description>Defender Gonzalo Jara was caught trying to provoke Uruguay's Edinson Cavani to get a red card in the Copa America quarterfinals</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
SANTIAGO, Chile -- South American football officials will look into the actions of Chile defender Gonzalo Jara , who was caught on video poking Edinson Cavani's behind to provoke a red card in the Copa America quarterfinals.
Alberto Lozada, a member of CONMEBOL's disciplinary panel, said Thursday that the local governing body "will open an investigation" into Jara.
Cavani, Uruguay's top striker in the tournament, was sent off after the 63rd-minute provocation by Jara, and Chile went on to score the only goal on Wednesday, and reach the semifinals for the first time in 16 years.
Cavani slapped Jara in the face immediately after the Chilean put his hand on him, but the referee punished only Cavani, giving him a second yellow card. While the slap appeared to be light, Jara dropped to the ground with his hand to his face.
Cavani's first yellow was for complaining to the linesman in the 30th.
Uruguay captain Diego Godin said after the match that Cavani "reacted the way he did" only because of what Jara did.
The striker entered the match enduring a personal ordeal back in Uruguay, where his father was detained after allegedly driving drunk and being involved in an accident that killed a motorcyclist.
It wasn't the first time Jara was seen provoking another player. In 2013, Uruguay striker Luis Suarez was sent off from a World Cup qualifier for punching Jara in the face after a similar provocation from the Chilean.
If Jara has a hearing and is suspended, it could be costly for the hosts, who are trying to win the Copa for the first time. Chile will play either Peru or Bolivia in the semifinals.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:30:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama administration slams Iran and Cuba for human rights abuses</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/obama-admin-criticizes-iran-and-cuba-for-human-rights-abuses/</Link>
        <Description>The State Department blasted the two nations, although attempts to improve relations with them are continuing</Description>
        <MainBody>Pamela Falk, CBS News Foreign Affairs Analyst, discusses the highest level U.S. delegation to Cuba in decades beginning two days of negotiations.
On Cuba, the human rights reports said the government continued to use threats and intimidation to suppress peaceful dissent in 2014. And they accused government officials of carrying out "most human rights abuses" at the direction of their superiors.
Although Cuba released 53 political prisoners as part of the normalization process with the United States, the reports noted that Cuban activists in 2014 had recorded the highest number of arbitrary arrests of dissidents in the past five years. And though the government in 2014 indicated it will expand internet and telecommunications access, it "continued to block its citizens' access to uncensored, independent information in general," the reports said.
Other Cuban rights abuses mentioned in the reports include the abridgement of the ability of citizens to change the government; use of government threats, extrajudicial physical assault, intimidation, violent government-organized counter-protests against peaceful dissent; and harassment and detentions to prevent free expression and peaceful assembly.
"Impunity for the perpetrators remained widespread," the reports said.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:23:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Noriega asks for Panama's forgiveness in jailhouse interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/manuel-noriega-panama-jailhouse-interview/</Link>
        <Description>Former dictator breaks long silence to ask compatriots to forgive military regime's actions that culminated in U.S. invasion</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
PANAMA CITY -- Former dictator Manuel Noriega broke a long silence to ask his compatriots on Wednesday to forgive actions by his military regime that culminated in the 1989 U.S. invasion.
Noriega began the brief jailhouse interview with local network Telemetro reading a handwritten statement in which he said his apology came after days of reflection with his family and members of the church.
He said he wasn't motivated by any personal interest but a sincere desire to bring closure to the military era, a dark chapter in Panama's history that left the country in ruin and hundreds dead.
"Before the altar of my conscience I've come to express myself in the spirit of forgiveness," Noriega said, his hand shaking but otherwise appearing in good health for his 81 years.
The onetime CIA informant hadn't spoken to a journalist since a 1996 interview with CNN's Larry King from a Miami federal prison, where following his capture by American troops he was sent for being a major conduit for Colombian cocaine traffickers.
After completing his sentence in the U.S., Noriega was extradited to France to serve time for money laundering. He returned to Panama in 2011 to complete a 60-year sentence for murder, corruption and embezzlement during the military's three-decade rule.
Referring to himself as the "last general of the military era," Noriega apologized to those "offended, affected, injured or humiliated" by his own actions or those of his superiors and subordinates during the regime that he began serving as a low-ranking officer in the 1960s.
He didn't comment on any specific abuses and refused to take the bait when pressed about whether his act of contrition involved clarifying the still murky circumstances that led to the disappearance and murder of two prominent opponents.
Saying he was "totally at peace" with himself, Noriega said he didn't want to distract from the "solemnity" of his statement.
Reaction among Panamanians was mixed.
Many on social media saw the apology as a surprising capitulation from the famously stubborn strongman, who lost his apparent interest and power to influence Panamanian politics years ago.
But others judged it as a sly move to pave the way for a presidential pardon or for him to finish his sentence under house arrest, something his lawyers have been seeking on medical grounds for years. Indeed, he prefaced his written statement with a brief protest against what he said were excessively long sentences imposed by Panamanian courts in absentia.
"The problem with Noriega is you can never distinguish between what's true or not," said R.M. Koster, an American novelist and biographer of Noriega who has lived in Panama for decades.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:04:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. same-sex marriage ruling could have global impact</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/supreme-court-same-sex-marriage-ruling-could-have-global-impact/</Link>
        <Description>Gay rights advocates worldwide hope U.S. Supreme Court's landmark decision in favor of same-sex marriage will help their cause</Description>
        <MainBody>As the Supreme Court says "I do" to gay marriage, we take a look back at the legal battles, tragedies, and personal bravery that brought the LGBT...
In other countries where gay sex is treated as a crime, beleaguered activists said they took heart from the U.S. ruling even though same-sex marriage is not on the horizon. In most cases, activists seek to decriminalize homosexuality before pressing for marriage rights and other benefits.
In the deeply conservative Arab world, where homosexuality is regarded as a crime in many countries, some clerics warned that the U.S. ruling would lead to the collapse of civilizations.
In Jordan, where homosexuality is not illegal but is considered taboo, one member of the small gay community said the U.S. ruling is "a victory for human rights in general and gives everyone hope."
He is hopeful same-sex marriage will one day be legal in Jordan.
"In this region, we are going through the dark ages, and when we come out, we will move toward full rights," he said, speaking on condition of anonymity because he feared the consequences of being identified as gay.
Marriage equality is also not part of the conversation in many parts of Africa, where more than two-thirds of the countries treat homosexuality as a crime.
That is true of Cameroon, which has pursued dozens of prosecutions in recent years under an anti-gay law imposing up to five years in prison for same-sex acts.
Lambert Lamba, a leading Cameroonian activist who has been imprisoned on accusations of violating anti-gay laws, said he was "exulting" in the U.S. ruling.
"It's a giant step for the fight in the United States," he said. "And it confirms for me that we can take giant steps in Cameroon as well."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:14:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Photos of the week</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/photos-of-the-week-june-20-26-2015/</Link>
        <Description>The most compelling photos from the week's news, June 20-26, 2015, including landmark rulings by the Supreme Court, a heatwave in Pakistan and a Colombian tattoo festival</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Shroud of Turin
Week in review: The most compelling photos from the week's news, June 20-26, 2015, including landmark rulings by the Supreme Court, a heatwave in Pakistan and a Colombian tattoo festival.
Here, nuns take pictures of the Pope arriving at Turin's cathedral to pray in front of the holy Shroud, believed by many Christians to be the burial shroud of Jesus of Nazareth, on June 21, 2015.
By CBSNews.com senior photo editor Radhika Chalasani
Credit: Alberto Pizzoli/AFP/Getty Images
Obama reacts to Supreme Court ruling
President Barack Obama reacts to news of the Supreme Court ruling on the Affordable Care Act subsidies, Thursday, June 25, 2015.
The President was in the middle of his daily briefing when Brian Mosteller, the director of Oval Office operations, abruptly opened the door at 10:10 AM. For one split second, the President's face was blank as if he was trying to comprehend the news. He then reacted in jubilation.
Credit: Pete Souza/The White House
Lai Chi Kok Amusement Park
A worker (C) secures ropes to a large sculpture that will be part of the new Lai Chi Kok amusement part in Hong Kong on June 23, 2015.  The Lai Chi Kok Amusement Park, once the largest family venue in Hong Kong, will be rebuilt on the promenade, 18 years after its closure.
Credit: Isaac Lawrence/AFP/Getty Images
A summer lightening storm on the Jersey City, New Jersey waterfront, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Gary Hershorn
Tunisia - tourists killed
Bodies of tourists shot dead by a gunman lie near the beachside Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
At least 39 people, mainly Western tourists, were killed when a gunman opened fir. The gunman was killed at the scene by security forces.
Credit: Amine Ben Aziza/Reuters
Chilean education protest
Students perform next to riot policemen during a demonstration to demand changes in the Chilean education system in Santiago, Chile June 25, 2015.
Credit: Ricardo Moraes/Reuters
Spain - fireworks
Revelers hold fireworks as they take part in 'Correfoc' (Run with fire) party during the Night of San Juan in Barcelona, June 23, 2015.
The event coincides with the Summer solstice. This celebration takes place during the longest night of the year in almost all cities and towns of Spain.
Credit: Manu Fernandez/AP
Same-sex marriage ruling
Gay rights supporters celebrate after the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the U.S. Constitution provides same-sex couples the right to marry, outside the Supreme Court building in Washington, D.C., June 26, 2015.
The high court ruled 5-4 that the Constitution's guarantees of due process and equal protection under the law mean that states cannot ban same-sex marriages. With the ruling, gay marriage became legal in all 50 states.
Credit: Jim Bourg/Reuters
Al-Jazeera reporter released
Al-Jazeera reporter Ahmed Mansour waves to jubilant supporters moments after walking free from the JVA Moabit prison where he spent two days in Berlin, Germany,June 22, 2015.
German police, acting on an Egyptian arrest warrant, arrested Mansour at Tegel airport on June 20, 2015 as he was preparing to board a flight for Qatar. German authorities ordered Mansour's release. Critics claim the Egyptian charges against Mansour are a fabrication and that the case is politically motivated.
Credit: Sean Gallup/Getty Images
Republican presidential candidate Scott Walker
Wisconsin Governor and Republican presidential candidate Scott Walker addresses supporters during a dinner at the "Road to Majority" conference in Washington, June 20, 2015.
Credit: Carlos Barria/Reuters
Argentinian Victor Peralta  attends  the Sixth Expotattoo Colombia 2015, in Medellin, on June 20, 2015.
Credit: Raul Arboleda/AFP/Getty Images
Rainbow colored White House
The White House is illuminated in rainbow colors after the historic Supreme Court ruling legalizing gay marriage across the country in Washington, D.C., June 26, 2015.
Credit: Gary Cameron/Reuters
Triton migrants rescue operatons
A migrants stretches his arm from the deck of the Belgian Navy Vessel Godetia after being being picked up during a search and rescue mission in the Mediterranean Sea off the Libyan coast on Tuesday, June 23, 2015.
Hundreds of migrants were rescued by the Godetia, which is one of EU Navy vessels taking part in the Triton migrants rescue operations.
Credit: Gregorio Borgia/AP
Charleston - funeral for Ethel Lance
Brandon Risher, left, is pulled away by a friend as he cries over the casket of his grandmother, Ethel Lance, following her burial service in Charleston, June 25, 2015.
Ethel Lance was one of nine people killed in the shooting at Emanuel AME Church the previous week in Charleston.
Credit: David Goldman/AP
Iran - funeral
A child looks on June 25, 2015 as Iranian mourners in Tehran attend the funeral of Mohammad Hamidi, Hasan Ghafari and Ali Amrai, all three members of the Islamic Republic's Revolutionary Guards reportedly killed in Syria.
Credit: Atta Kenare/AFP/Getty Images
France - migrant chase
A police officer sprays tear gas to migrants trying to access the Channel Tunnel on the A16 highway on June 23, 2015 in Calais, northern France.
Credit: Philippe Huguen/AFP/Getty Images
Spain - La Saca de yeguas
Wild mares trot past the shrine of El Rocio during La Saca de yeguas at El Rocio, in Almonte, southern Spain June 26, 2015.
Every year on June 26, hundreds of wild mares are grouped together by riders at Donana National Park and taken to a livestock fair in Almonte village.
Credit: Marcelo del Pozo/Reuters, REUTERS
Obergefell at Supreme Court
Plaintiff Jim Obergefell holds a photo of his late husband John Arthur as he speaks to members of the media after the U.S. Supreme Court handed down a ruling regarding same-sex marriage June 26, 2015 in Washington, D.C.
Obergefell and Arthur sued to force their home state of Ohio, where same-sex marriage wasn't legal, to recognize their out-of-state union. Arthur died three months after the couple married in July 2013. After the landmark ruling, Obergefell said, "I felt more like and equal American than I had in a very long time."
Credit: Alex Wong/Getty Images
Texas - Harris and Evans wed
Judge Dennise Garcia, left front, watches as George Harris, center left, 82, and Jack Evans, center right, 85, kiss after being married by Judge Garcia in Dallas on Friday, June 26, 2015.
Gay and lesbian Americans have the same right to marry as any other couples, the Supreme Court declared Friday in a historic ruling deciding one of the nation's most contentious and emotional legal questions. Prior to the Supreme Court ruling gay marriage was not legal in Texas.
Credit: Tony Gutierrez/AP
Festival-goers attend the Hellfest music Festival in Clisson, France, June 20, 2015.
Credit: Stephane Mahe/Reuters
Obamacare ruling
Interns with media organizations run with the long-awaited decision upholding the Affordable Care Act at the Supreme Court in Washington, D.C. June 25, 2015.
The high court upheld the nationwide availability of tax subsidies that are crucial to the implementation of President Barack Obama's signature healthcare law, handing a major victory to the president.
Credit: Joshua Roberts/Reuters
Queen Elizabeth smiles at robot
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and Britain's Queen Elizabeth smile as a robot waves during their visit at the Technical University of Berlin (TU Berlin) in Berlin, Germany June 24, 2015. Queen Elizabeth and the Duke of Edinburgh are on a three day state visit to Germany.
Credit: Michael Sohn/Pool /Reuters
Clementa Pinckney's funeral
A mourner bows his head in prayer June 26, 2015 during the funeral service for Reverend Clementa Pinckney, who was killed along with eight others in a mass shooting  in Charleston, South Carolina on June 17, 2015.
Suspected shooter Dylann Roof, 21, is accused of killing nine people during a Bible study at Emanuel AME Church, one of the nation's oldest black churches in Charleston.
Credit: Win McNamee/Getty Images
Azerbaijan - steeplechase
Athletes clear the water jump during the Women's 3000 metres steeplechase during day nine of the Baku 2015 European Games at the Olympic Stadium on June 21, 2015 in Baku, Azerbaijan.
Credit: Matthias Hangst/Getty Images for BEGOC
Gaza City - destroyed car
Palestinian children look at the remains of a car on June 22, 2015 in Gaza City that was destroyed during 50-day war between Israel and Hamas-militants in the summer of 2014.
A widely anticipated United Nations report said both Israel and Palestinian militants may have committed war crimes during last year's Gaza war, decrying "unprecedented" devastation and human suffering.
Credit: Mahmud Hams/AFP/Getty Images
Austrian brass band
A brass band leaves the course ahead of the start of the Austrian Formula One Grand Prix on the Red Bull Ring racing circuit in Spielberg, Austria on June 21, 2015.
Germany's Nico Rosberg won the Austrian Grand Prix ahead of British teammate and overall drivers standings leader Lewis Hamilton, with Brazilian Felipe Massa, in a Williams, in third 17sec off the pace.
Credit: Joe Klamar/AFP/Getty Images
France - Grand Siecle day
People dressed in a character era costumes have a picnic in the grounds of the 17th century Chateau of Vaux-le-Vicomte, in Maincy near Paris, on June 21, 2015 during the annual Grand Siecle day experience, a rendez-vous for costume passionates.
The day also marks the 400th anniversary of the birth of Nicolas Fouquet, a French parliamentarian who bought the chateau and transformed the grounds and the building into what it is now.
Credit: Francois Guillot/AFP/Getty Images
Pakistan heat wave
A Pakistani volunteer puts an identification tag onto a body of a heatwave victim as other dead bodies are seen in the the cold storage of the Edhi morgue in Karachi, June 22, 2015.
A heatwave in Pakistan's largest city Karachi and other districts of southern Sindh province has killed at least more than 1,200 people.
The southern port city of Karachi saw temperatures reach as high as 45 degrees Celsius (111 degrees Fahrenheit) on June 20, just short of an all-time high in the city of 47 C in June 1979.
Credit: Rizwan Tabassum/AFP/Getty Images
England - anti-fracking protest
An anti-fracking demonstrator writes messages on a wall outside Lancashire County Hall in Preston, northwest England June 23, 2015, during a demonstration against the applications from energy firm Cuadrilla to start two fracking operations on nearby sites.
Credit: Paul Ellis/AFP/Getty Images
China - newborn panda twins
Newborn twin female panda cubs are seen inside an incubator at the Giant Panda Research Base in Chengdu, China, June 22, 2015. Giant panda Ke Lin at the base gave birth to the female twins.
Credit: China Daily/Reuters
French anti-Uber protest
French riot police stand next to an overturned car as striking French taxi drivers demonstrate at the Porte Maillot to block traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, June 25, 2015.
French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
Israeli Air Force pilots graduate
Israeli Air Force pilots throw their hats in the air as they celebrate during their graduation ceremony at the Hatzerim base in the Negev desert, near the southern city of Beersheva, on June 25, 2015.
Credit: Thomas Coex/AFP/Getty Images
India - floods
An aerial view shows flood victims standing atop their submerged houses in Amreli district of Gujarat, India, in this June 24, 2015 handout provided by the Indian Air Force.
At least 24 people have died due to heavy rains and flood related incidents in the western state of Gujarat, local media reported.
Credit: Indian Air Force/Handout/Reuters
New Delhi - soap bubble
People are reflected on a soap bubble lying on a road during the evening in New Delhi, India, June 23, 2015.
Credit: Anindito Mukherjee/Reuters
Reverend Clementa Pinckney's funeral
A South Carolina Highway Patrol honor guard stands next to the casket of Reverend Clementa Pinckney, who was also a state senator, before his funeral service, in Charleston, South Carolina, Friday, June 26, 2015.
President Barack Obama delivered the eulogy at Pinckney's funeral.
Credit: David Goldman/AP
Stonehenge - Summer Solstice
Revellers watch the sunrise as they celebrate the pagan festival of Summer Solstice at Stonehenge in Wiltshire, southern England on June 21, 2015.
The festival, which dates back thousands of years, celebrates the longest day of the year when the sun is at its maximum elevation. Modern druids and people gather at the landmark Stonehenge every year to see the sun rise on the first morning of summer.
Credit: Niklas Halle'n/AFP/Getty Images
Burundi - traditional dance
A man does a traditional dance before a member of the ruling party, the National Council for the Defense of Democracy-Forces for the Defense of Democracy (CNDD-FDD), speaks in Mpanda, Burundi, June 23, 2015.
Credit: Spencer Platt/Getty Images
Sister Nirmala Joshi's funeral
Nuns pray as they surround the body of Sister Nirmala Joshi, who succeeded Mother Theresa as the head of the Missionaries of Charity, in Kolkata, India, Tuesday, June 23, 2015. The 81-year-old nun, whose health had been declining in recent days, died early Tuesday.
Credit: Bikas Das/AP
California - El Carrizo Hot Shots
Members of El Carrizo Hot Shots crew work through the night to try to contain the Lake Fire in the San Bernardino National Forest, California, June 19, 2015.
Credit: David McNew/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:52:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry returns to Iranian nuclear accord talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/kerry-returns-to-iranian-nuclear-accord-talks/</Link>
        <Description>After breaking his leg in a cycling accident, Secretary of State John Kerry is back in Vienna to negotiate with Iran. Kerry is under pressure to deliver President Obama's chief foreign policy goal - a nuclear accord. Margaret Brennan reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kerry returns to Iranian nuclear accord talks
June 27, 2015, 6:42 PM
|After breaking his leg in a cycling accident, Secretary of State John Kerry is back in Vienna to negotiate with Iran. Kerry is under pressure to deliver President Obama's chief foreign policy goal - a nuclear accord. Margaret Brennan reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:44:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry under pressure to deliver nuclear deal with Iran</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/iran-nuclear-deadline-just-days-away/</Link>
        <Description>Pressure mounting at home and abroad on secretary of state to finalize a deal before time runs out</Description>
        <MainBody>Secretary of State John Kerry is heading back to Vienna, Austria, to finalize a nuclear deal with Iran. The deadline is four days away. The agree...
He also wants all financial sanctions on Iran to be lifted immediately, not gradually as the U.S. has proposed.
There's pressure at home, too. Several former Obama aides warned in a recent letter that the emerging deal "may fall short of meeting the administration's own standard of a 'good' agreement."
James Jeffrey, the president's former ambassador to Iraq, signed that letter.
"We are worried that the administration is going to do a rush to signature and essentially cave to the supreme leader's most recent and absurd red lines," Jeffrey told CBS News.
From left, U.S. Secretary of Energy Ernest Moniz, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry and U.S. Under Secretary for Political Affairs Wendy Sherman meet with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, second from right, at a hotel in Vienna, Austria, June 27, 2015.
Carlos Barria/AP
Ali Rezaian's stake in a diplomatic breakthrough is personal. His brother, Washington Post Reporter Jason Rezaian, is in a Tehran prison on charges of espionage.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:16:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/france-terror-suspect-selfie-beheaded-victim/</Link>
        <Description>Investigators looking into what truck driver with history of radical Islamic ties did with the photo</Description>
        <MainBody>Yassine Salhi was arrested in France Friday, accused of beheading his boss and trying to cause an explosion at a plant. CBS News correspondent Ma...
One of the officials said the selfie was forwarded via WhatsApp, the globally popular instant messaging system owned by Facebook, to a phone number in Canada. The officials spoke to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because the investigation was ongoing.
No group immediately claimed responsibility. The severed head appeared to mimic ISIS' practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. French authorities say Salhi had links to radical Salafists in the past.
Paris prosecutor's office spokeswoman Agnes Thibault-Lecuivre said the leading suspect began speaking with investigators after first refusing to do so. She declined to provide details, but said investigators haven't found any foreign connection.
The site of the beheading wasn't yet known to investigators, and the victim had been strangled beforehand, she said.
A fourth person arrested Friday was released without being charged. Under French anti-terrorism laws, Salhi and the women can be held up to four days before either being released or handed preliminary charges and locked up.
View Gallery
A French special police forces officer gestures as police escort a woman from a residential building during a raid in Saint-Priest, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
President Francois Hollande's office said he will convene a meeting with top parliamentary leaders about the matter on Tuesday.
Separately on Saturday, hundreds of people turned out in the region to honor slain businessman Herve Cornara and denounce the violence. Dozens turned out for a minute of silence in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the town southeast of Lyon where Friday's attack took place at an Air Products chemicals warehouse.
Several hundred people also gathered outside a housing project in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone to honor Cornara, 54, the manager of a transportation company that had employed Salhi since March. They recalled a kind, humble man who was active in the community of the Lyon suburb.
"He lived on the fifth floor, me on the fourth. He spoke with all the young people in the neighborhood. He didn't differentiate between (non-Muslim) French and Muslims," said Leila Bouri, a 24-year-old cafeteria cashier. "If you ever had a problem, you would go see him."
"When I heard this, I was shocked. It's shameful," she said. "I am a Muslim, but you can't kill like this. It's not who we are. In Islam, we're not told to slit throats. We only slit the throats of sheep. You don't slit the throats of people."
The suspected killer, she added, "isn't a Muslim in my opinion."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:50:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Is Tunisia the next hotbed of terror activity?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/tunisia-the-next-hotbed-of-terror-activity/</Link>
        <Description>Once a bright spot of democratic success, Tunisia is now "facing a growing sense of terrorist threat and dread," an expert says</Description>
        <MainBody>ByReena FloresCBS NewsJune 27, 2015, 4:15 PM
Is Tunisia the next hotbed of terror activity?
Shares
After an attack at a Tunisian beach resort left at least 39 people dead -- many of them western tourists -- the world is once again focusing on the country as a hotbed of terrorist activity.
"In Tunisia, you have the problem that you have terrorist groups and operatives operating in a country that has been relatively stable compared to its neighbors," CBS News senior national security analyst Juan Zarate said, contrasting Tunisia from Libya and Egypt as a "bright spot" in the wake of the Arab Spring.
Tunisia is the only country in the region to have built a democratic system after the revolutions that rocked the Middle East and North Africa.
There have been a string of terror attacks overseas that have left over 60 dead and hundreds injured. In France, a man with a history of radical ...
"But the reality is they've been facing a growing sense of terrorist threat and dread," Zarate added. "You've seen these episodes of attacks, and certainly what you're seeing here is, I think, another episode where terrorists are trying to impose themselves either from the outside of Tunisia or taking advantage of terrorist operatives that are operating there in Tunisia."
An ISIS Twitter account claimed responsibility for the attack in Sousse , posting a photograph of the gunman, Seifeddine Rezgui, a Tunisian student who was later shot dead by security forces.
The country is no stranger to terror attacks. In March, gunmen at the national museum killed 22 people near the parliament building in Tunis. In 2013, the city of Sousse was also the site of a failed suicide bomber attack.
Tunisia Prime Minister Habib Essid announced Saturday that his administration would toughen security measures, including closing mosques known for embracing extremist ideologies and calling up army reservists.
Eyewitnesses describe deadly attack at Tunisia resort
"The fight against terrorism is a national responsibility," Essid, who came under fire in March after the national museum massacre exposed governmental security weaknesses , said at a press conference early Saturday. "We are at war against terrorism which represents a serious danger to national unity during this delicate period that the nation is going through."
Zarate, who served as the deputy national security adviser for combating terrorism under President George W. Bush, isn't surprised that the terror attack struck a western target in the Tunisian city. He notes that the mass assault was specifically "trying to hit western tourists."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:26:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eyewitnesses describe deadly attack at Tunisia resort</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/isis-claims-credit-tunisia-attack-eyewitnesses-deadly-assault/</Link>
        <Description>ISIS claims credit for gunman's assault on beach resort as thousands of tourists plan to leave North African country</Description>
        <MainBody>A gunman attacked a popular beach resort in Tunisia Friday, killing dozens of people, mostly foreign tourists. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'A...
"The fight against terrorism is a national responsibility," said a visibly exhausted Habib Essid at a press conference in Tunis early Saturday. "We are at war against terrorism which represents a serious danger to national unity during this delicate period that the nation is going through."
He announced a string of tough measures to fight extremism, including examining the funding of organizations suspected of promoting radicalism, closing some 80 mosques outside government control and declaring certain mountainous zones military areas.
At the Imperial Marhaba Hotel where the attack took place, vans and buses were carrying away tourists on Saturday. While the hotel was not actually closing down, the tour operators had urged everyone to leave, the director said.
"We may have zero clients today but we will keep our staff," said Mohammed Becheur, adding the 370-room hotel had been at 75 percent occupancy before the attack.
View Gallery
Tourists console each other following a shooting attack in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital, June 26, 2015.
Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tourism is a key part of Tunisia's economy and had already fallen some 25 percent after a terrorist attack on the national museum in the capital Tunis that killed 22 people in March.
"It's really sad but what can you do, for everyone, for the tourists, for the people who died, for their families," said Belgian tourist Clause Besser, as he recovered in the hospital from a gunshot wound he received fleeing from the attacker. "For me, somehow, with a bullet in the leg, it's not a catastrophe. For those who died or were injured for life, it's something else."
British travel companies Thomson and First Choice said they are flying back thousands of tourists from Tunisia Saturday and are canceling all flights to the country in the coming week. Tourist flights from Ireland to Tunisia have continued in the wake of the attack, but travel agents are offering full refunds for those canceling. Slovakia has sent a plane to evacuate some 150 of its citizens who are currently in Tunisia, according to the Foreign Ministry, and Scandinavian tour operators have stopped all flights to the North African country for the rest of the season.
"We felt a bit scared because Sousse isn't that far away, it's only 40-50 kilometers (25-30 miles) from where we stayed," said Kathrin Scheider as she waited in line to check in to her flight out of the country at the Hammamet airport near Sousse. "We felt quite safe during the whole holiday, but as soon as we heard, we were quite happy to leave because you don't feel that safe anymore if something happens like that."
The Tunisian Ministry of Health has confirmed the nationalities of 10 of the 39 victims of the attack , including eight Britons, a Belgian and a German. The government of Ireland said an Irish nurse was also among those who were killed.
Relatives and family friends say Lorna Carty was fatally shot as she sunbathed. She and her husband, Declan, had received the holiday as a present to help Declan Carty relax following his recent heart surgery. Family friends speaking to the couple's two children said Lorna Carty went ahead of her husband to the beach, where she suffered fatal gunshot wounds and was pronounced dead in hospital.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:11:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France factory attack suspect in custody</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/france-factory-attack-suspect-in-custody/</Link>
        <Description>The suspected Islamic terrorist killed one man at a gas factory owned by an American company near the city of Lyon. Mark Phillips reports with the latest near the factory site.</Description>
        <MainBody>France factory attack suspect in custody
June 27, 2015, 7:49 AM
|The suspected Islamic terrorist killed one man at a gas factory owned by an American company near the city of Lyon. Mark Phillips reports with the latest near the factory site.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:48:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 39 dead in attack on Tunisian resort</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/at-least-39-dead-in-attack-on-tunisian-resort/</Link>
        <Description>There have been a string of terror attacks overseas that have left over 60 dead and hundreds injured. In France, a man with a history of radical Islamic ties tried to blow up an American-owned chemical plant. A decapitated body was found. In Kuwait, several people were arrested in the bombing attack on a mosque that killed at least 27 and injured more than 200. And in Tunisia, a gunman at a beach-resort killed at least 39 people, most of them western tourists. Charlie D'Agata reports from Sousse, Tunisia.</Description>
        <MainBody>At least 39 dead in attack on Tunisian resort
June 27, 2015, 7:40 AM
|There have been a string of terror attacks overseas that have left over 60 dead and hundreds injured. In France, a man with a history of radical Islamic ties tried to blow up an American-owned chemical plant. A decapitated body was found. In Kuwait, several people were arrested in the bombing attack on a mosque that killed at least 27 and injured more than 200. And in Tunisia, a gunman at a beach-resort killed at least 39 people, most of them western tourists. Charlie D'Agata reports from Sousse, Tunisia.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:20:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eye Opener: Manhunt intensifies for lone escapee</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/eye-opener-manhunt-intensifies-for-lone-escapee/</Link>
        <Description>The hunt for two prison escapees is now down to one. And, several states scramble to issue marriage licenses after the U.S. Supreme Court's ruling on same-sex marriage. All that and all that matters in today's Eye Opener. Your world in 90 seconds.</Description>
        <MainBody>Eye Opener: Manhunt intensifies for lone escapee
June 27, 2015, 7:10 AM
|The hunt for two prison escapees is now down to one. And, several states scramble to issue marriage licenses after the U.S. Supreme Court's ruling on same-sex marriage. All that and all that matters in today's Eye Opener. Your world in 90 seconds.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 09:51:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. beats China, heads to Women's World Cup semifinal</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/u-s-defeats-china-1-0-at-womens-world-cup/</Link>
        <Description>Victory means U.S. will face top -ranked Germany in tournament semifinal</Description>
        <MainBody>The U.S. women's soccer team pursuing World Cup glory...
Despite missing midfielders Megan Rapinoe and Lauren Holiday, who were suspended for yellow card accumulation, the U.S. managed a more attacking attitude and extended its unbeaten streak against China to 25 matches dating to 2003.
"I think it was a highly energized performance," U.S. coach Jill Ellis said. "I thought we took care of the ball well, still created a lot of opportunities. So, yeah, we're really pleased."
Morgan Brian replaced Holiday in the middle of field, with Tobin Heath and Kelley O'Hara -- making her first start since March -- the flanks. Amy Rodriguez started up top with Alex Morgan, injecting more pace, while Abby Wambach did not enter until the 86th minute.
Wearing the captain's armband, Lloyd got the breakthrough with her 65th goal in 200 international appearances. Julie Johnston lofted a long ball into the penalty area and Lloyd met it with her head 10 yards from the goal line and bounced the ball off the artificial turf and past goalkeeper Fei Wang. That brought cheers from the overwhelmingly pro-American crowd of 24,141 at Lansdowne Stadium.
"These are the moments I live for," Lloyd said after the game, CBSSports.com's Sean Wagner-McGough reported .
Before that, the best American chance was by Johnston in the 26th minute that was cleared in front of an open net by defender Li Dongna. Johnston also had a header off a corner kick in the 31st minute that popped over the crossbar.
Brian had a chance to double the lead in the 73rd, but her long strike hit a post, and Lloyd missed high on the rebound.
The U.S. had a 17-6 advantage in shots and its offense was less stagnant than in the round-of-16 win over Colombia. The American face a considerable challenge in Germany, which lost to Japan in overtime in the 2011 quarterfinals.
"The U.S. only netted one goal, but it finally played a game that resembled a top team in top form," Wagner-McGough wrote after the game. "The passing was crisper, the runs were more dangerous, and multiple goals were just inches away from materializing. For a U.S. team that has struggled so much on offense, the way in which it played has to give it confidence moving forward."
Germany advanced earlier by beating France 5-4 on penalty kicks after a 1-1 tie. The United States has an 18-4-7 overall record against the Germans, including a 3-2 advantage in World Cup matches.
In Saturday's quarterfinals, host Canada faces England and Australia plays defending champion Japan.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:57:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French taxi drivers smash cars in strike against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/french-taxi-drivers-smash-cars-in-strike-against-uber/</Link>
        <Description>Taxi drivers in France took to the streets to protest ride-sharing service, saying it is taking away their livelihood</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
PARIS - French taxi drivers smashed up livery cars, set tires ablaze and blocked traffic across the country on Thursday in a nationwide strike aimed at Uber after weeks of rising, sometimes violent tensions over the U.S. ride-hailing company.
Travelers going to and from the airport walked alongside highways with their bags or got caught in ambushes, like singer Courtney Love, who was rescued by two men on a motorcycle.
"They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage," Love tweeted. "They're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France- I'm safer in Baghdad."
It wasn't immediately clear what type of car Love was riding in.
Taxi drivers are angry, saying Uber's lowest cost service is taking their livelihood away.
Despite repeated rulings against the low-cost UberPop service, its drivers continue to ply French roads and the American company is actively recruiting drivers and passengers alike. Uber claims to have a total of 400,000 customers a month in France.
Striking taxi drivers block a street in Paris on June 25, 2015.
THOMAS SAMSON/AFP/Getty Images
Riot police chased strikers from Paris' ring road, where protesters torched tires in the middle of the roadway and swarmed onto exit ramps at rush hour.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, sent a litany of tweets on Thursday afternoon, including one to Kanye West suggesting she would have been better off staying at the airport with him. West later appeared at the Louis Vuitton menswear show, cool and calm.
She wrote: "paid some guys on motorcycles to sneak us out, got chased by a mob of taxi drivers who threw rocks, passed two police and they did nothing."
She later posted a selfie wearing a motorcycle helmet with her two smiling rescuers.
France's top security official said he had ordered an immediate ban on unlicensed services like UberPop in the Paris region but called for an end to violence against the service's drivers.
"We are calling for calm. We are in a state of law," Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said. "A state of law is not a state of violence."
Uber's more expensive livery service is still legal but a source of intense frustration for French taxi drivers, who pay tens of thousands of euros (dollars) for the equivalent of medallions and who face customer complaints that they are being resistant to changes such as credit cards and geolocation.
Taxi drivers complain that livery services like Uber unfairly undercut them and in recent weeks nearly 100 Uber drivers have been attacked, sometimes while carrying customers. One irritated taxi passenger was left with a broken face and black eye after he praised Uber.
"There are people who are willing to do anything to stop any competition," said Thomas Meister, a spokesman for Uber. "We are only the symptom of a badly organized market."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:59:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devastating heat wave slowly easing in Pakistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/death-tolls-till-climbing-as-devastating-heat-wave-slowly-subsides-in-pakistan/</Link>
        <Description>Even as the heat subsides, the death toll continues to rise</Description>
        <MainBody>APJune 25, 2015, 2:31 PM
Devastating heat wave slowly easing in Pakistan
Shares
More +
KARACHI, Pakistan - The devastating heat wave that struck southern Pakistan last weekend is slowly subsiding but the toll was still climbing Thursday,  a senior health official said.
While the Associated Press is reporting 860 confirmed deaths due to the heat, Reuters, citing government and hospital officials, reports more than 1,100 people have died since Saturday due to the searing heat.
Jam Mehtab Hussain, the provincial health minister in the southern Sindh province, said people were still being admitted to hospitals with heat-related ailments - though in smaller numbers than in previous days. Previously dehydrated patients lay in hospital corridors and outside on the streets as overwhelmed medical staff struggled to cope with the disaster.
Ahmad Kamal, a spokesman for the National Disaster Management Authority, said authorities were providing free medical treatment to people in Karachi, the capital of Sindh province. He said the situation was improving due to lower temperatures .
The death toll from the recent heat wave in Pakistan continues to soar, even as temperatures cool
On Thursday, the temperature dropped to 34 degrees Celsius (93.2 degrees Fahrenheit) in Karachi from a high of 45 degrees Celsius (113 degrees Fahrenheit) on Sunday.
TV footage showed ambulances transporting heatstroke patients to various hospitals in Karachi, where people continued holding small rallies against power outages, which had exacerbated the effects of the heat wave.
Weather pattern shift bringing more heat waves
The heat wave was the worst seen in the city since 1979, officials said, and came as Muslims were fasting from dawn to dusk for the holy month of Ramadan.
The drinking of even a single drop of water invalidates the fast, but Muslims are also encouraged not to fast if they are sick or if doing so would cause serious physical harm.
A man with his daughter who suffers from dehydration due to extreme weather waits for a medical help outside a ward at a child hospital in Karachi, Pakistan, Wednesday, June 24, 2015. A cool wind from the sea and pre-monsoon rains brought the first signs of respite to southern Pakistan on Wednesday as the death toll from a scorching heat wave climbed to over 800, a high figure even for a nation accustomed to sizzling hot summers.
AP Photo/Shakil Adil
Mohammad Ayaz said he and other Karachi residents were struggling to stay cool, with hundreds of people sleeping outside because of long power cuts.
Wakil Ahmed, another resident, said the weather had improved from previous days, when it was so hot it became difficult to breathe. He said Thursday brought clouds and a slight breeze.
Karachi is home to some 20 million people and has long suffered from an inefficient power grid and a shortage of potable water.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:45:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin vows to strengthen Russian military</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/putin-vows-to-strengthen-russian-military/</Link>
        <Description>Remarks to military academy graduates reflect soaring tensions between Moscow, the West over Ukraine</Description>
        <MainBody>APJune 25, 2015, 1:00 PM
Putin vows to strengthen Russian military
President Vladimir Putin speaks at the Kremlin's meeting with graduates of Russian military academies, Moscow, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Putin said that Russia needs a powerful military to fend off threats near its borders, a statement that reflects tensions with the West over the Ukrainian crisis.
Mikhail Klimentyev/RIA-Novosti, Kremlin Pool Photo via AP
Shares
More +
MOSCOW - Russia needs a mighty military to fend off threats near its borders, President Vladimir Putin said Thursday, in a stance that reflects soaring tensions with the West over the crisis in Ukraine.
The Russian leader, whose approval ratings reached an all-time high this month despite a bruising recession, said a "powerful army equipped with modern weapons is the guarantor of sovereignty and territorial integrity of Russia."
Speaking at Thursday's Kremlin meeting with graduates of Russian military academies, Putin also vowed to continue a sweeping military modernization effort that envisions the purchase of large numbers of new weapons.
Despite the fact that oil-rich Russia is now in a recession, Putin's plan aims to spend 22 trillion rubles (over $400 billion) through 2020 to give the armed forces dozens of navy ships, hundreds of new planes and missiles and thousands of tanks and other weapons.
Russian President Vladimir Putin is calling on the U.S. to stop telling Russia what to do. Putin spoke at a business conference in Russia, which ...
Putin added that Russia has no aggressive intentions and aims to "settle any disputes exclusively by political means with respect to international law and interests of other nations."
Relations between Russia and the West have sunk to post-Cold War lows after Moscow's 2014 annexation of Ukraine's Crimean Peninsula and its support for a pro-Russian insurgency in eastern Ukraine.
The United States and the European Union have responded with sanctions that have sharply limited Russia's access to Western capital markets and curtailed the transfer of military and energy technologies.
Russia retaliated by banning the import of agricultural products from the EU, U.S., Australia, Canada and Norway. The Cabinet formally extended the ban by one year after the EU agreed this week to keep its sanctions in place through January.
Coupled with plummeting prices for oil, Western sanctions helped drive the Russian economy into recession, resulting in a drop in incomes for the first time since Putin took the helm in 2000. But despite the economic woes, Putin's popularity has soared.
The president's approval rating reached an all-time high of 89 percent this month, according to a nationwide poll conducted by the Levada Center, a leading independent opinion research firm. The survey, based on interviews with 1,600 people, had a margin of error of no more than 3.4 percentage points.
Many observers attribute the solid support for Putin to blanket positive coverage of his activities by state television stations and other Kremlin-controlled media that have described the Ukrainian crisis as part of Western efforts to weaken Russia.
Levada head Lev Gudkov called the TV propaganda as the main factor behind Putin's popularity.
"This is a very aggressive and false propaganda," he said. "All alternative channels, therefore all alternative points of view, assessments are pushed out of the public sphere."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:48:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Marines heading to Bulgaria to convince "Putin to refrain from aggression"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-marines-heading-to-bulgaria-to-reassure-allies-amid-tension-with-russia/</Link>
        <Description>Announcement comes after Ash Carter says more American military equipment would be positioned in Europe</Description>
        <MainBody>After Russian planes flew too close to Swedish airspace, Sweden scrambled fighter jets to intercept the aircraft. As Russia flexes its muscle, it...
"Ideally this culminates with integrated exercises with units from more and more allied nations that are able to call for fire from one another's artillery, our tanks maneuver in support of their infantry units, and vice versa," he said.
The U.S. already regularly conducts maneuvers with allied countries. In Romania on Thursday, U.S Navy Adm. Mark E. Ferguson III, a top NATO commander, said recent exercises have shown that the alliance is capable of training and operating across northern and eastern Europe.
He also noted that NATO successfully relocated the Allied Joint Force Command temporarily from Italy to Romania for exercises this month involving 1,000 troops from 21 nations, as the alliance continues to hone its ability to react to Russia's moves in Ukraine or other security challenges.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 05:13:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Portraits of Tunisian terror attack victims begin to emerge</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/victims-of-deadly-tunisian-terror-attack-begin-to-emerge/</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of sunbathers were killed in a horrific attack at a Tunisian resort</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS News/APJune 26, 2015, 8:04 PM
Portraits of Tunisian terror attack victims begin to emerge
Shares
More +
SOUSSE, Tunisia -- A young man pulled a Kalashnikov from a beach umbrella and sprayed gunfire at European sunbathers at a Tunisian resort, killing at least 37 people - one of three deadly attacks Friday from Europe to North Africa to the Middle East that followed a call to violence by Islamic State extremists.
The Health Ministry said among  the 37 dead included Tunisians, British, Germans and Belgians, without giving a breakdown.
Dozens killed after gunman opens fire on tourists in a Tunisian tourist resort town
The Irish Times reports one of the victims was an Irish national, Lorna Carty, a nurse on vacation with her husband. The Times reports she had traveled to Tunisia with her husband after he gave her the trip as a present. He had recently underwent heart surgery. She has two children, Hazel, 18, and Simon, 21.
In a statement Irish Minister of Foreign Affairs and Trade, Charles Flanagan, confirmed the death of an Irish citizen.
"I condemn unreservedly the terrorist attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France today. Sadly, I can confirm that an Irish citizen has been killed in the attack in Sousse , Tunisia," he said.
Others began Tweeting about missing family members who they said had been in Tunisia at the time of the attack, but hadn't been heard from.
My nan, Eileen Swannack &amp;her partner John.Pls get in contact if any1 has news.They're stayin at riu imperial #Tunisia pic.twitter.com/HScE8VtDBZ
 Lucie Marie (@MissLucieMarie) June 26, 2015
Haven't spoke to my Dad since the attack, please, please, please RT as he is missing along with his partner #Tunisia pic.twitter.com/s1Mp2loO1W
 A$AP ROSSI (@rossinaylor) June 26, 2015
#FindSueDavey #Tunisia haven't spoke to my mom since attack an phone has been handed in please RT !! pic.twitter.com/RfwQQv49le
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 26, 2015
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond says at least five Britons were killed but expected to toll to rise because a high proportion of the dead were believed to be British.
Heroes also began to emerge in the midst of such devastation. The BBC reports , a Welsh tourist used his body as a shield to protect his Fianc when the shooting on the beach began. Saera Wilson, 26, the Fianc of gas engineer Matthew James, 30, said he is alive, but his pelvis is shattered after being shot three times.
The shootings in the Tunisian resort of Sousse happened at about the same time as a bombing at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and an attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France that included a beheading. It was unclear if the violence was linked but it came days after the IS militants urged their followers "to make Ramadan a month of calamities for the nonbelievers." In all, the assailants killed at least 65 people.
Photo on Saera Wilson's Facebook page with her Fianc, Matthew James. She told the BBC he shielded her when the bullets began flying.
Facebook
The attack in Tunisia, the country's worst ever, comes just months after the March 18 massacre at the national Bardo museum in Tunis that killed 22 people, again mostly tourists, and has called into question the newly elected government's ability to protect the country.
"Once again, cowardly and traitorous hands have struck Tunisia, targeting its security and that of its children and visitors," President Beji Caid Essebsi told reporters at the RIU Imperial Marhaba hotel, near the beach rampage site.
Essebsi promised "painful but necessary" measures, adding: "No country is safe from terrorism, and we need a global strategy of all democratic countries."
British tourist Gary Pine told AP he was on the beach with his wife around noon when heard the shooting. They shouted for their son to get out of the water, grabbed their bag and ran for the hotel. Their son told them he saw someone shot on the beach.
Tourists console each other following a shooting attack in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015.
FETHI BELAID/AFP/Getty Images
There was "sheer panic" at the hotel, Pine said. "There were a lot of concerned people, a few people in tears with panic and a few people - older guests - they'd turned their ankles or there was a few little minor injuries and nicks and scrapes."
Elizabeth O'Brien, an Irish tourist who was with her two sons, told Irish Radio she was on the beach when the shooting began.
"I thought, 'Oh my God. It sounds like gunfire,' so I just ran to the sea to my children and grabbed our things" before fleeing to their hotel room, she said.
The FBI and U.S. Department of Homeland Security issued a bulletin Friday warning of attacks against law enforcement officers and the military during the July 4th holiday.
CBS News/AP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:34:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man beheaded in France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/man-beheaded-in-france-terror-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Yassine Salhi was arrested in France Friday, accused of beheading his boss and trying to cause an explosion at a plant. CBS News correspondent Mark Phillips reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man beheaded in France terror attack
June 26, 2015, 7:18 PM
|Yassine Salhi was arrested in France Friday, accused of beheading his boss and trying to cause an explosion at a plant. CBS News correspondent Mark Phillips reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 06:32:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunman storms Tunis resort in deadly attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/gunman-storms-tunis-resort-in-deadly-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A gunman attacked a popular beach resort in Tunisia Friday, killing dozens of people, mostly foreign tourists. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gunman storms Tunis resort in deadly attack
June 26, 2015, 6:44 PM
|A gunman attacked a popular beach resort in Tunisia Friday, killing dozens of people, mostly foreign tourists. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:50:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Martin O'Malley outlines his plan to fight ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/omalley-boots-on-the-ground-vs-isis-could-be-counterproductive/</Link>
        <Description>The Democratic presidential candidate criticized 2003 Iraq invasion as a "mindless rush to war"</Description>
        <MainBody>The State Department acknowledged that the emails from presidential candidate Hillary Clinton's private email account are missing in some form. E...
"We must recognize that there are real lessons to be learned from the tragedy in Benghazi," he said. "Namely, we need to know in advance who is likely to take power or vie for it once a dictator is toppled."
Doug Wilson, who serves as O'Malley's senior foreign policy adviser and chair of the board of advisers at Truman, told reporters following O'Malley's remarks that the speech was not meant as a criticism of Hillary Clinton. Clinton, the frontrunner for the Democratic nomination in the presidential race, voted for the Iraq invasion as a senator and has been accused of mishandling the Benghazi attack during her tenure as Secretary of State.
"You see no mention of any candidates names in what he had to say," Wilson said. "You see only a mention of what he thinks this country needs to do in order to have a better shot at succeeding around the world."
He also defended the former Baltimore mayor and governor of Maryland's foreign policy experience.
"This governor has traveled. He has met with foreign leaders," he said, mentioning that O'Malley has met with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. "He has also met with leaders on regional and local levels and in civil society on his travels he believes these are people who are going to have influence on policies in their countries for a long time to come."
O'Malley's emphasis on partnerships runs through his entire vision of American foreign policy. He has called for more engagement around the world, in terms of national defense but also to combat what he calls "21st century challenges" like climate change and cyberterrorism.
"After 12 years on the battlefields of Iraq and Afghanistan," he said, "it is understandable that many Americans would like to disengage from the world. Understandable, but not responsible."
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman on trial for deaths of 8 of her babies</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/frenchwoman-on-trial-for-deaths-of-8-of-her-babies/</Link>
        <Description>The worst infanticide case in modern French history hinges on woman's claim that she was longtime victim of incest</Description>
        <MainBody>APJune 25, 2015, 12:43 PM
Woman on trial for deaths of 8 of her babies
Dominique Cottrez, flanked by her lawyer, Franck Berton, appears at the North Assize Court in Douai, France, June 25, 2015. Cottrez, a former nurse's aid, is charged with having killed eight of her children at birth since 1989.
PHILIPPE HUGUEN/AFP/Getty Images
More +
DOUAI, France - One day in the summer of 2010, a man was digging in his garden in northern France when he discovered a trash bag containing the remains of an infant. When he summoned the police, they found the body of another newborn. A few days later, they found more bags in the garage with six additional small corpses.
Police contacted the house's previous owners, and quickly discovered the horrifying explanation: Frenchwoman Dominique Cottrez confessed to secretly bearing and then killing eight of her newborns, saying she feared they were children of a long, incestuous relationship with her father.
Cottrez, a 51-year-old mother of two grown daughters, went on trial Thursday in the city of Douai, accused of multiple counts of first-degree murder of minors.
Cottrez wept as she took her seat. She faces life in prison if found guilty.
Her lawyers are expected to argue that she was a victim of rape and incest, and ask for a lesser sentence.
The worst infanticide case in modern French history stunned the country when the bodies were discovered in and around the Cottrez' former home in 2010.
Cottrez's obesity appeared to hide the pregnancies, which went unnoticed by her husband, children, neighbors, colleagues -- and even doctors at a nearby hospital.
Dozens of forensic and psychiatric experts, police investigators and witnesses, including her husband, daughters and siblings, are scheduled to testify to help understand the incomprehensible, and perhaps to help the defendant open up.
A withdrawn, secretive nurse's aide, Cottrez told investigators she was raped by her father, first when she was 8 and repeatedly through her childhood and teenage years, according to judicial documents. She later entered a long, incestuous relationship with him as an adult, including after she married, and said that it became consenting, and even said she was in love with her father more than she was with her husband.
Her father died in 2007.
One of the first witnesses called to the stand Thursday is Leonard Meriaux, who bought the Cottrez family house and discovered the first corpse in 2010.  He called police, who found another in the garden.
Anne Segond (left), president of the North Assize Court in Douai, France, speaks during the trial of Dominique Cottrez, who is charged with infanticide, on June 25, 2015.
PHILIPPE HUGUEN/AFP/Getty Images
From one interrogation to another, the police went from surprise to stupor. Cottrez first admitted killing the two infants found in the garden. Then she herself informed the investigators that several other bodies were in the garage of the house, but she didn't know how many exactly, according to court documents.
She told the investigating judge that she had never used contraception or had an abortion because of a phobia of doctors. She also said she didn't keep the babies because she was afraid that they were the results of her incestuous relations with her father. She said the killing had become a "means of contraception," according to the judicial documents.
She said she told her father of the eight pregnancies and the eight murders, and investigators believe he could have helped her hide some of the bodies.
The death she described the most clearly is the first one, in 1989. She said she smothered the baby boy with sheets, placed him in a trash bag that she had prepared in advance, and put the bag in her wardrobe, according to the documents.
The second killing happened when she was hospitalized for an epilepsy seizure. She said she gave birth in the hospital toilet, strangled the child, wrapped it in plastic sheeting and towels, placed it in the closet of her hospital room and then brought it back home, hidden in her garment bag.
Her memories became blurred for the following births and deaths. The last infanticide was in 2000.
Her husband and daughters say they noticed foul odors in various parts of the house, but thought they came from sewage, or their dog, or even their father's feet.
Cottrez was released from jail in 2012 after spending two years in temporary detention. In a January interview with a local newspaper, she said: "I never gave first names to the babies. The first one, I saw he was a baby boy. The others, I didn't look, I didn't want to. But when they were in the garage, when it was cold, I went there and covered them with a blanket. "
The verdict is expected next Thursday.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:08:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother, baby found alive 4 days after plane crash in jungle</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/mother-baby-found-alive-4-days-after-plane-crash-in-colombia-jungle/</Link>
        <Description>Woman and her one-year-old son survived deadly crash in Colombia jungle by drinking coconut water</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
BOGOTA, Colombia -- A woman who survived a jungle plane crash with her 1-year-old son drank coconut water to stay alive for four days until being rescued, Colombia's air force says.
Rescuers reached Maria Nelly Murillo and her child in a remote area of western Colombia and flew them to the nearby town of Quibdo for medical treatment on Wednesday. Murillo suffered some injuries and burns but the baby was unhurt.
They were aboard a twin-engine Cessna that crashed Saturday into the thick jungle shortly after taking flight from Quibdo, near the Pacific Ocean.
The pilot was killed, but rescuers said a load of fish on board absorbed much of the impact in the plane's cabin, allowing Murillo and her son to survive against the odds.
Colombia's air force posted images of the woman and her son on Twitter, calling the rescue a "miracle."
Un milagro en las selvas de Choc http://t.co/IjIkS6lEEQ va @RevistaSemana pic.twitter.com/8oPIRIg37v
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:08:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia beach terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/deadly-tunisia-beach-terror-attack/</Link>
        <Description>Dozens killed after gunman opens fire on tourists in a Tunisian tourist resort town</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Tunisia terror attack
At least 39 people, most of them Western tourists, were killed when a gunman opened fire on a Tunisian beachside hotel in the popular resort of Sousse on Friday, June 26, 2015.
Here, bodies of dead tourists lie near Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015. The majority of the tourists killed were from Britain, Germany and Beligum.
Credit: Amine Ben Aziza/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
Flowers at the scene of a beach terror attack in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015, the morning after a lone gunman killed at least 39 people at a beach resort.
Credit: Darko Vojinovic/AP
Tunisia terror attack
A young woman  lays flowers at the scene of a shooting  in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015, the morning after a lone gunman killed at least 39 people at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel.
Credit: Darko Vojinovic/AP
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisian security forces man a checkpoint at the entrance of the resort area where Imperial Marhaba Hotel is located on the outskirts of Sousse south of the capital Tunis, on June 27, 2015, in the aftermath of a shooting attack on the beach resort.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
People react at the site of a shooting attack on the beach in front of the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Port el Kantaoui, on the outskirts of Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Credit: Kenzo Tribouillard/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisian security forces stand in front of the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015, following a shooting attack.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Criss Callaghan, 62, a British tourist who was injured during an attack on the beachside Imperial Marhaba Hotel, is hugged by her husband as she lies in bed at a hospital in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Zoubeir Souissi/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
Police officers patrol Atocha train station in Madrid, Spain, June 27, 2015.
Spain said it was beefing up security around key infrastructure after attacks in France, Kuwait and Tunisia killed dozens on June 26, 2015.
Credit: Susana Vera/Reuters
Seifeddine Rezgui
This image taken from a militant website associated with ISIS extremists, posted June 27, 2015, purports to show Tunisian gunman Seifeddine Rezgui who killed tens at least 39 people in the Tunisian beach resort of Sousse on June 26, 2015.
Police have identified Seifeddine Rezgui, a young Tunisian student who was not previously known to authorities, as the gunman. Rezgui was shot dead by security forces.
Credit: Militant photo via AP
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists queue to leave Tunisia at the Enfidha international airport June 27, 2015, after the terrorist attack at the Imperial Marhaba Hotel on June 26, 2015.
British tourist companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, June 27, 2015, a day after a gunman killed at least 39 people as they lounged at the beach.
Credit: Zoubeir Souissi/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
Police officers control the crowd while surrounding a man (front C) after a gunman opened fire on a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, as a woman reacts (R), June 26, 2015.
Credit: Amine Ben Aziza/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists leave the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometers (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015, following a terrorist attack in the beach resort packed with foreign tourists, in the North African country's worst attack in recent history.
Credit: Kenzo Tribouillard/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists comfort each other after the mass shooting in the resort town of Sousse, Tunisia on June 26, 2015.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisian medics stand next to the bodies of tourists in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisia's President Beji Caid Essebsi (R) arrives in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, following the mass shooting on June 26, 2015.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisian medics carry an injured woman on a stretcher in the resort town of Sousse, Tunisia on June 26, 2015, following a shooting attack.
Credit: Mohamed Fliss/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisian men help an injured woman in the resort town of Sousse, Tunisia on June 26, 2015, following a shooting attack.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
European leaders
Spain's Interior minister Jorge Fernandez Diaz (2nd L) speaks with Socialist party representatives Patxi Lopez (3rd R) and Antonio Hernando (2nd R) and Jose Enrique Serrano (R) during an urgency meeting at the interior ministry, in Madrid on June 26, 2015.
European leaders condemned Friday's "heinous" suspected Islamist attack on a gas factory in France and massacres in Tunisia and Kuwait, vowing to stay united against "barbarism."
Credit: Dani Pozo/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
The body of a tourist shot dead by a gunman lies near a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Amine Ben Aziza/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
A Tunisian security member stands next to a swimming pool at the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015, following a shooting attack.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists are seen leaving the Imperial Marhaba hotel after a gunman opened fire on a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a weapon he had hidden in an umbrella. The victims were tourists, including those from Britain, Germany and Belgium, as they lounged at the beach and pool in the popular resort town.
The death toll from the shooting attack rose to 37, the health ministry said in a statement carried by state news agency TAP.
Credit: Stringer/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
Tunisian army soldiers arrive after a gunman opened fire on a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia June 26, 2015.
Credit: Stringer/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
The body of a tourist shot dead by a gunman lies near a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Amine Ben Aziza/Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists react in the Imperial hotel at the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
A broken glass window at the Imperiale Marhaba hotel is seen after a gunman opened fire at the beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia June 26, 2015.
Credit: Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
A security person escorts a tourist in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015, following a terrorist attack.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists are evacuated after a gunman opened fire on a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Reuters
Tunisia terror attack
The body of a tourist is seen poolside at the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
A general view shows ambulances parked in front of the Imperial Marhaba Hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015, following a shooting attack.
Credit: Bechir Taieb/AFP/Getty Images
Tunisia terror attack
Tourists react at the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 140 kilometres (90 miles) south of the Tunisian capital, on June 26, 2015, following a shooting attack.
Credit: Fethi Belaid/AFP/Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:01:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunman kills dozens in rampage at Tunisia beach resort</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/tunisia-hotel-attack-in-tourist-resort-town-of-sousse/</Link>
        <Description>Young man unfurls an umbrella and pulls out Kalashnikov, opening fire on European sunbathers; ISIS claims credit</Description>
        <MainBody>Dozens killed after gunman opens fire on tourists in a Tunisian tourist resort town
The killings in the Tunisian resort of Sousse happened at about the same time as a bombing at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and an attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France that included a beheadin g. It was unclear if the violence was linked but it came days after ISIS militants urged their followers "to make Ramadan a month of calamities for the nonbelievers." In all, at least 67 people were killed.
The SITE Intelligence Group reported later that the IS claimed credit for the Tunisia attack on its Twitter account and identified the gunman as Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani.
The attack in Tunisia, the country's worst ever, comes just months after the March 18 assault on the national Bardo museum in Tunis that killed 22 people, again mostly tourists, and has called into question the newly elected government's ability to protect the country.
"Once again, cowardly and traitorous hands have struck Tunisia, targeting its security and that of its children and visitors," President Beji Caid Essebsi told reporters at the RIU Imperial Marhaba hotel, near the beach rampage site.
Essebsi promised "painful but necessary" measures, adding: "No country is safe from terrorism, and we need a global strategy of all democratic countries."
Rafik Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry, told The Associated Press that the attack was carried out by a young student not previously known to authorities. The shooting spree ended when he was shot to death by police.
The body of an unidentified tourist shot dead by a gunman lies near a beachside hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 26, 2015.
REUTERS
ISIS claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing at the Shiite mosque in Kuwait City that killed at least 27 people and wounded scores of other worshippers at midday prayers - the first such attack in the mostly quiet and relatively secure Gulf Arab nation in more than two decades.
In southeastern France, a man with ties to Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory, touching off an explosion that injured two people. Authorities arriving at the site made a grisly discovery: the severed head of the driver's employer was found hanging at the plant entrance.
The suspect, Yassine Salhi, was seized by an alert firefighter, authorities said, and French President Francois Hollande said the attacker's intention had been to cause an explosion. A security alert for the southeast region was raised to its highest level for the next three days, and the U.S. Embassy in Paris warned American citizens to be vigilant.
In an audio recording released Tuesday, ISIS called on its supporters to increase attacks during Ramadan and "be keen on waging invasion in this eminent month and commit martyrdom."
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
