<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 07:02:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>International headlines: May 26, 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/international-headlines-may-26-2015/</Link>
        <Description>Largest hotel in the world set to be built in Mecca; Kenyan lawyer offers President Obama dowry for Malia; scenes from 'Game Of Thrones' Season 6 to be filmed in Spain; and a robotic kitchen that does the cooking for you.</Description>
        <MainBody>International headlines: May 26, 2015
May 28, 2015, 7:49 PM
|Largest hotel in the world set to be built in Mecca; Kenyan lawyer offers President Obama dowry for Malia; scenes from 'Game Of Thrones' Season 6 to be filmed in Spain; and a robotic kitchen that does the cooking for you.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:22:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fishing in Cuba, Hemingway style</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/fishing-in-cuba-hemingway-style/</Link>
        <Description>Ernest Hemingway's grandsons, Patrick and John, recently participated in a fishing tournament off Cuba's coast. For the first time in decades, several American vessels were allowed to participate. CBS News correspondent Dean Reynolds reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fishing in Cuba, Hemingway style
May 28, 2015, 7:05 PM
|Ernest Hemingway's grandsons, Patrick and John, recently participated in a fishing tournament off Cuba's coast. For the first time in decades, several American vessels were allowed to participate. CBS News correspondent Dean Reynolds reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 06:12:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA boss Sepp Blatter remains defiant in face of scandal</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/fifa-boss-sepp-blatter-remains-defiant-in-face-of-scandal/</Link>
        <Description>"I cannot monitor everyone, all the time," said Sepp Blatter on Thursday. The president of FIFA said he'd cooperate with investigators but deflected all responsibility in a scandal involving bribery and corruption. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>FIFA boss Sepp Blatter remains defiant in face of scandal
May 28, 2015, 6:59 PM
|"I cannot monitor everyone, all the time," said Sepp Blatter on Thursday. The president of FIFA said he'd cooperate with investigators but deflected all responsibility in a scandal involving bribery and corruption. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:27:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Washington Post hits back at Iran over reporter claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/iran-obama-letter-jason-rezaian-washington-post/</Link>
        <Description>Iran accuses jailed journalist on trial for espionage of writing letter to Obama</Description>
        <MainBody>Ali Rezaian, brother of Jason Rezaian, a Washington Post reporter charged with espionage by Iran, says he has deteriorated mentally and physicall...
Baron said Rezaian received an unsigned, form response by email to his online job application and was never hired. He continued work as a freelance journalist in Tehran until he began reporting for the Post in 2012 as its full-time Tehran correspondent.
"Jason never wrote directly to President Obama and was never hired by the Obama administration," Baron said.
Rezaian, his wife, Yeganeh Salehi, and two photojournalists were detained on July 22 in Tehran. All were later released except Rezaian, who was born and spent most of his life in the United States, and who holds both American and Iranian citizenship. Iran does not recognize other nationalities for its citizens.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:45:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man's fight with bear in Warsaw zoo "could have ended much worse"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/fight-with-bear-in-warsaw-zoo-could-have-ended-much-worse/</Link>
        <Description>Officials at the zoo in Warsaw, Poland say they don't know why an unidentified man tussled with the animal then disappeared, but he later surfaced in a hospital</Description>
        <MainBody>At Little Rock Zoo in Arkansas, a child was injured after he fell over the railing, into the jaguar exhibit and was attacked by the animals. KTHV...
Blood was found Sunday outside the enclosure. A witness then posted photos on the Internet showing the man inside, bare-footed and in shorts. In one photo he has his right palm in the bear's mouth. From other photos it appears the bear, a female named Sabina, tried to bite his arm and that the man hit the bear. From the photos it is not clear which happened first.
However, the tabloid Fakt, citing witnesses, reported Wednesday that it was the man who first attacked Sabina, hitting the 200-kilo (440-pound) bear with his fists.
"He survived only thanks to a miracle," Fakt wrote.
Krakowiak said the zoo is hoping that city authorities will now install cameras to monitor the bear's enclosure. A popular fixture in Warsaw for decades, the enclosure is on a busy street, a few hundred yards from the zoo proper.
Police spokeswoman Paulina Onyszko told The Associated Press that police informed the man that he could face a fine of up to around $270 if found guilty of provoking the animal into aggression.
The case was being sent to court, Onyszko said; she did not know when the hearing could take place.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:26:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA arrests shine new light on Qatar World Cup deaths</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/fifa-scandal-qatar-world-cup-deaths/</Link>
        <Description>Migrant worker deaths following Middle East country's winning bid has been estimated at more than 1,000</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APMay 28, 2015, 2:40 PM
FIFA arrests shine new light on Qatar World Cup deaths
Shares
Soccer analyst and co-host of podcast and TV show "Men in Blazers," says the allegations are "what we have always known but have never been able ...
The Supreme Committee for Delivery and Legacy, which is leading Qatar's development of World Cup venues and other projects, has so far declined repeated requests to comment since the investigations became public on Wednesday. So has Qatar's government.
Although FIFA spokesman Walter de Gregorio said there will be no re-vote for hosting of the 2018 and 2022 World Cups, the investigations nonetheless increase the pressure on Qatar. Its winning bid has been assailed by critics over a host of issues ranging from allegations of corruption to questions over migrant workers.
The World Cup is about to kick off in Brazil, but FIFA is scrambling to save the 2022 game in Qatar that is caught up in a bribery scandal. Mark ...
Organizers have denied wrongdoing, but World Cup sponsors Adidas, Coca-Cola and Visa last week publicly pressured FIFA to push Qatar harder on improving working conditions, with Visa saying it has expressed "grave concern" about labor conditions.
In a 2014 report, the International Trade Union Confederation estimated (PDF) that 1,200 World Cup workers have died since Qatar was named host in 2010.
A recent history of FIFA scandals
The group estimated that at least 4,000 more workers will die before its World Cup starts in 2022. The estimation was based on statistics from the Indian and Nepali embassies. The group said about half of the migrant workers comes from those two countries.
The Washington Post compared worker fatalities from Qatar's World Cup against deaths from preparing such events as last year's Olympics in Sochi, Russia, and the London Olympics in 2012. The newspaper posted a chart illustrating the wide gap to Twitter.
The human toll of FIFA's corruption, in one chart http://t.co/reXXZRhkt4 pic.twitter.com/7NI1QiVxPF
 Washington Post (@washingtonpost) May 27, 2015
Last week, a BBC reporting crew spent two nights in a Qatari prison after being arrested while trying to meet migrant workers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:01:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. charges 15 Chinese nationals in SAT fraud scheme</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/united-states-charges-15-chinese-nationals-in-sat-fraud-scheme/</Link>
        <Description>Imposters allegedly took college entrance exams using counterfeit passports</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS NewsMay 28, 2015, 1:38 PM
U.S. charges 15 Chinese nationals in SAT fraud scheme
AP
More +
Fifteen Chinese nationals have been indicted by a federal grand jury in Pennsylvania in connection with a fraud scheme where imposters used counterfeit passports to take college and graduate school entrance exams.
The 35-count indictment, which was handed down on May 21, includes charges of conspiracy, counterfeiting foreign passports, mail fraud and wire fraud, U.S. Attorney David J. Hickton for the Western District of Pennsylvania announced Thursday.
The indictment alleges that between 2011 and 2015, the defendants engaged in a conspiracy to defraud Educational Testing Services (ETS) and the College Board by having imposters take college and graduate school standardized entrance examinations, such as the Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEF), the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT) and the Graduate Record Examination (GRE).
The indictment names as defendants: Han Tong, Xi Fu, Xiaojin Guo, Yudong Zhang, Yue Zou, Biyuan Li aka "Jack Li," Jia Song, Ning Wei, Gong Zhang, Songling Peng, Siyuan Zhao and Yunlin Sun.
The identities of three additional defendants have not been released.
The indictment alleges the conspirators had Chinese passports made and sent to the United States, which then were used to trick ETS administrators into believing they were other people, namely the conspirators who would receive the benefit of the imposter's test score for use at American colleges and universities.
The majority of the fraudulent exams were allegedly taken in western Pennsylvania.
"These students were not only cheating their way into the university, they were also cheating their way through our nation's immigration system," said Special Agent in Charge John Kelleghan for Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) of Philadelphia.
Those charged face up to 20 years in prison on the wire and mail fraud charges, up to 10 years in prison on the counterfeiting charges and up to five years in prison on the conspiracy charges.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:55:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Roger Bennett: FIFA is "a rotten culture to the core"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/replacing-fifa-president-sepp-blatter-may-not-solve-corruption-says-roger-bennett/</Link>
        <Description>"Men in Blazers" co-host offers his take on scandal embroiling soccer's governing body and its president, Sepp Blatter</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS News talks with former U.S. Men's National Team soccer player Alexi Lalas on the impact the arrest of top FIFA officials might have on the sp...
"Sources in England have been investigating him for years, and every time the English papers investigate him, he uses it to rally his base. This is Chicago politics on a global scale. That's how FIFA works. It's a medieval fiefdom. There's no Democratic process, there's no transparency. Every time they investigate him he rallies his base in Africa, rallies his base in Asia and says 'They're trying to push us down,'" Bennett said.
Most recently, he has come under fire as investigators look into corruption related to the Qatar 2022 selection.
Last year, The Sunday Times said a "senior FIFA insider" had provided a vast quantity of emails and other documents detailing payments totaling $5 million that Qatari official Mohamed bin Hammam allegedly gave football officials to build support for the bid.
Hours after American officials made sweeping arrests, Swiss officials launched criminal proceedings , looking into FIFA's awarding of the 2018 World Cup to Russia, and the 2022 World Cup to Qatar -- or as Bennett said, an investigation into the "bags of money that have swapped hands."
"To have the World Cup in Qatar -- Qatar is as big as Connecticut, the population is as large as New Mexico, it's 122 degrees there in the summer, Mars or Antarctica would be as logical. It's obviously a little questionable," he said.
Russian President Vladimir Putin accused the U.S. of meddling in international soccer, saying the corruption investigation is an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from his country.
Blatter is up for reelection Friday and is expected to win. It remains to be seen how these latest allegations will affect the vote.
UK Prime Minister David Cameron recently endorsed Blatter's opponent.
"With the election on Friday this will either going to happen very quickly and he'll be pulled away or this is going to be a long embroiled investigation which will pull in massive global brands and be humiliating for all," Bennett said.
The indictment also noted "a multinational sportswear company" bribed a Brazilian soccer official for a sponsorship deal. While Nike isn't named in that indictment, its website says the company signed a sponsorship deal with the Brazilian Soccer Federation in 1996, the same year the events described in the indictment took place.
As the investigation continues, advertisers like Visa, Budweiser, Coke and McDonald, Bennett said, are turning up the heat .
"Right now VISA are the first to come out to say they're extremely concerned, which is marketing language for they're applying pressure, they need to take it to the next level. There's marketing code words that make it clear that if money, which is the only language that FIFA understands, is going to still be siphoned to them, they have to make that transition at the top."
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:40:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA chief speaks out after soccer officials arrested</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/fifa-president-sepp-blatter-racketeering-case-cast-a-long-shadow-football/</Link>
        <Description>Sepp Blatter says U.S. racketeering case has "cast a long shadow over football"</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS News Homeland Security Correspondent Jeff Pegues talks with CBS News Senior National Security Analyst Juan Zarate about the U.S. indictments ...
In addition, Swiss officials are investigating the FIFA votes that sent the World Cup tournament to Russia in 2018 and to Qatar in 2022. Both decisions were marred by allegations of wrongdoing.
One of FIFA's major sponsors, Visa, warned Thursday that it could pull out of its contract, which is worth at least $25 million a year through 2022.
Visa urged FIFA "to take swift and immediate steps to address these issues within its organization."
While acknowledging that many people hold him responsible for FIFA's tattered image, Blatter blamed the "actions of individuals" for harming the organization.
"If people want to do wrong, they will also try to hide it," he said. "I will not allow the actions of a few to destroy the hard work and integrity of the vast majority of those who work so hard for football."
Blatter said the crisis could mark a "turning point" for FIFA to clean itself up.
"We will cooperate with all authorities to make sure anyone involved in wrongdoing, from top to bottom, is discovered and punished," he said. "There can be no place for corruption of any kind. The next few months will not be easy for FIFA. I'm sure more bad news will follow. But it is necessary to begin to restore trust in our organization."
Referring to Friday's election, Blatter said: "We have the opportunity to begin on what will be a long and difficult road to rebuilding trust. We have lost their trust, at least a part of it, and we must now earn it back."
The seven soccer officials, including Jeffrey Webb, president of the North and Central American and Caribbean regional body known as CONCACAF, were arrested in a police raid on a luxury Zurich hotel early Wednesday. They are fighting extradition to the United States.
Defendants named in the indictment face up to 20 years in prison and their questioning could reveal further evidence that leads back to Blatter's Zurich-based organization. Webb was a member of FIFA's audit committee more than a decade ago.
Swiss investigators began questioning 10 of Blatter's colleagues on the FIFA executive committee from 2010 that chose Russia and Qatar as the next two World Cup hosts.
International Olympic Committee President Thomas Bach said Blatter and FIFA can learn from the way the Olympic body cleaned itself up after the vote-buying scandal involving Salt Lake City's winning bid for the 2002 Winter Games.
Bach urged Blatter - who is also an IOC member - to "take all necessary measures" following the U.S. and Swiss corruption investigations, adding: "In the IOC we know from experience 15 years ago that this fight is challenging and painful."
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said he supported the idea of delaying the FIFA election, given the current corruption scandal and told France-Inter radio, "There have been accusations of corruption for years."
But Russian President Vladimir Putin came to the defense of Blatter and FIFA, accusing the U.S. of meddling in soccer's internal affairs and hinting it was part of an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from his country.
"Our American counterparts, unfortunately, are using the same methods to reach their goals and illegally persecute people," Putin said in a TV interview, comparing the case to those of whistleblowers Julian Assange and Edward Snowden.
"I have no doubt that this is yet another evident attempt to derail Mr. Blatter's re-election as FIFA president," Putin said.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:45:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>England town bans mankinis in the name of peace</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/newquay-england-mankini-ban-drops-crime-rate/</Link>
        <Description>Seaside resort town of Newquay was plagued by rowdy groups of young bachelors in revealing garments -- but no longer</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
LONDON -- It was one small ban for mankinis, one giant step for an English seaside resort town.
Officials in Newquay say crime has fallen since they cracked down on stag parties - the days-long, booze-fuelled British version of the bachelor party -- wearing the revealing one-piece garments.
The town in southwest England is a haven for surfers and also attracts large numbers of young partygoers.
After two teenagers fell from cliffs to their deaths in 2009, residents protested about the excessive partying.
Police clamped down on anti-social behavior, including public drunkenness and the wearing of "inappropriate clothing" such as the sling-style swimsuits made notorious by comic character Borat.
Mayor David Sleeman said Thursday the town was unrecognizable from a few years ago, when "you couldn't walk the streets on a Saturday without seeing someone wearing a mankini or what have you."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:39:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Walking the tightrope of dissent in China</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/china-crackdown-on-dissent-against-communist-party-and-xi-jinping-a-mixed-bag/</Link>
        <Description>One man took government regulators to task, and was invited to brief leaders, while another has been jailed over a picture</Description>
        <MainBody>Censorship and repression by China's government have grown over the last two years, according to a new human rights report. But it appears that t...
"It was so unexpected," Wu said after returning from his first-ever visit to the secluded Zhongnanhai political compound in the Chinese capital.
In a country where ordinary people often say their voices are never heard and where critics of the government routinely get silenced, harassed and even jailed , Wu's experience seems exceptional: It suggests a leadership that, in its efforts to stamp out corruption and improve government efficiency, is willing to hear unflattering accounts.
"I have come to believe that the Chinese government, like any other government, really cares about what people think and wants to hear different voices," said Wu, who also sits on a political advisory board for a city district in Beijing.
Wu, who owns 65 hotels in more than 20 Chinese cities, was motivated by his desire to fix problems in the country's vast local bureaucracy as the country tries to give private enterprise a more central place in the economy. That aligns him squarely with stated priorities of the central government.
Wu is likely to have been vetted and deemed a friendly critic rather than one who is hostile to the ruling Communist Party, said Willy Lam, an expert on Chinese politics at Chinese University in Hong Kong.
"Unlike other critics, Mr. Wu does not question the ruling party's legitimacy," Lam said of Wu's opinions. "It's also possible this is propaganda warfare to show that the authorities are not intolerant but can tolerate criticism."
But it all depends who the criticism is coming from.
An obscure Chinese artist was detained after posting a humorous portrait of President Xi Jinping online, his wife said Thursday.
Judy Zhu said police accused her husband, Dai Jianyong, of "creating a disturbance" after detaining him Tuesday near their Shanghai home.
Dai is known for posting eclectic photos on social media, including some showing himself and others scrunching up their lips and eyes. Dai posted images of Xi with the same expression while wearing a moustache.
Some online commentators have compared the Xi portrait to Adolf Hitler, although Dai's Instagram image has much broader moustache than the small, square-shaped, "toothbrush moustache" associated with Hitler and Charlie Chaplin.
Dai faces up to five years in prison if convicted. Shanghai police didn't answer phone calls Thursday.
Xi's clampdown has also ensnared citizen activists who have posted eyewitness video and other information deemed embarrassing to authorities.
Earlier this month, Chinese authorities indicted the prominent rights lawyer Pu Zhiqiang for his online speech that questioned China's ethnic policies and derided several political figures. Whistle blowers who have turned to social media to expose government corruption often see themselves harassed or jailed for disrupting social order or provoking trouble.
Unlike them, Wu is not considered a threat to the state power, Lam said: "He is not attacking the party rule."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:13:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crunch time coming for Iran nuke talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/john-kerry-iran-nuclear-talks-deadline-looms-zarif-excessive-demands/</Link>
        <Description>Kerry headed back into the fray as negotiations over Iran's nuclear program face a deadline the U.S., at least, insists is firm</Description>
        <MainBody>Speaking to a large Jewish congregation in Washington, D.C., the president promised that he will "not accept a bad deal" with Iran over its nucle...
But he warned that "excessive demands" would make an agreement hard to envisage, even without a deadline.
The proposed deal would freeze Iran's nuclear program for a decade, in return for sanctions relief. Iran insists its nuclear program is solely for peaceful purposes, while the West fears it could allow it to build nuclear weapons.
The State Department said Wednesday that its lead nuclear negotiator, undersecretary Wendy Sherman, would leave her post when the negotiations with Iran are finished.
Sherman has led much of the technical discussion in Europe with Iranian officials over the last two years. During her tenure the U.S. and Iran reached an interim agreement in November 2013 and a framework pact in April.
Kerry called Sherman a "critical" member of his team, hailing her "tenacity and skill."
Kerry was to leave Washington on Thursday for Nigeria, where he'll attend Muhammadu Buhari's presidential inauguration.
From Geneva, Kerry will head to Madrid to meet with Spain's king and prime minister. Later, Kerry will attend a conference in Paris on fighting the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS).
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:36:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ash Carter seeks ways to improve Iraq training, equipment</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/ash-carter-seeks-ways-to-improve-iraq-training-equipment/</Link>
        <Description>The defense secretary says U.S. military leaders are looking for ways to improve and speed up training for Iraqi forces</Description>
        <MainBody>AP May 28, 2015, 8:38 AM
Ash Carter seeks ways to improve Iraq training, equipment
U.S. Secretary of Defense Ash Carter answers reporters' questions during a news conference with the United Kingdom Secretary of State for Defense Michael Fallon at the Pentagon March 11, 2015 in Arlington, Virginia. Chip Somodevilla, Getty Images
Shares
More +
U.S. military leaders are looking for ways to improve and speed up the program to train and equip Iraqi forces, including options to better prepare Sunni tribes to join the fight, Defense Secretary Ash Carter said Thursday.
Getting equipment to the battlefield more quickly and enhancing the training could help build the Iraqi forces' confidence, Carter said, just days after he publicly chastised them for showing "no will to fight" when they fled Ramadi last week even though they greatly outnumbered Islamic State militants .
"One particular way that's extremely important is to involve the Sunni tribes in the fight - that means training and equipping them," said Carter, who called a special meeting of his top advisers on Tuesday and tasked them to come up with options. "Those are the kinds of things the team back home is looking at."
Iraqi army regroups after losing Ramadi to ISIS
Iraqi officials have complained that they are not getting the heavy military equipment they need fast enough. And on Tuesday President Barack Obama said the U.S. and its allies must examine whether they are deploying military assets in Iraq effectively.
A senior defense official said Carter is not considering providing weapons directly to the Sunnis, and still wants to work through the Iraqi government. The official was not authorized to discuss the options publicly so spoke on condition of anonymity.
Iraqi forces have announced a counteroffensive against ISIS, designed to retake Anbar province. CBS News foreign forrespondent Holly Williams joi...
Speaking to reporters traveling with him to Asia, Carter said that the events in Ramadi "highlighted the central importance of having a capable ground partner" in Iraq.
"I think training and equipment affect the effectiveness of the forces and therefore their ability to operate, and their confidence in their ability to operate," said Carter. "So, there's a direct relationship."
Carter spoke at the start of an 11-day overseas trip that includes stops in Singapore for an international security conference and visits to maritime facilities in Vietnam and India.
According to officials, Carter met with Gen. Martin Dempsey, the Joint Chiefs chairman, Gen. Lloyd Austin, his top Middle East commander, and other key policy officials to the Tuesday session and told them he wanted options for improving and hastening the training and equipping program.
Has Obama's 2014 foreign policy reboot been successful?
Carter's criticism of the Iraqi forces triggered a quick response from Baghdad, where leaders defended their troops. And the White House moved to temper his comments a bit in the days that followed.
It's unclear, however, how quickly the U.S. will move to adjust the training or speed up the delivery of equipment, even as the Iraqis mobilize to try and retake western Anbar Province. The Obama administration has so far shown no inclination to commit more U.S. forces to Iraq or allow train and assist teams to move closer to the battlefront with smaller Iraqi units.
On Tuesday, just as Iraqi forces prepared their offensive, Islamic State militants launched a series of suicide bombings outside Fallujah, killing at least 17 soldiers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:26:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Roger Bennett of "Men in Blazers" on fallout from FIFA corruption probe</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/roger-bennett-of-men-in-blazers-on-fallout-from-fifa-corruption-probe/</Link>
        <Description>Soccer analyst and co-host of podcast and TV show "Men in Blazers," says the allegations are "what we have always known but have never been able to prove." Bennett joins "CBS This Morning" to discuss what comes next for FIFA and the sport.</Description>
        <MainBody>Roger Bennett of "Men in Blazers" on fallout from FIFA corruption probe
May 28, 2015, 8:02 AM
|Soccer analyst and co-host of podcast and TV show "Men in Blazers," says the allegations are "what we have always known but have never been able to prove." Bennett joins "CBS This Morning" to discuss what comes next for FIFA and the sport.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:40:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin suggests America's FIFA probe aimed at Russia</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/putin-suggests-americas-fifa-probe-aimed-at-russia/</Link>
        <Description>World soccer body's president stays out of site as Russian leader accuses U.S. of targeting him, and Moscow's 2018 World Cup</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS/APMay 28, 2015, 7:47 AM
Putin suggests America's FIFA probe aimed at Russia
Shares
More +
Russian President Vladimir Putin accused the United States of meddling in FIFA's affairs and hinted that it was part of an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from his country.
Putin said in televised comments Thursday that he found it "odd" that the probe was launched at the request of U.S. officials for crimes which do not involve its citizens and did not happen in the United States.
Corruption charges in the U.S. were announced Wednesday against 14 people, with at least two of them holding American citizenship. Seven of the 14 were arrested Wednesday morning in Zurich ahead of a FIFA meeting and Friday's presidential election in which Sepp Blatter is expected to win a fifth term.
In a separate probe, Swiss prosecutors opened criminal proceedings into FIFA's awarding of the 2018 World Cup to Russia and the 2022 tournament to Qatar .
CBS News talks with former U.S. Men's National Team soccer player Alexi Lalas on the impact the arrest of top FIFA officials might have on the sp...
CBS News correspondent Vladimir Duthiers reports that, while the investigation spans all corners of the globe, U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch said Wednesday that the suspects planned their crimes on U.S. soil, paid bribes through U.S. banks and took advantage of Americans' growing interest in the world's most popular game.
Putin said even if "someone has done something wrong," Russia "has nothing to do with it." He then tried to portray the probe as a U.S. attempt to go after dissenters, likening the case to the persecution of whistleblowers Julian Assange and Edward Snowden.
"Our American counterparts, unfortunately, are using the same methods to reach their goals and illegally persecute people. I don't rule out that this is the case in relation to FIFA," Putin said. "I have no doubt that this is yet another evident attempt to derail Mr. Blatter's re-election as FIFA president. We are aware of the pressure that he was subjected to in relation to Russia holding the 2018 World Cup."
Russian Sports Minister Vitaly Mutko, who is also a FIFA executive committee member and is in Zurich for the governing body's congress and presidential election, said Wednesday that his country welcomes the investigation.
Blatter, meanwhile, chaired an emergency meeting with continental soccer bodies the day after the FIFA crisis erupted, while staying out of public view himself.
FIFA spokeswoman Delia Fischer said Blatter met with representatives from soccer's six confederations "to discuss the current situation."
Blatter has resisted calls from European soccer body UEFA to postpone Friday's FIFA presidential election by six months.
Russia's President Vladimir Putin and FIFA President Sepp Blatter take part in the official handover ceremony for the 2018 World Cup in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, July 13, 2014.
REUTERS
He has avoiding appearing in public since Wednesday's arrests, missing a scheduled speech to open a session of FIFA's medical conference in a Zurich hotel on Thursday -- his third skipped public appearance within 24 hours.
Britain's sports minister said Thursday that Blatter must resign over the corruption allegations.
Culture, Media and Sport Secretary John Whittingdale said that "change in the leadership of FIFA is very badly needed."
Whittingdale said major sponsors should follow Visa and review their links with FIFA in the wake of corruption charges against senior FIFA officials.
"This is merely the latest sorry episode which suggests that FIFA is a deeply flawed and corrupt organization," Whittingdale told lawmakers in the House of Commons on Thursday.
World Cup sponsor Visa made its strongest call yet for FIFA to act against corruption in world soccer, warning it could leave a deal that runs through 2022.
Ahead of Friday's presidential election, Visa said it expected FIFA "to take swift and immediate steps to address these issues within its organization."
"Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship," Visa said.
Visa re-signed with FIFA last year to cover the 2018 and 2022 World Cups, hosted by Russia and Qatar respectively.
The value of top-tier FIFA sponsor deals is not disclosed. It was valued at around $100 million for the 2014 tournament.
Visa signed in 2007 after FIFA's former financial services partner Mastercard sued for breach of contract. FIFA paid $90 million to settle that case after a New York judge criticized its business ethics.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:42:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calls to oust FIFA chief amid bribery indictments</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/calls-to-oust-fifa-chief-amid-bribery-indictments/</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin is accusing the U.S. of "meddling" in international soccer. He says the FIFA corruption investigation is an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from Russia. Millions of dollars from sponsors are at risk. Vladimir Duthiers reports on the criminal allegations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Calls to oust FIFA chief amid bribery indictments
May 28, 2015, 7:08 AM
|Russian President Vladimir Putin is accusing the U.S. of "meddling" in international soccer. He says the FIFA corruption investigation is an attempt to take the 2018 World Cup away from Russia. Millions of dollars from sponsors are at risk. Vladimir Duthiers reports on the criminal allegations.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:30:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Is Russia behind massive IRS breach?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/is-russia-behind-massive-irs-breach/</Link>
        <Description>Hackers stole tax information from more than 100,000 Americans. The IRS is investigating whether criminals in Russia are behind the cybersecurity breach. Jeff Pegues reports on the multi-million-dollar theft in Washington.</Description>
        <MainBody>Is Russia behind massive IRS breach?
May 28, 2015, 7:12 AM
|Hackers stole tax information from more than 100,000 Americans. The IRS is investigating whether criminals in Russia are behind the cybersecurity breach. Jeff Pegues reports on the multi-million-dollar theft in Washington.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:06:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Study questions motivation for "jihadi brides"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/study-jihadi-brides-motivation-western-countries-join-isis-women-teens/</Link>
        <Description>Experts on radicalization warn against over-simplifying the allure of ISIS to young women in the West</Description>
        <MainBody>In Britain, the families of three females who are believed to have joined ISIS say they could have stopped the girls from leaving London. They te...
Young women are often vulnerable to this kind of rhetoric because they are questioning their identities as they grow into adults. Many of the young women observed said they felt socially and culturally isolated in secular Western society, and saw the region controlled by ISIS as "a safe haven for those who wish to fully embrace and protect Islam," according to the report.
About 550 young women, some as young as 13, have already traveled to ISIS controlled territory, according to the report.
The authors combed the social media accounts of more than 100 female profiles across platforms such as Twitter, Facebook and Tumblr. To grow their sample, they used a "snowball" technique in which female ISIS migrants were identified among networks of other ISIS networks. Photos, online chats and other accounts helped place the women geographically in Syria or Iraq. Researchers say the women came from 15 countries and were largely operating in English.
They consistently talked about the camaraderie they experienced after moving to ISIS territory, and often used social media to post images of veiled "sisters" posing together.
"This is often contrasted with discussions about the false feeling or surface-level relationships they iterate they previously held in the West," the authors said. "This search for meaning, sisterhood, and identity is a primary driving factor for many women to travel."
They are also searching for romance in the form of marriage.
"Online, images of a lion and lioness are shared frequently to symbolize this union," the report said. "This is symbolic of finding a brave and strong husband, but also propagandizes the notion that supporting a jihadist husband and taking on the ISIS ideology is an empowering role for females."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:25:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Planned new U.S. Embassy in Mexico a "fiasco"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-embassy-mexico-city-fiasco/</Link>
        <Description>Embassy was supposed to cost $577 million to build, but construction estimate has gone up by a third, and they've not even broken ground yet</Description>
        <MainBody>CBS NewsMay 28, 2015, 6:57 AM
Planned new U.S. Embassy in Mexico a "fiasco"
Shares
More +
Critics say new American embassies are getting more expensive.
Cost overruns in Afghanistan are over $150 million, and the new embassy in London could top $1 billion.  Nearly a year ago, CBS News correspondent Nancy Cordes showed us how glass for the London embassy had to be shipped back and forth across the Atlantic for framing. Now, Cordes reports from Washington on problems with an embassy in the works in Mexico.
It is an embassy that was supposed to cost $577 million to build, but the construction estimate has gone up by one third -- and the State Department hasn't even broken ground yet.
No one disputes that the current U.S. Embassy in Mexico City is crowded, outdated and needs to be replaced. So four years ago the State Department bought a 15 acre plot in a former industrial district for $120 million. But there was a catch: the site had housed a Colgate-Palmolive factory for decades, which left behind hazardous waste. Colgate has been cleaning the site but it's been three and a half years and it's still not ready for construction.
"It's a bit of a fiasco," said Rep. Jason Chaffetz, R-Utah.
Chaffetz chairs the House Oversight and Government Reform committee. He went to Mexico to see the site himself, but he didn't stay long.
"I'm not going to step in there with the dirt, with all that toxins on it," Chaffetz said.
The estimated cost of construction has risen from $577 million to $763 million. Add on the cost of the land and the unique design, and it's over $939 million; one of the most expensive U.S. embassies in the world.
"The State Department changed the way they build these things. They went from a Standard Embassy Design, which were coming in under budget and they were coming in swifter, and now they are now to the point where they have a new process and it's a lot more expensive and a lot slower," Chaffetz said.
Lydia Muniz, who heads the State Department's Embassy Construction Bureau told CBS News in a statement that costs have grown because the original estimate was "based on a staffing plan that provided office space for approximately 890 desks," but staffing needs have grown to 1,335 desks due to "increased bilateral activities with Mexico" on trade, drugs, and migration.
She acknowledged that the plan to award a construction contract in 2016 will not hold. Muniz flew to Mexico to meet with officials last week to discuss the Embassy project. But Patrick F. Kennedy, U.S. State Dept. Under Secretary for Management, told us last year that the agency is simply tailoring its embassies to their locations, which should save money over time.
"We have reviewed our processes and feel very, very comfortable that our use of the design initiative gets us the security we need and the functionality we need at the best possible price," Kennedy said.
Former State Department officials told us they are worried delays in construction could mean State Department employees have to work longer in an unsafe location.
Colgate-Palmolive told CBS News it has completed all cleanup work at the site, except for a small section. Congressman Chaffetz says the company told him that the work is going to take another nine months to two years.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:36:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How much is a lock of Mozart's hair worth?</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/mozart-beethoven-hair-on-auction-in-london/</Link>
        <Description>London auction house gives classical music fans chance to buy strands of history, and Mozart's isn't the only famous coiffure on offer</Description>
        <MainBody>After Mozart died in 1791, aged 35, his widow gave the hair to the mother of German composer Karl Anschutz. It was acquired by the late British composer Arthur Sommervell and is being sold by his family.
The hair is up for auction Thursday with an estimated price of $15,400 to $18,450.
The sale also includes a lock of Ludwig van Beethoven's hair and an invitation to his 1827 funeral, together valued at $3,100 to $4,600.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
