<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 17:54:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Joseph Kent: "Keep protesting, but positively"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/joseph-kent-keep-protesting-but-positively/</Link>
        <Description>Young Baltimore activist tells CBS News he's OK despite his arrest on live TV, which sparked outrage on Twitter</Description>
        <MainBody>He was trying to defuse tensions between police and people protesting the death of Freddie Gray Tuesday night when an armored truck pulled up and a team of National Guard troops rushed him.
"I just disappeared," Kent said of the arrest. "It happened so quickly and professionally."
The incident was captured on live TV and sparked outrage on Twitter, where some people called his arrest a "kidnapping."
Kent, who works two jobs at Mondawmin Mall and McDonald's in East Baltimore, has been a prominent figure in other protests of police brutality and has been widely credited with helping to keep those protests peaceful.
He told CBSN his message will not change despite his arrest. "Don't use this (arrest) as an excuse to have another riot," he said.
Kent, who was charged with a curfew violation, said the police commissioner recognized him and expedited his release.
Kent's high-profile activism and subsequent arrest have garnered a legion of admirers. His Instagram account has hundreds - maybe even thousands - of new followers and he says his phone has been ringing off the hook.
Kent says he is able to defuse the tensions between police and protesters because many of the people expressing anger can relate to him.
"They know where I come from," he said. "They look at me as one of them."
Gray's mysterious death from a spinal injury a week after his April 12 arrest is what sparked riots Monday - the worst the city has seen since 1968.
"Police brutality is still happening and it's a pattern," Kent said.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:45:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>​What was heard inside the Freddie Gray van</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/what-was-heard-inside-the-freddie-gray-van/</Link>
        <Description>Donta Allen, a second prisoner inside the Baltimore police van with Freddie Gray, describes what happened</Description>
        <MainBody>ByChip ReidCBS NewsApril 30, 2015, 6:57 PM
What was heard inside the Freddie Gray van
Shares
More +
Last Updated Apr 30, 2015 8:54 PM EDT
BALTIMORE -- The mystery surrounding Freddie Gray's death deepened Thursday with revelations from the second prisoner inside the van with Gray. Donta Allen had heard Gray trashing about and didn't see any harm done to Gray, according to Baltimore police.
But on Thursday Allen told WJZ-TV he heard more than just Gray's movements.
Donta Allen, the second prisoner inside the van with Freddie Gray
WJZ-TV
"So when we got to the station all l I hear is them (police) like, 'we got him,  we gave him a run for his money,'" said Allen.
The police denied that Gray was given what is known in Baltimore as a "wild ride," intended to frighten or even injure prisoners.
But Police Commissioner Anthony Batts has admitted mistakes were made.
"We know he was not buckled in the transportation wagon as he should have been," said Batts. "No excuses for that."
Allen's description of what he heard adds another layer to an already challenging timeline to follow.
On April 20th, during the Baltimore Police Department's first press conference, Deputy Police Commissioner Jerry Rodriguez said: "When Mr. Gray was placed inside that van, he was able to talk, he was upset, and when Mr. Gray was taken out of that van, he could not talk and he could not breathe."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:59:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Self-made billionaire's passion for U.S. history</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/self-made-billionaires-passion-for-u-s-history/</Link>
        <Description>Preview: Philanthropist David Rubenstein says willing too much money to a child isn't productive; he says he will donate most of his fortune to patriotic causes; watch Sunday, May 3 at 7 p.m. ET/PT on CBS</Description>
        <MainBody>David Rubenstein
CBS News
The federal government is in debt and could use a hand says billionaire David Rubenstein.  So he is donating his own money to fix the Washington Monument, Monticello and the Iwo Jima Memorial.  He won't be fixing his children up with hundreds of millions of dollars, however, telling Morley Safer that to do so might stunt their productivity. Safer profiles the hedge fund founder  who is determined to give most of his fortune away - much of it to preserve America's public treasures - on the next edition of 60 Minutes Sunday, May 3 at 7 p.m. ET/PT.
His family is comfortable with his decision and will certainly be left comfortable financially should he die, but Rubenstein, a co-founder of the Carlyle Group, is talking more than comfort money. "In the end, it's not clear that if you give a child $500 million, he or she will win a Nobel Prize for doing something," says Rubenstein.  "I think if you give somebody too much money, it can force them not to work as hard and be as productive," he tells Safer.
Rubenstein has no foundation and makes his own choices about where to spread his wealth, a fortune estimated more than $3 billion. "I generally look at things where my money will make a difference and in patriotic philanthropy, I think I can make a difference."
When the Washington Monument was damaged in a minor earthquake, he offered to foot the $15 million repair bill.  The government split it with him, not wanting to look completely destitute in its own capital.  And it will get more from the history buff, who says he is looking to help the government preserve more of America's monuments, such as the Lincoln Memorial and some of the homes of the founding fathers. "Well, the government doesn't have the resources it once had," says Rubenstein.  "We have gigantic budget deficits and large debt and I think private citizens now need to pitch in."
It's more than just pitching in; it's giving back.  Rubenstein has also spent more over $50 million on historical documents such as original copies of the Declaration of Independence and the Emancipation Proclamation that he has put in public places. He began this quest when he bought the last privately held copy of the Magna Carta for $21 million and built a multimillion-dollar display in the National Archives for the seminal British law document.  As he told reporters at the auction, "I'm giving it to the country, in effect, as a down payment on my obligation to give back to the country."
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Recent Segments
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 18:18:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eye Opener: Baltimore police deliver report to prosecutors</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/eye-opener-baltimore-police-deliver-report-to-prosecutors/</Link>
        <Description>There are new revelations about what happened to Freddie Gray inside a Baltimore police van. Also, dramatic new video of the Nepal earthquake. All that and all that matters in today's Eye Opener. Your world in 90 seconds.</Description>
        <MainBody>Eye Opener: Baltimore police deliver report to prosecutors
May 1, 2015, 7:01 AM
|There are new revelations about what happened to Freddie Gray inside a Baltimore police van. Also, dramatic new video of the Nepal earthquake. All that and all that matters in today's Eye Opener. Your world in 90 seconds.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
