<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:29:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/france-terror-attack-saint-quentin-fallavier/</Link>
        <Description>An attack on a gas factory near the eastern city of Lyon left at least one person dead</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Terror attack
At least one assailant rammed a car onto the premises of a U.S. gas company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast France, June 26, 2015, causing oxygen containers to explode. A decapitated head with Arabic writing on or near it was found at the site.
Here, French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
Terror attack
The Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, southeastern France, after an assault June 26, 2015, in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates.
One person was killed and several others were injured.
Credit: Jean-Philippe Ksiazek/AFP/Getty Images
Terror attack
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
One of the attackers reportedly waved an Islamic  State of Iraq and Syria flag.
Credit: Emmanuel Foudrot/Reuters
Terror attack
French security and emergency services gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, southeastern France, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
Terror attack
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Credit: REUTERS
Terror attack
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve gives a press conference near the entrance of the Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier near Lyon, southeastern France, June 26, 2015.
A suspect arrested in connection with the attack on a French gas factory was investigated nine years ago for radicalization and has links to the Salafist movement, Cazeneuve said.
Credit: Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
President Francois Hollande
French President Francois Hollande gives a statement at the European Council headquarters in Brussels, June 26, 2015. Hollande said an attack that morning in southeast France was of "a terrorist nature" and that a suspect had been arrested and identified.
Credit: Yves Herman/Reuters
Terror attack
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Credit: Emmanuel Foudrot/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:01:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly attack targets tourists in Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/tunisia-hotel-attack-in-tourist-resort-town-of-sousse/</Link>
        <Description>Officials confirm multiple fatalities as gunmen attack popular resort area on Tunisia's northeast coast, just months after museum massacre</Description>
        <MainBody>Twenty people, mostly tourists, were killed by gunmen at the National Bardo Museum in Tunis
Tunisia, a popular destination for European and Tunisian travelers, has been on high alert since a deadly assault on the famed Bardo museum in March by a pair of gunmen who killed 22 people at the tourist attraction in the capital city of Tunis.
The gunmen opened fire on tourists getting out of buses and then entered the museum, apparently unimpeded, and fired on more tourists inside. Two gunmen were killed in a shootout with police. Four Italians were among the dead.
The Islamic State in Iraq and Syria ( ISIS ) claimed responsibility for the Bardo attack.
This is a developing story, please check back for updates.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:39:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens killed as Kurds answer latest ISIS offensive</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/isis-attacks-on-kobani-hasskeh-leave-hundreds-dead-thousands-displaced/</Link>
        <Description>Thousands flee Hassakeh while activists says dozens of bodies left in streets after 2 days of fighting in Kobani</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS fighters advanced into the south west of the Syrian Kurdish town of Kobani overnight
The Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said on Friday that the attack on Kobani and its suburbs left 120 civilians dead.
Bali said more than 100 civilians were killed in Kobani as well as 40 ISIS fighters whose bodies were still in the streets.
Kobani, on Syria's border with Turkey, had become a symbol of Kurdish resistance against the ISIS extremists.
On Thursday, ISIS fighters also attacked the town of Hassakeh in northeast Syria.
According to a Reuters report, 60,000 people were displaced due to the fighting.
Reuters reported that 200,000 people in Hassakeh eventually could try and escape north toward the Turkish border.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man decapitated in apparent France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/man-decapitated-in-apparent-france-terror-attack/</Link>
        <Description>A suspected terror attack may have targeted an American gas company. Police say two attackers set off an explosion at the gates of an industrial complex near Lyon. They also found a severed head at the scene and banners with Islamist messages on them. Elizabeth Palmer reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in apparent France terror attack
June 26, 2015, 7:02 AM
|A suspected terror attack may have targeted an American gas company. Police say two attackers set off an explosion at the gates of an industrial complex near Lyon. They also found a severed head at the scene and banners with Islamist messages on them. Elizabeth Palmer reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:49:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Philippine official: China island-building in full swing</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/philippines-official-china-constructing-islands-reclamation-south-china-sea/</Link>
        <Description>10 days after Beijing said land reclamation in disputed South China Sea territory was near complete, local mayor sees "full-blast construction"</Description>
        <MainBody>There are growing tensions between China, its neighbors and the U.S. over disputed waters in the South China Sea. The Chinese military is racing ...
CBS News correspondent Seth Doane was on the Philippines' Pag-Asa Island earlier this month, where he reported that the Chinese have filled in enough of the South China Sea to create 2,000 acres of artificial islands in just the last 18 months.
In the mid-portion of the emerging island, a 1.9-mile-long landfill is taking the shape of a runway, Bito-onon said.
His comments followed similar findings by the U.S. military and independent defense analysts.
Two senior Philippine military officials, speaking on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to talk to the media, said that aside from Subi Reef, China's island-building has also continued on Mischief Reef, also in the Spratlys, based on recent military surveillance.
Chinese Embassy officials in Manila did not comment immediately.
The Chinese Foreign Ministry said on June 16 that the land reclamation projects on some islands and reefs "will be completed in upcoming days." However, in a sign that the developments were far from over, the ministry also said on its website that China would follow up by building infrastructure for operations ranging from maritime search and rescue to environmental conservation and scientific research.
The U.S. and the Philippines, its defense treaty ally, have expressed concern that China's island-building on at least half a dozen features in the South China Sea could be used for positioning military planes and navy ships to intimidate other claimants, reinforce China's claim over virtually the entire sea and threaten freedom of navigation in one of the world's busiest shipping lanes.
China's Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang said in the statement that the projects "do not affect the freedom of navigation and overflight enjoyed by all countries in accordance with international law in the South China Sea."
A U.S. Navy plane flying near one of the artificial islands last month was told to leave the area by the Chinese military . In a separate incident, a Philippine air force plane was similarly ordered by the Chinese navy several weeks ago to leave the area. The incidents raised fears that China was preparing to enforce an air defense identification zone over the South China Sea, similar to one it declared over disputed Japanese-held islands in the East China Sea in 2013.
The U.S. argues that China can't use artificially constructed islands to expand its sovereignty. U.S. officials have said they were considering stepping up patrols to ensure free navigation in the contested region.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 16:20:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man found decapitated in France terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/reports-of-terror-attack-in-eastern-france/</Link>
        <Description>President Hollande confirms 1 suspect in custody after attempt to blow up gas factory near Lyon that also left 2 injured; officials say more detained</Description>
        <MainBody>ByTucker RealsCBS NewsJune 26, 2015, 5:26 AM
Man found decapitated in France terror attack
Shares
More +
Last Updated Jun 26, 2015 8:20 AM EDT
One person was found decapitated and two others injured Friday after an assailant -- with a possible accomplice -- drove a vehicle onto an industrial complex near the eastern city of Lyon and tried to blow up a gas factory.
An attack on a gas factory near the eastern city of Lyon left at least one person dead
"The intent was without doubt to cause an explosion. It was a terrorist attack," President Francois Hollande said at a news conference in Belgium.
The attack targeted a chemical factory in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, about 20 miles southeast of Lyon. The plant is owned by the U.S. firm Air Products .
Witnesses said a man drove into the forecourt of the gas supply company, spun his car around in the yard, reports CBS News' Elaine Cobbe. Then they heard an explosion and saw fire.
The slain victim's head was found yards away from the body, stuck on a perimeter fence, with Arabic writing on or near it. There were also flags or banners bearing Arabic writing found at the scene.
The newspaper Le Dauphine libere reports that the decapitated victim was the manager of a transport company who happened to be at the site for a delivery.
French Defense Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian declared the attack an "act of terrorism," and said the national Defense Council was to convene at the presidential Elyse Palace at 3 p.m. local time (9 a.m. Eastern).
CBS News correspondent Elizabeth Palmer reports the factory was locked down along with other businesses in the area during the police investigation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 08:46:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paraglider landing on cable car breaks the Internet</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/paraglider-landing-on-cable-car-breaks-the-internet/</Link>
        <Description>A paraglider was filmed launching off a cliff and landing on a cable car. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has the wild video.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paraglider landing on cable car breaks the Internet
June 25, 2015, 9:35 PM
|A paraglider was filmed launching off a cliff and landing on a cable car. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has the wild video.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 08:38:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Luhu, the sad cat goes viral</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/luhu-the-sad-cat-goes-viral/</Link>
        <Description>An instagram featuring a cat's perpetually sad expressions has gone viral. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has more on the fussy feline.</Description>
        <MainBody>Luhu, the sad cat goes viral
June 25, 2015, 9:26 PM
|An instagram featuring a cat's perpetually sad expressions has gone viral. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers has more on the fussy feline.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 08:24:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Queen unimpressed with her portrait</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/queen-unimpressed-with-her-portrait/</Link>
        <Description>The Queen of England had a lackluster response to an illustration of her as a child. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers describes her underwhelmed reaction</Description>
        <MainBody>Queen unimpressed with her portrait
June 25, 2015, 9:13 PM
|The Queen of England had a lackluster response to an illustration of her as a child. CBSN's Vladimir Duthiers describes her underwhelmed reaction
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:29:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taxi drivers protest in France over Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/videos/taxi-drivers-protest-in-france-over-uber/</Link>
        <Description>Taxi drivers in France took to the streets to protest Uber's presence in the country. The cabbies say the company is killing their business. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taxi drivers protest in France over Uber
June 25, 2015, 6:48 PM
|Taxi drivers in France took to the streets to protest Uber's presence in the country. The cabbies say the company is killing their business. CBS News correspondent Charlie D'Agata reports.
Related Videos
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:15:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber French taxi drivers</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/pictures/french-taxi-drivers-protest-uber/</Link>
        <Description>French taxi drivers created chaos in Paris and other cities protesting the U.S. online ride service's European service - UberPOP</Description>
        <MainBody>Next
France Uber strike
French taxi drivers smashed cars, set tires ablaze and blocked traffic across the country on June 25, 2015 in a nationwide strike aimed at Uber after weeks of rising, sometimes violent tensions over the U.S. ride-hailing company's booking service, known in France as UberPOP. The angry taxi drivers say Uber's lowest cost service is taking their livelihood away.
French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Here, smoke rises from a fire, as a French riot police officer keeps watch next to an overturned car during protests by taxi drivers at Porte Maillot in Paris, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Thomas Samson/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
The sign on the wall reads "Death to Uber."
French riot police secure the Porte Maillot during a demonstration by French taxi drivers, who are on strike,  during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris on June 25, 2015.
Access to three terminals at Paris-Charles de Gaulle airport and in a number of areas of Paris, especially Porte Maillot, were blocked.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
Taxis gather at a major Paris traffic artery, Thursday, June 25, 2015.
French taxis are on strike around the country, snarling traffic in major cities and slowing access to Paris' Charles de Gaulle airport after weeks of rising and sometimes violent tensions over Uber.
UberPOP, the popular taxi app, is facing fierce opposition from traditional cab drivers.
Credit: Michel Euler/AP
France Uber strike
During a strike by French taxi drivers on Thursday, June 25, 2015, travelers going to and from the airport walked alongside highways with their bags or got caught in ambushes, like U.S. singer Courtney Love, who was rescued by two men on a motorcycle.
"They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage," Love tweeted. "They're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France- I'm safer in Baghdad."
Here, a man looks at an overturned car, allegedly used by an UberPOP driver, at Porte Maillot in Paris on June 25, 2015, as taxi drivers demonstrated nearby.
Credit: Thomas Samson/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
Riot policemen deploy through the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout, with The Arc de Triomphe in Paris, as taxi drivers stage a demonstration/blockade, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Loic Venance/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
French taxi drivers burn tires during a protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against UberPOP, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Anne-Christine Poujoulat/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
Riot police stand by an overthrown car during a taxi drivers demonstration, in Paris, Thursday, June 25, 2015.
Credit: AP Photo/Michel Euler
France Uber strike
French riot police stand in front of the Tour Oxygene as taxi drivers take part in a protest against car-sharing service Uber in Lyon, France, June 25, 2015. French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Credit: Emmanuel Foudrot/Reuters
France Uber strike
A taxi driver waves a French flag inscribed with the words "Uber, here it's  France" during a demonstration in Paris, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Michel Euler/AP
France Uber strike
A taxi with a banner that reads, "Uber get out" is seen during a protest in the southern city of Marseille as taxi drivers demonstrate against UberPOP, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Anne-Christine Poujoulat/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
French taxi drivers, who are on strike, block traffic on the city ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Paris, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
French riot police stand next to an overturned car as striking French taxi drivers demonstrate at the Porte Maillot, blocking traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in France, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
Taxi drivers on strike burn tires during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber in Marseille, France, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Jean-Paul Pelissier/Reuters
France Uber strike
The inscription "Death to Uber" is tagged onto a wall at the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout in Paris, as taxi drivers stage a demonstration/blockade, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Loix Venance/AFP/Getty Images
France Uber strike
An overturned car is seen in the distance as French taxi drivers demonstrate at Porte Maillot to block traffic on the city ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, June 25, 2015. French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP on Thursday, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities.
Credit: Charles Platiau/Reuters
France Uber strike
Passengers drag their suitcases as they make their way towards Orly airport as striking taxi drivers block access roads south of Paris during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, June 25, 2015.
Credit: Christian Hartmann/Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:08:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean soccer player investigated for intimate touch of opponent</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/chile-soccer-player-investigated-for-provoking-opponent/</Link>
        <Description>Defender Gonzalo Jara was caught trying to provoke Uruguay's Edinson Cavani to get a red card in the Copa America quarterfinals</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
SANTIAGO, Chile -- South American football officials will look into the actions of Chile defender Gonzalo Jara , who was caught on video poking Edinson Cavani's behind to provoke a red card in the Copa America quarterfinals.
Alberto Lozada, a member of CONMEBOL's disciplinary panel, said Thursday that the local governing body "will open an investigation" into Jara.
Cavani, Uruguay's top striker in the tournament, was sent off after the 63rd-minute provocation by Jara, and Chile went on to score the only goal on Wednesday, and reach the semifinals for the first time in 16 years.
Cavani slapped Jara in the face immediately after the Chilean put his hand on him, but the referee punished only Cavani, giving him a second yellow card. While the slap appeared to be light, Jara dropped to the ground with his hand to his face.
Cavani's first yellow was for complaining to the linesman in the 30th.
Uruguay captain Diego Godin said after the match that Cavani "reacted the way he did" only because of what Jara did.
The striker entered the match enduring a personal ordeal back in Uruguay, where his father was detained after allegedly driving drunk and being involved in an accident that killed a motorcyclist.
It wasn't the first time Jara was seen provoking another player. In 2013, Uruguay striker Luis Suarez was sent off from a World Cup qualifier for punching Jara in the face after a similar provocation from the Chilean.
If Jara has a hearing and is suspended, it could be costly for the hosts, who are trying to win the Copa for the first time. Chile will play either Peru or Bolivia in the semifinals.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:30:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama administration slams Iran and Cuba for human rights abuses</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/obama-admin-criticizes-iran-and-cuba-for-human-rights-abuses/</Link>
        <Description>The State Department blasted the two nations, although attempts to improve relations with them are continuing</Description>
        <MainBody>Pamela Falk, CBS News Foreign Affairs Analyst, discusses the highest level U.S. delegation to Cuba in decades beginning two days of negotiations.
On Cuba, the human rights reports said the government continued to use threats and intimidation to suppress peaceful dissent in 2014. And they accused government officials of carrying out "most human rights abuses" at the direction of their superiors.
Although Cuba released 53 political prisoners as part of the normalization process with the United States, the reports noted that Cuban activists in 2014 had recorded the highest number of arbitrary arrests of dissidents in the past five years. And though the government in 2014 indicated it will expand internet and telecommunications access, it "continued to block its citizens' access to uncensored, independent information in general," the reports said.
Other Cuban rights abuses mentioned in the reports include the abridgement of the ability of citizens to change the government; use of government threats, extrajudicial physical assault, intimidation, violent government-organized counter-protests against peaceful dissent; and harassment and detentions to prevent free expression and peaceful assembly.
"Impunity for the perpetrators remained widespread," the reports said.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:23:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Noriega asks for Panama's forgiveness in jailhouse interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/manuel-noriega-panama-jailhouse-interview/</Link>
        <Description>Former dictator breaks long silence to ask compatriots to forgive military regime's actions that culminated in U.S. invasion</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
PANAMA CITY -- Former dictator Manuel Noriega broke a long silence to ask his compatriots on Wednesday to forgive actions by his military regime that culminated in the 1989 U.S. invasion.
Noriega began the brief jailhouse interview with local network Telemetro reading a handwritten statement in which he said his apology came after days of reflection with his family and members of the church.
He said he wasn't motivated by any personal interest but a sincere desire to bring closure to the military era, a dark chapter in Panama's history that left the country in ruin and hundreds dead.
"Before the altar of my conscience I've come to express myself in the spirit of forgiveness," Noriega said, his hand shaking but otherwise appearing in good health for his 81 years.
The onetime CIA informant hadn't spoken to a journalist since a 1996 interview with CNN's Larry King from a Miami federal prison, where following his capture by American troops he was sent for being a major conduit for Colombian cocaine traffickers.
After completing his sentence in the U.S., Noriega was extradited to France to serve time for money laundering. He returned to Panama in 2011 to complete a 60-year sentence for murder, corruption and embezzlement during the military's three-decade rule.
Referring to himself as the "last general of the military era," Noriega apologized to those "offended, affected, injured or humiliated" by his own actions or those of his superiors and subordinates during the regime that he began serving as a low-ranking officer in the 1960s.
He didn't comment on any specific abuses and refused to take the bait when pressed about whether his act of contrition involved clarifying the still murky circumstances that led to the disappearance and murder of two prominent opponents.
Saying he was "totally at peace" with himself, Noriega said he didn't want to distract from the "solemnity" of his statement.
Reaction among Panamanians was mixed.
Many on social media saw the apology as a surprising capitulation from the famously stubborn strongman, who lost his apparent interest and power to influence Panamanian politics years ago.
But others judged it as a sly move to pave the way for a presidential pardon or for him to finish his sentence under house arrest, something his lawyers have been seeking on medical grounds for years. Indeed, he prefaced his written statement with a brief protest against what he said were excessively long sentences imposed by Panamanian courts in absentia.
"The problem with Noriega is you can never distinguish between what's true or not," said R.M. Koster, an American novelist and biographer of Noriega who has lived in Panama for decades.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:57:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French taxi drivers smash cars in strike against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/french-taxi-drivers-smash-cars-in-strike-against-uber/</Link>
        <Description>Taxi drivers in France took to the streets to protest ride-sharing service, saying it is taking away their livelihood</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
PARIS - French taxi drivers smashed up livery cars, set tires ablaze and blocked traffic across the country on Thursday in a nationwide strike aimed at Uber after weeks of rising, sometimes violent tensions over the U.S. ride-hailing company.
Travelers going to and from the airport walked alongside highways with their bags or got caught in ambushes, like singer Courtney Love, who was rescued by two men on a motorcycle.
"They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage," Love tweeted. "They're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France- I'm safer in Baghdad."
It wasn't immediately clear what type of car Love was riding in.
Taxi drivers are angry, saying Uber's lowest cost service is taking their livelihood away.
Despite repeated rulings against the low-cost UberPop service, its drivers continue to ply French roads and the American company is actively recruiting drivers and passengers alike. Uber claims to have a total of 400,000 customers a month in France.
Striking taxi drivers block a street in Paris on June 25, 2015.
THOMAS SAMSON/AFP/Getty Images
Riot police chased strikers from Paris' ring road, where protesters torched tires in the middle of the roadway and swarmed onto exit ramps at rush hour.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, sent a litany of tweets on Thursday afternoon, including one to Kanye West suggesting she would have been better off staying at the airport with him. West later appeared at the Louis Vuitton menswear show, cool and calm.
She wrote: "paid some guys on motorcycles to sneak us out, got chased by a mob of taxi drivers who threw rocks, passed two police and they did nothing."
She later posted a selfie wearing a motorcycle helmet with her two smiling rescuers.
France's top security official said he had ordered an immediate ban on unlicensed services like UberPop in the Paris region but called for an end to violence against the service's drivers.
"We are calling for calm. We are in a state of law," Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said. "A state of law is not a state of violence."
Uber's more expensive livery service is still legal but a source of intense frustration for French taxi drivers, who pay tens of thousands of euros (dollars) for the equivalent of medallions and who face customer complaints that they are being resistant to changes such as credit cards and geolocation.
Taxi drivers complain that livery services like Uber unfairly undercut them and in recent weeks nearly 100 Uber drivers have been attacked, sometimes while carrying customers. One irritated taxi passenger was left with a broken face and black eye after he praised Uber.
"There are people who are willing to do anything to stop any competition," said Thomas Meister, a spokesman for Uber. "We are only the symptom of a badly organized market."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:59:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devastating heat wave slowly easing in Pakistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/death-tolls-till-climbing-as-devastating-heat-wave-slowly-subsides-in-pakistan/</Link>
        <Description>Even as the heat subsides, the death toll continues to rise</Description>
        <MainBody>APJune 25, 2015, 2:31 PM
Devastating heat wave slowly easing in Pakistan
Shares
More +
KARACHI, Pakistan - The devastating heat wave that struck southern Pakistan last weekend is slowly subsiding but the toll was still climbing Thursday,  a senior health official said.
While the Associated Press is reporting 860 confirmed deaths due to the heat, Reuters, citing government and hospital officials, reports more than 1,100 people have died since Saturday due to the searing heat.
Jam Mehtab Hussain, the provincial health minister in the southern Sindh province, said people were still being admitted to hospitals with heat-related ailments - though in smaller numbers than in previous days. Previously dehydrated patients lay in hospital corridors and outside on the streets as overwhelmed medical staff struggled to cope with the disaster.
Ahmad Kamal, a spokesman for the National Disaster Management Authority, said authorities were providing free medical treatment to people in Karachi, the capital of Sindh province. He said the situation was improving due to lower temperatures .
The death toll from the recent heat wave in Pakistan continues to soar, even as temperatures cool
On Thursday, the temperature dropped to 34 degrees Celsius (93.2 degrees Fahrenheit) in Karachi from a high of 45 degrees Celsius (113 degrees Fahrenheit) on Sunday.
TV footage showed ambulances transporting heatstroke patients to various hospitals in Karachi, where people continued holding small rallies against power outages, which had exacerbated the effects of the heat wave.
Weather pattern shift bringing more heat waves
The heat wave was the worst seen in the city since 1979, officials said, and came as Muslims were fasting from dawn to dusk for the holy month of Ramadan.
The drinking of even a single drop of water invalidates the fast, but Muslims are also encouraged not to fast if they are sick or if doing so would cause serious physical harm.
A man with his daughter who suffers from dehydration due to extreme weather waits for a medical help outside a ward at a child hospital in Karachi, Pakistan, Wednesday, June 24, 2015. A cool wind from the sea and pre-monsoon rains brought the first signs of respite to southern Pakistan on Wednesday as the death toll from a scorching heat wave climbed to over 800, a high figure even for a nation accustomed to sizzling hot summers.
AP Photo/Shakil Adil
Mohammad Ayaz said he and other Karachi residents were struggling to stay cool, with hundreds of people sleeping outside because of long power cuts.
Wakil Ahmed, another resident, said the weather had improved from previous days, when it was so hot it became difficult to breathe. He said Thursday brought clouds and a slight breeze.
Karachi is home to some 20 million people and has long suffered from an inefficient power grid and a shortage of potable water.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:45:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin vows to strengthen Russian military</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/putin-vows-to-strengthen-russian-military/</Link>
        <Description>Remarks to military academy graduates reflect soaring tensions between Moscow, the West over Ukraine</Description>
        <MainBody>APJune 25, 2015, 1:00 PM
Putin vows to strengthen Russian military
President Vladimir Putin speaks at the Kremlin's meeting with graduates of Russian military academies, Moscow, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Putin said that Russia needs a powerful military to fend off threats near its borders, a statement that reflects tensions with the West over the Ukrainian crisis.
Mikhail Klimentyev/RIA-Novosti, Kremlin Pool Photo via AP
Shares
More +
MOSCOW - Russia needs a mighty military to fend off threats near its borders, President Vladimir Putin said Thursday, in a stance that reflects soaring tensions with the West over the crisis in Ukraine.
The Russian leader, whose approval ratings reached an all-time high this month despite a bruising recession, said a "powerful army equipped with modern weapons is the guarantor of sovereignty and territorial integrity of Russia."
Speaking at Thursday's Kremlin meeting with graduates of Russian military academies, Putin also vowed to continue a sweeping military modernization effort that envisions the purchase of large numbers of new weapons.
Despite the fact that oil-rich Russia is now in a recession, Putin's plan aims to spend 22 trillion rubles (over $400 billion) through 2020 to give the armed forces dozens of navy ships, hundreds of new planes and missiles and thousands of tanks and other weapons.
Russian President Vladimir Putin is calling on the U.S. to stop telling Russia what to do. Putin spoke at a business conference in Russia, which ...
Putin added that Russia has no aggressive intentions and aims to "settle any disputes exclusively by political means with respect to international law and interests of other nations."
Relations between Russia and the West have sunk to post-Cold War lows after Moscow's 2014 annexation of Ukraine's Crimean Peninsula and its support for a pro-Russian insurgency in eastern Ukraine.
The United States and the European Union have responded with sanctions that have sharply limited Russia's access to Western capital markets and curtailed the transfer of military and energy technologies.
Russia retaliated by banning the import of agricultural products from the EU, U.S., Australia, Canada and Norway. The Cabinet formally extended the ban by one year after the EU agreed this week to keep its sanctions in place through January.
Coupled with plummeting prices for oil, Western sanctions helped drive the Russian economy into recession, resulting in a drop in incomes for the first time since Putin took the helm in 2000. But despite the economic woes, Putin's popularity has soared.
The president's approval rating reached an all-time high of 89 percent this month, according to a nationwide poll conducted by the Levada Center, a leading independent opinion research firm. The survey, based on interviews with 1,600 people, had a margin of error of no more than 3.4 percentage points.
Many observers attribute the solid support for Putin to blanket positive coverage of his activities by state television stations and other Kremlin-controlled media that have described the Ukrainian crisis as part of Western efforts to weaken Russia.
Levada head Lev Gudkov called the TV propaganda as the main factor behind Putin's popularity.
"This is a very aggressive and false propaganda," he said. "All alternative channels, therefore all alternative points of view, assessments are pushed out of the public sphere."
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:48:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Marines heading to Bulgaria to convince "Putin to refrain from aggression"</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-marines-heading-to-bulgaria-to-reassure-allies-amid-tension-with-russia/</Link>
        <Description>Announcement comes after Ash Carter says more American military equipment would be positioned in Europe</Description>
        <MainBody>After Russian planes flew too close to Swedish airspace, Sweden scrambled fighter jets to intercept the aircraft. As Russia flexes its muscle, it...
"Ideally this culminates with integrated exercises with units from more and more allied nations that are able to call for fire from one another's artillery, our tanks maneuver in support of their infantry units, and vice versa," he said.
The U.S. already regularly conducts maneuvers with allied countries. In Romania on Thursday, U.S Navy Adm. Mark E. Ferguson III, a top NATO commander, said recent exercises have shown that the alliance is capable of training and operating across northern and eastern Europe.
He also noted that NATO successfully relocated the Allied Joint Force Command temporarily from Italy to Romania for exercises this month involving 1,000 troops from 21 nations, as the alliance continues to hone its ability to react to Russia's moves in Ukraine or other security challenges.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman on trial for deaths of 8 of her babies</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/frenchwoman-on-trial-for-deaths-of-8-of-her-babies/</Link>
        <Description>The worst infanticide case in modern French history hinges on woman's claim that she was longtime victim of incest</Description>
        <MainBody>APJune 25, 2015, 12:43 PM
Woman on trial for deaths of 8 of her babies
Dominique Cottrez, flanked by her lawyer, Franck Berton, appears at the North Assize Court in Douai, France, June 25, 2015. Cottrez, a former nurse's aid, is charged with having killed eight of her children at birth since 1989.
PHILIPPE HUGUEN/AFP/Getty Images
More +
DOUAI, France - One day in the summer of 2010, a man was digging in his garden in northern France when he discovered a trash bag containing the remains of an infant. When he summoned the police, they found the body of another newborn. A few days later, they found more bags in the garage with six additional small corpses.
Police contacted the house's previous owners, and quickly discovered the horrifying explanation: Frenchwoman Dominique Cottrez confessed to secretly bearing and then killing eight of her newborns, saying she feared they were children of a long, incestuous relationship with her father.
Cottrez, a 51-year-old mother of two grown daughters, went on trial Thursday in the city of Douai, accused of multiple counts of first-degree murder of minors.
Cottrez wept as she took her seat. She faces life in prison if found guilty.
Her lawyers are expected to argue that she was a victim of rape and incest, and ask for a lesser sentence.
The worst infanticide case in modern French history stunned the country when the bodies were discovered in and around the Cottrez' former home in 2010.
Cottrez's obesity appeared to hide the pregnancies, which went unnoticed by her husband, children, neighbors, colleagues -- and even doctors at a nearby hospital.
Dozens of forensic and psychiatric experts, police investigators and witnesses, including her husband, daughters and siblings, are scheduled to testify to help understand the incomprehensible, and perhaps to help the defendant open up.
A withdrawn, secretive nurse's aide, Cottrez told investigators she was raped by her father, first when she was 8 and repeatedly through her childhood and teenage years, according to judicial documents. She later entered a long, incestuous relationship with him as an adult, including after she married, and said that it became consenting, and even said she was in love with her father more than she was with her husband.
Her father died in 2007.
One of the first witnesses called to the stand Thursday is Leonard Meriaux, who bought the Cottrez family house and discovered the first corpse in 2010.  He called police, who found another in the garden.
Anne Segond (left), president of the North Assize Court in Douai, France, speaks during the trial of Dominique Cottrez, who is charged with infanticide, on June 25, 2015.
PHILIPPE HUGUEN/AFP/Getty Images
From one interrogation to another, the police went from surprise to stupor. Cottrez first admitted killing the two infants found in the garden. Then she herself informed the investigators that several other bodies were in the garage of the house, but she didn't know how many exactly, according to court documents.
She told the investigating judge that she had never used contraception or had an abortion because of a phobia of doctors. She also said she didn't keep the babies because she was afraid that they were the results of her incestuous relations with her father. She said the killing had become a "means of contraception," according to the judicial documents.
She said she told her father of the eight pregnancies and the eight murders, and investigators believe he could have helped her hide some of the bodies.
The death she described the most clearly is the first one, in 1989. She said she smothered the baby boy with sheets, placed him in a trash bag that she had prepared in advance, and put the bag in her wardrobe, according to the documents.
The second killing happened when she was hospitalized for an epilepsy seizure. She said she gave birth in the hospital toilet, strangled the child, wrapped it in plastic sheeting and towels, placed it in the closet of her hospital room and then brought it back home, hidden in her garment bag.
Her memories became blurred for the following births and deaths. The last infanticide was in 2000.
Her husband and daughters say they noticed foul odors in various parts of the house, but thought they came from sewage, or their dog, or even their father's feet.
Cottrez was released from jail in 2012 after spending two years in temporary detention. In a January interview with a local newspaper, she said: "I never gave first names to the babies. The first one, I saw he was a baby boy. The others, I didn't look, I didn't want to. But when they were in the garage, when it was cold, I went there and covered them with a blanket. "
The verdict is expected next Thursday.
 2015 The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:08:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother, baby found alive 4 days after plane crash in jungle</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/mother-baby-found-alive-4-days-after-plane-crash-in-colombia-jungle/</Link>
        <Description>Woman and her one-year-old son survived deadly crash in Colombia jungle by drinking coconut water</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
BOGOTA, Colombia -- A woman who survived a jungle plane crash with her 1-year-old son drank coconut water to stay alive for four days until being rescued, Colombia's air force says.
Rescuers reached Maria Nelly Murillo and her child in a remote area of western Colombia and flew them to the nearby town of Quibdo for medical treatment on Wednesday. Murillo suffered some injuries and burns but the baby was unhurt.
They were aboard a twin-engine Cessna that crashed Saturday into the thick jungle shortly after taking flight from Quibdo, near the Pacific Ocean.
The pilot was killed, but rescuers said a load of fish on board absorbed much of the impact in the plane's cabin, allowing Murillo and her son to survive against the odds.
Colombia's air force posted images of the woman and her son on Twitter, calling the rescue a "miracle."
Un milagro en las selvas de Choc http://t.co/IjIkS6lEEQ va @RevistaSemana pic.twitter.com/8oPIRIg37v
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
