<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="cbsnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 05:20:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inside the mind of Colorado theater shooter James Holmes</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/inside-the-mind-of-colorado-theater-shooter-james-holmes/</Link>
        <Description>At his murder trial, jurors see the notebook James Holmes kept before the July 2012 attack that killed 12 people and injured 70</Description>
        <MainBody>ByJim AxelrodCBS NewsMay 26, 2015, 7:05 PM
Inside the mind of Colorado theater shooter James Holmes
Shares
More +
CENTENNIAL, Colo. -- For the first time, a Colorado jury has had a look inside the mind of a killer: The gunman who killed 12 people and left 70 injured when he opened fire in a crowded movie theater.
As James Holmes mounts an insanity defense, jurors were shown the notebook that he mailed to a psychiatrist shortly before the attack .
The spiral notebook has long been thought to hold clues to Holmes' state of mind at the time of the July 20, 2012 attack -- but this was the first look inside. Tuesday afternoon, excerpts were read aloud by Aurora Police Sgt. Matthew Fyles.
On some of the 29 pages, Holmes wrote rambling observations and questions, including "What is the meaning of life?", and, "What is the meaning of death?"
On several pages he repeated the question: "Why? Why? Why?"
On others, accounts of scouting several theaters in the days before the attack.
Holmes apparently considered attacking an airport but decided against it, not wanting his attack to be confused with terrorism.
"The message is there is no message," Holmes wrote, according to Fyles.
He chose a theater, even though Holmes put the chances of being captured "99 percent."
Police officers who responded to the 2012 movie theater massacre gave emotional testimony Thursday as they recounted the bloodshed at the scene. ...
Jurors who will decide on a plea of "not guilty by reason of insanity," followed along in their own copies as Fyles read Holmes' writing aloud.
"The obsession to kill, since I was a kid, with age became more and more realistic," Holmes wrote.
He also said he had "decided to dedicate life to killing others so that I could live."
Holmes sent his notebook to his psychiatrist in a mailer with 20 different $20 bills -- all burned to some extent.
Also inside: A drawing of a circle with the numeral one and the infinity sign -- the same symbol found on a calendar inside Holmes' apartment the day of the shooting.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 04:28:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Herpes virus harnessed to fight a common cancer</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/herpes-virus-harnessed-to-fight-a-common-cancer/</Link>
        <Description>Human clinical trials show this promising technique attacks melanoma tumors on two levels</Description>
        <MainBody>ByBianca SeidmanCBS NewsMay 26, 2015, 6:59 PM
Herpes virus harnessed to fight a common cancer
Microscopic view of Herpes Simplex Virus Nephron/ Licensed under CC BY-SA 3.0 via Wikimedia Commons
Shares
More +
An experimental treatment using a genetically engineered herpes virus appears to be effective in treating one of the most common, deadly, and increasingly expensive cancers: melanoma .
Researchers have been experimenting with forms of therapy using viruses -- an approach called immunotherapy -- to fight cancer for the past several years. A new study, published Tuesday in the Journal of Clinical Oncology, is the first to show the approach works in patients in a Phase III clinical trial, the final step of human testing before a treatment can receive FDA approval.
In the clinical trial, patients who received the immunotherapy drug showed significantly improved odds in the treatment of these skin cancer tumors , especially inoperable ones.
When a modified form of the herpes simplex virus type-1 is injected directly into a melanoma, it causes two reactions that can destroy the cancer cells.  By itself and in combination with other treatments , it packs a powerful punch.
"They can launch a two-pronged attack on tumours -- both killing cancer cells directly and marshalling the immune system against them," Professor Kevin Harrington, Professor of Biological Cancer Therapies at The Institute of Cancer Research in London, who led the UK research team, said in a statement.
"And because viral treatment can target cancer cells specifically," he added, "it tends to have fewer side-effects than traditional chemotherapy or some of the other new immunotherapies."
Already a billionaire for creating an innovative cancer drug, Dr. Patrick Soon-Shiong is turning heads with more unconventional ways of treating ...
This particular treatment, called T-VEC, is a genetically-engineered version of the herpes simplex virus designed not to cause an active herpes infection, which can be dangerous to cancer patients.
In this random, controlled human trial, patients who had inoperable stage III and stage IV melanomas lived almost twice as long when injected with T-VEC therapy compared to earlier-stage melanoma patients using more traditional treatments.  The trial, the first to reach Phase III status, was funded by the manufacturer of T-VEC, Amgen.
Used alone, T-VEC is most useful for late-stage melanoma tumors that are easily accessed -- only a fraction of the melanomas diagnosed every year. But some researchers say the real promise of T-VEC and other immunotherapies is as part of a disease-fighting duo to attack late-stage cancer tumors.
"Right now I think this is an exciting advance in many ways," Dr. Philip Friedlander, Assistant Professor of Medicine in Hematology and Medical Oncology at the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, told CBS News.  "There are current studies looking at combining this treatment with other promising immune treatments."
These combined therapies can "take the brakes off the immune system," he said, increasing survival or life extension rates. In the study, 163 patients with stage III or early stage IV melanoma treated with T-VEC lived an average of 41 months, nearly twice as long as the control group.
Skin cancer is the most common form of cancer in the United States and rates have been increasing for the past 30 years.  According to The American Cancer Society's estimates , there could be more than 73,000 new cases of melanoma diagnosed this year and almost 10,000 deaths.
As with many cancers, melanoma is best fought with early detection .
"Sun is a contributing factor. But, at least for melanoma, it's not the complete story," said Dr. Friedlander.  "There are other undefined factors, there are family history related factors.
Anyone who has a first-degree relative -- mother, father, brother, sister -- diagnosed with skin cancer should be especially vigilant and check skin regularly.
"If anything's changing, show it to the dermatologist right away," he said.  "Once a month is a good interval.  If you check once a day, you might not notice any changes."
For those diagnosed with melanoma tumors, this new approach to harnessing viruses could offer the most effective method yet for fighting back.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:42:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Last-ditch effort to save world's most endangered turtle</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/elderly-turtle-artificially-inseminated-to-save-endangered-species/</Link>
        <Description>Scientists artificially inseminated a 100-year-old Yangtze giant softshell turtle, the last known female of her species</Description>
        <MainBody>More +
Conservationists were elated a few years back when they managed to get two endangered Yangtze giant softshell turtles - both believed to be around 100 years old - to mate.
It seemed to be the last hope for a species that had dwindled to four turtles, three of them male. They displayed courting behavior but her eggs never hatched.
So this year, scientists turned to a breeding method popular for captive pandas : artificial insemination. They announced this week that they had successfully collected semen from the male - no easy task in an elderly turtle - and successfully inseminated the female.
"It now appears that artificial insemination is the only possible option for the pair of Rafetus swinhoei in Suzhou Zoo to reproduce successfully," said Lu Shunqing, Wildlife Conservation Society China's reptile program director. "The fate of the most endangered softshell turtle of the world is now in the balance."
A female Yangtze giant softshell turtle, one of four remaining in the world in a pond at Suzhou Zoo in China. This turtle was recently artificially inseminated by scientists in an effort to save her species from extinction.
Gerald Kuchling
The scientists turned to artificial insemination for the first time for this species of turtle after it was determined the male's sex organs had been damaged, possibly in an earlier fight with another male.
"We had to find out if the last known male in China no longer produces viable sperm due to old age or an inability to inseminate the female," Gerald Kuchling, organizer of the artificial insemination effort and Rafetus breeding program leader for the Turtle Survival Alliance.
Listed as critically endangered by the International Union for Conservation of Nature, the Yangtze giant softshell turtle is the most critically endangered turtle in the world. Its status in the wild has long been recognized as grim, but extinction risk now is believed higher than ever. Much of its demise has been attributed to over-harvesting and the degradation of its freshwater habitat in China.
If she produces fertile eggs, it would end a difficult journey for a female turtle that had languished for years in obscurity. The female turtle's keepers at Changsha Zoo in southern China hadn't even known what kind of turtle she was or that she was the last remaining female.
Officials in 2007 responded to an urgent appeal sent to all of China's zoos in search of the Yangtze species, saying they had a female that looked like the turtle in the photo sent with the appeal.
They moved a male from another Chinese zoo 600 miles away and the courting began. At the time, artificial insemination was too risky. But after the female's eggs didn't hatch, they had no choice.
The procedure, which brought together top scientists from China, Australia and the United States, was deemed a success and both turtles are recovering. But the true test comes when she lays her eggs next month.
"The conservation world will once again be holding its collective breath until we know if this was successful," Fort Worth Zoo Biologist and Turtle Survival Alliance President Rick Hudson said. "The optimism we felt back in 2008 when the pair was mating and laying eggs has slowly faded as reality sank in that this pair would not breed without intervention."
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon May 25 19:40:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>John Nash: The "60 Minutes" interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/john-nash-60-minutes-beautiful-mind/</Link>
        <Description>From the archives, Mike Wallace's interview with mathematician John Nash, the subject of the movie "A Beautiful Mind"</Description>
        <MainBody>Facebook
Comments
Mike Wallace and I did interviews with war criminals, corrupt politicians, and murderers, but one of the most challenging was with a mathematician -- John F. Nash, Jr., the Nobel Prize-winning mathematician, whose lifelong struggle with schizophrenia was the subject of the Oscar-winning film "A Beautiful Mind." John and his wife Alicia died in a taxi accident on Sunday.
John and Alicia Nash, 2002
CBS News
John Nash was an unlikely subject of a 60 Minutes interview or a major Hollywood picture. His mathematical discoveries regarding game theory are known and understood by only a small circle of experts, and he spent much of his life in obscurity, largely because of long-term, severe bouts of psychosis.
When reporter Sylvia Nasar wrote a detailed biography of John's mathematics work and his schizophrenia, it was not the kind of book you would imagine on the silver screen someday. But producer Brian Grazer and director Ron Howard saw something in the story, and with writer Akiva Goldsman, they turned John's life story into a gripping film that, in 2002, was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Picture.
In the months leading up to the Oscars, a whisper campaign started, suggesting that John was not the heroic figure that was portrayed by actor Russell Crowe. There were suggestions that John had anti-Semitic leanings in his youth and that he had abandoned an out-of-wedlock child. The implication was that this film was about a nasty guy, and the filmmakers covered it up, so it was not worthy of the coveted Best Picture Oscar.
The studio approached 60 Minutes to suggest an exclusive interview with John, in hopes of rehabilitating his reputation. We don't do PR for studios, but there was something about the story that really moved Mike. Having struggled with his own mental health demons, Mike thought he could connect with this man who achieved greatness, despite his challenges. Mike and I also saw it as an opportunity to help address the ongoing stigma around mental illness.
Aaron Tomlinson/60 Minutes
In the fall of 2002, we both welcomed the Nash story as a break from our national security reporting in the wake of the 9/11 attacks. After chasing intelligence agents and terrorists, this was going to be an easy one.
So we thought.
Negotiating with a genius suffering from schizophrenia is simply not easy. John operated on a plane that was different than ours, even when the topic had nothing to do with math. Insulin shock therapy may have slowed him down a bit, but not much. The first meeting went well. Mike, my associate producer Trisha Sorrells Doyle, and I met with John and his wife Alicia at a restaurant near Princeton University, where John spent much of his academic career. John asked astute questions. We talked politics and mental health policy. The meeting ended cordially, and an interview looked likely.
Then I got a call. There were rumors swirling that John was bisexual and that he had a relationship with a graduate school classmate back in the 1950s. John insisted this was categorically not true, and he decided he did not want to do an interview. I explained that we had nothing to do with those rumors, and really didn't care about his sexuality, but he would not budge.
It was clear that John's reluctance came from a fixation and anxiety around this one specific rumor, and I asked his wife Alicia for advice. She suggested patience.
Over the next two months, I made regular trips to Princeton to visit with John and Alicia, in their humble bungalow a few miles from campus. I reassured John that Mike and I had no interest in his sexuality.  But mostly I just sat with them, talking about life and math and family. I spent time with their son Johnny, who is also a mathematician and also suffers from schizophrenia. John introduced me to the art of drinking sherry and would pull out the bottle of Harveys Bristol Cream whenever I stopped by.
Just weeks before the Oscar ceremony, John called and said he changed his mind - he was willing to sit down for an interview. We scrambled to make arrangements. Mike, Trisha and I came up with a set of questions, and I suggested that we avoid the topic of the allegations of bisexuality, since it's not something we would ever put into the story, and it would only upset John and potentially derail the interview. Mike agreed that was prudent.
John wanted to take us to Trenton Psychiatric, where he endured painful electroshock therapies -- as gruesome, John said, as was portrayed in the film. He and Alicia told Mike about their love affair, which was also portrayed in the film. The interview took about two hours, with a focus primarily on John's work and his mental health. Mike asked John about the alleged anti-Semitic rantings in the 1960s, and John admitted that, because of his illness, "I did have strange ideas during certain periods of time." He went on to explain he also ranted about aliens. Schizophrenia plays tricks on the mind.
The interview was going on well, and then Mike asked about the alleged affair with his male classmate. I remember John turned slightly, as if to look to me for help. He paused, collected his thoughts and answered matter-of-factly. I looked at Trisha, and we both shook our heads. Mike couldn't help himself.
Of course, the exchange never made it into the piece, since it was not germane to the story. We did address the alleged anti-Semitism and the abandoned son, but by the time our story aired, Academy votes were in, so the studio's efforts to use this profile to boost their chances of an Oscar were foiled. "A Beautiful Mind" still ended up winning Best Picture.
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Recent Segments
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
