<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quiz: Test your news knowledge</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/quiz-test-your-news-knowledge</Link>
        <Description>Test your knowledge of this week's news and current events.</Description>
        <MainBody>Quiz: Test your news knowledge 0
Friday, May 1, 2015       7:00:00 EDT AM
Brenda, who won a trip to a Canadian city on 'The Price is Right,' turned down a free hotel stay and opted for an RV excursion in the Rocky Mountains. (YouTube)
Change text size for the story
Print
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:57:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Retiree still must pay alimony</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/retiree-still-must-pay-alimony</Link>
        <Description>Federal civil servant Robert Cossette 
thought by taking early retirement at 55, 
his days of alimony payments were done.</Description>
        <MainBody>Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
TORONTO-
Federal civil servant Robert Cossette thought by taking early retirement at 55, his days of alimony payments were done.
He was wrong.
In fact, unless spelled out in your separation agreement, you could be on the hook for the rest of your life. At times you will not be allowed to retire if the court wants you to continue paying support, warns Ottawa family lawyer Wade Smith.
In his clients case, a panel of the Divisional Court Divisional Court this week upheld a lower court ruling that refused to consider Cossettes voluntary retirement from the civil service as a material change in circumstance that could end his support obligations. The motions judge specifically found that one of the reasons for Mr. Cossettes retirement was the desire to stop paying spousal support, noted the three-member panel.
We agree with his conclusion that retirement was not a material change. Parties cannot sidestep support obligations by unilaterally deciding to leave the workforce.
Smith says his client is now considering taking the case to the Ontario Court of Appeal. I think most people think that when they retire, their obligations will end. That was certainly Mr. Cossettes expectation.
Cossette had put in his 33 years at work and supported two children. His ex was now employed and making the same as he draws from his pension. He thought hed crossed the finish line, Smith said.
But in Ontario, theres no definitive law on when you can stop paying support; instead, its on a case by case basis. I think its a significant problem, the lawyer said. Sometimes its support for life and sometimes its not. Its something that should be clarified.
The Cossettes married in 1979, when he was 20 and she was 21. They separated after 22 years of marriage and in a 2006 court settlement, he agreed to pay $1,000 a month in alimony for an indefinite period.
Seven years later, he took early retirement from his $104,000 a year government position. Cossette then applied to the court to stop paying spousal support, citing his material change in circumstance.
When the matter was first heard in 2014, Cossette claimed that he had to retire early because his lifelong battle with depression meant he couldnt continue working. The court didnt buy it. They saw no evidence of any psychological or psychiatric reports or anything except a family doctors report that hed prescribed an anti-depressant to help him deal with stress.
While Mr. Cossette may have been stressed and/or depressed that he was paying spousal support, that is an unfortunate reality of life, the court noted with little sympathy. His reality is that he retired at 55 and moved across the country, is staying in shape, is mountain climbing, has purchased a new house and is engaged to be married.
They viewed his voluntary retirement as an attempt at a get out of support early card and ordered him to continue paying alimony.
Now living in Calgary, Cossette appealed to the Divisional Court, but this time didnt press the depression issue. Instead, his lawyer argued that someone shouldnt be forced to continue working past their eligible retirement date just to satisfy their support payments.
The judges disagreed. Mr. Cossettes retirement should not operate as either a sword or a shield  it should not, in the circumstances of this case, immunize him from ongoing support payments.
The lesson, the court added, is that divorcing couples should consider the issue of retirement and support in their separation agreement.
His ex-wife is relieved, says her lawyer, Pam MacEachern. She believes the decision will have repercussions for other divorced baby boomers who assumed they could leave the rat race early.
He was arguing that he gets to retire  Ive worked long enough, I dont have to work anymore and Im going to go climb mountains, MacEachern said.
Lucky for him. But that doesnt mean his ex-wife should suffer. Or as her lawyer says, she cant afford to retire.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:07:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore officials ask for patience in probe of black man's death</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/more-than-100-arrested-in-baltimore-overnight</Link>
        <Description>Residents of Baltimore and activists across the United States waited on Thursday for official word on the cause of a black man's death in police custody earlier this month, as protests over the case spread to other cities.</Description>
        <MainBody>Media reacts differently to claims Freddie Gray injured self
BALTIMORE - As protesters marched in several cities, Baltimore officials asked for patience on Thursday while prosecutors decide whether to charge six officers involved in the arrest of a black man who later died of injuries he sustained while in custody.
The office of Marilyn Mosby, the state's attorney, will include the internal report as part of its own investigation into the death of Freddie Gray, who suffered spinal injuries sometime between his April 12 arrest for carrying a switchblade knife and his arrival at a police station.
Gray's death a week later has become the latest flashpoint in a national outcry over the treatment of African-Americans and other minority groups by a white-dominated U.S. law enforcement establishment.
After a night of rioting in Baltimore on Monday, protests spread to other major cities later in the week in a reprise of demonstrations last year set off by police killings of unarmed black men in Ferguson, Missouri, New York and elsewhere.
A few hundred protesters marched through Baltimore in a noisy but peaceful demonstration on Thursday, joined by NBA star Carmelo Anthony and other celebrities, ahead of a 10 p.m. EDT (0200 GMT) curfew that city officials said would continue through the weekend.
"I'm hoping that we will get justice," said Janai Peters, 22, who works at an area hospital. She said city prosecutors must act quickly to resolve the case. "My hopes aren't high, but I am hoping for something positive."
The Washington Post reported that police on Thursday night found the body of a man inside a semi truck parked near a CVS pharmacy that was burned and looted during Monday's violence.
Baltimore police spokesman Sergeant Jarron Jackson told the Post that officials were investigating it as a suspicious death, but it did not appear to be connected with the unrest.
A rally of about 1,000 people in Philadelphia briefly turned tense as protesters tried to march onto a highway and were blocked by police.
TEST FOR NEW PROSECUTOR
Mosby, a 35-year-old African-American who took office in January, said her staff was regularly briefed by police investigators during the course of their probe, and at the same time, her office has been conducting its own independent probe.
"We are not relying solely on their findings but rather the facts that we have gathered and verified," Mosby, a Democrat, said in a statement. "We ask for the public to remain patient and peaceful and to trust the process of the justice system."
Mosby faces the biggest test of her short career in trying to determine what exactly happened to 25-year-old Gray and whether any of the officers should face criminal charged. The six are on suspension.
The daughter and granddaughter of police officers and the wife of a city councilman, Mosby vowed during her campaign to crack down on repeat offenders and promised to be more visible in the community than her predecessor.
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake vowed to see justice done. She noted that she, Mosby and Attorney General Loretta Lynch, whose department is also investigating Gray's death, were important figures in the case.
"If, with the nation watching, three black women at three different levels can't get justice... for this community, you tell me where you're going to get it in our country," Rawlings-Blake told reporters.

NEW QUESTIONS SURFACE ON GRAY'S INJURIES
While there are no immediate plans to make the findings of the police report public, media reports on Thursday offered new perspectives about what may have happened to Freddie Gray.
A Washington Post story suggested Gray tried to hurt himself while riding in a police van.
A prisoner who rode in the van said he had heard sounds that suggested Gray was banging his own head against the wall, according to a document written by a police investigator and obtained by the newspaper. The other prisoner could not see Gray because they were separated by a metal divider.
"I think it's unfortunate that these little things are coming out... People should take a deep breath and wait for the state's attorney to come out with the entire information," Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts told CNN.
Local television station WJLA said the medical examiner saw no evidence that Gray suffered the fatal injury during his arrest, pointing instead to the injury happening during his ride in the police van, multiple law enforcement sources told the station.
The medical examiner found that Gray appeared to break his neck when his head slammed into the back of the van, the sources told WJLA. He also suffered a head wound matching a bolt jutting from the vehicle's back door.
Police have already said Gray was not wearing restraints during the ride, a violation of department policies.
The leaks did not impress protesters. School employee Gregory Baugh, 37, called the new reports "bogus".
"He had plenty of bruises all over him, that had to happen some way."
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:24:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal quake toll passes 6,100, $2 billion needed for reconstruction</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/01/nepal-quake-toll-passes-6100-2-billion-needed-for-reconstruction</Link>
        <Description>KATHMANDU - The death toll from Nepal's devastating earthquake rose steadily past 6,100 on Friday as fresh aftershocks and the stench of rotting bodies made it hard for nervous survivors to return to their homes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boy, woman rescued from rubble
KATHMANDU - The death toll from Nepal's devastating earthquake rose steadily past 6,100 on Friday as fresh aftershocks and the stench of rotting bodies made it hard for nervous survivors to return to their homes.
Disposal of the hundreds of bodies still being found six days after the 7.9 magnitude quake devastated the Himalayan nation of 28 million people was becoming a problem for officials, who have ordered immediate cremations.
"Morgues are full beyond capacity and we have been given instruction to incinerate bodies immediately after they are pulled out," said Raman Lal, an Indian paramilitary force official working in coordination with Nepali forces.
Aid was slowly beginning to reach remote towns and villages nestled in the mountains and foothills but the overpowering smell of bodies trapped beneath the rubble of collapsed buildings in the capital was making it hard for residents to return to their homes.
Many Nepalis have been sleeping in the open since Saturday's quake. According to the United Nations, 600,000 houses have been destroyed or damaged.
Finance Minister Ram Sharan Mahat said Nepal would need at least $2 billion to rebuild homes, hospitals, government offices and historic buildings and appealed for help from international donors.
"This is just an initial estimate and it will take time to assess the extent of damage and calculate the cost of rebuilding," Mahat told Reuters.
The United Nations has said 8 million people had been affected, with at least 2 million in need of tents, water, food and medicines over the next three months.
A home ministry official said the death toll had risen to 6,134, with 13,906 injured.
Information Minister Minendra Rijal said the government would provide $1,000 in immediate assistance to the families of those killed, as well as $400 for cremation or burial.
Prime Minister Sushil Koirala told Reuters earlier this week the death toll from the quake could reach 10,000.
That would surpass the 8,500 who died in a 1934 earthquake, the last disaster on this scale to hit the Himalayan nation sandwiched between India and China.
UNPRECEDENTED SCALE
Home ministry official Laxmi Prasad Dhakal said that, even though the 1934 quake was more powerful, there were fewer people living in the Kathmandu valley then.
"The scale of reconstruction will be unprecedented," Dhakal said. "We have still not even been able to assess the damage in remote areas, which have been completely devastated."
Officials have said the chances of finding any more survivors were fading, even though a boy and a woman had on Thursday been pulled from the rubble where they had lain trapped for five days.
As rescuers slowly started reaching outlying areas, witnesses reported seeing 70 to 80 percent of buildings severely damaged in Chautara, northeast of Kathmandu towards the border with China's Tibet.
Anger over the pace of the rescue has flared in some areas, with Nepalis accusing the government of being too slow to distribute international aid that has flooded into the country.
It has yet to reach many in need, particularly in areas hard to reach given the quake damage, poor weather and aftershocks.
Tensions between foreigners and Nepalis desperate to be evacuated have also surfaced. In Ashrang village in Gorkha, one of the worst-hit districts about four hours by road west of Kathmandu, hundreds of villagers were living outdoors with little food and water even as boxes of biscuits, juice and sacks of rice and wheat were stored in a nearby government office.
Nepal is also appealing to foreign governments for more helicopters help the 20 at work in rescue operations. China was expected to send more, home ministry official Dhakal said.
In the Himalayas, climbing is set to reopen on Mount Everest next week after damage caused by avalanches triggered by the quake is repaired, although many have abandoned their ascents.
A massive avalanche killed 18 climbers and sherpa mountain guides at the Everest base camp.
(Additional reporting by Andrew MacAskill, Sanjeev Miglani, Ross Adkin, Frank Jack Daniel, Andrew Marshall, Adnan Abidi and Christophe Van Der Perre in Nepal; Writing by Paul Tait; Editing by Alex Richardson)

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:41:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boon’s supporters grow, to no avail</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/boons-supporters-grow-to-no-avail</Link>
        <Description>Veteran Art Boon will fly to the Netherlands Friday night to take part in ceremonies marking the 70th anniversary of the country’s liberation from the Nazis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Board's inane excuses dishonour vet's deeds
STRATFORD-
Veteran Art Boon will fly to the Netherlands Friday night to take part in ceremonies marking the 70th anniversary of the countrys liberation from the Nazis.
Jamie Boon, his 20-year-old grandson, will be by his side.
Not making the trip will be Art Boons son Rick. The decision by the Avon Maitland District school board to deny Rick Boons request for unpaid leave sparked a wave of public and political indignation that resulted Thursday in a community meeting in Stratford and sharp criticism of the board by federal Veterans Affairs Minister Erin OToole.
Art Boon, 90, received a standing ovation when he arrived Thursday night at Stratford city hall to take part in the forum organized by Stratford singer Loreena McKennitt, who championed Boons request to have his son Rick accompany him on the trip.
Art Boon arrived late because he had attended a meeting at the Legion.
I have a great feeling for the Netherlands and the Dutch people in this area, he said.
Boon said he hoped to share the special experience with son, who is an elementary school teacher with the board. Boon said he counts on his son when he travels to make sure he takes his medication.
Im always comfortable when Rick is with me, he said in an interview.
The board has been under intense pressure to reverse its decision and allow Rick Boon to take six days of unpaid leave so he could make the once-in-a-lifetime trip with his father for the ceremonies in Holland, where love of Canadian veterans still burns strong seven decades after they freed the country from the Nazis brutal rule.
Anger over the boards decision burned up radio talk show lines and led hundreds to sign a petition that was delivered to the board this week.
Politicians weighed in, including OToole who said Thursday he called the Avon Maitland board to express his frustration and try to find a solution.
I do not normally insert myself into the affairs of school boards and know they have tough decisions to make, but I wanted them to know that my interest was the well-being of Mr. Boon. I wanted to ensure he could attend this important commemoration in a way that he was most comfortable, he said.
If Art Boon wants his son with him, as a Canadian hero, he should have that, OToole said.
He knows this could be his last trip to the country that he and thousands of other young Canadians liberated 70 years ago. He wants to represent his comrades who are not well enough to make the journey. Most importantly, he wants to honour and remember his 7,600 Canadian comrades who made the ultimate sacrifice in the liberation of the Dutch people.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:33:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A dozen dead kittens found at roadside</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/a-dozen-dead-kittens-found-at-roadside</Link>
        <Description>ST. CATHARINES, Ont. -- A dozen dead kittens found on the side of the road in Beamsville, Ont., early April may have come from as many as four litters.</Description>
        <MainBody>155 dead cats found in apartment
ST. CATHARINES, Ont. -- A dozen dead kittens found on the side of the road in Beamsville, Ont., early April may have come from as many as four litters.
The Lincoln County Humane Society said a post-mortem examination was recently completed on the kittens, who were found on South Service Rd. near the Town of Lincoln offices on April 8.
Executive director Kevin Strooband said the cats ranged in age from six to eight weeks old and were from at least two litters and as many as four.
The humane society isn't saying how they died, but the case is being investigated as a possible act of cruelty to animals.
"It's part of the investigation," Strooband said.
Humane society officials are appealing to the public for information about anyone recently caring for at least two litters of kittens.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:59:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tortoise gets wheels for front legs after rat attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/tortoise-gets-wheels-for-front-legs-after-rat-attack</Link>
        <Description>Mrs. T the tortoise has been given a second chance at life at 90-years-old.</Description>
        <MainBody>Canoe.com
Thursday, April 30, 2015       9:59:43 EDT PM
A tortoise who had its front legs gnawed off has been given wheels for legs. (Screenshot from YouTube)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
Mrs. T the tortoise has been given a second chance at life at 90-years-old.
After rats broke into the tortoise's cage and gnawed off its two front legs, owner Jude Ryder decided to do something.
According to the Telegraph , she asked her son, Dale, to make wheels for the pet.
"We were hoping initially that there was going to be enough of the stubs left so we could fix ... prosthetic legs to her, but unfortunately too much of the legs had to be cut off so we ended up coming up with the idea of wheels," Dale said in a video by the Telegraph.
The turtle can walk backward, forward and turn around, Dale said, thanks to the model airplane wheels he glued to its shell.
"Hopefully she's got another 90 years left in her."
Mobile users, click here for video
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:32:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Londoner William Kechego faces bulk of charges in break-ins last year across Southwestern Ontario</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/londoner-william-kechego-faces-bulk-of-charges-in-break-ins-last-year-across-southwestern-ontario</Link>
        <Description>A London man is facing charges in a rash of pharmacy robberies last year spread over Southwestern Ontario.</Description>
        <MainBody>Londoner William Kechego faces bulk of charges in break-ins last year across Southwestern Ontario 0
By Dan Brown , The London Free Press
Thursday, April 30, 2015       8:32:29 EDT PM
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
A London man is facing charges in a rash of pharmacy robberies last year spread over Southwestern Ontario.
William Kechego, of Adelaide St., faces more than 20 charges, including six counts of break and enter and theft, and four of wearing a disguise, the OPP said Thursday.
The same suspect  charged after a Kitchener-area drug store robbery last fall  is charged along with two others, including a Middlesex County man.
Police allege three people were responsible for a string of robberies from August to November of last year, at pharmacy stores in Ailsa Craig, Bayfield, Forest, Grand Bend and North Perth Township.
In each instance, quantities of drugs were stolen and used for the purpose of trafficking, the OPP said.
Theyre not all that far apart. When you start looking at that kind of thing, well start working with other services, said OPP media officer Const. Mark Foster.
Police said an investigation involving more than one police force led to the charges. We share information, Foster said.
Kechego, 34, faces two charges of possession for the purposes of trafficking, one of possession of marijuana over 30 grams, three counts of trafficking a controlled substance, three of trafficking stolen goods valued at more than $5,000, and single counts each of possession of stolen goods worth more than $5,000 and less than $5,000.
To have this many charges, in relation to one or two people, thats a significant number of charges, Foster added.
Earlier this year, OPP arrested Kechego in connection with the robbery of the Port Rowan Pharmasave on New Years Eve.
In that incident, an alert citizen heard glass breaking and called police, then tried but failed to pull over a silver-coloured van seen racing up a street away from the Pharmasave.
The van wound up in Simcoe.
Kechego and another man were arrested and charged. The charges against Kechego included obstructing police.
Last November, Kechego and another Londoner were charged with a rash of offences  including Kechego with impaired driving  after a pharmacy break-in in Elmira and a head-on SUV crash in Kitchener.
Charges with Kechego in the latest string of robberies are Kateland Watson, 22, of no fixed address, and Robert Roth of Middlesex County.
Watson faces two counts of break and enter and one of wearing a disguise, while Roth is charged with three counts of break, enter and theft, three of wearing a disguise and three of failing to stop for police.
Kechego is in custody in Waterloo on other charges.
Watson and Roth are to appear in court in London.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:25:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>16 eagles killed, dumped in B.C.</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/16-eagles-killed-dumped-in-bc</Link>
        <Description>Someone is killing eagles and dumping their carcasses in B.C.'s South Cariboo region, conservation officers say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bald eagle hatches on popular nest camera
Someone is killing eagles and dumping their carcasses in B.C.'s South Cariboo region, conservation officers say.
So far, 16 eagles have been found since April 3, nearly all of them bald eagles, Sgt. Len Butler said. At least four of them were shot; it's suspected others were poisoned.
Many of the birds were found inside garbage bags, "indiscriminately" discarded by the side of a rural road, Butler said. As the snow melts, more are being discovered.
Some of the kills were recent, judging by the lack of decomposition, while other were clearly older. The carcasses have all been sent to a lab for analysis. Butler is counting on the forensics to help explain the deaths.
"We don't have very many leads at this time," he said.
Butler said there have been suggestions the birds were to be used in First Nations ceremonial events or for trafficking in eagle parts, but conservation officers have ruled that out because the birds are "fully intact."

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:14:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Injured woman cheers auditor general's winter road maintenance report</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/injured-woman-cheers-auditor-generals-winter-road-maintenance-report</Link>
        <Description>Gisele Doyon narrowly escaped death this 
winter when her car hit a patch of ice 
near Sault Ste. Marie and slid across the 
highway — right into the path of an 
oncoming transport truck.</Description>
        <MainBody>Deaths spiked after Liberal cuts: AG
Gisele Doyon narrowly escaped death this winter when her car hit a patch of ice near Sault Ste. Marie and slid across the highway  right into the path of an oncoming transport truck.
Still recovering six months later, shes convinced the blame lies squarely at the doorstep of Queens Park cutbacks.
This could have been prevented had the roads been cleaned, insists Doyon, 51, whos been unable to return to work as a dietary aide since the accident last November. There was no salt, no sand, nothing. They dont have the manpower or the equipment.
So she wanted to cheer when a scathing auditors report this week confirmed what she already knows from painful experience:  motorists were at greater risk on the provinces highways because the cost-cutting Ontario Ministry of Transportation had moved to low-bid, performance-based contracts where there was little oversight.
Left largely to their own devices in determining how they would get the work done, private sector contractors are skimping on salt, sand, and deicing liquid and cutting back on the frequency of their plowing. Winter maintenance service levels across the province decreased, leading in some cases to hazardous driving conditions, concluded Ontario Auditor General Bonnie Lysyk.
Not surprisingly, accidents and deaths may have been the result. The ministry acknowledged that after a decade of declining fatalities, preliminary information indicated there was an increase in the number of deaths on Ontario highways in 2013 where snow, slush or ice was a factor. More can be done.
The irony, of course, is that whatever the government has saved may be offset by all the money theyll have to dish out to those taking them to court. An estimated 200 lawsuits have been filed against the MTO. Doyon is in the midst of preparing to launch one herself.
The mother of two was on Hwy. 17, part of the Trans-Canada that slices across northern Ontario, driving her Ford Mustang with all-season tires that have always served her well in the winter.  She was heading about 20 minutes out of town to pick up her son after work but when she got there, he told her he was going home with a friend. As they all headed back, conditions on the highway had badly deteriorated  they were snow covered with ice building under the surface.
Doyon was heading up the notorious Mile Hill just on the outskirts of Sault Ste Marie, a steep incline thats supposed to be maintained 24/7, she says, when the rear of her car suddenly lost all grip on the road.
I hit a patch of ice that made my back wheels swing out and I had no control, she recalls. All I can remember were the headlights coming at me.
Helpless in the car behind her, her son watched the horrifying scene play out before him: his moms vehicle skidded into the oncoming lane and into the path of a transport. Luckily, the truck driver had slowed right down because he had planned to exit into a weigh station.
He told my son that if hed been doing full speed, your mother wouldnt be here today, she says.
Doyon also credits the driver with manouevering his truck so that it hit her car on the passenger side. He actually saved my life.
The next thing she remembers is waking up in hospital. Shed suffered a broken sternum and soft tissue damage to most of her body. She was bedridden for about a month and a half and her son had to take time off work to nurse her. Doyon is still in physiotherapy but hoping to go back to work part-time by June 1. Her doctor has warned her that a full recovery will take a year.
Shes just hoping that by the time she is back winter driving, the government will have heeded the auditor generals report and improved highway maintenance.
Road conditions in northern Ontario are ferocious. Its unbelievable what were supposed to be travelling on, Doyon says. We need to all stand up and show them were not going sit back anymore. We need to stand together and press for change.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:51:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oshawa's GM pain could spread  to London</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/oshawas-gm-pain-could-spread--to-london</Link>
        <Description>With GM steering Camaro production to Michigan from Ontario, London-area parts makers may feel the loss.</Description>
        <MainBody>Oshawa's GM pain could spread  to London 0
By Norman DeBono , The London Free Press
Thursday, April 30, 2015       7:51:13 EDT PM
(Supplied image - GM)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
With GM steering Camaro production to Michigan from Ontario, London-area parts makers may feel the loss.
The automaker announced Thursday its Oshawa plant will stop making Camaros Nov. 20, eliminating one shift and 1,000 jobs. The plant has 3,600 workers on four shifts.
The Camaro will be made in Grand River, Mich., a four-hour drive from London, and parts makers in Michigan can bid on the supply work being done locally, said Dave Paterson, vice-president GM Canada.
The bidding to supply the next generation (Camaro) is well underway ... theres a chance they will win, he said of London-area suppliers.
It will be competitive.
London parts maker Autoneum and Formet in St. Thomas supply parts for the Camaro. Autoneum makes carpets and interior finishes.
We have retained the Camaro business at this point so I imagine that we have to at least consider us losing that product, said Bert Briley, a worker at Autoneum.
The company is building a 400,000-square-foot plant in Indiana that may compete with work done here, Briley said.
The London plant also supplies Ford and Chrysler operations in Michigan.
Moving production of the Camaro to Michigan could affect production in London, said Jim Reid, chairperson of Unifor Local 27 that represents workers at several area auto parts plants, including  Autoneum.
The Forment plant in St. Thomas supplies rocker panels for the Camaro. Formet is not aware of any impact GMs move will have, Magna spokesperson Tracy Fuerst said.
GM is moving Camaro production to Michigan because its a rear-wheel drive vehicle, and the Michigan plant makes other rear wheel drive cars.
The addition of a new vehicle at the Oshawa plant will depend on how negotiations proceed next year with Unifor, Paterson said.
We will evaluate cost effectiveness of the plant and that will involve many different factors, including the union contract.
About 2,100 of GMs 3,600 Oshawa workers are eligible for early retirement and will be offered incentives of $50,000 and a $20,00 car voucher, in addition to their early pension.
The Oshawa plant will continue to build the Chevrolet Impala, Buick Regal and Cadillac XTS and finish some Chevrolet Equinoxes shipped for final assembly from Cami Assembly in Ingersoll that is at capacity.
That plant is still vibrant, Paterson said.
As for Cami, the automaker has announced the plant is getting a $560-million investment from GM to build the next generation Equinox and Terrain.
GM also announced it is investing $5.4 billion in its U.S. operations over the next three years.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:40:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dutch explorers presumed drowned in Canadian Arctic</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/dutch-explorers-presumed-drowned-in-canadian-arctic</Link>
        <Description>Two people who went missing while exploring sea ice north of Resolute Bay, Nunavut, are believed to have drowned, RCMP say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Canada wants to claim to North Pole
Two people who went missing while exploring sea ice north of Resolute Bay, Nunavut, are believed to have drowned, RCMP say.
Police said the expedition members from the Netherlands sent out a distress signal on Wednesday from an area near Bathurst Island, 100 km north of Resolute Bay.
A local aircraft spotted equipment near open water and poor ice conditions, RCMP said.
Search and rescue personnel later flew over the area. They didn't find the expedition members and confirmed that personal items were floating in the water at the location of the distress signal.
RCMP said after further search efforts, the Dutch explorers are presumed drowned.
The pair was working for a project called Cold Facts based in the Netherlands and left Resolute Bay on April 4.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:40:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>School board's 'guns pointed in wrong direction': Veterans Affairs Minister Erin O'Toole</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/school-boards-guns-pointed-in-wrong-direction-veterans-affairs-minister-erin-otoole</Link>
        <Description>It is not “leadership” for a school 
board not to reconsider a decision 
preventing one of their teacher from 
travelling with his 90-year-old father 
to ceremonies marking the 70th 
anniversary of the liberation of the 
Netherlands, Veterans Affairs Minister 
Erin O’Toole said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>School board won't budge
STRATFORD-
Standing ovations in this town are usually reserved for the talents of Shakespeare and the greats who have performed here.
But there was another star on stage here Thursday.
On this night 90-year-old Canadian veteran Art Boon was bigger than Shakespeare  and Justin Bieber, too.
There was no debate on that either. The auditorium inside the City Hall here was packed to the balcony with people upset about the latest Shakespearian drama.
They want Art to be accompanied by his teacher son Rick to the 70th anniversary in the Netherlands and were not shy about expressing it.
When he walked into the room, everybody rose to their feet and applauded for about 10 minutes.
Message sent. And two trustees on the Avon Maitland District School Board were there to receive it at the head table at the community discussion about how it is a veteran could actually be put in a position to fight down to the wire to see if mindd can be changed and his son permitted to go.
As of deadline it appeared the original decision to not allow him to take an unpaid leave was still very much in place.
That said, the Sun has learned, that Rick Boon was called Thursday evening to travel to nearby Seaforth for a meeting with school board officials at its head office.
I dont know what its about yet, said Art. I sure hope they are talking to him about finding a way that would allow him to go on this trip.
The school board has not responded to queries about it so far.
But Art said he was taking it as a positive that they were at least talking and meeting and considering.
Prior to this, rigid might be the best way to describe it.
The school board has made it very clear when they said they would not be reconsidering this decision, said singer and honorary RCAF Col. Loreena McKennitt. We want to get them to reconsider it because this veteran deserves that.
Art Boon was part of the liberation forces and is having the trip for him and his son Rick paid for the Dutch government as part of their big celebrations next week. He was at the 70th anniversary of D-Day at Juno Beach last year, as was his son Rick.
That the board allowed their teacher an unpaid leave last year, resulted in a decision to not allow him to have a similar opportunity this year.
Director of Education Ted Doherty said in weighing the needs of the board and the students he decided to not grant the leave.
There still is, however, time to make this right. The flight for the Netherlands does not leave until 10:55 p.m. Friday.
The movement to see that happen received a giant boost Thursday night when Veterans Affairs minister Erin OToole stepped into this and scolded the stubborn stance of the board.
This is not about the teacher, it is about the Veteran, said OToole. I truly hope that the Avon Maitland District School Board recognizes that public concern is based out of genuine concern for a 90-year old veteran who deserves to be heard. Sticking to your guns when they are pointed the wrong way is not leadership.
Thats exactly how this packed room felt in Stratford. When trustees Doug Pratley and Lynette Geddes tried to explain the reasons behind it, there was an uneasy grumbling throughout.
McKennitt eloquently tried to urge the board again to look for a compromise and find a way to make this happen and make it right.
Moderator Ted Barris asked an excellent question: If he was able to legally go on the trip to Juno Beach last year, why is it different this year?
The Boons, after all, are not going to Disneyland, on vacation, to a curling bonspiel or a family reunion  all noble pursuits but not something worthy of missing work for. The Boons are going back to trace the steps of Canadian valour, glory and sacrifice and to reserve the recognition from the Dutch people who are very appreciative that people like Art risked his life to help them escape Nazi occupation. That is far bigger than any rule in a school board manual.
We better start remembering where we got our freedoms, Art told the crowd near the end of the meeting. It was not from lawyers or rules but from 140,000 Canadians who sacrificed their lives.
He received another ovation.
Doherty and the school board still have time to make it a great day and avoid a Stratford-style Shakespearean tragedy.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:57:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Topless Femen protester disrupts Quebec press conference</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/topless-femen-protester-disrupts-quebec-press-conference</Link>
        <Description>A topless Femen protester interrupted the Quebec culture minister's press conference on Thursday sporting red-splotched underwear and shouting "My uterus, my priority!"</Description>
        <MainBody>Topless protesters disrupt anti-abortion rally
A topless Femen protester interrupted the Quebec culture minister's press conference on Thursday sporting red-splotched underwear and shouting "My uterus, my priority!"
The radical feminist group opposes Quebec's Bill 20, which they believe will restrict abortion access -- a suggestion Health Minister Gaetan Barrette denies.
The bill would put an annual quota of patients and medical procedures in place for Quebec family doctors, and each abortion performed would count towards that quota.
A group of doctors recently released a report indicating that this system would take priority status away from abortions.

Posted by FEMEN - Canada on Thursday, 30 April 2015
"We are outraged: it is not because Gaetan Barrette doesn't have a uterus himself that he gets to decide that humans who do are secondary! A FEMEN activist went to the National Assembly to lift up her skirt and show HER priority: her uterus and the violence done to her body by the suppression of essential health care services," Femen Canada said in a Facebook post.
The protester, who snuck into Culture Minister Helene David's press conference by pretending to be a journalist, was arrested and released.
She may face charges of committing an indecent act in a public place, police said.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:54:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Immigrants brought own home to Canada</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/04/30/immigrants-brought-own-home-to-canada</Link>
        <Description>Finding a permanent home was an important milestone for the wave of European immigrants who came to Canada to escape the devastation of the Second World War.</Description>
        <MainBody>HISTORY: Arnold Broeders chose Canada over South Africa
Immigrants brought own home to Canada 0
By Ellwood Shreve , Chatham Daily News
Thursday, April 30, 2015       6:54:11 EDT PM
Image: 1 of 3
Previous Next
Arnold Broeders Jr. displays documents issued from the Nazis to his father, Arnold Broeders, during the Second World War, including a permission form, which he is holding,  allowing his father to continue operating a small, family-owned woodworking factory in Holland. Also pictured is an identification document, bottom right, that Dutch residents had to have on their person at all times. The identification includes a picture and thumb print of his father. Broeders also saved an story that appeared in the Monday, Aug. 27, 1951 issue of the Windsor Daily Star that details how his father pre-fabricated a home at the woodworking factory to be shipped to Blenheim, Ont. when his family immigrated to Canada in 1951. Photo taken in Chatham, Ont. on Thursday April 30, 2015. Ellwood Shreve/Chatham Daily News/Postmedia Network
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
Finding a permanent home was an important milestone for the wave of European immigrants who came to Canada to escape the devastation of the Second World War.
The late Arnold Broeders had a leg up on most immigrants in having a new home when he brought his wife Maria and six children to Blenheim, Ont., from Tilburg, Holland, on June 26, 1951.
He had prefabricated his home at a small family-owned woodworking factory in preparation for the move.
His son, Arnold Broeders Jr., 71, shared the story of his family's first home in Canada, which is still located on Marlborough Street, on the southwest edge of the community.
As European countries struggled to recover from the war, Broeders Jr. said there were restrictions on how much money you could take out of Holland, so his father decided to export a home.
The story was chronicled in a feature story by the Windsor Daily Star, published Aug. 27, 1951.
The 40 bundles and cases that contained the modest 1,000-square-foot home reached Montreal on Aug. 5, 1951, before being transported to the plot of land Broeders Sr. had bought in Blenheim.
The customs were very friendly and co-operative and as soon as possible my 40 bundles were cleared and the same night we had it on my property, Broeders Sr. was quoted in the Windsor Daily Star article.
While most young men were forced into labouring for the Nazis during the war, Broeders Jr. said his father was fortunate to receive permission from the Germans to continue to operate the factory. He still has the permission form his father received from the Nazis.
According to the Star story, Broeders Sr. had plenty of experience making prefabricated homes.
He was quoted: Since I built hundreds of houses after the war was over, in order to provide homes for the people who lost them in the devastating terror of the war and the occupation by the Germans and moreover as many fabricated homes went to Australia, New Zealand, Brazil and South Africa, I decided to make one of my own and come to Canada.
Broeders Jr. said his father went to South Africa for several months in 1947 to see if it would be a suitable country to raise a family. He said his father could see the trouble brewing as apartheid was about to begin and decided this is not a place to raise a family.
Having been born in Argentina, Broeders Sr. was willing to go anywhere in the world where there was work and he could build a life for his family.
Broeders Jr. said his parents were happy to be in Canada because of the Dutch community here.
Even when Europe benefited from a post-war economic boom, he said his parents never gave a thought to returning to Holland. He added they liked the fact Canada was a safe country and figured it would never be invaded by another country.
I think for anybody who immigrates, it's always more for your family than yourself, said Broeders Jr.
The 70th anniversary of the Liberation of Holland is approaching and Broeders Jr. has a special memory because of what his mother, Maria, told him.
He was just two years old when the Dutch were liberated in 1945 by Canadian military forces, so he doesn't remember the jubilation it brought.
The only thing I remember is the war (for Holland) really ended on my birthday, which was May 7, he said, adding the actual Liberation Day was declared on May 8.
My mother told me: 'That's really when the war ended, hostilities ended.'
As for that prefabricated home from Holland, it still stands and has an interesting history.
The house was purchased by George and Peggy McIntyre in 1962, who raised more than 90 boys there over a five-decade period, according to their daughter Dixie McIntyre.
She said her parents were government-approved parents who took in boys from the former Southwest Regional Centre, located nearby, to raise them to be integrated back into the community.
McIntyre said her mother moved out in 2012, at age 94, after caring for the last boy from the centre.
They had 10 to 11 boys in the house at one time, McIntyre said of her parents.
The home still remains in the family.
Suzanne Marble, granddaughter of George and Peggy McIntyre, now owns the home.
It's got a lot of great memories, she said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
