<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:26:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>N.Y. socialite sentenced to 18 years for poisoning autistic son</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/ny-socialite-sentenced-to-18-years-for-poisoning-autistic-son</Link>
        <Description>A wealthy New York socialite was sentenced to 18 years in prison on Thursday after being convicted of killing her young autistic son at a luxury Manhattan hotel room in 2010.</Description>
        <MainBody>N.Y. socialite sentenced to 18 years for poisoning autistic son 0
Sebastien Malo, Reuters
Thursday, May 28, 2015       7:26:28 EDT PM
Gigi Jordan, a wealthy New York socialite who was convicted in 2014 of first-degree manslaughter for the 2010 killing of her 8-year-old autistic son, appears in Manhattan Criminal Court for her sentencing hearing in New York May 28, 2015. Jordan was sentenced to 18 years in prison. REUTERS/Mike Segar
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
NEW YORK - A wealthy New York socialite was sentenced to 18 years in prison on Thursday after being convicted of killing her young autistic son at a luxury Manhattan hotel room in 2010.
Gigi Jordan, 54, was convicted of first-degree manslaughter in November after admitting that she administered an overdose of prescription pills to 8-year-old Jude Mirra at the posh Peninsula Hotel on Fifth Avenue, using a crusher and syringe.
Jordan's attorneys argued throughout the two-month trial that she had killed the boy in an act of mercy to prevent the boy's biological father from sexually abusing him, a scenario that prosecutors said was based on fiction.
Judge Charles Solomon of the state Supreme Court in Manhattan handed down a sentence that was close to the maximum of 25 years in prison under New York guidelines, saying he was mystified by the mother's lack of remorse.
"It's very difficult for me to understand the defendant," Solomon said. "I certainly would think that I would hear something from the defendant expressing remorse about what she did - something."
In a 30-minute statement read to the court, Jordan appealed for leniency and again said she had been acting in her son's best interests.
"I love Jude more than anything in this world," the former pharmaceuticals executive and self-made millionaire said in a 30-minute statement. "I believe that he lived and died in unbelievable agony."
At her trial last year, the jury accepted the defense's claim that Jordan had acted under extreme emotional distress, finding her guilty of manslaughter rather than the top murder charge sought by prosecutors.
Even though Mirra was unable to express himself well, Jordan's attorneys argued, he had told his mother that he was being sexually abused by his father, Emil Tzekov.
Tzekov, a yoga instructor who became Jordan's second ex-husband, has denied the accusations.
Jordan said she feared she would be unable to protect her boy because her first husband, Philadelphia businessman Raymond Mirra Jr., planned to have her killed or institutionalized, and Tzekov would gain custody of her son.
Prosecutors argued that Jordan carefully planned the death of her son after travelling the country to find a cure for his autism. They said that Jordan killed her son because she could not accept that he was disabled and she could not fix his medical condition.
Outside of court, Jordan's attorney, Norman Siegel, expressed disappointment with the sentence and said Jordan would appeal.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:48:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former U.S. House Speaker Hastert indicted on federal charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/former-us-house-speaker-hastert-indicted-on-federal-charges</Link>
        <Description>Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert was indicted on Thursday on federal charges including making false statements to the FBI, the U.S. Attorney's Office in Chicago said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Former U.S. House Speaker Hastert indicted on federal charges 0
REUTERS
Thursday, May 28, 2015       5:48:03 EDT PM
Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert (R-IL) speaks during a news conference in Batavia, Illinois in this October 5, 2006 file photo. Hastert was indicted on May 28, 2015 on federal charges including making false statements to the FBI, the U.S. Attorney's Office in Chicago said.  REUTERS/John Gress/Files
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
Former U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Dennis Hastert was indicted on Thursday on federal charges including making false statements to the FBI, the U.S. Attorney's Office in Chicago said.
The Illinois Republican, who left office in 2007, was charged with structuring the withdrawal of $952,000 in cash in order to evade the requirement that banks report cash transactions over $10,000, and lying to the FBI about his withdrawals, the U.S. Attorney's Office said in a statement.
Each count of the two-count indictment carries a maximum penalty of five years in prison and a $250,000 fine.
Hastert, 73, was not immediately available for comment.
According to the indictment, the misconduct involved payments to an unnamed individual who had been a Yorkville,  Illinois, resident and had known Hastert for most of the person's life.
Around 2010, Hastert met with the person several times and discussed past misconduct by Hastert. Eventually, Hastert agreed to pay the person $3.5 million in compensation and to conceal unspecified misconduct, the indictment said.
Shortly afterward, Hastert began making cash payments to the unnamed person, according to the indictment.
Hastert served as a Republican congressman from suburban Chicago for more than 20 years before resigning from the House in November 2007, having lost the speaker's job when Democrats gained control of the House in the 2006 elections.
Hastert joined the Washington law firm Dickstein Shapiro in 2008 as a senior adviser. The Chicago Mercantile Exchange said on Thursday that Hastert resigned from its board.


Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:21:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More storms lash Texas after severe weather kills 16</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/new-flood-warning-for-texas-where-storms-have-killed-16</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of people fled areas near Texas rivers that overflowed their banks on Thursday as the state reeled from severe storms this week that killed at least 16 people, flooded cities and set a record for the wettest month.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds evacuate Texas as death toll rises
AUSTIN, Texas - Hundreds of people fled areas near Texas rivers that overflowed their banks on Thursday as the state reeled from severe storms this week that killed at least 16 people, flooded cities and set a record for the wettest month.
The National Weather Service issued a flash flood watch on Thursday stretching from south of San Antonio to Dallas, through Oklahoma, where severe weather this week killed an additional six people, and into Kansas. Thunderstorms pelted large parts of the affected region on Thursday.
The city of Wharton, about 100 kilometres southwest of Houston, issued a voluntary evacuation notice for about 300 homes along the Colorado River, where water began spilling over the banks on Thursday afternoon and was expected to rise through Friday.
The Brazos River has flooded about 50 km west of Fort Worth and is expected to crest on Thursday evening. Hundreds left their homes on Wednesday as the waterway began breaching its banks, Parker County officials said.
State climatologist John Nielsen-Gammon said on Thursday the average rainfall across the state was 19 centimetres in May, breaking the record of 17 cm set in June 2004, according to records that date to 1895.
"It has been ridiculous," Nielsen-Gammon said.
The body of a boy was recovered on Wednesday near the central city of San Marcos, Hays County officials said. The boy, who has not been identified, was thought to have been swept away in Blanco River floods that ripped houses off their foundations, county officials said.
There were eight people missing in the county after the flooding, which started on Monday.
The new storms could hinder rescue workers who have been searching for days for those washed away in floods along the Blanco River.
"We are not expecting another surge of the river but it is going to shift debris piles," Kharley Smith, the county's emergency management coordinator, told a news conference.
President Barack Obama has pledged federal support and said the U.S. government had been working with local officials.
"They appear to have the assets they need at this stage to respond, but there's going to be a lot of rebuilding," Obama said in Miami on Thursday during a tour of the National Hurricane Center.
There was no damage estimate available for Texas, which has a $1.4 trillion-a-year economy and is the country's leading domestic source of energy.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:57:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suburban Detroit ex-cop to stand trial in beating of motorist</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/detroit-suburb-to-pay-14-mln-to-settle-police-beating-suit</Link>
        <Description>A white former police officer from suburban Detroit must stand trial for assault and other charges in the videotaped beating of a black motorist in January, a judge ruled on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Michigan cop charged with assault
INKSTER, Mich. - A white former police officer from suburban Detroit must stand trial for assault and other charges in the videotaped beating of a black motorist in January, a judge ruled on Thursday.
William Melendez was fired from the police force in the Detroit suburb of Inkster after he was filmed punching Floyd Dent, in one of a number of cases that has fueled national debate on race and policing.
Dent testified at a preliminary hearing in criminal court on Thursday, a day after he reached a $1.4 million settlement in his civil lawsuit against the city of Inkster.
Dent said he had memory loss and other damage from the beating.
"As I got out the car I had my arms out, the officer grabbed my arms and threw me to the ground," Dent testified before Judge Sabrina Johnson.
Wayne County Assistant Prosecutor Robert Donaldson added an additional charge of strangulation against Melendez.
"He choked me so hard I couldn't breathe," said Dent, who works for Ford.
If convicted, Melendez faces up to 10 years in prison.
During questioning by Donaldson, Dent said he was aware that he did not have a valid driver's license at the time of the traffic stop.
"That doesn't give the right to victimize another black man," said Dent's attorney, Gregory Rohl, during a recess.
Jim Thomas, one of three defense attorneys for Melendez, challenged Dent's recollection of the night's events during his cross examination, including whether he had leaned to the right inside his vehicle when he was stopped, a move he argued that could have been interpreted as hiding something.
Rohl confirmed that the city of Inkster, which has a majority black population, but a majority white police force, reached a settlement agreement in the civil case in the amount of $1.375 million this week.
"I think there was an intent to get Inkster to heal," Rohl said of the city's decision to settle the civil police brutality case out of court.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:02:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man pleads guilty in Chicago-area air control centre fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/man-pleads-guilty-in-chicago-area-air-control-centre-fire</Link>
        <Description>A Chicago-area man pleaded guilty on Thursday to federal charges of setting fire to a major air traffic control centre in September, an incident that snarled flights across the country for days, the Department of Justice said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Team working 24/7 to restore Chicago FAA site
CHICAGO - A Chicago-area man pleaded guilty on Thursday to federal charges of setting fire to a major air traffic control centre in September, an incident that snarled flights across the country for days, the Department of Justice said.
Brian Howard, 37, worked in telecommunications at the Chicago Air Route Traffic Control Center in Aurora and was apparently upset over a pending job transfer. On Sept. 26, he used wire cutters to sever cables at the center, then rubbed gasoline on telecoms equipment and set it on fire, according to the guilty plea.
The centre controls aircraft flying above 5,000 feet over a large part of the central United States, including Chicago's O'Hare International Airport, one of the world's busiest airports.
Howard faces up to 30 years in prison and a maximum fine of US$250,000 or twice the loss caused by fire, the Department of Justice said in a news release.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:57:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. charges fifteen Chinese nationals in SAT fraud scheme</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/us-charges-fifteen-chinese-nationals-in-sat-fraud-scheme</Link>
        <Description>Fifteen Chinese nationals living in the United States have been charged with developing a fraud scheme in which impostors took college entrance exams including the SAT, the Justice Department said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. charges fifteen Chinese nationals in SAT fraud scheme 0
Julia Edwards, Reuters
Thursday, May 28, 2015       1:57:34 EDT PM
(REUTERS/file)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
WASHINGTON - Fifteen Chinese nationals have been charged with developing a fraud scheme in which they paid imposters to take entrance exams, including the SAT, and gained acceptance to elite American colleges and universities, the U.S. Department of Justice said on Thursday.
Conspirators were paid up to $600 each time they used counterfeit Chinese passports to trick test administrators into thinking they were the person who would benefit from the test score, a federal grand jury charged.
Between 2011 and 2015, mainly in western Pennsylvania, the defendants paid imposters to take the SAT - previously known as the Scholastic Aptitude Test - the Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL) and the Graduate Record Examinations (GRE), under false names, according to the Justice Department statement.
Both the test takers and the people they claimed to be are being charged.
U.S. Attorney for the Western District of Pennsylvania David Hickton said the beneficiaries secured admission to undergraduate and graduate schools that are "among our finest educational institutions."
Hickton declined to name the specific schools, but said that they are located all over the United States. The students also cheated student visa requirements by using counterfeit Chinese passports, he said.
The defendants are men and women between the ages of 19 and 26 currently living in several cities where universities are located, including Blacksburg, Virginia, home of Virginia Tech and Boston, Massachusetts, home to dozens of colleges and several elite schools.
"These students were not only cheating their way into the university, they were also cheating their way through our nation's immigration system," said John Kelleghan, Special Agent in Charge for Homeland Security Investigations of Philadelphia.
If convicted, the defendants face a maximum sentence of 20 years in prison, a fine of $250,000 or both for each count of wire and mail fraud. Conspiracy charges carry an additional five-year maximum sentence.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:52:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bartender sentenced after man drinks 56 shots and dies</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/bartender-sentenced-after-man-drinks-56-shots-and-dies</Link>
        <Description>A bartender in France was convicted of manslaughter after a man drank 56 shots and later died.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bartender sentenced after man drinks 56 shots and dies 0
Canoe.com
Thursday, May 28, 2015       12:52:50 EDT PM
A man died in hospital a day after breaking the shots record at a bar in France by drinking 56 shots. (Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
A bartender in France was convicted of manslaughter after a man drank 56 shots and later died.
Renaud Prudhomme, 56, died in hospital a day after breaking the shots record at a bar in Clermont-Ferrand, France, last October, reports Agence France-Presse .
At an earlier hearing, bartender Gilles Crepin, 47, said displaying the shots record may have encouraged Prudhomme to drink to excess.
Crepin received a four-month suspended sentence on Wednesday and is not allowed to work in a bar for a year, however his lawyer plans on appealing the ruling.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:26:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hippo birth caught on video at Aussie zoo</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/hippo-birth-caught-on-video-at-aussie-zoo</Link>
        <Description>The Melbourne Zoo has captured on video the birth of a pygmy hippopotamus — the first to be born there in 33 years.</Description>
        <MainBody>Monkey will be called Charlotte despite protest
The Melbourne Zoo has captured on video the birth of a pygmy hippopotamus  the first to be born there in 33 years.
The clip shows the mother, Petre, appearing surprised when it finds the calf in the hay moments after the birth Monday. Petre then appears to settle into its role quickly and cleans the small hippo and nuzzles it.
The calf is the fourth offspring born to Petre, but the first for father Felix.
The birth was filmed by newly installed CCTV cameras, allowing keepers in an office next to the den to view the baby's birth live, the zoo said on its website Thursday.
"Petre is showing herself to be a very good and attentive mother to the newborn," the zoo said.
Keepers have been giving mom and baby space to bond, but believe the new baby to be a boy.
Zoo vet Dr. Sarah Frith planned to attempt to weigh the calf in the coming days and confirm its gender.
Pygmy hippos, native to Africa, are endangered in the wild due to poaching and the loss of their rainforest habitat.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:13:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Army chief says no human error seen in anthrax mishap</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/us-army-chief-says-no-human-error-seen-in-anthrax-mishap</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON - U.S. personnel working at an Army facility in Utah appeared to follow correctly all the outlined procedures to inactivate anthrax before they mistakenly shipped off live samples of the deadly bacteria, the Army's top general said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. military mistakenly ships live anthrax to lab
WASHINGTON - U.S. personnel working at an Army facility in Utah appeared to follow correctly all the outlined procedures to inactivate anthrax before they mistakenly shipped off live samples of the deadly bacteria, the Army's top general said on Thursday.
Army Chief of Staff General Raymond Odierno said investigators were now reviewing the procedures themselves to determine why the bacteria was not rendered inactive.
"The best I can tell there was not human error," Odierno told reporters, cautioning that his information was based solely on preliminary reports.
U.S. officials disclosed on Wednesday that U.S. Army facilities mistakenly shipped live anthrax bacteria to laboratories in nine states and an air base in South Korea.
The Pentagon has said there was no known suspected infection or risk to the public.
But four U.S. civilians have started taking preventive measures called post-exposure prophylaxis, which usually includes the anthrax vaccine, antibiotics or both.
Twenty-two personnel at the base in South Korea were also given precautionary medical measures although none have shown sign of exposure.
The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)  has begun an investigation of the incident. Odierno said the CDC was reviewing whether "we have to change the procedures that are in place."
Odierno did not offer specifics and said he did not know how long the procedures had been in place.
"But we definitely believe no one is in danger. We believe we followed all the proper procedures," Odierno said.
The mishap comes 11 months after the CDC, one of the government's top civilian labs, similarly mishandled anthrax. Researchers at a lab designed to handle extremely dangerous pathogens sent what they believed were killed samples of anthrax to another CDC lab, one with fewer safeguards and therefore not authorized to work with live anthrax.
Scores of CDC employees could have been exposed to the live anthrax, but none became ill.
That incident and a similar one last spring, in which CDC scientists shipped what they thought was a benign form of bird flu but which was actually a highly virulent strain, led U.S. lawmakers to fault a "dangerous pattern" of safety lapses at government labs.
In the latest case, the Army's Dugway Proving Ground in Utah reported in March 2014 that gamma irradiation had inactivated the anthrax stock in question, and along with another Army facility, began shipments that continued through April 2015, a U.S. official said.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:51:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boston bomber to face victims when death sentence handed down</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/boston-bomber-to-face-victims-when-death-sentence-handed-down</Link>
        <Description>Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev late next month will confront people who lost limbs and loved ones in the deadly 2013 attack when he is scheduled to be formally sentenced to death for his crimes, a judge said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston bomber to face 20 victims at sentencing
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev late next month will confront people who lost limbs and loved ones in the deadly 2013 attack when he is scheduled to be formally sentenced to death for his crimes, a judge said on Thursday.
The same federal jury that found Tsarnaev, 21, guilty of killing three people and injuring 264 in one of the highest-profile attacks on U.S. soil since Sept. 11, 2001, last month voted to sentence him to death. U.S. District Judge George O'Toole will formally hand down the sentence on June 24.
Tsarnaev's trial evoked memories of the darkest days in recent memory in Boston as victims testified of being hurled through the air by the twin pressure-cooker bombs, struggling to save the lives of those who had lost limbs amid screams of pain and fears that additional explosions would follow.
Survivors of the attack and family members of the three people who died in the bombing, as well as the family of a university police officer who was shot to death three days later, will have an opportunity to speak at the sentencing.
Martin Richard, 8, 23-year-old Chinese exchange student Lingzi Lu and 29-year-old restaurant manager Krystle Campbell were killed in the attack. Tsarnaev was also convicted in the slaying of Massachusetts Institute of Technology police officer Sean Collier, 26.
Tsarnaev, who did not testify in his own defense during the guilt or sentencing phases of his trial, will also have the right to speak, though he is under no obligation to do so.
Defense attorneys, who are expected to appeal the death sentence and conviction, argued that Tsarnaev was the junior partner in a scheme hatched and driven forward by his 26-year-old brother, Tamerlan, who died four days after the bombing following a gunfight with police that ended when Dzhokhar inadvertently ran his brother over with a stolen car.
Just three of the 74 people sentenced to death in the United States for federal crimes since 1988 have been executed. The first was Timothy McVeigh, put to death in June 2001 for killing 168 people in his 1995 attack on the federal government office building in Oklahoma City.
No federal prisoners have been put to death since 2003.
Several court cases related to the bombing are due to draw to a close over the next month. Three college friends of Tsarnaev who were found guilty of impeding the investigation into the attack are due to be sentenced next week.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:11:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State photos purport to show unharmed Palmyra ruins</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/islamic-state-photos-purport-to-show-unharmed-palmyra-ruins</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT - Islamic State posted photographs online which it said were taken in the central Syrian city of Palmyra and appeared to show its ancient ruins unharmed since the hardline group seized it from government forces.</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State killed 400 people in Syria's Palmyra
BEIRUT - Islamic State posted photographs online which it said were taken in the central Syrian city of Palmyra and appeared to show its ancient ruins unharmed since the hardline group seized it from government forces.
Reuters was not able to independently confirm the authenticity of the photographs posted on jihadi forums by the Islamic State's media branch. Activists in contact with people inside the city have also said there has been no damage to the UNSECO World Heritage site since the takeover.
Islamic State is an offshoot of al Qaeda that has seized territory in Syria and Iraq and is the target of a U.S.-led air strike campaign in both countries.
The group has destroyed antiquities in neighbouring Iraq and Syria's antiquities chief has voiced fears it might now devastate Palmyra, home to renowned Roman ruins including temples, colonnades and an amphitheatre.
On Wednesday the group shot dead around 20 men in the amphitheatre, accusing them of being government supporters, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group said.
It has said the group has killed at least 200 people and taken around 600 captive in and around the city, which is also known as Tadmur.
The 10 images were published as a photographic report entitled "The ancient city of Tadmur" and showed the inside and entrance to the amphitheatre.
It appeared to have an Islamic State flag flying on top of it. There were also pictures of columns and arches.
A separate photo report claimed to show the city's prison in control of the group. It included images of an entrance, cell doors, an empty single cell and collective detention room. A picture of an empty office inside the jail had an image of late Syrian President Hafez al-Assad on the wall.
The Syrian air force has carried out airstrikes in and around Palmyra. U.S.-led forces, whose campaign U.S. officials say is not coordinated with Damascus, have not bombed the city, which sits on a crossroads leading westwards to Homs city and the capital.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:55:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italian boy survives after spending 42 minutes underwater</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/italian-boy-survives-after-spending-42-minutes-underwater</Link>
        <Description>An Italian teen who jumped into a shallow canal in Milan and spent 42 minutes underwater before rescuers could find his motionless body in the murky water is miraculously on the road to recovery, Italian media report.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italian boy survives after spending 42 minutes underwater 0
Postmedia Network
Thursday, May 28, 2015       10:55:59 EDT AM
Bridge near Milan where a teen jumped into a shallow canal and spent 42 minutes underwater on April 24, 2015. (Google Maps)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
An Italian teen who jumped into a shallow canal in Milan and spent 42 minutes underwater before rescuers could find his motionless body in the murky water is miraculously on the road to recovery, Italian media report.
The 14-year-old boy, identified in reports only as Michael, suddenly woke up after spending a month in hospital in San Raffaele and asked his parents whether his favourite soccer team, Juventus, was still in the Champions League, according to The Milan Chronicle .
His doctor, Alberto Zangrillo, a personal physician to former Italian prime minister Silvio Berlusconi, told reporters saving the boy's life gave him "the greatest satisfaction" of his career.
Zangrillo said he believes the cold water helped save the boy by slowing down his pulse. Doctors put the boy into an induced coma and performed extracorporeal membrane oxygenation, which involves removing oxygen-deprived blood, warming it and adding oxygen before re-injecting it, The Milan Chronicle reported.
His right leg was amputated below the knee because of circulation problems, but doctors say he doesn't appear to have brain damage.
Zangrillo said despite the ordeal, his patient has a great sense of humour. "The other day, he asked us for a mojito."
"He has recovered the spirit of the kid his parents and friends knew. He is a great guy, with uncommon intelligence. Every day I talk to him and joke," he said.
"There are very big question marks about the human brain. We don't know its full possibilities. What we do know is that you should never give up."

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:48:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chicago police officers seen posing over antlered black man in racist photo</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/chicago-police-officers-seen-posing-over-antlered-black-man-in-racist-photo</Link>
        <Description>A photo of two white Chicago police officers holding rifles and posing over a black man wearing antlers like an animal killed on a hunt was released by an Illinois court, the Chicago Tribune reported on Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>New video shows Freddie Gray arrest in Baltimore
A photo of two white Chicago police officers holding rifles and posing over a black man wearing antlers like an animal killed on a hunt was released by an Illinois court, the Chicago Tribune reported on Wednesday.
The news comes amid a national outcry against police treatment of minority groups, and African-Americans in particular, following several high-profile police killings of unarmed black men in cities like Ferguson, Mo., and New York over the past year.
The Chicago Police Board terminated the employment of former Detective Timothy McDermott over the photo in October, the newspaper said.
McDermott has filed a lawsuit to regain his job, and the Tribune said a judge blocked his and his attorneys' requests to have the photo kept under seal.
McDermott was joined in the picture by Officer Jerome Finnigan, who was sentenced to 12 years in prison for home invasions and robberies as part of a disgraced police task force and for "ordering a hit" on another officer he believed to be helping investigators probe the corruption, the newspaper said.
The identity of the black man and how he came to be in the photograph were not immediately known.
McDermott described participating in the photo as a mistake to police internal affairs in 2013, the paper said.
"I made a mistake as a young impressionable police officer who was trying to fit in," McDermott said, according to the Tribune.
The police board said in its charges against McDermott that the photo was snapped sometime between October 1999 and July 2003, according to the newspaper.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:39:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Washington man leaves $2,000 tip on $93 restaurant bill</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/washington-man-leaves-2000-tip-on-93-restaurant-bill</Link>
        <Description>A Washington man shocked the staff of a neighbourhood restaurant earlier this week by leaving a $2,000 tip for a meal of beer and gumbo he shared with a friend, the proprietor said Wednesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Waitress gets surprise $2,000 tip
WASHINGTON - A Washington man shocked the staff of a neighbourhood restaurant earlier this week by leaving a $2,000 tip for a meal of beer and gumbo he shared with a friend, the proprietor said Wednesday.
The man, described by Blue 44's owner Chris Nardelli as a gumbo-loving regular who lives nearby, left the tip on a $93 bill on Monday night.
"Thank you for the gumbo!" he wrote on the bill after indulging his taste for the Louisiana Creole dish, a specialty of the house.
"It was pretty shocking to say the least," said Nardelli, who also is a chef and bartender at the four-year-old restaurant in the Chevy Chase neighbourhood. "It made everybody do a triple take."
The customer, who was not identified, asked on the bill that $1,000 go to chef James Turner and $500 each for Nardelli and waitress Laura Dally.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:25:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Video shows man knock out senior, rob him of $1 </title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/28/video-shows-man-knock-out-senior-rob-him-of-1</Link>
        <Description>Police in Washington, D.C., are searching for a man who punched an elderly man and robbed him of $1 last week in an attack captured on surveillance video.</Description>
        <MainBody>Video shows man knock out senior, rob him of $1 0
Postmedia Network
Thursday, May 28, 2015       9:25:19 EDT AM
D.C. police released surveillance camera video in an attempt to find a man who punched out and robbed an elderly man of $1 on May 17, 2015. (YouTube)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
Police in Washington, D.C., are searching for a man who punched an elderly man and robbed him of $1 last week in an attack captured on surveillance video.
The video shows a man in a red T-shirt approach a man on the sidewalk before punching him in the face and knocking him out on Sunday at 5:44 p.m.
The police report says the suspect robbed the man of a $1 bill, MyFoxDC reported.
While the man appears to be unconsciousness, the suspect rummages through the man's pockets and walks away while witnesses look on.
The victim suffered a severe cut and bruise, and has since been released from hospital, the station reported.
Man punches out and robs elderly man of $1 in D.C.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
