<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:25:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/france-factory-attack-severed-head-left-near-arabic-banners</Link>
        <Description>A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France - A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.
Speaking from a European Union summit in Brussels, French President Francois Hollande described it at a terrorist attack and said all measures would be taken to stop any future attacks on a country still reeling from Islamist assaults in January.
One suspect had been arrested and was already known to French intelligence sources, Hollande said.
"Two individuals deliberately rammed a car into the gas containers to trigger an explosion," a police source said.
It was not known whether the victim, so far the only known fatality in the incident that also injured two people, was decapitated before or after the car smashed into the building, or whether the victim had been on site at the time of the attack, or killed elsewhere.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," Hollande told the news conference.
ISLAMIST FLAG
Police sources earlier said the decapitated body was found at the site, along with a flag bearing Islamist inscriptions.
Local newspaper Le Dauphine said the head covered in Arabic writing was found on a fence.
The French public prosecutor said its anti-terrorist section had been deployed to investigate.
France, which has deployed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since the Charlie Hebdo killings in January.
Then, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalized by Islamist fighters, Valls said "never has the threat been so high".
The site belonged to Air Products, a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company, according to a spokeswoman for Air Liquide, a French company in the same sector. It was immediately ringfenced by police and emergency services.
The chairman and CEO of Air Products is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a U.S. Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born. Mainly Shi'ite Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State.
No group claimed responsibility for the attack and the motive was unknown.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was at the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30 km (20 miles) southeast of the city of Lyon.
French media said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around sensitive sites in the surrounding Rhone-Alpes region.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:06:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bristol Palin announces she's pregnant for second time, says she doesn't want any lectures</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/bristol-palin-announces-shes-pregnant-for-second-time-says-she-doesnt-want-any-lectures</Link>
        <Description>Bristol Palin, who launched an abstinence campaign after giving birth as an unwed teenage mother, announced Thursday she is pregnant with her second child out-of-wedlock.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bristol Palin booted off Dancing
ANCHORAGE, Alaska -- Bristol Palin, who launched an abstinence campaign after giving birth as an unwed teenage mother, announced Thursday she is pregnant with her second child out-of-wedlock.
The disclosure came a month after her wedding with Medal of Honor winner Dakota Meyer was called off.
Palin, the daughter of 2008 Republican vice-presidential candidate and former Alaska Gov. Sarah Palin, directed Twitter followers and Facebook friends to her blog, where she announced the pregnancy. Her representative, David Martin, and Palin family lawyer John Tiemessen confirmed the blog post.
Martin declined further comment.
"I know this has been, and will be, a huge disappointment to my family, to my close friends, and to many of you," the 24-year-old Palin wrote, before asking for privacy for her and her son Tripp.
"I do not want any lectures and I do not want any sympathy," she said.
Palin was 18 when her mother was selected by U.S. Sen. John McCain to be his running mate in the 2008 presidential election. Shortly after the selection, it was announced that Bristol was pregnant.
Sarah Palin said Bristol and the baby's father, later revealed to be Levi Johnston, would marry, but the couple eventually ended the relationship.
Bristol Palin later became a paid spokeswoman advocating abstinence and warning against teenage pregnancies. She twice performed on "Dancing with the Stars" and had a short-lived cable television show, "Life's a Tripp."
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:58:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family flees home after receiving creepy letters from 'The Watcher'</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/family-flees-home-after-receiving-creepy-letters-from-the-watcher</Link>
        <Description>A couple who says they were scared away from their new $1.4 million home because of creepy letters from a stalker has sued the sellers for not telling them about a person with a "mentally disturbed fixation" on the house.</Description>
        <MainBody>Haunted mansion? It's only US$105,000
ELIZABETH, N.J. -- A couple who says they were scared away from their new $1.4 million home because of creepy letters from a stalker has sued the sellers for not telling them about a person with a "mentally disturbed fixation" on the house.
Derek and Maria Broaddus said the former owners of the home in Westfield, N.J., west of New York City, should have warned them of the person who signs the letters as "The Watcher."
The letter writer claims to have been controlling the house for two decades and that former owners John and Andrea Woods sold it because "it was their time to move on and kindly sold it when I asked them to," according to the lawsuit filed this month.
"Do you need to fill the house with the young blood I requested?" one letter reads, according to the suit. "Once I know their names I will call to them and draw them too (sic) me."
The lawsuit also names an insurance company and settlement company as defendants. Officials from the companies didn't immediately return calls for comment. Contact information for the Woods and their attorneys wasn't immediately available.
The Broadduses says they would never have bought the house if the sellers had warned them about the letter writer. They are now attempting to re-sell the house "as they are unable to live in the home without extreme anxiety and fear for their children's safety and wellbeing," according to the lawsuit.
The suit says they are having a hard time selling because of the letters. They want the former owners to refund them the purchase price and pay punitive damages.
Poll
Would creepy letters cause you to flee your home?
Friday, June 26, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:20:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quiz: Test your news knowledge</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/quiz-test-your-news-knowledge</Link>
        <Description>Test your knowledge of this week's news and current events.</Description>
        <MainBody>Quiz: Test your news knowledge 0
Friday, June 26, 2015       6:20:32 EDT AM
A police helicopter flies past a full moon in this April 27, 2013 file photo. (Chris Procaylo/Postmedia Network Files)
Change text size for the story
Print
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:01:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Plane crashes in Alaska, all nine people on board dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/plane-crashes-in-alaska-condition-of-nine-people-on-board-unknown</Link>
        <Description>An excursion plane carrying eight passengers from a Holland America Line cruise ship crashed on Thursday in southeast Alaska, the company said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Plane crashes in Alaska, all nine people on board dead 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Friday, June 26, 2015       2:01:45 EDT AM
A Holland America Line cruise ship in Alaska. (File photo)
Change text size for the story
Print
ANCHORAGE, Alaska -- All nine people aboard a sightseeing plane died in a crash Thursday in southeast Alaska, authorities said, but stormy weather prevented the immediate recovery of the bodies.
"We have nine fatalities," said Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office.
Rain and wind forced an end to recovery efforts Thursday night in the rugged terrain about 20 miles northeast of Ketchikan. Officials would mount a recovery attempt again on Friday, he said.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop crashed. It was found Thursday against the granite rock face of a cliff, 800 feet above Ella Lake.
Johnson said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down.'
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 800 miles southeast of Anchorage.
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to travelling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 2-million-acre Misty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:41:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. museums increasingly evading restitution of Nazi-looted art: Report</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/us-museums-increasingly-evading-restitution-of-nazi-looted-art-report</Link>
        <Description>U.S. museums are increasingly evading the restitution of Nazi-looted art by using legal tactics to avoid resolving the cases on their merits, according to a report by the World Jewish Restitution Organization released Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. museums increasingly evading restitution of Nazi-looted art: Report 0
Ula Ilnytzky, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       7:41:08 EDT PM
A security guard stands near "Zwei Reiter am Strand mach links (Two Riders on a Beach)" by Max Liebermann at Sotheby's in London, Britain June 19, 2015. The painting was successfully restituted to it's original owner after being seized by the Nazi's in the 1930's, but in the U.S. museums are evading similar restitution. REUTERS/Suzanne Plunkett
Change text size for the story
Print
NEW YORK -- U.S. museums are increasingly evading the restitution of Nazi-looted art by using legal tactics to avoid resolving the cases on their merits, according to a report by the World Jewish Restitution Organization released Thursday.
The tactic is a trend that has grown in recent years, it said.
"American museums have an obligation to ensure that claimants get a fair chance to get a hearing on their case," said Gideon Taylor, chair of WJRO operations. "That increasingly is not happening in U.S. museums."
The technical defence approach by museums also likely is a deterrent to claimants coming forward because they face an expensive and protracted legal struggle, according to the report.
It cites five museum cases in which the courts sided with the institutions, which won their cases resorting to legal technicalities such as statute of limitations. A sixth case involving a disputed Camille Pissarro painting donated to the Fred Jones Jr. Museum of Art at the University of Oklahoma in 2000 is pending.
The Oklahoma museum said the family who donated the artwork to the museum "undisputedly purchased the painting in good faith from a reputable art dealer, with legitimate and verified title."
"We continue to hope for a resolution that will be fair to all parties," it added.
The report also shows that other countries have taken a different approach to settling claims of stolen Nazi-era art, establishing tribunals or special venues where these issues can be heard based on the merits, not on technical grounds.
"We're not saying every claimant is right and that every claim is a valid claim. We're saying let the claim be heard by a neutral body," Taylor said. "If the museums are confident in their interpretation of the facts, then they should be confident to let the court adjudicate whether that's right or not."
Among its recommendations, the report says the American Alliance of Museums should ensure museums comply with its guidelines "by abstaining from blocking claims on technical grounds." Museums that fail to do so should be subject to a review of their accreditation with the AAM, it says. It also recommends legislation to extend statutes of limitations for Holocaust-era restitution claims.
The museum organization said in a statement that it "takes seriously issues surrounding the question of Nazi-era looted art and is committed to ensuring museums act ethically and in accordance with standards."
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:39:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French taxi drivers smash cars, set tires ablaze in nationwide strike against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/nationwide-taxi-strike-in-france-after-rising-sometimes-violent-tensions-over-uber</Link>
        <Description>French taxi drivers pulled out the throttle in an all-out confrontation with the ultra-cheap Uber car service Thursday, smashing livery cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic during a nationwide strike that caught tourists and celebrities alike in the mayhem.</Description>
        <MainBody>French taxi drivers smash cars, set tires ablaze in nationwide strike against Uber 0
Elaine Ganley And Lori Hinnant, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       6:39:01 EDT PM
French riot police stand next to an overturned car as striking French taxi drivers demonstrate at the Porte Maillot to block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, France, June 25, 2015. French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP on Thursday, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities. REUTERS/Charles Platiau
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
PARIS - French taxi drivers pulled out the throttle in an all-out confrontation with the ultra-cheap Uber car service Thursday, smashing livery cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic during a nationwide strike that caught tourists and celebrities alike in the mayhem.
Travellers going to and from the airport were forced to walk alongside highways with their bags, while others, including singer Courtney Love, had their cars set upon by striking taxi drivers.
"They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage," Love tweeted. "They're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad,"
The French government was aghast, with Prime Minister Manuel Valls lamenting: "These incidents give a deplorable image to visitors of our country."
Taxi drivers justified their rage, saying Uber's lowest-cost service UberPop was ruining their livihoods.
Despite repeated rulings against it and an October law that explicitly outlaws UberPop, its drivers continue to ply French roads and the American ride-hailing company is actively recruiting drivers and passengers alike. Uber claims to have a total of 400,000 customers a month in France.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve rushed back from a trip to Marseille to meet with taxi unions, declaring afterward that UberPop must be shut down and its vehicles seized if caught by police carrying passengers. He said 70 vehicles had been damaged around France in Thursday's protests and 10 people were arrested.
Cazeneuve said he would meet with UberPop officials to tell them their service is illegal. "It must, therefore, be closed," he said. "The government will never accept the law of the jungle."
He ordered a meeting of French anti-fraud officials Monday to put in place measures to immediately stop illegal taxis from servicing customers. Only a decision by the Justice Ministry can ban the App for UberPop, he said.
Earlier, Cazeneuve ordered an immediate ban on unlicensed drivers in the Paris region.
That didn't faze Uber France chief Thibaud Simphal, who said on RTL radio he was telling his drivers "to continue." He contended that thus far the justice system "has not demanded that UberPop be forbidden."
Anger seethed across France, with riot police chasing strikers from Paris' ring road, where protesters torched tires and swarmed onto exit ramps during rush hour on the busy artery that leads to Charles de Gaulle airport. In Toulouse in the southwest, angry taxi drivers dumped flour onto UberPop cars, tires were burned in Nantes in the west, and in Lyon, in the southeast, roads were blocked.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, said she was ambushed while travelling from the airport, then saved by two men on a motorcycle. It wasn't immediately clear what type of car she was riding in.
"paid some guys on motorcycles to sneak us out, got chased by a mob of taxi drivers who threw rocks, passed two police and they did nothing," she tweeted.
She later posted a selfie of herself wearing a motorcycle helmet with her two smiling rescuers.
Uber's more expensive livery service is still legal but a source of intense frustration for French taxi drivers, who pay tens of thousands of euros (dollars) for the equivalent of medallions and who face customer complaints that they are being resistant to changes such as credit cards and geolocation.
Taxi drivers in other European countries also complain that car services like Uber unfairly undercut them.
A judge ordered a temporary suspension in Spain, and in the Netherlands a Dutch court has ruled that UberPop must stop service. A world away, in China, the government banned drivers of private cars from offering services through an app.
In France, in recent weeks, nearly 100 Uber drivers have been attacked, sometimes while carrying customers, a scenario repeated on Thursday. One passenger was left with a swollen face and black eye after he took an UberPop ride over the weekend, then posted his mangled face on Facebook, an image that quickly made the rounds on French media.
"There are people who are willing to do anything to stop any competition," said Thomas Meister, a spokesman for Uber. "We are only the symptom of a badly organized market."
The French government, meanwhile, said nearly 500 legal cases had been filed across the country involving complaints over UberPop. Officials raise concerns about passenger safety, insisting they are not protected in case of an accident by an UberPop driver.
Violence peaked in the Paris region, where images from around the city captured the rage, with an Uber-style car overturned, others with tires slashed and windshields cracked.
Fast-moving technological innovations such as smartphone apps have given the French government headaches when it comes to adapting national laws. With the French unemployment rate in the double-digits, many of the jobless are looking for opportunities to work.
Even Interior Ministry officials acknowledge the emergence of Uber and similar services -- which can feature perks such as free bottled water, polite drivers and the chance to pay by credit card -- have created a competitive market that is forcing changes in the taxi industry.
However, Cazeneuve pushed back. "Modernity is not illegal work," he said, denouncing Uber and its leaders "who with arrogance apply not one of the rules of law."
Addressing a leading complaint of taxi drivers -- that authorities are not doing enough to apply the new law -- ministry officials emphasized that it will take time to fully implement.
Serge Metz CEO of the G7 taxi service acknowledged room for improvement, especially in quality of service that taxis offer, but said unfair competition was making drivers' lives impossible.
"This is the first time we've had a multinational so cynical that, in every country where it operates, flouts the laws in place and lobbies with an army of lawyers and lobbyists to change the laws," Serge Metz, CEO of the G7 taxi service, said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:32:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado movie massacre defence seeks to prove gunman's insanity</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/colorado-movie-massacre-defence-seeks-to-prove-gunmans-insanity</Link>
        <Description>Defence lawyers in Colorado's movie massacre trial opened their case on Thursday, calling a psychiatrist as they seek to prove gunman James Holmes was insane and not in control of his actions when he plotted and carried out the 2012 rampage.</Description>
        <MainBody>Colorado gunman outgoing in private: Ex-girlfriend
CENTENNIAL, Colo. - Defense lawyers in Colorado's movie massacre trial opened their case on Thursday, calling a psychiatrist as they seek to prove gunman James Holmes was insane and not in control of his actions when he plotted and carried out the 2012 rampage.
Holmes, a 27-year-old former neuroscience graduate student, opened fire inside a packed midnight premiere of a Batman film at a Denver-area multiplex, killing 12 people and wounding 70.
He could face the death penalty if convicted.
The prosecution wrapped up its case last week after calling more than 200 witnesses, including first responders, survivors, and two court-appointed psychiatrists who both concluded Holmes was sane when he planned and launched the attack.
The defense attorneys' first expert witness, psychiatrist Jonathan Woodcock, said that when he examined Holmes in jail on their behalf four days after the rampage he was startled to hear the defendant tell him he was "bored."
"I found that absolutely extraordinary," Woodcock told jurors, adding he diagnosed Holmes to be severely mentally ill, suffering from psychosis, delusions and "emotional flattening."
Asked by public defender Daniel King whether Holmes had the capacity to tell right from wrong, or to act with intention and after deliberation, Woodcock said that he did not.
During cross-examination, District Attorney George Brauchler repeatedly challenged the psychiatrist's analysis, noting that Woodcock had met with Holmes for fewer than three hours.
"He has potentially a motive to want to tell you things that will help him in that situation, is that fair?" the prosecutor asked him in one of several testy exchanges.
Woodcock agreed that it was.
The defendant, who carried out the murders wearing a gas mask, ballistic helmet and listening to loud techno music through headphones, first hurled a teargas canister into theater nine at the Century 16 cinema in Aurora, an eastern suburb of Denver.
He then opened fire with an automatic rifle, shotgun and pistol. Prosecutors say he did it because he had lost his career, his girlfriend and his purpose in life, and that he had a longstanding "hatred of mankind."
Holmes' public defenders say their client suffers from schizophrenia, that since he was in high school he has heard voices in his head commanding him to kill, and that he was not in control of his actions.
KEY DEFENSE WITNESS
Despite the overwhelming evidence that the California native was solely responsible for the massacre, a conviction and then death sentence is far from certain, said former veteran Denver prosecutor Craig Silverman.
"It only takes one juror to derail this death penalty train," said Silverman, who prosecuted the last defendant in the city to receive a capital punishment sentence.
Under Colorado's death penalty statute, a defendant can be found not guilty by reason of insanity if a person cannot tell right and wrong, or if a mental disease prevents the individual from forming the "culpable mental state."
In a videotaped sanity examination shown to jurors by the prosecution, Holmes indicated that he knew he would go to prison if caught, and that he now "regrets" the shootings.
A key defense witness will be psychiatrist Raquel Gur, director of the Schizophrenia Research Center at the University of Pennsylvania.
Gur, who once examined Unabomber Ted Kaczynski and Tucson mass shooter Jared Loughner, and who was consulted by the White House following the 2012 Sandy Hook Elementary School massacre, interviewed Holmes in the months after the rampage.
Public defenders will likely argue that Gur's diagnosis is more valid than those of the two court-appointed psychiatrists, since she met Holmes sooner after the massacre than they did, and before he was so heavily medicated.
"The defense psychiatrist may also have performed some physiological testing, such as brain imaging, that could bolster their case," Silverman said.
If the jury cannot reach a unanimous verdict in the trial's guilt phase, resulting in a hung jury and mistrial, prosecutors could retry the case.
But if there is a conviction, the defense need to convince just one juror to spare Holmes' life at the sentencing phase, and if that happens "then it's game over," Silverman said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:49:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Winter Olympic city Sochi hit with flooding, one dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/russias-black-sea-resort-of-sochi-hit-with-flooding-1-person-dead</Link>
        <Description>A flood caused by heavy rains has swept Russia's Black Sea resort of Sochi that hosted the 2014 Winter Games, killing one man and causing major damage and disruptions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ex-Winter Olympic city Sochi hit with flooding, one dead 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       4:49:41 EDT PM
A person standing under an umbrella looks at a partially submerged truck on a street flooded after heavy rains in Sochi, Russia, June 25, 2015. REUTERS/Kazbek Basaev
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
MOSCOW -- A flood caused by heavy rains has swept Russia's Black Sea resort of Sochi that hosted the 2014 Winter Games, killing one man and causing major damage and disruptions.
The regional branch of the Russian Interior Ministry said the victim's body was found during salvage works during Thursday's flooding. The man's identity and the circumstances of his death weren't immediately clear.
The torrential rains caused rivers flowing through the city to burst banks and sweep the streets of Sochi, smashing fences and garages. Numerous cars were carried away by streams, and some residents could be seen swimming across streets.
The flooding also cut railway traffic and swept the city's airport, prompting its closure for most of the day Thursday.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:11:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK man guilty in 'revenge' machete attack for British soldier Rigby's murder</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/uk-man-guilty-in-revenge-machete-attack-after-british-soldier-rigbys-murder</Link>
        <Description>A man who attacked a Sikh trainee dentist with a machete in a racist assault intended as revenge for the slaying of a British soldier by Muslim extremists was convicted Thursday of attempted murder.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK man guilty in 'revenge' machete attack for British soldier Rigby's murder 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       3:11:53 EDT PM
(Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LONDON -- A man who attacked a Sikh trainee dentist with a machete in a racist assault intended as revenge for the slaying of a British soldier by Muslim extremists was convicted Thursday of attempted murder.
Zack Davies struck Sarandev Bhambra in the head with a foot-long (30-centimetre) blade in a supermarket in Mold, Wales, in January. Witnesses said they heard Davies shout "white power" and "this is for Lee Rigby."
Rigby was run down with a car and stabbed to death in a London street in May 2013 by two men inspired by Islamic extremism.
A former soldier, Peter Fuller, managed to get between Davies and his victim and stop the attack. Bhambra, 24, suffered what prosecutors called "life-changing" injuries.
Prosecutors said white supremacist material was found at Davies' home. Davies told police he belonged to the neo-Nazi group National Action, and told court he was fascinated and inspired by the masked militant known as Jihadi John, seen in Islamic State group murder videos.
A jury at Mold Crown Court found 26-year-old Davies guilty. He will be sentenced in September after undergoing psychiatric assessment.
Gareth Preston of the Crown Prosecution Service Wales said Davies was "a dangerous young man whose distorted and racist views led him to commit a terrifying act of violence."
Outside court, Bhambra's family criticized police and prosecutors for not classing the attack as terrorism.
"Sarandev was singled out because of the colour of his skin," they said in a statement. "This should have been rightly defined as an act of terrorism."
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:06:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man dies after being gored by bull in Spain</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/man-dies-after-being-gored-by-bull-in-spain</Link>
        <Description>A Spanish man has died after being gored by a bull during a summer festival in a southwestern Spanish town.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ont. rescue farm owner mangled in bull attack
MADRID -- A Spanish man has died after being gored by a bull during a summer festival in a southwestern Spanish town.
Coria town spokeswoman Clara Iglesias said Thursday the man was standing at a protective barrier in the town's bull ring when the bull charged and managed to get a horn between the barrier's vertical tube bars to gore him twice. A video of the goring, which occurred Wednesday evening, was posted on several Spanish news websites.
A town hall statement said the 43-year-old man died later from injuries to the abdomen and chest in Coria's hospital. He was from a neighbouring town.
Fiestas featuring bulls are common in Spain and many people are injured each year.
Spain's most famous bull-running event is in the San Fermin festival in Pamplona in July.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:44:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Outrage after U.S. presidential hopeful says he dislikes being called Indian-American</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/outrage-after-us-presidential-hopeful-says-he-dislikes-being-called-indian-american</Link>
        <Description>NEW DELHI - Louisiana Governor and U.S. presidential candidate Bobby Jindal caused a Twitter storm of jokes and insults in India on Thursday after he said he dislikes being called an Indian-American.</Description>
        <MainBody>Outrage after U.S. presidential hopeful says he dislikes being called Indian-American 0
REUTERS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       9:44:30 EDT AM
Republican presidential candidate and Louisiana Governor Bobby Jindal formally announces his campaign for the 2016 Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, Louisiana June 24, 2015.  REUTERS/Jonathan Bachman
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
NEW DELHI - Louisiana Governor and U.S. presidential candidate Bobby Jindal caused a Twitter storm of jokes and insults in India on Thursday after he said he dislikes being called an Indian-American.
Republican Jindal is the first person of Indian origin to join the U.S. presidential race. During his campaign launch on Wednesday, Jindal said he was "done with" descriptions that identified Americans by their origin, ethnicity or wealth.
"We are not Indian-Americans, African-Americans, Irish-Americans, rich Americans, or poor Americans. We are all Americans," the two-term governor said to loud cheers at the event in a suburb of New Orleans.
The comment, however, was interpreted by some people on Twitter as an attempt to distance himself from India.
The hashtag #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite recorded more than 6,400 tweets and was among India's top trending topics on Thursday.
"#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite teacher used to use him as a chalk on board," said one Twitter user named aindrila. Another user, Yusuf B, said: "#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite that we only see the outline of his body when he stands in front of a white wall."
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite teacher used to use him as a chalk on board
 aindrila (@falana_dimkhana) June 25, 2015
Jindal's office could not be reached out of business hours on Thursday.
Some people also came out in Jindal's support. "Strange, he is being ridiculed for his assertion of his Americanship," Twitter user Rajiv wrote.
Jindal, who converted from Hinduism to Christianity as a teenager, is popular with social conservatives and evangelical Christians.
But he has struggled recently with a fiscal crisis in his state. He frequently ranks near the bottom end of opinion polls of Republicans seeking the party's nomination in the 2016 election.
In January, Jindal made similar remarks and said his parents moved to America to be Americans.
"If we wanted to be Indians, we would have stayed in India," Jindal said.
Tanned? I think that's your heritage struggling to get out, sir! #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite https://t.co/iJgykCWrvp
 Seema Goswami (@seemagoswami) June 25, 2015
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:01:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan morgues run out of space as heat wave kills more than 1,000</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/pakistan-morgues-run-out-of-space-as-heat-wave-kills-more-than-1000</Link>
        <Description>KARACHI - The worst heat wave to hit Pakistan's southern city of Karachi for nearly 35 years has killed more than 1,000 people, a charity said on Thursday, as morgues ran out of space and residents rushed to supply over-stretched public hospitals.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan heat wave kills more than 838
KARACHI - The worst heat wave to hit Pakistan's southern city of Karachi for nearly 35 years has killed more than 1,000 people, a charity said on Thursday, as morgues ran out of space and residents rushed to supply over-stretched public hospitals.
Tents offering iced water and rehydration salts have mushroomed on street corners, run by rival political parties and the military. Residents in one neighbourhood hacked into a main water pipe and then danced delightedly in the spray.
The heat wave in the city of 20 million people coincided with severe electricity cuts, leaving many without fans, water or light, and the beginning of the holy month of Ramadan, when many Muslims do not eat or drink during daylight hours.
Some shops have refused to sell ice or water during the day, citing religious laws that mean they can be fined. It is also illegal to eat or drink in public from dawn to dusk.
Temperatures shot up to 44 degrees Celsius (111 Fahrenheit) at the weekend, the hottest since 1981, although they dipped to 38C (100F) on Thursday. Forecasters have been predicting rain for days, but there has been no significant fall.
An influx of dead means body bags have stacked up on the floor of the morgues, said Anwar Kazmi, a senior official of the charitable organisation the Edhi Foundation.
"The refrigeration unit was not working properly because there were too many bodies," he said.
Kazmi said more than 1,000 people had died of heat-related causes so far. The provincial government had done little except try to blame others, he said.
"We pay tributes to the doctors and staff of the government hospitals who are working tirelessly treating an endless number of patients," he said.
Hospitals called in student doctors to work extra shifts and appealed for basic items like sheets and stretchers. Decades of chronic neglect by successive civilian governments or military regimes have gutted social services like health and education.
Many public hospitals said citizens dropped off carloads of iced water and other supplies. The number of patients was slowly declining as the temperature goes down, doctors said.
Jinnah hospital had an overwhelming response to its appeal for cold water and stretchers, said Dr. Tasneem Butt, and a charity had arranged for rented air conditioners. As she spoke, her phone rang with a call from another donor.
Behind her a motorized rickshaw pulled up, a young woman inside shouting for help her as her father slumped out into the arms of volunteers.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 02:15:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pet store in Mexico closed after video surfaces of employees slapping dogs</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/24/pet-store-in-mexico-closed-after-video-surfaces-of-employees-slapping-dogs</Link>
        <Description>A Mexican pet store has been temporarily closed and two employees are under investigation by prosecutors after a video surfaced of them slapping Chihuahua dogs repeatedly to "welcome" them to the store.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pet store in Mexico closed after video surfaces of employees slapping dogs 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, June 24, 2015       7:15:16 EDT PM
A still from the video in question of pet store employees in Mexico abusing dogs. (YouTube/Screengrab)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
MEXICO CITY -- A Mexican pet store has been temporarily closed and two employees are under investigation by prosecutors after a video surfaced of them slapping Chihuahua dogs repeatedly to "welcome" them to the store.
The Maskota pet store chain said Wednesday that it had identified the two employees from the video and filed criminal complaints against them. It said their behaviour violated the chain's commitment to animal welfare.
In the video, the two take turns holding up Chihuahuas by the scruffs of their necks and repeatedly slapping, shaking and kneeing them.
The prosecutor's office in the north-central state of Hidalgo said it is investigating the incident as a property damage complaint.
It is unclear if Hidalgo has animal protection laws that might carry more serious penalties.
***WARNING: Video contains offensive and disturbing images***
On mobile? Click here to watch the video
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:49:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>240 million-year-old lizard-like reptile considered 'grandfather' of turtles</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/24/scientists-consider-lizard-like-reptile-as-grandfather-of-all-turtles</Link>
        <Description>It looked like an odd lizard with a bulky body and only the skeletal precursor of a shell, but scientists say 240 million-year-old fossils unearthed in a quarry in southern Germany represent the grandfather of all turtles.</Description>
        <MainBody>240 million-year-old lizard-like reptile considered 'grandfather' of turtles 0
Will Dunham, Reuters
Wednesday, June 24, 2015       5:49:59 EDT PM
An artist's reconstruction shows the stem-turtle Pappochelys in this image released to Reuters on June 23, 2015. Scientists on June 24, 2015 announced the discovery of the oldest-known turtle, an 8-inch (20-cm) Triassic Period reptile combining traits of its lizard-like ancestors with a set of emerging turtle-like features. REUTERS/Rainer Schoch/Stuttgart Natural History Museum/Handout
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
WASHINGTON - It looked like an odd lizard with a bulky body and only the skeletal precursor of a shell, but scientists say 240 million-year-old fossils unearthed in a quarry in southern Germany represent the grandfather of all turtles.
The scientists on Wednesday announced the discovery of the oldest-known turtle, an 8-inch (20-cm) Triassic Period reptile combining traits of its lizard-like ancestors with a set of emerging turtle-like features.
They named it Pappochelys, meaning "grandfather turtle," owing to its position at the base of the turtle family tree.
"Pappochelys indeed forms a missing link for two reasons. It is far older than all so far known turtles. And its anatomy is more primitive in many features, showing the ancestral condition of various body regions," said paleontologist Rainer Schoch of Germany's State Museum of Natural History Stuttgart.
It is 20 million years older than the previous earliest-known turtle, Odontochelys from China. While Odontochelys boasted a rudimentary shell on its back, Pappochelys bore only the beginnings of this characteristic turtle trait that evolved in many steps over tens of millions of years.
"The belly armor is composed of thick, rib-like bones that are beginning to fuse to each other in many places," said paleontologist Hans-Dieter Sues of the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History in Washington, calling this "an important stage in the evolution of the turtle shell."
Pappochelys, known from 18 fossil skeletons, had a long tail, broad trunk, and, rather than a beak as in later turtles, a lizard-like skull with numerous peg-like teeth suitable for eating insects and small lizards.
It resided alongside a freshwater lake and may have used its tail for swimming and legs for steering in the water.
Schoch said Pappochelys, as a transitional creature between lizard-like ancestors and later turtles, provides a much clearer picture of turtle evolution.
"Transitional creatures are the most important contribution that paleontology can make to the study of evolution. They are often unexpected and show surprising features," Schoch said. "They show how complicated structures like the skull or turtle shell formed step by step, and also give evidence on the sequence of evolutionary steps."
Pappochelys lived 10 million years before the first dinosaurs, but plenty of danger existed. The lake's largest predator was the 16-foot (5-meter) amphibian Mastodonsaurus. The 20-foot (6-meter) terrestrial croc relative Batrachotomus prowled the land.
The research appears in the journal Nature.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
