<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:21:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosives stolen from army base in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/explosives-stolen-from-army-base-in-france</Link>
        <Description>Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 attacks foiled in France since Hebdo killings
MARSEILLE - Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.
The theft came even though France has heightened security after a suspected Islamist beheaded his boss and tried to blow up a gas plant near Lyon on June 26. Six months earlier, gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish foodstore in January.
The Marseille prosecution office has begun an investigation into the robbery, which was discovered on Monday. France's defence ministry ordered a review of the army's military supplies and the protection of ammunition storage units.
The Miramas site serves as a logistical base for the French army's external operations, the source said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:27:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beach fornicator Jose Caballero gets 2-1/2 years in jail</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/beach-fornicator-jose-caballero-gets-2-12-years-in-jail</Link>
        <Description>A man convicted of having sex on a Florida beach in front of families was sentenced to two-and-a-half years in prison on Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Couple convicted of beach sex face 15 years
BRADENTON, Fla. -- A man convicted of having sex on a Florida beach in front of families was sentenced to two-and-a-half years in prison on Monday.
Jose Caballero, 40, and Elissa Alvarez, 21, were convicted in May of two counts of lewd and lascivious behaviour in a case that drew international attention for the couple's brazen act. They were videotaped having sex on a Manatee County beach last summer in broad daylight. Witnesses testified that a three-year-old girl saw them.
Caballero told jurors that he and Alvarez were not having sex and that witnesses were mistaken. Jurors listened to graphic testimony from witnesses and saw a video of Alvarez moving on top of Caballero in a sexual manner in the middle of the day while others watched.
"We are grateful that the state has offered two-and-a-half years," said Ronald Kurpiers, defence attorney for Caballero.
He said Caballero planned to appeal his case. Alvarez, who was recently sentenced to time served, filed an appeal in her case in June.
Prosecutors say they were tougher on Caballero because he previously served eight years for cocaine trafficking. Both must now register as sex offenders. The Bradenton Herald reports the jury found them guilty after deliberating only 15 minutes. The couple had faced 15 years in prison.
"If you think about 2:30 in the afternoon on a crowded beach. It takes a certain type of person to do that in front of children a few feet away," said Assistant State Attorney Anthony Dafonseca.
Prosecutors said it was important that the community knew what wouldn't be tolerated on public beaches.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:46:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado movie gunman yet to acknowledge his parents at trial</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/colorado-movie-gunman-yet-to-acknowledge-his-parents-at-trial</Link>
        <Description>Colorado theatre shooter James Holmes' parents show up in court every day. But more than two months into his trial, their son has yet to turn around and acknowledge them.</Description>
        <MainBody>Co-worker recalls 'spaced out' Colorado gunman
CENTENNIAL, Colo. -- Colorado theatre shooter James Holmes' parents show up in court every day. But more than two months into his trial, their son has yet to turn around and acknowledge them.
Prosecutors say Holmes held his parents at a distance to conceal his plans for the July 2012 attack that killed 12 and injured 70. Defence attorneys say the fraying family ties show a delusional young man who couldn't bear revealing his struggle.
Holmes' parents have made few public statements since the attack. But Arlene Holmes says in a book she prays for the victims and feels self-guilt.
She and her husband may be called to testify at sentencing if the jury convicts their son, who they say has mental illness.
Just before the trial, Holmes' parents begged for a plea deal that would spare his life.
"We have always loved him, and we do not want him to be executed," they said in a statement in December.
Now, the couple sits two rows behind him in the courtroom. They have heard scores of victims describe the slaughter their son inflicted. They have declined to comment during the trial, and court orders prevent reporters from approaching them.
"We are mourners -- just like everyone else in the courtroom and nothing like anyone else in the courtroom because we are the parents," Arlene wrote in the book of prayers and reflections published earlier this year.
The relationship Arlene and Robert Holmes had with their son had been strained since he was a boy. Holmes has told a psychiatrist that he doesn't like to talk with people, even his mother and father.
Holmes' attorneys have referenced a family history of disorders, including an aunt with schizophrenia and a grandfather who was institutionalized. Holmes' parents and younger sister joined him in family therapy when he was in eighth grade.
Family therapy didn't help because he never opened up for fear of seeming weak, Holmes told a psychiatrist conducting a sanity evaluation two years after the attack.
Holmes abruptly dropped out of school not long before the attack, and his mother got a call from his therapist. Dr. Lynne Fenton asked if it was unusual for their son to seem so emotionless and withdrawn. Arlene Holmes responded that her son had always been socially awkward.
"She was always worried about him and wanted to help him, but she wasn't sure how to do that," Fenton testified.
His parents offered to let him move home. He said he preferred to live off unemployment. "Please let me know how you are doing and if we can help in any way," Robert emailed him later.
By then, Holmes had already assembled an arsenal of weapons. He had researched movie showings and picked the auditorium where he could kill the most people.
Holmes has said he didn't care if he got the death penalty but would probably fight it for his parents' sake.
"They would miss me," he said.
Holmes said his parents regularly send him letters in jail.
"I tell Jim I love him and pray he feels loved," Arlene wrote. "I hope his brain is not too disordered to remember what love feels like."
Holmes' mother also wrote of praying for the victims each night and waking up worrying their son has died behind bars. She mentioned her own feelings of guilt, too.
"I can never forgive myself for not knowing that this would happen," she wrote.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:39:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Maryland military hospital cleared after reports of gunshot</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/police-investigating-report-of-gunshot-at-maryland-military-hospital</Link>
        <Description>Authorities have found no sign of a gunshot on Monday at Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in suburban Washington after a report of a shot triggered a lockdown of the sprawling hospital campus, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Maryland military hospital cleared after reports of gunshot 0
Ian Simpson, Reuters
Monday, July 6, 2015       2:39:21 EDT PM
Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in Bethesda, Maryland. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
WASHINGTON - Authorities have found no sign of a gunshot on Monday at Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in suburban Washington after a report of a shot triggered a lockdown of the sprawling hospital campus, police said.
Officers cleared the 20-story structure where the gunshot was reported and found nothing, Montgomery County police said on Twitter.
Walter Reed UPDATE: Police operations are complete, there is no evidence of a firearm discharge. Normal operations expected to resume soon
 Montgomery Co Police (@mcpnews) July 6, 2015
A call to police reporting the sound of a gunshot triggered the lockdown at the 240-acre (98-hectare) hospital campus in Bethesda, Maryland, and a massive security response.
Captain Paul Stark told reporters, "There is no indication of any kind of a shooting" and no injuries were reported.
Police sniffer dogs will check the site for explosives, he said. Police said patient care at Walter Reed had been suspended for the day.
The U.S. Navy said employees were told to shelter in place as police and security personnel responded to the unconfirmed report of an active shooter.
The Walter Reed report came after an unfounded call of a gunshot at the Washington Navy Yard sparked a heavy police response on Thursday.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:15:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. man charged with posting on FBI website that he planned to kill President Obama</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/us-man-charged-with-posting-on-fbi-website-that-he-planned-to-kill-president-obama</Link>
        <Description>A U.S. man has been charged with posting on an FBI website that he planned to kill President Barack Obama.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. man charged with posting on FBI website that he planned to kill President Obama 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Monday, July 6, 2015       1:15:17 EDT PM
A Massachusetts man who posted his plans to kill U.S. President Barack Obama (pictured) on the FBI's website has been charged and faces up to five years in prison. REUTERS/Yuri Gripas
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BOSTON -- A U.S. man has been charged with posting on an FBI website that he planned to kill President Barack Obama.
Andrew O'Keefe, 28, of the state of Massachusetts, has been charged with a felony count of posting an online threat against the president.
According to court documents, when law enforcement officers tried to interview O'Keefe regarding the May 13 posting, he refused to speak with them outside his home. Authorities say more than 100 weapons were found at his home and in his vehicle, including swords, double-edged knives, hatchets and spears.
O'Keefe is expected to make his initial appearance in court on Monday. He faces a maximum sentence of five years in prison if convicted.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:48:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can a computer be a poet or a DJ?</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/can-a-computer-be-a-poet-or-a-dj</Link>
        <Description>Can an algorithm pass for an author? Can a robot rock the house? A series of contests at Dartmouth College is about to find out.</Description>
        <MainBody>Robot grabs, crushes worker at Volkswagen plant
CONCORD, N.H. -- Can an algorithm pass for an author? Can a robot rock the house? A series of contests at Dartmouth College is about to find out.
Dartmouth is seeking artificial intelligence algorithms that create "human-quality" short stories, sonnets and dance music sets that will be pitted against human-produced literature, poetry and music selections. The judges won't know which is which.
The goal is to determine whether people can distinguish between the two, and whether they might even prefer the computer-generated creativity.
"Historically, often when we have advances in artificial intelligence, people will always say, 'Well, a computer couldn't paint a sunset,' or 'a computer couldn't write a beautiful love sonnet,' but could they? That's the question," said Dan Rockmore, director of the Neukom Institute for Computational Science at Dartmouth .
Rockmore, a mathematics and computer science professor, spun off the idea for the contests from his experience riding a stationary bike. He started thinking about how the music being played during his spin class helped him pedal at the right the pace, and he was surprised when the instructor told him he selected the songs without the help of computer software.
"I left there thinking, 'I wonder if I could write a program that did that, or somebody could?'" he said. "Because that is a creative act -- a good spin instructor is a total artist. It sort of opened my mind to thinking about whether a computer or algorithm could produce something that was indistinguishable from or even perhaps preferred over what the human does."
The competitions are variations of the "Turing Test," named for British computer scientist Alan Turing, who in 1950 proposed an experiment to determine if a computer could have human-like intelligence. The classic Turing test involves intelligent computer programs that can fool a person carrying on a conversation with it, and there have been many competitions over the years, said Manuela Veloso, professor of computer science and robotics at Carnegie Mellon University and past president of the Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.
There also have been many efforts to create computer programs that can generate music or text, she said. The Associated Press, for example, recently began using computer programs to automatically generate business earnings reports and plans to do the same for college sports stories.
What sets the Dartmouth contests apart is the evaluation by judges who will try to determine whether the work was generated by computers or humans and whether people prefer the computer-generated work, Veloso said. She said it will be interesting to see who does the judging -- fooling a publisher with a computer-generated short story would be more significant than fooling the average reader, for example.
The contests, dubbed DigiLit, PoetiX and Algorhythms, will run through the upcoming academic year, with prizes awarded in April. For both writing contests, if a computer-generated story or poem is scored as human by a majority of judges, the creators will win $5,000, and a prize of $3,000 will be awarded to the team that enters the best software. In the music contest, six finalists will compete against human disc jockeys during a dance party, selecting music from a list of 1,000 tracks that will be released just before the competition. The prize again will be $3,000.
Both the human DJs and the computers will be hidden from view of the dance floor, Rockmore said.
"Roughly the way we have it imagined is like a 'Wizard of Oz' scenario -- there's a curtain, and there could be someone behind there or not," he said. "Then people will score it, human or machine."
The contests aren't intended to be dismissive of imagination, Rockmore said. Rather, he views them as another way of investigating the neuroscience of creativity and human taste.
"It's a challenge to produce a moving piece of literature, and I think in challenging yourself to try to do it, it makes you think hard about what moves you about a story, what goes into making a story," he said. "Thinking hard about those questions has a long tradition in the humanities, so it's just another way in which we can bring another lens to that, not in order to replace it but just to honestly consider it."

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:39:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman accused of leaving baby on roadside held on $500,000 bail</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/woman-accused-of-leaving-baby-on-roadside-held-on-500000-bail</Link>
        <Description>A Maryland woman accused of abandoning her six-week-old daughter on a roadside and in a car seat carrier was in custody on $500,000 bail on Monday, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Infant found on side of Maryland road
WASHINGTON - A Maryland woman accused of abandoning her six-week-old daughter on a roadside and in a car seat carrier was in custody on $500,000 bail on Monday, police said.
Sandra McClary, 26, was charged with neglect and reckless endangerment after her baby girl was discovered on a road in Pasadena, an unincorporated area about 20 miles southeast of Baltimore, just before midnight on Saturday, the Anne Arundel County Police said in a statement.
The infant was transported to a local hospital, where she was treated for dehydration, and later put in the custody of social services in good health, police said.
McClary, who lives in Baltimore, identified herself to authorities on Sunday after seeing reports about the abandoned child on social media, police said.
McClary initially said she thought the baby was in her father's care when she was found on the roadway, police said. Detectives later determined that McClary had removed the baby from the car and left her, police said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:33:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Farming by drone</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/farming-by-drone</Link>
        <Description>Agricultural use of drones is about to take off in the U.S. after being grounded for years by the lack of federal guidelines.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wedding photography costs reach new heights
CORDOVA, Md. -- Agricultural use of drones is about to take off in the U.S. after being grounded for years by the lack of federal guidelines.
The small, relatively inexpensive vehicles could replace humans in a variety of ways: transmitting detailed information about crops to combines and sprayers, directing them to problem spots and cutting down on the amount of water and chemicals that a farmer needs to use in those areas.
The Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International, a trade group, says agriculture could account for 80% of all commercial drone use.
The Federal Aviation Administration has approved more than 50 exemptions for farm-related operations since January. Companies with those exemptions say business has grown, helped by quick advances in the technology.
Bret Chilcott of AgEagle, which sells unmanned aerial vehicles and the software to help operate them, says his company took its first orders last year. Now it has a backlog of several hundred orders.
"Last year, users had to land their aircraft and then take the data to the computer," he says. "Now the data appears on your iPad or hand-held device a few minutes after flight."
That data could be pictures, 3D images of plants, thermal readings of crops or animals or other observations. Information that in the past took days to collect, or could not have been collected, can be gathered now in minutes or hours. In some cases, it can be integrated with data collected from other high-tech farm machinery.
"In five years, we won't have to blanket a field with chemicals," Chilcott says.
Still, most farmers cannot legally fly the vehicles yet.
The FAA is working on rules that would allow the drones to be used regularly for business while maintaining certain safety and privacy standards. An FAA proposal would allow flight of the vehicles as long as they weigh less than 55 pounds (24 kilograms), stay within the operator's sight and fly during the daytime, among other restrictions.
Operators would have to pass an FAA test of aeronautical knowledge and a Transportation Security Administration background check.
Pilots of crop dusters and other planes that operate around farms are concerned the rules do not go far enough to ensure safety.
"We can't see them," says Andrew Moore of the National Agricultural Aviation Association. His group advocated for the unmanned vehicles to include tracking systems or lights to help airplanes figure out where they are, but that was not included in the proposal.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:54:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi fighter jet accidentally drops bomb on Baghdad, civilians killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/iraqi-fighter-jet-accidentally-drops-bomb-on-baghdad-civilians-killed</Link>
        <Description>An Iraqi Russian-made fighter jet accidentally dropped a bomb over a Baghdad neighbourhood on Monday, killing at least 12 people on the ground, Iraqi officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraqi fighter jet accidentally drops bomb on Baghdad, civilians killed 0
Sinan Salaheddin, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Monday, July 6, 2015       11:54:35 EDT AM
Image: 1 of 13
Previous Next
A man carries an injured child found in the rubble after an Iraqi Sukhoi jet accidentally dropped a bomb in Ni'iriya district in Baghdad July 6, 2015. The Iraqi plane accidentally dropped the bomb on an eastern Baghdad neighbourhood on Monday, police and residents said, killing at least five people and destroying several houses. The Sukhoi jet had been taking part in an air strike against Islamic State militants, Iraqi television said. One of its bombs failed to detach from the plane during the mission then fell as the plane was returning to base. REUTERS/Stringer
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BAGHDAD -- An Iraqi fighter jet accidentally dropped a bomb over a Baghdad neighbourhood on Monday, killing at least 12 people on the ground, Iraqi officials said.
The plane -- one of several Russian-made Sukhois used by Iraq in the fight against the Islamic State group -- was returning to base when the accident happened.
Military spokesman Brig. Gen. Saad Maan Ibrahim told The Associated Press that a technical failure caused the Sukhoi jet to drop the bomb, which hit a number of houses in the Iraqi capital's eastern neighbourhood of New Baghdad.
Three children and two women were among the 12 killed, a police officer at the scene and a medical official at a nearby hospital said. At least 25 people were wounded, the two officials added.
AP footage showed rescue teams in orange jumpsuits and blue helmets searching through the rubble for victims. At least one victim was seen wrapped with a blanket and being rushed to an ambulance.
Iraq is going through its worst crisis since the 2011 withdrawal of U.S. troops. The Islamic State group controls large swaths of the country's north and west following a blitz last year when the militants captured Iraq's second-largest city of Mosul and the majority of the western Anbar province.
Also Monday, separate attacks in and around Baghdad killed at least seven people.
The deadliest took place in Baghdad's southern suburb of Arab Jabour when a booby-trapped house exploded, killing three members of security forces and wounding nine, a police officer said.
In another attack, two soldiers were killed and five hurt when mortar rounds hit their base in Abu Ghraib, west of Baghdad, the officer said. And two civilians were killed and six wounded in a bomb explosion at an outdoor market in the western Ghazaliyah neighbourhood.
Medical officials confirmed casualty figures. All officials spoke on condition of anonymity as they were not authorized to release information.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fugitive African warlord Joseph Kony is said to be sickly, in retreat from international hunt</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/fugitive-african-warlord-joseph-kony-is-said-to-be-sickly-in-retreat-from-international-hunt</Link>
        <Description>The fugitive leader of the Lord's Resistance Army is sickly and in retreat from an international manhunt that includes U.S. forces, a Ugandan military spokesman said Monday, citing the accounts of recent defectors who are backing up reports that the rebel group is in decline.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fugitive African warlord Joseph Kony is said to be sickly, in retreat from international hunt 0
Rodney Muhumuza, The Associated Press
Monday, July 6, 2015       10:25:57 EDT AM
In this July 31, 2006 file photo, Joseph Kony, leader of the Lord's Resistance Army, speaks during a meeting with a delegation of 160 officials and lawmakers from northern Uganda and representatives of non-governmental organizations in Congo near the Sudan border. (AP Photo/File)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
KAMPALA, Uganda -- The fugitive leader of the Lord's Resistance Army is sickly and in retreat from an international manhunt that includes U.S. forces, a Ugandan military spokesman said Monday, citing the accounts of recent defectors who are backing up reports that the rebel group is in decline.
Joseph Kony is possibly suffering from diabetes, according to defectors who surrendered to Ugandan troops last month in Central African Republic, said Lt. Col. Paddy Ankunda. That account is probably true, he said, because Ugandan intelligence over the years "also indicates that Kony has diabetes."
Kasper Agger, a researcher with the watchdog group Enough Project, said he receives many reports of Kony's failing health but it is impossible to independently verify them. The reports from defectors suggest that the apparently ill Kony "doesn't have the same willingness to fight," he said.
Although many of the defectors said Kony is suffering from diabetes, some also suggested the elusive warlord has AIDS, he said.
Kony is believed to be hiding in Kafia Kingi, a Sudanese-controlled enclave on the border of Central African Republic and South Sudan. Watchdog groups have described Kafia Kingi as a safe haven for Kony because African troops hunting for him do not have access to the territory.
The Lord's Resistance Army, which originated in Uganda in the 1980s as a tribal uprising against the government, became notorious for kidnapping children as fighters and forcing girls to be sex slaves. Kony became infamous across the world in 2012 when the advocacy group Invisible Children released an online video that highlighted his alleged crimes.
The group is reportedly in decline, with many of its fighters surrendering or dying in firefights with African troops across Central Africa.
About 100 U.S. military advisers are helping Ugandan and Congolese troops to hunt down the rebels.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:29:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly shooting suspect in San Francisco says gun fired 'on its own'</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/deadly-shooting-suspect-in-san-francisco-says-gun-fired-on-its-own</Link>
        <Description>A Mexican man arrested in the seemingly random fatal shooting of a woman at a San Francisco pier admitted in a jailhouse interview that he shot her, but said it was an accident.</Description>
        <MainBody>Deadly shooting suspect in San Francisco says gun fired 'on its own' 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Monday, July 6, 2015       9:29:54 EDT AM
Francisco Sanchez is seen in an undated photo released by the San Francisco Police Department. Sanchez has been arrested in connection with the shooting death of Kathryn Steinle, who was shot to death, in an apparent random act, at a San Francisco tourist site on Wednesday. REUTERS/ San Francisco Police Department/Handout
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
SAN FRANCISCO -- A Mexican man arrested in the seemingly random fatal shooting of a woman at a San Francisco pier admitted in a jailhouse interview that he shot her, but said it was an accident.
Francisco Sanchez, 45, told KGO-TV Sunday in a mix of Spanish and English that he found a gun wrapped inside a shirt while he was sitting on a bench at the pier and smoking a cigarette.
"So I picked it up and ... it started to fire on its own," Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
He appeared confused and sometimes spoke incoherently during the interview, and said he has poor vision and was under the influence of sleeping pills at the time of the shooting.
"All I want to say is that in the courts, I want them to give me the punishment I deserve and get it over with as soon as possible," Sanchez said during the roughly 45-minute interview.
Kathryn Steinle, 32, was gunned down while out for an evening stroll at Pier 14 with her father and a family friend on Wednesday. Police said witnesses heard no argument or dispute before the shooting, suggesting it was a random attack.
Witnesses at the popular waterfront attraction snapped photos of Sanchez immediately after the shooting, and the images helped police make the arrest while he was walking on a sidewalk a few blocks away.
The shooting has drawn national attention and criticism of the city's sanctuary ordinance after federal officials revealed that Sanchez has seven felony convictions and was deported five times to his native Mexico.
U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement had turned Sanchez over to authorities in San Francisco on March 26 on an outstanding drug warrant.
The Sheriff's Department released Sanchez on April 15 after the San Francisco district attorney's office declined to prosecute him for what authorities said was a decade-old marijuana possession case.
ICE spokeswoman Virginia Kice said the agency had issued a detainer for Sanchez, requesting notification of his release and that he stays in custody until immigration authorities could pick him up. The detainer was not honoured, she said.
Freya Horne, counsel for the San Francisco Sheriff's Department, said Friday that federal detention requests are not sufficient to hold someone. Under the city's sanctuary ordinance, people in the country illegally aren't handed over to immigration officials unless there's a warrant for their arrest.
Sanchez said he returned to the U.S. after being deported because he found better-paying jobs in the country than in Mexico.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 04:23:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Infant found abandoned on side of Maryland road</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/infant-found-abandoned-on-side-of-maryland-road</Link>
        <Description>An infant was found in a car seat carrier on the side of a Maryland road and a woman has come forward claiming to be the mother, officials said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman accused of abandoning baby held on bail
An infant girl was found in a car seat carrier on the side of a Maryland road and her mother has been charged with child neglect, officials said on Sunday.
Anne Arundel County Police said in a statement that the infant, who is in good condition and in the custody of social services, was found in the Baltimore-area city of Pasadena after someone called to report the baby girl late on July 4th.
Police said the mother, identified by police as 26-year-old Sandra McClary of Baltimore, came forward on Sunday after seeing reports on social media. McClary told police the father was supposed to have the baby and she did not know where the infant was.
Police said detectives later determined that she removed the baby from the car and left her on the side of the road. McClary has been charged with child neglect and reckless endangerment, police said.
The investigation into the case remains ongoing. The baby was treated at a local hospital for dehydration.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 01:08:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 dead, 3 missing after pontoon boat capsizes in Ohio River: Fire dept.</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/3-dead-3-missing-after-pontoon-boat-capsizes-in-ohio-river-fire-dept</Link>
        <Description>Kentucky authorities say two people were killed and three remain missing after the pontoon boat they were riding in hit a barge and capsized in the Ohio River.</Description>
        <MainBody>2 dead, 3 missing after pontoon boat capsizes in Ohio River: Fire dept. 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Sunday, July 5, 2015       6:08:12 EDT PM
In this image taken from video, police officers look on as an overturned pontoon boat is pulled out of the water of the Ohio River Saturday, July 4, 2015, in Louisville, Ky. (Nathan Davis, WHAS-TV via AP)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LOUISVILLE, Ky. -- Two people were killed and three remained missing after the pontoon boat they were riding in hit a barge and capsized in the Ohio River, Kentucky authorities said Sunday.
Louisville Fire Chief Greg Frederick said nine people were aboard the boat and that four were rescued after the accident shortly before 10 p.m. Saturday. He said three of those rescued were children and that they were wearing life jackets.
Frederick said the fatalities include one adult and one child. He said a child is among the missing. It's unclear if they were wearing life jackets.
No identifications have been released.
Frederick said the barge was in a construction site about a mile (1.6 kilometres) upstream from the Clark Memorial Bridge. He said authorities planned to search for survivors until Sunday night, and that the Civil Air Patrol was helping in the search.
Frederick said the current of the river was too strong to use divers, and that it contained a lot of debris.
"There are entire trees ... floating down at a rapid rate of speed," he said. "We just don't think it's safe to put divers in."


Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 23:05:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuke talks good for the brothels</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/iran-nuke-talks-good-for-the-brothels</Link>
        <Description>Anyone who says it's all work and no play for the hordes of diplomats, officials, security agents, analysts and reporters who have descended on Vienna for what should be the finale of almost two years of Iran nuclear talks is dead wrong.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuke talks good for the brothels 0
Fedja Grulovic, Louis Charbonneau and John Irish, REUTERS
Sunday, July 5, 2015       4:05:17 EDT PM
(Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
VIENNA - Anyone who says it's all work and no play for the hordes of diplomats, officials, security agents, analysts and reporters who have descended on Vienna for what should be the finale of almost two years of Iran nuclear talks is dead wrong. As the manager of a local brothel said, when the Iran talks are in town, "business is booming."
He declined to say who were his most frequent customers, but made clear that, as far as he was concerned, the longer the negotiations between Iran and six world powers drag on, the better.
Some journalists are also pleased that this round of talks is in Vienna; when the last ministerial round, in March, was held in Lausanne, in notoriously expensive Switzerland, an Iranian reporter complained that he was having trouble affording short-term companionship.
Brothels are legal in Austria - so much so that last month an Austrian night club announced it was offering customers free sex in a summer-long protest over what its owner described as punitive tax rates.
TOO MUCH 'THIRD MAN'?
Vienna's Palais Coburg hotel, a 19th-century palace, has hosted most rounds of the talks since February 2014, and for all that time rumours have circulated about a network of underground tunnels connecting it to brothels and other establishments.
One Western diplomat said they could be just Iran-talks folklore inspired by Carol Reed's classic 1949 film noir The Third Man, which features a chase scene through Vienna's sewer system.
Some negotiators opt for a different kind of leisure activity anyway. One took a day off from haggling over uranium centrifuges and the legal technicalities of U.N. inspections to cycle 70 km along the Danube River - seemingly undeterred by the bicycle crash that put U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry on crutches in May, the day after a nuclear meeting with Iran's foreign minister in Geneva.
Other diplomats shed their business attire and enjoyed a splash in the public pools.
But their impatience is clear. "These talks have become obsessional," said one. "I'd quite like to do something else now. It's enough to make you go crazy."
Like the food, for instance. Luxury hotel or not, after 10 days of the same lunch buffet, its starts to get repetitive; the Iranian delegation has taken to bringing in main courses from a local Persian restaurant.
ACHTUNG! ICE CREAM
The talks were supposed to finish by June 30 but, days before the deadline, one delegation were already joking in a beer garden in Vienna's Stadtpark about Groundhog Day, the 1993 film about a man who relives the same day over and over again. Sure enough, the talks were extended by another week.
With energy needing to be saved for the long haul, the closest local DIY and garden store rapidly sold out of folding picnic chairs, which have become essential equipment for reporters staking out the talks.
As daytime temperatures have soared towards 40 Celsius (104 Fahrenheit), keeping cool can be difficult.
Many television crews and photographers and a few correspondents are decked out in shorts and t-shirts and, in an attempt to cool the tempers of grumpy reporters, has Austrian Foreign Ministry has been supplying free ice cream.
At least once a day, a ministry employee wheels a cart full of lollies and cones into the media tent, calling out "Achtung, attention please!" to get the journalists with their laptops to clear a space - before the predictable scrum empties the cart of all but a few unpopular varieties.
'YOU'RE AN IDIOT!'
But that's still not enough to get some of the reporters through their day.
"I've run out of words," said a French-language reporter. "I used my last ounce of strength &#127;to do a story this morning. How many different ways can you say 'inched towards a deal'?"
For an Italian journalist in the tent, where temperatures soared above 40 Celsius after the air conditioning broke down, it was all too much.
"You're an idiot!" he screamed down the phone to his editor, "A moron! A moron! A moron!" And then he hung up.
One local reporter suggested to his foreign minister that keeping foreign correspondents cooped up in a stifling tent might be encouraging them to send home the wrong message about Austrian hospitality.
The minister, fresh-faced 28-year-old Sebastian Kurz, took the warning to heart and invited foreign reporters to Sunday brunch at his ministry, rather improbably making peace among nations in the process.
Iranian reporters came along - even though some of them were unable to enjoy the Viennese pastries because they were fasting for the holy month of Ramadan - and quickly found themselves rubbing shoulders with Israeli journalists, abandoning their usual reciprocal frostiness in the rush to get a "selfie" with the minister.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 23:00:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>David Sweat to spend 23 hours a day in cell</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/captured-ny-fugitive-david-sweat-moved-back-to-prison</Link>
        <Description>The surviving escapee from a prison break and three-week manhunt will spend 23 hours a day in a maximum-security cell, much more confined than he and a fellow murder convict were in the prison from which they managed a getaway, officials said Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fugitive to daughter: 'See you on the outside'
ROMULUS, N.Y. -- The surviving escapee from a prison break and three-week manhunt will spend 23 hours a day in a maximum-security cell, much more confined than he and a fellow murder convict were in the prison from which they managed a getaway, officials said Sunday.
David Sweat, who was shot and wounded during his June 28 capture, was taken early Sunday from Albany Medical Center to the infirmary at the Five Points Correctional Facility in the central New York town of Romulus, the state Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said in a news release.
After at least 24 hours in the infirmary for a medical evaluation, he'll be among the up to 150 men held in the prison's Special Housing Unit, where each inmate sleeps, eats, washes and spends nearly all his time in a 105-square-foot (9.75-square- meter) cell with a bed, a writing platform, a toilet, a sink and a shower. The inmates generally are allowed out of their cells to exercise for an hour a day.
Sweat, 35, will be put on suicide watch, the corrections department noted.
Set about 200 miles (320 kilometres) west of Albany amid New York's Finger Lakes, the 1,300-inmate prison opened in 2000.
Five Points Correctional is 155 years newer than the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, from which Sweat and fellow inmate Richard Matt escaped June 6.
Authorities said Matt and Sweat cut through their adjoining cell walls over months, climbed down catwalks to tunnels, got hold of contractors' tools, broke through a brick wall, cut into and out of a steam pipe and cut a chain holding a manhole cover outside the prison to get away. Sweat is serving a life sentence for killing a sheriff's deputy; Matt, 49, was serving 25 years to life after being convicted of kidnapping and dismembering his former boss.
Clinton Correctional is maximum-security, but as residents of the prison's "honour" block and workers in its tailor shop, Matt and Sweat were able to spend considerable time out of their cells.
They got a guard to give them art supplies, tools and access to a catwalk in exchange for favours and paintings, and they shared their escape plans with a female tailor-shop instructor who gave them hacksaw blades and even agreed to be their getaway driver before she backed out, prosecutors said. The guard and instructor have pleaded not guilty to various charges.
The prison's then-superintendent and 11 other staffers were put on leave after the escape. The honour block has been temporarily closed, and new security measures are being enacted.
Matt was shot dead when a U.S. border patrol team caught up with him June 26 in woods near Malone, about 30 miles (50 kilometres) from Clinton Correctional and near the Canadian border. Sweat was captured a few miles away, in Constable, two days later.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
