<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:21:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosives stolen from army base in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/07/explosives-stolen-from-army-base-in-france</Link>
        <Description>Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 attacks foiled in France since Hebdo killings
MARSEILLE - Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.
The theft came even though France has heightened security after a suspected Islamist beheaded his boss and tried to blow up a gas plant near Lyon on June 26. Six months earlier, gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish foodstore in January.
The Marseille prosecution office has begun an investigation into the robbery, which was discovered on Monday. France's defence ministry ordered a review of the army's military supplies and the protection of ammunition storage units.
The Miramas site serves as a logistical base for the French army's external operations, the source said.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:25:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/france-factory-attack-severed-head-left-near-arabic-banners</Link>
        <Description>A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France - A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.
Speaking from a European Union summit in Brussels, French President Francois Hollande described it at a terrorist attack and said all measures would be taken to stop any future attacks on a country still reeling from Islamist assaults in January.
One suspect had been arrested and was already known to French intelligence sources, Hollande said.
"Two individuals deliberately rammed a car into the gas containers to trigger an explosion," a police source said.
It was not known whether the victim, so far the only known fatality in the incident that also injured two people, was decapitated before or after the car smashed into the building, or whether the victim had been on site at the time of the attack, or killed elsewhere.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," Hollande told the news conference.
ISLAMIST FLAG
Police sources earlier said the decapitated body was found at the site, along with a flag bearing Islamist inscriptions.
Local newspaper Le Dauphine said the head covered in Arabic writing was found on a fence.
The French public prosecutor said its anti-terrorist section had been deployed to investigate.
France, which has deployed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since the Charlie Hebdo killings in January.
Then, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalized by Islamist fighters, Valls said "never has the threat been so high".
The site belonged to Air Products, a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company, according to a spokeswoman for Air Liquide, a French company in the same sector. It was immediately ringfenced by police and emergency services.
The chairman and CEO of Air Products is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a U.S. Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born. Mainly Shi'ite Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State.
No group claimed responsibility for the attack and the motive was unknown.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was at the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30 km (20 miles) southeast of the city of Lyon.
French media said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around sensitive sites in the surrounding Rhone-Alpes region.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:08:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; 1 adult killed, others injured</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/28/bus-carrying-british-schoolchildren-crashes-in-belgium-1-adult-killed-others-injured</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS -- A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, killing one adult chaperone and injuring the driver and some of the children, officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; 1 adult killed, others injured 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Sunday, June 28, 2015       10:08:56 EDT AM
Rescuers stand next to a British bus, transporting 34 children and which overturned and crashed on a motorway, near the city of Middelkerke Belgium, June 28, 2015. REUTERS/Dominique Jauquet
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BRUSSELS -- A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, killing one adult chaperone and injuring the driver and some of the children, officials said.
Belgian highway authorities said the vehicle apparently went out of control, struck a bridge pillar on the E40 highway, then shot off the road. The bus was carrying around 40 passengers, including 34 British children from 11 to 13 years old, authorities said.
The Belgian federal prosecutor's office said all of the children survived the accident, but an adult passenger had been killed. The bus driver was also seriously injured.
Three adults and some of the children were sent to a local hospital for treatment. Others were transported to a centre in the coastal city of Middelkerke.
British authorities said they were aware of the crash and working with Belgian authorities to help the U.K. citizens.
The E-40 highway, a major thoroughfare that links Belgium's North Sea coast to the capital city of Brussels, was closed to traffic following the crash.

>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:27:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beach fornicator Jose Caballero gets 2-1/2 years in jail</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/beach-fornicator-jose-caballero-gets-2-12-years-in-jail</Link>
        <Description>A man convicted of having sex on a Florida beach in front of families was sentenced to two-and-a-half years in prison on Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Couple convicted of beach sex face 15 years
BRADENTON, Fla. -- A man convicted of having sex on a Florida beach in front of families was sentenced to two-and-a-half years in prison on Monday.
Jose Caballero, 40, and Elissa Alvarez, 21, were convicted in May of two counts of lewd and lascivious behaviour in a case that drew international attention for the couple's brazen act. They were videotaped having sex on a Manatee County beach last summer in broad daylight. Witnesses testified that a three-year-old girl saw them.
Caballero told jurors that he and Alvarez were not having sex and that witnesses were mistaken. Jurors listened to graphic testimony from witnesses and saw a video of Alvarez moving on top of Caballero in a sexual manner in the middle of the day while others watched.
"We are grateful that the state has offered two-and-a-half years," said Ronald Kurpiers, defence attorney for Caballero.
He said Caballero planned to appeal his case. Alvarez, who was recently sentenced to time served, filed an appeal in her case in June.
Prosecutors say they were tougher on Caballero because he previously served eight years for cocaine trafficking. Both must now register as sex offenders. The Bradenton Herald reports the jury found them guilty after deliberating only 15 minutes. The couple had faced 15 years in prison.
"If you think about 2:30 in the afternoon on a crowded beach. It takes a certain type of person to do that in front of children a few feet away," said Assistant State Attorney Anthony Dafonseca.
Prosecutors said it was important that the community knew what wouldn't be tolerated on public beaches.

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:41:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 400 injured in explosion at Taiwan water park</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/fire-at-taiwan-water-park-injures-more-than-100-people</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI, Taiwan -- A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 400 people, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>British theme park crash victim has leg amputated
TAIPEI, Taiwan -- More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.
The fire late Saturday was sparked by an accidental explosion of a colored theatrical powder thrown from the stage in front of about 1,000 people, the local fire agency and media said. The powder for the one-time event called "Color Play Asia" ignited along the ground, mainly burning people's lower bodies, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command centre.
The exact cause of the fire was still being investigated, but Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo banned public activities that use the colored powder.
A total of 519 people were injured by the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, according to a statement from the city government's health bureau. It said that 419 remained hospitalized on Sunday afternoon, about half of whom were seriously injured, including 184 in intensive care. Apart from Taiwanese, the victims were four people from Hong Kong, two from the Chinese mainland and one each from Macau, Japan, Malaysia and Singapore. The nationalities of three other foreigners were not given.
President Ma Ying-jeou visited burns victims at a hospital in Taipei on Sunday afternoon and said authorities would do their best to ensure victims receive "the best medical care" and find out who was responsible for the "tragic incident."
Taiwan's Central News Agency said that police were questioning two park workers who had launched the powder as well as the party's on-site organizer and two technicians. They may face charges of professional negligence causing serious injuries and endangering the public, it said.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:06:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bristol Palin announces she's pregnant for second time, says she doesn't want any lectures</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/bristol-palin-announces-shes-pregnant-for-second-time-says-she-doesnt-want-any-lectures</Link>
        <Description>Bristol Palin, who launched an abstinence campaign after giving birth as an unwed teenage mother, announced Thursday she is pregnant with her second child out-of-wedlock.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bristol Palin booted off Dancing
ANCHORAGE, Alaska -- Bristol Palin, who launched an abstinence campaign after giving birth as an unwed teenage mother, announced Thursday she is pregnant with her second child out-of-wedlock.
The disclosure came a month after her wedding with Medal of Honor winner Dakota Meyer was called off.
Palin, the daughter of 2008 Republican vice-presidential candidate and former Alaska Gov. Sarah Palin, directed Twitter followers and Facebook friends to her blog, where she announced the pregnancy. Her representative, David Martin, and Palin family lawyer John Tiemessen confirmed the blog post.
Martin declined further comment.
"I know this has been, and will be, a huge disappointment to my family, to my close friends, and to many of you," the 24-year-old Palin wrote, before asking for privacy for her and her son Tripp.
"I do not want any lectures and I do not want any sympathy," she said.
Palin was 18 when her mother was selected by U.S. Sen. John McCain to be his running mate in the 2008 presidential election. Shortly after the selection, it was announced that Bristol was pregnant.
Sarah Palin said Bristol and the baby's father, later revealed to be Levi Johnston, would marry, but the couple eventually ended the relationship.
Bristol Palin later became a paid spokeswoman advocating abstinence and warning against teenage pregnancies. She twice performed on "Dancing with the Stars" and had a short-lived cable television show, "Life's a Tripp."
=======
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:46:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado movie gunman yet to acknowledge his parents at trial</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/colorado-movie-gunman-yet-to-acknowledge-his-parents-at-trial</Link>
        <Description>Colorado theatre shooter James Holmes' parents show up in court every day. But more than two months into his trial, their son has yet to turn around and acknowledge them.</Description>
        <MainBody>Co-worker recalls 'spaced out' Colorado gunman
CENTENNIAL, Colo. -- Colorado theatre shooter James Holmes' parents show up in court every day. But more than two months into his trial, their son has yet to turn around and acknowledge them.
Prosecutors say Holmes held his parents at a distance to conceal his plans for the July 2012 attack that killed 12 and injured 70. Defence attorneys say the fraying family ties show a delusional young man who couldn't bear revealing his struggle.
Holmes' parents have made few public statements since the attack. But Arlene Holmes says in a book she prays for the victims and feels self-guilt.
She and her husband may be called to testify at sentencing if the jury convicts their son, who they say has mental illness.
Just before the trial, Holmes' parents begged for a plea deal that would spare his life.
"We have always loved him, and we do not want him to be executed," they said in a statement in December.
Now, the couple sits two rows behind him in the courtroom. They have heard scores of victims describe the slaughter their son inflicted. They have declined to comment during the trial, and court orders prevent reporters from approaching them.
"We are mourners -- just like everyone else in the courtroom and nothing like anyone else in the courtroom because we are the parents," Arlene wrote in the book of prayers and reflections published earlier this year.
The relationship Arlene and Robert Holmes had with their son had been strained since he was a boy. Holmes has told a psychiatrist that he doesn't like to talk with people, even his mother and father.
Holmes' attorneys have referenced a family history of disorders, including an aunt with schizophrenia and a grandfather who was institutionalized. Holmes' parents and younger sister joined him in family therapy when he was in eighth grade.
Family therapy didn't help because he never opened up for fear of seeming weak, Holmes told a psychiatrist conducting a sanity evaluation two years after the attack.
Holmes abruptly dropped out of school not long before the attack, and his mother got a call from his therapist. Dr. Lynne Fenton asked if it was unusual for their son to seem so emotionless and withdrawn. Arlene Holmes responded that her son had always been socially awkward.
"She was always worried about him and wanted to help him, but she wasn't sure how to do that," Fenton testified.
His parents offered to let him move home. He said he preferred to live off unemployment. "Please let me know how you are doing and if we can help in any way," Robert emailed him later.
By then, Holmes had already assembled an arsenal of weapons. He had researched movie showings and picked the auditorium where he could kill the most people.
Holmes has said he didn't care if he got the death penalty but would probably fight it for his parents' sake.
"They would miss me," he said.
Holmes said his parents regularly send him letters in jail.
"I tell Jim I love him and pray he feels loved," Arlene wrote. "I hope his brain is not too disordered to remember what love feels like."
Holmes' mother also wrote of praying for the victims each night and waking up worrying their son has died behind bars. She mentioned her own feelings of guilt, too.
"I can never forgive myself for not knowing that this would happen," she wrote.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:06:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Privately owned Texas town drops 'Bikinis' name</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/privately-owned-texas-town-drops-bikinis-name</Link>
        <Description>Bikinis, Texas, is no more. The privately owned town has reverted to Bankersmith, the name it had before it was bought by an Austin restaurateur whose chain requires waitresses to wear bikinis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Privately owned Texas town drops 'Bikinis' name 0
The Associated Press
Saturday, June 27, 2015       7:06:03 EDT PM
A waitress at the Texas restaurant Bikinis shows off the 2012 calendar in this photo from the restaurant's Facebook page. (Facebook)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BANKERSMITH, Texas - Bikinis, Texas, is no more. The privately owned town has reverted to Bankersmith, the name it had before it was bought by an Austin restaurateur whose chain requires waitresses to wear bikinis.
Doug Guller bought the ghost town in 2012. The town was intended to become a tourist attraction tied to the restaurant chain.
Since acquiring the property, Guller has built a hall with a bar and sound and light system for weddings and corporate events.
The Austin American-Statesman reports that the name change is meant to appease neighbours, who have complained about rowdiness at events.
Guller says the property can hold about 3,000 people.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:58:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Family flees home after receiving creepy letters from 'The Watcher'</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/family-flees-home-after-receiving-creepy-letters-from-the-watcher</Link>
        <Description>A couple who says they were scared away from their new $1.4 million home because of creepy letters from a stalker has sued the sellers for not telling them about a person with a "mentally disturbed fixation" on the house.</Description>
        <MainBody>Haunted mansion? It's only US$105,000
ELIZABETH, N.J. -- A couple who says they were scared away from their new $1.4 million home because of creepy letters from a stalker has sued the sellers for not telling them about a person with a "mentally disturbed fixation" on the house.
Derek and Maria Broaddus said the former owners of the home in Westfield, N.J., west of New York City, should have warned them of the person who signs the letters as "The Watcher."
The letter writer claims to have been controlling the house for two decades and that former owners John and Andrea Woods sold it because "it was their time to move on and kindly sold it when I asked them to," according to the lawsuit filed this month.
"Do you need to fill the house with the young blood I requested?" one letter reads, according to the suit. "Once I know their names I will call to them and draw them too (sic) me."
The lawsuit also names an insurance company and settlement company as defendants. Officials from the companies didn't immediately return calls for comment. Contact information for the Woods and their attorneys wasn't immediately available.
The Broadduses says they would never have bought the house if the sellers had warned them about the letter writer. They are now attempting to re-sell the house "as they are unable to live in the home without extreme anxiety and fear for their children's safety and wellbeing," according to the lawsuit.
The suit says they are having a hard time selling because of the letters. They want the former owners to refund them the purchase price and pay punitive damages.
Poll
Would creepy letters cause you to flee your home?
Friday, June 26, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 21:39:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Maryland military hospital cleared after reports of gunshot</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/police-investigating-report-of-gunshot-at-maryland-military-hospital</Link>
        <Description>Authorities have found no sign of a gunshot on Monday at Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in suburban Washington after a report of a shot triggered a lockdown of the sprawling hospital campus, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Maryland military hospital cleared after reports of gunshot 0
Ian Simpson, Reuters
Monday, July 6, 2015       2:39:21 EDT PM
Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in Bethesda, Maryland. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:20:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quiz: Test your news knowledge</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/quiz-test-your-news-knowledge</Link>
        <Description>Test your knowledge of this week's news and current events.</Description>
        <MainBody>Quiz: Test your news knowledge 0
Friday, June 26, 2015       6:20:32 EDT AM
A police helicopter flies past a full moon in this April 27, 2013 file photo. (Chris Procaylo/Postmedia Network Files)
Change text size for the story
Print
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:01:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Plane crashes in Alaska, all nine people on board dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/plane-crashes-in-alaska-condition-of-nine-people-on-board-unknown</Link>
        <Description>An excursion plane carrying eight passengers from a Holland America Line cruise ship crashed on Thursday in southeast Alaska, the company said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Plane crashes in Alaska, all nine people on board dead 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Friday, June 26, 2015       2:01:45 EDT AM
A Holland America Line cruise ship in Alaska. (File photo)
Change text size for the story
Print
ANCHORAGE, Alaska -- All nine people aboard a sightseeing plane died in a crash Thursday in southeast Alaska, authorities said, but stormy weather prevented the immediate recovery of the bodies.
"We have nine fatalities," said Clint Johnson, head of the National Transportation Safety Board's Alaska office.
Rain and wind forced an end to recovery efforts Thursday night in the rugged terrain about 20 miles northeast of Ketchikan. Officials would mount a recovery attempt again on Friday, he said.
There was no immediate indication of why the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop crashed. It was found Thursday against the granite rock face of a cliff, 800 feet above Ella Lake.
Johnson said it was too soon to know circumstances of the crash, including whether the plane flew into the cliff.
The NTSB was assembling a high-level team to investigate the crash, including three members from Alaska and at least two people from Washington, D.C.
"The initial rescue crew that went in had a very tough time because of the terrain," Johnson said. "It's a very steep, mountainous area, and weather conditions caused them to stand down.'
Coast Guard Petty Officer Lauren Steenson said the agency received a report around 2:15 p.m. that the plane was overdue. Troopers said an emergency locator transmitter activated in the Misty Fjords National Monument, and a helicopter pilot spotted the downed aircraft above Ella Lake, about 800 miles southeast of Anchorage.
Promech Air, an airline based in Ketchikan, operated the shore excursion sold through Holland America Line, the cruise ship company said in a statement. The eight passengers were guests on the Westerdam, which is on a seven-day cruise that departed Seattle on Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," the statement said. "Holland America Line is extending its full support to travelling companions of the guests involved."
Promech said that the crash happened about 11:20 a.m., and the plane was one of five Otter aircraft in its fleet.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
The Ketchikan Daily News reported the Westerdam had been scheduled to leave the city at 1 p.m., but it remained in port Thursday evening.
The airline's website advertises tours of the 2-million-acre Misty Fjord National Monument in its float planes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.

=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:19:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CNN spots 'ISIS' flag at Pride rally, actually pictures of dildos</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/cnn-spots-isis-flag-at-pride-rally-actually-pictures-of-dildos</Link>
        <Description>A clip of CNN misidentifying an "ISIS" flag, which actually displayed images of sex toys, went viral Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Canoe.com
Saturday, June 27, 2015       4:19:11 EDT PM
CNN misidentified this flag as belonging to the Islamic State. In reality it showed images of sex toys. (YouTube)
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
WASHINGTON - Authorities have found no sign of a gunshot on Monday at Walter Reed National Military Medical Center in suburban Washington after a report of a shot triggered a lockdown of the sprawling hospital campus, police said.
Officers cleared the 20-story structure where the gunshot was reported and found nothing, Montgomery County police said on Twitter.
Walter Reed UPDATE: Police operations are complete, there is no evidence of a firearm discharge. Normal operations expected to resume soon
 Montgomery Co Police (@mcpnews) July 6, 2015
A call to police reporting the sound of a gunshot triggered the lockdown at the 240-acre (98-hectare) hospital campus in Bethesda, Maryland, and a massive security response.
Captain Paul Stark told reporters, "There is no indication of any kind of a shooting" and no injuries were reported.
Police sniffer dogs will check the site for explosives, he said. Police said patient care at Walter Reed had been suspended for the day.
The U.S. Navy said employees were told to shelter in place as police and security personnel responded to the unconfirmed report of an active shooter.
The Walter Reed report came after an unfounded call of a gunshot at the Washington Navy Yard sparked a heavy police response on Thursday.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:15:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. man charged with posting on FBI website that he planned to kill President Obama</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/us-man-charged-with-posting-on-fbi-website-that-he-planned-to-kill-president-obama</Link>
        <Description>A U.S. man has been charged with posting on an FBI website that he planned to kill President Barack Obama.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. man charged with posting on FBI website that he planned to kill President Obama 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Monday, July 6, 2015       1:15:17 EDT PM
A Massachusetts man who posted his plans to kill U.S. President Barack Obama (pictured) on the FBI's website has been charged and faces up to five years in prison. REUTERS/Yuri Gripas
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BOSTON -- A U.S. man has been charged with posting on an FBI website that he planned to kill President Barack Obama.
Andrew O'Keefe, 28, of the state of Massachusetts, has been charged with a felony count of posting an online threat against the president.
According to court documents, when law enforcement officers tried to interview O'Keefe regarding the May 13 posting, he refused to speak with them outside his home. Authorities say more than 100 weapons were found at his home and in his vehicle, including swords, double-edged knives, hatchets and spears.
O'Keefe is expected to make his initial appearance in court on Monday. He faces a maximum sentence of five years in prison if convicted.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:06:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charleston shooting suspect: From troubled kid to racial radicalization</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/charleston-shooting-suspect-from-troubled-kid-to-racial-radicalization</Link>
        <Description>The people who know Dylann Storm Roof -- the people who watched his progression from a sweet child to a disturbed young man -- are struggling with guilt. How could they have missed the signs? Could they have done something to prevent the deaths of nine innocents at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church?</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman climbs flagpole, removes Confederate flag
CHAPIN, S.C. - The people who know Dylann Storm Roof -- the people who watched his progression from a sweet child to a disturbed young man -- are struggling with guilt. How could they have missed the signs? Could they have done something to prevent the deaths of nine innocents at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church?
How did it all happen?
Roof himself offers no answers. He sits in North Charleston's Sheriff Al Cannon Detention Center, charged with the murders.
But talk to his friends and family, and a portrait emerges of a troubled and confused 21-year-old, often drunk and occasionally threatening violence as he alternated between partying with black friends and spouting white power slogans to white friends. Court documents and nearly two dozen interviews show Roof's early childhood was troubled and confused as well, as he grew up in an unstable, broken home amid allegations of marital abuse and infidelity.
He apparently fell under the thrall of racist websites. But how and why are questions that remain unanswered.
As a 4-year-old, "He was so sweet and bright," recalls Patricia Hastings, who was once his step-grandmother.
Seventeen years later, she is among many who are trying to figure out what happened to Dylann Roof.
------
There is little dispute his childhood was difficult.
Franklin Bennett Roof was a 25-year-old carpenter working for a home construction company, when he met 29-year-old Amelia "Amy" Cowles, a recent divorcee, barely 5-feet (1.5-meters) tall with blonde hair to her ankles. He was the son of a prominent Columbia attorney; she was a bartender at the Silver Fox. They married in 1988 and had a daughter, Amber, four months later.
They separated in 1990, and divorced a year later. A few years later they briefly reconciled, but split again before Dylann was born on April 3, 1994.
Four years later, Franklin Roof married Paige Hastings.
In an affidavit filed in her 2009 divorce, Paige said she became a surrogate mother for the children: "I raised his kids from a very young age, took them to all of their activities."
Patricia Hastings said her daughter loved Dylann and Amber "unconditionally as her own." She said Amy Roof would leave them in Paige's care with little notice, even though Paige had her own new baby, their half-sister Morgan.
Paige cut Dylann's hair in the bowl cut he still wears; she took Amber to college orientation because "both parents were unavailable," Paige's friend Leslie McArver wrote in an affidavit.
As he grew, Dylann exhibited obsessive compulsive behaviour, Hastings said. He would obsess over germs, and insisted on having his hair cut in that same style, Hastings said.
Still, he played video games, interacted with the family, attended church and Bible camp.
But things grew stressful at home. Money was a problem so Paige took a part-time job. Franklin Roof was often out of town.
Franklin Roof was verbally abusive, Paige's friend Carol Elliott wrote in an affidavit.
After Paige filed for divorce, Franklin Roof hired a private investigator to shadow her, revealing she was having an affair, according to the court documents.
The divorce was granted in 2009. Hastings recalls that her daughter told her she felt guilty leaving Dylann.
------
Roof began having trouble in school. He failed the ninth grade twice, then dropped out for good in 2010.
People around him worried about his lack of direction. He was spending too much time in his room in front of the computer. They pushed him to get a job, but he was unhappy, his friends said.
Over the past year, Roof became increasingly unhinged.
In February, worried employees at a Columbia shopping mall called the police when Roof, dressed in black, asked them suspicious questions about when stores closed and when they left for the night, according to court records. He was arrested on a misdemeanour charge of possessing the drug Suboxone.
In March, a police officer searched his car and found six empty 40-round magazines for an AR-15 assault rifle, according to a police report. Roof said he was saving up to buy an AR-15, the report said.
In April, he was arrested again on a charge of trespassing at the mall, where he'd been banned.
He had become a recluse. He never responded to an invitation to Amber's wedding -- which had been planned for last weekend but was postponed after the massacre. He also appears to have begun a journey into the world of Internet hate sites, according to the Southern Poverty Law Center, which tracks those sites.
"If you don't have much of a social life in the real world, this is a way for you to interact with other individuals and be affirmed and encouraged," said Keegan Hanks, of the Southern Poverty Law Center.
Roof appeared to be "AryanBlood1488," who began posting on the white supremacist site the Daily Stormer in August, Hanks said. Over several months, "AryanBlood1488" described how he typed "black on white crime" into a Google search, found the Council of Conservative Citizens site and descended into radicalism from there.
Kyle Rogers, a member of the Council of Conservative Citizens who lives in Summerville, South Carolina, denied Roof had any direct dealings with the group.
On Feb. 9, according to Internet records, someone using Roof's name, address and phone number registered a new website. On it, were photos of Roof at a cemetery for Confederate soldiers who died fighting for the pro-slavery, secessionist southern states in the American Civil War, brandishing a gun, burning the American flag and spitting on it. The site also contained a manifesto explaining an indoctrination into radical racism.
On his 21st birthday in April, Roof bought himself a present: a .45-calibre Glock semi-automatic handgun with a high-point laser for accuracy.
------
Paige has remarried; her last name is now Mann. She refused to talk to the AP, as did Franklin and Amy Roof.
Mann had barely seen her former stepson since her nasty divorce. But last month, when she went to pick up her daughter at her ex-husband's house, he was there.
According to Patricia Hastings, recounting recent conversations with her daughter, Roof was quieter than he used to be; he looked distant, lost. He was no longer the sweet blond kid she helped raise for nearly a decade. As she was getting ready to leave, Roof, not one for affection, hugged her tight.
"It was like he was saying goodbye," Hastings said.
The next time Mann saw him, it was on television as the man accused of the killings.
Roof's friend Joseph Meek said he too is replaying, reinterpreting, his memories of Roof over the last months.
"I just wish he would have talked to me. I wish he would have told me what was bothering him. I would have done something. This will stay with me, with all of us," he said.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:48:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Can a computer be a poet or a DJ?</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/can-a-computer-be-a-poet-or-a-dj</Link>
        <Description>Can an algorithm pass for an author? Can a robot rock the house? A series of contests at Dartmouth College is about to find out.</Description>
        <MainBody>Robot grabs, crushes worker at Volkswagen plant
CONCORD, N.H. -- Can an algorithm pass for an author? Can a robot rock the house? A series of contests at Dartmouth College is about to find out.
Dartmouth is seeking artificial intelligence algorithms that create "human-quality" short stories, sonnets and dance music sets that will be pitted against human-produced literature, poetry and music selections. The judges won't know which is which.
The goal is to determine whether people can distinguish between the two, and whether they might even prefer the computer-generated creativity.
"Historically, often when we have advances in artificial intelligence, people will always say, 'Well, a computer couldn't paint a sunset,' or 'a computer couldn't write a beautiful love sonnet,' but could they? That's the question," said Dan Rockmore, director of the Neukom Institute for Computational Science at Dartmouth .
Rockmore, a mathematics and computer science professor, spun off the idea for the contests from his experience riding a stationary bike. He started thinking about how the music being played during his spin class helped him pedal at the right the pace, and he was surprised when the instructor told him he selected the songs without the help of computer software.
"I left there thinking, 'I wonder if I could write a program that did that, or somebody could?'" he said. "Because that is a creative act -- a good spin instructor is a total artist. It sort of opened my mind to thinking about whether a computer or algorithm could produce something that was indistinguishable from or even perhaps preferred over what the human does."
The competitions are variations of the "Turing Test," named for British computer scientist Alan Turing, who in 1950 proposed an experiment to determine if a computer could have human-like intelligence. The classic Turing test involves intelligent computer programs that can fool a person carrying on a conversation with it, and there have been many competitions over the years, said Manuela Veloso, professor of computer science and robotics at Carnegie Mellon University and past president of the Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence.
There also have been many efforts to create computer programs that can generate music or text, she said. The Associated Press, for example, recently began using computer programs to automatically generate business earnings reports and plans to do the same for college sports stories.
What sets the Dartmouth contests apart is the evaluation by judges who will try to determine whether the work was generated by computers or humans and whether people prefer the computer-generated work, Veloso said. She said it will be interesting to see who does the judging -- fooling a publisher with a computer-generated short story would be more significant than fooling the average reader, for example.
The contests, dubbed DigiLit, PoetiX and Algorhythms, will run through the upcoming academic year, with prizes awarded in April. For both writing contests, if a computer-generated story or poem is scored as human by a majority of judges, the creators will win $5,000, and a prize of $3,000 will be awarded to the team that enters the best software. In the music contest, six finalists will compete against human disc jockeys during a dance party, selecting music from a list of 1,000 tracks that will be released just before the competition. The prize again will be $3,000.
Both the human DJs and the computers will be hidden from view of the dance floor, Rockmore said.
"Roughly the way we have it imagined is like a 'Wizard of Oz' scenario -- there's a curtain, and there could be someone behind there or not," he said. "Then people will score it, human or machine."
The contests aren't intended to be dismissive of imagination, Rockmore said. Rather, he views them as another way of investigating the neuroscience of creativity and human taste.
"It's a challenge to produce a moving piece of literature, and I think in challenging yourself to try to do it, it makes you think hard about what moves you about a story, what goes into making a story," he said. "Thinking hard about those questions has a long tradition in the humanities, so it's just another way in which we can bring another lens to that, not in order to replace it but just to honestly consider it."

=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:41:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. museums increasingly evading restitution of Nazi-looted art: Report</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/us-museums-increasingly-evading-restitution-of-nazi-looted-art-report</Link>
        <Description>U.S. museums are increasingly evading the restitution of Nazi-looted art by using legal tactics to avoid resolving the cases on their merits, according to a report by the World Jewish Restitution Organization released Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. museums increasingly evading restitution of Nazi-looted art: Report 0
Ula Ilnytzky, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       7:41:08 EDT PM
A security guard stands near "Zwei Reiter am Strand mach links (Two Riders on a Beach)" by Max Liebermann at Sotheby's in London, Britain June 19, 2015. The painting was successfully restituted to it's original owner after being seized by the Nazi's in the 1930's, but in the U.S. museums are evading similar restitution. REUTERS/Suzanne Plunkett
Change text size for the story
Print
NEW YORK -- U.S. museums are increasingly evading the restitution of Nazi-looted art by using legal tactics to avoid resolving the cases on their merits, according to a report by the World Jewish Restitution Organization released Thursday.
The tactic is a trend that has grown in recent years, it said.
"American museums have an obligation to ensure that claimants get a fair chance to get a hearing on their case," said Gideon Taylor, chair of WJRO operations. "That increasingly is not happening in U.S. museums."
The technical defence approach by museums also likely is a deterrent to claimants coming forward because they face an expensive and protracted legal struggle, according to the report.
It cites five museum cases in which the courts sided with the institutions, which won their cases resorting to legal technicalities such as statute of limitations. A sixth case involving a disputed Camille Pissarro painting donated to the Fred Jones Jr. Museum of Art at the University of Oklahoma in 2000 is pending.
The Oklahoma museum said the family who donated the artwork to the museum "undisputedly purchased the painting in good faith from a reputable art dealer, with legitimate and verified title."
"We continue to hope for a resolution that will be fair to all parties," it added.
The report also shows that other countries have taken a different approach to settling claims of stolen Nazi-era art, establishing tribunals or special venues where these issues can be heard based on the merits, not on technical grounds.
"We're not saying every claimant is right and that every claim is a valid claim. We're saying let the claim be heard by a neutral body," Taylor said. "If the museums are confident in their interpretation of the facts, then they should be confident to let the court adjudicate whether that's right or not."
Among its recommendations, the report says the American Alliance of Museums should ensure museums comply with its guidelines "by abstaining from blocking claims on technical grounds." Museums that fail to do so should be subject to a review of their accreditation with the AAM, it says. It also recommends legislation to extend statutes of limitations for Holocaust-era restitution claims.
The museum organization said in a statement that it "takes seriously issues surrounding the question of Nazi-era looted art and is committed to ensuring museums act ethically and in accordance with standards."
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:56:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ohio man, 73, rides Kings Island roller coaster for 12,000th time</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/ohio-man-73-rides-kings-island-roller-coaster-for-12000th-time</Link>
        <Description>A 73-year-old man has taken his 12,000th ride on his favourite roller coaster at King's Island amusement park in Ohio.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ohio man, 73, rides Kings Island roller coaster for 12,000th time 0
The Associated Press
Saturday, June 27, 2015       2:56:30 EDT PM
A roller-coaster. (Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
MASON, Ohio - A 73-year-old man has taken his 12,000th ride on his favourite roller coaster at Kings Island amusement park in Ohio.
The park says Gary Coleman of Monfort Heights took the milestone ride in the front row of the Diamondback roller coaster on Monday.
The retired minister has made 493 trips to the theme park outside of Cincinnati since 2009, when the 230-foot (70-meter) steel roller coaster opened. It's the tallest and fastest roller coaster at Kings Island and reaches speeds of 80 mph (130 kph).
Coleman says he's loved coasters since childhood. He says he plans to continue increasing his ride count as long as he remains healthy enough to do so.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:39:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman accused of leaving baby on roadside held on $500,000 bail</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/woman-accused-of-leaving-baby-on-roadside-held-on-500000-bail</Link>
        <Description>A Maryland woman accused of abandoning her six-week-old daughter on a roadside and in a car seat carrier was in custody on $500,000 bail on Monday, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Infant found on side of Maryland road
WASHINGTON - A Maryland woman accused of abandoning her six-week-old daughter on a roadside and in a car seat carrier was in custody on $500,000 bail on Monday, police said.
Sandra McClary, 26, was charged with neglect and reckless endangerment after her baby girl was discovered on a road in Pasadena, an unincorporated area about 20 miles southeast of Baltimore, just before midnight on Saturday, the Anne Arundel County Police said in a statement.
The infant was transported to a local hospital, where she was treated for dehydration, and later put in the custody of social services in good health, police said.
McClary, who lives in Baltimore, identified herself to authorities on Sunday after seeing reports about the abandoned child on social media, police said.
McClary initially said she thought the baby was in her father's care when she was found on the roadway, police said. Detectives later determined that McClary had removed the baby from the car and left her, police said.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:39:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French taxi drivers smash cars, set tires ablaze in nationwide strike against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/nationwide-taxi-strike-in-france-after-rising-sometimes-violent-tensions-over-uber</Link>
        <Description>French taxi drivers pulled out the throttle in an all-out confrontation with the ultra-cheap Uber car service Thursday, smashing livery cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic during a nationwide strike that caught tourists and celebrities alike in the mayhem.</Description>
        <MainBody>French taxi drivers smash cars, set tires ablaze in nationwide strike against Uber 0
Elaine Ganley And Lori Hinnant, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       6:39:01 EDT PM
French riot police stand next to an overturned car as striking French taxi drivers demonstrate at the Porte Maillot to block the traffic on the Paris ring road during a national protest against car-sharing service Uber, in Paris, France, June 25, 2015. French taxi drivers stepped up protests against U.S. online cab service UberPOP on Thursday, blocking road access to airports and train stations in Paris and other cities. REUTERS/Charles Platiau
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
PARIS - French taxi drivers pulled out the throttle in an all-out confrontation with the ultra-cheap Uber car service Thursday, smashing livery cars, setting tires ablaze and blocking traffic during a nationwide strike that caught tourists and celebrities alike in the mayhem.
Travellers going to and from the airport were forced to walk alongside highways with their bags, while others, including singer Courtney Love, had their cars set upon by striking taxi drivers.
"They've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage," Love tweeted. "They're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad,"
The French government was aghast, with Prime Minister Manuel Valls lamenting: "These incidents give a deplorable image to visitors of our country."
Taxi drivers justified their rage, saying Uber's lowest-cost service UberPop was ruining their livihoods.
Despite repeated rulings against it and an October law that explicitly outlaws UberPop, its drivers continue to ply French roads and the American ride-hailing company is actively recruiting drivers and passengers alike. Uber claims to have a total of 400,000 customers a month in France.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve rushed back from a trip to Marseille to meet with taxi unions, declaring afterward that UberPop must be shut down and its vehicles seized if caught by police carrying passengers. He said 70 vehicles had been damaged around France in Thursday's protests and 10 people were arrested.
Cazeneuve said he would meet with UberPop officials to tell them their service is illegal. "It must, therefore, be closed," he said. "The government will never accept the law of the jungle."
He ordered a meeting of French anti-fraud officials Monday to put in place measures to immediately stop illegal taxis from servicing customers. Only a decision by the Justice Ministry can ban the App for UberPop, he said.
Earlier, Cazeneuve ordered an immediate ban on unlicensed drivers in the Paris region.
That didn't faze Uber France chief Thibaud Simphal, who said on RTL radio he was telling his drivers "to continue." He contended that thus far the justice system "has not demanded that UberPop be forbidden."
Anger seethed across France, with riot police chasing strikers from Paris' ring road, where protesters torched tires and swarmed onto exit ramps during rush hour on the busy artery that leads to Charles de Gaulle airport. In Toulouse in the southwest, angry taxi drivers dumped flour onto UberPop cars, tires were burned in Nantes in the west, and in Lyon, in the southeast, roads were blocked.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, said she was ambushed while travelling from the airport, then saved by two men on a motorcycle. It wasn't immediately clear what type of car she was riding in.
"paid some guys on motorcycles to sneak us out, got chased by a mob of taxi drivers who threw rocks, passed two police and they did nothing," she tweeted.
She later posted a selfie of herself wearing a motorcycle helmet with her two smiling rescuers.
Uber's more expensive livery service is still legal but a source of intense frustration for French taxi drivers, who pay tens of thousands of euros (dollars) for the equivalent of medallions and who face customer complaints that they are being resistant to changes such as credit cards and geolocation.
Taxi drivers in other European countries also complain that car services like Uber unfairly undercut them.
A judge ordered a temporary suspension in Spain, and in the Netherlands a Dutch court has ruled that UberPop must stop service. A world away, in China, the government banned drivers of private cars from offering services through an app.
In France, in recent weeks, nearly 100 Uber drivers have been attacked, sometimes while carrying customers, a scenario repeated on Thursday. One passenger was left with a swollen face and black eye after he took an UberPop ride over the weekend, then posted his mangled face on Facebook, an image that quickly made the rounds on French media.
"There are people who are willing to do anything to stop any competition," said Thomas Meister, a spokesman for Uber. "We are only the symptom of a badly organized market."
The French government, meanwhile, said nearly 500 legal cases had been filed across the country involving complaints over UberPop. Officials raise concerns about passenger safety, insisting they are not protected in case of an accident by an UberPop driver.
Violence peaked in the Paris region, where images from around the city captured the rage, with an Uber-style car overturned, others with tires slashed and windshields cracked.
Fast-moving technological innovations such as smartphone apps have given the French government headaches when it comes to adapting national laws. With the French unemployment rate in the double-digits, many of the jobless are looking for opportunities to work.
Even Interior Ministry officials acknowledge the emergence of Uber and similar services -- which can feature perks such as free bottled water, polite drivers and the chance to pay by credit card -- have created a competitive market that is forcing changes in the taxi industry.
However, Cazeneuve pushed back. "Modernity is not illegal work," he said, denouncing Uber and its leaders "who with arrogance apply not one of the rules of law."
Addressing a leading complaint of taxi drivers -- that authorities are not doing enough to apply the new law -- ministry officials emphasized that it will take time to fully implement.
Serge Metz CEO of the G7 taxi service acknowledged room for improvement, especially in quality of service that taxis offer, but said unfair competition was making drivers' lives impossible.
"This is the first time we've had a multinational so cynical that, in every country where it operates, flouts the laws in place and lobbies with an army of lawyers and lobbyists to change the laws," Serge Metz, CEO of the G7 taxi service, said.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:31:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devastating heat wave in Pakistan kills 1,233 people, official says</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/devastating-heat-wave-in-pakistan-kills-1233-people-official-says</Link>
        <Description>A devastating weeklong heat wave in Pakistan's southern port city of Karachi killed 1,233 people, an official said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan heat wave kills more than 1,000
ISLAMABAD - A devastating weeklong heat wave in Pakistan's southern port city of Karachi killed 1,233 people, an official said.
Nazar Mohammad Bozdar, operations director at the Provincial Disaster Management Authority, said about 65,000 heatstroke patients were treated by doctors at all of Karachi's hospitals since June 20 when the heat wave struck Sindh province, where Karachi is the provincial capital.
He told The Associated Press that 1,923 patients with heat-related ailments were still being treated.
"The government quickly responded by making arrangements for the treatment of heatstroke patients and the situation has improved now," he said.
Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record coincided with the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, when Pakistan's Muslim majority observed a dawn-to-dusk fast.
The temperatures in Karachi came down to 34 degrees Celsius (93 degrees Fahrenheit) after reaching 45 degrees Celsius (113 degrees Fahrenheit) a week ago amid chronic power outages, which forced many residents to spend nights outdoors.
The heat wave shocked many Pakistanis just weeks after soaring temperatures caused nearly 2,200 deaths in neighbouring India.
Since then, it has raised fears that South Asia could be seeing some of the devastating effects of human-caused climate change.
On Saturday, TV footage showed a charity burying several unidentified bodies of people who died earlier this week because of the heatstroke. Pakistani television stations reported that several unidentified bodies were buried by the Edhi Foundation charity because local morgues were overflowing.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:33:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Farming by drone</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/farming-by-drone</Link>
        <Description>Agricultural use of drones is about to take off in the U.S. after being grounded for years by the lack of federal guidelines.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wedding photography costs reach new heights
CORDOVA, Md. -- Agricultural use of drones is about to take off in the U.S. after being grounded for years by the lack of federal guidelines.
The small, relatively inexpensive vehicles could replace humans in a variety of ways: transmitting detailed information about crops to combines and sprayers, directing them to problem spots and cutting down on the amount of water and chemicals that a farmer needs to use in those areas.
The Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International, a trade group, says agriculture could account for 80% of all commercial drone use.
The Federal Aviation Administration has approved more than 50 exemptions for farm-related operations since January. Companies with those exemptions say business has grown, helped by quick advances in the technology.
Bret Chilcott of AgEagle, which sells unmanned aerial vehicles and the software to help operate them, says his company took its first orders last year. Now it has a backlog of several hundred orders.
"Last year, users had to land their aircraft and then take the data to the computer," he says. "Now the data appears on your iPad or hand-held device a few minutes after flight."
That data could be pictures, 3D images of plants, thermal readings of crops or animals or other observations. Information that in the past took days to collect, or could not have been collected, can be gathered now in minutes or hours. In some cases, it can be integrated with data collected from other high-tech farm machinery.
"In five years, we won't have to blanket a field with chemicals," Chilcott says.
Still, most farmers cannot legally fly the vehicles yet.
The FAA is working on rules that would allow the drones to be used regularly for business while maintaining certain safety and privacy standards. An FAA proposal would allow flight of the vehicles as long as they weigh less than 55 pounds (24 kilograms), stay within the operator's sight and fly during the daytime, among other restrictions.
Operators would have to pass an FAA test of aeronautical knowledge and a Transportation Security Administration background check.
Pilots of crop dusters and other planes that operate around farms are concerned the rules do not go far enough to ensure safety.
"We can't see them," says Andrew Moore of the National Agricultural Aviation Association. His group advocated for the unmanned vehicles to include tracking systems or lights to help airplanes figure out where they are, but that was not included in the proposal.

=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:32:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado movie massacre defence seeks to prove gunman's insanity</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/colorado-movie-massacre-defence-seeks-to-prove-gunmans-insanity</Link>
        <Description>Defence lawyers in Colorado's movie massacre trial opened their case on Thursday, calling a psychiatrist as they seek to prove gunman James Holmes was insane and not in control of his actions when he plotted and carried out the 2012 rampage.</Description>
        <MainBody>Colorado gunman outgoing in private: Ex-girlfriend
CENTENNIAL, Colo. - Defense lawyers in Colorado's movie massacre trial opened their case on Thursday, calling a psychiatrist as they seek to prove gunman James Holmes was insane and not in control of his actions when he plotted and carried out the 2012 rampage.
Holmes, a 27-year-old former neuroscience graduate student, opened fire inside a packed midnight premiere of a Batman film at a Denver-area multiplex, killing 12 people and wounding 70.
He could face the death penalty if convicted.
The prosecution wrapped up its case last week after calling more than 200 witnesses, including first responders, survivors, and two court-appointed psychiatrists who both concluded Holmes was sane when he planned and launched the attack.
The defense attorneys' first expert witness, psychiatrist Jonathan Woodcock, said that when he examined Holmes in jail on their behalf four days after the rampage he was startled to hear the defendant tell him he was "bored."
"I found that absolutely extraordinary," Woodcock told jurors, adding he diagnosed Holmes to be severely mentally ill, suffering from psychosis, delusions and "emotional flattening."
Asked by public defender Daniel King whether Holmes had the capacity to tell right from wrong, or to act with intention and after deliberation, Woodcock said that he did not.
During cross-examination, District Attorney George Brauchler repeatedly challenged the psychiatrist's analysis, noting that Woodcock had met with Holmes for fewer than three hours.
"He has potentially a motive to want to tell you things that will help him in that situation, is that fair?" the prosecutor asked him in one of several testy exchanges.
Woodcock agreed that it was.
The defendant, who carried out the murders wearing a gas mask, ballistic helmet and listening to loud techno music through headphones, first hurled a teargas canister into theater nine at the Century 16 cinema in Aurora, an eastern suburb of Denver.
He then opened fire with an automatic rifle, shotgun and pistol. Prosecutors say he did it because he had lost his career, his girlfriend and his purpose in life, and that he had a longstanding "hatred of mankind."
Holmes' public defenders say their client suffers from schizophrenia, that since he was in high school he has heard voices in his head commanding him to kill, and that he was not in control of his actions.
KEY DEFENSE WITNESS
Despite the overwhelming evidence that the California native was solely responsible for the massacre, a conviction and then death sentence is far from certain, said former veteran Denver prosecutor Craig Silverman.
"It only takes one juror to derail this death penalty train," said Silverman, who prosecuted the last defendant in the city to receive a capital punishment sentence.
Under Colorado's death penalty statute, a defendant can be found not guilty by reason of insanity if a person cannot tell right and wrong, or if a mental disease prevents the individual from forming the "culpable mental state."
In a videotaped sanity examination shown to jurors by the prosecution, Holmes indicated that he knew he would go to prison if caught, and that he now "regrets" the shootings.
A key defense witness will be psychiatrist Raquel Gur, director of the Schizophrenia Research Center at the University of Pennsylvania.
Gur, who once examined Unabomber Ted Kaczynski and Tucson mass shooter Jared Loughner, and who was consulted by the White House following the 2012 Sandy Hook Elementary School massacre, interviewed Holmes in the months after the rampage.
Public defenders will likely argue that Gur's diagnosis is more valid than those of the two court-appointed psychiatrists, since she met Holmes sooner after the massacre than they did, and before he was so heavily medicated.
"The defense psychiatrist may also have performed some physiological testing, such as brain imaging, that could bolster their case," Silverman said.
If the jury cannot reach a unanimous verdict in the trial's guilt phase, resulting in a hung jury and mistrial, prosecutors could retry the case.
But if there is a conviction, the defense need to convince just one juror to spare Holmes' life at the sentencing phase, and if that happens "then it's game over," Silverman said.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:07:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York manhunt for prison escapee heats up after accomplice killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/new-york-manhunt-for-prison-escapee-heats-up-after-accomplice-killed</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of law enforcement officers hunting for a convicted murderer who escaped from a New York state maximum security prison scoured an area of near the Canadian border on Saturday, a day after a fellow escapee was killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>N.Y. fugitive killed by police: Report
MALONE - A manhunt for a convicted murderer who escaped from a New York state maximum security prison focused on a rural area near the Canadian border on Saturday, a day after his fellow escapee was killed.
David Sweat, 35, remained at large three weeks after taking flight from the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, New York. His accomplice on Friday was shot dead by authorities near Malone, New York.
After Richard Matt was killed by U.S. Border Patrol officers, a tight security perimeter was set up in the area,  where Sweat was believed to be holed up.
About 1,200 federal, state and local law enforcement officers, were searching through a 22 square-mile (57 sq km) area along a highway between the towns of Malone and Duane in northern New York, New York State Police said in a statement.
At checkpoints on the zone's perimeter, rifle-carrying officers stopped vehicles. As darkness approached, halogen lights illuminated makeshift checkpoints.
Police in vehicle caravans spent the day passing over roads, as officers with dogs combed the ground and helicopters patrolled overhead.
Franklin County Sheriff Kevin Mulverhill spoke hopefully about finding Sweat, who was sentenced to life without parole in 2003 for killing a New York sheriff's deputy.
"After three weeks, he would have to be fatigued," Mulverhill said. "He's not getting regular meals, not getting good sleep."
Authorities declined to say why they thought Sweat was still in the general area where Matt was killed. Malone is 27 miles (43 km) northwest of the Clinton prison where the convicts were discovered missing on June 6.
Police tracked Matt to the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins.
On Friday, after Matt apparently fired a shot at a passing camping trailer, officers spotted and confronted him outside a cabin, New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico told reporters.
Border Patrol agents warned Matt to drop the shotgun he was holding, and shot and killed him when he failed to comply, police said.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York.
To stage their elaborate prison break, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and slithered through a steam pipe beneath the prison before popping out through a manhole.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them. Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop.
Mitchell, who also was charged in connection with the escape, told investigators the inmates expected her to pick them up outside the prison walls and drive a getaway car.
When she instead checked into a local hospital with a panic attack, the escapees were apparently forced to take off on foot through rugged, mountainous terrain.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:54:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi fighter jet accidentally drops bomb on Baghdad, civilians killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/iraqi-fighter-jet-accidentally-drops-bomb-on-baghdad-civilians-killed</Link>
        <Description>An Iraqi Russian-made fighter jet accidentally dropped a bomb over a Baghdad neighbourhood on Monday, killing at least 12 people on the ground, Iraqi officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraqi fighter jet accidentally drops bomb on Baghdad, civilians killed 0
Sinan Salaheddin, THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Monday, July 6, 2015       11:54:35 EDT AM
Image: 1 of 13
Previous Next
A man carries an injured child found in the rubble after an Iraqi Sukhoi jet accidentally dropped a bomb in Ni'iriya district in Baghdad July 6, 2015. The Iraqi plane accidentally dropped the bomb on an eastern Baghdad neighbourhood on Monday, police and residents said, killing at least five people and destroying several houses. The Sukhoi jet had been taking part in an air strike against Islamic State militants, Iraqi television said. One of its bombs failed to detach from the plane during the mission then fell as the plane was returning to base. REUTERS/Stringer
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BAGHDAD -- An Iraqi fighter jet accidentally dropped a bomb over a Baghdad neighbourhood on Monday, killing at least 12 people on the ground, Iraqi officials said.
The plane -- one of several Russian-made Sukhois used by Iraq in the fight against the Islamic State group -- was returning to base when the accident happened.
Military spokesman Brig. Gen. Saad Maan Ibrahim told The Associated Press that a technical failure caused the Sukhoi jet to drop the bomb, which hit a number of houses in the Iraqi capital's eastern neighbourhood of New Baghdad.
Three children and two women were among the 12 killed, a police officer at the scene and a medical official at a nearby hospital said. At least 25 people were wounded, the two officials added.
AP footage showed rescue teams in orange jumpsuits and blue helmets searching through the rubble for victims. At least one victim was seen wrapped with a blanket and being rushed to an ambulance.
Iraq is going through its worst crisis since the 2011 withdrawal of U.S. troops. The Islamic State group controls large swaths of the country's north and west following a blitz last year when the militants captured Iraq's second-largest city of Mosul and the majority of the western Anbar province.
Also Monday, separate attacks in and around Baghdad killed at least seven people.
The deadliest took place in Baghdad's southern suburb of Arab Jabour when a booby-trapped house exploded, killing three members of security forces and wounding nine, a police officer said.
In another attack, two soldiers were killed and five hurt when mortar rounds hit their base in Abu Ghraib, west of Baghdad, the officer said. And two civilians were killed and six wounded in a bomb explosion at an outdoor market in the western Ghazaliyah neighbourhood.
Medical officials confirmed casualty figures. All officials spoke on condition of anonymity as they were not authorized to release information.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:49:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Winter Olympic city Sochi hit with flooding, one dead</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/russias-black-sea-resort-of-sochi-hit-with-flooding-1-person-dead</Link>
        <Description>A flood caused by heavy rains has swept Russia's Black Sea resort of Sochi that hosted the 2014 Winter Games, killing one man and causing major damage and disruptions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ex-Winter Olympic city Sochi hit with flooding, one dead 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       4:49:41 EDT PM
A person standing under an umbrella looks at a partially submerged truck on a street flooded after heavy rains in Sochi, Russia, June 25, 2015. REUTERS/Kazbek Basaev
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
MOSCOW -- A flood caused by heavy rains has swept Russia's Black Sea resort of Sochi that hosted the 2014 Winter Games, killing one man and causing major damage and disruptions.
The regional branch of the Russian Interior Ministry said the victim's body was found during salvage works during Thursday's flooding. The man's identity and the circumstances of his death weren't immediately clear.
The torrential rains caused rivers flowing through the city to burst banks and sweep the streets of Sochi, smashing fences and garages. Numerous cars were carried away by streams, and some residents could be seen swimming across streets.
The flooding also cut railway traffic and swept the city's airport, prompting its closure for most of the day Thursday.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:25:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman takes down Confederate flag in front of South Carolina statehouse</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/woman-takes-down-confederate-flag-in-front-of-south-carolina-statehouse</Link>
        <Description>An activist climbed a flagpole outside the South Carolina state capitol early on Saturday and took down the Confederate flag, state officials said, a day after U.S. President Barack Obama called the banner a symbol of racial oppression.</Description>
        <MainBody>From troubled kid to racial radicalization
CHARLESTON, S.C. - An activist climbed a flagpole outside the South Carolina state capitol early on Saturday and took down the Confederate flag, state officials said, a day after U.S. President Barack Obama called the banner a symbol of racial oppression.
Two people were arrested and charged with defacing a monument, the South Carolina Department of Public Safety said in a statement. The banner was replaced within an hour, it said.
The department identified them as 30-year-olds Brittany Ann Byuarim Newsome and James Ian Tyson, from North Carolina.
The Civil War-era flag has been a focal point in the United States after the fatal shooting last week of nine African Americans during a Bible study session at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
On mobile? Click here for video of the flag being taken down
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley was applauded on Saturday at the funeral of one of the victims, librarian Cynthia Hurd, when she told mourners, "I am sorry this happened on my watch, but we will make it right."
Haley, who has attended all four of the funerals so far for the victims, on Monday led calls for the flag's removal saying that while it was an important part of South Carolina's past, it "does not represent the future of our great state."
The suspect in the shootings, Dylann Roof, 21, had posed with a Confederate flag in photos posted on a website that also displayed a racist manifesto.
A group of local activists said they organized the removal of the flag, which by law flies at a memorial on the Statehouse grounds honoring soldiers who fought on the side of the pro-slavery Confederacy during the 1860-65 American Civil War.
"We could not sit by and watch the victims of the Charleston Massacre be laid to rest while the inspiration for their deaths continues to fly above their caskets," an activist group organized under the Twitter tag #KeepItDown said in a statement.
At a funeral for the slain Emanuel church pastor in Charleston on Friday, Obama called the banner "a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation".
"For too long we were blind to the pain that the Confederate flag stirred in too many of our citizens," Obama said in his eulogy for Reverend Clementa Pinckney, 41.
The South Carolina Legislature is expected to begin debate next week on removing the flag from the memorial.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:25:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fugitive African warlord Joseph Kony is said to be sickly, in retreat from international hunt</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/fugitive-african-warlord-joseph-kony-is-said-to-be-sickly-in-retreat-from-international-hunt</Link>
        <Description>The fugitive leader of the Lord's Resistance Army is sickly and in retreat from an international manhunt that includes U.S. forces, a Ugandan military spokesman said Monday, citing the accounts of recent defectors who are backing up reports that the rebel group is in decline.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fugitive African warlord Joseph Kony is said to be sickly, in retreat from international hunt 0
Rodney Muhumuza, The Associated Press
Monday, July 6, 2015       10:25:57 EDT AM
In this July 31, 2006 file photo, Joseph Kony, leader of the Lord's Resistance Army, speaks during a meeting with a delegation of 160 officials and lawmakers from northern Uganda and representatives of non-governmental organizations in Congo near the Sudan border. (AP Photo/File)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
KAMPALA, Uganda -- The fugitive leader of the Lord's Resistance Army is sickly and in retreat from an international manhunt that includes U.S. forces, a Ugandan military spokesman said Monday, citing the accounts of recent defectors who are backing up reports that the rebel group is in decline.
Joseph Kony is possibly suffering from diabetes, according to defectors who surrendered to Ugandan troops last month in Central African Republic, said Lt. Col. Paddy Ankunda. That account is probably true, he said, because Ugandan intelligence over the years "also indicates that Kony has diabetes."
Kasper Agger, a researcher with the watchdog group Enough Project, said he receives many reports of Kony's failing health but it is impossible to independently verify them. The reports from defectors suggest that the apparently ill Kony "doesn't have the same willingness to fight," he said.
Although many of the defectors said Kony is suffering from diabetes, some also suggested the elusive warlord has AIDS, he said.
Kony is believed to be hiding in Kafia Kingi, a Sudanese-controlled enclave on the border of Central African Republic and South Sudan. Watchdog groups have described Kafia Kingi as a safe haven for Kony because African troops hunting for him do not have access to the territory.
The Lord's Resistance Army, which originated in Uganda in the 1980s as a tribal uprising against the government, became notorious for kidnapping children as fighters and forcing girls to be sex slaves. Kony became infamous across the world in 2012 when the advocacy group Invisible Children released an online video that highlighted his alleged crimes.
The group is reportedly in decline, with many of its fighters surrendering or dying in firefights with African troops across Central Africa.
About 100 U.S. military advisers are helping Ugandan and Congolese troops to hunt down the rebels.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:11:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK man guilty in 'revenge' machete attack for British soldier Rigby's murder</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/uk-man-guilty-in-revenge-machete-attack-after-british-soldier-rigbys-murder</Link>
        <Description>A man who attacked a Sikh trainee dentist with a machete in a racist assault intended as revenge for the slaying of a British soldier by Muslim extremists was convicted Thursday of attempted murder.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK man guilty in 'revenge' machete attack for British soldier Rigby's murder 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       3:11:53 EDT PM
(Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LONDON -- A man who attacked a Sikh trainee dentist with a machete in a racist assault intended as revenge for the slaying of a British soldier by Muslim extremists was convicted Thursday of attempted murder.
Zack Davies struck Sarandev Bhambra in the head with a foot-long (30-centimetre) blade in a supermarket in Mold, Wales, in January. Witnesses said they heard Davies shout "white power" and "this is for Lee Rigby."
Rigby was run down with a car and stabbed to death in a London street in May 2013 by two men inspired by Islamic extremism.
A former soldier, Peter Fuller, managed to get between Davies and his victim and stop the attack. Bhambra, 24, suffered what prosecutors called "life-changing" injuries.
Prosecutors said white supremacist material was found at Davies' home. Davies told police he belonged to the neo-Nazi group National Action, and told court he was fascinated and inspired by the masked militant known as Jihadi John, seen in Islamic State group murder videos.
A jury at Mold Crown Court found 26-year-old Davies guilty. He will be sentenced in September after undergoing psychiatric assessment.
Gareth Preston of the Crown Prosecution Service Wales said Davies was "a dangerous young man whose distorted and racist views led him to commit a terrifying act of violence."
Outside court, Bhambra's family criticized police and prosecutors for not classing the attack as terrorism.
"Sarandev was singled out because of the colour of his skin," they said in a statement. "This should have been rightly defined as an act of terrorism."
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 07:27:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly gun attack at Tunisian beachside hotel</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/deadly-gun-attack-at-tunisian-beachside-hotel</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 people, including foreign tourists, were killed when at least one gunman opened fire on a Tunisian beachside hotel in the popular resort of Sousse on Friday, an interior ministry spokesman said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in terror attack
SOUSSE, Tunisia - A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a rifle he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people including Britons, Germans and Belgians as they lounged at the beach in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted at the Imperial Marhaba in Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead, witnesses and security officials said.
The bodies of several tourists lay crumbled where they fell in the sand, covered with yellow towels and blankets among the plastic white sunbeds. Blood smeared stone steps leading from the hotel main area.
"This was always a safe place but today was horror," said an Irish tourist who gave only his first name, Anthony. "He started on the beach and went to the lobby, killing in cold blood."
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, on a day in which a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found in France, a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait and at least 145 civilians were reported killed by Islamic State militants in northern Syria.
In a statement on social media, Islamic State claimed responsibility for the Tunisian attack. It had urged its followers to step up assaults during Ramadan.
Twitter accounts that support Islamic State released three photos they said showed the gunman. A man is seen from behind walking down a street and holding an assault rifle, though his identity and the location are unclear.
"Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yihya al-Kairouni, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures," the statement said. It said he had attacked a "bordel" and killed 40 "infidels'.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire left and right at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot.
Prime Minister Habib Essid said his government plans within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control, for inciting violence, and crack down on financing for certain associations, as a countermeasure.
Rafik Chelli, a senior interior ministry official, said the gunman killed was unknown to authorities and not on any watchlist of potential jihadists. A security source named him as Saifeddine Rezgui, a 23-year-old electrical engineering student.
Local radio said police captured a second gunman, but officials did not immediately confirm the arrest or his role in the attack.
"It was just one attacker," said a hotel worker at the site. "He was a young guy dressed in shorts like he was a tourist himself."
'RUN, RUN, RUN!'
It was the worst attack in Tunisia's modern history and the second major massacre this year following the Islamist militant assault on Tunis Bardo museum when gunmen killed 21 foreign visitors.
A health ministry statement said British, German and Belgian nationals were among the 39 dead. The health minister told French radio 36 others were wounded in the shooting.
At least five British citizens were among the dead, Britain's Foreign Minister Philip Hammond said. Ireland's foreign ministry said at least one Irish citizen was killed.
Tunisia, which has been hailed as a model of democratic transition since its 2011 'Arab Spring' uprising, is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world. Its beach resorts and nightclubs on the Mediterranean are popular with foreigners.
Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol.
Irishwoman Elizabeth O'Brien, who was staying at a neighbouring hotel with her two sons, said there was panic on the beach when gunfire erupted.
"I honestly thought it was fireworks and then when I saw people running... I thought, my God, it is shooting," she told Irish radio station RTE. "The waiters and the security on the beach started to say 'Run, run, run!'"
CATASTROPHE
Islamic State made some claim to the Bardo museum attack, but authorities blamed possible splinter fighters from the Okba Ibn Nafaa, a brigade of al Qaeda-affiliated fighters, operating in the Chaambi mountains along the Algerian border.
In Sousse, many tourists were already packing their suitcases into busses and checking out of hotels to leave after the attack.
German tour operator TUI said on Friday it was organising flights for tourists wishing to return from Tunisia and said those who booked Tunisian holidays for this summer could rebook or cancel the trips free of charge.
Sousse, alongside nearby Hammamet and the island of Djerba, is the heartland of Tunisia's most popular beach resorts, drawing visitors from Europe and neighbouring North African countries like Algeria.
Six million tourists, mostly Europeans, visited Tunisia's beaches, desert treks and medina souks last year, providing seven percent of its gross domestic product, most of its foreign currency revenues and more jobs than anything but farming.
"This is a catastrophe for the economy," Tourism Minister Salma Loumi said. "Our losses will be great, but the loss of human life was even greater."
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine el-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful democratic transition bringing free elections and a new constitution seen as a model for the region.
But the country has also struggled with the rise of Islamist movements as ultra-conservative preachers took advantage of the upheaval and young democracy to take over mosques and spread their hardline message.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have left the country to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up jihadist training camps and promised to return to attack their homeland.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 16:29:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly shooting suspect in San Francisco says gun fired 'on its own'</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/06/deadly-shooting-suspect-in-san-francisco-says-gun-fired-on-its-own</Link>
        <Description>A Mexican man arrested in the seemingly random fatal shooting of a woman at a San Francisco pier admitted in a jailhouse interview that he shot her, but said it was an accident.</Description>
        <MainBody>Deadly shooting suspect in San Francisco says gun fired 'on its own' 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Monday, July 6, 2015       9:29:54 EDT AM
Francisco Sanchez is seen in an undated photo released by the San Francisco Police Department. Sanchez has been arrested in connection with the shooting death of Kathryn Steinle, who was shot to death, in an apparent random act, at a San Francisco tourist site on Wednesday. REUTERS/ San Francisco Police Department/Handout
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
SAN FRANCISCO -- A Mexican man arrested in the seemingly random fatal shooting of a woman at a San Francisco pier admitted in a jailhouse interview that he shot her, but said it was an accident.
Francisco Sanchez, 45, told KGO-TV Sunday in a mix of Spanish and English that he found a gun wrapped inside a shirt while he was sitting on a bench at the pier and smoking a cigarette.
"So I picked it up and ... it started to fire on its own," Sanchez said, adding that he heard three shots go off.
He appeared confused and sometimes spoke incoherently during the interview, and said he has poor vision and was under the influence of sleeping pills at the time of the shooting.
"All I want to say is that in the courts, I want them to give me the punishment I deserve and get it over with as soon as possible," Sanchez said during the roughly 45-minute interview.
Kathryn Steinle, 32, was gunned down while out for an evening stroll at Pier 14 with her father and a family friend on Wednesday. Police said witnesses heard no argument or dispute before the shooting, suggesting it was a random attack.
Witnesses at the popular waterfront attraction snapped photos of Sanchez immediately after the shooting, and the images helped police make the arrest while he was walking on a sidewalk a few blocks away.
The shooting has drawn national attention and criticism of the city's sanctuary ordinance after federal officials revealed that Sanchez has seven felony convictions and was deported five times to his native Mexico.
U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement had turned Sanchez over to authorities in San Francisco on March 26 on an outstanding drug warrant.
The Sheriff's Department released Sanchez on April 15 after the San Francisco district attorney's office declined to prosecute him for what authorities said was a decade-old marijuana possession case.
ICE spokeswoman Virginia Kice said the agency had issued a detainer for Sanchez, requesting notification of his release and that he stays in custody until immigration authorities could pick him up. The detainer was not honoured, she said.
Freya Horne, counsel for the San Francisco Sheriff's Department, said Friday that federal detention requests are not sufficient to hold someone. Under the city's sanctuary ordinance, people in the country illegally aren't handed over to immigration officials unless there's a warrant for their arrest.
Sanchez said he returned to the U.S. after being deported because he found better-paying jobs in the country than in Mexico.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:06:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man dies after being gored by bull in Spain</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/man-dies-after-being-gored-by-bull-in-spain</Link>
        <Description>A Spanish man has died after being gored by a bull during a summer festival in a southwestern Spanish town.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ont. rescue farm owner mangled in bull attack
MADRID -- A Spanish man has died after being gored by a bull during a summer festival in a southwestern Spanish town.
Coria town spokeswoman Clara Iglesias said Thursday the man was standing at a protective barrier in the town's bull ring when the bull charged and managed to get a horn between the barrier's vertical tube bars to gore him twice. A video of the goring, which occurred Wednesday evening, was posted on several Spanish news websites.
A town hall statement said the 43-year-old man died later from injuries to the abdomen and chest in Coria's hospital. He was from a neighbouring town.
Fiestas featuring bulls are common in Spain and many people are injured each year.
Spain's most famous bull-running event is in the San Fermin festival in Pamplona in July.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:56:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Supreme Court rules in favour of gay marriage nationwide</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/us-supreme-court-rules-in-favour-of-gay-marriage-nationwide</Link>
        <Description>The Supreme Court ruled on Friday that the U.S. Constitution provides same-sex couples the right to marry in a historic triumph for the American gay rights movement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Raw video: Tory on gay marriage
WASHINGTON - The Supreme Court ruled on Friday that the U.S. Constitution provides same-sex couples the right to marry, handing a historic triumph to the American gay rights movement.
The court ruled 5-4 that the Constitution's guarantees of due process and equal protection under the law mean that states cannot ban same-sex marriages. With the landmark ruling, gay marriage becomes legal in all 50 states.
Immediately after the decision, same-sex couples in many of the states where gay marriage had been banned headed to county clerks' offices for marriage licenses as officials in several states said they would respect the ruling.
President Barack Obama, appearing in the White House Rose Garden, hailed the ruling as a milestone in American justice that arrived "like a thunderbolt."
"This ruling is a victory for America," said Obama, the first sitting president to support gay marriage. "This decision affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts. When all Americans are treated as equal, we are all more free."
As night fell, the White House was lit in rainbow colors - a symbol of gay pride - to mark the high court's decision.
The ruling, the culmination of a long legal fight by gay rights advocates, follows steady gains in public approval in recent years for same-sex marriage. In 2004 Massachusetts became the first state to legalize gay marriage. But the decision may provoke fresh legal fights in some conservative, Republican-governed states.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, writing on behalf of the court, said the hope of gay people intending to marry "is not to be condemned to live in loneliness, excluded from one of civilization's oldest institutions. They ask for equal dignity in the eyes of the law. The Constitution grants them that right."
"Without the recognition, stability and predictability marriage offers, their children suffer the stigma of knowing their families are somehow lesser," Kennedy wrote.
Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, was joined in the majority by the court's four liberal justices.
Appointed by Republican President Ronald Reagan in 1988, Kennedy has now authored all four of the court's major gay rights rulings, with the first in 1996.
The ruling is the Supreme Court's most important expansion of marriage rights in the United States since its landmark 1967 ruling in the case Loving v. Virginia that struck down state laws barring interracial marriages.
At least two states, Louisiana and Mississippi, said they would not immediately issue marriage licenses to same-sex couples while awaiting legal formalities. Supreme Court rulings generally take 25 days to go into effect.
'THREAT TO AMERICAN DEMOCRACY'
In a blistering dissenting opinion, conservative Justice Antonin Scalia said the decision shows the court is a "threat to American democracy." The ruling "says that my ruler and the ruler of 320 million Americans coast-to-coast is a majority of the nine lawyers on the Supreme Court," Scalia added.
Conservative Chief Justice John Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in his 10 years on the court. Roberts said although there are strong policy arguments in same-sex marriage, it was not the court's role to force states to change their marriage laws.
"Five lawyers have closed the debate and enacted their own vision of marriage as a matter of constitutional law," Roberts wrote.
The dissenters raised concerns about the impact of the case on people opposed to same-sex marriage on religious grounds.
While the ruling only affects state laws and religious institutions can still choose whether to marry same-sex couples, Roberts predicted future legal conflicts.
"Hard questions arise when people of faith exercise religion in ways that may be seen to conflict with the new right to same-sex marriage," Roberts said.
There were 13 state bans in place, while another state, Alabama, had contested a court ruling that lifted the ban there.
The ruling is the latest milestone in the gay rights movement. In 2010, Obama signed a law allowing gays to serve openly in the U.S. military. In 2013, the high court ruled unconstitutional a 1996 U.S. law that declared for the purposes of federal benefits marriage was defined as between one man and one woman.
Reaction came swiftly. James Obergefell, the Ohio man who was the lead plaintiff in the case, told a cheering crowd outside the Supreme Court, "Today's ruling from the Supreme Court affirms what millions across this country already know to be true in our hearts - our love is equal, that the four words etched onto the front of the Supreme Court - equal justice under law - apply to us, too."
Obama telephoned Obergefell to offer congratulations.
Hundreds of gay rights supporters celebrated outside the courthouse with whoops and cries of "U-S-A!" and "Love is love" as the decision came down.
In Ann Arbor, Michigan, another of the plaintiffs, April DeBeor, told cheering supporters, "To my beautiful children, we did this for you," referring to her adopted children.
"Love won," added popular comedian and talk show host Ellen DeGeneres, who is gay.
'JUDICIAL TYRANNY'
Conservatives denounced the ruling. Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee called it "an out-of-control act of unconstitutional judicial tyranny."
Wisconsin Republican Governor Scott Walker, who is expected to run for president, called for amending the U.S. Constitution to allow states to again ban same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Governor Greg Abbott said, "Marriage was defined by God. No man can redefine it."
Archbishop Joseph Kurtz of Louisville, Kentucky, president of the U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops, said, "It is profoundly immoral and unjust for the government to declare that two people of the same sex can constitute a marriage."
Opponents say same-sex marriage's legality should be decided by states, not judges. Some opponents argue it is an affront to traditional marriage between a man and a woman and that the Bible condemns homosexuality.
Gay marriage is also gaining acceptance in other Western countries. Last month in Ireland, voters backed same-sex marriage by a landslide in a referendum that marked a dramatic social shift in the traditionally Roman Catholic country.
Ireland followed several Western European countries including Britain, France and Spain in allowing gay marriage, which is also legal in South Africa, Brazil and Canada. But homosexuality remains taboo and often illegal in many parts of Africa and Asia.
The Supreme Court's ruling came in a consolidated case pulling together challenges filed by same-sex couples to gay marriage bans in Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee.
The Obama administration argued on the side of the same-sex marriage advocates.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 04:23:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Infant found abandoned on side of Maryland road</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/infant-found-abandoned-on-side-of-maryland-road</Link>
        <Description>An infant was found in a car seat carrier on the side of a Maryland road and a woman has come forward claiming to be the mother, officials said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman accused of abandoning baby held on bail
An infant girl was found in a car seat carrier on the side of a Maryland road and her mother has been charged with child neglect, officials said on Sunday.
Anne Arundel County Police said in a statement that the infant, who is in good condition and in the custody of social services, was found in the Baltimore-area city of Pasadena after someone called to report the baby girl late on July 4th.
Police said the mother, identified by police as 26-year-old Sandra McClary of Baltimore, came forward on Sunday after seeing reports on social media. McClary told police the father was supposed to have the baby and she did not know where the infant was.
Police said detectives later determined that she removed the baby from the car and left her on the side of the road. McClary has been charged with child neglect and reckless endangerment, police said.
The investigation into the case remains ongoing. The baby was treated at a local hospital for dehydration.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:44:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Outrage after U.S. presidential hopeful says he dislikes being called Indian-American</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/outrage-after-us-presidential-hopeful-says-he-dislikes-being-called-indian-american</Link>
        <Description>NEW DELHI - Louisiana Governor and U.S. presidential candidate Bobby Jindal caused a Twitter storm of jokes and insults in India on Thursday after he said he dislikes being called an Indian-American.</Description>
        <MainBody>Outrage after U.S. presidential hopeful says he dislikes being called Indian-American 0
REUTERS
Thursday, June 25, 2015       9:44:30 EDT AM
Republican presidential candidate and Louisiana Governor Bobby Jindal formally announces his campaign for the 2016 Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, Louisiana June 24, 2015.  REUTERS/Jonathan Bachman
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
NEW DELHI - Louisiana Governor and U.S. presidential candidate Bobby Jindal caused a Twitter storm of jokes and insults in India on Thursday after he said he dislikes being called an Indian-American.
Republican Jindal is the first person of Indian origin to join the U.S. presidential race. During his campaign launch on Wednesday, Jindal said he was "done with" descriptions that identified Americans by their origin, ethnicity or wealth.
"We are not Indian-Americans, African-Americans, Irish-Americans, rich Americans, or poor Americans. We are all Americans," the two-term governor said to loud cheers at the event in a suburb of New Orleans.
The comment, however, was interpreted by some people on Twitter as an attempt to distance himself from India.
The hashtag #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite recorded more than 6,400 tweets and was among India's top trending topics on Thursday.
"#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite teacher used to use him as a chalk on board," said one Twitter user named aindrila. Another user, Yusuf B, said: "#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite that we only see the outline of his body when he stands in front of a white wall."
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite teacher used to use him as a chalk on board
 aindrila (@falana_dimkhana) June 25, 2015
Jindal's office could not be reached out of business hours on Thursday.
Some people also came out in Jindal's support. "Strange, he is being ridiculed for his assertion of his Americanship," Twitter user Rajiv wrote.
Jindal, who converted from Hinduism to Christianity as a teenager, is popular with social conservatives and evangelical Christians.
But he has struggled recently with a fiscal crisis in his state. He frequently ranks near the bottom end of opinion polls of Republicans seeking the party's nomination in the 2016 election.
In January, Jindal made similar remarks and said his parents moved to America to be Americans.
"If we wanted to be Indians, we would have stayed in India," Jindal said.
Tanned? I think that's your heritage struggling to get out, sir! #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite https://t.co/iJgykCWrvp
 Seema Goswami (@seemagoswami) June 25, 2015
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:47:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escaped N.Y. prisoner killed by police: Report</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/escaped-prisoners-heading-for-canada-ny-cops</Link>
        <Description>Richard Matt, one of two prisoners who escaped from a New York state prison three weeks ago, has been shot and killed, The New York Times reported on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>New York offers $100K reward for escaped convicts
MALONE, N.Y. - Law enforcement officers on Friday shot and killed one of two prisoners who broke out of a maximum security prison in New York three weeks ago and were pursuing a second escapee near the Canadian border, authorities said.
Richard Matt, a 49-year-old convicted murderer, was killed by U.S. Border Patrol officers after he was spotted in a wooded area in the town of Malone, the New York State Police said.
Police were still combing the vicinity for Matt's accomplice, David Sweat, a 35-year-old who was imprisoned for killing a sheriff's deputy.
"You never want to see anyone lose their life, but I would remind people that Mr. Matt was an escaped murderer from a state prison," New York Governor Andrew Cuomo said at a news conference. "Mr. Matt killed two people that we know about."
Authorities said they have no evidence to confirm the whereabouts of the second escapee but have no reason to believe he was not with Matt recently and still in the area.
Malone lies 27 miles (43 km) northwest of the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, where the convicts staged their elaborate escape and were discovered missing on June 6. The manhunt has involved as many as 1,100 law enforcement officers.
Dozens of law enforcement vehicles, some of them equipped with floodlights, had converged on the area, signaling the search for Sweat would go on all night if necessary.
Jeff Tough, who lives within the search perimeter across from Lake Titus, said state troopers were lining State Route 30 at regular intervals.
"I feel relieved, to be honest," Malone resident Matt Maguire said while stopped at a roadblock after learning one of the escapees had been killed. "Everybody's been on edge for 20 days."
CABINS BURGLARIZED
Police started focusing the search in the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins, and items believed to have been dropped by Matt were found, said Joseph D'Amico, superintendent of the New York State Police.
Earlier Friday, authorities were alerted to a third break-in near Malone. When officers arrived at that cabin, they confronted Matt in the woods outside, D'Amico said, and warned the convict to drop the shotgun he was holding.
When Matt failed to comply, the Border Patrol agents shot and killed him, even though the escapee fired no shots of his own, the superintendent said. He declined to elaborate.
In making their escape three weeks ago, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and sneaked along the catwalk to a steam pipe, slithered through the pipe and popped out of a manhole outside the prison walls.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them. Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay from his job, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop. She also has been charged in connection with the escape.
Palmer also let the men slip behind their cell walls onto a prison catwalk to hide contraband and alter electrical wiring so they could cook in their cells, according to court documents.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York, and was sentenced to 25 years to life.
Sweat was serving a life sentence after his conviction in the shooting death of a Broome County Sheriff's deputy on July 4, 2002.
Immediately after the escape, the manhunt centered on an area east of Dannemora along the shore of Lake Champlain. Last weekend, the search shifted to New York's Southern Tier along its border with Pennsylvania. Officers were deployed to that area, where Sweat once lived, after a series of unconfirmed sightings of the pair, but the effort proved fruitless.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 01:08:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 dead, 3 missing after pontoon boat capsizes in Ohio River: Fire dept.</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/3-dead-3-missing-after-pontoon-boat-capsizes-in-ohio-river-fire-dept</Link>
        <Description>Kentucky authorities say two people were killed and three remain missing after the pontoon boat they were riding in hit a barge and capsized in the Ohio River.</Description>
        <MainBody>2 dead, 3 missing after pontoon boat capsizes in Ohio River: Fire dept. 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Sunday, July 5, 2015       6:08:12 EDT PM
In this image taken from video, police officers look on as an overturned pontoon boat is pulled out of the water of the Ohio River Saturday, July 4, 2015, in Louisville, Ky. (Nathan Davis, WHAS-TV via AP)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
LOUISVILLE, Ky. -- Two people were killed and three remained missing after the pontoon boat they were riding in hit a barge and capsized in the Ohio River, Kentucky authorities said Sunday.
Louisville Fire Chief Greg Frederick said nine people were aboard the boat and that four were rescued after the accident shortly before 10 p.m. Saturday. He said three of those rescued were children and that they were wearing life jackets.
Frederick said the fatalities include one adult and one child. He said a child is among the missing. It's unclear if they were wearing life jackets.
No identifications have been released.
Frederick said the barge was in a construction site about a mile (1.6 kilometres) upstream from the Clark Memorial Bridge. He said authorities planned to search for survivors until Sunday night, and that the Civil Air Patrol was helping in the search.
Frederick said the current of the river was too strong to use divers, and that it contained a lot of debris.
"There are entire trees ... floating down at a rapid rate of speed," he said. "We just don't think it's safe to put divers in."


=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:01:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistan morgues run out of space as heat wave kills more than 1,000</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/25/pakistan-morgues-run-out-of-space-as-heat-wave-kills-more-than-1000</Link>
        <Description>KARACHI - The worst heat wave to hit Pakistan's southern city of Karachi for nearly 35 years has killed more than 1,000 people, a charity said on Thursday, as morgues ran out of space and residents rushed to supply over-stretched public hospitals.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan heat wave kills more than 838
KARACHI - The worst heat wave to hit Pakistan's southern city of Karachi for nearly 35 years has killed more than 1,000 people, a charity said on Thursday, as morgues ran out of space and residents rushed to supply over-stretched public hospitals.
Tents offering iced water and rehydration salts have mushroomed on street corners, run by rival political parties and the military. Residents in one neighbourhood hacked into a main water pipe and then danced delightedly in the spray.
The heat wave in the city of 20 million people coincided with severe electricity cuts, leaving many without fans, water or light, and the beginning of the holy month of Ramadan, when many Muslims do not eat or drink during daylight hours.
Some shops have refused to sell ice or water during the day, citing religious laws that mean they can be fined. It is also illegal to eat or drink in public from dawn to dusk.
Temperatures shot up to 44 degrees Celsius (111 Fahrenheit) at the weekend, the hottest since 1981, although they dipped to 38C (100F) on Thursday. Forecasters have been predicting rain for days, but there has been no significant fall.
An influx of dead means body bags have stacked up on the floor of the morgues, said Anwar Kazmi, a senior official of the charitable organisation the Edhi Foundation.
"The refrigeration unit was not working properly because there were too many bodies," he said.
Kazmi said more than 1,000 people had died of heat-related causes so far. The provincial government had done little except try to blame others, he said.
"We pay tributes to the doctors and staff of the government hospitals who are working tirelessly treating an endless number of patients," he said.
Hospitals called in student doctors to work extra shifts and appealed for basic items like sheets and stretchers. Decades of chronic neglect by successive civilian governments or military regimes have gutted social services like health and education.
Many public hospitals said citizens dropped off carloads of iced water and other supplies. The number of patients was slowly declining as the temperature goes down, doctors said.
Jinnah hospital had an overwhelming response to its appeal for cold water and stretchers, said Dr. Tasneem Butt, and a charity had arranged for rented air conditioners. As she spoke, her phone rang with a call from another donor.
Behind her a motorized rickshaw pulled up, a young woman inside shouting for help her as her father slumped out into the arms of volunteers.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 02:16:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State suicide bomber kills 25, wounds 202 in Kuwait mosque</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/islamic-state-suicide-bomber-kills-more-than-10-in-kuwait-mosque</Link>
        <Description>KUWAIT - A suicide bomber blew himself up in a packed Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, killing more than ten people, the governor of Kuwait City and a witness said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in terror attack
KUWAIT - A suicide bomber killed 27 people when he blew himself up inside a packed Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, the health ministry and witnesses said, the first attack of its kind in the major oil-exporting state.
The Islamic State militant group claimed responsibility for the attack, which also wounded 227 people according to the interior ministry, in the district of Sawaber in the eastern part of the Kuwaiti capital.
Parliament member Khalil al-Salih, who was at the mosque when the attack occurred, said worshippers were kneeling in prayer when the bomber walked into the Imam al-Sadeq Mosque and detonated his explosives, destroying walls and the ceiling.
"It was obvious from the suicide bomber's body that he was young. He walked into the prayer hall during sujood (kneeling in prayer). He looked ...in his 20s, I saw him with my own eyes," he told Reuters by telephone.
"The explosion was really hard. The ceiling and wall got destroyed," he said, adding that more than 2,000 people from the Shi'ite Ja'afari sect were praying at the mosque.
The mosque preacher was quoted by state news agency KUNA as saying that the attack targeted worshippers at the back of the mosque, towards the end of the Friday prayers.
It was the first suicide bombing at a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait and worst militant attack in the country for many years.
Shi'ites comprise between 15 and 30 percent of the predominantly Sunni Muslim Gulf Arab state, where members of both communities are known to live side by side with little apparent friction.
Security forces quickly sealed off the perimeter of the mosque while rescue workers carried the wounded to hospital.
Kuwait National Petroleum Company (KNPC) spokesman Khaled al-Asousi told Reuters that the company was carrying out "extra monitoring and searches" to boost security around oil facilities after the attack.
Islamic State named the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said in a statement posted on social media that he had targeted a "temple of the rejectionists" -- a term it generally uses to refer to Shi'ites, whom it regards as heretics.
Islamic State had urged its followers on Tuesday to step up attacks during the Ramadan fasting month against Christians, Shi'ites and Sunni Muslims fighting with a U.S.-led coalition against the ultra-hardline jihadist group.
Also on Friday, a gunman killed 37 people including Western tourists at a beach resort in Tunisia, and in France a decapitated body covered in Arabic writing was found after an attacker rammed his car into a gas container, triggering an explosion.
There was no evidence the three attacks were deliberately coordinated. But coming so close together on the same day in three countries on three different continents, they underscored the far-reaching, fast-growing influence of Islamic State, Western politicians said.
BLOOD DONATIONS
The Health Ministry said Kuwait's blood bank had opened additional centres to receive blood donations and it urged citizens with non-urgent medical needs to avoid the emergency units.
Pictures posted on social media and Kuwaiti news websites showed men in traditional white robes smeared with blood outside the mosque. A second photo showed a row of victims wrapped in white body bags and a third the collapsed ceiling of the mosque.
Kuwait declared Saturday a day of mourning.
Emir Sheikh Sabah al-Ahmed al-Sabah, who visited the damaged mosque after the attack, said the bombing violated the sanctity of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan as well as Islamic law forbidding the shedding of the blood of innocents.
"National unity is a protective fence for the security of the nation," Sheikh Sabah said.
Prime Minister Sheikh Jaber al-Mubarak al-Sabah, who visited the wounded at the Emiri Hospital, also condemned the bombing as an attempt to jeopardise Kuwait's national unity.
"This incident targets our internal front, our national unity," Sheikh Jaber told Reuters outside the hospital. "But this is too difficult for them and we are much stronger than that."
Islamic State has recently twice targeted Shi'ite mosques in neighbouring Saudi Arabia and carried out attacks against members of the sect's Zaydi branch in Yemen.
Kuwait recently approved legislation allowing for security cameras to be placed at public places.
Yaqoub Al-Sanea, the minister of justice, religious endowments and Islamic affairs, said that despite Friday's attack, "Kuwait will remain an oasis of security for all groups of Kuwaiti society and all sects. The government is taking many procedures to protect prayers and mosques."
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jul 05 23:05:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuke talks good for the brothels</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/iran-nuke-talks-good-for-the-brothels</Link>
        <Description>Anyone who says it's all work and no play for the hordes of diplomats, officials, security agents, analysts and reporters who have descended on Vienna for what should be the finale of almost two years of Iran nuclear talks is dead wrong.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran nuke talks good for the brothels 0
Fedja Grulovic, Louis Charbonneau and John Irish, REUTERS
Sunday, July 5, 2015       4:05:17 EDT PM
(Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
VIENNA - Anyone who says it's all work and no play for the hordes of diplomats, officials, security agents, analysts and reporters who have descended on Vienna for what should be the finale of almost two years of Iran nuclear talks is dead wrong. As the manager of a local brothel said, when the Iran talks are in town, "business is booming."
He declined to say who were his most frequent customers, but made clear that, as far as he was concerned, the longer the negotiations between Iran and six world powers drag on, the better.
Some journalists are also pleased that this round of talks is in Vienna; when the last ministerial round, in March, was held in Lausanne, in notoriously expensive Switzerland, an Iranian reporter complained that he was having trouble affording short-term companionship.
Brothels are legal in Austria - so much so that last month an Austrian night club announced it was offering customers free sex in a summer-long protest over what its owner described as punitive tax rates.
TOO MUCH 'THIRD MAN'?
Vienna's Palais Coburg hotel, a 19th-century palace, has hosted most rounds of the talks since February 2014, and for all that time rumours have circulated about a network of underground tunnels connecting it to brothels and other establishments.
One Western diplomat said they could be just Iran-talks folklore inspired by Carol Reed's classic 1949 film noir The Third Man, which features a chase scene through Vienna's sewer system.
Some negotiators opt for a different kind of leisure activity anyway. One took a day off from haggling over uranium centrifuges and the legal technicalities of U.N. inspections to cycle 70 km along the Danube River - seemingly undeterred by the bicycle crash that put U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry on crutches in May, the day after a nuclear meeting with Iran's foreign minister in Geneva.
Other diplomats shed their business attire and enjoyed a splash in the public pools.
But their impatience is clear. "These talks have become obsessional," said one. "I'd quite like to do something else now. It's enough to make you go crazy."
Like the food, for instance. Luxury hotel or not, after 10 days of the same lunch buffet, its starts to get repetitive; the Iranian delegation has taken to bringing in main courses from a local Persian restaurant.
ACHTUNG! ICE CREAM
The talks were supposed to finish by June 30 but, days before the deadline, one delegation were already joking in a beer garden in Vienna's Stadtpark about Groundhog Day, the 1993 film about a man who relives the same day over and over again. Sure enough, the talks were extended by another week.
With energy needing to be saved for the long haul, the closest local DIY and garden store rapidly sold out of folding picnic chairs, which have become essential equipment for reporters staking out the talks.
As daytime temperatures have soared towards 40 Celsius (104 Fahrenheit), keeping cool can be difficult.
Many television crews and photographers and a few correspondents are decked out in shorts and t-shirts and, in an attempt to cool the tempers of grumpy reporters, has Austrian Foreign Ministry has been supplying free ice cream.
At least once a day, a ministry employee wheels a cart full of lollies and cones into the media tent, calling out "Achtung, attention please!" to get the journalists with their laptops to clear a space - before the predictable scrum empties the cart of all but a few unpopular varieties.
'YOU'RE AN IDIOT!'
But that's still not enough to get some of the reporters through their day.
"I've run out of words," said a French-language reporter. "I used my last ounce of strength &#127;to do a story this morning. How many different ways can you say 'inched towards a deal'?"
For an Italian journalist in the tent, where temperatures soared above 40 Celsius after the air conditioning broke down, it was all too much.
"You're an idiot!" he screamed down the phone to his editor, "A moron! A moron! A moron!" And then he hung up.
One local reporter suggested to his foreign minister that keeping foreign correspondents cooped up in a stifling tent might be encouraging them to send home the wrong message about Austrian hospitality.
The minister, fresh-faced 28-year-old Sebastian Kurz, took the warning to heart and invited foreign reporters to Sunday brunch at his ministry, rather improbably making peace among nations in the process.
Iranian reporters came along - even though some of them were unable to enjoy the Viennese pastries because they were fasting for the holy month of Ramadan - and quickly found themselves rubbing shoulders with Israeli journalists, abandoning their usual reciprocal frostiness in the rush to get a "selfie" with the minister.

=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 02:15:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pet store in Mexico closed after video surfaces of employees slapping dogs</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/24/pet-store-in-mexico-closed-after-video-surfaces-of-employees-slapping-dogs</Link>
        <Description>A Mexican pet store has been temporarily closed and two employees are under investigation by prosecutors after a video surfaced of them slapping Chihuahua dogs repeatedly to "welcome" them to the store.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pet store in Mexico closed after video surfaces of employees slapping dogs 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Wednesday, June 24, 2015       7:15:16 EDT PM
A still from the video in question of pet store employees in Mexico abusing dogs. (YouTube/Screengrab)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
MEXICO CITY -- A Mexican pet store has been temporarily closed and two employees are under investigation by prosecutors after a video surfaced of them slapping Chihuahua dogs repeatedly to "welcome" them to the store.
The Maskota pet store chain said Wednesday that it had identified the two employees from the video and filed criminal complaints against them. It said their behaviour violated the chain's commitment to animal welfare.
In the video, the two take turns holding up Chihuahuas by the scruffs of their necks and repeatedly slapping, shaking and kneeing them.
The prosecutor's office in the north-central state of Hidalgo said it is investigating the incident as a property damage complaint.
It is unclear if Hidalgo has animal protection laws that might carry more serious penalties.
***WARNING: Video contains offensive and disturbing images***
On mobile? Click here to watch the video
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 23:54:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/france-factory-attack-severed-head-left-near-arabic-banners</Link>
        <Description>A severed head covered in Arabic 
writing was found at a U.S. gas company 
in southeast France on Friday, police 
sources and French media said, after 
two assailants rammed a car into the 
premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>French beheading suspect was "normal neighbour"
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER - A delivery man with known Islamist connections beheaded his boss and left the body, daubed with Arabic writing, at the site of a U.S.-owned gas factory in southeast France before trying to blow up the complex.
The assailant rammed his delivery van into a warehouse containing gas canisters, triggering an initial explosion, and was arrested minutes later as he tried to open canisters containing flammable chemicals, prosecutors said on Friday.
Police found the head of the victim, the 54-year-old manager of the transport firm that employed the suspect, dangling from a fence.
"The head was discovered hanging on the factory's wire fence, framed by two flags that included references to the shahada, or (Muslim) profession of faith," Paris public prosecutor Francois Molins told a news conference.
France is still coming to terms with attacks by Islamist gunmen who killed 17 people in January at a satirical weekly newspaper and a Jewish food store.
The latest attack occurred on the same day that a gunman killed at least 37 people at a Tunisian beachside hotel and an Islamic State suicide bomber killed two dozen and wounded more than 200 at a mosque in Kuwait.
"There is no other link other than to say that terrorism is our common enemy," said President Francois Hollande, returning to Paris from an EU summit in Brussels.
"There should be no doubt as to our country's ability to protect itself and remain vigilant," he said, announcing a tightening of national security to levels he said were unprecedented in recent decades.
Hollande said there were inscriptions on the headless body, and police sources said they were in Arabic, but officials did not reveal their content.
FATHER OF THREE
No group claimed responsibility for the French attack and the motive was unknown.
The attacker was injured in the blast and arrested on the site. His wife, sister and a third person were taken into custody for questioning.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve named the suspect as Yassin Sahli. He said Sahli did not have a criminal record but had been under surveillance from 2006 to 2008 on suspicion of having become radicalised by Islamist associates.
The attack occurred at an industrial zone near the town of Saint-Quentin Fallavier to the south of the city of Lyon. Its air, rail and road links have made it one of Europe's major logistics hubs, with through-traffic of 5,000 trucks a day.
Sources close to the investigation said Sahli was a 35-year-old professional driver who lived in the Lyon suburbs. Europe 1 radio interviewed a woman they identified as his wife.
"In the morning he left for work and didn't come home between noon and 2. I was waiting for him," she told Europe 1 radio, saying she and her family of three children lived normal lives as Muslims. "My heart is about to give out."
French television filming outside Sahli's apartment showed pictures of police leading out a woman, her head covered by a blanket, into a waiting car. Forensic police were carrying out searches on the ground-floor apartment.
"They are a very normal family," a neighbour who gave her name as Brigitte said. "I only talked with madame, he didn't say hello or goodbye," the 46-year-old housewife told Reuters.
Police questioned employees for several hours at the transport company run by the victim and seized the suspect's car. A cleaner at a neighbouring business described the victim of the attack as a friendly and polite man, "always saying good morning or good evening and have a nice weekend to his staff".
UNPRECEDENTED THREAT
The attack underlined again the difficulty for authorities across Europe and elsewhere of protecting so-called "soft" targets against strikes by assailants operating by themselves or in small undercover cells.
France, which has contributed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In January, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since then.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalised by Islamist fighters, officials have long said France has never seen a higher threat level.
The site of Friday's attack belonged to Air Products , a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company. It was immediately ringfenced by police and emergency services.
Air Products said its crisis and emergency response teams were "working closely with all relevant authorities" and that it had increased security at its installations around the world.
The company's chairman and chief executive is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a U.S. Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born. Mainly Shi'ite Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State.
According to French regulations applicable to zones where gases and chemicals are handled, the site would have been required to implement security arrangements at the low end of the European Union's so-called "Seveso" scale, named after the location of an industrial accident in northern Italy in 1976.
Prosecutor Molins said closed-circuit TV images showed the attacker arriving at the site. Because his vehicle was authorised to make deliveries, it was allowed through the gates.
The CCTV cameras lost track of his movements for several minutes, then picked up the van again as it accelerated towards a warehouse within the premises. A loud explosion was heard.
When emergency services arrived a few minutes later, they found the headless body of the victim by the van and a knife nearby. They overpowered the suspect as he was opening bottles of acetone, a flammable liquid chemical.
Cazeneuve said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around all sensitive sites and Hollande announced that security arrangements in the region would be placed at their highest level for the next three days.
Image: 1 of 14
Previous Next
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015. A decapitated head covered in Arabic writing was found at a a site belonged to Air Products, a U.S.-based industrial gases technology company, in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.  REUTERS/Emmanuel Foudrot
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jul 05 23:00:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>David Sweat to spend 23 hours a day in cell</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/07/05/captured-ny-fugitive-david-sweat-moved-back-to-prison</Link>
        <Description>The surviving escapee from a prison break and three-week manhunt will spend 23 hours a day in a maximum-security cell, much more confined than he and a fellow murder convict were in the prison from which they managed a getaway, officials said Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fugitive to daughter: 'See you on the outside'
ROMULUS, N.Y. -- The surviving escapee from a prison break and three-week manhunt will spend 23 hours a day in a maximum-security cell, much more confined than he and a fellow murder convict were in the prison from which they managed a getaway, officials said Sunday.
David Sweat, who was shot and wounded during his June 28 capture, was taken early Sunday from Albany Medical Center to the infirmary at the Five Points Correctional Facility in the central New York town of Romulus, the state Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said in a news release.
After at least 24 hours in the infirmary for a medical evaluation, he'll be among the up to 150 men held in the prison's Special Housing Unit, where each inmate sleeps, eats, washes and spends nearly all his time in a 105-square-foot (9.75-square- meter) cell with a bed, a writing platform, a toilet, a sink and a shower. The inmates generally are allowed out of their cells to exercise for an hour a day.
Sweat, 35, will be put on suicide watch, the corrections department noted.
Set about 200 miles (320 kilometres) west of Albany amid New York's Finger Lakes, the 1,300-inmate prison opened in 2000.
Five Points Correctional is 155 years newer than the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, from which Sweat and fellow inmate Richard Matt escaped June 6.
Authorities said Matt and Sweat cut through their adjoining cell walls over months, climbed down catwalks to tunnels, got hold of contractors' tools, broke through a brick wall, cut into and out of a steam pipe and cut a chain holding a manhole cover outside the prison to get away. Sweat is serving a life sentence for killing a sheriff's deputy; Matt, 49, was serving 25 years to life after being convicted of kidnapping and dismembering his former boss.
Clinton Correctional is maximum-security, but as residents of the prison's "honour" block and workers in its tailor shop, Matt and Sweat were able to spend considerable time out of their cells.
They got a guard to give them art supplies, tools and access to a catwalk in exchange for favours and paintings, and they shared their escape plans with a female tailor-shop instructor who gave them hacksaw blades and even agreed to be their getaway driver before she backed out, prosecutors said. The guard and instructor have pleaded not guilty to various charges.
The prison's then-superintendent and 11 other staffers were put on leave after the escape. The honour block has been temporarily closed, and new security measures are being enacted.
Matt was shot dead when a U.S. border patrol team caught up with him June 26 in woods near Malone, about 30 miles (50 kilometres) from Clinton Correctional and near the Canadian border. Sweat was captured a few miles away, in Constable, two days later.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:49:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>240 million-year-old lizard-like reptile considered 'grandfather' of turtles</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/24/scientists-consider-lizard-like-reptile-as-grandfather-of-all-turtles</Link>
        <Description>It looked like an odd lizard with a bulky body and only the skeletal precursor of a shell, but scientists say 240 million-year-old fossils unearthed in a quarry in southern Germany represent the grandfather of all turtles.</Description>
        <MainBody>240 million-year-old lizard-like reptile considered 'grandfather' of turtles 0
Will Dunham, Reuters
Wednesday, June 24, 2015       5:49:59 EDT PM
An artist's reconstruction shows the stem-turtle Pappochelys in this image released to Reuters on June 23, 2015. Scientists on June 24, 2015 announced the discovery of the oldest-known turtle, an 8-inch (20-cm) Triassic Period reptile combining traits of its lizard-like ancestors with a set of emerging turtle-like features. REUTERS/Rainer Schoch/Stuttgart Natural History Museum/Handout
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
WASHINGTON - It looked like an odd lizard with a bulky body and only the skeletal precursor of a shell, but scientists say 240 million-year-old fossils unearthed in a quarry in southern Germany represent the grandfather of all turtles.
The scientists on Wednesday announced the discovery of the oldest-known turtle, an 8-inch (20-cm) Triassic Period reptile combining traits of its lizard-like ancestors with a set of emerging turtle-like features.
They named it Pappochelys, meaning "grandfather turtle," owing to its position at the base of the turtle family tree.
"Pappochelys indeed forms a missing link for two reasons. It is far older than all so far known turtles. And its anatomy is more primitive in many features, showing the ancestral condition of various body regions," said paleontologist Rainer Schoch of Germany's State Museum of Natural History Stuttgart.
It is 20 million years older than the previous earliest-known turtle, Odontochelys from China. While Odontochelys boasted a rudimentary shell on its back, Pappochelys bore only the beginnings of this characteristic turtle trait that evolved in many steps over tens of millions of years.
"The belly armor is composed of thick, rib-like bones that are beginning to fuse to each other in many places," said paleontologist Hans-Dieter Sues of the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History in Washington, calling this "an important stage in the evolution of the turtle shell."
Pappochelys, known from 18 fossil skeletons, had a long tail, broad trunk, and, rather than a beak as in later turtles, a lizard-like skull with numerous peg-like teeth suitable for eating insects and small lizards.
It resided alongside a freshwater lake and may have used its tail for swimming and legs for steering in the water.
Schoch said Pappochelys, as a transitional creature between lizard-like ancestors and later turtles, provides a much clearer picture of turtle evolution.
"Transitional creatures are the most important contribution that paleontology can make to the study of evolution. They are often unexpected and show surprising features," Schoch said. "They show how complicated structures like the skull or turtle shell formed step by step, and also give evidence on the sequence of evolutionary steps."
Pappochelys lived 10 million years before the first dinosaurs, but plenty of danger existed. The lake's largest predator was the 16-foot (5-meter) amphibian Mastodonsaurus. The 20-foot (6-meter) terrestrial croc relative Batrachotomus prowled the land.
The research appears in the journal Nature.
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:12:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French beheading suspect was "normal neighbour"</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/french-beheading-suspect-was-normal-neighbour</Link>
        <Description>SAINT-PRIEST, France - When suburban deliveryman Yassin Sahli set off for work on Friday, his wife said it seemed just like any other day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in terror attack
SAINT-PRIEST, France - When suburban deliveryman Yassin Sahli set off for work on Friday, his wife said it seemed just like any other day.
Within hours, the 35-year-old father of three was arrested on suspicion of beheading his boss, then ramming their van into an industrial gases site in southeast France, setting off an explosion that authorities called an attempted act of terrorism.
"Yesterday he was at work, he came home as usual. We spent a normal evening and in the morning he left for work and didn't come home between noon and 2. I was waiting for him," a woman identified as his wife told Europe 1 radio.
Sources close to the investigation said the wife, who has not been officially named, was subsequently arrested and was being held by police for questioning.
Yassin Sahli was named as the chief suspect by Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve in a brief statement at the site of the attack in the town of Saint-Quentin Fallavier, 30 km (20 miles) south of Lyon.
Very little has been officially released on his background.
Yet according to his wife's brief radio interview, theirs was an ordinary Muslim family living in the Lyon suburb of Saint-Priest, an account shared by neighbours who said contact with Sahli was limited to simple greetings.
He and his wife lived with their three children, aged between six and nine, on the ground floor of a three-storey, nondescript social housing block.
The area is quiet, with green spaces, clean streets and a new tram link to the centre of Lyon. It is far from the stereotypical image of a run-down city suburb.
"They are a very normal family," a neighbour who gave her name as Brigitte said. I only talked with madame, he didn't say hello or goodbye," the 46-year-old housewife said.
Though Sahli, of North African origin, had no criminal record, Cazeneuve said he was categorised by security services as far back as 2006 as someone at risk of being radicalised.
While that status allowed security forces to discreetly keep tabs on him, they did not see fit to renew it in 2008, although he was known to have contact with radical Islamists in France.
However, he was back on the radar of the DGSI domestic security service for at least the past two years and was described in 2013 as a "hardcore Muslim" in one intelligence memo, according to RTL radio.
Another memo dating from May 2014 said he had undergone a "radical" change, losing weight and shaving his beard. It said he was often away from home for unexplained absences of several weeks at a time.
The note said he held meetings at his home, hosting men who wore combat fatigues. Doorstep chatter with them was peppered with references to jihad, said RTL, citing the memo.
Sahli had been living in Saint-Priest for around six months. Before that, the Est Republicain newspaper said the suspect,  whose late father was Algerian and mother Moroccan, lived in Pontarlier near the Swiss border. The town is home to a mosque known for the virulent views of its preacher, who has since left France.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
