<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:06:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ontario bans sale of flavoured tobacco, puts limits on e-cigarettes</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/ontario-bans-sale-of-flavoured-tobacco-puts-limits-on-e-cigarettes</Link>
        <Description>Ontario has passed legislation that will ban the sale of flavoured tobacco, put new limits on e-cigarettes and require restaurant and convenience store chains to post calorie counts for their food and drink items.</Description>
        <MainBody>Proposed menthol smoke ban under fire
TORONTO-
Ontario has passed legislation that will ban the sale of flavoured tobacco, put new limits on e-cigarettes and require restaurant and convenience store chains to post calorie counts for their food and drink items.
Associate Health Minister Dipika Damerla said in an interview that the Making Healthier Choices Act, which received third reading Tuesday, addresses two main threats to modern health  smoking and calorie consumption.
It really puts Ontario at the forefront on so many counts, especially in Canada, but I would say across North America, she said. Were among the first jurisdictions to regulate electronic cigarettes. Were among the first jurisdictions in Canada and North America to ban menthol cigarettes and definitely the first jurisdiction in Canada to now have calorie counts in Ontarios chain restaurants.
Businesses will no longer be allowed to sell flavoured tobacco  it comes in kid-friendly tastes like cherry and grape  as of Jan. 1, 2016.
The Ontario government has until Jan. 1, 2018, to ban menthol cigarettes but the minister said she will likely act before that date.
Stores and restaurants with 20 or more locations in Ontario must begin prominently identifying calories for regular food and drink items by Jan 1, 2017.
As of Jan. 1, 2016 it will be illegal to sell e-cigarettes and vaporizers to anyone under the age of 19.
Adults will not be permitted to use e-cigarettes anywhere where smoking is prohibited, although an enforcement date has not been set.
Stores will not be allowed to advertise the products.
Progressive Conservative MPP Randy Hillier has asked the provincial government to delay the section of the bill that would see e-cigarettes and vaporizers treated in law like cigarettes.
Hillier is using a vaporizer  users inhale vapour, not smoke  to help kick his own tobacco habit.
I havent quit smoking completely but I have reduced smoking substantially, he said. Three of my staff members have quit smoking completely with the use of vapourizers. The benefits are substantial.
Hillier was joined by David Sweanor, a University of Ottawa adjunct law professor, and Andy Prevost, of the Tobacco Harm Reduction Association, Tuesday at a Queens Park media conference where they argued that the benefits of vaporizers as a smoking cessation product are ignored in the new law.
The smoke and additives in regular cigarettes pose the greatest risk to human health, not the controllable amounts of nicotine in vaporizers, Prevost said.
Damerla said vaping will continue to be legal in Ontario but limits are needed on a nicotine product in the interest of public health.
Right now, you can be 13-years-old  you cant legally buy a cigarette but you can buy an electronic cigarette because theres absolutely no regulation, she said. Right now, you could vape on a subway, you could vape in the Ontario legislature if you wanted to. You could vape in a classroom.
People dont do that but technically you could, Damerla said.
antonella.artuso@sunmedia.ca
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:50:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Municipal amalgamations resulted in higher costs, Fraser Institute report finds</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/municipal-amalgamations-resulted-in-higher-costs-fraser-institute-report-finds</Link>
        <Description>		

The mega-merger mania that enveloped Ontario in the 1990s — starting in Southwestern Ontario and radiating to the rest of the province — failed to save money or generate huge efficiencies.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Debora Van Brenk , The London Free Press
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       7:50:41 EDT PM
Former Ontario premier Mike Harris (QMI Agency file photo)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
The mega-merger mania that enveloped Ontario in the 1990s  starting in Southwestern Ontario and radiating to the rest of the province  failed to save money or generate huge efficiencies.
Thats the assessment of new report by the Fraser Institute, a conservative think-tank that says the cost savings the province promised never materialized.
Report author Lydia Miljan said some benefits to mergers included better development planning, so amalgamations cant be considered a total flop.
Its a bit more complicated than, Was it just a pass or a fail? (But) if its just a question of cost savings, yes, it was a fail.
In the mid-1990s, the province ordered Kent County towns and townships and the City Chatham to amalgamate into a single Municipality of Chatham-Kent, following years of acrimonious debate.
The new structure would save millions, cut bureaucracy and boost efficiency, the Progressive Conservatives under Premier Mike Harris said. They urged others to follow Chatham-Kent  voluntarily or involuntarily.
The number of municipalities dropped to almost half of their previous 800-plus.
Other studies have analyzed costs pre- and post-amalgamation. This report also compares a sampling of amalgamated and non-amalgamated communities.
Bob Wood, then the PC MPP for London South, said cost savings was never his motivation as an amalgamation advocate. What I saw them as doing was resulting in a better-functioning municipality.
Warwick Mayor Todd Case said Chatham-Kent was sort of the poster boy of how the province wanted restructuring to take place as it urged communities to merge.
So they did, and quickly. Some municipalities maybe hit the panic button because they felt they were going to be forced into it, Case said.
For Warwick and Watford, where co-operation turned into amalgamation, the process was less painful than elsewhere.
Costs still increased, partly because the province downloaded programs to local governments. What weve seen is that bigger is not always better.
Chatham-Kent Coun. Joe Faas served as Dresdens mayor from 1990 until it became part of Chatham-Kent in 1998.
He said there have been positives and negatives since, but that its long been considered a done deal.
We cant go back, he said. Things are in my opinion working fairly smoothly.
With files from Trevor Terfloth, Chatham Daily News
- - -
AMONG THE FINDINGS
Significant increases in property taxes, salaries and wages and long-term debt, in amalgamated and non-amalgamated communities. Amalgamated communities did no better financially, and many did worse, than those that didnt merge.
Download the full report at fraserinstitute.org
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:46:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Welland mall evacuated over 'swatting' hoax</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/welland-mall-evacuated-over-swatting-hoax</Link>
        <Description>WELLAND -- Seaway Mall in Welland was swatted Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man arrested over Xbox, PlayStation hacks
WELLAND -- Seaway Mall in Welland was swatted Tuesday.
Swatting involves prank phone calls meant to cause a reaction from police or emergency services such as tactical units, bomb squads and canine crews.
The shopping centre was evacuated shortly before 11 a.m. when somebody called 911 to report a threat against the mall.
The threat involved "violence towards Seaway Mall and its occupants," a Niagara Regional Police news release said.
Sorry @SeawayMall but your shops are shut early &lt;3 #Raped
 RapeSquad (@R4peSquad) May 26, 2015
Const. Phil Gavin said the call came in at 10:42 a.m. and officers were on scene within three minutes.
Paramedics and firefighters also responded and a police canine unit was called in to search the mall before it was reopened.
As the situation unfolded, a Twitter user with the handle @R4peSquad taunted both the mall and police and later took responsibility for the threat.
The anonymous Twitter account appeared to be followed by and was following hackers.
Said one tweet at 11:13 a.m.: "Sorry @SeawayMall but your shops are shut early #raped."
Said another: "@SeawayMall we take responsibility for this, don't forget to praise the rapists."
More swats on the way, please bear with us!
 RapeSquad (@R4peSquad) May 26, 2015
A later tweet used the hashtag #seawaymallswatted.
Welland fire Chief Denys Prevost tweeted at 12:38 p.m.: "People who think it amusing to call-in hoaxes, i.e. swatting, will not think it so amusing when they face criminal charges and jail."
Reached later by phone, Prevost said these types of calls tax police, fire and EMS resources. He said he didn't want to speak further to the matter of swatting, saying he didn't want to give anybody any ideas.
"The news media coverage on swatting is part of the reason this is happening," he said.
Despite the online taunting of Niagara's police service, Gavin wasn't prepared to associate the mall case with the escalation of hoaxes.
"We don't want to call this thing swatting," he said.
He did call it a criminal act.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:26:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chatham-Kent Children's Safety Village seeking online votes</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/chatham-kent-childrens-safety-village-seeking-online-votes</Link>
        <Description>With a little help from Cargill, the Chatham-Kent Children's Safety Village hopes the community's rural children will be a little safer.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Diana Martin , Chatham Daily News
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       7:26:17 EDT PM
Gary Patterson, Chatham-Kent Children's Safety Village board president, is attempting to upgrade the farm safety program tools by winning a $25,000 grant from Cargill through an online contest. Photo taken Blenheim Ont. on Monday May 25, 2015. (Diana Martin/Chatham Daily News/Postmedia Network)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
With a little help from Cargill, the Chatham-Kent Children's Safety Village hopes the community's rural children will be a little safer.
With our agriculture influence we need to have the tools here and readily available (for the farm safety program), said Barb Lovell. Not just for these Grade 6 kids but, because we are expanding programs, we want to reach more children with our farm safety program. It could grow to include adults as well.
Lovell, the executive director for the CKCSV, said they currently have to rent the appropriate items and have them shipped from out west, which increases the cost to the non-profit agency.
Lovell said the Cargill Together We Thrive competition offers a chance at $25,000 to invest in farm programs that cover injury prevention dealing with power take-offs (PTO), grain, chemical, lawnmower and ATV safety.
PTOs travel at a high rate of speed and can tangle your clothes, your hair and it doesn't stop if something gets tangled in it, said Lovell. A lot of limbs and lives have been lost because of improper use.
The CKCSV is competing against 16 other organizations across Ontario who are vying for online votes.
This is a new contest celebrating 150 years of Cargill, said Lovell. We had a number of local farmers and agriculture businesses encourage us to apply because they feel so strongly about the farm safety program. They're the ones who've shown us the way for this.
People can vote once a day using their e-mail address to sign in and have until June 30 to throw their support behind the program, said Lovell. Although votes are the main driving force on the website, each group is judged on their overall impact to the community.
Gary Patterson, board president of the CKCSV, said their group reaches 3,000 children across the 23 communities in the municipality with their injury prevention and life saving programs.
He said every year an estimated 25,500 children under the age of 14 are hospitalized due to preventable injuries and that another 390 die.
Patterson said the board included a parent whose child had been run over by a tractor, but because the area had received an overload of rain the child was pressed down in to the mud and survived with injures.
We've had four deaths in the last 10 year or so of kids under the age of 17 due to ATV accidents and there have been multiple injuries, said Patterson. We don't want this anymore. That's why ATV is part of our farm program and lawnmower safety.
The group also launched a gofundme campaign to help fund a revamped 32-week plan to provide programming to students in Grades 1 to 8, as well as seniors and other at risk groups in the community.
We have these new programs coming on and we have summer camps and good support from the community, said Lovell. Winning this competition would just help us reach more children for farm and rural safety.
You can vote for CKCSV at http://togetherwethrive.ca/vote/details/chatham-kent-childrens-safety-village or donate to their gofundme campaign at http://www.gofundme.com/cksafetyvillage

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:07:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Public high school teacher strikes illegal, classes to resume</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/public-high-school-teacher-strikes-illegal-olrb-rules</Link>
        <Description>Public high school teachers in Durham, Peel and Sudbury are participating in an illegal strike and must return to work immediately, the Ontario Labour Relations Board (OLRB) has ruled.</Description>
        <MainBody>ETFO puts sex-ed training on hold
TORONTO-
Public high school students in Peel, Durham and Sudbury return to class Wednesday  one day after the Ontario Labour Relations Board (OLRB) ruled that their teachers were on an illegal strike.
In a written judgment released Tuesday, board chair Bernard Fishbein effectively ordered the teachers back on the job Wednesday for a minimum two-week period.
I direct that these strikes cease at least for two weeks from the date of this decision, he said. After this two-week moratorium has elapsed, the local strike may continue ... subject to proceedings or outcomes elsewhere which have been initiated during the course of these proceedings.
All three school boards advised parents that classes would resume Wednesday.
The Ontario government was already moving back-to-work legislation through the legislature to bring an end to the strikes that put 74,000 students out of class.
The bill is expected to be in place by the time the OLRB strike moratorium is up.
Education Minister Liz Sandals said government lawyers were still reviewing the OLRB decision late Tuesday but her government intends to continue pursuing back-to-work legislation.
It really doesnt change the focus  the focus at this point is we have to get the students back in school, Sandals said. And the only way that we can be sure that well get the students back in school, and then have them stay in school for the rest of the school year, is by passing the back-to-work legislation.
The Education Relations Commission had officially advised Sandals that the academic year for public high school students in Durham, Peel and Sudbury was in jeopardy until they return promptly to class.
Durham teachers have been on the picket line since April 20, and teachers at the other two boards followed closely on their heels.
The three school boards took the Ontario Secondary School Teachers Federation (OSSTF) to the OLRB, arguing that the local strikes were being fought over issues that legally belonged at a provincial bargaining table.
Under legislation introduced by the Kathleen Wynne government last year, teacher unions bargain with the provincial government at a central table over large monetary issues such as class sizes and at another table with school boards to resolve local issues.
The law demands local strikes be fought on local issues, and provincial strikes be fought on provincial issues.
Fishbein concluded that OSSTFs local strikes were at least in part fought over provincial issues such as class sizes.
Peel District School Board chair Janet McDougald had earlier accused OSSTF of using the boards students to send a message to the central table and the provincial government.
An immediate response from the OSSTF was not available but president Paul Elliott earlier told reporters that all three strikes were fought on local issues.
Decision_0376-15-U_Durham-Rainbow-Peel_District_School_Boards.pdf
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:05:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lucas student who was sent home for her ‘inappropriate’ clothing doesn’t want students to be perceived as disrespectful</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/lucas-student-who-was-sent-home-for-her-inappropriate-clothing-doesnt-want-students-to-be-perceived-as-disrespectful</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of London high school students say they’ll wear tank tops to school Wednesday to protest a dress code they say unfairly sexualizes girls.</Description>
        <MainBody>To change or not to change
Hundreds of London high school students say theyll wear tank tops to school Wednesday to protest a dress code they say unfairly sexualizes girls.
But the young woman who inspired the protest, Lucas secondary school student Laura Anderson, said she wants the tanks to be respectful, not outrageous.
My intention always was and always will be to make a positive change respectfully, Anderson said Tuesday evening.
If we bash the entire dress code on Wednesday, thats going to make us seem immature and rebellious.
Anderson was sent home Monday from school after a vice-principal told her that her loose-fitting tank top and ripped jeans were inappropriate and violated the Lucas dress code.
The Grade 12 student, who will major in English literature at Queens University in the fall, had to miss a lecture on Hamlet while she went home to change.
Shes used the experience as a jumping off point to talk about the sexualization of girls bodies and the problems with the schools dress code.
School administrators draft the dress code every year with input from the school council, which includes parents. Theres opportunity for students to give their input, too, said Sheila Powell, a superintendent of education whose schools include Lucas.
Were hoping that (Wednesday), if there is a protest, it will provide an opportunity for talks about the dress code. (The principal) and student leaders are looking for input so they can refine and change it, Powell said.
The vice-principal told Anderson the tank top was too sheer and that her undergarments were showing. Anderson was wearing a bandeau and bra underneath the tank.
A petition started on change.org Monday has brought in nearly 2,000 signatures, asking for the dress code to be changed. The hashtag #MyBodyMyBusiness was trending in London on Twitter.
Students at other schools have also said theyll join the protest.
Im going to wear a tank top, a regular one, probably more conservative than the one I wore on Monday. I love the support Im getting. It is building my confidence and my voice. I dont want to come across as rebelling and disrespecting. I want to keep it professional, Anderson said.
The dress code focuses too much on the administration telling us what is and isnt appropriate. I dont think we should show undergarments, I dont think we should show midriffs, but all this other stuff about no tanks or V-necks, its ridiculous. If its distracting, its distracting because were oversexualizing other peoples bodies.
Twitter.com/KateatLFPress
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:28:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Allegations include unwanted contact, threats</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/allegations-include-unwanted-contact-threats</Link>
        <Description>A London man sat in the prisoner’s box often shaking his head as an Ontario Court of Justice in Chatham heard allegations he appeared to strongly dispute.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Vicki Gough , Chatham Daily News
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       6:28:51 EDT PM
Chatham Court House
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
A London man sat in the prisoners box often shaking his head as an Ontario Court of Justice in Chatham heard allegations he appeared to strongly dispute.
The defendant is accused of repeatedly harassing and threatening his ex-girlfriend since the pair separated a year ago.
The 25-year-old was arrested Monday when he appeared at police headquarters after a warrant for his arrest was issued last week.
He was charged with six counts of uttering threats, three counts of criminal harassment, three counts of failing to comply and making harassing phone calls.
Chatham-Kent police said the womans mother told officers the man made menacing comments to both her and her daughter on more than one occasion.
During the defendants court appearance, an assistant Crown attorney said the accused and the former girlfriend dated for two years, but since the relationship ended in 2014 the man continued to contact the woman.
He made repeated unwelcome attempts to call her, Colleen Johnson said.
The defendant used vulgar names and threatened to smash her face and slit her throat, she added, during a synopsis of facts in the case.
Court heard the woman received approximately 100 death threats.
She would sleep with a baseball bat out of fear of the accused, Johnson said.
The defendant is currently bound by a peace bond not to contact the victim.
The accused was released to his father as surety and ordered not to visit Chatham-Kent unless attending court or to see a lawyer.
Will seek counselling
A Chatham man arrested on impaired driving charges last week told a bail court he has since taken steps to get counselling.
Court heard the defendant registered over four times the legal limit during breath tests.
Witnesses told police a black Mustang was swerving across Prince Albert Road at a high rate of speed shortly after 9 p.m. Thursday.
Court heard two oncoming drivers had to avoid being struck by the car while another driver followed the accused into Chatham.
Police located the car stopped in an empty lot in the Wilson Street area at about 9:30 p.m.
While speaking to the driver, the officer detected a smell of alcohol on his breath and noted two cases of beer inside the vehicle.
Two valid breath tests registered 370 and 377 mg of alcohol per 100 ml of blood, court heard.
Assistant Crown attorney Colleen Johnson said police were concerned about the mans health and took him to the Chatham-Kent Health Alliance for a medical assessment.
Shawn Wry, 46, was released with a surety on $2,000 bail.
He was ordered not to possess or consume alcohol and obey a curfew between 10 p.m. and 6 a.m. if not in a residential treatment program.
Further trial delay
A Grande Pointe man charged with historic sexual-related charges involving children is still not healthy enough to stand trial.
Defence lawyer Mark Mackew told a Superior Court justice Monday his client, Gerald Lucier, was medically unfit to attend court.
The 79-year-old defendant suffered a heart attack just days before his last scheduled court appearance in early April.
The matter was rescheduled to go to trial on Sept. 8.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:23:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stolen battery charger grounds Chatham couple</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/stolen-battery-charger-grounds-chatham-couple</Link>
        <Description>A Chatham couple is stuck at home after the charger for their mobility scooter was stolen early Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Don Robinet , Postmedia Network
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       6:23:06 EDT PM
Cindy Sprigg, seen with her husband, Richard, sits on a mobility scooter she can no longer use after the charger was stolen. Photo taken Tuesday, May 26, 2015 in Chatham, Ont. (DON ROBINET/POSTMEDIA NETWORK)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
A Chatham couple is stuck at home after the charger for their mobility scooter was stolen early Monday.
Cindy Sprigg, 53, and her husband, Richard, 67, love their home at 80 Essex Court in St. Clair Estates, where they moved in April from Taylor Avenue. They say they were able to purchase the home for about the same money they were paying each month in rent while on Taylor.
The couple have enjoyed their time at manufactured home park, which they consider to be subject to less crime than their former neighbourhood, but were dismayed to find the charger for the Maple Leaf MP4B scooter missing, along with some hand tools.
The police said they rarely get calls here, said Cindy, saying they think of the St. Clair Estates area as being law-abiding and friendly.
Most people will wish you a good day whether you know them or not, said Richard, who added, Even the high school kids are friendly and open.
Cindy, who is a stroke survivor, has limited ability to walk, and now finds herself in the middle of the neighbourhood without easy access to the bus stop or stores. I can make it about a block and a half, she said. I can't make it to the bus stop.
They acquired the used mobility scooter in May, shortly after moving into St. Clair Estates, and have stored it outside, beneath a cover at night, and have charged it using an extension cord leading to their home. They say the home is not large enough to hold the scooter inside, and even if there was room, there is no wheelchair ramp.
Richard, who said he was diagnosed and treated for prostate cancer, also has limited mobility, being able to walk a couple of blocks at the most. The couple say before they acquired the scooter, they paid someone to drive them around on their errands.
The couple said they are hoping that by going public, someone who has an extra charger that is no longer being used may get into contact with them, as they aren't able to pay for a new charger on their fixed income.
A spokesperson with Shoppers Home Health Care on St. Clair Street said a new charger for that model of scooter costs about $250.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:05:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>John Baird joins law firm as senior adviser</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/john-baird-joins-law-firm-as-senior-advisor</Link>
        <Description>Former foreign affairs minister John Baird, who used to be an Ottawa-area MP, has a new job as senior adviser at Bennett Jones, a Canadian law firm with 380 lawyers. The company announced the appointment in a press release dated May 26.</Description>
        <MainBody>MacLeod quits PC race, eyes Baird seat
Former foreign affairs minister John Baird, who used to be an Ottawa-area MP, has a new job as senior adviser at Bennett Jones, a Canadian law firm with 380 lawyers. The company announced the appointment in a press release dated May 26.
Bennett Jones is a Toronto-based business law firm with nine offices. Baird said the company's global reach appealed to him, citing his interest in Canada-China relations and the company's Beijing office.
Baird stunned Parliament-watchers earlier this year when he stepped down from his high-profile post in Prime Minister Stephen Harper's cabinet and also quit as the member of Parliament for Ottawa West-Nepean. Baird entered politics in 1995 as a member of provincial Parliament in Mike Harris' Conservative government. He switched to federal politics in 2006.
-- Ottawa Sun
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:02:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chatham-Kent branches gearing up for busy summer</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/chatham-kent-branches-gearing-up-for-busy-summer</Link>
        <Description>Staff at the Chatham Public Library are happy as ever, if a little tired.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Louis Pin , The Daily News
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       6:02:33 EDT PM
Brysen Anderson, 8, is busy as work with his tutor, Kailagh Hammell, at the Chatham Branch Library. The library will be holding its annual book sale next week, from Wednesday to Saturday. (Louis Pin/Chatham Daily News/Postmedia Network)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
Staff at the Chatham Public Library are happy as ever, if a little tired.
Theyve been running around, planning everything from magicians to drummers  performers set to play in all 11 branches.
Summer is the busiest time, said Sarah Hart, program manager with the Chatham-Kent Public Library. Were in the planning  well, no, the solidifying stage.
This year, even more emphasis will be put on students to read over summer. According to Hart, reports show that a childs literacy slides during summer months, unless they make an effort to read.
The number of books  is different for every child, Hart said. The goal is to keep them engaged, to motivate them.
To pique the interests of younger students, the library will be bringing in Owen Anderson, a local magician who often has children help with his tricks. With jugglers and drummers also on the summer roster, students will have numerous opportunities to find new interests and hobbies.
This June will also mark the end of the annual Bag of Books campaign, the successful initiative done to bring books to students.
We go out [with] 25 books or one per student, said Donna Gaumond, Child Services Technician at the Chatham branch. Some students live too far away, or cant afford bus fare to get here  if that happens, we visit.
There are also summer events for other ages. Teens will have a chance to put together Minecraft keychains, experiment with Retro Techno, and get a taste of Japanese pop culture on Anime and Manga Day.
The Adult Summer Reading Program is popular as well, where anyone can cast a ballot for each book they read. Each branch has an individual draw at the end of the year, and then a system-wide grand prize draw.
Last year, we received over 5,700 ballots, said Hart.

Next Up
The Chatham Branchs spring book sale, happening from June 3 to June 6 next week. The special preview on Wednesday costs $5, but gives readers the first choice of donated books.

Popular Books in Chatham Kent
As reported by the Sarnia Observer, some books - like James Patterson's 14th Deadly Sin - are rising high in popularity outside of Chatham-Kent, too. Heres a look at the most popular books around here, and where they rank in Sarnia:

1. 14th Deadly Sin, by James Patterson (Sarnia Rank: 2)
2. Memory Man, by David Baldacci (6)
3. The Mountain Story, by Lori Lansens
4. The Girl on the Train, by Paula Hawkins (1)
5. The Liar, by Nora Roberts (4)
6. Truth or Die, by James Patterson
7. Every Fifteen Minutes, by Lisa Scottoline
8. The Stranger, by Harlan Coben
9. Wicked Charms: A Lizzy and Diesel Novel, by Janet Evanovich
10. Gray Mountain, by John Grisham

1. My Secret Sister, by Edwards and Smith (1)
2. They Left Us Everything : A Memoir, by Plum Johnson
3. 17 Carnations : The Royals, the Nazis, and the Biggest Cover-up in History
4. American Sniper : The Autobiography of the Most Lethal Sniper in U.S. Military History, by Chris Kyle
5. The Brain's Way of Healing, by Norman Doidge, M.D. (10)
6. Dead Wake : The Last Crossing of the Lusitania, by Erik Larson (9)
7. The Inconvenient Indian : A Curious Account of Native People in North America, by Thomas King
8. Yes Please, by Amy Poehler
9. Hope: A Memoir of Survival in Cleveland, by Amanda Berry and Gina DeJesus (2)
10. I Must Say: My Life as a Humble Comedy Legend, by Martin Short

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:53:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Painted House Gala features unique locally painted furniture and canvases</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/painted-house-gala-features-unique-locally-painted-furniture-and-canvases</Link>
        <Description>An up-cycled table painted by Marilyn Hearn features two black-capped chickadees resting lightly on thin branches framed by soft blues and gold highlights.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Diana Martin , Chatham Daily News
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       5:53:41 EDT PM
Artist Marilyn Hearn, left, Joanne Gamble, May Court Club of Chatham's Painted House Gala convener and Sue Cummings, Emergency Lunch Box Program convener display some of the upcycled art pieces that will be auctioned at the event May 29. Photo Taken:  in Chatham, Ont. on Monday May 25, 2015. (Diana Martin/Chatham Daily News/Postmedia Network)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
An up-cycled table painted by Marilyn Hearn features two black-capped chickadees resting lightly on thin branches framed by soft blues and gold highlights.
The whimsical cottage-style D-shaped end table is one of several unique pieces up for auction at the May Court Club of Chatham's Painted House Gala Friday at Club Lentinas in Chatham.
The year before I did six pieces, this year I just did two, Hearn said. These are hand-made, one of a kind items you won't find anywhere else and their done locally.
Hearn said the unique furniture is a great driver for the May Court Club fundraiser because similar pieces would cost upwards of $400 to $500 to buy from a shop, if you could find them.
They help children, Hearn said of the club. This is a way that I can contribute  through art.
The biennial Painted House event supports May Court Club's Emergency Lunch Box (ELB)program, the Queen Elizabeth II Public School breakfast program and other service groups through grants.
The ELB spent $18,500 this year providing nutritious packaged snacks, such as granola bars, yogurt, cheese strings and bagels, once a month to 25 Chatham-Kent schools in the public, Catholic and French Catholic school boards. It spent $5,000 on the breakfast program at Queen Elizabeth and provided them with 50% of the volunteers to run it.
We fill in the gap for when kids don't have enough in their lunches or don't have lunches at all, said Sue Cummings, program convener. Every school has some type of breakfast program and then there is the Farm to School program we fill in the gaps for what those programs don't provide.
The gala features 32 items for the live auction, 115 for the silent auction and three raffle packages including more than $2,500 worth of gift certificates, said convener Joanne Gamble.
Whether it's the live auction or the silent auction, they are running back and forth to increase their bids, said Joanne Gamble, gala convener. It's a very fun night and it appeals to a wide audience, not just women.
Gamble said the community and local businesses stepped up this year to provide the gala with sports packages, birthday packages aimed at children, a jersey from Matt Duchene who plays for Colorado Avalanche, a gourmet dinner party for six and a bathroom makeover worth $4,475.
We have a good number of the items on the May Court Club of Chatham Facebook page, she said, adding. We also have a raffle, with three separate packages, that total over $2,500 and the tickets are only $5 each.
Gamble said the doors open at 6 p.m. With the live auction beginning at 8 p.m.
Tickets for the evening are $35 and include entry and hor d'oeuvres. There will be a cash bar.
Gamble said advance tickets can by purchased by calling, 519-354-6905 or 519-352-1092 or at River House Gifts in the Downtown Chatham Centre.
A number of tickets will also be available at the door.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:53:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Everest College student waiting for diploma</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/ex-everest-college-student-waiting-for-diploma</Link>
        <Description>Melissa O'Connell doesn't care about wearing a cap and gown, she just wants her diploma.</Description>
        <MainBody>Everest students locked out as school closed
Melissa O'Connell doesn't care about wearing a cap and gown, she just wants her diploma.
The former Everest College student says she completed her medical office administration program a week before the privately-owned U.S. based college shut down in February.
Four months later, she still has nothing to show for it.
"I'm frustrated. I'm pissed. I'm annoyed," said O'Connell, a 25-year-old single mother. "I understand they need to focus on the students that do need to continue their education but they haven't focused on the students that have completed."
The Ministry of Training, Colleges and Universities says it went through more than 30,000 student files across Everest's 14 Ontario campuses, found 134 signed diplomas and mailed them to each student.
Since then, the ministry has received 93 requests for diplomas from students -- including one from O'Connell -- who completed their Everest programs before the college shuttered its doors on Feb. 19.
However, the ministry can't seem to find those diplomas.
"The Ministry reviewed each of these students files and determined that Everest College had not placed a copy of a signed diplomas in these students files prior to its closure," Belinda Bien, spokeswoman for the ministry, told the Sun in an e-mail Tuesday.
O'Connell was contacted by the ministry to complete a Transfer Credit Approval Form. She believed Herzing College, another private college in the St. Laurent Mall, could then sign off on her diploma.
"I just needed a signature. My diploma was waiting in the room (in Everest)," she said.
Then O'Connell received a call on May 21 from Herzing College saying she had to go back to school in order to get a diploma which she already earned. It would be paid by the ministry.
"They told me I have six months of school left. I don't need another diploma, I don't need to go back to school," she said.
According to the ministry, because O'Connell chose to complete her training at Herzing College, it must conduct a Prior Learning Assessment Review to measure students' knowledge against their curriculum.
Herzing then determines what is required to obtain a diploma.
O'Connell was hired at Sunshine Medical Clinic -- where she completed her two-week placement -- even though she never technically graduated.
"If I want to go get another job, they'll want my credentials and I don't have anything to show them," she said. "I'm not going to quit my job, I have a three-year-old daughter."
O'Connell said she doesn't know where to go from here.
"I've been at them (the ministry) for four months. I've e-mailed them again and again. I can understand if I had four months left, I would have done the six months," she said. "I just want my diploma."
Twitter: @ Keaton_Robbins
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:49:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Council hears consultant update</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/council-hears-consultant-update</Link>
        <Description>An update on the municipality's tourism efforts was presented to council on Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Trevor Terfloth , Chatham Daily News
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       5:49:25 EDT PM
Chatham-Kent Civic Centre
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
An update on the municipality's tourism efforts was presented to council on Monday.
Richard Innes, a consultant with Brain Trust Marketing and Communications, provided details on the tourism destination management plan, which is currently in the works.
Destination management is a continuous process of co-ordinating, developing and marketing the area's tourism potential, he said.
However, it will require the co-operation of all sectors in order to be successful, he added.
It's not just the tourism department that's involved in tourism, he said.
Chatham-Kent's Tourism Stakeholders Advisory Council has been meeting monthly since the beginning of this year.
To date, there have been working group orientations, online and ground assessments, and tours throughout the municipality.
With destinations across the world courting visitors, Innes said municipalities need to be proactive in order to remain competitive.
He recommended that Chatham-Kent identify clusters of best bet assets to focus on, noting that natural amenities, heritage and black history are among the attractions.
Innes also said those in the tourism business need to think like a visitor to help them make the most of their time in a community.
Stakeholder vision sessions have been planned and the final report is expected to be completed in late summer.
South Kent Coun Karen Herman called it an important task that will help move the community forward.
I think it's very impressive to get all this work done, she said.
In celebration of Tourism Week in Canada, an information and brochure swapping event will take place Tuesday, June 2 at the St. Clair College Capitol Theatre from 5:30-7:30 p.m.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:46:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wildfire forces 5,000 from homes in Alberta</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/wildfire-prompts-evacuation-of-residents-east-of-slave-lake</Link>
        <Description>Margo Auger is anxious to return home to Wabasca in northern Alberta, where an out-of-control wildfire has forced more than 5,000 people to flee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wildfire forces 5,000 from homes in Alberta 0
Peter Lozinski, Kristy Brownlee and Nicole Ireland, Postmedia Network
Tuesday, May 26, 2015       5:46:04 EDT PM
Smoke rises from a wildfire east of Slave Lake, Alberta May 25, 2015 in a photo supplied by the Alberta Wildfire Info department.  REUTERS/Alberta Environment and Sustainable Resource Development (ESRD)/handout via Reuters
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
COLD LAKE, Alta. - Margo Auger is anxious to return home to Wabasca in northern Alberta, where an out-of-control wildfire has forced more than 5,000 people to flee.
"We're all praying for rain," she told Postmedia Network by phone from the camp in Calling Lake, Alta., where she and more than 100 other evacuees are living in trailers and tents.
Hundreds more  including members of Auger's family  are sleeping on cots in the nearby recreation centre.
"It is pretty uncomfortable" inside the centre, Auger said, and people aren't getting much sleep.
But she said the evacuees are grateful.
Some of the most vulnerable evacuees, including the elderly and people who are sick, have been flown to Edmonton to stay in hotel rooms.
A forecast of smoke spreading through Alberta and British Columbia in a series of meteorology images provided from Development Canada and the University of British Columbia. Green is least dense and the darker the red, the denser the smoke. (Development Canada/Postmedia Network)
Firefighters, helicopters and airtankers continued to battle the 208-hectare blaze Tuesday.
The weather hasn't helped. As of Tuesday, lightning had sparked many new fires in 24 hours. Hot and dry conditions prompted an Alberta-wide fire ban on Monday.
On Monday night, several dozen residents had to flee their homes east of Slave Lake in northern Alberta. That 139-hectare blaze was burning 25 km east of town along the Old Smith Hwy.
Officials said Tuesday morning the blaze doesn't pose a risk to Slave Lake, where just four years ago wildfires caused $1 billion in damages and 700 people were left homeless.
For Auger, memories of the Slave Lake disaster were top of mind when Wabasca started getting ready to evacuate on the weekend.
"(Slave Lake) had absolutely no time (to get ready)," she recalled.
So far the flames have stayed out of Wabasca.

UPDATE AT 10:15 PM. Latest picture of the wildfire 25 km east of Slave Lake along the Old Smith Hwy.
More than 1,600 firefighters and 200 aircraft continue to battle dozens of wildfires across northern Alberta. As of Tuesday, 66 wildfires were burning, according to the province's website.  Nineteen of the fires were listed as out of control.
Oil and gas companies evacuated at least three sites -- moving thousands of workers -- over the weekend.
Another was partially evacuated Tuesday with 110 people flying out from the Leismer facility. And Christina Lake oilsands project halted operations.
Carlene Belcourt, owner of a business in nearby Cold Lake, Alta., told Postmedia Network her daughter was one of the last 100 employees to be flown out by helicopter from one of the sites.
"It was pretty scary," Belcourt said. Her daughter told her just the road was in flames, and that she was safe.
But her mom couldn't help worrying.
"It's a parental thing," Belcourt said.
Since April 1, 629 wildfires have burned 13,098 hectares in Alberta.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:40:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ontario's elementary teachers ramping up job action</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/05/26/elementary-teachers-to-ramp-up-job-action</Link>
        <Description>Training for the new sex-education curriculum and autism therapy are on the union’s naughty list as the province’s public elementary teachers get set to escalate job action.</Description>
        <MainBody>Teacher strikes ordered over
Toronto-
Training for the new sex-education curriculum and autism therapy are on the unions naughty list as the provinces public elementary teachers get set to escalate job action.
A Bargaining Bulletin issued to members of the Elementary Teachers Federation of Ontario (ETFO) Monday says that effective June 1, teachers will not participate in a number of tasks, in addition to those duties already withdrawn during the current work-to-rule campaign.
Teachers are being told not to participate in new curriculum training, including the controversial new sex-ed program that is to be launched in all schools this fall.
Training and workshops for Applied Behavioural Analysis (ABA), a program provided to children with autism, have also been put on ETFOs no-go list.
The move comes as collective bargaining with the major teacher unions continues to flounder.
Education Minister Liz Sandals said ETFO claims that its work-to-rule campaign is against school boards and the provincial government.
This is hurting children, Sandals said Tuesday. And I really am quite appalled that they would refuse to participate in promotion meetings, the sort of meetings where you talk about arranging what support a child thats leaving your classroom ... a special needs child, what support are they going to need. This is really hitting at kids.
Sandals rejected the idea of pausing the implementation of the new sex-ed curriculum even though not all teachers will have received training on it.
The ministry has completed regional and board level training on the curriculum and will put supportive documents online for teachers, she said.
Sandals downplayed concerns that the province is heading for a full strike in its Catholic and public elementary and secondary school boards in the fall.
We have three months to bargain, we have three months to find solutions, she said.
ETFO president Sam Hammond would not confirm the enhanced job action.
I can indicate that there has been no movement at all on the part of the government and OPSBA (the Ontario Public School Boards Association) to contact ETFO or to recommence bargaining, Hammond said. Despite the fact that our ETFO collective agreements expired nine months ago, OPSBA and the Liberal government do not seem interested in reaching a reasonable and fair collective agreement with ETFO.
ETFO advised its members to not complete any paperwork to the ministry for special grants or funding with the exception of applications on behalf of students with special needs.
Teachers are also told not to participate in preparation or completion of Grade 8 to Grade 9 Transition Reports, any grade to grade transition meetings or in-school meetings, or professional learning activities on the end-of-the-year PA Day.
Instead, teachers and OTs (occasional teachers) will use this time for their own self-directed activities within the classroom/school, the bulletin dated May 25 says.
No field trips should be booked for the 2015-16 instructional year, the memo says.
Elementary teachers are still participating in extracurricular programs and providing student marks for report cards, although ETFO told members not to provide comments.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
