<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="chathamdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:08:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; 1 adult killed, others injured</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/28/bus-carrying-british-schoolchildren-crashes-in-belgium-1-adult-killed-others-injured</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS -- A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, killing one adult chaperone and injuring the driver and some of the children, officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; 1 adult killed, others injured 0
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
Sunday, June 28, 2015       10:08:56 EDT AM
Rescuers stand next to a British bus, transporting 34 children and which overturned and crashed on a motorway, near the city of Middelkerke Belgium, June 28, 2015. REUTERS/Dominique Jauquet
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BRUSSELS -- A bus carrying British schoolchildren went off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast on Sunday, killing one adult chaperone and injuring the driver and some of the children, officials said.
Belgian highway authorities said the vehicle apparently went out of control, struck a bridge pillar on the E40 highway, then shot off the road. The bus was carrying around 40 passengers, including 34 British children from 11 to 13 years old, authorities said.
The Belgian federal prosecutor's office said all of the children survived the accident, but an adult passenger had been killed. The bus driver was also seriously injured.
Three adults and some of the children were sent to a local hospital for treatment. Others were transported to a centre in the coastal city of Middelkerke.
British authorities said they were aware of the crash and working with Belgian authorities to help the U.K. citizens.
The E-40 highway, a major thoroughfare that links Belgium's North Sea coast to the capital city of Brussels, was closed to traffic following the crash.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:41:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than 400 injured in explosion at Taiwan water park</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/fire-at-taiwan-water-park-injures-more-than-100-people</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI, Taiwan -- A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 400 people, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>British theme park crash victim has leg amputated
TAIPEI, Taiwan -- More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.
The fire late Saturday was sparked by an accidental explosion of a colored theatrical powder thrown from the stage in front of about 1,000 people, the local fire agency and media said. The powder for the one-time event called "Color Play Asia" ignited along the ground, mainly burning people's lower bodies, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command centre.
The exact cause of the fire was still being investigated, but Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo banned public activities that use the colored powder.
A total of 519 people were injured by the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, according to a statement from the city government's health bureau. It said that 419 remained hospitalized on Sunday afternoon, about half of whom were seriously injured, including 184 in intensive care. Apart from Taiwanese, the victims were four people from Hong Kong, two from the Chinese mainland and one each from Macau, Japan, Malaysia and Singapore. The nationalities of three other foreigners were not given.
President Ma Ying-jeou visited burns victims at a hospital in Taipei on Sunday afternoon and said authorities would do their best to ensure victims receive "the best medical care" and find out who was responsible for the "tragic incident."
Taiwan's Central News Agency said that police were questioning two park workers who had launched the powder as well as the party's on-site organizer and two technicians. They may face charges of professional negligence causing serious injuries and endangering the public, it said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:06:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Privately owned Texas town drops 'Bikinis' name</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/privately-owned-texas-town-drops-bikinis-name</Link>
        <Description>Bikinis, Texas, is no more. The privately owned town has reverted to Bankersmith, the name it had before it was bought by an Austin restaurateur whose chain requires waitresses to wear bikinis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Privately owned Texas town drops 'Bikinis' name 0
The Associated Press
Saturday, June 27, 2015       7:06:03 EDT PM
A waitress at the Texas restaurant Bikinis shows off the 2012 calendar in this photo from the restaurant's Facebook page. (Facebook)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
BANKERSMITH, Texas - Bikinis, Texas, is no more. The privately owned town has reverted to Bankersmith, the name it had before it was bought by an Austin restaurateur whose chain requires waitresses to wear bikinis.
Doug Guller bought the ghost town in 2012. The town was intended to become a tourist attraction tied to the restaurant chain.
Since acquiring the property, Guller has built a hall with a bar and sound and light system for weddings and corporate events.
The Austin American-Statesman reports that the name change is meant to appease neighbours, who have complained about rowdiness at events.
Guller says the property can hold about 3,000 people.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:19:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CNN spots 'ISIS' flag at Pride rally, actually pictures of dildos</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/cnn-spots-isis-flag-at-pride-rally-actually-pictures-of-dildos</Link>
        <Description>A clip of CNN misidentifying an "ISIS" flag, which actually displayed images of sex toys, went viral Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Canoe.com
Saturday, June 27, 2015       4:19:11 EDT PM
CNN misidentified this flag as belonging to the Islamic State. In reality it showed images of sex toys. (YouTube)
Change text size for the story
Print
A clip of CNN misidentifying an "ISIS" flag, which actually displayed images of sex toys, went viral Saturday.
The flag was spotted by CNN International's Lucy Pawle during the Pride parade in London, England.
"This man dressed in black and white was waving what appears to be a very bad mimicry, but a clear attempt to mimic, the ISIS flag. The black and white flag with the distinctive lettering," Pawle said on-air over photos of the flag. "If you look at the flag closely, it's clearly not Arabic. In fact, it looks like it could be gobbledygook."
The "lettering" was in fact silhouettes of various dildos and butt plugs.
CNN has since removed the video from its website.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:06:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charleston shooting suspect: From troubled kid to racial radicalization</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/charleston-shooting-suspect-from-troubled-kid-to-racial-radicalization</Link>
        <Description>The people who know Dylann Storm Roof -- the people who watched his progression from a sweet child to a disturbed young man -- are struggling with guilt. How could they have missed the signs? Could they have done something to prevent the deaths of nine innocents at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church?</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman climbs flagpole, removes Confederate flag
CHAPIN, S.C. - The people who know Dylann Storm Roof -- the people who watched his progression from a sweet child to a disturbed young man -- are struggling with guilt. How could they have missed the signs? Could they have done something to prevent the deaths of nine innocents at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church?
How did it all happen?
Roof himself offers no answers. He sits in North Charleston's Sheriff Al Cannon Detention Center, charged with the murders.
But talk to his friends and family, and a portrait emerges of a troubled and confused 21-year-old, often drunk and occasionally threatening violence as he alternated between partying with black friends and spouting white power slogans to white friends. Court documents and nearly two dozen interviews show Roof's early childhood was troubled and confused as well, as he grew up in an unstable, broken home amid allegations of marital abuse and infidelity.
He apparently fell under the thrall of racist websites. But how and why are questions that remain unanswered.
As a 4-year-old, "He was so sweet and bright," recalls Patricia Hastings, who was once his step-grandmother.
Seventeen years later, she is among many who are trying to figure out what happened to Dylann Roof.
------
There is little dispute his childhood was difficult.
Franklin Bennett Roof was a 25-year-old carpenter working for a home construction company, when he met 29-year-old Amelia "Amy" Cowles, a recent divorcee, barely 5-feet (1.5-meters) tall with blonde hair to her ankles. He was the son of a prominent Columbia attorney; she was a bartender at the Silver Fox. They married in 1988 and had a daughter, Amber, four months later.
They separated in 1990, and divorced a year later. A few years later they briefly reconciled, but split again before Dylann was born on April 3, 1994.
Four years later, Franklin Roof married Paige Hastings.
In an affidavit filed in her 2009 divorce, Paige said she became a surrogate mother for the children: "I raised his kids from a very young age, took them to all of their activities."
Patricia Hastings said her daughter loved Dylann and Amber "unconditionally as her own." She said Amy Roof would leave them in Paige's care with little notice, even though Paige had her own new baby, their half-sister Morgan.
Paige cut Dylann's hair in the bowl cut he still wears; she took Amber to college orientation because "both parents were unavailable," Paige's friend Leslie McArver wrote in an affidavit.
As he grew, Dylann exhibited obsessive compulsive behaviour, Hastings said. He would obsess over germs, and insisted on having his hair cut in that same style, Hastings said.
Still, he played video games, interacted with the family, attended church and Bible camp.
But things grew stressful at home. Money was a problem so Paige took a part-time job. Franklin Roof was often out of town.
Franklin Roof was verbally abusive, Paige's friend Carol Elliott wrote in an affidavit.
After Paige filed for divorce, Franklin Roof hired a private investigator to shadow her, revealing she was having an affair, according to the court documents.
The divorce was granted in 2009. Hastings recalls that her daughter told her she felt guilty leaving Dylann.
------
Roof began having trouble in school. He failed the ninth grade twice, then dropped out for good in 2010.
People around him worried about his lack of direction. He was spending too much time in his room in front of the computer. They pushed him to get a job, but he was unhappy, his friends said.
Over the past year, Roof became increasingly unhinged.
In February, worried employees at a Columbia shopping mall called the police when Roof, dressed in black, asked them suspicious questions about when stores closed and when they left for the night, according to court records. He was arrested on a misdemeanour charge of possessing the drug Suboxone.
In March, a police officer searched his car and found six empty 40-round magazines for an AR-15 assault rifle, according to a police report. Roof said he was saving up to buy an AR-15, the report said.
In April, he was arrested again on a charge of trespassing at the mall, where he'd been banned.
He had become a recluse. He never responded to an invitation to Amber's wedding -- which had been planned for last weekend but was postponed after the massacre. He also appears to have begun a journey into the world of Internet hate sites, according to the Southern Poverty Law Center, which tracks those sites.
"If you don't have much of a social life in the real world, this is a way for you to interact with other individuals and be affirmed and encouraged," said Keegan Hanks, of the Southern Poverty Law Center.
Roof appeared to be "AryanBlood1488," who began posting on the white supremacist site the Daily Stormer in August, Hanks said. Over several months, "AryanBlood1488" described how he typed "black on white crime" into a Google search, found the Council of Conservative Citizens site and descended into radicalism from there.
Kyle Rogers, a member of the Council of Conservative Citizens who lives in Summerville, South Carolina, denied Roof had any direct dealings with the group.
On Feb. 9, according to Internet records, someone using Roof's name, address and phone number registered a new website. On it, were photos of Roof at a cemetery for Confederate soldiers who died fighting for the pro-slavery, secessionist southern states in the American Civil War, brandishing a gun, burning the American flag and spitting on it. The site also contained a manifesto explaining an indoctrination into radical racism.
On his 21st birthday in April, Roof bought himself a present: a .45-calibre Glock semi-automatic handgun with a high-point laser for accuracy.
------
Paige has remarried; her last name is now Mann. She refused to talk to the AP, as did Franklin and Amy Roof.
Mann had barely seen her former stepson since her nasty divorce. But last month, when she went to pick up her daughter at her ex-husband's house, he was there.
According to Patricia Hastings, recounting recent conversations with her daughter, Roof was quieter than he used to be; he looked distant, lost. He was no longer the sweet blond kid she helped raise for nearly a decade. As she was getting ready to leave, Roof, not one for affection, hugged her tight.
"It was like he was saying goodbye," Hastings said.
The next time Mann saw him, it was on television as the man accused of the killings.
Roof's friend Joseph Meek said he too is replaying, reinterpreting, his memories of Roof over the last months.
"I just wish he would have talked to me. I wish he would have told me what was bothering him. I would have done something. This will stay with me, with all of us," he said.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:56:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ohio man, 73, rides Kings Island roller coaster for 12,000th time</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/ohio-man-73-rides-kings-island-roller-coaster-for-12000th-time</Link>
        <Description>A 73-year-old man has taken his 12,000th ride on his favourite roller coaster at King's Island amusement park in Ohio.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ohio man, 73, rides Kings Island roller coaster for 12,000th time 0
The Associated Press
Saturday, June 27, 2015       2:56:30 EDT PM
A roller-coaster. (Fotolia)
Change text size for the story
Print
Report an error
MASON, Ohio - A 73-year-old man has taken his 12,000th ride on his favourite roller coaster at Kings Island amusement park in Ohio.
The park says Gary Coleman of Monfort Heights took the milestone ride in the front row of the Diamondback roller coaster on Monday.
The retired minister has made 493 trips to the theme park outside of Cincinnati since 2009, when the 230-foot (70-meter) steel roller coaster opened. It's the tallest and fastest roller coaster at Kings Island and reaches speeds of 80 mph (130 kph).
Coleman says he's loved coasters since childhood. He says he plans to continue increasing his ride count as long as he remains healthy enough to do so.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:31:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Devastating heat wave in Pakistan kills 1,233 people, official says</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/devastating-heat-wave-in-pakistan-kills-1233-people-official-says</Link>
        <Description>A devastating weeklong heat wave in Pakistan's southern port city of Karachi killed 1,233 people, an official said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistan heat wave kills more than 1,000
ISLAMABAD - A devastating weeklong heat wave in Pakistan's southern port city of Karachi killed 1,233 people, an official said.
Nazar Mohammad Bozdar, operations director at the Provincial Disaster Management Authority, said about 65,000 heatstroke patients were treated by doctors at all of Karachi's hospitals since June 20 when the heat wave struck Sindh province, where Karachi is the provincial capital.
He told The Associated Press that 1,923 patients with heat-related ailments were still being treated.
"The government quickly responded by making arrangements for the treatment of heatstroke patients and the situation has improved now," he said.
Pakistan's deadliest heat wave on record coincided with the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, when Pakistan's Muslim majority observed a dawn-to-dusk fast.
The temperatures in Karachi came down to 34 degrees Celsius (93 degrees Fahrenheit) after reaching 45 degrees Celsius (113 degrees Fahrenheit) a week ago amid chronic power outages, which forced many residents to spend nights outdoors.
The heat wave shocked many Pakistanis just weeks after soaring temperatures caused nearly 2,200 deaths in neighbouring India.
Since then, it has raised fears that South Asia could be seeing some of the devastating effects of human-caused climate change.
On Saturday, TV footage showed a charity burying several unidentified bodies of people who died earlier this week because of the heatstroke. Pakistani television stations reported that several unidentified bodies were buried by the Edhi Foundation charity because local morgues were overflowing.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:07:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York manhunt for prison escapee heats up after accomplice killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/new-york-manhunt-for-prison-escapee-heats-up-after-accomplice-killed</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of law enforcement officers hunting for a convicted murderer who escaped from a New York state maximum security prison scoured an area of near the Canadian border on Saturday, a day after a fellow escapee was killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>N.Y. fugitive killed by police: Report
MALONE - A manhunt for a convicted murderer who escaped from a New York state maximum security prison focused on a rural area near the Canadian border on Saturday, a day after his fellow escapee was killed.
David Sweat, 35, remained at large three weeks after taking flight from the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, New York. His accomplice on Friday was shot dead by authorities near Malone, New York.
After Richard Matt was killed by U.S. Border Patrol officers, a tight security perimeter was set up in the area,  where Sweat was believed to be holed up.
About 1,200 federal, state and local law enforcement officers, were searching through a 22 square-mile (57 sq km) area along a highway between the towns of Malone and Duane in northern New York, New York State Police said in a statement.
At checkpoints on the zone's perimeter, rifle-carrying officers stopped vehicles. As darkness approached, halogen lights illuminated makeshift checkpoints.
Police in vehicle caravans spent the day passing over roads, as officers with dogs combed the ground and helicopters patrolled overhead.
Franklin County Sheriff Kevin Mulverhill spoke hopefully about finding Sweat, who was sentenced to life without parole in 2003 for killing a New York sheriff's deputy.
"After three weeks, he would have to be fatigued," Mulverhill said. "He's not getting regular meals, not getting good sleep."
Authorities declined to say why they thought Sweat was still in the general area where Matt was killed. Malone is 27 miles (43 km) northwest of the Clinton prison where the convicts were discovered missing on June 6.
Police tracked Matt to the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins.
On Friday, after Matt apparently fired a shot at a passing camping trailer, officers spotted and confronted him outside a cabin, New York State Police Superintendent Joseph D'Amico told reporters.
Border Patrol agents warned Matt to drop the shotgun he was holding, and shot and killed him when he failed to comply, police said.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York.
To stage their elaborate prison break, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and slithered through a steam pipe beneath the prison before popping out through a manhole.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them. Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop.
Mitchell, who also was charged in connection with the escape, told investigators the inmates expected her to pick them up outside the prison walls and drive a getaway car.
When she instead checked into a local hospital with a panic attack, the escapees were apparently forced to take off on foot through rugged, mountainous terrain.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:25:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman takes down Confederate flag in front of South Carolina statehouse</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/27/woman-takes-down-confederate-flag-in-front-of-south-carolina-statehouse</Link>
        <Description>An activist climbed a flagpole outside the South Carolina state capitol early on Saturday and took down the Confederate flag, state officials said, a day after U.S. President Barack Obama called the banner a symbol of racial oppression.</Description>
        <MainBody>From troubled kid to racial radicalization
CHARLESTON, S.C. - An activist climbed a flagpole outside the South Carolina state capitol early on Saturday and took down the Confederate flag, state officials said, a day after U.S. President Barack Obama called the banner a symbol of racial oppression.
Two people were arrested and charged with defacing a monument, the South Carolina Department of Public Safety said in a statement. The banner was replaced within an hour, it said.
The department identified them as 30-year-olds Brittany Ann Byuarim Newsome and James Ian Tyson, from North Carolina.
The Civil War-era flag has been a focal point in the United States after the fatal shooting last week of nine African Americans during a Bible study session at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston.
On mobile? Click here for video of the flag being taken down
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley was applauded on Saturday at the funeral of one of the victims, librarian Cynthia Hurd, when she told mourners, "I am sorry this happened on my watch, but we will make it right."
Haley, who has attended all four of the funerals so far for the victims, on Monday led calls for the flag's removal saying that while it was an important part of South Carolina's past, it "does not represent the future of our great state."
The suspect in the shootings, Dylann Roof, 21, had posed with a Confederate flag in photos posted on a website that also displayed a racist manifesto.
A group of local activists said they organized the removal of the flag, which by law flies at a memorial on the Statehouse grounds honoring soldiers who fought on the side of the pro-slavery Confederacy during the 1860-65 American Civil War.
"We could not sit by and watch the victims of the Charleston Massacre be laid to rest while the inspiration for their deaths continues to fly above their caskets," an activist group organized under the Twitter tag #KeepItDown said in a statement.
At a funeral for the slain Emanuel church pastor in Charleston on Friday, Obama called the banner "a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation".
"For too long we were blind to the pain that the Confederate flag stirred in too many of our citizens," Obama said in his eulogy for Reverend Clementa Pinckney, 41.
The South Carolina Legislature is expected to begin debate next week on removing the flag from the memorial.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 07:27:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly gun attack at Tunisian beachside hotel</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/deadly-gun-attack-at-tunisian-beachside-hotel</Link>
        <Description>At least 27 people, including foreign tourists, were killed when at least one gunman opened fire on a Tunisian beachside hotel in the popular resort of Sousse on Friday, an interior ministry spokesman said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in terror attack
SOUSSE, Tunisia - A gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire at a Tunisian hotel on Friday with a rifle he had hidden in an umbrella, killing 39 people including Britons, Germans and Belgians as they lounged at the beach in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Terrified tourists ran for cover after the gunfire and an explosion erupted at the Imperial Marhaba in Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis, before police shot the gunman dead, witnesses and security officials said.
The bodies of several tourists lay crumbled where they fell in the sand, covered with yellow towels and blankets among the plastic white sunbeds. Blood smeared stone steps leading from the hotel main area.
"This was always a safe place but today was horror," said an Irish tourist who gave only his first name, Anthony. "He started on the beach and went to the lobby, killing in cold blood."
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, on a day in which a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found in France, a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait and at least 145 civilians were reported killed by Islamic State militants in northern Syria.
In a statement on social media, Islamic State claimed responsibility for the Tunisian attack. It had urged its followers to step up assaults during Ramadan.
Twitter accounts that support Islamic State released three photos they said showed the gunman. A man is seen from behind walking down a street and holding an assault rifle, though his identity and the location are unclear.
"Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yihya al-Kairouni, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures," the statement said. It said he had attacked a "bordel" and killed 40 "infidels'.
After pulling out a weapon hidden inside an umbrella, the assailant strolled through the hotel grounds, opening fire left and right at the pool and beach, reloading his weapon several times and tossing an explosive, witnesses said.
A security source said another bomb was found on his body, which lay with a Kalashnikov assault rifle where he was shot.
Prime Minister Habib Essid said his government plans within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control, for inciting violence, and crack down on financing for certain associations, as a countermeasure.
Rafik Chelli, a senior interior ministry official, said the gunman killed was unknown to authorities and not on any watchlist of potential jihadists. A security source named him as Saifeddine Rezgui, a 23-year-old electrical engineering student.
Local radio said police captured a second gunman, but officials did not immediately confirm the arrest or his role in the attack.
"It was just one attacker," said a hotel worker at the site. "He was a young guy dressed in shorts like he was a tourist himself."
'RUN, RUN, RUN!'
It was the worst attack in Tunisia's modern history and the second major massacre this year following the Islamist militant assault on Tunis Bardo museum when gunmen killed 21 foreign visitors.
A health ministry statement said British, German and Belgian nationals were among the 39 dead. The health minister told French radio 36 others were wounded in the shooting.
At least five British citizens were among the dead, Britain's Foreign Minister Philip Hammond said. Ireland's foreign ministry said at least one Irish citizen was killed.
Tunisia, which has been hailed as a model of democratic transition since its 2011 'Arab Spring' uprising, is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world. Its beach resorts and nightclubs on the Mediterranean are popular with foreigners.
Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because of their open Western lifestyles and tolerance of alcohol.
Irishwoman Elizabeth O'Brien, who was staying at a neighbouring hotel with her two sons, said there was panic on the beach when gunfire erupted.
"I honestly thought it was fireworks and then when I saw people running... I thought, my God, it is shooting," she told Irish radio station RTE. "The waiters and the security on the beach started to say 'Run, run, run!'"
CATASTROPHE
Islamic State made some claim to the Bardo museum attack, but authorities blamed possible splinter fighters from the Okba Ibn Nafaa, a brigade of al Qaeda-affiliated fighters, operating in the Chaambi mountains along the Algerian border.
In Sousse, many tourists were already packing their suitcases into busses and checking out of hotels to leave after the attack.
German tour operator TUI said on Friday it was organising flights for tourists wishing to return from Tunisia and said those who booked Tunisian holidays for this summer could rebook or cancel the trips free of charge.
Sousse, alongside nearby Hammamet and the island of Djerba, is the heartland of Tunisia's most popular beach resorts, drawing visitors from Europe and neighbouring North African countries like Algeria.
Six million tourists, mostly Europeans, visited Tunisia's beaches, desert treks and medina souks last year, providing seven percent of its gross domestic product, most of its foreign currency revenues and more jobs than anything but farming.
"This is a catastrophe for the economy," Tourism Minister Salma Loumi said. "Our losses will be great, but the loss of human life was even greater."
Since its 2011 uprising to oust autocrat Zine el-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has been praised for its peaceful democratic transition bringing free elections and a new constitution seen as a model for the region.
But the country has also struggled with the rise of Islamist movements as ultra-conservative preachers took advantage of the upheaval and young democracy to take over mosques and spread their hardline message.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have left the country to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighbouring Libya, where some have set up jihadist training camps and promised to return to attack their homeland.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:56:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Supreme Court rules in favour of gay marriage nationwide</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/us-supreme-court-rules-in-favour-of-gay-marriage-nationwide</Link>
        <Description>The Supreme Court ruled on Friday that the U.S. Constitution provides same-sex couples the right to marry in a historic triumph for the American gay rights movement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Raw video: Tory on gay marriage
WASHINGTON - The Supreme Court ruled on Friday that the U.S. Constitution provides same-sex couples the right to marry, handing a historic triumph to the American gay rights movement.
The court ruled 5-4 that the Constitution's guarantees of due process and equal protection under the law mean that states cannot ban same-sex marriages. With the landmark ruling, gay marriage becomes legal in all 50 states.
Immediately after the decision, same-sex couples in many of the states where gay marriage had been banned headed to county clerks' offices for marriage licenses as officials in several states said they would respect the ruling.
President Barack Obama, appearing in the White House Rose Garden, hailed the ruling as a milestone in American justice that arrived "like a thunderbolt."
"This ruling is a victory for America," said Obama, the first sitting president to support gay marriage. "This decision affirms what millions of Americans already believe in their hearts. When all Americans are treated as equal, we are all more free."
As night fell, the White House was lit in rainbow colors - a symbol of gay pride - to mark the high court's decision.
The ruling, the culmination of a long legal fight by gay rights advocates, follows steady gains in public approval in recent years for same-sex marriage. In 2004 Massachusetts became the first state to legalize gay marriage. But the decision may provoke fresh legal fights in some conservative, Republican-governed states.
Justice Anthony Kennedy, writing on behalf of the court, said the hope of gay people intending to marry "is not to be condemned to live in loneliness, excluded from one of civilization's oldest institutions. They ask for equal dignity in the eyes of the law. The Constitution grants them that right."
"Without the recognition, stability and predictability marriage offers, their children suffer the stigma of knowing their families are somehow lesser," Kennedy wrote.
Kennedy, a conservative who often casts the deciding vote in close cases, was joined in the majority by the court's four liberal justices.
Appointed by Republican President Ronald Reagan in 1988, Kennedy has now authored all four of the court's major gay rights rulings, with the first in 1996.
The ruling is the Supreme Court's most important expansion of marriage rights in the United States since its landmark 1967 ruling in the case Loving v. Virginia that struck down state laws barring interracial marriages.
At least two states, Louisiana and Mississippi, said they would not immediately issue marriage licenses to same-sex couples while awaiting legal formalities. Supreme Court rulings generally take 25 days to go into effect.
'THREAT TO AMERICAN DEMOCRACY'
In a blistering dissenting opinion, conservative Justice Antonin Scalia said the decision shows the court is a "threat to American democracy." The ruling "says that my ruler and the ruler of 320 million Americans coast-to-coast is a majority of the nine lawyers on the Supreme Court," Scalia added.
Conservative Chief Justice John Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in his 10 years on the court. Roberts said although there are strong policy arguments in same-sex marriage, it was not the court's role to force states to change their marriage laws.
"Five lawyers have closed the debate and enacted their own vision of marriage as a matter of constitutional law," Roberts wrote.
The dissenters raised concerns about the impact of the case on people opposed to same-sex marriage on religious grounds.
While the ruling only affects state laws and religious institutions can still choose whether to marry same-sex couples, Roberts predicted future legal conflicts.
"Hard questions arise when people of faith exercise religion in ways that may be seen to conflict with the new right to same-sex marriage," Roberts said.
There were 13 state bans in place, while another state, Alabama, had contested a court ruling that lifted the ban there.
The ruling is the latest milestone in the gay rights movement. In 2010, Obama signed a law allowing gays to serve openly in the U.S. military. In 2013, the high court ruled unconstitutional a 1996 U.S. law that declared for the purposes of federal benefits marriage was defined as between one man and one woman.
Reaction came swiftly. James Obergefell, the Ohio man who was the lead plaintiff in the case, told a cheering crowd outside the Supreme Court, "Today's ruling from the Supreme Court affirms what millions across this country already know to be true in our hearts - our love is equal, that the four words etched onto the front of the Supreme Court - equal justice under law - apply to us, too."
Obama telephoned Obergefell to offer congratulations.
Hundreds of gay rights supporters celebrated outside the courthouse with whoops and cries of "U-S-A!" and "Love is love" as the decision came down.
In Ann Arbor, Michigan, another of the plaintiffs, April DeBeor, told cheering supporters, "To my beautiful children, we did this for you," referring to her adopted children.
"Love won," added popular comedian and talk show host Ellen DeGeneres, who is gay.
'JUDICIAL TYRANNY'
Conservatives denounced the ruling. Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee called it "an out-of-control act of unconstitutional judicial tyranny."
Wisconsin Republican Governor Scott Walker, who is expected to run for president, called for amending the U.S. Constitution to allow states to again ban same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Governor Greg Abbott said, "Marriage was defined by God. No man can redefine it."
Archbishop Joseph Kurtz of Louisville, Kentucky, president of the U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops, said, "It is profoundly immoral and unjust for the government to declare that two people of the same sex can constitute a marriage."
Opponents say same-sex marriage's legality should be decided by states, not judges. Some opponents argue it is an affront to traditional marriage between a man and a woman and that the Bible condemns homosexuality.
Gay marriage is also gaining acceptance in other Western countries. Last month in Ireland, voters backed same-sex marriage by a landslide in a referendum that marked a dramatic social shift in the traditionally Roman Catholic country.
Ireland followed several Western European countries including Britain, France and Spain in allowing gay marriage, which is also legal in South Africa, Brazil and Canada. But homosexuality remains taboo and often illegal in many parts of Africa and Asia.
The Supreme Court's ruling came in a consolidated case pulling together challenges filed by same-sex couples to gay marriage bans in Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee.
The Obama administration argued on the side of the same-sex marriage advocates.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:47:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escaped N.Y. prisoner killed by police: Report</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/escaped-prisoners-heading-for-canada-ny-cops</Link>
        <Description>Richard Matt, one of two prisoners who escaped from a New York state prison three weeks ago, has been shot and killed, The New York Times reported on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>New York offers $100K reward for escaped convicts
MALONE, N.Y. - Law enforcement officers on Friday shot and killed one of two prisoners who broke out of a maximum security prison in New York three weeks ago and were pursuing a second escapee near the Canadian border, authorities said.
Richard Matt, a 49-year-old convicted murderer, was killed by U.S. Border Patrol officers after he was spotted in a wooded area in the town of Malone, the New York State Police said.
Police were still combing the vicinity for Matt's accomplice, David Sweat, a 35-year-old who was imprisoned for killing a sheriff's deputy.
"You never want to see anyone lose their life, but I would remind people that Mr. Matt was an escaped murderer from a state prison," New York Governor Andrew Cuomo said at a news conference. "Mr. Matt killed two people that we know about."
Authorities said they have no evidence to confirm the whereabouts of the second escapee but have no reason to believe he was not with Matt recently and still in the area.
Malone lies 27 miles (43 km) northwest of the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, where the convicts staged their elaborate escape and were discovered missing on June 6. The manhunt has involved as many as 1,100 law enforcement officers.
Dozens of law enforcement vehicles, some of them equipped with floodlights, had converged on the area, signaling the search for Sweat would go on all night if necessary.
Jeff Tough, who lives within the search perimeter across from Lake Titus, said state troopers were lining State Route 30 at regular intervals.
"I feel relieved, to be honest," Malone resident Matt Maguire said while stopped at a roadblock after learning one of the escapees had been killed. "Everybody's been on edge for 20 days."
CABINS BURGLARIZED
Police started focusing the search in the Malone area, just south of the Canadian border, when two burglaries were reported this week at backwoods cabins, and items believed to have been dropped by Matt were found, said Joseph D'Amico, superintendent of the New York State Police.
Earlier Friday, authorities were alerted to a third break-in near Malone. When officers arrived at that cabin, they confronted Matt in the woods outside, D'Amico said, and warned the convict to drop the shotgun he was holding.
When Matt failed to comply, the Border Patrol agents shot and killed him, even though the escapee fired no shots of his own, the superintendent said. He declined to elaborate.
In making their escape three weeks ago, Matt and Sweat cut through the walls of their adjoining cells and sneaked along the catwalk to a steam pipe, slithered through the pipe and popped out of a manhole outside the prison walls.
Two prison workers have been charged with aiding them. Gene Palmer, 57, a corrections officer for 27 years, was suspended without pay from his job, the New York State Department of Corrections and Community Supervision said.
He is accused of bringing hacksaw blades and a screwdriver bit to the inmates, hidden in frozen hamburger meat supplied by Joyce Mitchell, 51, a training supervisor in the prison tailor shop. She also has been charged in connection with the escape.
Palmer also let the men slip behind their cell walls onto a prison catwalk to hide contraband and alter electrical wiring so they could cook in their cells, according to court documents.
Matt was convicted in the 1997 torture, murder and dismemberment of his boss in Tonawanda, New York, and was sentenced to 25 years to life.
Sweat was serving a life sentence after his conviction in the shooting death of a Broome County Sheriff's deputy on July 4, 2002.
Immediately after the escape, the manhunt centered on an area east of Dannemora along the shore of Lake Champlain. Last weekend, the search shifted to New York's Southern Tier along its border with Pennsylvania. Officers were deployed to that area, where Sweat once lived, after a series of unconfirmed sightings of the pair, but the effort proved fruitless.
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 02:16:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State suicide bomber kills 25, wounds 202 in Kuwait mosque</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/islamic-state-suicide-bomber-kills-more-than-10-in-kuwait-mosque</Link>
        <Description>KUWAIT - A suicide bomber blew himself up in a packed Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, killing more than ten people, the governor of Kuwait City and a witness said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in terror attack
KUWAIT - A suicide bomber killed 27 people when he blew himself up inside a packed Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, the health ministry and witnesses said, the first attack of its kind in the major oil-exporting state.
The Islamic State militant group claimed responsibility for the attack, which also wounded 227 people according to the interior ministry, in the district of Sawaber in the eastern part of the Kuwaiti capital.
Parliament member Khalil al-Salih, who was at the mosque when the attack occurred, said worshippers were kneeling in prayer when the bomber walked into the Imam al-Sadeq Mosque and detonated his explosives, destroying walls and the ceiling.
"It was obvious from the suicide bomber's body that he was young. He walked into the prayer hall during sujood (kneeling in prayer). He looked ...in his 20s, I saw him with my own eyes," he told Reuters by telephone.
"The explosion was really hard. The ceiling and wall got destroyed," he said, adding that more than 2,000 people from the Shi'ite Ja'afari sect were praying at the mosque.
The mosque preacher was quoted by state news agency KUNA as saying that the attack targeted worshippers at the back of the mosque, towards the end of the Friday prayers.
It was the first suicide bombing at a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait and worst militant attack in the country for many years.
Shi'ites comprise between 15 and 30 percent of the predominantly Sunni Muslim Gulf Arab state, where members of both communities are known to live side by side with little apparent friction.
Security forces quickly sealed off the perimeter of the mosque while rescue workers carried the wounded to hospital.
Kuwait National Petroleum Company (KNPC) spokesman Khaled al-Asousi told Reuters that the company was carrying out "extra monitoring and searches" to boost security around oil facilities after the attack.
Islamic State named the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said in a statement posted on social media that he had targeted a "temple of the rejectionists" -- a term it generally uses to refer to Shi'ites, whom it regards as heretics.
Islamic State had urged its followers on Tuesday to step up attacks during the Ramadan fasting month against Christians, Shi'ites and Sunni Muslims fighting with a U.S.-led coalition against the ultra-hardline jihadist group.
Also on Friday, a gunman killed 37 people including Western tourists at a beach resort in Tunisia, and in France a decapitated body covered in Arabic writing was found after an attacker rammed his car into a gas container, triggering an explosion.
There was no evidence the three attacks were deliberately coordinated. But coming so close together on the same day in three countries on three different continents, they underscored the far-reaching, fast-growing influence of Islamic State, Western politicians said.
BLOOD DONATIONS
The Health Ministry said Kuwait's blood bank had opened additional centres to receive blood donations and it urged citizens with non-urgent medical needs to avoid the emergency units.
Pictures posted on social media and Kuwaiti news websites showed men in traditional white robes smeared with blood outside the mosque. A second photo showed a row of victims wrapped in white body bags and a third the collapsed ceiling of the mosque.
Kuwait declared Saturday a day of mourning.
Emir Sheikh Sabah al-Ahmed al-Sabah, who visited the damaged mosque after the attack, said the bombing violated the sanctity of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan as well as Islamic law forbidding the shedding of the blood of innocents.
"National unity is a protective fence for the security of the nation," Sheikh Sabah said.
Prime Minister Sheikh Jaber al-Mubarak al-Sabah, who visited the wounded at the Emiri Hospital, also condemned the bombing as an attempt to jeopardise Kuwait's national unity.
"This incident targets our internal front, our national unity," Sheikh Jaber told Reuters outside the hospital. "But this is too difficult for them and we are much stronger than that."
Islamic State has recently twice targeted Shi'ite mosques in neighbouring Saudi Arabia and carried out attacks against members of the sect's Zaydi branch in Yemen.
Kuwait recently approved legislation allowing for security cameras to be placed at public places.
Yaqoub Al-Sanea, the minister of justice, religious endowments and Islamic affairs, said that despite Friday's attack, "Kuwait will remain an oasis of security for all groups of Kuwaiti society and all sects. The government is taking many procedures to protect prayers and mosques."
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 23:54:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/france-factory-attack-severed-head-left-near-arabic-banners</Link>
        <Description>A severed head covered in Arabic 
writing was found at a U.S. gas company 
in southeast France on Friday, police 
sources and French media said, after 
two assailants rammed a car into the 
premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>French beheading suspect was "normal neighbour"
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER - A delivery man with known Islamist connections beheaded his boss and left the body, daubed with Arabic writing, at the site of a U.S.-owned gas factory in southeast France before trying to blow up the complex.
The assailant rammed his delivery van into a warehouse containing gas canisters, triggering an initial explosion, and was arrested minutes later as he tried to open canisters containing flammable chemicals, prosecutors said on Friday.
Police found the head of the victim, the 54-year-old manager of the transport firm that employed the suspect, dangling from a fence.
"The head was discovered hanging on the factory's wire fence, framed by two flags that included references to the shahada, or (Muslim) profession of faith," Paris public prosecutor Francois Molins told a news conference.
France is still coming to terms with attacks by Islamist gunmen who killed 17 people in January at a satirical weekly newspaper and a Jewish food store.
The latest attack occurred on the same day that a gunman killed at least 37 people at a Tunisian beachside hotel and an Islamic State suicide bomber killed two dozen and wounded more than 200 at a mosque in Kuwait.
"There is no other link other than to say that terrorism is our common enemy," said President Francois Hollande, returning to Paris from an EU summit in Brussels.
"There should be no doubt as to our country's ability to protect itself and remain vigilant," he said, announcing a tightening of national security to levels he said were unprecedented in recent decades.
Hollande said there were inscriptions on the headless body, and police sources said they were in Arabic, but officials did not reveal their content.
FATHER OF THREE
No group claimed responsibility for the French attack and the motive was unknown.
The attacker was injured in the blast and arrested on the site. His wife, sister and a third person were taken into custody for questioning.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve named the suspect as Yassin Sahli. He said Sahli did not have a criminal record but had been under surveillance from 2006 to 2008 on suspicion of having become radicalised by Islamist associates.
The attack occurred at an industrial zone near the town of Saint-Quentin Fallavier to the south of the city of Lyon. Its air, rail and road links have made it one of Europe's major logistics hubs, with through-traffic of 5,000 trucks a day.
Sources close to the investigation said Sahli was a 35-year-old professional driver who lived in the Lyon suburbs. Europe 1 radio interviewed a woman they identified as his wife.
"In the morning he left for work and didn't come home between noon and 2. I was waiting for him," she told Europe 1 radio, saying she and her family of three children lived normal lives as Muslims. "My heart is about to give out."
French television filming outside Sahli's apartment showed pictures of police leading out a woman, her head covered by a blanket, into a waiting car. Forensic police were carrying out searches on the ground-floor apartment.
"They are a very normal family," a neighbour who gave her name as Brigitte said. "I only talked with madame, he didn't say hello or goodbye," the 46-year-old housewife told Reuters.
Police questioned employees for several hours at the transport company run by the victim and seized the suspect's car. A cleaner at a neighbouring business described the victim of the attack as a friendly and polite man, "always saying good morning or good evening and have a nice weekend to his staff".
UNPRECEDENTED THREAT
The attack underlined again the difficulty for authorities across Europe and elsewhere of protecting so-called "soft" targets against strikes by assailants operating by themselves or in small undercover cells.
France, which has contributed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In January, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since then.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalised by Islamist fighters, officials have long said France has never seen a higher threat level.
The site of Friday's attack belonged to Air Products , a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company. It was immediately ringfenced by police and emergency services.
Air Products said its crisis and emergency response teams were "working closely with all relevant authorities" and that it had increased security at its installations around the world.
The company's chairman and chief executive is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a U.S. Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born. Mainly Shi'ite Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State.
According to French regulations applicable to zones where gases and chemicals are handled, the site would have been required to implement security arrangements at the low end of the European Union's so-called "Seveso" scale, named after the location of an industrial accident in northern Italy in 1976.
Prosecutor Molins said closed-circuit TV images showed the attacker arriving at the site. Because his vehicle was authorised to make deliveries, it was allowed through the gates.
The CCTV cameras lost track of his movements for several minutes, then picked up the van again as it accelerated towards a warehouse within the premises. A loud explosion was heard.
When emergency services arrived a few minutes later, they found the headless body of the victim by the van and a knife nearby. They overpowered the suspect as he was opening bottles of acetone, a flammable liquid chemical.
Cazeneuve said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around all sensitive sites and Hollande announced that security arrangements in the region would be placed at their highest level for the next three days.
Image: 1 of 14
Previous Next
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015. A decapitated head covered in Arabic writing was found at a a site belonged to Air Products, a U.S.-based industrial gases technology company, in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.  REUTERS/Emmanuel Foudrot
Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:12:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French beheading suspect was "normal neighbour"</title>
        <Link>http://www.chathamdailynews.ca/2015/06/26/french-beheading-suspect-was-normal-neighbour</Link>
        <Description>SAINT-PRIEST, France - When suburban deliveryman Yassin Sahli set off for work on Friday, his wife said it seemed just like any other day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in terror attack
SAINT-PRIEST, France - When suburban deliveryman Yassin Sahli set off for work on Friday, his wife said it seemed just like any other day.
Within hours, the 35-year-old father of three was arrested on suspicion of beheading his boss, then ramming their van into an industrial gases site in southeast France, setting off an explosion that authorities called an attempted act of terrorism.
"Yesterday he was at work, he came home as usual. We spent a normal evening and in the morning he left for work and didn't come home between noon and 2. I was waiting for him," a woman identified as his wife told Europe 1 radio.
Sources close to the investigation said the wife, who has not been officially named, was subsequently arrested and was being held by police for questioning.
Yassin Sahli was named as the chief suspect by Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve in a brief statement at the site of the attack in the town of Saint-Quentin Fallavier, 30 km (20 miles) south of Lyon.
Very little has been officially released on his background.
Yet according to his wife's brief radio interview, theirs was an ordinary Muslim family living in the Lyon suburb of Saint-Priest, an account shared by neighbours who said contact with Sahli was limited to simple greetings.
He and his wife lived with their three children, aged between six and nine, on the ground floor of a three-storey, nondescript social housing block.
The area is quiet, with green spaces, clean streets and a new tram link to the centre of Lyon. It is far from the stereotypical image of a run-down city suburb.
"They are a very normal family," a neighbour who gave her name as Brigitte said. I only talked with madame, he didn't say hello or goodbye," the 46-year-old housewife said.
Though Sahli, of North African origin, had no criminal record, Cazeneuve said he was categorised by security services as far back as 2006 as someone at risk of being radicalised.
While that status allowed security forces to discreetly keep tabs on him, they did not see fit to renew it in 2008, although he was known to have contact with radical Islamists in France.
However, he was back on the radar of the DGSI domestic security service for at least the past two years and was described in 2013 as a "hardcore Muslim" in one intelligence memo, according to RTL radio.
Another memo dating from May 2014 said he had undergone a "radical" change, losing weight and shaving his beard. It said he was often away from home for unexplained absences of several weeks at a time.
The note said he held meetings at his home, hosting men who wore combat fatigues. Doorstep chatter with them was peppered with references to jihad, said RTL, citing the memo.
Sahli had been living in Saint-Priest for around six months. Before that, the Est Republicain newspaper said the suspect,  whose late father was Algerian and mother Moroccan, lived in Pontarlier near the Swiss border. The town is home to a mosque known for the virulent views of its preacher, who has since left France.

Reader's comments 
If you already have an account on this newspaper, you can login to the newspaper to add your comments.
By adding a comment on the site, you accept our terms and conditions and our netiquette rules.
Featured Businesses
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
