<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:58:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexico bans wild animals in circuses -- but there's no place for them to go</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150706/mexico-bans-wild-animals-in-circuses-x2014-but-theres-no-place-for-them-to-go</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Circuses
Mexico bans wild animals in circuses  but theres no place for them to go
Circus elephants, like this one performing in Paris, France, are banned in Mexico beginning July 8. Bertrand Guay/AFP/Getty Images
By Emilie Munson, GlobalPost
Circus workers perform as they take part in a protest against a law that prohibits the use of wild animals in their shows, in Mexico City on June 10, 2014. Alfredo Estrella/AFP/Getty Images
Lions and tigers and bears no more.
A new law in Mexico banning the use of tigers, elephants, zebras, lions and other exotic animals in circuses comes into effect next week.
The law, which was approved in March 2015, is aimed at preventing animal cruelty, and those who violate it will be fined nearly $225,000.
Some 3,000 to 3,500 circus animals will be freed from performing under the big top thanks to the law, according to the International Business Times .
The question remains, however, what will happen to all of these animals?
For many circus owners, the animals will be too expensive to keep. One Mexican animal tamer estimated that it costs around 3,000 pesos (almost $200) a day to feed circus tigers. When you add other costs like veterinary bills on top of that, keeping wild animals is a pricey expense.
An official from the Mexican environmental protection agency said the government is evaluating different facilities that could take in the animals. Privately owned zoos have also offered to house them.
Some circus owners claim that the new law, designed to protect circus animals, is actually putting the animals in worse danger.
A lot of owners dont want to give the government the animals that are their livelihoods, President of the National Association of Circus Owners Armando Cedeo told the Guardian . Some are looking to sell them, and you dont always know who is buying. Others are so desperate they are looking to put them to sleep.
The Associated Press reported that Mexican authorities had found six tigers, seven baboons, four camels and three dromedaries abandoned in cages last week. Theyd been left without food or water.
Circuses across Mexico are also worried about revenue. Without animal attractions to draw spectators, attendance could drop, and some smaller circus operations have been forced to shut down already.
Workers, naturally, are concerned about their jobs. Over 1,000 circus employees protested against the law in Mexico City a year ago, saying that the law will leave thousands unemployed.
Mexico is the 29th country to pass a nationwide ban on circus animals, according to Stop Circus Suffering , a campaign of the NGO Animal Defenders International. Other countries with nationwide bans include Austria, Croatia, Greece, Bolivia and Costa Rica.
Advertisement
The US has full or partial bans on circus animals in only 22 states .
Perhaps cock fighting and bull fighting will be Mexicos next legal targets.
This article originally appeared on GlobalPost .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 17:37:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek government racing against the clock as banks run out of cash</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150706/greek-government-racing-against-the-clock-as-banks-run-out-of-cash</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Greek government racing against the clock as banks run out of cash
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis puts his helmet on Monday as he is surrounded by media after his resignation in Athens, Monday. Greece and its membership in Europes joint currency faced an uncertain future, with the country under pressure to reach a bailout deal with creditors as soon as possible after Greeks resoundingly rejected the notion of more austerity in exchange for aid. Petros Karadjias  The Associated Press
By Elena Becatoros, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Greeces Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, leaves after a meeting Monday with Greek political party leaders at the Presidential Palace as Minister of State Nikos Pappas, left, and Government spokesman Gabriel Sakellaridis, right, follow him in Athens. With Greek banks running out of cash and facing the danger of collapse within days without new aid, the government is racing against the clock. Angelos Christofilopoulos  The Associated Press
ATHENS, Greece &gt;&gt; Greece and its membership in Europes joint currency faced an uncertain future Monday, with the country under pressure to restart bailout talks with creditors as soon as possible after Greeks resoundingly rejected the notion of more austerity in exchange for aid.
With Greek banks running out of cash and facing the danger of collapse within days without new aid, the government in Athens is racing against the clock.
In an effort to facilitate negotiations on a new aid program, Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis, who had clashed with European officials in the bailout talks, announced his resignation Monday.
But Greece and its creditors, who will meet again Tuesday to discuss how to keep the country in the euro, remain far apart on key issues, particularly the notion of debt relief.
Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and Chancellor Angela Merkel spoke on the phone Monday ahead of the Tuesday summit, though no details were disclosed of what they discussed.
New negotiations will be complicated for the European creditors by Tsipras triumph in Sundays referendum. More than 61 percent of Greeks backed his call to vote no to budget cuts the creditors had proposed in return for rescue loans the country needs  even though those proposals were no longer on the table.
The vote was painted by opposition parties and many European officials as one on whether Greece should remain in Europes joint currency. In the aftermath, many European leaders softened their tone and said talks would resume, though Greeces chance of staying in the euro was looking increasingly shaky.
The countrys banks remained shut on Monday for a sixth working day and the government kept tight limits on cash withdrawals at ATMs and money transfers to limit the drain on deposits.
All eyes now turn to whether the European Central Bank will increase the amount of credit the banks can draw on to make up for the cash drain. Analysts expect the ECB to not provide more emergency assistance on Monday.
That means the banks would not be able to reopen and Greece might have to tighten its limits on cash withdrawals and transfers from the current 60 euros ($67) per day. Some banks may even face the risk of collapse in coming days as they continue to be drained of banknotes.
Greeces economy minister, Giorgos Stathakis, told the BBC that if the ECB keeps its support unchanged, the current cash withdrawals limits can stay in place until Friday without any banks collapsing.
Facing such urgency, the Greek government has vowed to quickly restart negotiations with creditors in other eurozone countries and with the institutions that oversaw the countrys bailout: the ECB, European Commission and International Monetary Fund.
Advertisement
Varoufakis appeared to be the first casualty of the Greek governments attempt to reach a deal with creditors.
With his brash style and fondness for frequent media appearances, Varoufakis had visibly annoyed many of the eurozones finance ministers during the past months debt negotiations.
Varoufakis said in a statement he was told shortly after the referendum result that some other eurozone finance ministers and the countrys other creditors would appreciate his not attending the ministers meetings.
The idea was one that the Prime Minister judged to be potentially helpful to him in reaching an agreement. For this reason I am leaving the Ministry of Finance today, he said.
As for his European negotiating colleagues, he said of them: I shall wear the creditors loathing with pride.
A replacement was to be announced later Monday.
With his high-stakes gamble to call a referendum with just a weeks notice, Tsipras aimed to show creditors that Greeks, whose economy has been shattered and who face spiraling unemployment and poverty, have had enough and that the austerity prescribed isnt working.
But everything hinges on European reaction.
European officials appear to be split on a key demand by Greece to have the burden of its bailout loans be made more manageable.
Frances finance minister, Michel Sapin, indicated that discussing Greeces debt is not taboo, saying the country could not recover with its current obligations in the months and years to come.
Sapin also called for the ECB to maintain liquidity assistance to Greek banks.
Germany, however, remains reluctant to discuss debt forgiveness.
Finance Ministry spokesman Martin Jaeger said Germanys position is well-known ... a debt cut is not an issue for us.
More broadly, Chancellor Angela Merkels spokesman said talks on a new bailout program for Greece would depend on what proposals Athens makes.
Steffen Seibert said Germany respects the clear no vote by Greeks against austerity measures.
However, he added that in view of Greek citizens decision yesterday, the conditions are not there at present to enter negotiations on a new program. He said the no vote is a vote against the principle  still supported by Germany  that solidarity requires countries to make their own reform efforts.
Besieged by a prolonged recession, high unemployment and banks dangerously low on capital, Greece defaulted on an IMF loan repayment last week, becoming the first developed nation to do so.
Now some analysts wonder if Greece is so starved of cash that it could be forced to start issuing its own currency and become the first country to leave the 19-member eurozone, established in 1999.
Tsipras was elected in January on promises to repeal the austerity demanded in return for its bailout and negotiations broke down late last month after dragging on unsuccessfully for five months.
Demetri Nellas and Menelaos Hadjicostis in Athens, Greece, Lori Hinnant in Paris, Raf Casert in Brussels and Geir Moulson in Berlin contributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 21:50:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Terminator,' 'Magic Mike' fizzle at July 4th box office</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150705/terminator-magic-mike-fizzle-at-july-4th-box-office</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Box office receipts
Terminator, Magic Mike fizzle at July 4th box office
This photo provided by Paramount Pictures shows, Arnold Schwarzenegger as the Terminator in Terminator Genisys, from Paramount Pictures and Skydance Productions. Melinda Sue Gordon  Paramount Pictures via AP
By Jake Coyle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
This image released by Warner Bros. Pictures shows Channing Tatum in a scene from the film, Magic Mike XXL. Claudette Barius  Warner Bros. Pictures via AP
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; July 4th went off like a dud at the box office. Anticipated new releases Magic Mike XXL and Terminator Genisys fizzled, leaving the popular holdovers Jurassic World and Inside Out to top the holiday weekend.
Despite the brawny enticements of Channing Tatum and Arnold Schwarzenegger, the four-week rule of Universals dinosaur sensation Jurassic World continued with an estimated $30.9 million, according to studio estimates Sunday.
Pixars acclaimed Inside Out nearly caught up to the runaway dinos, taking in $30.1 million in its third weekend of release.
The strength of those June hits and the unfortunate timing of July 4th this year coming on a Saturday (rather than stretching out a long weekend) meant the sequels Terminator Genisys and Magic Mike XXL both failed to match previous installments.
Paramounts Terminator Genisys, the fifth film in the series which also marks Schwarzeneggers return to his most iconic character, took in $28.7 million over the weekend and $44.2 million since opening Wednesday.
Warner Bros. also tried to expand the weekend, opening Tatums male-stripper romp Magic Mike XXL on Wednesday. But after a strong start, the film managed just $12 million over the weekend. Over five days it made $27.1 million.
The openings were disappointing for the new releases, but each has a different makeup. Terminator Genisys, an attempted reboot in the 31-year-old, James Cameron-created franchise, was made for $155 million. Magic Mike XXL, a road-trip sequel to Steven Soderberghs 2012 hit original, was made for just under $15 million.
Megan Colligan, head of worldwide distribution for Paramount, said the weekend simply didnt play like a holiday weekend.
The weekend got off to a very sluggish start because people didnt have off until Friday, said Colligan. Our start was just not where it needed to be. Some of that does have to do with it is pretty severe competition. Jurassic is still such a powerhouse in the marketplace and it was hard to anticipate that that wouldnt have burned off a little more by now.
Genisys failed to come close to the previous Terminator film, the Schwarzenegger-less Salvation, which had a five-day debut of $65.3 million over Memorial Day weekend in 2009. Genisys, which critics have slammed, is finding better business abroad. It made $74 million international over the weekend.
Magic Mike XXL, however, had the benefit of largely positive reviews and tracking numbers that suggested a possible No. 1 opening of more than $40 million. The original debuted with $39.1 million.
Advertisement
But Magic Mike XXL failed to expand its audience. Whereas moviegoers for the first film were 73 percent female, Magic Mike XXL was a staggering 96 percent female, Warner Bros. said.
Dan Fellman, head of domestic distribution for Warner Bros., said the film performed worse than expected in the South, Midwest and in Canada. Such a girls-night-out release, he said, didnt materialize over the holiday weekend.
Our audience wasnt available to us, said Fellman. We might be down but were not out. Im in the wait and see mode.
Hollywoods summer has been inching close to equaling its record 2013 season, thanks partly to the unexpected success of Jurassic World. (Now with $558.2 million domestically, its already the fourth-best showing of all time in North America.)
The biggest potholes this summer have been holiday weekends, noted Paul Dergarabedian, senior media analyst for box-office firm Rentrak.
Those weekends usually are the tent poles to Hollywoods summer spectacle, but the lagging Independence Day weekend follows a lackluster Memorial Day, when Disneys Tomorrowland flopped.
These are the weekends everyones going, Wow, what happened? said Dergarabedian. Part of it was the calendar. Part of it, too, was you have two movies out there  Jurassic World and Inside Out  that are just dominating the marketplace. Both those movies have appealed to every audience segment imaginable.
This weekend was still up 6.9 percent over last year, when Melissa McCarthys Tammy and the sci-fi adventure Earth to Echo made for Hollywoods worst July 4 in decades.
Universals animated off-shoot sequel Minions will debut next weekend after a strong international performance. The film, which gives the pipsqueak henchmen of the Despicable Me movies the spotlight, has already grossed $124.2 million abroad, including $54.3 million this weekend.
Estimated ticket sales for Friday through Sunday at U.S. and Canadian theaters, according to Rentrak. Where available, the latest international numbers for Friday through Sunday are also included. Final domestic figures will be released Monday.
1. Jurassic World, $30.9 million ($42 million international).
2. Inside Out, $30.1 million ($18.6 million international).
3. Terminator: Genisys, $28.7 million ($74 million international).
4. Magic Mike XXL, $12 million.
5. Ted 2, $11 million.
6. Max, $7 million.
8. San Andreas, $3 million.
9. Me and Earl and the Dying Girl, $1.3 million.
10. Dope, $1.1 million.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 20:43:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASCAR fans defend, display Confederate flags at Daytona</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/sports/20150705/nascar-fans-defend-display-confederate-flags-at-daytona</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Motorsports
NASCAR fans defend, display Confederate flags at Daytona
Confederate flags fly on top of a motor home at Daytona International Speedway, Saturday in Daytona Beach, Fla. NASCAR and the speedway offered to replace any flag a race brings to the track with an American flag. Phelan M. Ebenhack  The Associated Press
By Mark Long, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Confederate and American flags fly on top of motor homes at Daytona International Speedway, Saturday in Daytona Beach, Fla. NASCAR and the speedway offered to replace any flag a race brings to the track with an American flag. Phelan M. Ebenhack  The Associated Press
DAYTONA BEACH, Fla. &gt;&gt; Steven Rebenstorf has numerous flags flying atop his canopy tent inside Daytona International Speedway.
The Confederate flag is front and center.
Its been like that for years. And the 57-year-old Rebenstorf has no plans to take it down  not even if NASCAR decides to ban the embattled flag from its racetracks.
Theyd have to come and get it, Rebenstorf said Saturday, pointing out that his American flag purposely flies a few inches higher than the rest.
Rebenstorf and others staunchly defended their Confederate flags at NASCARs first race in the South since the racing series and its tracks urged fans to no longer wave the banner. Dozens were scattered throughout the vast infield all weekend leading to Sundays race.
It kills me that NASCAR is jumping on the bandwagon, said 55-year-old Paul Stevens of nearby Port Orange. They should just let it pass, let everything die down. But NASCAR is too quick to try to be politically correct like everybody else.
NASCAR took a stance on the Confederate flag after last months South Carolina church massacre. It backed Gov. Nikki Haleys call to remove it from the Statehouse grounds and noted it doesnt allow the flag on anything it sanctions. The series stopped short of banning fans from displaying the flag at its events, but Daytona and 29 other tracks asked fans to refrain from flying them.
Not everyone obliged. Daytona also offered to exchange Confederate flags for American flags this weekend, and track officials said a few made the swap Sunday morning.
I think the voluntary exchange program for us right now was appropriate with the limited window that we had coming into this event weekend, track president Joie Chitwood said. And more importantly, I think its important to trust our fans, asking our fans to display a flag that we should all be proud of. Everybody should be proud of the American flag.
Indeed, the American flag is prominently displayed all around Daytona  no surprise given the Fourth of July holiday and the patriotism that NASCAR routinely promotes.
But spotting a Confederate flag is easier than finding a souvenir shop, restroom or beer stand.
The first motorhome located inside the Turn 4 tunnel has one flying high above it, and it doesnt take long to reach double figures when counting them on a stroll through the infield. Theyre on clothing, coolers and cars, and even tattooed on skin.
Advertisement
Larry Reeves of Jacksonville Beach has a tattered Confederate flag on top of his motorhome. He initially thought NASCAR was banning the banner and didnt display it this week. But once he saw some flying around him and asked a few questions, he realized it was voluntary and quickly sent his back up the pole.
Its just a Southern pride thing, the 66-year-old Reeves said. Its nothing racist or anything. Ive been doing this for 30 years. My family is from Alabama and weve been going to Talladega forever. It isnt a Confederate thing so much as it is a NASCAR thing. Thats why I fly it.
Like others at Daytona, Reeves believes the flag flap is much ado about nothing.
Its not a big deal one way or the other, Reeves said. If I cant fly it, I wont. But if I dont have to take it down, Im just going to leave it up.
Rebenstorf plans to leave his up no matter what NASCAR mandates.
The St. Petersburg resident spent six years in the Navy, served in the color guard and has strong feelings about vexillology, the scientific study of the history, symbolism and usage of flags.
The Confederate flag has absolutely nothing to do with slavery. It has nothing to do with divisiveness. It has nothing to do with any of that, Rebenstorf said, pausing for a few minutes to pull off his floppy hat, stand at attention and salute during the national anthem Saturday. It was just a battle banner until the Ku Klux Klan draped it around themselves. Now, all of a sudden, it represents slavery and thats not at all true.
The Civil War-era flag has been under attack since nine black men and women were gunned down at a historic church in Charleston on June 17.
The suspect, 21-year-old Dylann Roof, had posed with a Confederate flag in photos posted on a website that displayed a racist manifesto attributed to him.
NASCAR, which has roots in the deep South, moved quickly to distance itself from the flag despite some backlash from fans. The sanctioning body could have done  and eventually might do  more.
I think what happens in this situation is you have people on both sides who feel very strongly about something and theyre very passionate about it, Chitwood said. You cant argue with someones passion or their opinion. That creates something that ends up on the front page of the newspaper or is the headline in the news. If were going to enter that discussion, youve got to be thoughtful and weve got to really think through it and be fair to both sides and make sure that whatever we come up can work.
In something like this, the more thoughtful we can be, understanding and really taking the time to really vet through, I think thats going to be the important thing moving forward.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:30:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Standoff over social media passwords breaks new legal ground</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/media/20150705/standoff-over-social-media-passwords-breaks-new-legal-ground</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Social media
Standoff over social media passwords breaks new legal ground
Jeremy Alcede talks about his legal issues Friday outside the federal courthouse in Houston. Alcede spent nearly seven weeks in jail for refusing a judges order to share his social media passwords with the new owner of the business he lost in bankruptcy. Pat Sullivan  The Associated Press
By Juan A. Lozano, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
HOUSTON &gt;&gt; A Texas man used social media to promote his gun store, posting politically charged messages that criticized the president and promoted Second Amendment rights.
But after losing ownership of his suburban Houston store in bankruptcy, Jeremy Alcede spent nearly seven weeks in jail for refusing a federal judges order to share with the new owner the passwords of the business Facebook and Twitter accounts, which the judge had declared property.
Its all about silencing my voice, said Alcede, who was released in May after turning over the information. ... Any 3-year-old can look at this and tell this is my Facebook account and not the companys.
Alcedes ultimately failed stand charts new territory in awarding property in bankruptcy proceedings and points to the growing importance of social media accounts as business assets. Legal experts say it also provides a lesson for all business owners who are active on social media.
If your business is something you feel very passionately about, it can be hard to separate those things, said Benjamin Stewart, a Dallas-based bankruptcy lawyer. The moral for people is you have to keep your personal life separate from your business life.
U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Jeff Bohm, who handled Alcedes case, acknowledged the landscape of social media is yet mostly uncharted in bankruptcy, and cited a 2011 New York bankruptcy court case that treated such accounts like subscriber lists, which provide valuable access to customers and potential customers.
Other cases in the U.S. and abroad have touched on similar issues. In 2012, a South Carolina Internet company settled a lawsuit filed against a former employee it had said cost them thousands of dollars in lost business when he took 17,000 Twitter followers with him. A Pennsylvania federal court in 2013 ruled in favor of a woman who had sued after her former employer took over her LinkedIn account following her firing.
That same year, a British court approved a companys request to temporarily stop a group of ex-employees from using the firms LinkedIn contacts to start a rival business. The employees claimed the LinkedIn accounts and contacts were personal.
Villanova University School of Law professor Michael Risch said Facebook and Twitter accounts, among other social media platforms, are now seen as property by companies.
I suspect thats what the judge was looking at, is this primarily an asset being used for business advertising to get customers to talk about what is going on with the company, said Risch, who specializes in Internet law. It might have started out as a personal (account) but turned into a business property.
Advertisement
Alcede, however, remains defiant, even after his release from jail, saying his refusal to hand over the passwords was not about keeping his Facebook page but fighting tyrannical big government.
He said his Facebook posts and tweets criticizing President Barack Obama and supporting gun owners rights were his personal views and not done to promote the business. But Bohm ruled in April that the gun stores social media accounts were not personal but used to boost sales, citing a tweet in which Alcede told his followers he was at a gun trade show as an example of something that would attract customers because it showed him as a connected insider in the gun-buying community.
Control of the store and social media accounts was given to Steven Coe Wilson, Alcedes former business partner. Bohms ruling described Alcede as a disgruntled former business partner trying to control assets that no longer belonged to him.
Alcede, who in June filed a motion to revoke the bankruptcy plan, had argued the accounts werent listed as assets in the bankruptcy court filings. He told The Associated Press he only turned over the passwords so he could deal with various personal issues, including health problems he developed while jailed.
Wilson said in an email he couldnt comment until Bohm releases the company from bankruptcy. Richard Kincheloe, Wilsons attorney, did not return phone calls seeking comment, but said at an April court hearing that the issues related to the social media accounts were not about what someone is allowed to say. Its about paying creditors.
If the new owners could not access the business accounts and send messages to followers, it could impact the stores profits, making it less valuable, Stewart said. While having Alcede spend seven weeks in jail over the passwords was harsh, Stewart said that in the end, Alcede held the key to his freedom.
You have to strike a balance between making sure people respect the courts authority and giving people the right to make their own decision and accept the consequences if that is the way they want to go, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:29:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN approves world heritage status for The Alamo, other sites</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150705/un-approves-world-heritage-status-for-the-alamo-other-sites</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
UN approves world heritage status for The Alamo, other sites
In this file photo, John Potter, a member of the San Antonio Living History Association, patrols the Alamo in San Antonio, during a pre-dawn memorial ceremony to remember the 1836 Battle of the Alamo and those who fell on both sides. The San Antonio Missions in Texas have been awarded world heritage status by the U.N.s cultural body.UNESCOs World Heritage Committee approved the listing Sunday of the five Spanish Roman Catholic sites built in the 18th century in and around what is now the city of San Antonio. Eric Gay  The Associated Press file
By Christoph Noelting and Frank Jordans, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
BONN, Germany &gt;&gt; The United States has succeeded in its bid to Remember the Alamo, after the U.N. cultural body approved its status as a world heritage site Sunday.
The Alamo was one of five Spanish Roman Catholic sites, known as the San Antonio Missions, to receive the coveted label likely to boost tourism.
UNESCOs World Heritage Committee approved the Missions status along with more than a dozen others from around the globe, including the Gunkanjima industrial site off Japan that South Korea had long objected to.
Susan Snow, an archaeologist for San Antonio Missions National Historical Park, said the site in Texas represents the very essence of the great melting pot of the United States.
These Missions are a living example of the interchange of cultures bringing together the indigenous, Spanish, Mexican, and other influences that form South Texas today, Snow said in a statement following the decision in Bonn, Germany.
The Missions were built in the 18th century in and around what is now the city of San Antonio to convert indigenous people to Catholicism and make them Spanish subjects.
The best known of the missions, The Alamo, was the site of the famous 1836 battle when an outnumbered band of Texas settlers staged a courageous stand before Gen. Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna and his Mexican forces seized the mission. During the Battle of San Jacinto weeks later, then-victorious Texas soldiers shouted, Remember the Alamo!
U.S. officials hope the designation will boost tourism to San Antonio, already one of the citys top five industry and responsible for one in eight jobs.
The Missions were the only sites in the United States proposed for world heritage status this year. Other American icons already on the list include the Statue of Liberty and the Grand Canyon.
In another decision, Japan received world heritage status for a collection of almost two dozen sites that illustrate the countrys industrial revolution during the 19th century.
The unanimous vote in favor of Japans bid was approved only after Tokyo and Seoul resolved a spat over whether to acknowledge the sites history of wartime forced labor, particularly that of Gunkanjima, or Battleship Island.
The fortress island near Nagasaki was key to Japans rapid development during the 1868-1912 era of the Meiji Emperor, who sought to catch up with Western colonial powers.
Advertisement
Until recently, Seoul had objected to the listing unless the role of Korean prisoners forced to work there during World War II was formally recognized.
Japan is prepared to take measures that allow an understanding that there were a large number of Koreans and others who were brought against their will and forced to work under harsh conditions in the 1940s at some of the sites, the Japanese delegation said in a statement after the decision.
More than a dozen other sites have also been granted world heritage status in recent days. They include:
 The Burgundy vineyards south of Dijon, France, which have been shaped by centuries of wine making. Along with surrounding villages and the historic center of Dijon, the site represents an industry in existence since at least the 12th century.
 Champagne, the sparkling wine distinctive of the eponymous French region, represented in the vineyards, the cellars where the bottled wine ferments a second time, and the storied sales houses.
 The Diyarbakir Fortress and Hevsel Gardens of Turkey, which goes back to ancient Greek and Roman times.
 The Par Force Hunting Landscape northeast of Copenhagen, a sculpted woodland where Danish kings hunted with hounds until the 18th century.
 A Lutheran church settlement known as Christiansfeld, also in Denmark. Founded in 1773 in the region of South Jutland, the town was built around a central church square to represent the democratic ideal of this Protestant denomination.
 Tusi sites in southwest China, named after the tribal chiefs who ruled there from the 13th to the early 20th century.
 The archaeological mounds and Ardeshirs palace along the Shavur River in Iran. Known as Susa, the site was continuously settled from the 5th century B.C. until the 13th century.
 The Maymand valley region of central Iran inhabited by semi-nomadic people who move between mountain pastures and caves depending on the season.
 Singapores Botanical Gardens, which were created in 1859 and have since become a world-class conservation and research site, as well as a major tourist attraction for the city state.
 The Baekje region of South Korea comprising archaeological sites dating from the late 5th to late 7th century.
 Mongolias sacred Great Burkhan Khaldun Mountain where Central Asian steppe meets the Siberian taiga. Tradition holds that it is the site of Genghis Khans birth and burial.
 Sicilian churches and palaces dating back to the islands 12th-century Norman rule, which incorporated Arab and Byzantine culture.
 Christian pilgrimage sites in modern Jordan where Jesus is said to have been baptized, along with Roman and Byzantine remains in the area.
 Prehistoric rock art showing human and animal figures in Saudi Arabias Hail Region.
 Hamburgs Speicherstadt district, a vast complex of red-brick warehouses built between 1883 and 1927 in Germanys biggest port.
 The Rjukan-Notodden industrial site in Norway, built in the early 20th century to produce fertilizer to meet the booming demand from agriculture.
 The Necropolis of Beth Shearim, a series of catacombs built from the 2nd century B.C. onward as a Jewish burial place. Located southeast of Haifa, Israel, the site features inscriptions in Greek, Aramaic and Hebrew.
 Scotlands Forth Bridge, completed in 1890 to carry trains over the Forth River and still in use today.
 The Blue and John Crow Mountains, Jamaicas first world heritage site. Located on the southeast of the island, they became a refuge for indigenous people and escaped African slaves during colonial times and are considered a biodiversity hotspot.
Frank Jordans reported from Berlin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:28:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police: Man dies after launching firework from the top of his head</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150705/police-man-dies-after-launching-firework-from-the-top-of-his-head</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Police: Man dies after launching firework from the top of his head
By The Associated Press
# Comments
CALAIS, Maine &gt;&gt; A young man who was drinking and celebrating the Fourth of July tried to launch a firework off the top of his head, fatally injuring himself, authorities said Sunday.
Devon Staples and his friends had been drinking and setting off fireworks Saturday night in the backyard of a friends home in the small eastern Maine city of Calais, said Stephen McCausland, a spokesman for the state Department of Public Safety. Staples, 22, of Calais, placed a fireworks mortar tube on his head and set it off, he said.
The firework exploded, killing Staples instantly, McCausland said.
His death is the first fireworks fatality in Maine since the state legalized fireworks on Jan. 1, 2012, authorities said.
Calais is on the Canadian border near New Brunswick.
State fire marshals were also investigating several other Fourth of July fireworks accidents involving injuries in Friendship, Jefferson, Lebanon and Woodstock. They said most of the accidents involved burns and eye injuries. McCausland said further details were expected to be released later Sunday.
In 2011, lawmakers voted to repeal a 1949 law banning fireworks, reasoning the industry would create jobs and generate additional revenue.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:04:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Farmers eager for drones, but most can't legally fly them</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/business/20150705/farmers-eager-for-drones-but-most-cant-legally-fly-them</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Agriculture
Farmers eager for drones, but most cant legally fly them
In this photo, a DJI Phantom 3 drone is flown by Matthew Creger, left, marketing director for Intelligent UAS, as he talks with Chip Bowling, from Newburg, Md., president of the National Corn Growers, during a drone demonstration at a farm and winery on potential use for board members of the National Corn Growers in Cordova, Md. Alex Brandon  The Associated Press
By Mary Clare Jalonick, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this photo, a DJI Phantom 3 drone is flown by Chip Bowling, left, from Newburg, Md., president of the National Corn Growers, with Matthew Creger, marketing director for Intelligent UAS, during a drone demonstration at a farm and winery on potential use for board members of the National Corn Growers in Cordova, Md. Alex Brandon  The Associated Press
CORDOVA, Md. &gt;&gt; Mike Geske wants a drone.
Watching a flying demonstration on Marylands Eastern Shore, the Missouri farmer envisions using an unmanned aerial vehicle to monitor the irrigation pipes on his farm  a job he now pays three men to do.
The savings on labor and fuel would just be phenomenal, Geske says, watching as a small white drone hovers over a nearby corn field and transmits detailed pictures of the growing stalks to an iPad.
Nearby, farmer Chip Bowling tries his hand at flying one of the drones. Bowling, president of the National Corn Growers Association, says he would like to buy one for his Maryland farm to help him scout out which individual fields need extra spraying.
Another farmer, Bobby Hutchison, says he is hoping the man he hires weekly to walk his fields and observe his crops gets a drone, to make the process more efficient and accurate.
I see it very similar to how I saw the computer when it first started, says Hutchison, 64. It was a no-brainer.
Farmers are eager for the technology.
The small, relatively inexpensive vehicles could replace humans in a variety of ways around large farms: transmitting detailed information about crops to combines and sprayers, directing them very precisely to problem spots and cutting down on the amount of water and chemicals that a farmer needs to use in those areas.
The Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International, a trade group, says agriculture could account for 80 percent of all commercial drone use.
Agricultural use of drones is about to take off after being grounded for years by the lack of federal guidelines. The Federal Aviation Administration has approved more than 50 exemptions for farm-related operations since January.
Companies with those exemptions say business has grown, helped by quick advances in the technology.
Bret Chilcott of Kansas-based AgEagle, which sells unmanned aerial vehicles and the software to help operate them, says his company took its first orders last year. Now it has a backlog of several hundred orders. He says the technology has transformed the market during that short period.
Last year users had to land their aircraft and then take the data to the computer, he says. Now the data appears on your iPad or hand-held device a few minutes after flight.
That data could be pictures, 3-D images of plants, thermal readings of crops or animals or other observations that a drone could make while in the air. Information that in the past took days to collect  or could not have been collected at all  can be gathered now in minutes or hours and, in some cases, integrated with separate data collected from other high-tech farm machinery.
Advertisement
Chilcott is optimistic that the technology to scout out problem spots so precisely will be transformative because farmers can limit spraying just to those places.
In five years we wont have to blanket a field with chemicals, he says.
Still, most farmers cannot legally fly the vehicles yet.
The FAA is working on rules that would allow the drones to be used regularly for business while maintaining certain safety and privacy standards. An FAA proposal this year would allow flight of the vehicles as long as they weigh less than 55 pounds, stay within the operators sight and fly during the daytime, among other restrictions. Operators would have to pass an FAA test of aeronautical knowledge and a Transportation Security Administration background check.
Thomas Haun of North Carolina-based PrecisionHawk, another company with an exemption, says it is unclear what the business will look like eventually. Farmers may hire services that have unmanned aerial vehicles or every farm may get its own drone. Most likely, it will be a combination.
Haun says the proposed rules are appropriate. Its pretty spot on for where the technology is right now, he says.
Some people have concerns about the guidelines. Pilots of crop dusters and other planes that operate around farms are concerned the rules do not go far enough to ensure safety.
We cant see them, says Andrew Moore of the National Agricultural Aviation Association. His group advocated for the unmanned vehicles to include tracking systems or lights to help airplanes figure out where they are, but that was not included in the proposal.
The rules could pose some challenges for the eager farmers, too.
Geske may not be able to use drones efficiently to monitor all the irrigation pipes on his 2,100 acre Missouri farm if he has to keep them within sight. Hes still interested, though. The men he hires now use a lot of fuel and their trucks tear up his land and roads.
You can wait forever on advancing technology, Geske says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:03:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russian craft delivers long-awaited cargo to space station</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/science/20150705/russian-craft-delivers-long-awaited-cargo-to-space-station</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Space exploration
Russian craft delivers long-awaited cargo to space station
In this image taken from video, a Soyuz-U rocket blasts off at the Russian leased Baikonur cosmodrome, Kazakhstan, Friday. The unmanned cargo ship is heading to the International Space Station, whose crew is anxiously awaiting it after the successive failures of two previous supply missions. NASA TV via AP
By The Associated Press
# Comments
MOSCOW &gt;&gt; An unmanned Russian cargo ship has docked successfully at the International Space Station, where it was anxiously awaited by the U.S.-Russian crew after the successive failures of two previous supply missions.
The Progress M-28M ship, which is carrying 2.5 metric tons of fuel, oxygen, water, food and other supplies, was launched into orbit on Friday from the Baikonur launch pad in Kazakhstan. Russian Mission Control said it docked successfully Sunday in the automated mode at the orbiting space station.
The previous Progress launch in April had ended in failure and a week ago a U.S. supply mission failed when SpaceXs Falcon 9 rocket broke apart shortly after liftoff.
The mishaps were preceded by last Octobers launch pad failure of Orbital Sciences Antares rocket, also carrying station cargo for NASA.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:02:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>On his native turf, Pope Francis touches on cherished issues</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150705/on-his-native-turf-pope-francis-touches-on-cherished-issues</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Religion
On his native turf, Pope Francis touches on cherished issues
Pope Francis waves to reporters at Romes Fiumicino International airport, Sunday as he boards his flight to Quito, Ecuador, where he will start a week-long trip to South America, including Bolivia and Paraguay. Francis is taking his church for the poor to three of South Americas poorest and most peripheral countries, making a grueling, week-long trip that will showcase the pope at his unpredictable best: speaking his native Spanish on his home turf about issues closest to his heart. Riccardo De Luca  The Associated Press
By Frank Bajak and Nicole Winfield, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
QUITO, Ecuador &gt;&gt; Historys first Latin American pope returns to Spanish-speaking South America for the first time on Sunday, bringing a message of solidarity with the regions poor, who are expected to turn out in droves to welcome their native son home.
The pope of the poor chose to visit Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay specifically because they are among the poorest and most marginal nations of a region that claims 40 percent of the worlds Catholics. Hes skipping his homeland of Argentina, at least partly to avoid papal entanglement in this years presidential election.
The trip starts in Ecuador, where falling world prices for oil and minerals threaten to fray the social safety net woven by President Rafael Correa, who has been buffeted for nearly a month by the most serious anti-government street protests of his more than eight years in power.
Crowds began gathering Sunday morning along the route from the airport to the papal nuncios residence, where Francis will be staying. The pope will switch from a car to a bubble-windowed popemobile for the last five miles of the trip.
Francis is likely to raise environmental concerns with Correa and the leader of Bolivia  who have promoted mining and oil drilling in wilderness areas  given his recent encyclical on the need to protect nature and the poor who suffer most when it is exploited.
In that document, Francis called for a new development model that rejects todays profit-at-all cost mentality in favor of a Christian view of economic progress that respects human rights, safeguards the planet and involves all sectors of society, the poor and marginalized included.
In a video message on the eve of his departure, Francis said he wanted to bring a message of hope and joy to all especially the neediest, the elderly, the sick, those in prison and the poor and all those who are victims of this throwaway culture.
Francis stops include a violent Bolivian prison, a flood-prone Paraguayan shantytown and a meeting with Bolivian trash pickers, the sort of people he ministered to in the slums of Buenos Aires as archbishop.
Crowds are expected to be huge. While the countries themselves are tiny compared to regional powerhouses like Brazil and Argentina, they are fervently Catholic: 79 percent of the population is Catholic in Ecuador, 77 percent in Bolivia and a whopping 89 percent in Paraguay, according to the Pew Research Center.
Advertisement
You can imagine what this embrace of love will be, this devotion of our people toward the pope, the universal pastor who comes from Latin America, said Guzman Carriquiri, the No. 2 of the Pontifical Commission for Latin America and a top papal adviser.
The Vatican says it expects more than 1 million people to turn out for Francis major public Masses in each country, and organizers have scheduled plenty of time for the pope to meander through the throngs expected to line his motorcade route.
When St. John Paul II visited Ecuador in 1985, he called for a more just society and reminded indigenous groups of the role played by missionaries who had arrived on the continent centuries before. Francis will likely repeat those messages and pay particular attention to the role his Jesuit order played.
John Pauls visits were shadowed by the Polish popes concern about the rise of liberation theology, fearing that Marxists were using its preferential option for the poor to turn the Gospel into a call for armed revolution.
Carriquiri said a less turbulent situation awaits Francis, who has sought to revive a purer, less political version of liberation theology and recently approved beatification for one of its heroes, Salvadoran Archbishop Oscar Romero. Francis also brokered a historic thaw between the United States and Cuba, countries he will visit in September.
Francis visit will be a huge boost to the priests of the Third World and theology of liberation, said Xavier Albo, a fellow Jesuit who, like the pope, is 80. He lives that theology through mercy, modesty and his obligation to the poor, the immigrants and the imprisoned.
Jesuits paid with their lives defending the downtrodden against dictatorships, as the pope knows well from his days as head of the Jesuits during the right-wing military dictatorship in Argentina.
Opponents of dictatorships in neighboring Paraguay and Bolivia were also disappeared. One, who was tortured and killed in 1980, was Father Luis Espinal, a Bolivian close to Albo whose body was dumped by the side of the airport road that Francis will travel on his way into La Paz on Wednesday.
Francis will stop the Popemobile there, get out and pray.
Nicole Winfield reported from Rome. Associated Press writer Gonzalo Solano in Quito contributed to this report.
__
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:01:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli PM warns of growing concessions in Iran nuke talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150705/israeli-pm-warns-of-growing-concessions-in-iran-nuke-talks</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Israeli PM warns of growing concessions in Iran nuke talks
Israels Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, center, speaks during the weekly cabinet meeting in Jerusalem, Sunday. Baz Ratner  Pool Photo via AP
By The Associated Press
# Comments
JERUSALEM &gt;&gt; Israels prime minister says each day that passes brings greater Western concessions toward Iran in talks over its nuclear program.
Benjamin Netanyahu said Sunday the progressing talks in Vienna do not represent a breakthrough but rather a breakdown. Western diplomats are trying to reach a deal before an extended July 7 target date. Any deal would result in an end to longstanding sanctions against Iran.
Israel has been a vocal opponent of loosening sanctions in return for curbs on Irans nuclear program, saying this would just lead to a bomb and aid the Islamic Republic in expanding its network of global terrorism.
Netanyahu assailed a preliminary deal reached earlier this year. He says the looming accord is even worse than the one that previously allowed North Korea to go nuclear.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:01:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly strikes by US-led coalition targeting Islamic State stronghold in Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150705/deadly-strikes-by-us-led-coalition-targeting-islamic-state-stronghold-in-syria</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deadly strikes by US-led coalition targeting Islamic State stronghold in Syria
By Zeina Karam, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
BEIRUT &gt;&gt; U.S.-led coalition aircraft unleashed a series of airstrikes targeting the Islamic State groups stronghold of Raqqa in eastern Syria in what the coalition said Sunday was one of its most sustained aerial operations carried out in Syria to date.
IS said at least 10 people were killed and many others wounded.
At least 16 airstrikes were reported late Saturday and early Sunday, triggering successive explosions that shook the city and created panic among residents, activists said. The U.S.-led coalition often targets IS-held towns and cities in Syria, but the overnight strikes on Raqqa were rare in their intensity.
In a statement issued early Sunday, the coalition said it had conducted 16 airstrikes throughout Raqqa, destroying vital IS-controlled structures and transit routes in Syria.
The significant airstrikes tonight were executed to deny Daesh the ability to move military capabilities throughout Syria and into Iraq, said coalition spokesman Lt. Col. Thomas Gilleran, using the Arabic acronym for the Islamic State group.
This was one of the largest deliberate engagements we have conducted to date in Syria, and it will have debilitating effects on Daeshs ability to move from Raqqa, he said.
Raqqa is the de facto capital of the so-called Islamic caliphate declared a year ago by the Islamic State group in territories it controls in Iraq and Syria. The sustained airstrikes add pressure on the militants in Raqqa, still reeling from last months loss of the border town of Tal Abyad to Kurdish fighters. The town on the Turkish border was a major avenue for commerce and smuggling for the group.
A militant website said 10 people were killed and dozens of others wounded. An IS-affiliated Facebook page said one civilian was among those killed and 10 were wounded including women and children. It also said the bombing destroyed several bridges.
The IS-affiliated Aamaq news agency released a video of what it said was the effects of shelling Saturday by a U.S. drone on Raqqa. It showed several wounded men on a stretcher and at least three young boys being treated for wounds at what appeared to be a hospital.
A Raqqa-based anti-IS activist network reported eight civilians were killed by the coalition airstrikes, including a 10-year-old child.
The casualty figures could not be independently confirmed.
The network, called Raqqa is Being Silently Slaughtered, said at least one airstrike targeted a group of IS members in the city center. Another targeted an IS checkpoint while a third destroyed large parts of an IS-held brick factory in the city.
Advertisement
In the remote northeastern city of Hassakeh, IS suicide bombers detonated an explosives-laden truck near a main power plant Sunday. State-run news agency SANA reported casualties and damage in the plant on the southern edge of the city.
Fighting has raged in Hassakeh since the IS group attacked several southern neighborhoods held by government troops earlier this month. The violence has forced tens of thousands of residents to flee. The predominantly Kurdish city was split between government forces and Kurdish fighters, who have been fighting the IS group separately.
In Iraq, a Defense Ministry statement said government forces repelled an IS attack Sunday morning on the town of Haditha and the nearby Haditha dam in Anbar province. At least 20 militants were killed in the failed attack, said the statement, which did not provide any further information.
Iraqi forces, backed by Shiite militias, have been struggling to recapture areas lost to the IS group in the countrys west and north.
In May, the militant group scored a stunning victory, overrunning Ramadi, the provincial capital of western Anbar province. Yet, Haditha and some other towns remain under control of government forces and allied Sunni tribal fighters.
In Lebanon, some 200 Kurdish nationals staged a demonstration in downtown Beirut in solidarity with their brethren in Syria who are fighting against IS militants.
Associated Press writers Sameer N. Yacoub in Baghdad and Maamoun Youssef in Cairo contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 21:57:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bombings kill 19 people in and around Baghdad</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150704/bombings-kill-19-people-in-and-around-baghdad</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Bombings kill 19 people in and around Baghdad
By SAMEER N. YACOUB, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
BAGHDAD &gt;&gt; A series of attacks, mainly car bombs, in Iraq killed at least 19 people and wounded dozens on Saturday, authorities said.
Police officials said the deadliest attack occurred Saturday night when a car bomb exploded on a commercial street in Baghdads western neighborhood of Amil, killing nine people and wounding 24 others. Several shops and cars were damaged.
Earlier, police said a car bomb blast near a bus stop killed three people and wounded 15 in southern Baghdad. A bomb explosion near an outdoor market killed three people in Mhamoudiya town, just south of Baghdad.
Another car bomb went off near a row of restaurants in the Shiite town of Balad Ruz, killing four and wounding 14. Balad Ruz is 70 kilometers (45 miles) northeast of Baghdad.
Hospital officials confirmed the casualties from all the attacks. All officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they are not authorized to talk to reporters.
Nobody claimed responsibility for the attacks. Iraq sees near-daily bombings that are often claimed by the Islamic State group which seized a large swath of the country during an offensive last year. The Iraqi army, backed by Shiite and Sunni militia fighters, has been gradually retaking territory.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 19:58:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>America welcomes July 4 with hot dogs, cool music, cold beer</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/lifestyle/20150704/america-welcomes-july-4-with-hot-dogs-cool-music-cold-beer</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Fourth of July
America welcomes July 4 with hot dogs, cool music, cold beer
People hang from the Sky Flyer ride at the State Fair Meadowlands during a Fourth of July fireworks display, Friday, July 3, 2015, in East Rutherford, N.J. AP Photo/Julio Cortez
By The Associated Press
# Comments
A young girl waves a flag during rehearsal for the annual Boston Pops orchestra Fourth of July concert at the Hatch Shell in Boston, Friday, July 3, 2015. AP Photo/Michael Dwyer
The United States marks 239 years as an independent nation on Saturday as it celebrates the Fourth of July with parades, fireworks, food and music. Here are some highlights and lowlights of Independence Day celebrations:
PRESIDENTIAL HOPEFULS CAMPAIGN IN PARADES
Parades across Iowa and New Hampshire, which hold the first presidential nominating contests, were clear reminders of the race for the White House: Red balloons promoting Jeb! 2016, a tractor draped in a Rick Perry banner and dutiful volunteers holding signs and chanting for their chosen candidates.
Former Govs. Jeb Bush of Florida, Rick Perry of Texas and Lincoln Chafee of Rhode Island as well as South Carolina Sen. Lindsey Graham worked the crowd in Amherst, while Hillary Rodham Clinton marched in a parade in New Hampshires North Country. New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie and Florida Sen. Marco Rubio spent the holiday in New Hampshires Lakes Region, as Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal, Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders and former Maryland Gov. Martin OMalley met voters in Iowa.
NATHANS HOT DOG EATING CONTEST
Matt Stonie devoured 62 wieners and buns in 10 minutes to upset Joey Jaws Chestnut in the annual hot dog eating contest at Nathans Famous in Coney Island, breaking Chestnuts bid for a ninth straight victory.
Stonie, who finished second last year, beat Chestnut on Saturday by two wieners. Both are from San Jose, California. The third-place finisher ate 35 hot dogs.
Defending champion Miki Sudo won the womens division by devouring 38 wieners and buns in 10 minutes.
The Las Vegas woman retained the coveted mustard yellow winners championship belt by downing four more hot dogs than last year and besting Sonya Black Widow Thomas of Alexandria, Virginia, who devoured 31 wieners.
MUSIC, CULTURAL CELEBRATIONS ON NATIONAL MALL
A fife and drum corps, parade and concerts on the National Mall highlight the festivities in Washington.
As morning rains cleared, the capitals Fourth of July parade kicked off. The parade features marching bands, floats and balloons with plenty of red, white and blue.
The National Mall is also hosting the Smithsonian Folklife Festival. The annual festival features the culture of Peru this year, drawing thousands of visitors to the mall before the evening fireworks.
Advertisement
The U.S. Air Force Band performs Saturday evening on the Washington Monument grounds. And the big event is the Capitol Fourth concert on the west lawn of the Capitol, featuring Barry Manilow and the National Symphony Orchestra before the fireworks.
FIREWORKS SHOOT INTO COLORADO CROWD, BURN 9
Officials say nine people suffered minor burns during an accident at a fireworks show in Avon, Colorado.
Virginia Egger, the town manager in Avon, says a malfunction caused a fireworks shell to explode in its tube rather than firing into the sky Friday night. She says the misfired shell caused a rack of shells to tip, causing two or three shells to go off toward the crowd.
The accident occurred about 17 minutes into the 23-minute fireworks show over Nottingham Lake, bringing the event to a halt. The annual event attracts about 20,000 people.
The cause of the malfunction is under investigation.
IN AMERICAS BIRTHPLACE: CONCERTS, A PARADE AND BEER
Philadelphia started its Fourth of July celebration a little early.
The citys Liberty Block Party kicked off the festivities Friday near Independence Hall with music on three stages, treats from local food trucks and restaurants and a beer garden.
The Philly Pops performed patriotic tunes Friday night on the Independence Hall steps.
Saturdays events include a Celebration of Freedom ceremony, a parade through the citys historic district and a free concert and fireworks on the Benjamin Franklin Parkway. The Celebration of Freedom marks the 50th anniversary of a protest outside Independence Hall that would be a milestone in the fight for gay rights.
The concert features performances from Philadelphias own The Roots, Miguel and Jennifer Nettles.
BOSTON POPS FEATURE 42ND SHOW
Boston gospel singer Michelle Brooks-Thompson will perform the national anthem as Keith Lockhart celebrates his 20th year as conductor for the annual Boston Pops Fireworks Spectacular on Saturday.
The star-studded event is held at the DCR Hatch Cell in the citys Back Bay off the Charles River Esplanade and will also feature Broadway star Michael Cavanaugh, American Idol finalist Melinda Doolittle and Americas Got Talent finalist Sons of Serendip, a quartet who met at Boston University.
Drum and bugle corps the Boston Crusaders and the USO Show Troupe will also perform.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 19:10:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McCain: US must reassess Afghanistan troop withdrawal</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150704/mccain-us-must-reassess-afghanistan-troop-withdrawal</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>McCain: US must reassess Afghanistan troop withdrawal
By Associated Press
# Comments
KABUL, Afghanistan &gt;&gt; The ongoing Taliban offensive in Afghanistan demands a reassessment of the Obama administrations current plan to drawdown U.S. forces, U.S. Sen. John McCain said Saturday during a visit to the countrys capital.
The Republican told reporters that Afghan national forces are fighting bravely, but suffering heavy losses in the field.
American and international troops have already stopped playing a combat role, remaining as trainers for local forces. The international numbers will be reduced further at the end of 2016. But McCain said reductions should be based on conditions on the ground.
With the rise of ISIS and the distinct fighting season that is marked this year, the threat environment continues to evolve in ways that clearly, in my view, demands a reassessment of the administrations current calendar-driven drawdown of U.S. forces with a plan that must be based on conditions on the ground, McCain said.
Meanwhile, Afghan lawmakers rejected President Ashraf Ghanis nominee for defense minister, a position that has remained empty for more than nine months amid some of the toughest fighting since the Taliban insurgency began 14 years ago. Masoom Stanekzai received 84 out of the 107 votes needed for parliamentary approval.
Stanekzais rejection reflects in part a power struggle between Ghani and Afghanistans Chief Executive Abdullah Abdullah. Stanekzai, the second nominee put forth by Ghani to be rejected, is also seen by some to be ineffective, based on the chaotic security situation around the country.
Stanekzai led the High Peace Council negotiating body charged with ending the conflict with the Taliban. He has been serving as the countrys top defense official in an acting capacity.
In January, Gen. Sher Mohammad Karimi also failed to get enough votes in parliament. It could be months before a new nominee for the position is put forth.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
