<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 19:00:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore police complete Freddie Gray death investigation, give findings to prosecutors</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150430/baltimore-police-complete-freddie-gray-death-investigation-give-findings-to-prosecutors</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Police
Baltimore police complete Freddie Gray death investigation, give findings to prosecutors
Baltimore Police Department Commissioner Anthony Batts announces that the department's investigation into the death of Freddie Gray was turned over to the State's Attorney's office a day early at a news conference, Thursday, April 30, 2015, in Baltimore. Pictured at right is Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis. Batts did not give details of the report or take questions. He said the department dedicated more than 30 detectives to working on the case and report.  ( (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky)
By Amanda Lee Myers and David Dishneau, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
BALTIMORE &gt;&gt; Baltimore police have completed their investigation into the death of Freddie Gray and turned over their findings to prosecutors  one day earlier than the departments self-imposed deadline, the commissioner said Thursday morning.
Authorities have said the states attorneys office will review the information, consider charges and decide how to move forward in the death of Gray, who was stopped by police April 12. He suffered spinal injuries while in custody and died a week later.
In his announcement at a news conference, Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts did not give details of the report or take questions. He said the department dedicated more than 30 detectives to working on the case and report.
I understand the frustration; I understand the sense of urgency. ... That is why we have finished it a day ahead of time, Batts said.
Batts also said police would continue to work on the case at the direction of the states attorney.
At the same news conference, Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis reviewed the timeline of Grays time in custody and his death. Gray was arrested after he made eye contact with officers and ran. After a chase, officers pinned him down and handcuffed him. They loaded him into a van and put leg cuffs on him when officers said he became irate in the wagon.
Davis said Thursday that police discovered a new stop the van made with Gray in it, but they did not say what happened.
Gray was eventually taken to a hospital. He died a week later.
On Wednesday, rumors circulated that some kind of verdict will be rendered when police handed their report to prosecutors. But Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake and other officials worked to dispel that notion.
It became very clear ... that people misunderstood, Rawlings-Blake said.
Hassan Murphy, a lawyer for Grays family, underscored their comments, saying, This family wants justice and they want justice that comes at the right time and not too soon.
Said Rawlings-Blake: Whatever time the states attorneys office needs to make that determination, the family wants to get it right.
In widespread protests Wednesday night  not only in Baltimore, but in several cities including Boston, New York and Washington, D.C.  it was clear that tensions over the case are far from subsiding.
While the demonstrations were mostly peaceful, police made numerous arrests, including 16 in Baltimore and at least 60 in New York.
Grays death was the latest in a series of high-profile cases around the country in which black men have died as the result of encounters with police.
Advertisement
Similar protests have erupted over the deaths of Michael Brown in Ferguson, Missouri, and Eric Garner in New York last year, and the death earlier this month in South Carolina of Walter Scott. Scott was fatally shot in the back by a white police officer who has since been charged with murder.
Associated Press writers Ben Nuckols, Juliet Linderman, Matthew Barakat, Tom Foreman Jr., Jessica Gresko, Brian Witte and Jeff Horwitz contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 17:11:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>200 girls, 93 women rescued from Boko Haram</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150430/200-girls-93-women-rescued-from-boko-haram</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>200 girls, 93 women rescued from Boko Haram
By The Associated Press
# Comments
MAIDUGURI, Nigeria &gt;&gt; A day after the Nigerian army celebrated the rescue of 200 girls and 93 women in the forest stronghold of Boko Haram, the armyS spokesman said more women and children believed to have been abducted by the Islamic extremists were rescued as firefights broke out there.
Several lives were lost including that of a soldier and a woman during shootouts in nine separate extremist camps in the Sambisa Forest, according to a statement late Wednesday from Col. Sani Usman. He said eight women sustained gunshot wounds and four soldiers were seriously injured.
Some of the females who were freed earlier have been so transformed by their captivity that they opened fire on their rescuers, authorities have said. A veteran counselor said Wednesday they would need intensive psychological treatment.
The army spokesman said several Boko Haram field commanders and foot soldiers were killed and combat tanks and munitions of high caliber used by Boko Haram were recovered while others were destroyed.
The troops have also rescued additional women and children, the statement said, without saying how many were rescued. They have been evacuated to a safety zone for further processing.
The military was flying in medical and intelligence teams to evaluate the former captives, many of whom were severely traumatized, Usman said earlier.
It remained unclear if any of the schoolgirls kidnapped from the northeastern town of Chibok a year ago were to be among the 200 girls and 93 women whose rescue was announced on Tuesday.
The plight of the schoolgirls, who have become known as the Chibok girls, aroused international outrage and a campaign for their release under the hashtag #BringBackOurGirls. Their kidnapping brought Boko Haram, whose nickname means Western education is forbidden in the local Hausa language, to the worlds attention. Of the Chibok girls, 219 remain missing.
Nigerian military and counter-insurgency spokesmen have said they have information indicating at least some of the Chibok girls still are being held in the Sambisa Forest.A counselor who has treated other women freed from Boko Haram captivity said some had become indoctrinated into believing the groups Islamic extremist ideology, while others had established strong emotional attachments to militants they had been forced to marry.
Some of the about 90 women and girls freed by the army four months ago in Yobe state, for example, had upset their community on their return by maintaining that the militants were good people who had treated them well, said the counselor, who spoke to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because he has been targeted by the militants in the past.
Advertisement
The trauma suffered by the (abducted) women and girls is truly horrific, said Amnesty Internationals Africa director for research and advocacy, Netsanet Belay. Some have been repeatedly raped, sold into sexual slavery or indoctrinated and even forced to fight for Boko Haram.
Amnesty International said earlier this month that at least 2,000 women and girls have been taken by Boko Haram since the start of 2014.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 17:05:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASA spacecraft Messenger to crash on Mercury Thursday after 4 years of orbit</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/science/20150429/nasa-spacecraft-messenger-to-crash-on-mercury-thursday-after-4-years-of-orbit</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Space exploration
NASA spacecraft Messenger to crash on Mercury Thursday after 4 years of orbit
In this undated photo provided by NASA, technicians with The Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory in Titusville, Fla., prepare the MESSESNGER spacecraft for a move to a hazardous processing facility in preparation for loading the spacecrafts hypergolic propellants. NASA via AP
By Marcia Dunn, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
This October 2008 image provided by NASA shows the Rembrandt impact basin discovered by the Messenger spacecraft during its second flyby of Mercury. NASA, Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory, Carnegie Institution of Washington via AP
CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. &gt;&gt; NASAs Mercury-orbiting spacecraft, Messenger, is going out with a bang this week, adding a hefty crater to the little planet closest to the sun.
The first spacecraft to circle Mercury, Messenger is expected to slip out of orbit and slam into Mercury on Thursday following a successful four-year tour of the rocky planet. The spacecraft will be traveling 8,750 mph (14,081 kph) when it hits, fast enough to carve out a crater 52 feet (16 meters) wide. The spacecraft itself stretches 10 feet (3 meters) solar wingtip to wingtip.
Messenger has run out of fuel, but ground controllers managed in recent weeks to eke out some extra life, raising Messengers orbit by dipping into helium gas reserves not originally intended for use as fuel. But now thats all gone and Messenger is at the mercy of gravity.
I guess the end is coming, the Messenger team said via Twitter earlier this week. After 10 years, spacecraft will end life as just another crater on Mercurys surface.
A look at Mercurys soon-to-be-obliterated travel companion:
ROUNDABOUT FLIGHT
Messenger rocketed away from Cape Canaveral, Florida, in August 2004. It flew twice past Venus and three times past Mercury, before entering orbit around Mercury in March 2011. Only one other spacecraft, NASAs Mariner 10, has ever visited Mercury, and that was back in the 1970s. Mariner 10 flew past, but did not orbit the innermost planet. The $427 million Messenger mission was developed and run for NASA by Johns Hopkins University.
SCIENCE DISCOVERIES
During its four years in orbit  comprising more than 4,000 laps  Messenger has revealed volcanic deposits at Mercury that are helping to explain the planets important eruptive and interior-melting past; polar caps of frozen water at or near the surface; and incredible global shrinkage thanks to a cooling interior. In addition, despite its proximity to the sun, Mercury is more abundant in volatile elements, like potassium and sulfur, than anticipated before Messengers arrival, according to Messengers principal investigator Sean Solomon, director of Columbia Universitys Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory. Planetary scientists will be looking at Messengers huge stash of data for years, probably for decades, as we try to understand the origin and evolution of Mercury, Solomon said.
SUPER SUNSHADE
Messengers creators needed to keep the spacecraft cool during its super-hot mission at Mercury. Its an enormously hostile environment, said Jim Green, director of planetary science for NASA. Designers came up with a novel sunshade of lightweight ceramic cloth. This sunscreen tolerated more than 600 degrees Fahrenheit (316 degrees Celsius) on the front, while keeping everything behind it at room temperature, including the seven scientific instruments. Messenger also regularly performed an intricate dance to balance all the infrared heat that was reflected off Mercury back at the spacecraft. At the same time, engineers equipped Messenger with numerous heaters to keep the fuel from freezing and the electronics from faltering when the spacecraft ducked behind the planet, away from the sun.
Advertisement
SMASHING END
On Thursday, Messenger is expected to crash into the side of Mercury facing away from Earth. So there will be no cameras or observatories to witness the impact. Scientists expect to gather information from Messenger until 10 to 15 minutes before its fatal plunge. The expected crash site is about two-thirds of the way up the planet, near the north pole. Mercury is the smallest planet  a little bigger than our moon.
UPCOMING AT MERCURY:
A pair of European and Japanese spacecraft will aim for Mercury following a 2017 launch from South Americas French Guiana. It will take seven years for the two satellites to reach Mercury and enter its orbit, in 2024. The mission is called BepiColombo after the late Italian scientist who came up with the calculations for repeated fly-bys of Mercury by Mariner 10.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed Apr 29 16:50:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore streets once rocked by riots quiet after curfew</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150429/baltimore-streets-once-rocked-by-riots-quiet-after-curfew/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Baltimore streets once rocked by riots quiet after curfew
Members of the National Guard walk along North Avenue near where Monday's riots occurred following the funeral for Freddie Gray, after a 10 p.m. curfew went into effect Wednesday, April 29, 2015, in Baltimore. (AP Photo/David Goldman)
By Amanda Lee Myers and David Dishneau, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A man is arrested for violating the curfew Tuesday, April 28, 2015, in Baltimore. A line of police behind riot shields hurled smoke grenades and fired pepper balls at dozens of protesters to enforce a citywide curfew. (AP Photo/David Goldman)
BALTIMORE &gt;&gt; Baltimore streets previously rocked by riots were quiet Wednesday morning at the lifting of a nighttime curfew that was enforced by 3,000 police and National Guardsmen.
The curfew ended at 5 a.m. with no reports of disturbances in the early morning hours. The morning rush was getting underway with traffic flowing on most streets downtown.
The curfew, which went into effect at 10 p.m. Tuesday, got off to a not-so-promising start, however, as about 200 protesters initially ignored the warnings of police officers and the pleas of community activists to disperse.
Some threw water bottles or lay down on the ground. A line of police behind riot shields hurled tear gas canisters and fired pepper balls at the crowd and slowly advanced forward to push it back. Demonstrators picked up the canisters and hurled them back at officers. But the crowd rapidly dispersed and was down to just a few dozen people within minutes.
The clash came after a day of high tension but relative peace in Baltimore, which was rocked by looting and widespread arson Monday in the citys worst outbreak of rioting since 1968.
Police, city leaders and many residents condemned the violence, and hundreds of volunteers showed up Tuesday to sweep the streets of glass and other debris.
Just before midnight Tuesday, Baltimore Police Commissioner Anthony Batts declared the curfew a success.
We do not have a lot of active movement throughout the city as a whole. ... Tonight I think the biggest thing is the citizens are safe, the city is stable, he said. We hope to maintain it that way.
Batts said a total of 10 people were arrested after the curfew went into effect: two for looting, one for disorderly conduct, and seven for violating the curfew.
Gov. Larry Hogan, Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake and other officials made appearances throughout the day, promising to reclaim and restore pride to their city. Baltimore Public Schools CEO Gregory Thornton said in a notice posted on the school systems website that schools will be open Wednesday. The notice said after-school sports and clubs will also take place.
But life was unlikely to get completely back to normal anytime soon: The curfew was to go back into effect at 10 p.m. Wednesday and baseball officials  in what may be a first in the sports 145-year history  announced that Wednesdays Baltimore Orioles game at Camden Yards would be closed to the public.
Advertisement
The violence set off soul-searching among community leaders and others, with some suggesting the uprising was not just about race or the police department, but also about high unemployment, high crime, poor housing, broken-down schools and lack of opportunity in Baltimores inner-city neighborhoods  issues that are not going away anytime soon.
Activists also stressed that they would continue to press authorities for answers in the case of Freddie Gray, a 25-year-old black man who died of a spinal-cord injury under mysterious circumstances while in police custody. His case is what spurred Mondays riots.
A group of pastors announced plans to hold a rally and prayer vigil for the city of Baltimore and Grays family at noon Wednesday and to draw public attention to 17 police accountability bills the state legislature failed to pass during the recent legislative session.
Meanwhile, under the state of emergency Gov. Hogan declared Monday, the more than 200 people arrested since the unrest began could wait longer than usual to have their day in court.
Normally, state law requires that people arrested without warrants appear before a court official within 24 hours of their arrests. But as part of the state of emergency, the governor extended the period to no later than 47 hours, according to a letter he sent Tuesday to Judge Barbara Baer Waxman, the administrative judge for the Baltimore District Court.
This exercise of my authority is necessary to protect the public safety and to address the more than 200 arrests that were made by Baltimore Police Department and other law enforcement officials, Hogan wrote in the letter, a copy of which was obtained by The Associated Press.
Associated Press writers Juliet Linderman, Matthew Barakat, Tom Foreman Jr., Jessica Gresko and Jeff Horwitz contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Apr 28 16:26:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court to hear historic same-sex marriage arguments</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150428/supreme-court-to-hear-historic-same-sex-marriage-arguments</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Same sex marriage
Supreme Court to hear historic same-sex marriage arguments
Shelly Bailes, 74, left, and her wife Ellen Pontac, 73, both of Davis, Calif., kiss in front of the Supreme Court in Washington, Tuesday, April 28, 2015. The Supreme Court is set to hear historic arguments in cases that could make same-sex marriage the law of the land. The justices are meeting Tuesday to offer the first public indication of where they stand in the dispute over whether states can continue defining marriage as the union of a man and a woman, or whether the Constitution gives gay and lesbian couples the right to marry. (AP Photo/Cliff Owen)
By Mark Sherman, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; The Supreme Court is set to hear historic arguments in cases that could make same-sex marriage the law of the land.
The justices are meeting Tuesday to offer the first public indication of where they stand in the dispute over whether states can continue defining marriage as the union of a man and a woman, or whether the Constitution gives gay and lesbian couples the right to marry.
The court is hearing extended arguments, scheduled to last 2  hours, which also will explore whether states that do not permit same-sex marriage must nonetheless recognize such unions from elsewhere.
Same-sex couples can marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia.
People on both sides of the issue gathered outside the marble courthouse early Tuesday. Some waved gay rights banners, while others carried placards proclaiming marriage as the union of a man and a woman. Homo sex is a sin, read one of the more mildly phrased signs.
The cases before the court come from Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee, four of the 14 remaining states that allow only heterosexual marriage. Those four states had their marriage bans upheld by the federal appeals court in Cincinnati in November. That is the only federal appeals court that has ruled in favor of the states since the Supreme Court in 2013 struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law.
Justice Anthony Kennedy has written the courts three prior gay rights decisions, including the case from two years ago. All eyes will be on Kennedy for any signals that he is prepared to take the final step in granting marriage rights to same-sex couples.
Such an outcome was inconceivable just a few years ago.
The first state to allow gay and lesbian couples to marry was Massachusetts, in 2004. Even as recently as October, barely a third of the states permitted it. Now, same-sex couples can marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia, a dramatic change in the law that has been accompanied by an equally fast shift in public opinion.
The main thrust of the states case is to reframe the debate.
This case is not about the best marriage definition. It is about the fundamental question regarding how our democracy resolves such debates about social policy: Who decides, the people of each state or the federal judiciary? John Bursch, representing Michigan, wrote in his main brief to the court.
Other arguments by the states and more than five-dozen briefs by their defenders warn the justices of harms that could result if you remove the man-woman definition and replace it with the genderless any-two-persons definition, said Gene Schaerr, a Washington lawyer.
Advertisement
The push for same-sex marriage comes down to fairness, said Mary Bonauto, who will argue on behalf of the plaintiffs. The people who have brought their cases to the Supreme Court are real people who are deeply committed to each other. Yet they are foreclosed from making that commitment simply because of who they are, she told reporters last week.
Arguments made by Bonauto, other lawyers for same-sex couples and more than six-dozen supporting briefs have strong echoes of the 1967 Loving v. Virginia case, in which the Supreme Court struck down state bans on interracial marriage. In that case, the justices were unanimous that those bans violated the constitutional rights of interracial couples.
No one expects unanimity this time. But many believe the justices will take the final step toward what gay rights supporters call marriage equality, in part because they allowed orders in favor of same-sex couples to take effect even as the issue made its way through the federal court system.
That was action through inaction, as other judges played a major role over the years. Only 11 states have granted marriage rights to same-sex couples through the ballot or the legislature. Court rulings are responsible for all the others.
A decision is expected in late June.
Follow Mark Sherman on Twitter at http://www.twitter.com/shermancourt .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Apr 28 16:20:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>250 people feared missing after mudslide in Nepal village</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150428/250-people-feared-missing-after-mudslide-in-nepal-village</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
250 people feared missing after mudslide in Nepal village
People gather camping and climbing equipment that was earlier strewn about after an avalanche hit the area on Saturday at Everest Base Camp, Nepal, Tuesday, April 28, 2015. An avalanche on Saturday, set off by the massive earthquake that struck Nepal, left more than a dozen people dead and dozens more injured. (AP Photo/Nima Namgyal Sherpa)
By Katy Daigle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
GORKHA, Nepal &gt;&gt; An official says 250 people are believed missing following a mudslide and avalanche in an isolated village in rural Nepal not far from the epicenter of Saturdays powerful earthquake.
District official Gautam Rimal says heavy snow had been falling Tuesday near the village, Ghodatabela. He said officials received initial reports of the disaster by phone but then lost contact.
The village, about a 12-hour walk from the nearest town, is along a popular trekking route, but it was not clear if the missing included trekkers.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Apr 26 19:19:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Death toll in Nepal earthquake rises to more than 3,200</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150426/death-toll-in-nepal-earthquake-rises-to-more-than-3200</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Death toll in Nepal earthquake rises to more than 3,200
By Binaj Gurubacharya and Katy Daigle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A woman weeps during the cremation of a victim of Saturdays earthquake, at the Pashupatinath temple, on the banks of Bagmati river, in Kathmandu, Nepal, Sunday. The earthquake centered outside Kathmandu, the capital, was the worst to hit the South Asian nation in over 80 years. It destroyed swaths of the oldest neighborhoods of Kathmandu, and was strong enough to be felt all across parts of India, Bangladesh, Chinas region of Tibet and Pakistan. Bernat Armangue  The Associated Press
KATHMANDU, Nepal &gt;&gt; The death toll from Nepals earthquake rose to 3,218 on Monday, two days after the massive quake ripped across this Himalayan nation, leaving tens of thousands shell-shocked and sleeping in streets.
Aid groups received the first word from remote mountain villages  reports that suggested many communities perched on mountainsides were devastated or struggling to cope.
Landslides hindered rescue teams that tried to use mountain trails to reach those in need, said Prakash Subedi, chief district official in the Gorkha region, where the quake was centered.
 Photos: Nepal Earthquake
Villages like this are routinely affected by landslides, and its not uncommon for entire villages of 200, 300, up to 1,000 people to be completely buried by rock falls, said Matt Darvas, a member of the aid group World Vision. It will likely be helicopter access only.
Saturdays magnitude 7.8 earthquake spread horror from Kathmandu to small villages and to the slopes of Mount Everest, triggering an avalanche that buried part of the base camp packed with foreign climbers preparing to make their summit attempts. At least 18 people died there and 61 were injured.
Deputy Inspector General of Police Komal Singh Bam said Monday that the death toll had risen to 3,218 people but he gave no further details. So far 18 people have also been confirmed dead in an avalanche that swept through the Mount Everest base camp in the wake of the earthquake. Another 61 people were killed in neighboring India. China reported that 20 people had died in Tibet.
Kathmandu district chief administrator Ek Narayan Aryal said tents and water were being handed out Monday at 10 locations in Kathmandu, but that aftershocks were leaving everyone jittery.
There have been nearly 100 earthquakes and aftershocks, which is making rescue work difficult. Even the rescuers are scared and running because of them, he said.
Tens of thousands spent the night sleeping in parks or on a golf course. Others camped in open squares lined by cracked buildings and piles of rubble.
We dont feel safe at all. There have been so many aftershocks. It doesnt stop, said Rajendra Dhungana, 34, who spent the day with his nieces family for her cremation at the Pashuputi Nath Temple in Katmandu. Ive watched hundreds of bodies burn.
Advertisement
The capital city is largely a collection of small, poorly constructed brick apartment buildings. But outside of the oldest neighborhoods, many in Kathmandu were surprised by how few modern structures collapsed in the quake.
Aid workers also warned that the situation could be far worse near the epicenter. The U.S. Geological Survey said the quake was centered near Lamjung, about 80 kilometers (50 miles) northwest of Kathmandu.
The earthquake was the worst to hit the South Asian nation in more than 80 years. It destroyed swaths of the oldest neighborhoods of Kathmandu and was strong enough to be felt all across parts of India, Bangladesh, Chinas region of Tibet and Pakistan.
Nepals worst recorded earthquake in 1934 measured 8.0 and all but destroyed the cities of Kathmandu, Bhaktapur and Patan.
Rescuers aided by international teams spent Sunday digging through rubble of buildings - concrete slabs, bricks, iron beams, wood - to look for survivors. Because the air was filled with chalky concrete dust, many people wore breathing masks or held shawls over their faces.
Hundreds of people in Kathmandus western Kalanki neighborhood nervously watched the slow progress of a single backhoe digging into the rubble of the collapsed Lumbini Guest House, once a three-story budget hotel.
Most areas were without power and water. The United Nations said hospitals in the Kathmandu Valley were overcrowded and running out of emergency supplies and space to store corpses.
Most shops in Kathmandu were closed after the government declared a weeklong period of recovery. Only fruit vendors and pharmacies seemed to be doing business.
More people are coming now, fruit seller Shyam Jaiswal said. They cannot cook so they need to buy something they can eat raw.
Jaiswal said stocks were running out, and more shipments were not expected for at least a week, but added, We are not raising prices. That would be illegal, immoral profit.
The quake will probably put a huge strain on the resources of this impoverished country best known for Everest, the highest mountain in the world. The economy of Nepal, a nation of 27.8 million people, relies heavily on tourism, principally trekking and Himalayan mountain climbing.
The first nations to respond were Nepals neighbors - India, China and Pakistan, all of which have been jockeying for influence over the landlocked nation. Nepal remains closest to India, with which it shares deep political, cultural and religious ties.
Other countries sending support Sunday included the United States, Canada, the United Arab Emirates, Britain, Germany, France, Poland, Italy, Israel and Singapore.
An American military plane left Delawares Dover Air Force Base for Nepal, carrying 70 people, including a disaster-assistance response team and an urban search-and-rescue team, and 45 tons of cargo, the Pentagon said.
Associated Press writers Muneeza Naqvi and Tim Sullivan in New Delhi contributed to this report.
More
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Apr 27 01:31:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Experts gathered in Nepal a week ago to ready for earthquake</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150426/experts-gathered-in-nepal-a-week-ago-to-ready-for-earthquake</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Experts gathered in Nepal a week ago to ready for earthquake
By SETH BORENSTEIN, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Nepals devastating earthquake was the disaster experts knew was coming.
Just a week ago, about 50 earthquake and social scientists from around the world came to Kathmandu, Nepal, to figure out how to get this poor, congested, overdeveloped, shoddily built area to prepare better for the big one, a repeat of the 1934 temblor that leveled this city. They knew they were racing the clock, but they didnt know when what they feared would strike.
It was sort of a nightmare waiting to happen, said seismologist James Jackson, head of the earth sciences department at the University of Cambridge in England. Physically and geologically what happened is exactly what we thought would happen.
But he didnt expect the massive quake that struck Saturday to happen so soon. The magnitude 7.8 earthquake killed nearly 1,400 and counting and caused widespread destruction.
I was walking through that very area where that earthquake was and I thought at the very time that the area was heading for trouble, said Jackson, lead scientist for Earthquakes Without Frontiers, a group that tries to make Asia more able to bounce back from these disasters and was having the meeting.
A Kathmandu earthquake has long been feared, not just because of the natural seismic fault, but because of the local, more human conditions that make it worse.
The same size shaking can have bigger effects on different parts of the globe because of building construction and population and thats something the U.S. Geological Survey calculates ahead of time. So the same level of severe shaking would cause 10 to 30 people to die per million residents in California, but 1,000 maybe more in Nepal, and up to 10,000 in parts of Pakistan, India, Iran and China, said USGS seismologist David Wald.
While the trigger of the disaster is natural  an earthquake  the consequences are very much man-made, Jackson said. Except for landslides, which in this case are a serious problem, its buildings that kill people not earthquakes, Jackson said. If you lived in a flat desert with no water, an earthquake wouldnt harm you, but then few people want to live there.
The real problem in Asia is how people have concentrated in dangerous places, Jackson said.
Kathmandu was warned, first by the Earth itself: this is the fifth significant quake there in the last 205 years, including the massive 1934 one.
They knew they had a problem but it was so large they didnt where to start, how to start, said Hari Ghi, southeast Asia regional coordinator for Geohazards International, a group that works on worldwide quake risks. Ghi, Jackson and Wald said Nepal was making progress on reducing its vulnerability to earthquakes, but not quickly or big enough.
Advertisement
Ghis group on April 12 updated a late 1990s report summarizing the Kathmandu Valley risks.
With an annual population growth rate of 6.5 percent and one of the highest urban densities in the world, the 1.5 million people living in the Kathmandu Valley were clearly facing a serious and growing earthquake risk, the report said, laying out the problem the valley faces. It was also clear that the next large earthquake to strike near the Valley would cause significantly greater loss of life, structural damage, and economic hardship than past earthquakes had inflicted.
And for years there were no building codes and rampant development so homes and other structures could be built without any regards to earthquakes, the report said. There are now building codes, but that doesnt help the older structures, and the codes arent overly strong, Ghi said.
Its actually even made worse because of local inheritance laws that require property be split equally among all sons, Jackson said. So that means buildings are split vertically among brothers making very thin rickety homes that need more space so people add insecure living space on additional floors, he said.
The construction is appalling in Kathmandu, Jackson said.
Poverty and pollution make the problem worse, Jackson said. Thats because people dont spend time worrying about some future earthquake because they have more pressing problems.
If you live in the Kathmandu Valley you have other priorities, daily threats and daily nasty things happen to you in terms of air quality, water quality, pollution, traffic and just poverty, Jackson said. But it doesnt mean that the earthquakes go away.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Apr 27 01:11:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As nuclear powers meet, New York rally demands end to weapons</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150426/as-nuclear-powers-meet-new-york-rally-demands-end-to-weapons</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
As nuclear powers meet, New York rally demands end to weapons
People participate in an anti-nuclear rally in Union Square in New York, Sunday. This year marks the 70th anniversary of the United States using nuclear bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in Japan. Seth Wenig  The Associated Press
By Cara Anna, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A woman holds a fan with a message during an anti-nuclear rally in Union Square in New York, Sunday. This year marks the 70th anniversary of the United States using nuclear bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in Japan. Seth Wenig  The Associated Press
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; Global activists presented 8 million petitions to the U.N. disarmament chief on Sunday demanding a world free of nuclear weapons, kicking off a conference by world powers to review progress toward eventually achieving total disarmament.
Secretary of State John Kerry and Irans foreign minister are both expected to speak at the conference Monday amid intense interest in the fate of negotiations over Irans nuclear program.
The Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty, or NPT, Review Conference happens every five years, and experts have warned that little progress is expected this time, especially with relations cool between the two largest nuclear powers, Russia and the United States.
The more than a thousand demonstrators demanded that the worlds nine nuclear-armed countries do far more toward cutting stockpiles.
Many protesters were from Japan, the only country ever hit by a nuclear attack. Fragile survivors of the U.S. attacks on Hiroshima and Nagasaki 70 years ago led the way in wheelchairs.
I hope we dont have to have the NPT five years from now! said 83-year-old Hiroshima survivor Setsuko Thurlow.
The U.N. disarmament chief, Angela Kane, stood by the wall of boxes of petitions and told the crowd that receiving the millions of names was very humbling. She said she had signed one of the petitions herself when she was in Japan.
Kane said she spoke Friday with U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon and told the crowd, Hes with you.
As the march made its way uptown past the Manhattan brunch crowd, some bystanders showed little grasp of the number of nuclear weapons remaining around the world today.
Guesses ranged from 120 to 150,000 to no idea whatsoever. Experts estimate its more like 16,000.
Hundreds. Thousands. Doesnt matter. Theyre all bad, said Hal Alterwein, 75. All you need is one nut case to blow it up.
The other nuclear-armed countries are Britain, France, China, India, Pakistan, Israel and North Korea. Only the United States, Russia, Britain, France and China have signed on to the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Apr 27 01:10:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Corinthian Colleges to shut down all 28 remaining campuses</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150426/corinthian-colleges-to-shut-down-all-28-remaining-campuses</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Corinthian Colleges to shut down all 28 remaining campuses
By The Associated Press
# Comments
SANTA ANA &gt;&gt; Corinthian Colleges will shut down all of its remaining 28 ground campuses, displacing about 16,000 students, less than two weeks after the U.S. Department of Education announced it was fining the for-profit institution $30 million for misrepresentation.
In a statement Sunday, the Santa Ana, California-based company said it was working with other schools to help students continue their education. The closures include Heald College campuses in California, Hawaii and Oregon, as well as Everest and WyoTech schools in California, Arizona and New York.
Corinthian was one of the countrys largest for-profit educational institutions. It collapsed last summer amid a cash shortage and fraud allegations.
The Education Department contends that Corinthian failed to comply with requests to address allegations of falsifying job placement data and altering grades and attendance records. It agreed to sell or close its campuses under pressure from the department.
Earlier in April, the department fined subsidiary Heald College, alleging the school had shown a pattern of falsifying post-graduation employment data. In one instance, the companys Honolulu campus declared a student had found work in her chosen field of accounting, even though administrators knew she was working at Taco Bell, the department said.
Most of the companys former schools have been sold, and Corinthian attempted to sell Heald as well but was blocked by California attorney general Kamala Harris refusal to provide prospective buyers with a release from liability.
The company said Sunday it had been in advanced negotiations with several parties to sell the 150-year-old college and allow outside partners to let Everest and WyoTech students continue their education but was unsuccessful.
Unfortunately, the current regulatory environment would not allow us to complete a transaction with several interested parties that would have allowed for a seamless transition for our students, Corinthian CEO Jack Massimino said in a statement.
The company also defended its work, saying its graduation and job placement rates compared favorably with community colleges and that many of its students hadnt been able to get their needs met at a traditional higher education institution.
Neither our board of directors, our management, our faculty, nor our students believe these schools deserved to be forced to close, Massimino said.
A group of current and former Corinthian students are petitioning the Education Department to waive their federal student debt based on the alleged misconduct. According to the companys filings, the schools generated $1.2 billion government loans its final year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Apr 26 23:19:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israel says airstrike on Syrian border targeted militants</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150426/israel-says-airstrike-on-syrian-border-targeted-militants</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Israel says airstrike on Syrian border targeted militants
By Ian Deitch, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
JERUSALEM &gt;&gt; Israels military said Sunday it launched an airstrike on its border with Syria after spotting militants carrying a bomb in the Israeli-held Golan Heights.
The military said it carried out the strike after troops saw a group of armed terrorists approach the border with an explosive intended to target Israeli troops. It said that Israeli aircraft targeted the squad, preventing the attack.
It did not offer any casualty figure for the strike. The Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said four Syrian soldiers were killed by a missile fired from Israeli-occupied territory in the Golan. Observatory director Rami Abdurrahman said it was not clear whether the missile was fired by a plane or from a vehicle.
On Twitter, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sent messages commending the soldiers involved in the strike.
Any attempt to harm our soldiers and civilians will be met with a determined response like the military action tonight that thwarted a terror attack, Netanyahu said.
No one immediately claimed responsibility of the attack launched from inside Syria, which has been in the grips of a civil war since 2011. Syrian state media did not immediately report on the strike.
Israel has tried to stay out of the war in Syria, but it has spilled into the country before. In September, the Israeli military shot down a Syrian fighter jet in airspace over the Golan Heights, which Israel captured from Syria in the 1967 Middle East war and later annexed in a move that has never been internationally recognized. In August, Israel shot down a drone that came into the same airspace from Syria.
Israeli troops also have responded to occasional mortar fire from Syria. Israel says some of the attacks may have been accidental spillover, while others have been intentionally aimed at Israeli civilians and soldiers. It has always held Syria responsible for any cross-border fire.
Israel and Syria are bitter enemies. While relations are hostile, the ruling Assad family in Syria has kept the border area with Israel quiet for most of the past 40 years. Israel is concerned that the possible ouster of embattled President Bashir Assads ouster could push the country into the hands of Islamic State extremists or al-Qaida linked militants, or plunge the region further into sectarian warfare.
It also repeatedly has threatened to take military action to prevent Syria from transferring advanced weapons to its ally, Hezbollah. Israel is believed to have carried out several airstrikes in Syria in recent years that have targeted sophisticated weapons systems, including Russian-made anti-aircraft missiles and Iranian-made missiles.
There were reports in Arab media last week that Israel had carried out another attack on such weapons in Syria. Israeli officials have not commented.
But just hours before the border strike Sunday night, Israeli Defense Minister Moshe Yaalon warned Syria and Iran against arming Hezbollah with such weapons.
Advertisement
We will not allow the transfer of quality weapons to terror groups led by Hezbollah and we know how to reach them and those that dispatch them at any time, Yaalon said. He added that Iran is continuously trying to find ways to arm Hezbollah with the weapons.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Apr 26 20:05:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Furious 7' holds on to box office; 'Age of Ultron' looms</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150426/furious-7-holds-on-to-box-office-age-of-ultron-looms/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Box office receipts
Furious 7 holds on to box office; Age of Ultron looms
This undated file photo provided by Universal Pictures shows, Paul Walker as Brian, in a scene from Furious 7. Furious 7 topped Age of Adaline and lead the box office for a fourth straight week. The Universal action film made an estimated $18.3 million in North American theaters over the weekend, according to studio estimates Sunday. Universal Pictures  The Associated Press file
By Jake Coyle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; Furious 7 enjoyed a victory lap over the weekend, becoming only the third film ever to make $1 billion internationally and leading the domestic box office for the fourth straight week. But the movie thats poised to topple the Universal juggernaut, Marvels The Avengers: Age of Ultron, revved up overseas with a massive $201.2 million debut.
In North American theaters, Furious 7 had enough left in the tank to top all films with an estimated $18.3 million, according to studio estimates Sunday. While the film has been a huge domestic hit, its been even bigger abroad  particularly in China, where its set a record with $323 million.
Furious 7, a film whose fate was once in doubt after the death of star Paul Walker midway through shooting, has now made $1.3 billion globally. Only two other films, both by James Cameron Avatar and Titanic  have made more money internationally than Furious 7.
Furious 7 has had little competition to challenge it throughout April. This weekend, the only new wide release was the Blake Lively fantasy romance The Age of Adaline. The Lionsgate and Lakeshore Entertainment release came in third with $13.4 million. The Sony comedy Paul Blart: Mall Cop 2 held up stronger than expected to take second place with $15.5 million in its second week.
But the reign of Furious 7 is effectively over now that the highly anticipated Avengers sequel is on the way. Though it doesnt open in North America until Thursday night, it debuted in 44 countries and territories this weekend. That represents about half of its international rollout.
Disney said the film is exceeding the pace of 2012s The Avengers by 44 percent in the places it has opened. Joss Whedons first installment of the super team-up franchise, starring Robert Downey Jr., Mark Ruffalo, Scarlett Johansson and many others, made $1.5 billion worldwide, good for third all-time.
With two enormous blockbusters covering much of the globe, the summer movie season is ready to officially begin next weekend. In the meantime, a few smaller releases reached more screens.
Russell Crowes directorial debut, The Water Diviner, opened in 320 locations with $1.3 million. The critically acclaimed indie science-fiction drama Ex Machina expanded to 1,255 screens in its second week of release and earned $5.4 million.
Estimated ticket sales for Friday through Sunday at U.S. and Canadian theaters, according to Rentrak. Where available, the latest international numbers for Friday through Sunday are also included. Final domestic figures will be released Monday.
Advertisement
1. Furious 7, $18.3 million.
2. Paul Blart: Mall Cop 2, $15.5 million.
3. The Age of Adaline, $13.4 million.
4. Home, $8.3 million.
6. Ex Machina, $5.4 million.
7. The Longest Ride, $4.4 million.
8. Get Hard, $3.9 million.
9. Monkey Kingdom, $3.5 million.
10. Woman in Gold, $3.5 million.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Apr 26 20:01:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fighting rages in Yemen's 3rd-largest city, strikes continue</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150426/fighting-rages-in-yemens-3rd-largest-city-strikes-continue</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>War and unrest
Fighting rages in Yemens 3rd-largest city, strikes continue
Men look at a car destroyed by a recent Saudi-led airstrike  in Yemens capital, Sanaa,  Saturday.  With combatants fighting in neighborhoods and Saudi-led coalition warplanes pounding Iran-backed rebels from the sky, Yemens war is wreaking a particularly bloody toll among civilians: more than 550 have been killed in the past month, including 115 children, the U.N. said Friday. Hani Mohammed  The Associated Press
By Ahmed Al-Haj, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A Saudi man looks at an army tank being transported, in the city of Najran, Saudi Arabia, near the border with Yemen, Thursday. In a stunning development, Saudi Arabia had declared on Tuesday that it was halting coalition airstrikes targeting Yemens Shiite rebels known as Houthis  a four-week air campaign meant to halt the rebel power grab and help return to office embattled President Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi, a close U.S. ally who fled Yemen. Hasan Jamali  The Associated Press
SANAA, Yemen &gt;&gt; Deadly street battles raged in Yemens third-largest city on Sunday, as airstrikes by the Saudi-led coalition battling Shiite rebels struck targets in several cities, security officials said.
The fighting in Taiz between government forces and rebels was heaviest around government and security buildings in the city center, killing some 20 civilians and wounding dozens more, they said, adding that indiscriminately fired mortar rounds hit several private residences and landed near a hospital at one point.
Reached by telephone, Taiz residents described relentless artillery, tank and heavy machine gun fire blasting through the city as families sought shelter wherever they could.
Its like our homes have become a military target, they are killing us in cold blood, said resident Tawfiq Al Maamari. We left our homes with our children because the missiles are raining down on us without mercy.
The continued airstrikes and combat between rival factions on the ground underline how a negotiated peace remains elusive in the Arab worlds poorest country, despite a Saudi announcement last week that coalition operations would scale down and shift to focus on diplomacy, humanitarian and counter-terrorism issues. Both sides have said they welcome a return to dialogue.
The Shiite rebels, known as Houthis, are allied with military units loyal to former President Ali Abdullah Saleh.
Fighting continued across the country on Sunday, with airstrikes hitting the capital, Sanaa, as well as the cities of Dhamar, Marib, Aden, Shabwa, Hajjah, Saada, Ibb, and Lahj, the officials said. In Sanaa they began just after midnight, hitting a military base known to be an arms depot on the mountainous city outskirts, as well as sites near the presidential palace where weapons were being moved.
In the southern port city of Aden, officials said air raids targeted rebels as street fighting between them and forces loyal to embattled President Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi continued. West of Aden, military officials said the Houthis and pro-Saleh forces captured an area leading up to the strategic Bab al-Mandab strait, which overlooks the entrance to the Red Sea, a key global shipping route.
The officials all spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to brief journalists.
Although Hadi is Yemens internationally recognized leader, he was forced to flee the capital and later fled the country as the Houthis advanced toward his stronghold of Aden last month. The Saudi-led coalition began conducting airstrikes against rebel positions on March 26.
Advertisement
Hadi is now in the Saudi capital of Riyadh. The Houthis still control much of the country. The Sunni Arab countries in the coalition and their Western supporters say the Houthis get their arms from Shiite powerhouse Iran, something both Tehran and the rebels deny.
The United Nations said Friday that the war has killed over 550 civilians in the past month, including 115 children.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Apr 26 19:31:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>No time to lose: Global response to Nepal quake gears up</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150426/no-time-to-lose-global-response-to-nepal-quake-gears-up</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Earthquakes
No time to lose: Global response to Nepal quake gears up
Members of a German rescue organization board a plane at the airport in Frankfurt, central Germany, Sunday for their flight to earthquake-torn Nepal. International Search and Rescue Germany says a team of 52 relief workers including doctors, experts trained in searching for people buried under rubble and several dog squads will fly to Nepal. Christoph Schmidt  dpa via AP
By Gregory Katz, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
LONDON &gt;&gt; There is still time to save lives  thats why governments and aid agencies Sunday rushed doctors, volunteers and equipment to Nepal without waiting for the dust to settle.
Substantial logistical hurdles remain, but there were hopeful signs as Kathmandus international airport reopened after Saturdays crushing earthquake, and some aid vehicles were able to travel overland from Indian to the stricken Nepalese city of Pokhara.
That means supplies could potentially come in overland from India. That is a positive sign, said Ben Pickering, Save the Childrens humanitarian adviser in Britain. The airport opening is a small miracle.
He cautioned that chaotic conditions may create a bottleneck at the airport as governments and aid agencies try to bring in personnel and supplies in the coming days.
The need is great: UNICEF said Sunday that at least 940,000 children in areas affected by the earthquake are in urgent need of humanitarian assistance. UNICEF staff reported dwindling water supplies, power shortages and communications breakdowns.
There is still a dearth of information about conditions at the epicenter of the earthquake, Pickering said, and is not clear which roads are passable.
Going forward its about access to the epicenter, and helicopters are the key, but its not clear whether they can be sourced and whether the high altitude is a problem, he said, adding that Save the Children has emergency kits pre-positioned in three warehouses in Nepal and plans to distribute bedding, buckets and other basic supplies to 2,000 families as quickly as possible.
Other charities face similar roadblocks.
International Search and Rescue Germany said a team of 52 relief workers including doctors, experts trained in searching for people buried under rubble and several dog squads are flying Sunday. The team will bring a mobile medical treatment center.
Spokesman Stefan Heine said the priority was to get to the scene of the quake as quickly as possible to find those still alive.
They will be supported by numerous governments that have announced plans to send aid worth millions of dollars.
The United Arab Emirates deployed an 88-member search-and-rescue team to Nepal Sunday, and the Emirates Red Crescent also sent a team.
The Israeli military said it is sending a 260-member mission to Nepal to provide immediate search-and-rescue help and medical aid.
Advertisement
An advanced multi-department medical facility, equipped with approximately 95 tons of humanitarian and medical supplies from Israel and a medical staff of 122 doctors, nurses and paramedics, will be rapidly established in the city of Katmandu to provide medical care for disaster casualties, the Israeli military said.
European nations deployed as well: France said it would send 11 rescuers on Sunday; Britain announced that an advance team of eight had been sent and that a 5 million pound ($7.6 million) aid package would be available under a rapid response plan; and the Swiss Foreign Ministry said a team of experts including a doctor, a building surveyor and water quality technician had left for Nepal on Sunday.
Volunteers from various British charities gathered at Londons Heathrow Airport getting ready for overnight flights to the Nepal region.
Gary Francis, leader of the Search and Rescue Assistance in Disasters group, said the group is bringing in enough tents, food and water to operate self-sufficiently for 15 days.
They are bring in a vast array of equipment including sound and vibration detectors, seismic listening devices, and cutting equipment, with an eye toward finding survivors.
Once we are there weve got the ability to carry out a coordination role or urban search and rescue looking for survivors trapped in collapsed buildings, he said.
Associated Press writers Adam Schreck in Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Ian Deitch in Jerusalem; Angela Charlton in Paris; and Kirsten Grieshaber in Berlin contributed.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Apr 26 19:25:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Technology and outdoor sports converge at drone conference</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/technology/20150426/technology-and-outdoor-sports-converge-at-drone-conference</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Technology
Technology and outdoor sports converge at drone conference
Romeo Durscher, director of education for drone-maker DJI, flies one of his companys products Tuesday in Davenport  Top drone-makers, along with investors, regulators and inventors, are gathering in one of the most popular regions for outdoor activity in the U.S., Californias Central Coast, to show off their devices, hear about new uses for airborne robots, and hit the waves and trails at the Drones Data X Conference in Santa Cruz from May 1 to 3, 2015. Marcio Jose Sanchez  The Associated Press
By Martha Mendoza, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
The Inspire 1, a drone manufactured by DJI, is flown Tuesday in Davenport  Top drone-makers, along with investors, regulators and inventors, are gathering in one of the most popular regions for outdoor activity in the U.S., Californias Central Coast, to show off their devices, hear about new uses for airborne robots, and hit the waves and trails at the Drones Data X Conference in Santa Cruz from May 1 to 3, 2015. Marcio Jose Sanchez  The Associated Press
Santa Cruz &gt;&gt; Surfers catching waves and mountain bikers pedaling through forests are used to the occasional low flying pelican or diving hawk, but these days outdoor recreationalists can find whats up in the air isnt a bird at all, its a drone.
This week top drone-makers, along with investors, regulators and inventors, are gathering in one of the most popular regions for outdoor activity in the U.S., Californias Central Coast, to show off their devices, hear about new uses for airborne robots, and hit the waves and trails.
Drones Data X Conference Santa Cruz, from May 1 to 3, will also feature experts explaining how unmanned-aerial vehicles can map remote areas or rescue hikers or swimmers.
Federal regulators, who are still sorting out drone rules, will be on hand with updates on regulations about whether operators need to keep a drone within their line of sight, how high they can go and whether they can fly directly above a person.
Drones are in a bit of their Wild West period right now, but in the future theyll be used to transport people, medicine, goods; anything done on a highway will just as well be done by air, conference organizer Philip McNamara said.
Spending on unmanned aerial vehicles is projected to double over the next decade, from about $6.4 billion a year to $11.5 billion a year, according to industry analyst Teal Group.
McNamara said about 90 percent of the venture capital flowing toward drone technologies comes from the nations high tech hub, Silicon Valley, about 30 miles from the conference. Santa Cruz economic development director Bonnie Lipscomb said the city hopes some firms will like what they see, from sandy beaches to redwood forests, as well as a university and tech startups.
It was a great opportunity to showcase not only our burgeoning tech scene but also our outdoor enthusiast paradise, she said.
Local mountain bike and kite surfing companies are loaning gear and expertise to the conference.
Sergio Capozzi at the Society of Outdoor Recreation Professionals said there is both crossover and conflict between outdoor recreationalists and drone enthusiasts.
There is likely an appropriate time and place for drones in nature. The challenge comes in finding the right balance of when and where drones are appropriate, he said.
Advertisement
As prices go down and drone technology advances, park and wilderness visitors who want to use drones also need to make sure that everyone is having a safe and enjoyable experience, he said. He noted that, on the plus side, drones can be used to gather photos and videos that wouldnt be accessible otherwise.
Sharing these experiences encourages others to seek out similar experiences, in particular on public landscapes, he said.
But Richard Dolesh, a vice president at the National Recreation and Park Association, said park managers arent paying enough attention to increased drone use.
Drones are going to be everywhere and people who are managing outdoor land and outdoor recreation are pretty clueless right now about what its going to take to effectively manage them, he said.
Dolesh noted that national parks banned drones after visitors complained about their noise.
People travel long distances, he said, for peace and solitude.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
