<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailynews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jun 21 20:09:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Illicit drugs 'rampant' in California state prisons</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150621/illicit-drugs-rampant-in-california-state-prisons/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Prisons
Illicit drugs rampant in California state prisons
In this photo taken Wednesday, May 20, 2015, Bentley, a 3-year-old Labrador retriever,  checks an inmate for traces of narcotics at California State Prison, Solano, in Vacaville, Calif.  In an effort to reduce the amount of inmates dying of drug overdoses, the Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation is tightening its policies for searching visitors, inmates and employees. More than $8 million has been spent this year on drug-sniffing dogs, airport-style ion spectrometry devices and low-dose X-ray body scanners.(AP Photo/Rich Pedroncelli)
By Don Thompson, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this photo taken Wednesday May 20, 2015, Correctional Officer M. Jones puts on gloves before demonstrating an airport-style ion spectrometer that tests for illegal narcotics at Vacaville State Prison in Vacaville, Calif. In an effort to reduce the amount of inmates dying of drug overdoses, the Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation is tightening its policies for searching visitors, inmates and employees.  More than $8 million has been spent this year on drug-sniffing dogs, airport-style ion spectrometry devices and low-dose X-ray body scanners.(AP Photo/Rich Pedroncelli)
VACAVILLE &gt;&gt; California inmates are dying of drug overdoses at nearly triple the national rate and its unclear whether the tough steps state officials took this year to stop illicit drugs from getting into prisons are having any effect, though they are prompting criticism from civil rights advocates.
The Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation is spending $8 million this year on drug-detecting scanners and a new breed of drug-sniffing dogs while also employing strip searches on visitors suspected of carrying drugs.
Corrections officials believe the stepped-up efforts are discouraging smuggling, but the data thats available so far doesnt support that  more than 6,000 scans have been done on visitors and employees at 11 prisons since December without finding anyone with drugs.
The state doesnt track if anyone has been arrested because of the dog searches and waited until mid-May to begin tracking the number of arrests made using any of the new procedures.
Meantime, criticism is mounting about false-positive results by the scanners and dogs that can lead to strip searches. Concerned lawmakers who oversee state prisons included language in the California budget plan passed this week that would end the searches and require an evaluation of the departments other efforts.
Its a humiliating process, can be easily used to humiliate and demean people, and was only for visitors, often women, Democratic Sen. Loni Hancock, said of the strip searches. There are many concerns about the dogs, which have historically been emblematic of intimidation of many communities of color, most notably during the civil rights movement.
But no one wants to see drug deaths, and she said the evaluation will show which of the new programs are effective.
More than 150 California inmates have died of drug overdoses since 2006, with a high of 24 in 2013. Moreover, the sharing of intravenous needles often spreads hepatitis C infections, which killed 69 inmates in 2013 alone.
Corrections Secretary Jeffrey Beard recently told lawmakers that drugs are rampant in the prisons.
What we are trying to do is send a message to people to not try to smuggle drugs in to the institution, he said in an interview. If we dont do this, were going to have people keep dying, were going to have continued violence in the prisons.
Beard is modeling Californias new procedures on those used successfully in the Pennsylvania corrections department he led for a decade. While California has a long-term annual rate of eight drug- or alcohol-related deaths per 100,000 inmates, Pennsylvanias is one.
Advertisement
Florida, Georgia, Illinois, Ohio and Texas also each averaged one death a year per 100,000 inmates from 2001-2012, according to the most recent national figures. Maryland had the nations worst rate, at 17 deaths per 100,000 inmates.
Beard said Californias program would have more rapid success if lawmakers had given him more money, and he may seek funds to expand the program as early as this fall.
He believes the ion scanners  similar to those used to screen airport travelers  are deterring smugglers. The lack of results may be because only about 5 percent of visitors and employees are being scanned, he said, though the eventual goal is 30 percent. By contrast, Pennsylvania scanned 68 percent of visitors last year and at least 20 percent of employees.
Pennsylvania officials could not say how much contraband was found by using the scanners.
Records show the German shepherd and similar looking dogs long used in California prisons have been effective at rooting out hidden drugs. But to search visitors, employees and inmates the department is turning to less aggressive dogs including Labrador retrievers  fluffy, friendly dogs, Northern California canine program coordinator Sgt. Brian Pyle said.
The decision to use dogs to search humans, instead of unoccupied spaces as was previously the policy, prompted the resignation last fall of Wayne Conrad, the departments statewide canine program coordinator. He criticized the expense of sending California dog handlers to Pennsylvania for training, the use of breeds that he said are less reliable, and what he said was a supervisors effort to stifle concerns about the program because it was championed by Beard.
The dogs are going to start alerting on people whose kids are smoking dope or something, and that false positive could prompt an unnecessary strip search, Conrad said. The next thing thats going to come is the lawsuits.
Beard said he is seeking alternatives to strip searches, and downplayed the possibility that false-positive alerts unfairly implicate innocent visitors and employees. But thats what happened to Tania Gamboa of Riverside when she went to see her brother at Kern Valley State Prison.
She initially laughed when the ion machine tested positive for exposure to heroin, saying she doesnt even drink alcohol. But she was crying after she was required to strip naked in front of two female correctional officers and squat to demonstrate that she was not concealing drugs.
It doesnt make sense for me, knowing that I dont do all that and I got detected for it, she said.
Mohamed Shehk, an Oakland-based spokesman for Critical Resistance, which advocates for better conditions for inmates, said the policies are turning visitors into suspects.
The statistics  $8 million, 6,000 scans and nothing to show for it  show that these are intended to intimidate and criminalize people who are going to see their loved ones inside, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 21:25:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Jurassic World' holds box office, but 'Inside Out' shows bite</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150621/jurassic-world-holds-box-office-but-inside-out-shows-bite</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Box office receipts
Jurassic World holds box office, but Inside Out shows bite
This photo provided by Universal Pictures shows, Chris Pratt, left, and Bryce Dallas Howard in a scene from the film, Jurassic World, directed by Colin Trevorrow, in the next installment of Steven Spielbergs groundbreaking Jurassic Park series. The 3D movie releases in theaters by Universal Pictures on. Chuck Zlotnick  Universal Pictures via AP
By Jake Coyle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this file image released by Disney-Pixar, characters, from left, Anger, voiced by Lewis Black, Disgust, voiced by Mindy Kaling, Joy, voiced by Amy Poehler, Fear, voiced by Bill Hader, and Sadness, voiced by Phyllis Smith appear in a scene from Inside Out. The movie releases in theaters on. Disney-Pixar via AP, File
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; In a box-office bout of Tyrannosaurus-sized proportions, Jurassic World kept the No. 1 spot with one of the biggest second weeks ever, while Pixars Inside Out nearly matched it with a $91 million debut well above expectations.
Universals Jurassic World took in $102 million in North American theaters, according to studio estimates Sunday, making it only the second release to break $100 million in its second week. The enormous holdover for Jurassic World, which last week set an opening weekend record with $208.8 million, has been bested by only 2012s The Avengers, which made $103.1 million in second week.
The unexpected sensation of the Colin Trevorrow-directed, Steven Spielberg-produced fourth entry in the franchise had turned Disneys $175 million 3-D Inside Out into an underdog expected to merely nip at the heels of Jurassic World. But the emotional Inside Out, about the voices in the head of an 11-year-old girl, blew past its own forecasts to set records, too.
Inside Out was the first Pixar release not to open in first place, following an unparalleled two-decade streak of 14 straight no. 1s. But its the largest opening for a wholly original movie (one not based on source material or a sequel), unseating Avatar in that distinction. Directed by Pete Docter (Up) and co-directed by Ronaldo del Carmen, Inside Out had been expected to open in the range of previous Pixar non-sequels like Wall-E ($63.8 million opening) and Brave ($66.3 million).
But Inside Out was propelled by gushing reviews from critics, a flashy premiere at the Cannes Film Festival and an appetite for a movie from Pixar. The animation studio hadnt had a release in two years after delaying The Good Dinosaur last year.
We came into the weekend thinking wed do something in the 60s, said David Hollis, distribution head for Disney. As we got closer to release, we hit a critical mass of really unbelievable critical response. In this day and age where technology allows people to see a Rotten Tomatoes score or read something and pass it along to their friends, all of a sudden, there was quite a stir about this as a thing to see.
The twin hits of Inside Out and Jurassic World are giving Hollywoods summer a major boost. The weekend was up a staggering 64.6 percent over the same weekend last year, according to box-office data firm Rentrak. In 10 days, Jurassic World has already almost made $981.3 million  nearly $1 billion  and appears poised to be among the highest-grossing releases of all time.
Part of the success of Inside Out is owed to this massive infusion of moviegoers into the marketplace, says Paul Dergarabedian, senior media analyst for Rentrak. If you look at last weekend, around the world, how many people were in theaters when Jurassic World made its debut?
Advertisement
He added, though, that Inside Out was also driven by Pixars unique storytelling knack: They can take almost any subject and turn it into something insightful, poignant and moving.
Inside Out and Jurassic World had the multiplexes largely to themselves over the weekend. The other wide release to open was Dope, a low-budget teen comedy set in Los Angeles Inglewood neighborhood. Written and directed by Rick Famuyiwa, starring newcomer Shameik Moore and boasting some high-profile producers (Forest Whitaker, Pharrell Williams), Dope was acquired by Open Road after a buzzy premiere at the Sundance Film Festival.
Though Open Road gave Dope an optimistic wide release of 2,002 theaters, it took in only $6 million.
In limited release, the Adam Scott and Jason Schwartzman comedy The Overnight  also a Sundance premiere  opened on three screens in New York and Los Angeles, pulling in $61,523, good enough for the most packed theaters (albeit in far tinier numbers) besides those playing Jurassic World and Inside Out.
Estimated ticket sales for Friday through Sunday at U.S. and Canadian theaters, according to Rentrak. Where available, the latest international numbers for Friday through Sunday are also included. Final domestic figures will be released Monday.
1. Jurassic World, $102 million ($160.5 million international).
2. Inside Out, $91 million ($41 million international).
3. Spy, $10.5 million.
4. San Andreas, $8.2 million.
5. Dope, $6 million.
6. Insidious Chapter 3, $4.1 million.
7. Pitch Perfect 2, $3.3 million.
8. Mad Max: Fury Road, $2.8 million.
9. Avengers: Age of Ultron, $2.7 million.
10. Tomorrowland, $2 million.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 20:48:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couples, officials, foes readying for Supreme Court gay marriage ruling</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150621/couples-officials-foes-readying-for-supreme-court-gay-marriage-ruling</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>United States Supreme Court decisions
Couples, officials, foes readying for Supreme Court gay marriage ruling
In this photo, Pastor Greg Bullard is shown in his chapel in Madison, Tenn. Bullard intends to perform same-sex weddings in the chapel if the U.S. Supreme Court lifts the states gay marriage ban. Mark Humphrey  The Associated Press
By Dan Sewell, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this Monday photo, Ethan Fletcher, left, and partner Andrew Hickam pose for a photograph in Cincinnati. The U.S. Supreme Court is expected to rule sometime this month on the legal status of same-sex marriage; Ohio is among states that still ban it. Gay couples, such as Fletcher and Hickam are gearing up for a quick run to the courthouse in Ohio, Michigan, Kentucky and Tennessee _ the states involved in the cases that were argued in April before the justices. Dan Sewell  The Associated Press
CINCINNATI &gt;&gt; With a U.S. Supreme Court ruling on same-sex marriage expected any day now, gay couples in states with bans are making wedding plans, courthouse officials are getting ready for different scenarios and steadfast foes are working on their strategies to keep up the opposition.
Marriage license bureaus are bracing for a rush of applicants if the court overturns bans. Meanwhile, theres been a series of planning sessions by groups that intend to explore religious objection responses to protect traditional marriage limited to heterosexuals.
Gay couples, such as Ethan Fletcher and Andrew Hickam of Cincinnati, are gearing up for a quick run to the courthouse in Ohio, Michigan, Kentucky and Tennessee  the states involved in the cases that were argued in April before the justices. Theyre among 14 states that ban same-sex marriage, and if the high court rules in favor of gay marriage, it would apply nationally.
Fletcher, 31, a University of Cincinnati senior academic adviser, and Hickam, 30, a GE Aviation engineer, have arranged to take off work to get their license if the decision allows immediate same-sex marriages and will then plan a formal wedding. They became engaged nearly two years ago but decided against getting married in another state as long as there was the possibility they could do it at home.
Well, we live here and we pay taxes here and our families live here, said Fletcher, adding that they want his grandmother and Hickams mother to be able to attend. We didnt feel that it was reasonable for us to have to travel out of state for the freedom to marry.
In Hamilton County, where Cincinnati is located, the marriage license bureau said other courthouse staffers have been cross-trained and forms are available online to help speed the process. Court officials in Cuyahoga County, where Cleveland is located, say theyre prepared to process triple the usual number of applications.
Probate Court Judge Jan Michael Long, of Pickaway County, near Columbus, said he and other probate judges met to discuss potential rulings and their impacts. There are a lot of procedural issues involving the need for gender-neutral wording and who gets legal notifications, he said, and it could be complicated depending on when the court ruling becomes effective and how its worded.
In Ingham County, Michigan, Clerk Barb Byrum said she might not wait for a new marriage license form from the state, and could simply white-out bride and groom on the application when she gets the legal green light.
Advertisement
She has collected dozens of email addresses from local same-sex couples to notify them of the Supreme Court decision when she knows it. She was among four clerks who issued licenses on a Saturday during a 24-hour period in 2014 when gay marriage in Michigan was legal between court orders.
The Tennessee Equality Project has been asking people to let them know in advance if they plan to get married on Day One. Its website includes instructions on obtaining licenses and finding officiants.
Bleu Copas, who lives just outside of Knoxville, said he wants to get married right away if the ban is lifted.
Were looking at wedding bands and what to wear, he said.
He and his fiance plan to marry at a small chapel on a farm belonging to the pastor of Nashvilles Covenant of the Cross Church, Greg Bullard, who intends to host at least 15 free weddings for same-sex couples on July 3 if the court makes it legal.
Some pastors, though, have signaled plans to resist a Supreme Court ruling in favor of same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Gov. Greg Abbott recently signed a pastor protection law that allows clergy members to refuse officiating marriages that violates his religious beliefs.
Leaders of the Southern Baptist Convention, meeting Wednesday in Columbus, issued a statement saying they would not recognize, host or perform same-sex marriages. Some county clerks in Kentucky and other states, including Nebraska, have expressed objections to the possibility of same-sex marriages, but Douglas County Clerk Thomas Cavanaugh, in Omaha, said Nebraskas largest counties already have changed marriage license applications to include gender-neutral wording and are ready to follow whatever the high court decides is the law.
North Carolina and Utah have passed laws allowing some court officials to refuse to perform gay marriage responsibilities.
Advocacy groups opposed to same-sex marriage have been discussing the legal defenses for religious objectors including business owners, employers and others besides clergy and court officials. Phil Burress, leader of the Citizens for Community Values that opposes gay marriage, predicts a ruling in favor of it will trigger more litigation and political action.
In Cincinnati, Hickam and Fletcher say if the court upholds bans, theyll go to a state that has recognized same-sex marriage through state, not federal action, to wed and then work for the political movement to gain recognition at the ballot box.
We would then just join forces with the rest of the gay community to bring about change through the democratic process, Hickam said. And things would be hopeful going that route.
Contributing to this report were Associated Press writers Travis Loller in Nashville, Tennessee; Ed White in Detroit; Margery A. Beck in Omaha, Nebraska; and Andrew DeMillo in Little Rock, Arkansas.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:35:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Sixth mass extinction': Earth's species disappearing at frightening rate, new study says</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/environment-and-nature/20150621/sixth-mass-extinction-earths-species-disappearing-at-frightening-rate-new-study-says</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Endangered and extinct species
Sixth mass extinction: Earths species disappearing at frightening rate, new study says
A female Grizzly bear exits Pelican Creek October 8, 2012 in the Yellowstone National Park in Wyoming. KAREN BLEIER/AFP/GettyImages
By Lisa M. Krieger, lkrieger@mercurynews.com , @lisamkrieger on Twitter
Posted:
# Comments
In the most sobering study of extinction yet, a team of Bay Area scientists says that animal species are disappearing at an accelerating rate  portending the sixth mass extinction in the 4.5-billion-year history of the Earth.
We are entering a mass extinction equivalent to what happened to the dinosaurs unless conservation efforts are intensified, said UC Berkeley paleontologist Anthony D. Barnosky and an author of the report, which was published Friday.
If the trend continues, within two human lifetimes we are in danger of losing three of four species on Earth, he said.
The 21st century may mark the end of the line for animals confined to small and shrinking habitats, such as the Yangtze River dolphin or the African black rhinoceros. And, Barnosky said, their loss may be followed by icons such as elephants and tigers.
Californias state mammal, the grizzly bear, is among species at risk of extinction by the end of the century.
Also vulnerable are Californias state tree, the redwood; the state reptile, the desert tortoise; the state amphibian, the red-legged frog; and the state mammal, the grizzly bear, he said.
They are all moving to same status as the state fossil, the saber-tooth cat, Barnosky said.
Grizzlies were already extinct in California three decades before the Legislature named it the state animal in 1953. But more than 1,500 still survive in states such as Idaho, Montana and Wyoming.
Based on fossil records, the expected rate of extinction of vertebrate species, without human activity, is 2 per 100 years per 10,000 species. At this rate, nine species would have been expected to go extinct since 1900.
But the actual toll has been far greater, the team found. At least 198 vertebrate species have been lost since 1900: 35 mammals, 57 birds, 8 reptiles, 32 amphibians and 66 fishes. When the category is broadened to include species that are possibly extinct or extinct in the wild, the total rises to 477.
A continued trajectory is like going into the worlds most famous museum  say the Louvre in Paris  and slashing with a razor blade three out of every four paintings, Barnosky said. In one century, were destroying works of art that evolved over millions of years.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:13:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman removes Confederate flag in front of SC statehouse</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/woman-removes-confederate-flag-in-front-of-sc-statehouse</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Woman removes Confederate flag in front of SC statehouse
Bree Newsome of Charlotte, N.C., right, is taken into custody after she removed the Confederate battle flag from a monument in front of the South Carolina Statehouse in Columbia, S.C., on Saturday, June, 27, 2015. The flag was raised again by capitol workers about 45 minutes later. AP Photo/Bruce Smith
By EMILY MASTERS and BRUCE SMITH, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Bree Newsome of Charlotte, N.C., removes the Confederate battle flag at a Confederate monument at the Statehouse in Columbia, S.C., on Saturday, June, 27, 2015. She was taken into custody when she came down. The flag was raised again by capitol workers about 45 minutes later.  AP Photo/Bruce Smith
COLUMBIA, S.C. &gt;&gt; The Confederate flag was temporarily removed from the front of the South Carolina Statehouse on Saturday when a woman climbed the flagpole and  despite calls by police to get down  removed the banner.
Bree Newsome, 30, of Charlotte, North Carolina, was about halfway up the more than 30-foot steel flagpole just after dawn Saturday when officers of the South Carolina Bureau of Protective Services ran to the flagpole and told her to get down. Instead, she continued climbing to the top and removed the flag.
She and a man who had climbed over a four-foot wrought-iron fence to get to the flag were arrested.
The flag, which is protected by state law, was raised about 45 minutes later, well ahead of a rally later Saturday by supporters of keeping the flag where it is.
Sherri Iacobelli, a spokeswoman for the state Department of Public Safety, said Newsome and James Ian Tyson, 30, also of Charlotte, have been charged with defacing monuments on state Capitol grounds. Thats a misdemeanor that carries a fine of up to $5,000 and a prison term of up to three years or both.
A staff member at the Alvin Glenn Detention Center where the two were taken said she did not know if they had attorneys. About the time of her arrest, Newsome released an email statement to the media.
We removed the flag today because we cant wait any longer. We cant continue like this another day, it said. Its time for a new chapter where we are sincere about dismantling white supremacy and building toward true racial justice and equality.
Authorities said Newsome was from Raleigh. However, Mervyn Marcano, a spokesman for the small group of activists who worked together to take down the flag, said she had recently moved to Charlotte.
Tamika Lewis, another member of the group, said taking down the flag was done because we were tired of waiting for the judicial system to make the decision they have been prolonging for a very long time.
Later Saturday, about 50 people who support keeping the flag held a rally at the statehouse. Many were waving Confederate flags as they shouted Heritage Not Hate!
This is not a flag of hate. Its a flag of heritage, and we have a right to our heritage, said Leland Browder of Greenville. And, you know, Im from the South and proud of the South and, you know, proud of this flag.
Advertisement
Supporters also said the voters should decide the fate of the flag and shouted: Let the People Vote.
Calls for removing the flag have been renewed since nine black churchgoers were killed in what police characterized as a racist attack at a Charleston, South Carolina church last week.
South Carolina lawmakers took the initial steps last Tuesday toward removing the Confederate battle flag from the Statehouse grounds by agreeing to allow discussion of the matter during the legislative session.
The agreement came a day after Republican Gov. Nikki Haley reversed course and called for the divisive symbol to come down. The flag has flown in front of the state Capitol for 15 years after being moved from atop the Statehouse dome.
Some state lawmakers worried that Newsomes actions will hurt efforts to bring the flag down permanently.
There are 2 ways the Confederate Flag can be removed forever. Citizens please engage legally or we lose! state Sen. Marlon Kimpson of Charleston, a Democrat, said on his Twitter account.
And, in another tweet, Republican state Sen. Shane Massey of Edgefield said such actions will make this discussion much more difficult. Both lawmakers favor bringing down the flag.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:10:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/french-terror-suspect-took-selfie-with-beheaded-victim</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Terrorism
French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim
Police officers guard the road leading to a plant in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France, Saturday, June 27, 2015, where an attack took place yesterday June 26. A spokeswoman for the Paris prosecutors office says one of the four suspects detained over an explosion and beheading in southeast France has been released, while the suspected assassin isnt speaking to investigators. AP Photo/Michel Euler
By PHILIPPE SOTTO and JAMEY KEATEN, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Police officers guard a road leading to a plant which was attacked on Friday in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France, Saturday, June 27, 2015. A spokeswoman for the Paris prosecutors office says one of the four suspects detained over an explosion and beheading in southeast France has been released, while the suspected assassin isnt speaking to investigators. AP Photo/Michel Euler
FONTAINES-SUR-SAONE, France &gt;&gt; The top suspect in the beheading of a businessman that French authorities are calling terrorist attack took a selfie photo with the slain victim and sent the image via WhatsApp to a Canadian mobile phone number, officials said Saturday.
French investigators were working to confirm the identity of the recipient, but werent able to immediately confirm media reports that it was an unspecified person now in Syria, where the radical Islamic State group has seized territory, the security officials said. They spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation was ongoing.
Leading suspect Yassine Salhi, a truck driver with a history of radical Islamic ties, as well as his sister and wife remained in custody in the city of Lyon a day after he allegedly crashed a truck into an U.S.-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employers severed head on a factory gate, officials have said.
One of the security officials said the selfie was forwarded via WhatsApp, the globally popular instant messaging system owned by Facebook, to a phone number in Canada.
No group immediately claimed responsibility. The severed head appeared to mimic Islamic States practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. French authorities say Salhi had links to radical Salafists in the past.
Paris prosecutors office spokeswoman Agnes Thibault-Lecuivre said earlier Saturday that Salhi was refusing to speak to police investigators. She said that one of the other suspects initially arrested on Friday was released without being charged.
Investigators have not turned up any motive or possible foreign connection, Thibault-Lecuivre said. Under French anti-terrorism laws, Salhi and the women can be held up to four days before either being released or handed preliminary charges and locked up.
Separately on Saturday, hundreds of people turned out in the region to honor slain businessman Herve Cornara and denounce the violence. Dozens turned out for a minute of silence in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the town southeast of Lyon where Fridays attack took place at an Air Products chemicals warehouse.
Several hundred people also gathered outside a housing project in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone to honor Cornara, 54, the manager of a transportation company that had employed Salhi since March. They recalled a kind, humble man who was active in the community of the Lyon suburb.
Advertisement
He lived on the fifth floor, me on the fourth. He spoke with all the young people in the neighborhood. He didnt differentiate between (non-Muslim) French and Muslims, said Leila Bouri, a 24-year-old cafeteria cashier. If you ever had a problem, you would go see him.
When I heard this, I was shocked. Its shameful, she said. I am a Muslim, but you cant kill like this. Its not who we are. In Islam, were not told to slit throats. We only slit the throats of sheep. You dont slit the throats of people.
The suspected killer, she added, isnt a Muslim in my opinion.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:08:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/egypt-sees-sandstorm-and-earthquake-on-the-same-day</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Dust and sandstorms
Egypt sees sandstorm and earthquake on the same day
A couple observe a sandstorm that shrouds the capital city from an observation deck of the Cairo Tower in Zamalek, Cairo, Egypt, Saturday, June 27, 2015. AP Photo/Mosaab Elshamy
By MERRIT KENNEDY, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A sandstorm shrouds the capital city of Cairo, Egypt, Saturday, June 27, 2015. AP Photo/Mosaab Elshamy
CAIRO &gt;&gt; Egypt faced treacherous weather conditions Saturday as a sandstorm blanketed the north of the country and a magnitude-5.2 earthquake centered in the Sinai peninsula shook buildings more than 200 miles away in the capital, Cairo.
The epicenter of the quake was 4 kilometers (2.5 miles) southeast of the beachside town of Nuweiba in the Sinai, and about 75 kilometers (46 miles) south of Egypts border with Israel, according to the U.S. Geological Survey.
Airports near Alexandria and Marsa Matrouh, along the Mediterranean coast, closed and diverted flights to Cairo due to poor visibility from the days sandstorm, Civil Aviation Minister Hossam Kamel said in a statement. Visibility reached as low as 500 meters at the Burg al-Arab airport near Alexandria, he said.
Fierce winds whipped through the capital as many residents took cover from the sand by staying indoors. Others were seen braving the storm wearing surgical masks or covering their faces with clothing, as the wind sent rubbish and dust swirling.
At its peak, the sandstorm covered the capital in a thick orange cloud, dramatically reducing visibility.
In the Red Sea town of Dahab, 68 kilometers (42 miles) south of the epicenter of the quake in the Sinai peninsula, the tremor shook loose clouds of dust that enveloped nearby mountains, according to a witness. The quake appeared to startle local residents and tourists. It also shook the nearby Gaza strip. No serious damage was immediately reported from the earthquake in Egypt or in Gaza.
The Egyptian Ministry of Health said in a statement that there were no reports of deaths or injuries anywhere in Egypt due to the quake.
Israeli media reported that very mild aftershocks of the earthquake were felt in some places in the south of the country, but that no damage or injuries were caused.
The extreme weather conditions provided fodder for social media humor. Some wondered which of the 10 Biblical plagues would come next, while the popular Zamalek football club tweeted that it wasnt actually an earthquake--just preparation for their match tonight.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:07:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>35 California counties extend health care to immigrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150627/35-california-counties-extend-health-care-to-immigrants/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>35 California counties extend health care to immigrants
By Associated Press
# Comments
SACRAMENTO &gt;&gt; Thirty-five California counties have agreed to provide health care coverage to people who are in the United States illegally.
The decision was made Thursday by the County Medical Services Program. That program provides health services to the poor in the mostly rural, sparsely populated counties.
The program could begin next year. Several thousand people are expected to enroll.
Forty-seven of Californias 58 counties have now agreed to provide low-cost medical coverage to eligible people regardless of their immigration status.
Immigrants who are in the state illegally now comprise the single biggest group of Californias uninsured.
Last week, Gov. Jerry Brown signed a state budget that expands Medi-Cal coverage to low-income children regardless of their legal status.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Advertisement
There is broad consensus among scientists that extinction rates have reached their highest levels since dinosaurs died out 66 million years ago.
More recently, Duke University biologist Stuart Pimm and others have asserted that this represents the beginning of Earths sixth mass extinction  echoing the five great extinctions over 4.5 billion years, each depleting 75 percent or more of all species.
But that conclusion has been criticized for using assumptions that overestimate the severity of the extinction crisis.
The new findings, published in the journal Science Advances by UC Berkeleys Barnosky and Stanford University biologists Paul Ehrlich and Gerardo Ceballos, support the dire forecasts, even though they used more modest rates of extinction.
The study shows without any significant doubt that we are now entering the sixth great mass extinction event, said Ehrlich, professor of population studies and a fellow at the Stanford Woods Institute for the Environment.
The work was divided between the Berkeley and Stanford labs. At Berkeley, Barnosky focused on fossil records of vertebrates, primarily mammals, which have the most reliable ancestral data. At Stanford, Erhlich and Ceballos, a Mexican conservationist, compared the rate of natural extinction before humans  2 per 10,000 species per 100 years  with current extinction rates, derived from data from the 2014 International Union of Conservation of Natures Red List.
Past mass extinctions were caused by massive volcanic eruptions and an asteroid falling from the sky.
Now, humans are delivering the coup de grce, according to the team. Were emitting carbon that drives climate change and ocean acidification. Were also cutting down forests, introducing invasive species and releasing poisons into fragile ecosystems.
If Earths population  now 7.13 billion  stops at 9 to 10 billion by the year 2050, other species stand a chance, Barnosky said.
But if it shoots up to 16 billion, he said, it is probably not going to work for keeping other species on Earth.
While its not too late to slow the loss of species, the window of opportunity is rapidly closing, they said. Already, the specter of extinction hangs over about 41 percent of all amphibian species and 26 percent of all mammals.
I dont want to be the generation that wiped out all these species, Barnosky said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:21:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>1st service held at Charleston church since 9 slayings</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150621/1st-service-held-at-charleston-church-since-9-slayings</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Religion
1st service held at Charleston church since 9 slayings
Parishioners sit at the Emanuel A.M.E. Church four days after a mass shooting that claimed the lives of its pastor and eight others on Sunday in Charleston, S.C. David Goldman  The Associated Press
By Phillip Lucas, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
CHARLESTON, S.C. &gt;&gt; Members of a historic black church worshipped at their sanctuary Sunday for the first time since a gunman opened fire at a Bible study, killing nine people, and uniformed police officers stood among the congregation as a measure of added security.
The service started with a message of love, recovery and healing, which will no doubt reverberate throughout churches across the country.
We still believe that prayer changes things. Can I get a witness? the Rev. Norvel Goff said. The congregated responded with a rousing Yes.
But prayer not only changes things, it changes us, Goff said.
Sunday morning marked the first service at Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church since Dylann Roof, 21, sat among a Bible study group and opened fire after saying that he targeted them because they were black, authorities said. Among the nine killed was the church pastor, the Rev. Clementa Pinckney, who was also a state senator.
Events to show solidarity are planned throughout the city and beyond. At 10 a.m. EDT, church bells rang throughout downtown this Holy City  which garnered the nickname because of the numerous churches here.
South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley and Mayor Joseph Riley attended the service at Emanuel.
Despite grim circumstances the congregation has been faced with, the welcoming spirit Roof exploited before the shooting is still alive, church members said.
I think just because of what people have gone through emotions are definitely heightened, not just in Charleston but with anyone going to church because it is such a sacred place, it is such a safe place, Shae Erdos, 29, said after a multiracial group of women sang Amazing Grace outside the church Saturday afternoon.
To have something like that completely shattered by such evil  I think it will be in the back of everyones heads, really, Erdos said. Erdos was planning on attending Sunday service in nearby Mount Pleasant.
The suburb is connected to Charleston by the Arthur Ravenel Bridge, where people are expected to join hands in solidarity Sunday evening. The bridges namesake is a former state lawmaker and a vocal Confederate flag supporter.
Roof had been photographed with the flag several times before the shooting.
Advertisement
Unity Church of Charleston the Rev. Ed Kosak said delivering his own Sunday morning sermon would be emotionally taxing but he felt empowered by the strength and grace Emanuel members have shown  a demeanor he said has set the tone for religious leaders everywhere.
Ive gone into Sunday sermons before like when Virginia Tech happened, and when the Sikh shootings happened Kosak said. The situation in Charleston may be harder to give a sermon on because it hits so close to home. But, Kosak said, I am more ready than ever to speak to this tragedy in ways I didnt think I could before.
For the family of Cynthia Hurd, Sundays service will be especially poignant. Hurd, a longtime librarian, would have been celebrating her 55th birthday and was planning a trip to Virginia with her siblings.
Sunday will not be a sad day for me; it will be a celebration for me. It will be a celebration for our family because our faith is being tested, Hurds younger brother Malcolm Graham said Friday. She was in the company of God trying to help somebody out. She was where she needed to be.
Felicia Breeland, an 81-year-old lifelong Emanuel member, said she sang in the choir with Susie Jackson, 87, who was also fatally shot Wednesday.
Its going to be sad. She sits right on the front row, too, Breeland said. She had a very soft soprano voice. It was beautiful.
Associated Press National Writer Allen Breed contributed to this report.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:21:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran parliament bans inspector access to military sites</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150621/iran-parliament-bans-inspector-access-to-military-sites</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Iran parliament bans inspector access to military sites
By Ali Akbar Dareini, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
TEHRAN, Iran &gt;&gt; With some lawmakers chanting Death to the America, Irans parliament voted to ban access to military sites, documents and scientists as part of a future deal with world powers over its contested nuclear program.
The bill, if approved into law, could complicate the ongoing talks in Vienna between Iran and the six-nation group  the U.S., Britain, France, Russia, China and Germany  as they face a self-imposed June 30 deadline. The talks are focused on reaching a final accord that curbs Irans nuclear program in return for the lifting of economic sanctions.
Of 213 lawmakers present on Sunday, 199 voted in favor of the bill, which also demands the complete lifting of all sanctions against Iran as part of any final nuclear accord. The bill must be ratified by the Guardian Council, a constitutional watchdog, to become a law.
The terms stipulated in the bill allow for international inspections of Iranian nuclear sites, but forbid any inspections of military facilities.
Parliament Speaker Ali Larijani read the bill aloud in a session broadcast live on state radio. It states in part, The International Atomic Energy Agency, within the framework of the safeguard agreement, is allowed to carry out conventional inspections of nuclear sites.
However it concludes that access to military, security and sensitive non-nuclear sites, as well as documents and scientists, is forbidden.
Irans nuclear negotiators say they have already agreed to grant United Nations inspectors managed access to military sites under strict control and specific circumstances. That right includes allowing inspectors to take environmental samples in the vicinity of military sites.
But Iranian officials, including supreme authority Ayatollah Ali Khameni, have strongly rejected the idea of Iranian scientists being interviewed, calling that a violation of the countrys dignity and sovereignty.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis pauses in silent prayer before Shroud of Turin</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/social-affairs/20150621/pope-francis-pauses-in-silent-prayer-before-shroud-of-turin</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Religion
Pope Francis pauses in silent prayer before Shroud of Turin
Pope Francis salutes the faithful gathered outside the hospital Cottolengo of Turin, northern Italy, Sunday. Pope Francis earlier prayed in front of the Holy Shroud, the 14 foot-long linen revered by some as the burial cloth of Jesus, on display at the Cathedral of Turin. Massimo Pinca  The Associated Press
By The Associated Press
# Comments
Pope Francis speaks to faithful in front of the  Santa Maria Ausiliatrice Basilica, in Turin, Italy, Sunday. Pope Francis earlier prayed in front of the Holy Shroud, the 14 foot-long linen revered by some as the burial cloth of Jesus, on display at the Cathedral of Turin. Luca Bruno  The Associated Press
TURIN, Italy &gt;&gt; Pope Francis paused in silent prayer before the Shroud of Turin Sunday, becoming the latest of hundreds of thousands of people who have come this year to Turins cathedral to view the burial linen some believe covered the body of Jesus after crucifixion.
Francis sat for several minutes before the shroud, contained in a protective glass case. He lowered his head at times in apparent reflection and occasionally gazed up at the 4.3-meter (14-foot) long cloth. Then he took a few steps, placed his hand on the case, and walked away without comment.
Later, after celebrating Mass of the faithful in a packed Turin square, Francis gave his impression of the cloth as he spoke of the love Jesus had for humanity when being crucified.
Icon of this love is the Shroud, which, even this time, has attracted so many people here to Turin, Francis said. The Shroud draws (people) to the tormented face and body of Jesus and, at the same time, directs (people) toward the face of every suffering and unjustly persecuted person.
The shrouds display began April 19 and runs through June 24.
Other pontiffs have made the journey to the northern city during previous displays of the shroud. When John Paul II saw the shroud in 1998, he said the mystery surrounding the cloth forces questions about faith and science and whether it really was Jesus burial linen. He urged continuous study. Benedict XVI described the cloth as an icon written with the blood of a crucified man.
Skeptics say the cloth bearing the image of a crucified man is a medieval forgery.
Turin, the heartland of Italys auto industry, is considered Italys blue-collar labor capital, and Francis used his two-day visit to the city to denounce exploitation of workers, singling out women, young people and immigrants as frequent victims.
Immigration increases competition, but migrants shouldnt be blamed because they themselves are victims of injustice, of this throw-away economy and of wars, Francis said in a speech in a square outside the cathedral.
He then made an apparent reference to European countries as well as some northern Italian regions which are refusing or are reluctant to take some of the tens of thousands of migrants who have landed at southern Italian ports after being rescued in the Mediterranean from overcrowded, unseaworthy smugglers boats.
Advertisement
It makes one cry to see the spectacle of these days in which human beings are treated as commercial goods, Francis said.
Turin is the Piedmont regions capital, and during Mass, the Argentine-born Francis quoted from a poem in local dialect that praises the qualities of those who emigrated from Piedmont  like some of his own ancestors  to seek work abroad.
Our ancestors knew well what it meant to be rock-solid, Francis said. Quoting from the poem, the pope said these emigrants were proper and sincere, they appear to be what they are.
In an unscheduled stop, Francis ducked into the church in Turin where his paternal grandparents were married in 1907, and where, in 1908, his father Mario was baptized. The ANSA news agency quoted the Rev. Giustizio Zoppi as saying Francis left a vase of yellow roses on the altar and then asked for a chair so he could sit in silence for a few minutes.
We didnt ask him to come, he wanted to, Zoppi said.
On Monday, before he heads back to Rome, Francis will lunch in Turin with some of his relatives who live in Piedmont.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:14:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israel, Hamas in unspoken alliance against Gaza extremists</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150621/israel-hamas-in-unspoken-alliance-against-gaza-extremists</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>War and unrest
Israel, Hamas in unspoken alliance against Gaza extremists
In this Wednesday photo, Palestinian Hamas gunmen ride on the back of a pick-up truck as they patrol the border with Israel near the southern Gaza Strip town of Khan Younis, as Israeli military bulldozers are seen in the background. Nearly a year after a devastating war, Israel and Gazas Hamas rulers appear to have formed an unspoken alliance in a common battle against the shared threat of jihadis aligned with the Islamic State group. Khalil Hamra  The Associated Press
By Fares Akram, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this Wednesday photo, Palestinian Hamas gunmen ride on the back of a pick-up truck as they patrol the border with Israel near the southern Gaza Strip town of Khan Younis. Nearly a year after a devastating war, Israel and Gazas Hamas rulers appear to have formed an unspoken alliance in a common battle against the shared threat of jihadis aligned with the Islamic State group. Khalil Hamra  The Associated Press
KHAN YOUNIS, Gaza Strip &gt;&gt; Nearly a year after a devastating war, Israel and Gazas Hamas rulers appear to have formed an unspoken alliance in a common battle against the shared threat of jihadis aligned with the Islamic State group.
While Israel and Hamas remain arch-enemies, both have an interest in preserving an uneasy calm that has prevailed since the fighting ended in a cease-fire last August  a stalemate that is largely the result of a lack of options on either side.
More than 2,200 Palestinians were killed in last years fighting, according to Palestinian officials, and Hamas suffered heavy losses. It is isolated internationally, Gazas economy is in tatters and reconstruction efforts have moved slowly. A renewal of hostilities would be devastating for Gazas 1.8 million people.
On the Israeli side, 73 people, including 67 soldiers, were killed in last years fighting, and the summer-long war disrupted the lives of millions of people as they coped with repeated rocket attacks and air-raid sirens. But Hamas, which seized power in Gaza eight years ago, has survived three wars, and the cost of toppling the group would be extremely high, so Israel appears content to contain Hamas and keep things quiet.
Hamas officials say that efforts are underway, through Qatari mediators, to work out a long-term cease-fire. The deal would call for Israel to ease a stifling blockade on Gaza in exchange for Hamas pledges to disarm, the officials said, speaking on condition of anonymity because they were discussing sensitive negotiations. It is unclear whether any progress has been made in the cease-fire efforts, which include Hamas demands to reopen sea and airports in Gaza. Israeli officials declined comment.
In the short run, the biggest threat to the quiet is a small but growing number of extremists in Gaza inspired by the Islamic State group, who have fired rockets across the heavily guarded frontier in order to undermine Hamas. The militants believe Hamas is soft on Israel and has failed to establish an Islamic state.
That has transformed Israel and Hamas  bitter enemies for nearly three decades  into unspoken allies against a shared threat.
Nowhere is this more evident than in the southern town of Khan Younis, where Hamas militants have been supervising work crews that are opening a road along Gazas eastern fence with Israel. The patrols have helped preserve quiet in a volatile area used in the past by rocket-launching squads.
Hamas officials say that maintaining the cease-fire is a national interest. A young element breaking that understanding is our responsibility and the responsibility of all of us and all the factions to stop him, said Hamas official Salah Bardawil. Nobody should break the national understanding in a meaningless way.
The road work has been taking place as close as 150 meters (175 yards) from the border, an area that Israel in the past has made off-limits. In an unusual scene earlier this month, four Israeli military bulldozers entered a buffer zone to remove brush along the fence. Camouflaged Hamas militants approached the area but did not confront them.
Advertisement
For sure, there are implicit, indirect understandings by both sides not to attack each other, said Ibrahim al-Madhoun, a Gaza analyst who is close to Hamas. The road is a message that there is a flexible political mind in Gaza (Hamas) that can take reasonable steps in the light of any regional or international changes.
Such a scene would have been unthinkable a year ago, when Israel and Hamas battled for 50 days in their third war since the Islamic militant group  which is sworn to Israels destruction  seized power in Gaza in 2007.
Hamas has honored the cease-fire that ended the war. But a number of small jihadi groups have grown increasingly active in Gaza and appear set on disrupting the calm. They dream of joining Gaza to the IS groups self-styled caliphate in Syria and Iraq, but because they are too weak to challenge Hamas directly, they have instead sought to undermine it by firing rockets at Israel.
Mkhaimar Abusada, a political science professor at Gazas Al-Azhar University, said the rocket fire is aimed at embarrassing Hamas and provoking Israeli military action against the ruling militant group. Any confrontation will ease the security pressure Hamas put on the Salafists, he said, referring to ultraconservative Islamic groups.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said he holds Hamas responsible for all attacks coming out of Gaza and threatened to use Israels full strength to respond. But so far, Israeli reprisals against the recent rocket fire have been limited to empty training sites, and there have been no casualties on either side.
The Israeli military declined to comment on the matter. But defense officials, speaking on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the media, said they are aware of Hamas efforts to preserve the calm.
In addition to the border patrols, Hamas has arrested dozens of Salafi activists in recent months and set up checkpoints in sensitive areas to look for suspects.
Hamas officials say little about the road patrols. Mahmoud Zahar, a Hamas leader, said the action has helped improve security by preventing Palestinians from infiltrating into Israel and is helping protect the properties of people from Israel. He also said the road would help local farmers gain access to lands that could not easily be reached following the war.
Alon Ben-David, the senior military correspondent for Israels Channel 10 TV, said Hamas was sending a conciliatory message to Israel.
What they are broadcasting with those patrols is: We are preventing friction with you (Israel), he said. We are here to prevent fire on Israel.
But he said the Hamas patrols are also collecting intelligence on Israeli military positions and soldiers. So this could all in a second turn upside down and become a military offensive maneuver. But now their objective is the opposite, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:10:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Huckabee avoids stand on Confederate battle flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150621/huckabee-avoids-stand-on-confederate-battle-flag</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Politics
Huckabee avoids stand on Confederate battle flag
Salley Rickenbacker, of Columbia, S.C., holds an U.S flag as the Confederate flag flies nearby during a rally to take down the flag at the South Carolina Statehouse, Saturday in Columbia, S.C. Rep. Doug Brannon, R-Landrum, said its past time for the Confederate flag to be removed from South Carolinas Statehouse grounds after nine people were killed at the Emanuel AME Church shooting. Rainier Ehrhardt  The Associated Press
By Kevin Freking, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Protesters close their eyes in silent prayer as they stand on the South Carolina Statehouse steps during a rally to take down the Confederate flag, Saturday in Columbia, S.C. Rep. Doug Brannon, R-Landrum, said its past time for the Confederate flag to be removed from South Carolinas Statehouse grounds after nine people were killed at the Emanuel A.M.E. Church shooting. Rainier Ehrhardt  The Associated Press
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; Republican Mike Huckabee says the Confederate flag debate in South Carolina is something for that states residents to take on if they so choose, but he doesnt believe presidential candidates need to take a stand on the topic.
Mitt Romney, the Republican nominee for president in 2012, has called for the immediate removal of the Confederate battle flag from outside the South Carolina Statehouse.
The former Arkansas governor says he believes voters want presidential candidates focused on the economy and keeping Americans safe. They dont want the candidates weighing in on every little issue in all 50 states however important that issue is to a particular state.
Huckabees comments on NBCs Meet the Press come in the wake of the shooting of nine black people at a Charleston church.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:09:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Orleans police arrest suspect in killing of officer</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150621/new-orleans-police-arrest-suspect-in-killing-of-officer</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
New Orleans police arrest suspect in killing of officer
Investigators look over a New Orleans Police department vehicle in which one officer was shot and killed while transporting a prisoner in New Orleans, Saturday. The New Orleans Police Department said Officer Daryle Holloway was shot while transporting Travis Boys, who managed to get his handcuffed hands from behind his back to the front, grab a firearm and shoot the officer. A manhunt was underway for the 33-year-old Boys, according to Police Chief Michael Harrison. Gerald Herbert  The Associated Press
By Kevin Mcgill, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
NEW ORLEANS &gt;&gt; Police in New Orleans say they have arrested a suspect they believe managed to slip into the front seat of a police vehicle while handcuffed and shoot the police officer who was transporting him to jail.
The New Orleans Police Department, in brief announcements on social media, announced the arrest Sunday morning of 33-year-old Travis Boys. The arrest follows a 24-hour manhunt for Boys, who escaped from the vehicle after allegedly shooting and killing Officer Daryle Holloway.
Holloway, 45, had been a member of the New Orleans Police Department since 1992. He was the father of three children.
Boys was under arrest on an aggravated assault charge at the time of the shooting. It was unclear how he allegedly obtained a weapon, worked his handcuffed wrists from behind his back and got through a barrier that separated him from the front seat.
Police Superintendent Michael Harrison and Mayor Mitch Landrieu were to hold a press conference later Sunday to provide further details on the investigation into the killing.
Harrison said he met with two of Holloways children and Holloways former wife at the hospital after he died. As a new chief, it was the hardest thing Ive ever had to do in my life, said Harrison, who became chief last year.
He said he had known Holloway for 23 years and described him as a great police officer.
Landrieu on Saturday decried the killing as the lowest of the low and called on the public to help police with information on Boys whereabouts.
Killing an officer in the line of duty is an attack on our community that will not stand, Landrieu said in a statement. The heart and soul of New Orleans is heavy today as our community mourns one of our citys finest.
The last New Orleans Police Department officer killed in the line of duty was Officer Rodney Thomas on July 7, 2013, according to Gamble. More recently, a Housing Authority police officer, James Bennett Jr., 45, was found shot to death in his patrol car.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:07:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands mark summer solstice at Stonehenge</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150621/thousands-mark-summer-solstice-at-stonehenge</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Thousands mark summer solstice at Stonehenge
People stand on the stones as thousands of revellers gather at the ancient stone circle Stonehenge to celebrate the Summer Solstice, the longest day of the year, near Salisbury, England,Sunday. Tim Ireland  The Associated Press
By The Associated Press
# Comments
The sun rises as thousands of revellers gathered at the ancient stone circle Stonehenge to celebrate the Summer Solstice, the longest day of the year, near Salisbury, England, Sunday. Tim Ireland  The Associated Press
LONDON &gt;&gt; Thousands of revelers, new-agers and self-styled Druids descended on the ancient stone circle at Stonehenge on Sunday, catching a brief glimpse of the sun as they marked the summer solstice  the longest day of the year in the northern hemisphere.
About 23,000 sun-watchers gathered on the Salisbury Plain about 80 miles (130 kilometers) southwest of London, police said. But with the sun visible only briefly, the party was markedly shorter than in past years. Authorities reported nine arrests for drug offenses  fewer than in the past.
Visitors kissed the stones, dancers swirled on the grass and drummers pounded as part of the free-form celebrations. A small group of yoga enthusiasts held a short class and couples renewed their commitments to one another.
Stonehenge is an icon of Britain, and one of its most popular attractions. It was built in three phases between 3,000 B.C. and 1,600 B.C. and its purpose remains under study.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 19:04:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In open letter, Taylor Swift criticizes 'shocking' Apple Music</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/technology/20150621/in-open-letter-taylor-swift-criticizes-shocking-apple-music</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Technology
In open letter, Taylor Swift criticizes shocking Apple Music
In a file photo, Taylor Swift poses in the press room with the awards for top Billboard 200 album for 1989, top female artist, chart achievement, top artist, top Billboard 200 artist, top hot 100 artist, top digital song artist, and top streaming song (video) for Shake It Off at the Billboard Music Awards at the MGM Grand Garden Arena, in Las Vegas. Photo by Eric Jamison  Invision  AP, File
By The Associated Press
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; In an open letter to Apple, Taylor Swift has criticized the companys new streaming music service for failing to pay artists for a free three-month trial.
Writing on her Tumblr page Sunday in a posting titled To Apple, Love Taylor, Swift said she would withhold her 2014 album 1989 from Apple Music, which launches June 30. The pop star called Apples plan not to compensate artists, writers or producers during the three-month trial shocking, disappointing, and completely unlike this historically progressive and generous company.
Swift said she was speaking up for the music community at large, not for her own personal gain. Three months, she said, is a long time to go unpaid. Last November, Swift also pulled 1989 off Spotify.
Apple did not immediately respond to requests for comment.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 03:15:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Orleans police officer killed while transporting suspect</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150620/new-orleans-police-officer-killed-while-transporting-suspect</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Shootings
New Orleans police officer killed while transporting suspect
Investigators talk at the scene where a New Orleans Police officer was shot and killed while transporting a prisoner in New Orleans, Saturday, June 20, 2015. The prisoner remains at large. AP Photo/Gerald Herbert
By KEVIN McGILL, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
This undated photo provided by the City of New Orleans shows Officer Daryle Holloway.  The New Orleans Police Department said Holloway was shot while transporting a suspect, Travis Boys, who managed to get his handcuffed hands from behind his back to the front, grab a firearm and shoot the officer. A manhunt was underway for the 33-year-old Boys, according to Police Chief Michael Harrison. City of New Orleans via AP
NEW ORLEANS &gt;&gt; A handcuffed prisoner in a moving police cruiser managed to grab a gun, fatally shoot the officer at the wheel and escape from the vehicle, which careened into a utility pole at a busy intersection, police said Saturday.
Officer Daryle Holloway, 45, died at a hospital, police chief Michael Harrison said. Meanwhile, an intense manhunt was on for Travis Boys, 33, the suspect who had been arrested on an aggravated assault charge and was being taken to jail when he escaped.
The New Orleans Crimestoppers organization announced a $10,000 reward for information leading to Boys arrest.
Rifle-toting police in bullet-proof vests, some with trained canines, searched whole blocks of one neighborhood about a mile from the citys French Quarter Sunday afternoon. Residents clustered on street corners to watch as officers checked backyards and squinted under modest homes elevated on flood-protection piers.
He will be caught and he will be brought to justice for the murder of Officer Holloway and for this assault on our entire community, Harrison said in a police department statement.
The shooting happened Saturday morning as Boys was handcuffed in the back seat of the vehicle. Boys managed to get his hands from behind his back to the front and obtain a weapon as well, Harrison told reporters at the scene in a video interview posted on the departments Facebook page.
Boys got to the front seat through an opening in the cage that separates front and back seats and shot Holloway, Harrison said.
Officer Holloway put up a fight to try to get the subject to not exit the vehicle but succumbed to his injuries, Harrison said.
Department spokesman Tyler Gamble said police were trying to determine what weapon Boys used and how he obtained it, but do not believe Boys used the officers gun.
John Polk, who lives around the corner from where the police SUV came to rest, said he was just awakening when he heard a loud noise and his power went out. The noise, he figured, was an electrical transformer blowing.
I look out the door  Id heard the boom  I see the fire truck here on the corner, he said. It was only later 45 minutes later, after police had swarmed into the area that he learned what happened.
A helicopter circled overhead as marked and unmarked units from state police and other law enforcement agencies cruised the side streets. Utility workers worked to replace the downed power pole.
State police, St. Tammany Parish deputies, Housing Authority of New Orleans police and the U.S. Marshals Service were among those searching for Boys.
Advertisement
Police seeking Boys halted traffic Saturday into an area of several city blocks of the St. Roch neighborhood not far from where the shooting occurred. Officers kept people from entering the area, and others from leaving.
Vincent Alexander, a prep cook at Margaritaville restaurant in the French Quarter, said he was walking home from work when police detoured him a short distance from his house. I just called my roommate. Theyre not letting him get out the house.
Holloway had been a member of the New Orleans Police Department since 1992. He was the father of three children.
Harrison said Holloway was not the arresting officer but was transporting Boys to a jail when the shooting occurred.
Harrison said he met with two of those children and Holloways former wife at the hospital after he died. As a new chief, it was the hardest thing Ive ever had to do in my life, said Harrison, who became chief last year.
He said he had known Holloway for 23 years and described him as a great police officer.
Mayor Mitch Landrieu decried the killing as the lowest of the low and called on the public to help police with information on Boys whereabouts.
Killing an officer in the line of duty is an attack on our community that will not stand, Landrieu said in a statement. The heart and soul of New Orleans is heavy today as our community mourns one of our citys finest.
The last New Orleans Police Department officer killed in the line of duty was Officer Rodney Thomas on July 7, 2013, according to Gamble. More recently, a Housing Authority police officer, James Bennett Jr., 45, was found shot to death in his patrol car.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 20 19:25:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charleston church shooting site to re-open; FBI reviews manifesto</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150620/charleston-church-shooting-site-to-re-open-fbi-reviews-manifesto</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Shootings
Charleston church shooting site to re-open; FBI reviews manifesto
Mourners Cynthia Wright-Murphy, right, hugs her sister Carolyn Wright-Porcher, right, outside the Emanuel AME Church, Saturday, June 20, 2015  in Charleston, S.C. A steady stream of people brought flowers and notes and shared somber thoughts at a growing memorial in front of the church. (AP Photo/Stephen B. Morton)
By JEFFREY COLLINS and EMILY MASTERS, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Charleston, S.C., shooting suspect Dylann Storm Roof is escorted from the Cleveland County Courthouse in Shelby, N.C., Thursday, June 18, 2015. Roof is a suspect in the shooting of several people Wednesday night at the historic The Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston. The current brick Gothic revival edifice, completed in 1891 to replace an earlier building heavily damaged in an earthquake, was a mandatory stop for the likes of Booker T. Washington and the Rev. Martin Luther King Jr. Still, Emanuel was not just a church for the black community.(AP Photo/Chuck Burton)
CHARLESTON, S.C. &gt;&gt; Parishioners were let into the bullet-scarred Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church on Saturday, getting a firsthand glimpse of the room where nine people from their congregation were slain.
Around that same time, two federal law enforcement officials said the FBI was investigating a manifesto purportedly written by the suspected gunman, 21-year-old Dylan Roof.
The website linked to Roof contained photos of him holding a burning American flag and standing on one. In other images, he was holding a Confederate flag, considered a divisive symbol by civil rights leaders and others.
The hate-filled 2,500-word essay talks about white supremacy and the author says the event that truly awakened me was the Trayvon Martin case.
Martin was an unarmed black teenager who was fatally shot in Florida in 2012 by neighborhood watch volunteer George Zimmerman. Martin was walking home, got into a confrontation with Zimmerman and was shot.
Prosecutors accused Zimmerman of profiling Martin, but he was acquitted of murder. The manifesto said it was obvious that Zimmerman was in the right and that the case led him to search black on White crime on the Internet.
I have never been the same since that day, it said.
Its unclear if Roof wrote it but the rants are in line with what he has told friends and what he said before allegedly opening fire inside the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal church Wednesday night.
Cleaning crews worked at the church Saturday and church members announced they will hold a Sunday service. Harold Washington, 75, was with the small group that saw the lower-level room where the victims were shot.
They did a good job cleaning it up, there were a few bullet holes around but what they did, they cut them out so you dont see the actual holes, he said.
He said he expected an emotional service Sunday, and a large turnout.
Were gonna have people come by that weve never seen before and will probably never see again, and thats OK, he said. Its a church of the Lord  you dont turn nobody down.
The church had that same welcoming nature when Roof walked into their Bible study, Felecia Sanders, who survived the shooting, said at Roofs bail hearing Friday. She lost her son Tywanza in the attack.
Two federal law enforcement officials close to the investigation said the FBI is aware of the website linked to Roof and is reviewing it. The officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak publicly on the case.
Advertisement
Internet registry records show that the website was created on Feb. 9 via a Russian registry service with the owners personal details hidden. A man who answered the phone at the Moscow-based company would not say who the sites owner was.
Roof is being held in jail, facing nine counts of murder and a weapons charge.
A police affidavit released Friday accused Roof of shooting all nine multiple times, and making a racially inflammatory statement as he stood over an unidentified survivor.
Roof had complained while getting drunk on vodka recently that blacks were taking over the world and that someone needed to do something about it for the white race, according to Joey Meek, who tipped off the FBI when he saw his friend on surveillance images.
In Charleston, the grief was so palpable three days after the shooting that a family re-routed its trip home from the beach and a bride-to-be interrupted her wedding day to pay their respects.
Its been a weird feeling, trying to have a celebration this weekend. But the whole city has been so supportive and such a show of grace, said Kathryn Cole, 27, who lives two blocks away from the church and is set to say her nuptials Saturday night. Life is carrying on. We arent letting this change our everyday lives.
Derrick Jones was vacationing on Hilton Head Island when he decided to drive an hour out of his way home to Greenville. He stopped at the church with his wife and three boys.
Theyve been asking questions all day since this has happened, Jones said. And I dont really have all the answers. I try to explain it the best way I can.
Greenville residents Stacey and Kenneth Penland arrived in Charleston for vacation Friday. During their first full day in the city, they came to the church with their children, 6-year-old Luke and 3-year-old Logan.
Weve been at the beach, and then the market, and of course we stopped by here, said Kenneth Penland.
___
Contributors include Seanna Adcox, Phillip Lucas, Meg Kinnard and David Goldman.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 20 19:21:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Roadside bomb kills at least 12 civilians in Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150620/roadside-bomb-kills-at-least-12-civilians-in-afghanistan</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Roadside bomb kills at least 12 civilians in Afghanistan
By MIRWAIS KHAN, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
KANDAHAR, Afghanistan &gt;&gt; An Afghan family returning to their home after fleeing a possible military operation struck a roadside bomb Saturday in the countrys south, killing at least 12 of them and wounding eight, authorities said.
The blast struck the familys van in Helmand provinces Marjah district, largely a Taliban stronghold. At least 12 died in the blast, though the death toll could rise, said Nabil Jan Mullahkhail, the provincial police chief.
The family fled the district in recent days after hearing a government offensive could take place there, relative Mohammad Salih said. Salih said the death toll likely was higher, as he believed as many as 21 of his relatives had been killed in the blast.
No one immediately claimed responsibility for the blast. The Taliban routinely plant roadside bombs to target Afghan security forces, though the bombs often explode as civilian vehicles pass by, killing them instead.
In February, the United Nations Assistance Mission in Afghanistan documented 10,548 civilian casualties in 2014, the highest number in a single year since 2009. They include 3,699 civilian deaths, up 25 percent from 2013.
The U.N. said at the time that the Taliban and other insurgents were responsible for 72 percent of all civilian casualties, with government forces and foreign troops responsible for just 14 percent. The U.N. report attributed the rise in casualties to intensified ground fighting, in which weapons like mortars, rockets and grenades are used in populated areas, sometimes indiscriminately.
U.S. and NATO troops pulled back from volatile areas last year, handing security responsibility over to Afghan forces and officially concluding their combat mission at the end of the year. In the time since, local Afghan security forces have been increasingly targeted in insurgent attacks.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:02:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia pledges tough security post-attack, as tourists flee</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/tunisia-pledges-tough-security-post-attack-as-tourists-flee</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Terrorist attacks
Tunisia pledges tough security post-attack, as tourists flee
Tunisian army patrol near the attacked Imperial Marhaba hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The morning after a lone gunman killed dozens of people at a beach resort in Tunisia, busloads of tourists are heading to the nearby Enfidha-Hammamet airport hoping to return to their home countries. AP Photo/Darko Vojinovic
By ELAINE GANLEY and BOUAZZA BEN BOUAZZA, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
Tourists line up at a boarding desk as the leave Sousse, Tunisia, after the attack, Saturday June 27, 2015 at the Nfidha airport near Sousse. Tunisias prime minister announced on Saturday a string of new security measures including closing renegade mosques and calling up army reservists as thousands of tourists left the North African country in wake of its worst terrorist attack ever. AP Photo/Salah Rhim
SOUSSE, Tunisia &gt;&gt; Tunisias prime minister announced on Saturday a string of new security measures including closing renegade mosques and calling up army reservists as thousands of tourists fled the North African country in wake of its worst terrorist attack ever.
Tourists crowded into the airport at Hammamet near the coastal city of Sousse where a young man dressed in shorts on Friday pulled an assault rifle and grenades out of his beach umbrella and killed 38 people, mostly tourists. At least 15 victims were British, according to the U.K. foreign minister.
Tobias Ellwood warned that the toll may well rise and described it as the most significant terrorist attack on the British people, since the July 2005 bombings of the London transport network that killed 52 people.
In the early hours of the morning Saturday, a visibly exhausted Prime Minister Habib Essid called for everyone to work against terrorism and promised financial rewards for information leading to arrests.
The fight against terrorism is a national responsibility, he said. We are at war against terrorism which represents a serious danger to national unity during this delicate period that the nation is going through.
The attack came the same day that a suicide bomber killed 27 people in a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and a man in France ran his truck into a warehouse and hung his employers severed head on the gate.
Essid announced the call-up of army reservists and said they would be deployed in tourist sites around the country and inside hotels, while he called on the hotels themselves to do more to enforce security.
He also said that political parties and associations espousing radical ideas with suspicious funding would be closed down and around 80 mosques known for extremist preaching would be shut.
The government has been criticized for its lackluster anti-terror measures, especially since 22 people were killed by gunmen at the national museum in March. There was also been a failed suicide bomb attack in Sousse in 2013.
The attacker, who was killed by security forces, was identified as Seifeddine Rezgui, a young student at Kairouan University.
Witnesses said the young man used grenades in the attack as he moved methodically from the beach to the pool and then into the lobby.
When he came he tossed a grenade and we saw only black  it was smoky, Imen Belfekih, who works for the Imperial Marhaba Hotel where the attack took place, told The Associated Press. Other accounts from survivors also describe hearing explosions in addition to the gunfire during the attack.
Advertisement
A tweet from the Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the attack and gave his jihadi pseudonym of Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani, according to the SITE intelligence group.
The attack in Kuwait was also claimed by the Islamic State and on Saturday thousands of people took part in a mass funeral procession. Police said they are interrogating a number of suspects with possible links to the bombing, which was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group.
In southeastern France, one of the four suspects detained over the explosion and beheading has been released, while the suspected killer was not speaking to investigators, a spokeswoman for the Paris prosecutors office said Saturday.
At the Imperial Marhaba vans and buses were carrying away tourists on Saturday. While the hotel wasnt actually closing down, the tour operators had urged everyone to leave, the director said.
We may have zero clients today but we will keep our staff, said Mohammed Becheur, adding the 370-room hotel had been at 75 percent occupancy before the attack.
On the beach, there was as scattering of tourists while police on horses rode along the beach and their security boats patrolled along the coast.
Tourism is a key part of Tunisias economy and had already fallen some 25 percent after the March museum attack.
Its really sad but what can you do, for everyone, for the tourists, for the people who died, for their families, said Belgian tourist Clause Besser, as he recovered in the hospital from a gunshot wound he received fleeing from the attacker. For me, somehow, with a bullet in the leg, its not a catastrophe. For those who died or were injured for life, its something else.
British travel companies Thomson and First Choice said they are flying back thousands of tourists from Tunisia on Saturday and are cancelling all flights to the country in the coming week. Tourist flights from Ireland to Tunisia have continued in the wake of the attack, but travel agents are offering full refunds for those canceling.
Slovakia has sent a plane to evacuate about 150 of its citizens who are in Tunisia, according to the Foreign Ministry. Scandinavia tour operators say they are flying thousands of people out of Tunisia over the next days.
Since yesterday, there have been about 15 extra flights scheduled at the airport with nine already leaving carrying 1,400 passengers, said Mohamed Walid Ben Ghachem, director of the Enfidha-Hammamet Airport.
Waiting for his flight, British tourist Matthew Price said that he was cutting his weeklong vacation short by three days. Even though it was his third visit to Tunisia, he expected it to be his last.
Its the first time Ive ever been on holiday and feared for my life. So obviously you cant come back somewhere its not safe, he said.
The Tunisian Health Ministry has said that a Belgian and a German were killed in addition to Britons. Irelands government said an Irish nurse was also among those who were killed.
Relatives and family friends say Lorna Carty was fatally shot as she sunbathed. She and her husband, Declan, had received the holiday as a present to help Declan Carty relax following his recent heart surgery. Family friends speaking to the couples two children said Lorna Carty went ahead of her husband to the beach, where she was shot and she was later pronounced dead at a hospital.
Of the wounded, 24 were Britons, seven Tunisian, three Belgian as well as a German, Russian and Ukrainian and one unidentified, said the Health Ministry. Two were still in critical condition.
While many tourists have left, Welsh couple Angela Chambers and Peter Phillips said from the beach near where the attack took place that they had declined their tour operators offer to take them to the airport last night.
We want to see our holiday out, Phillips said.
___
Bouazza Ben Bouazza reported from Tunis, Tunisia. Associated Press reporters Paul Schemm in Rabat, Morocco, Shawn Pogatchnik in Dublin, and Benjamin Wiacek in Sousse contributed to this report.
___
A previous version of this story has been corrected to show that the gunman killed 38 people, not 39.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:26:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mali: Gunmen attack military camp near Mauritania border</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/mali-gunmen-attack-military-camp-near-mauritania-border/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mali: Gunmen attack military camp near Mauritania border
By BABA AHMED, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
BAMAKO, Mali &gt;&gt; Gunmen attacked a military camp in western Mali on Saturday, exchanging shots with soldiers as residents of a nearby village hid in their homes, officials and witnesses said.
The attack began at around 5 a.m. at the camp near the village of Nara, which is about 50 kilometers (31 miles) from the border with Mauritania, said army spokesman Col. Souleymane Maiga.
The army repelled the attackers who had entrenched themselves in the village, Maiga said. Until around 9 a.m. there were exchanges of fire between the army and the assailants in the streets of the village.
Civilians took shelter as soon as they heard the fighting, said Nara resident Foussein Keita.
Armed men are in the village. We are in our homes listening to automatic gunfire but we dont know what exactly is happening in the village, Keita said.
Casualty information was not immediately available and the assailants were unknown, Maiga said.
But a source in Malis intelligence service, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to speak to the media, said the gunmen were Islamic militants linked to Ansar Dine, one of the groups that took control of northern Mali following a military coup in 2012.
A French-led military intervention launched in 2013 scattered the Islamic extremists, though northern Mali remains insecure and in recent months violence has extended further south. In March a masked gunman opened fire in a restaurant popular with foreigners in Malis capital, Bamako, killing five people.
Earlier this month Malis main coalition of Tuareg separatist rebels signed a peace agreement with the government.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:22:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Weeklong heat weave in southern Pakistan kills 1,233 people</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/weeklong-heat-weave-in-southern-pakistan-kills-1233-people/2</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Weeklong heat weave in southern Pakistan kills 1,233 people
By MUNIR AHMED, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
ISLAMABAD &gt;&gt; A devastating weeklong heat wave in Pakistans southern port city of Karachi killed 1,233 people, an official said.
Nazar Mohammad Bozdar, operations director at the Provincial Disaster Management Authority, said about 65,000 heatstroke patients were treated by doctors at all of Karachis hospitals since June 20 when the heat wave struck Sindh province, where Karachi is the provincial capital.
He told The Associated Press that 1,923 patients with heat-related ailments were still being treated.
The government quickly responded by making arrangements for the treatment of heatstroke patients and the situation has improved now, he said.
Pakistans deadliest heat wave on record coincided with the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, when Pakistans Muslim majority observed a dawn-to-dusk fast.
The temperatures in Karachi came down to 34 degrees Celsius (93 degrees Fahrenheit) after reaching 45 degrees Celsius (113 degrees Fahrenheit) a week ago amid chronic power outages, which forced many residents to spend nights outdoors.
The heat wave shocked many Pakistanis just weeks after soaring temperatures caused nearly 2,200 deaths in neighboring India.
Since then, it has raised fears that South Asia could be seeing some of the devastating effects of human-caused climate change.
On Saturday, TV footage showed a charity burying several unidentified bodies of people who died earlier this week because of the heatstroke. Pakistani television stations reported that several unidentified bodies were buried by the Edhi Foundation charity because local morgues were overflowing.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:10:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Authorities identify 9 victims in deadly Alaska plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150627/authorities-identify-9-victims-in-deadly-alaska-plane-crash</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Authorities identify 9 victims in deadly Alaska plane crash
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska, on Thursday, June 25, 2015. Officials say eight passengers on an excursion off the ship and a pilot were in a plane that was found crashed against the granite rock face of a cliff about 20 miles northeast of Ketchikan, Alaska.  All nine people aboard died in the crash, authorities said. Taylor Balkom/Ketchikan Daily News via AP
By BECKY BOHRER, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
JUNEAU, Alaska &gt;&gt; recovery crew on Friday reached a remote site in southeast Alaska where a sightseeing plane crashed, killing all nine people aboard.
Chris John of the Ketchikan Volunteer Rescue Squad said the aircraft was sitting at a steep angle and three members from his organization had to secure it so they could safely work to recover the bodies.
Eight cruise ship passengers and the pilot died when the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down Thursday in Misty Fjords National Monument near Ketchikan.
The cause of the crash remained under investigation.
Authorities tentatively identified the victims as Hal Cheney, 71, and Mary Doucette, 59, of Lodi, California; Glenda Cambiaso, 31, and Hugo Cambiaso, 65, of North Potomac, Maryland; June Kranenburg, 73, and Leonard Kranenburg, 63, of Medford, Oregon; Margie Apodaca, 63, and Raymond Apodaca, 70, of Sparks, Nevada; and the pilot, Bryan Krill, 64 of Hope, Idaho.
Their remains will be taken to and positively identified at the state medical examiners office in Anchorage.
The plane crashed on a cliff above a lake in steep, muddy and slippery terrain, John said. The fuselage was largely intact but the wings and tail were separated or heavily deformed, he said.
On Thursday, the Coast Guard received a report that the plane was overdue. An emergency locator transmitter activated and a helicopter pilot later spotted the downed aircraft.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery Thursday. Winds were not a concern Friday but there was cloud cover.
A National Transportation Safety Board team was assembled to investigate the crash. Plans were being made to take them to the site on Saturday, John said.
Ketchikan-based airline Promech Air operated the shore excursion offered through Holland America Line. The eight passengers were traveling on the Westerdam on a seven-day cruise that had departed Seattle last Saturday.
We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families, Holland America said in a statement.
The airline echoed those sentiments.
There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling, Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement.
Advertisement
The ship left Ketchikan Thursday night and was expected back in Seattle on Saturday.
Promechs website advertises tours of the more than 3,000-square-mile Misty Fjord National Monument in its floatplanes.
Towering granite cliffs, 1,000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape, it says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 21:01:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Timeline: The gay marriage battle</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150626/timeline-the-gay-marriage-battle</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>United States Supreme Court decisions
Timeline: The gay marriage battle
John Becker, 30, of Silver Spring, Md., waves a rainbow flag in support of gay marriage outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, Thursday June 25, 2015. The same-sex marriage ruling is among the remaining to be released before the term ends at the end of June. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
By Bay Area News Group
Posted:
# Comments
Sept. 21, 1996: The Defense of Marriage Act becomes a federal law, defining marriage for federal purposes as the union of one man and one woman, and allows states to refuse to recognize same-sex marriages granted under the laws of other states.
March 7, 2000: By a 61 percent majority, California voters approve Proposition 22, which says only marriage between a man and a woman is valid.
Feb. 12, 2004: San Francisco Mayor Gavin Newsom defies state law by issuing marriage licenses to same-sex couples at City Hall.
Feb. 24, 2004: President George W. Bush makes gay marriage a campaign issue, calling for a constitutional amendment banning gay marriage.
March 11, 2004: California Supreme Court orders San Francisco to stop marrying gay couples.
May 17, 2004: Massachusetts becomes first state to legalize gay marriage.
Oct. 12, 2007: California Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger vetoes a bill that would have legalized gay marriage.
May 15, 2008: California Supreme Court strikes down states existing laws banning same-sex marriage, saying they violate the rights of gay couples under the California Constitution. Afterward, an estimated 18,000 couples marry.
Oct. 10, 2008: Connecticut Supreme Court grants gays the right to marry.
Nov. 4, 2008: By a 52 percent majority, California voters approve Proposition 8, which restores the ban on same-sex marriage.
April 3, 2009: Iowa Supreme Court legalizes gay marriage.
April 7, 2009: Vermont Legislature overrides governors veto on bill, making gay marriage legal.
May 6, 2009: Maine becomes fifth state to legalize gay marriage.
May 26, 2009: California Supreme Court upholds Proposition 8 but rules that gay couples who married before it passed are still married.
June 3, 2009: New Hampshire legalizes gay marriage.
July 8, 2010: Federal judge rules that 1996 Defense of Marriage Act, which defines marriage as the union of a man and a woman, is unconstitutional.
Aug. 4, 2010: U.S. District Chief Judge Vaughn Walker strikes down Proposition 8, ruling that gays have a constitutional right to marry. Courts later put same-sex marriages on hold pending appeals.
June 24, 2011: New York legalizes gay marriage.
Nov. 17, 2011: After the state refuses to defend Proposition 8, California Supreme Court rules that its sponsors have legal standing to defend it.
Advertisement
Feb. 7, 2012: Federal appeals court affirms Walkers 2010 ruling, saying Proposition 8 unconstitutionally discriminates.
March 1, 2012: Maryland legalizes gay marriage.
Oct. 18, 2012: 2nd U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals in New York finds Defense of Marriage Act unconstitutional in a ruling the U.S. Supreme Court later agrees to review. It is one of several lower court decisions striking down the act.
Nov. 6, 2012: Maine and Washington voters approve gay marriage.
Dec. 7, 2012: U.S. Supreme Court says it will hear challenges to Proposition 8 and Defense of Marriage Act.
June 25, 2013: In a 5-4 decision, the U.S. Supreme Court strikes down part of the Defense of Marriage Act of 1996 that denies federal benefits to same-sex couples. The decision does not guarantee a right to same-sex marriage, but allows people who live in states that allow same-sex marriage to receive the same federal benefits as heterosexual couples.
Nov. 6, 2014: The Cincinnati-based 6th Circuit U.S. Court of Appeals upholds bans on same-sex marriage in Kentucky and Michigan and also rules that Ohio, Tennessee and Kentucky are not required to recognize gay marriages that take place in other states. This ruling bucks the trend of other appeals courts, pressuring the Supreme Court to take up the issue.
June 26, 2015: The U.S. Supreme Court rules that the U.S. Constitution guarantees the right for same-sex couples to marry in all 50 U.S. states.
-- Bay Area News Group research
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:46:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PHOTOS: Supreme Court declares same-sex marriage legal in U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150626/photos-supreme-court-declares-same-sex-marriage-legal-in-us</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>United States Supreme Court decisions
PHOTOS: Supreme Court declares same-sex marriage legal in U.S.
Stonewall Inn's bartender who goes by the single name of Tree, far left, is interviewed while a couple, right, requesting anonymity,  kiss outside the iconic Greenwich Village bar, Friday, June 26, 2015, in New York.  "I was here dancing with my friends the day of the rebellion when the cops raided the place," said Tree about 1969 event credited for igniting the gay rights movement. The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the U.S.  (AP Photo/Bebeto Matthews)
By Los Angeles News Group
Posted:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:13:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Justice Antonin Scalia's dissent in gay marriage decision gets ranty. Cue the memes.</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150626/justice-antonin-scalias-dissent-in-gay-marriage-decision-gets-ranty-cue-the-memes/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>United States Supreme Court decisions
Justice Antonin Scalias dissent in gay marriage decision gets ranty. Cue the memes.
By Christina Gullickson , Los Angeles Daily News
Posted:
# Comments
File Photo: This artist rendering shows civil rights lawyer Mary Bonauto right. arguing before the Supreme Court during its hearing on same-sex marriage, Tuesday, April 28, 2015, in Washington. Justices, from left are, Sonia Sotomayor, Stephen Breyer, Clarence Thomas, Antonin Scalia, Chief Justice John Roberts, Anthony Kennedy, Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Samuel Alito Jr., and Elena Kagan. The court's decision was issued Friday, June 26, 2015, with Scalia's dissent coming under heavy fire on social media. (AP File Photo/Dana Verkouteren)
The Supreme Court of the United States declared gay marriage legal on Friday, June 26, 2015. Justice Antonin Scalias dissent instantly became Internet fodder with phrases such as ask the nearest hippie striking a chord with many.
Viewing on mobile? Go here.
Advertisement
About the Author
Christina Gullickson is the Digital Director of Mobile and Social for the Los Angeles News Group. Reach the author at christina.gullickson@langnews.com or follow Christina on Twitter: @CGullTweets .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:53:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece, creditors closer on euro-saving bailout</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150626/greece-creditors-closer-on-euro-saving-bailout</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody># Comments
German Chancellor Angela Merkel speaks during a final media conference Friday after an EU summit in Brussels. VIRGINIA MAYO  The Associated Press
BRUSSELS &gt;&gt; Greece and its creditors moved closer to clinching a deal this weekend that would keep the country from defaulting on its debts and falling out of the euro bloc, after Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras made more concessions Friday.
Greece has agreed to reforms that are close to what creditors have demanded before they release new loans, officials said on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the negotiations. The creditors in return offered Greece a five-month extension to its bailout program, which is due to end Tuesday.
The concessions come only days after Greece proposed 8 billion euros in budget savings over two years. But the creditors, particularly the International Monetary Fund, said those proposed measures were not good enough, arguing they rely too much on business taxes that could hurt growth.
Fridays latest proposals brought the sides much closer together, enough for some to anticipate that an emergency meeting on Saturday of the eurozones 19 finance ministers could bring a decisive breakthrough.
Tomorrows meeting is of decisive character, German Chancellor Angela Merkel said after meeting Tsipras and French President Francois Hollande.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker agreed. There is a real chance to conclude an agreement, he said, adding that Saturday was a crucial day not only for Greece but for the euro area as a whole. Im quite optimistic but not overly optimistic.
Under the latest proposal, Athens said it will cut spending on pensions, a key requirement by creditors. Greece will reduce the contribution from the state to pensions by between 0.25 percent and 0.5 percent of GDP this year and by 1 percent next year.
An official from one of the creditor institutions said that if you assess both sides the difference now is very, very small.
According to the text of creditors proposals seen by The Associated Press, Athens was offered an extension to its bailout program through November, with loans worth 15.5 billion euros. That includes 7.2 billion euros from the existing rescue program and money left over from a bank rescue fund.
A Greek government official expressed dissatisfaction with the terms, saying it amounted to Greece accepting to make more cuts in return for existing bailout funds that would just cover its needs.
Advertisement
The official said the government was pushing for an improved proposal on Saturday.
Markets nevertheless rose on news of the concessions, with the Athens stock index closing up 2 percent and other major European indexes edging higher.
The gap between Greece and its creditors looks much smaller now that Greece has caved on some of its proposed pension reforms, said Megan Greene, chief economist at Manulife Asset Management.
Greece has to pay 1.6 billion euros to the IMF on Tuesday. Should it default on its debt, the country could eventually have to leave Europes joint currency, the euro. That would likely plunge Greece back into a deep and long recession and shake European and global markets.
It really has to happen tomorrow, said Jeroen Dijsselbloem, president of the eurogroup of finance ministers, since any deal would have to go through the parliaments of Greece and several other eurozone countries.
Tsipras, elected in January on promises to repeal the deep austerity measures imposed on the country in return for two bailouts totaling 240 billion euros, has long been adamant he would not agree to more measures that would hurt the economy. But faced with the prospect of a national default, he is having to compromise.
Business leaders in Greece have been alarmed by the latest measures Tsipras has proposed, which include increases in company and consumer taxes.
The trust has to return and that requires a deal, it requires a number of reforms and they will have to accept that, Dijsselbloem said.
Separately, a banking official said the European Central Bank had agreed Friday to a request for support to Greek banks. The official declined to specify whether the request was for an increase in the emergency credit Greek banks have been receiving.
Worried depositors have been pulling their money out of Greek banks, fearing a failure in the negotiations could lead to financial turmoil and a restriction on banking transactions. An estimated 4 billion left Greek banks last week.
____
Elena Becatoros in Athens, Lorne Cook in Brussels, Mike Corder in The Hague, Netherlands, and Geir Moulson in Berlin contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 20:09:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Illicit drugs 'rampant' in California state prisons</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150621/illicit-drugs-rampant-in-california-state-prisons/1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Prisons
Illicit drugs rampant in California state prisons
In this photo taken Wednesday, May 20, 2015, Bentley, a 3-year-old Labrador retriever,  checks an inmate for traces of narcotics at California State Prison, Solano, in Vacaville, Calif.  In an effort to reduce the amount of inmates dying of drug overdoses, the Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation is tightening its policies for searching visitors, inmates and employees. More than $8 million has been spent this year on drug-sniffing dogs, airport-style ion spectrometry devices and low-dose X-ray body scanners.(AP Photo/Rich Pedroncelli)
By Don Thompson, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this photo taken Wednesday May 20, 2015, Correctional Officer M. Jones puts on gloves before demonstrating an airport-style ion spectrometer that tests for illegal narcotics at Vacaville State Prison in Vacaville, Calif. In an effort to reduce the amount of inmates dying of drug overdoses, the Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation is tightening its policies for searching visitors, inmates and employees.  More than $8 million has been spent this year on drug-sniffing dogs, airport-style ion spectrometry devices and low-dose X-ray body scanners.(AP Photo/Rich Pedroncelli)
VACAVILLE &gt;&gt; California inmates are dying of drug overdoses at nearly triple the national rate and its unclear whether the tough steps state officials took this year to stop illicit drugs from getting into prisons are having any effect, though they are prompting criticism from civil rights advocates.
The Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation is spending $8 million this year on drug-detecting scanners and a new breed of drug-sniffing dogs while also employing strip searches on visitors suspected of carrying drugs.
Corrections officials believe the stepped-up efforts are discouraging smuggling, but the data thats available so far doesnt support that  more than 6,000 scans have been done on visitors and employees at 11 prisons since December without finding anyone with drugs.
The state doesnt track if anyone has been arrested because of the dog searches and waited until mid-May to begin tracking the number of arrests made using any of the new procedures.
Meantime, criticism is mounting about false-positive results by the scanners and dogs that can lead to strip searches. Concerned lawmakers who oversee state prisons included language in the California budget plan passed this week that would end the searches and require an evaluation of the departments other efforts.
Its a humiliating process, can be easily used to humiliate and demean people, and was only for visitors, often women, Democratic Sen. Loni Hancock, said of the strip searches. There are many concerns about the dogs, which have historically been emblematic of intimidation of many communities of color, most notably during the civil rights movement.
But no one wants to see drug deaths, and she said the evaluation will show which of the new programs are effective.
More than 150 California inmates have died of drug overdoses since 2006, with a high of 24 in 2013. Moreover, the sharing of intravenous needles often spreads hepatitis C infections, which killed 69 inmates in 2013 alone.
Corrections Secretary Jeffrey Beard recently told lawmakers that drugs are rampant in the prisons.
What we are trying to do is send a message to people to not try to smuggle drugs in to the institution, he said in an interview. If we dont do this, were going to have people keep dying, were going to have continued violence in the prisons.
Beard is modeling Californias new procedures on those used successfully in the Pennsylvania corrections department he led for a decade. While California has a long-term annual rate of eight drug- or alcohol-related deaths per 100,000 inmates, Pennsylvanias is one.
Advertisement
Florida, Georgia, Illinois, Ohio and Texas also each averaged one death a year per 100,000 inmates from 2001-2012, according to the most recent national figures. Maryland had the nations worst rate, at 17 deaths per 100,000 inmates.
Beard said Californias program would have more rapid success if lawmakers had given him more money, and he may seek funds to expand the program as early as this fall.
He believes the ion scanners  similar to those used to screen airport travelers  are deterring smugglers. The lack of results may be because only about 5 percent of visitors and employees are being scanned, he said, though the eventual goal is 30 percent. By contrast, Pennsylvania scanned 68 percent of visitors last year and at least 20 percent of employees.
Pennsylvania officials could not say how much contraband was found by using the scanners.
Records show the German shepherd and similar looking dogs long used in California prisons have been effective at rooting out hidden drugs. But to search visitors, employees and inmates the department is turning to less aggressive dogs including Labrador retrievers  fluffy, friendly dogs, Northern California canine program coordinator Sgt. Brian Pyle said.
The decision to use dogs to search humans, instead of unoccupied spaces as was previously the policy, prompted the resignation last fall of Wayne Conrad, the departments statewide canine program coordinator. He criticized the expense of sending California dog handlers to Pennsylvania for training, the use of breeds that he said are less reliable, and what he said was a supervisors effort to stifle concerns about the program because it was championed by Beard.
The dogs are going to start alerting on people whose kids are smoking dope or something, and that false positive could prompt an unnecessary strip search, Conrad said. The next thing thats going to come is the lawsuits.
Beard said he is seeking alternatives to strip searches, and downplayed the possibility that false-positive alerts unfairly implicate innocent visitors and employees. But thats what happened to Tania Gamboa of Riverside when she went to see her brother at Kern Valley State Prison.
She initially laughed when the ion machine tested positive for exposure to heroin, saying she doesnt even drink alcohol. But she was crying after she was required to strip naked in front of two female correctional officers and squat to demonstrate that she was not concealing drugs.
It doesnt make sense for me, knowing that I dont do all that and I got detected for it, she said.
Mohamed Shehk, an Oakland-based spokesman for Critical Resistance, which advocates for better conditions for inmates, said the policies are turning visitors into suspects.
The statistics  $8 million, 6,000 scans and nothing to show for it  show that these are intended to intimidate and criminalize people who are going to see their loved ones inside, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 21:25:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Jurassic World' holds box office, but 'Inside Out' shows bite</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150621/jurassic-world-holds-box-office-but-inside-out-shows-bite</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Box office receipts
Jurassic World holds box office, but Inside Out shows bite
This photo provided by Universal Pictures shows, Chris Pratt, left, and Bryce Dallas Howard in a scene from the film, Jurassic World, directed by Colin Trevorrow, in the next installment of Steven Spielbergs groundbreaking Jurassic Park series. The 3D movie releases in theaters by Universal Pictures on. Chuck Zlotnick  Universal Pictures via AP
By Jake Coyle, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this file image released by Disney-Pixar, characters, from left, Anger, voiced by Lewis Black, Disgust, voiced by Mindy Kaling, Joy, voiced by Amy Poehler, Fear, voiced by Bill Hader, and Sadness, voiced by Phyllis Smith appear in a scene from Inside Out. The movie releases in theaters on. Disney-Pixar via AP, File
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; In a box-office bout of Tyrannosaurus-sized proportions, Jurassic World kept the No. 1 spot with one of the biggest second weeks ever, while Pixars Inside Out nearly matched it with a $91 million debut well above expectations.
Universals Jurassic World took in $102 million in North American theaters, according to studio estimates Sunday, making it only the second release to break $100 million in its second week. The enormous holdover for Jurassic World, which last week set an opening weekend record with $208.8 million, has been bested by only 2012s The Avengers, which made $103.1 million in second week.
The unexpected sensation of the Colin Trevorrow-directed, Steven Spielberg-produced fourth entry in the franchise had turned Disneys $175 million 3-D Inside Out into an underdog expected to merely nip at the heels of Jurassic World. But the emotional Inside Out, about the voices in the head of an 11-year-old girl, blew past its own forecasts to set records, too.
Inside Out was the first Pixar release not to open in first place, following an unparalleled two-decade streak of 14 straight no. 1s. But its the largest opening for a wholly original movie (one not based on source material or a sequel), unseating Avatar in that distinction. Directed by Pete Docter (Up) and co-directed by Ronaldo del Carmen, Inside Out had been expected to open in the range of previous Pixar non-sequels like Wall-E ($63.8 million opening) and Brave ($66.3 million).
But Inside Out was propelled by gushing reviews from critics, a flashy premiere at the Cannes Film Festival and an appetite for a movie from Pixar. The animation studio hadnt had a release in two years after delaying The Good Dinosaur last year.
We came into the weekend thinking wed do something in the 60s, said David Hollis, distribution head for Disney. As we got closer to release, we hit a critical mass of really unbelievable critical response. In this day and age where technology allows people to see a Rotten Tomatoes score or read something and pass it along to their friends, all of a sudden, there was quite a stir about this as a thing to see.
The twin hits of Inside Out and Jurassic World are giving Hollywoods summer a major boost. The weekend was up a staggering 64.6 percent over the same weekend last year, according to box-office data firm Rentrak. In 10 days, Jurassic World has already almost made $981.3 million  nearly $1 billion  and appears poised to be among the highest-grossing releases of all time.
Part of the success of Inside Out is owed to this massive infusion of moviegoers into the marketplace, says Paul Dergarabedian, senior media analyst for Rentrak. If you look at last weekend, around the world, how many people were in theaters when Jurassic World made its debut?
Advertisement
He added, though, that Inside Out was also driven by Pixars unique storytelling knack: They can take almost any subject and turn it into something insightful, poignant and moving.
Inside Out and Jurassic World had the multiplexes largely to themselves over the weekend. The other wide release to open was Dope, a low-budget teen comedy set in Los Angeles Inglewood neighborhood. Written and directed by Rick Famuyiwa, starring newcomer Shameik Moore and boasting some high-profile producers (Forest Whitaker, Pharrell Williams), Dope was acquired by Open Road after a buzzy premiere at the Sundance Film Festival.
Though Open Road gave Dope an optimistic wide release of 2,002 theaters, it took in only $6 million.
In limited release, the Adam Scott and Jason Schwartzman comedy The Overnight  also a Sundance premiere  opened on three screens in New York and Los Angeles, pulling in $61,523, good enough for the most packed theaters (albeit in far tinier numbers) besides those playing Jurassic World and Inside Out.
Estimated ticket sales for Friday through Sunday at U.S. and Canadian theaters, according to Rentrak. Where available, the latest international numbers for Friday through Sunday are also included. Final domestic figures will be released Monday.
1. Jurassic World, $102 million ($160.5 million international).
2. Inside Out, $91 million ($41 million international).
3. Spy, $10.5 million.
4. San Andreas, $8.2 million.
5. Dope, $6 million.
6. Insidious Chapter 3, $4.1 million.
7. Pitch Perfect 2, $3.3 million.
8. Mad Max: Fury Road, $2.8 million.
9. Avengers: Age of Ultron, $2.7 million.
10. Tomorrowland, $2 million.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 21 20:48:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couples, officials, foes readying for Supreme Court gay marriage ruling</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/government-and-politics/20150621/couples-officials-foes-readying-for-supreme-court-gay-marriage-ruling</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>United States Supreme Court decisions
Couples, officials, foes readying for Supreme Court gay marriage ruling
In this photo, Pastor Greg Bullard is shown in his chapel in Madison, Tenn. Bullard intends to perform same-sex weddings in the chapel if the U.S. Supreme Court lifts the states gay marriage ban. Mark Humphrey  The Associated Press
By Dan Sewell, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this Monday photo, Ethan Fletcher, left, and partner Andrew Hickam pose for a photograph in Cincinnati. The U.S. Supreme Court is expected to rule sometime this month on the legal status of same-sex marriage; Ohio is among states that still ban it. Gay couples, such as Fletcher and Hickam are gearing up for a quick run to the courthouse in Ohio, Michigan, Kentucky and Tennessee _ the states involved in the cases that were argued in April before the justices. Dan Sewell  The Associated Press
CINCINNATI &gt;&gt; With a U.S. Supreme Court ruling on same-sex marriage expected any day now, gay couples in states with bans are making wedding plans, courthouse officials are getting ready for different scenarios and steadfast foes are working on their strategies to keep up the opposition.
Marriage license bureaus are bracing for a rush of applicants if the court overturns bans. Meanwhile, theres been a series of planning sessions by groups that intend to explore religious objection responses to protect traditional marriage limited to heterosexuals.
Gay couples, such as Ethan Fletcher and Andrew Hickam of Cincinnati, are gearing up for a quick run to the courthouse in Ohio, Michigan, Kentucky and Tennessee  the states involved in the cases that were argued in April before the justices. Theyre among 14 states that ban same-sex marriage, and if the high court rules in favor of gay marriage, it would apply nationally.
Fletcher, 31, a University of Cincinnati senior academic adviser, and Hickam, 30, a GE Aviation engineer, have arranged to take off work to get their license if the decision allows immediate same-sex marriages and will then plan a formal wedding. They became engaged nearly two years ago but decided against getting married in another state as long as there was the possibility they could do it at home.
Well, we live here and we pay taxes here and our families live here, said Fletcher, adding that they want his grandmother and Hickams mother to be able to attend. We didnt feel that it was reasonable for us to have to travel out of state for the freedom to marry.
In Hamilton County, where Cincinnati is located, the marriage license bureau said other courthouse staffers have been cross-trained and forms are available online to help speed the process. Court officials in Cuyahoga County, where Cleveland is located, say theyre prepared to process triple the usual number of applications.
Probate Court Judge Jan Michael Long, of Pickaway County, near Columbus, said he and other probate judges met to discuss potential rulings and their impacts. There are a lot of procedural issues involving the need for gender-neutral wording and who gets legal notifications, he said, and it could be complicated depending on when the court ruling becomes effective and how its worded.
In Ingham County, Michigan, Clerk Barb Byrum said she might not wait for a new marriage license form from the state, and could simply white-out bride and groom on the application when she gets the legal green light.
Advertisement
She has collected dozens of email addresses from local same-sex couples to notify them of the Supreme Court decision when she knows it. She was among four clerks who issued licenses on a Saturday during a 24-hour period in 2014 when gay marriage in Michigan was legal between court orders.
The Tennessee Equality Project has been asking people to let them know in advance if they plan to get married on Day One. Its website includes instructions on obtaining licenses and finding officiants.
Bleu Copas, who lives just outside of Knoxville, said he wants to get married right away if the ban is lifted.
Were looking at wedding bands and what to wear, he said.
He and his fiance plan to marry at a small chapel on a farm belonging to the pastor of Nashvilles Covenant of the Cross Church, Greg Bullard, who intends to host at least 15 free weddings for same-sex couples on July 3 if the court makes it legal.
Some pastors, though, have signaled plans to resist a Supreme Court ruling in favor of same-sex marriage. Texas Republican Gov. Greg Abbott recently signed a pastor protection law that allows clergy members to refuse officiating marriages that violates his religious beliefs.
Leaders of the Southern Baptist Convention, meeting Wednesday in Columbus, issued a statement saying they would not recognize, host or perform same-sex marriages. Some county clerks in Kentucky and other states, including Nebraska, have expressed objections to the possibility of same-sex marriages, but Douglas County Clerk Thomas Cavanaugh, in Omaha, said Nebraskas largest counties already have changed marriage license applications to include gender-neutral wording and are ready to follow whatever the high court decides is the law.
North Carolina and Utah have passed laws allowing some court officials to refuse to perform gay marriage responsibilities.
Advocacy groups opposed to same-sex marriage have been discussing the legal defenses for religious objectors including business owners, employers and others besides clergy and court officials. Phil Burress, leader of the Citizens for Community Values that opposes gay marriage, predicts a ruling in favor of it will trigger more litigation and political action.
In Cincinnati, Hickam and Fletcher say if the court upholds bans, theyll go to a state that has recognized same-sex marriage through state, not federal action, to wed and then work for the political movement to gain recognition at the ballot box.
We would then just join forces with the rest of the gay community to bring about change through the democratic process, Hickam said. And things would be hopeful going that route.
Contributing to this report were Associated Press writers Travis Loller in Nashville, Tennessee; Ed White in Detroit; Margery A. Beck in Omaha, Nebraska; and Andrew DeMillo in Little Rock, Arkansas.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
