<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailymail">
    <Article id="0">
        <date/>
        <title>
	RSPCA inspectors find 29 Shih Tzus suffering at 'filthy and unhygienic’ house
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152120/Brother-sister-banned-keeping-dogs-RSPCA-inspectors-29-Shih-Tzus-suffering-filthy-unhygienic-house.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Brother and sister Paul and Rosemary Wiggin left wet puppies outside their Staffordshire home. Pregnant dogs were also kept in a 'filthy and unhygienic' house covered in faeces (pictured).
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
A court heard officials found faeces ground into carpets, fly eggs in food that had been left out and some dogs soaking wet and suffering without shelter in the garden.
The pair denied failing to provide adequate living conditions for their animals but were found guilty by JPs sitting at Burton Magistrates Court.
Mr Wiggin was given a 12 month conditional discharge, a 12 month ban on keeping dogs and ordered to pay 7,000 costs.
A court heard officials found faeces ground into carpets and fly eggs in food that had been left out for ages
Some of the helpless dogs were also soaking wet and suffering without shelter in the pair's garden
Ms Wiggin was sentenced to a three year conditional discharge, told to pay 1,000 in costs and was also banned from keeping dogs for a year.
Sentencing, District Judge Shamim Qureshi said although the case did not involve cruelty, the pair had shown a complete failure to own up to what they had done.
RSPCA Inspector Jayne Bashford told the court she found an 'chaotic' atmosphere when she visited the home in Burntwood, Staffordshire, last summer.
She said the dogs were removed and with the arrival of new puppies the number has increased to 44 and the bill for boarding them has come to 75,000..
Inspector Bashford added: 'The whole house was very, very dirty.
'There appeared to be an awful lot of ground in faeces and dirt that covered the carpet.
One tiny puppy sits covered in dirt and soaking wet in the brother and sister's back garden
RSPCA Inspector Jayne Bashford told the court she found an 'chaotic' atmosphere when she visited the home in Burntwood, Staffordshire, last summer
'The conditions we found the dogs in were wholly inappropriate.
'There were numerous hazards in the garden including items in a shed stained with faeces and bones in the garden presenting choking hazards.
'The puppies were cold, wet and whining, with no clean and comfortable resting place. I have no doubt they were suffering.
'Whilst I sympathise and understand the defendants did love their animals, they refused to accept any assistance in improving their welfare, and therefore it would have been wholly unacceptable for the dogs to have remained in these conditions.'
The dogs have been removed from the house, but several have since had puppies - bringing their number up to 44 dogs
Mr and Ms Wiggin fought a prosecution brought by the RSPCA for failing to ensure the welfare of the dogs, but a district judge came down in favour of the animal charity
Mr Wiggin today remained unrepentant and said he had been invited by the RSPCA to keep seven of the dogs as long as the rest could be taken for rehoming
He added: 'To my knowledge there is no law defining the amount of dogs you are allowed to keep.
'If our home is good enough for seven dogs, it is good enough for all of them.
'The RSPCA is a charity and has no expertise in animals whatsoever, yet they tell you how to look after animals.
'I have had pets for 48 years, and never been subjected to what I have in the last 11 months.
'Anyone who has got so-called hazards either in the garden or home - even a dog bone - is likely to be subjected to the same charge we were.'
Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Canada Wood Kitchen and Bar diner told to 'grow a set' by restaurant boss
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151926/Grow-set-amazing-response-restaurateur-stunned-diner-posted-critical-review-establishment-online.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Phil Jeruzal, 27, left an honest review on the Facebook page of Canada Wood Kitchen and Bar in Falkirk, Stirlingshire, after having an 'average' and disappointing meal - only to be told to 'grow a set'.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
131 shares
In response to the suggestions, Mr Jeruzal replied: 'LOL wow, that is the most hilariously unprofessional response to a customer I've ever received. "Grow a set", good god, amazing.
'Thank you so much this has made my day'.
He later added: 'You can have a go at me all you want - even though its hilariously unprofessional and no self-respecting restaurant should ever actually do it - but its not my fault the food isn't good.'
However, the furore did not end there, and Ms Shaw continued to sarcastically thank the customer for his 'detailed feedback'.
MrJeruzal, had taken his girlfriend (pictured together above) for Sunday lunch at the Canada Wood Kitchen and Bar in Falkirk but they both felt let down by the experience and were disappointed with the 'average' food
Mr Jeruzal, a digital content and marketing assistant, said the Canada Wood Restaurant and Bar in Falkirk (pictured) had a 'great location' but was let down by a 'chef that doesn't really seem to know what he is doing'
She wrote: 'Phil, thanks for your detailed feedback I'm sure all of the idiots that rated us four and five star will appreciate your comments'.
Others on the restaurant's Facebook page also picked up on the 'rude' response and condemned the way Ms Shaw handled the complaint.
Aly Gilardoni wrote: 'Seriously rude behaviour on the restaurants part &amp; due to a cock sure attitude from the 'manager' or whom ever replied I'd say many people will certainly think twice before patronising your restaurant in the future.
Claire Smith added: 'Well with the response from the restaurant, I'd never eat here. Unprofessional and rude.'
Lyn McLoughlin said: 'The response from the company here is a fine example of how not to run your business.'
Mr Jeruzal described the restaurant as 'average at best' and rated his experience with two stars on the Facebook review (pictured). It prompted restaurant boss Monica Shaw to reply urging him to 'grow a set'
The restaurant replied telling Mr Jeruzal to 'grow a set' which he described as 'hilariously unprofessional'
And Dale Wright said: 'The restaurant's response to his post was HIGHLY inappropriate, and was apparently written by a manager who has zero training in how to effectively manage and interact with the public.'
Speaking after the social media spat, Mr Jeruzal said he did not want to complain during the meal because he 'didn't want a confrontation with lunch'.
He said: 'In all honesty I found it hilarious, and it's really made my day. Of course it's a completely unprofessional response.
'I can understand that it might be frustrating to have people complain about somewhere you work, but for the most part I was trying to be constructive.
'The internet does offer you a degree of confidence to say things you wouldn't normally say in person, but then again, I don't want a side of confrontation with my lunch.
Mr Jeruzal said he did not want to complain during the meal because he 'didn't want a confrontation with lunch' but felt he should leave a review. He has now blasted the response as 'completely unprofessional'
'Under a different chef I really think the place could be great, because the location is actually fantastic and the building is lovely.
'They are clearly aspiring for something a little different than what is on offer in the rest of Falkirk.
'But for the time being I probably won't be back, and I can't say their response to me online has done them any favours.
'To be honest, their feisty attitude has endeared me to them somewhat.'
Ms Shaw said she 'didn't wish respond' when contacted for comment.
Share or comment on this article
131
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date/>
        <title>
	David Cameron attends 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park for 10th anniversary remembrance
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151879/Never-forget-David-Cameron-Boris-Johnson-7-7-memorial-Hyde-Park-start-day-remembrance-10-years-security-chief-warns-threat-currently-face.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Mr Cameron placed the wreath at the memorial at 8.50am, timed to coincide with the first of the four deadly blasts on the London transport network which killed 52 people and injured hundreds more.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Britain remembers victims of 7/7 bombings: 10 years on, Cameron and Johnson join relatives at Hyde Park memorial to the 52 people who died in London terror attacks
Prime Minister and  Mayor laid floral wreaths at 8.50am, which was timed to coincide with the first of the four suicide blasts in 2005
52 people died and hundreds were injured in the four explosions on London's transport network
Victims remembered with service at St Paul's Cathedral and a minute's silence this morning, while a second service will take place at Hyde Park later today
Poignant anniversary comes amid warnings about threat of terrorism worldwide and a fortnight after Tunisia attack
Published: 07:49 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 13:19 GMT, 7 July 2015
1.2k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Morgan Huelin murder investigation sees 3 public schoolboys arrested in Jersey
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3150961/Three-public-schoolboys-arrested-suspicion-Jersey-s-murder-decade-fellow-pupil-16-dies-unconscious-street.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Three of five schoolboys arrested on suspicion of the murder of 16-year-old Morgan Huelin in Jersey attended the leading£4,800-a-year all boys' school Victoria College, police have confirmed.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
28 shares
Following his death, a Multi-Agency Critical Incident briefing was held with staff from the school, the Education Department, the Youth Service and Health and Children's Service.
Detective Superintendent Gull said: 'The loss of a young person in any circumstance is very sad.
'We are treating the death as unexplained and based on the circumstances as they have presented [a number of suspects] have been arrested on the suspicion of his murder.
'He was found by a lady who was out walking her dog.
'She is okay, under the circumstances, she is a key and significant witness and we are in the process of obtaining a witness statement.'
Friends today describedMorgan Huelin, from the St Lawrence area of the Channel Island, as a 'good kid'
A police officer stands guard in the area where a body was discovered by a dog walker on Saturday morning
The road was cordoned off yesterday while police worked at the scene to gather evidence for their inquiry
He added: 'We have met with senior colleagues [from Victoria College] and I think it is fair to say they are devastated.
'I am sure other pupils and members of staff will also be, in addition to the immediate community.'
Police have not yet revealed how the teenager died and a post-mortem examination is expected to be carried out today.
Friends have since paid tribute to Morgan on social media and by leaving floral tributes at the scene.
Tom Sinel said: 'Tragic news about Morgan, who I coached rugby and knew from Dunlop, sad to lose such a good kid so young. RIP.'
And another friend, called Aaron, added: 'And there you have it. What we all already knew has been confirmed. RIP Morgan. We'll miss you buddy.
One floral tribute read: 'Morgan Huelin, RIP. We hope your family are OK after this tragic day. We send you all our best. You can now rest eternally.'
Another said: 'I feel greatly for those who have lost a key person in their life and I hope things will work out in the end.'
And one anonymous message added: 'It's very sad and upsetting how he's dead. From what I've heard he was very intelligent and would've been a great house prefect.'
At the end of the school day pupils gathered around the wall of the Victoria College chapel where the shrine to Morgan lay. Children brought flowers and could be seen crying.
One tribute said: 'Dear Morgan, I'm so sorry for your loss. We will remember you for your talents. Enjoy your afterlife.'
Another pupil wrote: 'I didn't really know Morgan but I'm still struggling to get my head round this situation. I'm so sorry for your massive loss.'
Victoria College (pictured), in Jersey's capital of St Helier, is a selective 4,800-a-year boys school which counts leading horse racing pundit John McCririck and British actor Kenneth More among its former pupils
The school counts horse racing pundit John McCririck (left), British actor Kenneth More (right) cricketers Cornelis Bodenstei and Stephen Newton and television presenter Olly Smithamong its former pupils
Neighbour Jenny Norris, 64, who has lived opposite Morgan and his family for 14 years, said today she hoped those responsible were 'brought to justice'.
The grandmother-of-four, a retired pharmacy worker living in Le Clos Sara, St Lawrence, said: 'Morgan was a quiet young man who was very focused academically.
'I read on Facebook that a Victoria College pupil had died on Saturday and I immediately thought of him.
'When it came out it was Morgan I was so sad. I thought what is the world coming to?
'For a young lad like that to die so suddenly, what must have been going on for that to happen to him?
'I remember seeing him walking up the road with his mum Kerry. She and her husband Phil were scout leaders.
Morgan was highly respected by both staff and his peers at the college, not least because of his academic ability, charismatic personality and strong sense of independence
Alun Watkins,  Victoria College head
'His family is lovely. He had two younger brothers and a younger sister but I don't know how old they are.
'Jersey is such a nice place, things like this just don't happen here. I haven't spoken to the family directly but I'll send them a card.
'My deepest condolences go out to them. It's just so awful. You never know what's round the corner.
'I hope whoever is responsible is brought to justice.'
Alun Watkins, headmaster at Victoria College, said Morgan was a 'genuinely honest and good natured young man'.
In a statement, he said: 'The staff and Governors of Victoria College would like to extend their heartfelt condolences and prayers to the parents, family and friends of Morgan Huelin who has left us under such tragic circumstances.
'Morgan was highly respected by both staff and his peers at the College, not least because of his academic ability, charismatic personality and strong sense of independence.
'Morgan had varied interests. He was an excellent guitarist and a fully supportive member of Dunlop House contributing to it in every way he could including shooting, rugby, football and hockey.
'The College will do all it can to offer support to those pupils, staff and families who have been affected by these heart-breaking events.
'We are all incredibly stunned that such a genuinely honest and good natured young man has been taken from us under these circumstances.'
He added that the school would be working closely with the police throughout the investigation.
Morgan's father Phil is a mechanic and his mother Kerry a housewife. He had a Saturday job in a pharmacy in St Helier. 
Paul Greenan (pictured left) killed nurse Tracy Burns (right) in 2005 on the Channel Island of Jersey
The incident is one of a only a couple of murders to occur on the island in the last decade.
Last year,Darren McCormack was convicted of brutally killing46-year-old Colin Chevalier at a property in St Helier.
McCormick, 36, was told  he must serve at least 25 years after he admitted inflicting 40 injuries on his victim during an axe attack.
The court heard McCormick went to Mr Chevalier's house to buy drugs but attacked his victim as he lay in bed, cutting his ear off. He was arrested the following day with the ear of his victim in his pocket.
In 2005, 19-year-old Paul Greenan was convicted of murdering nurse Tracy Burns on the island. The teenager attempted to rape her before beating her to death in the shocking random attack.
Although he admitted killing her, he denied murder but was found guilty by a jury and sentenced to life in prison.
And in 2011 a builder on the island knifed six people to death, including his wife and two young children.
Damian Rzeszowski snapped after his wife Izabela admitted having a two-month affair with another man.
He armed himself with kitchen knives and killed her, along with his daughter Kinga, five, and two-year-old son Kacper, at their home in St Helier on August 14 last year.
However, Rzeszowski was convicted of six counts of manslaughter but cleared of murder following a trial.
Anyone with information about the incident should contact Jersey Police on 612612.
MURDER SHOCKS RESIDENTS OF JERSEY WHICH HAS VERY LOW CRIME RATE
Police have previously described Jersey (pictured) as one of the safest places in the Western World
Jersey has a much lower crime rate compared to the rest of the UK.
Police have previously described the Channel Island as one of the safest places in the Western World with recorded crime around half what it is on the mainland.
This is compared to England which has an annual average of 64 crimes per 1,000 people.
In 2011 crime in Jersey reached a 10-year low and it has continued falling ever since.
Just under 1,600 crimes were recorded in the first five months of 2011, which was nearly a third less than in 2004.
And last year, police on the island revealed there had been an by 18 per cent reduction in crime, the third year in a row figures had gone down.
But the image of Jersey as an idyllic destination in the public eye took a severe knock in 2008 when it became the focus of one of the largest child abuse investigations ever conducted in the British Isles.
It was launched after more than 100 former residents of the now infamous Haut de la Garenne care home came forward to report historic abuse by members of staff.
Share or comment on this article
28
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date/>
        <title>
	X Factor's Steve Brookstein sparks fury with 'insensitive' 7/7 tweet
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152130/Former-X-Factor-winner-Steve-Brookstein-sparks-fury-using-7-7-anniversary-boast-number-one-album.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The failed singer took to Twitter this morning to remind followers that on this day ten years ago, he had been abroad and was unaware of the attacks which killed 52 people and injured 700.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The former reality TV star, who was dropped by his record label eight months after his debut single, went on to fume: 'Sorry I missed the memo where all tweets today were dedicated to the victims of 7/7'.
He then added: 'I knew the faux outrage it would cause. That's Twitter for you,' when accused of mincing his words.
Fury: Incensed Twitter users responded to his comments within minutes, describing him as 'disgusting'
He hurriedly posted a photograph of Tweets he had written in 2011 praising those who helped the injured and affected as 'heroes'.
Later the singer, who now performs in clubs and pubs, took to Facebook to write a more lengthy attempt to explain his comments.
'We all have an idea of what we were doing at an important event. 9/11 i was staying at a friend's house and I was in Dixons, Putney to watch the events unfold. 7/7 was a weird one,' he wrote in a bid to explain the original tweet.
Flop: Brookstein was dropped from his record label just eight months after winning The X Factor in 2004
'I had an awful June. I had been banned from interviews after doing a couple of interviews that the record label disapproved of and so Eileen and I went away for a few days.
'First Barcelona then straight onto New York. All I remember was I was at the airport when we heard the terrible news. For me, 10 years ago brings back bad memories of media manipulation, lies and public humiliation. I totally missed the news about 7/7.
'Today I used my 140 characters on twitter to say that. Anyone who has read my book knows I didn't celebrate my single or album success. So the comments that it was some kind of "humblebrag" are totally false - it was sarcasm.
'It comes as no surprise that the media that ignored my book and my revelations about tabloid media, Max Clifford, historic abuse and bullying have all jumped on this tweet.
'Obviously, my troubles don't compare to those who have lost a loved one in London on July 7th 2005, but this does't stop people with an agenda trying to twist it to continue the vilification that I've endured since falling out with Cowell in 2005.
'My book was pretty much ignored last year and still went to number one on kindle and yet the press pick up on a tweet. Work it out for yourself,' he wrote.
Despite his protestations, his comments were slammed as 'insensitive' by scores of followers.
'And you wonder why you are a flop? RIP 7/7 victims, they will remain in our memories,' said one while another outraged: 'Steve Brookstein disgusts me!!!'.
Brookstein did not respond to MailOnline's repeated requests for comment this afternoon.
Thousands of Twitter users earlier took to the micro-blogging site to share photographs of their commute to work having stepped off public transport one stop early to walk the remainder in memory of those killed ten years ago.
They accompanied their touching tributes with the hashtag #walktogether and shared images of commuters holding hands, their feet and floral tributes left across London.
Meanwhile members of the royal family and the Prime Minister came together for a moment's silence at St Paul's after laying wreaths in memory of the tragedy's victims. 
Excuse: Later the failed singer posted a lengthier message on his Facebook account to explain his comments

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Syed Choudhury who planned to join ISIS in Syria is jailed for more than 3 years
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152172/Teenager-planned-join-ISIS-jailed-three-years.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Syed Choudhury, a student in Cardiff whose family are from Bradford, trawled the internet for terrorist material and told friends he 'would do anything' to get to Syria and fight for the jihadi group
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
She said: 'He was heard to say that all gay people should be killed and they would go to hell.
'On another occasion, the group were asked to produce a poster about any topic they chose in order to demonstrate their IT skills
'Mr Choudhury produced a poster with an image of a Muslim demonstration on it with a banner reading 'Islam will dominate the world, freedom can go to hell' written on it.'
He went to a protest with a banner proclaiming: 'Islamic State will bring peace to the Middle East'
Choudhury left the course in May 2013 with some qualifications and it is believed he spent some time in Bangladesh.
He downloaded Islamic State propaganda images on his phone in February last year, and turned up to a Gaza demonstration in July 2014 carrying a banner proclaiming: 'Islamic State will bring peace to the Middle East'.
Choudhury then turned his attention to trying to fly to Syria, via Turkey, to join ISIS fighters.
Sharing his plans with a friend on Twitter, he complained: 'Now we got Islamic country but we can't go but if we get caught then your arrested for life.'
Choudhury planned to use funds from his part-time jobs at a takeaway to fund the trip.
He also told his friend: 'If you want something nice over there better than AK it's up to you [a reference to an AK47 rifle].'
The court heard he had no contacts in the area, which is controlled by the extremist jihadis (file photo)
He posted on social media: 'I would love to go there [Syria] I love it' and later confessed: 'My heart is pulling me to Syria'.
When arrested, Choudhury told police the only reason he hadn't made it to Syria was because he had not found anyone to go with him.
Abdul Iqbal QC, defending, told the court: 'Naivety, immaturity, and lack of insight are the hallmarks of his character.
'He had no direct link with anyone in the area of Turkey or Syria, the enquiries seemed to be on the internet 'do you know, could you help'.
'They were enquiries by an individual showing enthusiasm for traveling to Syria via Turkey, but he had got no further than making enquiries and had not himself made any independent enquiries beyond those made on the Internet.'
Share or comment on this article
9
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Thomas Cook agrees to a five-figure payout for holidaymakers over bed bug bites
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-3151980/Five-figure-payout-holidaymakers-Thomas-Cook-ravaged-BED-BUGS-Caribbean-resort-suffered-severe-rashes-blisters.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Jessica Mann and then-boyfriend Aaron Rigby were forced to seek medical attention for painful rashes and blisters that broke out all over their bodies while on holiday in the Dominican Republic.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
84 shares
And now I have no choice but to live with my condition which seems to have been made worse by the holiday. It is immensely frustrating.
It was supposed to be a memorable break but looking back now, I just wish we'd never gone.
Aaron, a 34-year-old insulation engineer, received medication from a doctor at the resort and both sought medical treatment at Stepping Hill Hospital in Stockport when they returned home.
They were prescribed painkillers, steroids and creams for the large, irritable red blisters which burst.
Aaron Rigby (whose leg is pictured) and Jessica Mann were badly bitten while on  holiday in 2011
Jessica suffers from a skin condition and said the bites made her symptoms even worse
Aaron, a 34-year-old insulation engineer, received medication from a doctor at the Caribbean resort
Jessica said it was supposed to be a memorable break now wishes they had never gone
The pair hired lawyers from the firm of Irwin Mitchell, which secured payouts from Thomas Cook despite the firm denying liability.
The holidaymakers requested that the settlement amount remain confidential.
A Thomas Cook spokesperson told MailOnline Travel the tour operator takes health and hygiene issues very seriously.
The spokesperson added: We were sorry to hear about Ms Mann and Mr Rigbys experience while on holiday at the Sirenis Cocotal in the Dominican Republic in 2011.
Thomas Cook closely audits all the properties to which it operates to ensure that only the highest health and hygiene standards are maintained. We can confirm that the Sirenis Cocotal no longer features in our holiday programme.
It is never our intention to disappoint our customers. We are happy to say this matter has now been resolved to Ms Mann and Mr Rigbys satisfaction, and that we have reached an agreement with their legal representatives.
Aaron and Jessicasought medical treatment at Stepping Hill Hospital in Stockport when they returned home
They were prescribed painkillers, steroids and creams for the large, irritable red blisters which burst
Jessica said the couple's room was infested with bugs and the fridge and lights were not working properly
The pair stuffed newspapers under the door to prevent insects from crawling into their hotel room
Jessica said nothing can change what happened and she just wants to put the ordeal behind her and move on.
It was not just the rash that spoiled the holiday, there were lots of other things wrong with the hotel.
There were lots of insects in our hotel room and the fridge and lights in our first hotel room were not working properly.
When Aaron and I complained to both the Thomas Cook representative and the staff at the hotel they did not seem to take our complaints very seriously and at times it felt like I was spending more time complaining than I was enjoying the holiday.
Thomas Cook said theSirenis Cocotal Beach Resort no longer features in its holiday programme
Jessica said a Thomas Cook representative and hotel staff did not seem to take her complaints seriously
Jessica said the holiday turned out to be a 'very frightening experience' and she couldn't wait to go home
Clare Pearson, from Irwin Mitchell, said: This is a terrible situation in which our clients have developed extremely uncomfortable and embarrassing conditions during what was meant to be a relaxing holiday.
Sadly such cases are not uncommon and while nothing can be done to reverse the problems Jessica and Aaron have faced.
We hope that the settlements will go some way towards helping them to take steps to put these issues behind them.
Their story is an important reminder that everything possible should be done to ensure the safety of holidaymakers always comes first.
DON'T LET THE BED BUGS BITE
Bed bugs surface at night and feast on human blood
High on the list of holidaymakers biggest fears, bed bugs feast on the blood of humans and hide in cracks and crevices in and around beds.
They surface at night and bite exposed skin, leaving itchy red bumps that appear within 30 minutes and can last for days, or fluid-filled blisters.
Bed bugs are oval-shaped, flat and visible to the naked eye, with their colour varying between dark yellow, red or brown.
Bites usually occur to the face, neck, hands or arms, are often mistaken for mosquito bites and typically occur in straight lines.
Many people dont suffer a reaction or only have the odd spot, but those who develop itchy bumps should see their GP for treatment.
Other signs that bed bug are present include black spots on a mattress, which could be the bugs dried faeces, blood spots from a bug that has been squashed in the night, and mottled shells that the insects may have shed.
An infestation may bring with it an unpleasant, musty scent that is produced by adult bed bugs.
The good news, according to health experts, is bed bugs arent dangerous and dont transmit any human diseases.
But people should call their local council or a professional pest control firm to prevent the spread of an infestation, as the tiny insects can spread easily from room to room or building to building by crawling or being transported in luggage, clothing, furniture or bedding.
That makes it easier for them to hitch a ride into holidaymakers' homes.
Females lay up to 300 eggs over their lifetime, and they hatch about 10 days later to form tiny straw-coloured insects which grow into adults within six to eight weeks.
As the insects are not attracted to dirt, a bed bug infestation isnt a sign of an unclean home. They are more common in hotels or hostels.
Source: NHS
Share or comment on this article
84
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date/>
        <title>
	SAS paratrooper Norman Poole has died aged 95
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152073/Ex-SAS-paratrooper-British-soldier-set-foot-occupied-France-D-Day-died-aged-95.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	SAS paratrooper Lieutenant Norman Poole was one of a six-man team who landed on the Cherbourg peninsula in Normandy on the night of June 5-6, 1944.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Lieutenant Norman Harry Poole the first British soldier to set foot in France on D-Day, aged 95
The first British soldier to land in occupied France during the D-Day operation has died, aged 95.
SAS paratrooper Lieutenant Norman Poolewas one of a six-man team who landed on the Cherbourg peninsula in Normandy on the night of June 5-6, 1944, in an operation codenamed Titanic IV.
The soldier, who leapt from a plane with a carrier pigeon strapped to his chest, landed with 200 dummy parachutists and were tasked with the job of distracting German troops with amplifiers playing fake combat noises.
His pigeon was the only one that got home with a vital message for military chiefs - but he never told anyone what that message was and has now gone to his grave with the secret.
By the end of June 6 over 155,000 Allied troops had established bases along the Normandy coast and paved the way to eventual victory over Hitler's Germany.
Lt Poole and his team were separated from the other troops and they spent six weeks behind enemy lines before being captured by German troops.
The group were eventually liberated by the Americans and Norman was awarded the Military Cross for his bravery.
But Lt Poole, who after the war became a banker for Natwest, was reluctant to talk about his place in the historic invasion, even with his family.
He lived in Portishead, Somerset, with his wife Elisabeth and retired in 1980.Norman died in June - four years after Elisabeth.
The couple had two daughters, Elisabeth and Alison, and four grandchildren and five great grandchildren.
He lived in Portishead, Somerset, with his wife Elisabeth (both pictured) and retired in 1980. Norman died in June - four years after Elisabeth
Daughter Alison Dale, a former dental nurse of Studley, Warwickshire, said: 'On the day of the Normandy landings, he had a pigeon strapped to him - and his was the only pigeon that got home with a message for the SAS.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Marks and Spencer's clothes sales fall despite high-profile ad campaigns
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/news/article-3151850/M-S-clothes-sales-fall-despite-high-profile-ad-campaigns-food-sustains-revenues.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The retailer said its general merchandise - which is mostly clothes - sales fell 0.4 per cent in the three months to June, although its better than last year when notched up a 1.5 per cent decline.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
Some have questioned whether M&amp;S can ever get its clothes sales back on track.
Richard Hunter, at Hargreaves Lansdown, said: 'The elephant in the changing room remains, in the form of General Merchandise. Whether M&amp;S can ever return to former glories by enticing clothes shoppers back to its stores is arguably its largest challenge, even though the more recent experience implies at least a stabilisation of previously dropping numbers.'
Grilling: Marks &amp; Spencer boss Marc Bolland faces a tough time at Wembley Stadium today
As ever Marks &amp; Spencer food arm has proved its strongest asset.
The group's food like-for-like sales lifted 0.3 per cent during the period.
The retailer, which launched 700 new food lines during the period, continues to see its high-end items outperform the grocery market, which is locked in a supermarket price war.
Yesterday Marks &amp; Spencer announced that it will start rolling out free in-store collection at more than 100 of its Simply Food outlets.
The first new collection points will include Simply Food stores at King's Cross, Manchester Piccadilly and Cardiff Central railway stations.
The move sees Marks &amp; Spencer outfox rival John Lewis, which said it would start charging customers 2 to collect online orders in store, citing 'unsustainable' and 'bonkers' web-based business models.
It also comes after Marks &amp; Spencer reported a boost to online, with sales via the website up 38.7 per cent, after the 131-year old retailer invested and overhauled the site.
Chief executive, Marc Bolland, said: 'We continue to make progress against our key priorities. Our food business did very well in a difficult market. In general merchandise, sales were broadly level on last year and we are on track to deliver the planned increase in gross margin.'
The group also said it will launch a 150million share buyback programme for investors, which is due to begin on July 8.
Shareholders have gathered at the group's annual meeting at Wembley Stadium in London today.
Shares in Marks &amp; Spencer were up 1 per cent, or 4.0p, at 551.0p ahead of the meeting.
In May, the firm reported underlying profits for the year to March 28 rose 6.1 per cent to 661.2million, easing some of the intense pressure Bolland has been under in recent years.
Bolland took over at M&amp;S in 2010 and during his tenure he has seen rival Next overtake his business.
Share or comment on this article
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Pontypridd teenager paralysed after '3 youths threw stones at him on bridge' 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152038/Teenager-paralysed-three-youths-threw-stones-causing-fall-50ft-bridge-rocks.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Joshua Davies, pictured, who has Asperger's syndrome, was trying to escape the boys when he tripped and fell from the crossing in Pontypridd, South Wales, on to a rocks in the River Taff.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Ms Wilks said: 'He was side-stepping along the girder when one of the stones hit the shoulder strap of his rucksack. He fell on to the rocks below, where he sustained very serious injuries.'
The defendants checked if Mr Davies was okay before fleeing the scene, it was said.
The court heard police officers arrested a 15-year-old  later that afternoon.
The court heard Mr Davies (pictured in hospital) and his friend began to climb along the metal girders to avoid the stones, but the defendants crossed to the other side of the river and continued pelting them with rocks
Mr Davies fell off  the bridge (pictured above) and plummeted towards the rocky riverbed, the court heard
In an interview, he said he and his friends were throwing stones in an attempt to 'startle' the boys and claimed Mr Davies did not fall until several minutes after they had stopped throwing stones.
He admitted throwing five or six stones, but said he was not aiming at Joshua.
Two other teenagers, aged 16 and 18, were arrested later that evening.
The 16-year-old denied throwing any stones and said he did not know how Joshua had fallen. He claimed he had left the scene because he was 'shocked' after Joshua said he could not feel his legs.
Kurtis Lawrence admitted throwing two or three stones, but claimed he was aiming them at the wall. He reported hearing 'screaming and shouting' as he fell.
Mr Davies with his stepfather Michael, brother Michael, sisters Rachel and Alana-May and mother Cheryl
Mr Davies (pictured left aged 8 and right aged 13) was left wheelchair-bound after the incident last summer
Joshua, pictured in hospital with his parents, suffered injuries to his spine and fractures to his wrist and arm
The court heard Joshua was taken to the University Hospital of Wales.
Ms Wilks said: 'It is fair to say he suffered catastrophic injuries.'
She told the jury he suffered trauma to his spine and fractures to his wrist and arm. 'Despite months of rehabilitation, he remains paralysed in a wheelchair,' she added.
Ms Wilks said: 'It is the prosecution case that all three pursued him and all three deliberately threw stones at him. They intended to hit him with the stones.
'It would have been obvious to them that there was a very real risk he would fall and that would result in serious injury.'
The trial continues.
Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Distraction burglars jailed, they were so ugly that they were identified with ease
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152115/Distraction-burglars-ugly-identified-pensioners-dementia-jailed.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Police said Mark Smith, 42, and Rachel Cooper, 38, of Loughton, Essex, were so hard on the eye that victims with severe memory impairments were able to pick them out of an ID parade.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
'That's one of the reasons we were able to pick them up.
'The elderly victims - even though some had Alzheimer's - were able to describe them as their physical appearance, looking as they do, made them stick in the minds of their victims.
'One recognised Smith in an ID parade - she was in her 90s and managed to pick him out because of his distinctive looks.'
The pair, of Loughton, Essex, tricked their way into the homes of victims aged 70-94 by telling them they needed money to take a sick relative to hospital.
Sentenced: The pair were jailed at Snaresbrook Crown Court (pictured), Smith for eight years and Cooper for two years and nine months, after stealing hundreds of thousands of pounds from elderly victims
They targeted a 94-year-old woman with Alzheimer's on three occasions, stealing 5,000 cash and 2,000 jewellery from her home in Loughton.
Smith and Cooper were jailed for a total of 13 offences across Essex, London and Kent between July and November 2014.
Smith was arrested in September that year after attempting the scam on a man in Brentwood, Essex, who called officers and positively identified him.
They weren't the best looking, that's putting it mildly
Detective Sergeant Brett Hagen
Cooper was arrested in November 2014 after she was caught using a 91-year-old man's bank card in the moments after she stole it, having pushed him to the ground during a burglary in Woodford Green, north east London.
Det Sgt Hagenadded: 'Distraction burglary is a disgraceful crime and Smith and Cooper represent every elderly person's worst nightmare.
'They conned their way into addresses with brazen and concocted stories, specifically targeting vulnerable victims.
'We hope to see more come forward. There are probably tens if not hundreds more that have fallen foul to these two.'
Smith and Cooper were both found guilty of the distraction burglaries at Snaresbrook Crown Court.
Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date/>
        <title>
	18th century Norfolk mansion complete with its own cave goes on sale for £2m
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152012/Sprawling-18th-century-mansion-complete-cave-Barclay-family-lived-pet-LIONS-Mitzi-Fritzi-goes-sale-2m.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Colney Hall, a grade II listed seven bedroom property in Norwich, Norfolk, which was bought by Hugh Gurney Barclay in the late 19th century, has been put on the market for £2million.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Sprawling 18th century mansion complete with its own cave and where the Barclay family once lived with their pet LIONS Mitzi and Fritzi goes on sale for 2m
Colney Hall bought by Hugh Gurney Barclay in the late 19th century and he lived their with his children and pet lions
Grade II listed mansion boasts seven bedrooms, six bathrooms, receptions rooms and secret underground passage
Hall, which was built in Norfolk countryside between 1767 and 1781, now been put on the market for nearly 2million
Published: 10:29 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 12:47 GMT, 7 July 2015
20 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Tony Blair warns terrorism threat has ‘intensified’ since 7/7 London bombings
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152062/Blair-warns-terror-threat-intensified-10-years-7-7-urges-Western-leaders-combat-fanatics-ground.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Mr Blair, who was PM when four British bombers blew themselves up killing 52 people in 2005, warned today that the threat posed by Islamist fanatics has reached 'the edges of Europe'.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
143 shares
Mr Blair warned that if the international community was not prepared to tackle extremists groups such as Islamic State head on they would continue to grow.
'When you fight these people it's going to be tough because they're prepared to kill without mercy and die without regret and that makes them an enemy that may not have the same conventional military capability but has certainly got the determination to fight.'
Pressed over whether the response should involve British boots on the ground, he said: 'This is maybe a discussion for another day.'
Tony Blair talks about the 7/7 attacks and terrorist activity
David Cameron and Boris Johnson attend a wreath laying ceremony in Hyde Park,  to mark the 10 Year anniversary of the London 7/7 Bombings
The bombings of three Tube trains and a bus - carried out by four bombers linked to al-Qaeda and carrying rucksacks of explosives - was the worst single terrorist atrocity on British soil
Londoners pause for minute's silence to commemorate 7/7 victims
The former PM rejected claims the attacks had been prompted by the wars in Iraq or Afghanistan - which had themselves between a response to the September 11 terror attacks.
He said: 'I think it's very important to understand that the probable leader of the 7/7 attacks was someone who was first in a training camp in the middle of 2001, before 9/11, never mind before the invasion of Afghanistan or the invasion of Iraq and the difficulty is that there will always be reason and excuses that people use for terrorism.
'You have countries like France today that's the subject of terrorism or Norway or Belgium or Tunisia or Kuwait or countries across Africa, none of whom had anything to do with British or American foreign policy and yet whose citizens come under this type of violent and indiscriminate killing so I think in the end, the responsibility has got to lie with the people who carry this out and those who encourage them.'
An hour after the tube bombings, a fourth device was set off on a double-decker bus in Tavistock Square, killing 13 people
Earlier, PM David Cameron and London Mayor Boris Johnson were among those who laid wreaths in Hyde Park.
The bombings of three Tube trains and a bus - carried out by four bombers linked to al-Qaeda and carrying rucksacks of explosives - was the worst single terrorist atrocity on British soil.
At just after 8.50am on July 7, 2005, three explosions took place on the Underground - 26 people died at Russell Square, six at Edgware Road and seven at Aldgate.
Almost an hour later, a fourth device was set off on a double-decker bus in Tavistock Square, killing 13 people.
The bombings were carried out by Mohammad Sidique Khan, 30, Shehzad Tanweer, 22, Hasib Hussain, 18, and Germaine Lindsay, 19. The group had links to al-Qaeda in Pakistan and Afghanistan.
Mr Blair's intervention comes after the head of MI5 Andrew Parker warned that Britain faced a 'serious societal' threat from a tiny minority of Muslims with a 'twisted' belief their own country is the enemy.
Mr Parker describes 7/7 as the moment the UK fully woke up to the threat of Al Qaeda and other Islamists.
He says a 'step change' in counter-terrorism defences, as a result of the London bombings, allowed the Security Service to foil more plots and save thousands of lives.
But, in an article for MI5's website, Mr Parker says 'appalling acts' continue to be attempted by individuals who have 'grown up here but decided for whatever twisted reasons to identify their own country as the enemy'.
He adds: 'They are a tiny fraction of the population. But the continuing fact that some people born in the UK, with all the opportunities and freedoms that modern Britain offers, can nonetheless make those sorts of warped choices presents a serious societal and security challenge.'
It follows warnings by David Cameron that some Muslim communities are 'quietly condoning' the extremist ideology that can lead to terrorism.
The Prime Minister and other dignitaries will today pay tribute to victims of the bombers who set off homemade devices on three Tube trains and a bus a decade ago, killing 52 and injuring hundreds.
Police and security officials are on high alert, with a terrorist outrage officially rated highly likely.
Share or comment on this article
143
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Mother with terminal cervical cancer urges women to have smear tests
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3150932/Mother-three-diagnosed-terminal-cancer-never-having-smear-test-urges-women-routine-scan.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Tracy McPhee-Travers, 36, from Barnsley, South Yorkshire, is appealing to all women to make sure they have their smear tests after ignoring hers, and discovering that she has terminal cervical cancer.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
A terminally ill mother is appealing to all women to make sure they have their smear tests after she ignored hers and has been left fighting for her life.
Tracy McPhee-Travers, 36, from Barnsley, South Yorkshire, is now paying the biggest price for not having the routine scans after she was told her cervical cancer was terminal.
The mother-of-three is now in a desperate race against time to raise 50,000 for pioneering treatment in a bid to see her three daughters grow up.
Race against time: Tracy, second from left, with her children, Angelena (right), 10, Tracy, 13 (left), and 15-year-old Jasmine (second from right), is setting up a Go Fund Me page to raise money for cancer treatment
The mother-of-three was diagnosed with cervical cancer in 2013 - after never before having a smear test
Without the money, Tracy, who has set up a Go Fund Me page to raise the cash, fears she only has months to live.
She said: 'I have paid the biggest price for my own ignorance and stupidity.
'I plead with every woman out there not to do what I have done. Have your smear tests. It really could save your life.
'I'm now fighting to stay alive to see my children grow up which could have been so easily prevented if only I'd had the tests like I should have done.'
Tracy, who is a single mother to Angelena, 10, Tracy, 13, and 15-year-old Jasmine,was first diagnosed with cervical cancer in January last year, after a five-month battle with her GP to get referred.
She said: 'From August 2013, I was in constant pain, crippled by severe abdominal cramps and loss of blood.
'I pleaded with my GP for help, but I was told at least 10 times that what I was experiencing wasn't abnormal and lots of women have the same problems.'
Tracy is looking to raise a total of 50,000 and has so far managed to reach 6,174 on her Go Fund Me page
Tracy, pictured above left and right with her three children, says she wants to raise the money so she can have treatment in New York so that her 'girls can grow up with a mother'
She says she accepts she had never been for a smear test, which  for women aged 25 and over are available on the NHS and should be undertaken every three years.
Tracy said: 'Life was just very busy bringing up my three girls and it constantly slipped my mind. There was always something else to do.'
She added: 'But when I did ask for help, my pleas fell on deaf ears for five months, despite the agony I was in and the fact that I had lost over two stone in weight.
'Some days I literally couldn't lift myself out of bed. My daughters had to help me get up and dressed as I was so weak and in so much pain.'
I was absolutely devastated. I felt as though my world was crashing in around me. All I could think about was my three daughters and how I had to fight this awful disease for their sakes
Tracy claims her doctor told her she needed a smear test but couldn't have one until the bleeding stopped.
But in December 2013, after nearly collapsing in the surgery, she was finally referred to Barnsley Hospital for scans and a colposcopy, a procedure to find out whether a woman's cervix contains any abnormal cells.
Within two weeks, Tracy was called back for the results and was told she had a Grade 4 three centimetre tumour within her womb that had spread a further inch outside her womb lining.
The cancer had also been detected in Tracy's lymph nodes.
Tracy said: 'I was absolutely devastated. I felt as though my world was crashing in around me. All I could think about was my three daughters and how I had to fight this awful disease for their sakes.'
Tracy was referred to Weston Park Hospital, in Sheffield, where she immediately began a course of chemotherapy, radiotherapy and finally brachytherapy.
She said: 'After the treatment finished, I started to feel a lot better. I got my appetite back and began putting on weight.
'I was still tired but thought that was just a side effect of the treatment.'
Tracy, pictured with her children, said: 'All I want is to make sure I'm there for my girls until they are old enough to look after themselves and can live without me'
Tracy's daughtersAngelena and Tracy helping their mother's fundraising campaign
But in January this year, Tracy was dealt the devastating blow that the cancer had spread to her lungs.
She was offered another course of chemotherapy, but warned the side effects would leave her with no quality of life, and was advised to go home and spend what time she had left with her daughters.
Tracy, who easily becomes breathless and is on tablets to control the pain she suffers, said: 'I was absolutely stunned. I couldn't believe what I was hearing.
'I asked how long I had left and was told six months. That means I'm already on borrowed time. Really I shouldn't be here now.
'But I couldn't just give in and leave my daughters without a mother. I'd read about immunotherapy and contacted a clinic in New York that specialises in the treatment.'
Last week, Tracy was accepted on the trial but now must raise the money to pay for it.
Friends and family of the mother have now launched an appeal to help her fulfill Tracy's sole wish of seeing her daughters become adults.
Tracy, pictured with her daughter Angelena, said: 'Im overwhelmed by everyone's support. Knowing they are trying to help me stay alive, really does keep me going'
Tracy has launched a Go Fund Me page to raise 50,000 for treatment in New York that costs 1,590 a session
She explained: 'All I want is to make sure I'm there for my girls until they are old enough to look after themselves and can live without me.
'But without treatment, I won't survive. The cancer will kill me and my girls will grow up without a mother.
'It's every mother's worst nightmare and something I really can't contemplate.'
Tracy is now in a desperate bid against time to start the treatment in New York that could save her life. She has been accepted on a US-based PDL1 immunotherapy treatment plan to start later this month.
The treatment works by helping a person's body fight cancerous cells by recognising these cells as imposters. However it will cost 1,590 per session and Tracy may need at least seven months' worth of treatment.
She and her daughters, along with Tracy's mother, will have to stay in New York until the treatment is finished, needing money for the medical costs, accommodation and living expenses.
Tracy said: 'A conservative estimate of how much I will need is 50,000 but I know that could escalate depending on how many sessions I need. I'm still waiting for confirmation from the doctors in New York.'
Her anxious family and friends have launched an appeal and made a heartfelt plea for people to help pay for the costly treatment. Along with family members savings, they have raised 20,000, but still have a very long way to go.
An emotional Tracy, who says she is in constant excruciating pain, said she is desperate to live if only for her daughter's sakes.
She said: 'Im overwhelmed by everyone's support. Knowing they are trying to help me stay alive, really does keep me going.
'Everyone is doing so much - I'm completely humbled. I can't thank them enough.
'I have to fight this awful disease for my girls. I need to be here when they come home from school, or need a hug after their first tiff with a boyfriend. I want to see them get married and have families of their own.
'So I will do everything I can to fight this horrible condition.'
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
10
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date/>
        <title>
	NHS cancer patient has his mouth and tongue rebuilt using tissue from his ARM
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3151968/Cancer-patient-mouth-tongue-rebuilt-using-tissue-ARM-tumour-size-plum-removed-throat.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	David Barwell, of Nottingham, was diagnosed with T4 mouth cancer in March, after losing four stone in less than three months. Doctors now hope he will be able to eat, drink and talk again.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Cancer patient has his mouth and tongue rebuilt using tissue from his ARM... after a tumour the size of a plum is removed from his throat
David Barwell began feeling unwell in October but doctors in Poland, where he was living at the time, misdiagnosed his mouth cancer as an infection
Was diagnosed with T4 mouth cancer - the latest stage where the disease had spread to the nearby muscle and skin, making it hard to treat
He travelled back to the UK by campervan for NHS treatment
Underwent a 15-hour operation where surgeons removed the tumour and rebuilt his mouth, allowing him to eat drink and hopefully speak again
Published: 10:20 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 12:33 GMT, 7 July 2015
16 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Londoners #walktogether in memory of 7/7 victims 10 years on from terror attack
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151970/Londoners-walktogether-memory-7-7-victims-Thousands-London-commuters-Tube-early-walk-final-stop-10-years-terror-attacks-killed-52.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	In memory of those killed in the bombings a decade ago, commuters across London today stepped off the train, tube and bus one stop early to walk the remainder of their journey.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
#walktogether: Thousands of defiant London commuters get off the Tube early and walk their final stop in memory of the 52 people who died in 7/7 terror attacks 10 years ago today
Commuters shared their poignant tributes to the victims of the 7/7 bombings online as they walked to work today
Scores held up signs with the words #walktogether while others held hands and posted photographs of their feet
David Cameron and Boris Johnson were joined by politicians at a Hyde Park Memorial wreath-laying ceremony
It is ten years to the day that 52 people were killed and 700 injured in a series of blasts detonated across London 
Published: 10:00 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 12:32 GMT, 7 July 2015
1.6k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Egypt's 'ugly' Queen Nefertiti statue causes outrage across the country 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152001/Beauty-beast-Ugly-statue-Egypt-s-famously-stunning-Queen-Nefertiti-causes-outrage-country.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The statue, which was installed at the entrance to the city of Samalout, was intended to be replica of the famously beautiful 3,300-year old  bust unearthed in 1912.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Another Twitter user wrote: 'I guess this is what she looked like four days after she died.'
One launched a direct attack on the sculptors, saying: 'If you don't know how to make statues, don't go and do something so unfair to the beautiful Nefertiti.'
In a number of tweets, the bust was compared to the statue of Frankenstein in an old Egyptian film, it was reported by BBC Trending .
The statue, which was installed at the entrance to the city of Samalout, was intended to be a replica of the famously beautiful3,300-year old  bust unearthed in Ammarna in 1912.
Ugly: In a number of tweets, the bust was compared to the statue of Frankenstein in an old Egyptian film
But the groundswell of criticism has been so fervent officials have now removed the statue after just a few days, it was reported by Ahram .
The head of Samalout city, Gamal Kanaway, said the bust would be replaced with a statue of a peace dove.
Queen Nefertiti ruled alongside her husband, Pharaoh Akhenaten during the 14th Century BC.
Beauty is even written into her name, which translates as 'the beautiful one has come'.
The original bust is currently housed in Berlin's Neuse Museum.
Statue was meant to be a replica of the 3,300-year-old bust
QUEEN NEFERTITI REVERED FOR HER BEAUTY... BUT DID SHE HAVE 'BOTOX'?
The bust of Nefertiti, who died around 1330 BC aged between 29 and 38, is one of the most widely recognised Ancient Egyptian artefacts after the mask of the king Tutankhamen who may have been her son.
It was found in Egypt in 1912 at Tell el-Amarna, the short-lived capital of Nefertiti's husband, the Pharaoh Akhenaten. It is now housed in Berlin's Altes Museum.
Ever since its first public exhibition in 1923, the precision of the 3,300-year-old sculpture's symmetrical lines and its finely wrought features have drawn thousands of admirers from around the globe.
But in 2010, researchers claimed that a delicately carved face in the limestone core of the famous bust suggested the royal sculptor at the time may have smoothed creases around the mouth and fixed a bumpy nose to depict the 'Beauty of the Nile' in a better light.
The first suggestion that she may have had the ancient equivalent of botox and a nose job came a year earlier when German scientists analysed the limestone carving with CT scans.
Their analysis showed that compared to the outer stucco face, the inner face had less prominent cheekbones, a slight bump on the ridge of the nose, creases around the corner of mouth and cheeks, and less depth at the corners of the eyelids.
Egyptian officials have named the Nefertiti bust and the Rosetta Stone at the British Museum in London among five precious artefacts held abroad which they want to bring home, with mediation from the U.N. cultural agency UNESCO.
Read more:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Queen's hairdresser says style that ends near jawline acts as a facelift 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151751/Top-anti-ageing-tip-hairstyle-short-Queen-s-hairdresser-says-style-ends-near-jawline-acts-facelift.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	According to Her Majesty’s hairdresser, Denise McAdam, opting for a hair style that ends near the jawline acts as a facelift, provides bounce to ageing locks and can give a woman a sexy air.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Miss McAdam, 56, a judge on BBC 2 show Hair which begins July 13 and is described as the hairdressing equivalent of The Great British Bake Off, has cut the hair of the royal family for more than three decades.
She became well-known in 1986 when she styled the Duchess of Yorks hair for her wedding to the Duke of York. In 2010, she received the Royal Victorian Medal for hairdressing services to the royal family.
As she handed her the award - which is a personal gift from the Queen - Her Majesty said to Denise, Youve been with us a long time. You have done my sons and my grandchildren too. She also received a handwritten note of thanks from every member of the royal family - including Princess Anne.
Asked to reveal the biggest mistakes women make with their hair, Miss McAdam said it was opting for a massive restyle or change of colour a week before their wedding: Big mistake, thats definitely not a good time to do it. You would be amazed how many women do it. I also think another big mistake is not understanding how to talk to your hairdresser or the hairdresser not listening to you.
Denise McAdam is a judge on BBC 2 show Hair
Ms McAndrew has been the Queen's hairdresser for several years and has been rewarded for her service
Pop star Taylor Swift may be the woman of the moment, but Miss McAdam advised against copying her bob haircut.
She said: Pop stars are quite influential as are presenters at the moment. You have to work with your hairdresser, you cant just look at these girls and think you can have that hairstyle because each head of hair is different. You have to work the look to suit you, a new angle on that look. A pair of trousers may be fashionable but not everyone suits those trousers so you got for a different angle on it.
Share or comment on this article
72
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Tory Anna Soubry ridicules critics of Sunday Trading law plans
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151609/Stay-open-hours-Chancellor-s-Sunday-trading-revolution-set-towns-right-scrap-outdated-restrictions.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Small business minister Anna Soubry said plans to give elected mayors and councils the power to allow supermarkets to open for more than six hours on a Sunday were not a threat to family life.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
337 shares
John Hannett, general secretary of shopworkers' union Usdaw, added: 'This Act is a great British compromise, which has worked well for over 20 years and gives everyone a little bit of what they want.
'Retailers can trade, customers can shop, staff can work, whilst Sunday remains a special day, different to other days, and shopworkers can spend some time with their family.'
He added: 'We will vigorously campaign against such a proposal and we would be looking for the Government to learn from their two consultations and failed trial period (during the London Olympics) by leaving alone the existing Sunday trading arrangements agreed by the main stakeholders in the retail industry.'
But TUC general secretary Frances O'Grady said lifting the restrictions on Sunday opening would 'take precious family time away from shop workers'
Frontrunner for the Labour leadership Andy Burnham today promised to fight the proposals 'all the way'
SUNDAY OPENING HOURS: END OF A 'GREAT BRITISH COMPROMISE'?
At the moment, large stores can only open for six hours between 10am and 6pm on Sundays, while shops with a floor area of less than 3,000 square feet can open all day.
Attempts to remove restrictions on Sunday trading led to bitter disputes in the Eighties and were abandoned after the Shops Bill was defeated in the Commons in 1986.
A compromise deal was finally agreed in 1994.
The rules were lifted for eight weeks during the Olympics and Paralympics in 2012, resulting in a significant surge in sales.
But when the Keep Sunday Special group wrote to Mr Cameron before the election asking him to rule out a change in the law, his office said he believed the existing system provided a reasonable balance.
However Adrian Pepper of the Open Sundays campaign group said relaxing Sunday trading laws made sense for modern-day families.
'It is now the norm for adults in most families to be in full time work so the only time they can shop is at the weekend. Restricting Sunday opening makes no sense,' he said.
'The current Sunday trading laws do not preserve any valuable cultural aspects of our way of life.
'They just make life more inconvenient. If you want to go out early on a Sunday morning looking for a wide range of fresh produce to cook for a family Sunday lunch, you cannot.
'If you want to go to church on a Sunday morning, there is even less time to get the shopping done.'
The government claims there is a 'growing appetite' for Sunday trading in high streets and retail parks, and a trial of longer hours during the London Olympics had proved a success.
The Treasury pointed to research by the New West End Company which found two extra hours in the capital alone would create nearly 3,000 jobs and generate over 200 million a year in additional sales.
Freed from the constraints of five years of coalition with the Liberal Democrats, Mr Osborne will use his second Budget of the year to show where he has found 12 billion of welfare savings promised in the Conservative manifesto.
He told MPs that with global economies braced for the impact of the Greek debt crisis, he would use the set-piece to show how the Government intends to 'redouble our own efforts to put our house in order' with continued austerity measures.
Significant savings are expected to the system of tax credits brought in under the previous Labour government to top up the incomes of low-paid working families.
Mr Osborne will use his second Budget of the year tomorrow to show where he has found 12 billion of welfare savings promised in the Conservative manifesto
Mr Osborne is also going further than previously planned in cutting the benefits cap - currently set at 26,000-a-year - not just to 23,000 in London but to a still lower threshold in other parts of the country.
Savings of 250 million will be achieved by forcing 340,000 local authority and housing association tenants on incomes of 40,000 or more in London and 30,000 in the rest of England to pay a market, or near market, rent from 2017/18.
The 600 million-plus annual cost of providing free television licences to the over 75s is also being passed to the BBC from 2018/19 - with the broadcaster deciding whether the policy should continue after 2020.
We need a better economic plan than asking people to spend another day of the week putting debt on their credit cards
TUC chief Frances O'Grady
It may in return be able to extend the licence fee to cover people watching via the online iPlayer and the licence fee is expected to rise in line with the consumer price index (CPI) measure of inflation.
The Budget is also set to include an end to inheritance tax on family homes worth up to 1 million - at an estimated 1 billion cost to the Exchequer - a key plank of the Conservatives' general election manifesto.
But Mr Osborne appears set to disappoint Tories calling for a cut in the top rate of income tax from 45p to 40p - insisting his priority is raising the tax free allowance to 12,500 and increasing the threshold for the higher rate to 50,000.
The Chancellor is reported to have significant 'wiggle room' because of tax revenues around 15 billion higher than projected at the March budget.
Stockbrokers Hargreaves Lansdown said it also expected the Treasury to receive an additional 700 million this year - twice official expectations - in tax thanks to new pension freedoms.
Millions of over 55-year-olds have since April been able to cash in their pension pots rather than being forced to buy an annuity and the firm said experience from the early months suggested Mr Osborne was set for a big windfall.
Sunday trading has long been a thorny issue, with pressure building to relax the 1994 Sunday Trading Act which allowed smaller shops to open all day but restricted those over 280 sq m / 3,000 sq ft to six hours between 10am and 6pm.
A review by the then Labour government in 2006 resulted in no change amid protests.
But the Treasury said Britain was out of step with international competitors - with Paris having recently relaxed its rules and New York imposing no controls.

Share or comment on this article
337
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Asthma and depression can be cured by giggling claims Lynette Webbe
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3152104/Doctors-refer-patients-LAUGHTER-classes-says-mother-claims-giggling-cured-asthma-depression.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Lynette Webbe, 59, from Pill in Wales, claims laughter therapy classes, which involve giggling, storytelling and dancing  have cured her respiratory problems as well as her depression.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Doctors should refer patients to LAUGHTER classes, says mother who claims giggling has cured her asthma and depression
Lynette Webbe, 59, suffered asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease for 6 years as she smoked since the age of 13
Also suffered depression since she was a teenager after losing her parents, and began laughter classes as a natural treatment
Enjoyed the laughter therapy so much she trained to hold her own classes
After a year she claims her doctors said her respiratory problems are much better, and wants other people to be referred for laughter therapy
Published: 12:04 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 12:21 GMT, 7 July 2015
7 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date/>
        <title>
	New London restaurant After School Club serves meals modelled on canteen dinners
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/food/article-3151944/Latest-London-restaurant-serves-meals-modelled-school-dinners.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The After School Club is London's latest restaurant, housed in The Round Chapel, Old School Rooms in, Hackney, London. For £55 diners can tuck into shepherd's pie and spaghetti.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The themed menu has been created by chef Ellen who will serve her versions of shepherd's pie and alphabetti spaghetti.
There will also be walnut and pomegranate braised lamb served alongside wilted spinach and a pine nut and anchovy dressing on offer.
To finish diners can tuck into cardamom and sour cherry spotted dick with pistachio custard and charred peaches.
Back to school!: Alice and Ellen run pop-up collective Art of Dining
SAMPLE MENU 
Alphabet spaghetti served with a summer squash and parmesan broth with sage and walnut pesto.
Shepherds pie course of walnut and pomegranate braised lamb version served alongside wilted spinach and a pine nut and anchovy dressing.
Cardamom and sour cherry spotted dick with pistachio custard and charred peaches.
The ticket price for the event will also include a cocktail workshop and an art class.
The dining room, designed by Alice, will be made to look like a school hall, complete with blackboards on the walls, tables you can draw on and globes
Additionally all diners will receive a pencil case containing their cutlery, a school tie and a cocktail when they arrive.
According to the organisers, prizes, gold stars and punishments will be doled out throughout the evening by a 'particularly strict headmistress' and prefects.
The event will take place in The Round Chapel Old School Rooms in Clapton from 22 July to 6 August.
The restaurant's Twitter account instructs: 'Pack your books, press your uniform and head over to the Clapton Park Round Chapel. Hope you have done your homework.'
However some Twitter users have complained that this latest pop-up could be verging on the ridiculous. 
But not everyone thinks this is a good idea.
Twitter user Ruairi posted on the social media site:' I didn't think anything could be simultaneously so dumb and so weird.'
. @ArtofDiningLdn I didn't think anything could be simultaneously so dumb and so weird. #hackneyiseatingitself
 ruairi (@ruairidunne) July 3, 2015

@LDN @dalstonist Well, that's spectacularly tasteless given the number of kids in Hackney who rely on free school meals, but okay.
 La Maupin (@la_maupin) July 6, 2015
Another user La Maupin posted: 'Well, that's spectacularly tasteless given the number of kids in Hackney who rely on free school meals, but okay.'
The trend for restaurant pop-ups is one that has seen London play host to a myriad of interesting themes, from the Porridge Cafe which made its debut early this year to Cannabistro, which served a feast 'designed to recreate the careful ritual of getting high.'
VIDEO
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date/>
        <title>
	MailOnline spends 3 days in San Salvador where 52 shot dead in 72 hours
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151231/52-shot-dead-72-hours-world-s-new-murder-capital-MailOnline-spends-nightmarish-three-days-police-San-Salvador-streets-run-blood-fear-chokes-air.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT Over three nightmarish days with the police on the streets of San Salvador, MailOnline saw them respond to 52 murders - more than an entire years in the UK.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>52 shot dead in 72 hours in the world's new murder capital: MailOnline spends a nightmarish three days with police in San Salvador where the streets run with blood and fear chokes the air
WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT
At least 22 people are gunned down in El Salvador every single day and 677 lives were cut short last month alone
Forensics department in the capital San Salvador is overrun with corpses, with as many as 25 piling up overnight
Many lie unidentified for several months and if they are never claimed, the corpses are thrown into a mass grave
The police blame surge in violence on the breakdown of a truce between government and notorious street gangs
Published: 10:21 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 12:19 GMT, 7 July 2015
44 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Edinburgh Vaults tourists photobombed by 18th century ghost 'The Watcher'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152079/Tourists-photobombed-18th-century-ghost-dubbed-Watcher-visit-Edinburgh-vaults.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Emma Surgenor, 32, from Blackpool, was given a fright when she looked back at her pictures from a night tour at the Edinburgh vaults and saw what appeared to be a ghost standing behind her sister.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'To our shock this figure which looks like a man appeared in one of them. We got a chill sensation and just screamed "oh my god."
'It was a creepy moment. My sister was petrified. She was going on about how he was standing right behind her. Then she thought it was pretty cool. It's pretty scary stuff. There was no one else there.'
The 'spectral figure' which photobombed Emma's picture is stood directly behind her sister wearing what appears to be a long coat and boots. She believes it may be a ghost known as 'The Watcher' or 'Mr Boots.'
Emma said: 'There are a lot of stories about a man down there who wears big boots and a coat and another called "The Watcher" with long hair and 18th century clothing. It's weird that my sister was standing there behind him.. She was pretty creeped out at first.'
Eerie: The 'spectral figure' which photobombed Emma's picture is stood  behind her sister wearing what looks like a long coat and boots. The original photo the 32-year-old took is left, and a lightened version right
The Edinburgh vaults are a series of chambers formed in the arches of the South Bridge which were completed in 1788.
For around 30 years, the vaults were used to house tradesmen, and as a storage facility for illicit material, reportedly including the bodies of people killed by serial killers Burke and Hare for medical experiments.
As the conditions in the vaults deteriorated, due to damp and poor air quality, the businesses left and the poorest of Edinburgh's citizens moved in. But by around 1820 they are even believed to have left, too.
That people had lived there was only discovered in 1985 during an excavation when toys, medicine bottles, plates, and other signs of human habitation were found.
It was a creepy moment. My sister was petrified. She was going on about how he was standing right behind her
Emma Surgenor
Due to frequent reports of paranormal activity and ghost sightings, the Edinburgh vaults were featured on Living TV's Most Haunted. The vaults were monitored in both a 24-hour investigation and for a Most Haunted Live show on Halloween 2006, in which Scottish Investigator Ryan O'Neill took part.
Another television programme, Ghost Adventures, also filmed a show in the vaults and claimed to have experienced numerous encounters with spirits.
The Watcher or Mr Boots has apparently been seen by hundreds of visitors, with some reports describing him as tall with no eyes, a full beard, a long coat and big thigh-high boots.
Others suggest he watches visitors from the corridor and can be protective of the wall in one of the smaller vaults, sometimes shouting 'get out,' when people go near it.
Emma added: 'I have been down there a few times in the past and got another picture last year of a hand behind this guy. It was pretty creepy down there.  This time I didn't feel creeped out. There was no chill feeling when I took it or anything like that.
'I have another picture taken two seconds before and after where my sister isn't in the doorway and from the same angle and there is nothing there.
'It was so creepy but then we were chuffed we had found something. But it was a real shock that made your hair stand on end.'
VIDEO
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Garrick Club votes to continue excluding women despite Damian Lewis' support
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151919/Garrick-Club-votes-women.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	At the club's AGM in London, just 50.5 per cent of members voted in favour of  allowing women to join the club - falling short of the two-thirds majority needed for rules to be changed.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'I think women will do a lot for the good sense of the club,' he said.
But one member, who voted against the motion, said allowing women to join would threaten the 'camaraderie' and 'banter' members enjoy.
Gentlemen's club: Women are allowed into the Garrick, pictured, which is situated in the heart of London's West End, as guests of members but there are parts of the building where they are not permitted
Elite: From left to right, Ruth Leon, widow of Sheridan Morley, Sir Michael Parkinson, Prunella Scales, Nichola McAuliffe and Julian Glover at theSheridan Morley Prize for Theatre Biography at The Garrick Club in 2011
Women are allowed into the Garrick, which is situated in the heart of London's West End, as guests of members but there are parts of the building where they are not permitted.
Over the last 25 years, there have been a number of attempts to update the rules, with some fearing that the club gives its influential members unfair opportunities to network and develop relationships.
In 1991, broadcaster Melvyn Bragg - who last year hosted his 75th birthday celebrations at the gentlemen's club - was one of those who supported female members in a debate on the issue.
Speaking out: Labour MP Chris Bryant was among those who criticised the vote against allowing women
But he failed to convince the majority of members, and 70 per cent voted against allowing women.
Two decades later, women were nominated as prospective members for the first time in the club's history. Actress and activist Joanna Lumley was put forward by Hugh Bonneville, while broadcaster Lucinda Lambton was nominated by her husband SirPeregrine Worsthorne.
While a close examination of the rules revealed there was nothing preventing women from joining, it was decided that it would go against the spirit of the club and their applications were rejected.
That same year, Britain's most senior woman judge, Baroness Hale of Richmond, slammed the 'cosy club' enjoyed by her male colleagues.
Changing tides: Over the last 25 years, there have been a number of attempts to update the rules, with some fearing that the club gives its influential members unfair opportunities to network. Above, the Garrick Club
Baroness Hale, the only woman in the Supreme Court, said: 'I regard it as quite shocking that so many of my colleagues belong to the Garrick Club, but they don't see what all the fuss is about.'
She also told an InterLaw Diversity Forum, at London law firm Norton Rose, that the culture at the club was a key factor in why women did not make the top judicial ranks.
This was because there were 'too many systemic barriers' put in place that depended more on 'personal network relationships'.
Among those who spoke out against the 'no' vote today was Labour MP Chris Bryant, who called the decision 'extraordinary'.
Posting on Twitter, he wrote: 'Extraordinary that the Garrick Club still can't bring itself to admit women members'.
A spokeswoman for the Garrick Club said there would be no comment on the vote.
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
13
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date/>
        <title>
	HSBC staff sacked after filming ISIS-style mock execution during team-building day out
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151619/Six-HSBC-staff-sacked-filming-ISIS-style-mock-execution-team-building-day-karting-centre.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The video, taken at a go-karting centre in Birmingham, shows the balaclava-clad men laughing as a colleague kneels in front of them in an orange jumpsuit.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
1.1k shares
Mr Ahmed denied any knowledge of the video, which was posted on Instagram but later deleted.
A HSBC spokesperson said: 'We do not tolerate inappropriate behaviour.
'We took the decision to sack the individuals involved. This is an abhorrent video and HSBC would like to apologise for any offence caused.'
It is understood the film was made when the men were on a team-building exercise at a go kart track
The workers' video is the latest scandal for HSBC, which earlier this year was accused of helping rich clients avoid tax and turning a blind eye to arms dealers.
On the 'Our Values' page of its website, HSBC Chief Executive Stuart Gulliver says: 'By setting the highest standards of behavior our aim is that all of our employees and customers can be proud of our business.'
The bank's customers and Twitter users slammed the stunt online today, branding it 'utter, utter idiocy'.
Ben Rose tweeted: 'That HSBC mock ISIS beheading. Supposed educated individuals. Bunch of absolute morons more like.'
And another user added: 'HSBC only sacked those 'ISIS' goons because the film was made public. Imagine what goes on in private at that place.'
ISIS has used its carefully-produced propaganda videos to recruit extremists from around the world to its cause.
Six staff from HSBC (whose Birmingham building is pictured, left) have been sacked after filming the video
The horrific footage of the beheadings of US and British hostages featuring the killer known-as 'Jihadi John' were designed to cause maximum shock around the world.
Hostages were put in orange jumpsuits in a perverse reference to inmates at Guantanamo Bay detention camp, where high-risk terrorists were imprisoned by the US authorities.
The videos were spread through social media and YouTube in a bid to attract radicals from around the world to their side.
It is not the first time the propaganda videos have been recreated for poor-taste jokes. Earlier this year, actress Dakota Johnson was criticised for filming an ISIS-themed skit for US show Saturday Night Live.
The sequence poked fun at a Toyota advert, but showed Johnson jumping into the back of an ISIS jeep. The sketch was slammed as 'depraved' and 'tasteless' by viewers.
Do you know the men involved? Phone 0203 615 2676 or email richard.spillett@mailonline.co.uk
The footage posted online shows five men in black overalls and balaclavas laughing as they stand over an Asian colleague at an indoor go-karting centre (pictured) in Birmingham
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
1.1k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Greek referendum dismissed as 'irrelevant circus' by EC president Juncker
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151560/Greek-deal-blow-euro-apart-Merkel-refuses-write-Athens-debts.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Speaking in Brussels today, Juncker criticised the wording of the referendum question as 'intelligible', adding that has left him wondering what exactly the Greek people were voting to say.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
668 shares
Athens yesterday extended its 'bank holiday' until at least Thursday after the European Central Bank deferred a decision on whether to continue propping up the country's financial institutions.
But one American hedge fund, Balyasny, yesterday warned investors that Greek banks were on the verge of running dry, leaving the country 48 hours from civil unrest.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel showed the strain ahead of her meeting with Francois Hollande yesterday
In need of help: A Greek Orthodox priest blesses people outside a chapel in central Athens this morning as Eurozone leaders hold an emergency summit in Brussels on July 7 to discuss the country's future
Turning to religion: The faithful prepare to pray during a celebration of a saint at a church in Athens today
Waiting: People queue outside a bank to withdraw cash from a cash machine in central Athens this morning
Greece remains in economical crisis as banks stay closed
In a further signal that Greece's financial woes could spark a wider geopolitical crisis for the West, Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras yesterday held talks by phone with Russian President Vladimir Putin.
Moscow said the call had been arranged 'at the request' of Mr Tsipras, with the two men discussing the outcome of the referendum. Some observers believe Moscow could agree to bail out Greece in return for Athens blocking further EU sanctions against Russia.
France was last night pushing for an EU brokered deal, with Mr Hollande saying it was vital to Europe to show 'solidarity' with Greece.
The French President said 'the door is open' to further discussions with Mr Tsipras, who is expected to table fresh proposals in Brussels today.
But Germany gave no sign it is willing to back down in the face of the Greek referendum on Sunday, when voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity measures demanded as a condition of future bailout funds.
An elderly man leans on the main gate of the National Bank of Greece this morning as he waits for it to open
Elderly men and women queue to collect their pensions outside a bank in Kotzia Square, Athens today
Still waiting: Queues form outside banks before they opened this morning. Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is working on new debt crisis proposals and is due to present them at a eurozone emergency summit today
Welcome: A bank employee opens the main gate of the National bank of Greece in central Athens this morning
Mrs Merkel said the conditions for a deal 'are not there yet'. She added: 'We have already shown a great deal of solidarity to Greece and the latest proposal put forward to them was extremely generous.'
Sigmar Gabriel, the German vice-chancellor and economy minister, said there could be no question of writing off Greek debt because other countries that have had loans such as Ireland, Portugal and Spain would demand equal treatment.
'I really hope that the Greek government  if it wants to enter negotiations again  will accept that the other 18 member states of the euro can't just go along with an unconditional haircut,' he said.
'How could we then refuse it to other member states? And what would it mean for the eurozone if we'd do it? It would blow the eurozone apart, for sure.'
In the UK, ministers are pessimistic about the prospects for a deal.
David Cameron held talks by phone with Mrs Merkel on the crisis, while George Osborne discussed the issue with International Monetary Fund boss Christine Lagarde. But neither man emerged from the discussions with any indication that a deal is imminent.
Athens yesterday extended its 'bank holiday' until at least Thursday after the European Central Bank deferred a decision on whether to continue propping up the country's financial institutions
An elderly woman prepares to join the back of the queue outside a closed bank in Athens this morning
People read the front pages of various newspapers hanging at a kiosk in central Athens this morning
Lining up: People queue at an ATM to withdraw cash in central Athens earlier this morning
In the Commons, Mr Osborne said there was now a severe danger that the political talks would be overtaken by the financial realities on the ground.
The Chancellor said the chances of a 'happy resolution' were 'sadly diminished' by Sunday's 'No' vote in Greece.
He said the crisis would 'deteriorate rapidly' unless today's eurozone meeting signals that a deal is on the cards.
Valdis Dombrovskis, the European Commission vice president responsible for the euro, said a write-down of Greece's 270 billion debt mountain was now 'off the table' after the referendum.
He said the vote 'dramatically weakens the negotiating stance of the Greek government' and 'makes things more complicated'.
At a briefing in Brussels, he added: 'The 'No' result unfortunately widens the gap between Greece and other eurozone countries. There is no easy way out of this crisis. Too much time and too many opportunities have been lost.' Mr Dombrovskis also claimed the vote had no legal basis.
'Door for talks remains open': Merkel on Greece proposals
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras yesterday held talks by phone with Russian President Vladimir Putin (pictured together earlier this year)
Crisis talks: David Cameron held talks by phone with Mrs Merkel on the crisis, but a deal with Greece does not look imminent. George Osborne discussed the issue with International Monetary Fund boss Christine Lagarde
'We choose democracy!': Greece celebrates a 'no' referendum
Pressure on Greece's banks last night increased as the European Central Bank toughened the terms of its emergency funding.
The ECB demanded Greeks banks put up more collateral in order to keep the 89 billion euro lifeline of Emergency Liquidity Assistance.
Even though the country's four main banks are expected to meet the new threshold, the decision pushes them closer to the brink as they struggle to replenish cash machines.
Global stock markets slid lower yesterday as the result of the Greek referendum. Shares across Europe tumbled and the single currency was hammered amid speculation Greece is on the verge of leaving the euro and readopting the drachma.
Britain's blue chip companies have now lost 145billion of value since April in a blow to millions of families with savings and pensions.
But holidaymakers heading to the Continent are getting more bang for their buck thanks to the rising value of the pound. Sterling rose as high to above 1.41 euros  up more than 12 per cent on a year ago when 1 was worth less than 1.26 euros.

Tory eurosceptics have urged British voters to follow Greece's lead in standing up to EU 'bullying'.
Steve Baker, who leads the Conservatives for Britain campaign, said Greek's referendum should encourage Britons to 'be courageous and vote in line with what they think best when the referendum comes'.
He added that we have a 'much stronger economy' and therefore are 'much more able to depart from the EU' than Greece.

Share or comment on this article
668
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Karen Danczuk backs estranged husband Simon in battle with depression
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152019/Karen-Danczuk-backs-estranged-husband-s-battle-recover-depression.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Labour MP for Rochdale and his estranged wife - known for her Twitter selfies - have been locked in a very public spat since they split up earlier this year
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
He has worked to shed light on the crimes of former MP Cyril Smith in his constituency of Rochdale and has put pressure on the Home Office to do more to investigate historic crimes..
He said yesterday: 'It has made me depressed and I have decided to seek help. I've been getting angry at stuff I shouldn't be getting angry at, fairly mundane things, and have been aggressive - not violently aggressive - but getting angry about things.
'I've been drinking too much, a full bottle of wine of an evening,especially on Fridays when I would hear a lot and meet with a number of the victims. At times suicidal thoughts as well.'
Mr Danczuk said he felt'like a fool' for not suspecting after Karen started wearing make-up and skimpy kit to the gym, pictured is Karen with her trainer, Ben Bate
Karen Danczuk became known for posting racy Twitter images
He said his mental health had impacted his relationship as he had trouble sleeping and his wife had understandable become sick of hearing about child sex abuse.
He added: 'On a practical level, Karen would say why don't we not talk about this tonight, can we have a night off talking about child sexual abuse.
'Because I would be coming home some nights wanting to download some of what I had heard. Not everyone wants to listen to it, do they, quite understandably.'
He continued: 'We would go out as a couple with another couple which was relatively rare and my wife went to the toilet. When she came back she said; "What you guys talking about?" And of course, we're speaking about child sex abuse.'
The 48-year-old politician said he sought help through a parliamentary occupation health officer and he is now seeing a therapist.
His interview came after Mrs Danczuk, 32, told her 61,000 followers on Twitter that 'word is now out' that she is single and posted a screen grab of an internet dating site.
Labour MP Simon Danczuk and his selfie-mad wife Karen pictured during their marriage
Karen Danczuk faces Janet Street Porter over THOSE selfies
Last week, Mr Danczuk voiced fears that his wife had been cheating on him with her personal trainer for five months after Ben Bate, 33, was photographed leaving the couple's home at 5am on Friday.
And the 'selfie queen'  hit back saying she is 'disgusted' by his comments and vowing that the 'truth will out'.
Karen tweeted: 'I'm disgusted by the Suns story. Pure lies! I know truth, he knows truth! KD #alcoholic #arrogant #badtemper #goodwithhis..... #truthwillout.'
Her husband said it was 'clear' Karen and Mr Bate  had a close relationship and said he felt 'like a fool' for not suspecting after Karen started wearing make-up and skimpy kit to the gym.
The MP for Rochdale, 48, said her gym sessions went from once a week to every day and last month theyspent five days together in Spain last month at a boot camp near Alicante.
Mr Danczuk said: 'I would call Karen in the morning and she wouldn't answer at 10am. It was also hard to get hold of her at night.'
Putting on a brave face:Simon Danczuk posted this picture to Twitter over the weekend
Warning: Ms Danczuk posted this racy photo and message to Twitter on Friday
Mrs Danczuk announced her marriage to the Labour MP was over last week and on Friday night Mr Bate revealed on Twitter that he had separated from his wife Natalie.
Mr Bate, who fled to the hills to take part in the Three Peaks Challenge, tweeted:  'FYI I'm separated... me and @KarenDanczuk are friends. When two friends have gone through separation it's good to talk.'
Mrs Danczuk has said to point out that her personal trainer's marriage broke down in May.
She tweeted: 'One final point re: my PT and this is last word. His marriage broke down way back in May so not just last few days so sorry to disappoint.'
The former councillor again denied the rumours last night, saying: 'I don't fancy him  he's not very easy on the eye.'
She was seen taking her two sons to the cinema yesterday to watch the new Minions film.
Karen referred to her personal trainer as a 'great friend' and she she might as well have cheated because of the accusations.
For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here
Read more:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Crohn's disease mother's anger at not being able to use Co-op toilet
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152102/Crohn-s-disease-mother-s-anger-not-able-use-op-toilet.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Annie Richards, of Cradley Heath, West Midlands, was denied access to the toilet in a Plymouth branch of Co-op Food despite telling staff of her condition, which causes excruciating abdominal pain
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'I rarely go out, which is why it was devastating to be treated so cruelly by the Co-op. I'd had a lovely weekend, and it really knocked my confidence.
'Now I'm worried to even go out in case I have another accident.'
She says a member of staff ignored her pleas to be able to use the staff toilet. The company has apologised
Following the embarrassing incident, Ms Richards posted an angry comment on the Co-operative Food's Facebook page but the company failed to respond.
She said: 'I was really disappointed when no-one got back to me. I feel like much more needs to be done to educate people on the effects of Crohn's.
'Whilst I can accept that it might not be store policy to allow members of the public to use staff toilets, I would hope that people would use their common sense.
'I was clearly in a lot of pain, and as someone who used to work in a supermarket, I know I would never treat someone in that way.
'People need to understand that we're not exaggerating when we say we need the toilet. Hopefully companies will also teach their staff about the 'Can't Wait' cards so they can respond more appropriately in the future.'
Ms Richards is currently planning to complete a skydive in aid of the 'GetYourBellyOut' campaign, which was set up to raise awareness of Crohn's and colitis.
Ms Richards, left, after an a operation to remove part of her intestine and, right, with her son Cory
She said: 'I won't let what happened stop me from living my life. I want to help other people with the condition to know that they are not alone and there is nothing to be ashamed of.'
Caroline Reed, Membership Manager at Crohn's and Colitis UK, said: 'For many people with inflammatory bowel disease, the sudden and uncontrollable need to use a toilet is a genuine and recognised symptom of their condition.
'Having an 'accident' in public can have a devastating effect on their ability to undertake everyday activities, such as going to work, shopping and socialising.
'We hope that in the future staff members will be more sensitive to members of the public with 'invisible' diseases.'
A spokesperson for The Co-operative Food said: 'For health, safety and insurance reasons staff toilets are not generally available to customers, but their use by customers is left to the discretion of the store team.
'We are sorry to hear about this incident and as a gesture of goodwill we will make a donation of 100 to a local Colitis and Crohn's Disease Association charity.'
CROHN'S DISEASE: AN INFLAMMATION OF THE DIGESTIVE SYSTEM'S LINING
Suffferers of Crohn's disease include The Only Way is Essex star Sam Faiers
Crohns disease is a long-term condition that causes inflammation of the lining of the digestive system.
Inflammation can affect any part of the digestive system, from the mouth to the back passage, but most commonly occurs in the last section of the small intestine (ileum) or the large intestine (colon).
Symptoms include diarrhoea, abdominal pain, fatigue and weight loss and, in the long term, the inflammation can result in additional complications, such as narrowing of the colon.
It isnt fully understood what causes the condition but genes, a faulty immune system and previous infection may play a role.
There is no cure but there are medications to help control symptoms. In up to 75 per cent of cases, surgery will be needed to repair damaged parts of the digestive system.
One theory is that Crohn's, whose sufferers include Towie star Sam Faiers (right) is caused by the immune system attacking healthy bacteria in the gut.
So by giving the patient a new immune system - through a bone marrow transplant - it is hoped that the disease can be cured.
To have a bone marrow transplant, stem cells are removed, high-dose chemotherapy is given to suppress the immune system - and stem cells are then returned.
There are currently at least 115,000 people living with Crohns disease in the UK.Crohn's disease can affect people of all ages, including children.
However, most cases first develop between the ages of 16 and 30.
For more information on Crohn's disease and the 'GetYourBellyOut' campaign, visit www.crohnsandcolitis.org.uk

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Jim Naughtie to leave BBC Radio 4's Today programme after 21 years
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151992/Today-host-Jim-Naughtie-leave-BBC-flagship-Radio-4-show.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The veteran presenter has been host of the Radio 4 programme since February 1994, after a career in newspapers, much of it as a political correspondent at Westminster.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'Out of the office and on the road, Jim was in his element. Insatiably curious and always charming, Jim has a knack of grabbing interviews in a corridor or lift you never thought you'd ever get.
'And all of it anchored by his ability as a writer for radio, second to none, always able to conjure up for the audience a sense of place - a US convention, a party conference, moving into Kosovo in a Land Rover, all of it rendered vividly for a generation of Today listeners.'
James Naughtie and John Humphries reading the papers for The Today Programme.The presenter - who once famously mis-pronounced the first letter of former Culture Secretary Jeremy Hunt's surname on air - was described as 'chaotically charming by his colleagues
He has also presented every edition of Radio 4's monthly Bookclub since it began in 1998
Naughtie is the second longest-serving presenter after John Humphrys.
The announcement has fueled speculation over who will replace him - with the BBCs political editor Nick Robinson hotly tipped to fill the slot, despite not being back on full duties following surgery for a rare form of lung cancer.
In a statement, the Corporation said: 'In this role he will have a responsibility for charting the course of the constitutional changes at the heart of the UK political debate - devolution and independence, parliamentary reform and the changes in the UK's relations with Europe.
'Jim will also be a roving reporter and Radio 4 listeners will continue to hear from him at home and around the world.
'He is also being appointed as BBC News Books Editor. This will chiefly involve working for Radio 4, where he will present a regular book review for the Today programme on a Saturday morning.'
Mr Naughtie said: 'It was exciting to discover that the BBC and I had the same idea about what I should do next. I'm thrilled to be moving from one dream job to another, and working with the programmes across Radio 4 - including Today - that I love and have known for so long.
'I can't think of a more invigorating challenge. And after 21 years, I can turn off that 3am alarm at last'.
James Naughtie joined Today in 1994 following the death of Brian Redhead, having spent six years as presenter of The World at One, where he succeeded Sir Robin Day.
In his 21 years on the programme he interviewed every significant figure in British politics and has travelled the world for Today - in Europe, the Middle East, China including Tibet, Australia and to the United States.
He interviewed Barack Obama at the start of his political rise, before his name was known across the Atlantic, and every British prime minister from Margaret Thatcher onwards.
He has presented every edition of Radio 4's monthly Bookclub since it began in 1998.
Tony Hall, Director-General of the BBC, says: 'Jim has been the emotional heart of the Today programme for a generation.
'His persistent and incisive questioning has given millions of listeners a greater understanding of the stories of our time. Above all he's a writer and reporter at heart - he can bring to life a vivid scene on the radio better than anyone - and I'm delighted that on many of the biggest news stories of 2016 and beyond Jim will continue to be at the heart of our coverage.
Naughtie with Mo Mowlam.In his 21 years on the programme he has interviewed every significant figure in British politics and has travelled the world for Today - in Europe, the Middle East, China including Tibet, Australia and to the United States
James Harding, Director of News, says: 'Jim brings a range of passions and interests, a host of intelligence and understanding to all that he does on the BBC. As a presenter of Today, he has illuminated the national conversation on politics and world affairs, the arts and culture for more than 20 years. I am excited at the prospect of Jim, unleashed, as inquisitor and reporter, critic and twinkling enthusiast across the Radio 4 airwaves for years to come.'
Gwyneth Williams, Controller of BBC Radio 4, adds: 'Jim has been a leading Radio 4 presenter for as long as I can remember and I want to thank him for his many years on Today.
'Our discerning audience trusts his judgement and we all respond to his inimitable enthusiasm and verve. His is an elegant pen and Jim has made good writing his signature. Thus I am thrilled to be keeping for Radio 4, in this broader role, his particular voice, with its rich understanding of politics and culture and history.'

Share or comment on this article
22
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Revenge porn photo uploaded by Clayton Kennedy results in £400 fine
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152055/Jealous-man-fined-400-putting-revenge-porn-photo-ex-girlfriend-Facebook-dumped-him.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Clayton Kennedy, 20, was fined £400 and given a community order at Cardiff Magistrates' Court after admitting posting a photograph on social media of his ex-girlfriend performing a sex act.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
She told police she never consented to having the image posted on social media and was 'worried' about other people seeing it.
Chair of the bench Dr Chantal Nichols fined Kennedy 405 and handed him a community order.
She said: 'This was a nasty offence with the potential to have an emotional impact on the victim.
Scroll down for video
Kennedy has become one of the first people in Britain to be prosecuted under the new 'revenge porn' laws
At Cardiff Magistrates' Court (pictured) yesterday, Kennedy admitted disclosing private sexual photographs with intent to cause distress. He was fined 405 and given a community order for the 'nasty offence'
'This is a relatively new offence but we want to make sure that you understand that what you did is very serious.'
Siobhan Blake, Deputy Chief Crown Prosecutor for the Crown Prosecution Service, said: 'The distress caused by this type of behaviour is considerable.
'We want to make it abundantly clear that those who engage in this type of vindictive activity can expect to find themselves in court.'
'Although this case was brought to court under new legislation introduced within the last year, it should not be a surprise to anyone that online conduct of this nature is a criminal offence.'
MAXIMUM PRISON SENTENCE OF TWO YEARS: NEW REVENGE PORN LAWS
The distribution of a private sexual image of someone without their consent and with the intention of causing them distress could result in two years in prison under new laws (file picture)
Those convicted of revenge porn  the distribution of a private sexual image of someone without their consent and with the intention of causing them distress  could face two years in prison under new laws.
'Revenge porn' is now a specific offence, covering the sharing of images both online and offline, in the Criminal Justice and Courts Bill - which went through Parliament in April.
It means that images posted to social networking sites such as Facebook and Twitter are counted under the offence, as well as those that are shared via text message.
Images shared via email, on a website or the distribution of physical copies are also counted.
The offence covers photographs or films which show people engaged in sexual activity or depicted in a sexual way or with their genitals exposed, where what is shown would not usually be seen in public.
Victims of revenge porn have previously found it difficult to have pictures removed from the internet.
Many sites where the images are hosted are based outside the UK, and requests to remove content are often ignored. In some cases, asking for removal results in more attention being brought to the images.
The move to clamp down on 'revenge porn' came after 149 cases, the vast majority of them involving women victims, were reported over two and a half years. Only six led to prosecutions.
However, the new rules do not affect the consensual 'sexting' of images by under-18s. This is already illegal  but police cannot monitor mobile photo messages.
Under the new law, victims and others are able to report offences to the police to investigate and officers will then work with the Crown Prosecution Service to take forward cases for prosecution.
Announcing the new laws earlier this year,Justice Secretary Chris Grayling said: 'The fact that there are individuals who are cruelly distributing intimate pictures of their former partners without their consent is almost beyond belief.
'We want those who fall victim to this type of disgusting behaviour to know that we are on their side and will do everything we can to bring offenders to justice.'
Nicky Morgan, Minister for Women and Equalities, said: 'Circulating intimate photos of an individual without their consent is never acceptable. People are entitled to expect a reasonable level of respect and privacy.
'It is right that those who do circulate these images are held to account, and that we educate young people to the hurt that can be caused by breaking this trust.'
Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Rory McIlroy ruptures left ankle ligament playing football and is a huge doubt for the defence of his Open title at St Andrews
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sport/golf/article-3150841/Rory-McIlroy-ruptures-left-ankle-ligament-looks-certain-miss-defence-Open-title-St-Andrews-week.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	World No 1 Rory McIlroy has ruptured a ligament in his left ankle playing football and is a huge doubt to defend The Open at St Andrews next week. He may now miss out on £4.5m in prize money.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>The kickabout that could cost Rory 4million: Golf star McIlroy is set to miss British Open after rupturing ligaments playing football
World No 1 Rory McIlroy has torn a ligament in his ankle playing football 
The Northern Irishman revealed the news on his Instagram account
McIlroy has not ruled himself out of The Open at St Andrews next week
But could now miss as much as 4.5million in summer prize money
Jordan Spieth could replace McIlroy as world No 1 in his absence
Published: 10:10 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 11:54 GMT, 7 July 2015
145 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Shaggy says pumping his music into ISIS strongholds would prevent executions
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151974/Could-Mr-Lover-Lover-bring-peace-Middle-East-Reggae-star-Shaggy-says-pumping-music-ISIS-strongholds-prevent-executions-promotes-new-single-F-k-Yourself.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	As the Islamic State's bloodthirsty armies continue to wreak havoc with rape and massacre in the name of radical Islam, an unlikely contender has stepped forward to bring peace to the Middle East.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
121 shares
'If youre able to cut a mans head off, youre sick. But right music evokes emotion. So if theyre listening to Shaggy music or reggae music, theyre not going to want to cut somebodys head off,' he said.
'Therere two thing you want to do when you listen to reggae: You get somebody pregnant, or youre f**king high. High people dont want to kill nothing; they want to love. They need to bag some Jamaican weed and distribute it amongst ISIS. I guarantee there wont be any more wars out there.'
Militants: Shaggy went as far to say that if ISIS recruits were to listen his latest single, the pleasantly-titled 'Go F**k Yourself', they would turn away from terrorism altogether and embrace peace
Mr Lover Lover: Shaggy found fame in the mid-1990s with his hit single Boombastic (pictured)
Shaggy found fame in the mid-1990s with his  blend of reggae, hip hop and pop and a unique voice that inspired thousands of playground imitators.
Veteran: The 46-year-old Jamaican actually served as a US marine in Iraq during the first Gulf War
Though born in Kingston, Jamaica, Shaggy's family moved tothe Flatbush area of Brooklyn in New York aged 18, where he started singing and performing alongside friends.
He put his music career on temporary hold, however, to enlist as a Marine during the first Gulf War, serving with the firing battery from the 10th Marine Regiment in Iraq.
While serving in the army, Shaggy perfected his unique vocal style and wrote the song that would eventually become a hit single around the world, 'Boombastic'.
His first big success was a cover of the Folkes Brothers' 'Oh, Carolina', however, which hit number one in the UK in 1993.
'Boombastic' was the next big success two years later, reaching number one around the world after it was featured on a television advertisement for Levi jeans.
The album of the same name won a Grammy award the following year.
After a few years without a major hit, Shaggy returned alongside Jamaican singer RikRok on the smash hit single 'It Wasn't Me' in 2000, which again was an international number one.
The follow-up 'Angel' also fared well in the charts but Shaggy has struggled with mainstream success since the early 2000s.
Idea: The 90s star suggested that one peaceful solution to the threat posed by ISIS - led by Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi (pictured) is that his music could be pumped in ISIS strongholds and training camps
Share or comment on this article
121
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Dementia reverse possible by blocking B2M protein found in the blood
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3152030/Could-scientists-REVERSE-dementia-Blocking-protein-builds-blood-helps-combat-memory-loss.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Inhibiting a protein called B2M, which is involved in immunity, reversed the decline in thinking and memory associated with ageing, scientists from the University of California, San Francisco, found.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
32 shares
Older mice who received young blood in the first study could find the hidden platforms easier - though it was not clear why or how.
Ageing is associated with a progressive decline in cognitive function, the ability to think, understand, remember and learn, as well as slower regeneration of message-relaying neurons in the brain.
'Ageing remains the most dominant risk factor for dementia-related neurodegenerative diseases, such as Alzheimer's disease,' the authors of the study wrote in the paper.
As such, it is imperative to gain insight on the mechanisms that drive ageing in the brain, in order to understand what makes a person vulnerability to a declines in cognitive ability, they added.
From their latest work, it appears that B2M, a protein involved in immunity, may be associated with the ageing of the brain.
Scientists have found a protein called B2M which is found in higher levels of the blood of older people, impairs learning and memory, ageing the brain
B2M injections impaired the learning ability, memory, and neuron growth of lab mice, the team wrote.
But the effect was 'reversible' by stopping the injections.
In another experiment, the scientists eliminated B2M genetically in mice, and 'observed that the old mice lacking B2M did not develop memory loss', said Dr Villeda.
This all implied the molecule 'could be targeted to potentially restore cognitive ability in the elderly', he added.
The next step would be to develop a molecule that can either block the protein, or help remove it from old human blood.
B2M has previously also been found in elevated levels in the cerebral spinal fluid of dementia patients.
The research was published in the journal Nature Medicine.
KEY CHANGES IN THE BRAIN IN MIDDLE AGE MAY INDICATE ALZHEIMER'S DISEASE, SCIENTISTS DISCOVER
Scientists have discovered the key markers in the brain and spinal fluid in middle age that indicate if a person is likely to develop Alzheimer's disease.
This could allow doctors to identify those who will develop dementia years later, they said.
'It's too early to use these biomarkers to definitively predict whether individual patients will develop Alzheimer's disease, but we're working toward that goal,' said senior author Professor Anne Fagan, of Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis.
'One day, we hope to use such measures to identify and treat people years before memory loss and other cognitive problems become apparent.'
Scientists discovered key changes in the brain in middle age that can indicate Alzheimer's disease. Pictured is the brain of a person with Alzheimer's under the microscope
The study gathered data over 10 years and involved 169 cognitively normal research participants ages 45 to 75 when they entered the study.
Each participant received a complete clinical, cognitive imaging and cerebrospinal fluid biomarker analysis every three years, with a minimum of two evaluations.
The biomarkers they analysied included the amount of amyloid beta 42 present in the brain.
Amyloid beta 42 a protein that is the principal ingredient of Alzheimer's plaques.
Another is tau, a structural part of brain cells that increases in the cerebrospinal fluid as Alzheimer's disease damages brain cells.
They also looked at YKL-40, a protein produced by the brain cells that indicates inflammation.
Brain scans were also carried out to reveal the presence of amyloid plaques in the brain.
At the participants' initial assessments, researchers divided them into three age groups: early-middle age (45-54); mid-middle age (55- 64); and late-middle age (65-74).
The changes in the brain were more pronounced in people with a specific gene known to increase the risk of Alzheimer's, researchers found. Pictured are brain scans of a person with Alzheimer's disease
The scientists found that drops in amyloid beta 42 levels in the cerebrospinal fluid among the people in the study ages 45-54, who had normal thinking abilities at this point, are linked to the appearance of plaques in brain scans years later.
The researchers also found that tau and other markers of damage to brain cells increase sharply in some individuals as they reach their mid-50s to mid-70s.
YKL-40 rises throughout the age groups focused on in the study, researchers found.
Previous research has shown that all of these markers may be affected by Alzheimer's disease, but this is the first large data set to show that they change over time in middle-aged individuals.
All of these changes were more pronounced in participants who carried a form of a gene that significantly increases the risk of Alzheimer's disease.
The gene is known as APOE, and scientists have known that people with two copies of a particular version of this gene have up to 10 times the risk of developing Alzheimer's as those with other versions of the gene.
The study was published in the journal JAMA Neurology.

Share or comment on this article
32
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Parents paying for children's work experience placements to keep them 'grounded'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3151874/The-super-rich-parents-paying-children-clean-toilets-Families-seek-work-experience-placements-offspring-REAL-jobs-grounded.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Billionaires, attracted to London by the promise of good education, are seeking work experience placements for their kids that offer an insight into what life's like further down the social ladder.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
She added: 'They want a true perspective of whats going on in the world.'
While a gilded life may lay ahead of the children in question, many of whom are attending England's most elite independent schools, work experience offers the offspring of 'ultra high net worth individuals' - those in possession of at least a 20million wealth - the chance to walk in more ordinary shoes.
A leaf out of William's book: Back in 2000, Prince William, then aged 18, went to Chile for ten weeks to teach English to local school children
The Prince was famously captured cleaning toilets during his Chile placement
World's richest postcode: London has the highest proportion of billionaires with 140 now owning a home in the city(Pictured is 1 Cornwall Terrace, which sold for 80m in 2013)
Villani said that the biggest request for work placements was in areas of 'medicine and dentistry, law, banking, geo-political business research, finance, politics, photography, art, film and charitable work.'
Last month, luxury property agent Beauchamp Estates released its Ultra Prime Barometer, a study on billionaires and their property habits.
London has the highest concentration of billionaires in the world - with around 140 now owning a home in the city - far more than New York, which has 103, Moscow, which has 85, Hong Kong, which has 82 and Paris's 33.
While a London post-code is currently a must-have for the world's billionaires, there's also a growing trend towards placing them in more diverse educational facilities, in a bid to introduce children to people from different backgrounds.
Mrs Villiani said that England was appealing to the super-rich because living here often offered more freedom to their children than their own country of birth might.
The Salamanca Group also has a school placement service, which costs around 10,000 and offers to help parents find the right school for their children, as well as helping them source uniforms and practice interview techniques.
Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date/>
        <title>
	BBC scraps Wimbledon 2day delighting viewers but Clare Balding still moaned about
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151958/Thank-God-s-normal-Viewers-delighted-BBC-scraps-controversial-new-Wimbledon-returns-traditional-highlights-moaning-Clare-Balding.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Wimbledon 2day attracted a barrage of complaints with viewers lambasting the show's studio audience and setting in a plush hospitality area, with many calling for Clare Balding to be replaced.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Last week scores took to social media to complain the Corporation had lowered the tone of the highlights programme with its informal style and introduction of a studio audience.
In one episode Ms Balding was seen hitting a ball back and forth with Tim Henman using children's rackets. 
Among complaints were criticisms the sports presenter, who was largely praised for her coverage of the Olympics and Commonwealth Games, did not know enough about tennis.
She was drafted in by the BBC following the departure of John Inverdale last year who stepped down from the show amid a row over alleged sexism.
Wimbledon 2Day changes format following viewer backlash
Praise: Viewers were happy with the change in format on Monday though some still complained about Ms Balding's coverage
Criticised: Presenter Clare Balding was slammed for her coverage of the tournament with many claiming the presenter does not know enough about tennis for the role
Playful: Ms Balding and former player Tim Henman were filmed in one episode hitting a ball with children's tennis rackets
Tim Henman and Clare Balding warm up before Wimbledon Day 3
Last week the programme was filmed in The Gatsby Club, an expensive hospitality area within the grounds.
While the BBC said no additional cost had been incurred by moving the programme on Monday, it would not disclose how much had already been spent on filming in The Gatsby Club last week.
While viewers were grateful to see the programme rid of its playful studio audience, some were still left unimpressed by Ms Balding's coverage.
'Bring back John Inverdale. Clare Balding looks like a rabbit caught in headlights,' said one Twitter user while another fumed: 'Wimbledon 2day so much better tonight but what's glaringly obvious is how little Clare Balding actually knows about tennis.'
Asked why it had taken the decision to change the format halfway through, the BBC said the show had always been intended to 'evolve'.
'We said from the outset that Wimbledon 2Day would evolve throughout the Championship,' a spokesman told MailOnline.
'Of course we listen to audience feedback and that helps to shape the changes we make.
'We have moved to a new location, on top of the centre court building, which gives an excellent backdrop of the heart of Wimbledon, as the Championship builds to its climax.'
Replaced: John Inverdale departed the highlights show last year amid a row over alleged sexism

Share or comment on this article
15
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Benefits mother Cheryl Prudham wants £5k 34DD boob job using her state handouts
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152009/Now-benefits-mother-12-Cheryl-Prudham-wants-use-handouts-pay-new-5-000-34DD-boob-job.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Cheryl Prudham, from Skelmersdale, Lancashire, gave birth to her 12th child last month and had applied for NHS surgery to boost her 34A bust to a 34DD cup.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'I asked doctors for a boob job five years ago and they referred me to a plastic surgeon.
'But he refused to do the operation on the NHS. I was devastated because I had got my hopes up.
'Having 12 children has not helped my boobs. But I have always had a small chest and it affects my self-confidence.
'I am not doing it for Robert. I am doing it for myself.
'I cannot wear certain clothes as they make my chest look flat. I want the op as soon as I have saved up enough money.'
The Prudhams moved from Gravesend, Kent to Skelmersdale, Lancashire after claiming they had been victims of a 'vicious hate campaign.'
Mrs Prudham claims she received verbal abuse after boasting that she takes her family on foreign holidays and openly splashing out on designer handbags
She claims she received verbal abuse after boasting that she takes her family on foreign holidays and openly splashing out on designer handbags.
The family now live in a five-bedroom house with a 1,000-a-month rent bill. The couple's annual income is believed to be more than 72,000.
Until now, the Prudhams have claimed 39,192 in benefits a year on top of Mr Prudham's monthly salary of 1,600 as a delivery driver.
Mrs Prudham admits she is 'addicted' to having babies and had her first child George, now 15, when she was just 17.
She soon moved into a flat with her ex-boyfriend and had second son, Jack, 14, and her eldest daughter Caitlin, ten.
Mrs Prudham, who is making plans for a 13th child, said she enjoys being pregnant as her breasts get bigger, but then she feels depressed when her chest shrinks back
She then had three unplanned pregnancies; Maisie, nine, Lillie, seven, and Madison, six.
In March 2009, she met current husband Rob and they had Leon, now five. They then had Lenny, now three, before she gave birth to daughter Lainey in January last year.
She gave birth to twins Lacey-May and Lexi-Rose last autumn before having her 12th child last month.
Mrs Prudham, who believes she will have saved enough from benefits to have the breast enlargement next year, added that she is busy settling Tillie-Grace into their new home.
She said : 'It is complete chaos with endless loads of washing, ironing and nappies.
'But being so busy means I ping back to a size 10 and I never have stretch marks.
'The only thing I hate is my small boobs. But I will rectify that soon.'

Share or comment on this article
11
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Burmese python slithering along 20ft high telephone line in Wales
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3152005/Locals-Welsh-village-huge-Burmese-python-slithering-20ft-high-telephone-line.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Worried neighbours watched from below as a Burmese python escaped its tank and managed to climb out of an upstairs window at its owner's house in Anglesey, North Wales.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
This is the skin-crawling moment a deadly python was spotted slithering along a 20ft high telephone line as worried neighbours watched on from below.
The Burmese python - one of the five largest snakes in the world and capable of constricting an adult to death -was seen making its bid for freedom above a quiet residential street.
Police say the snake escaped its tank and managed to climb out of an upstairs window  before precariously making its way along the telephone wire in Anglesey, North Wales.
Great snakes! A Burmese python - one of the five largest snakes in the world and capable of constricting an adult to death - was seen making its bid for freedom above a quiet residential street inAnglesey, North Wales
Escape: The deadly python was spotted slithering along a 20ft high telephone line as worried neighbours watched on from below.Police say the snake escaped its tank and climbed out of an upstairs window
It was caught on camera by Sergeant Rob Taylor,from North Wales Polices rural crime unit, who said the Asian python managed to make it across the wire to the opposite house and was halfway down the drainpipe before it was captured.
The pictures were taken in a village on the island in July last year, but were tweeted  as a reminder for owners to keep tanks secure as the weather heats up.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Spain's Running of the Bulls festival sees man sent flying and 11 people injured
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151849/Terrifying-moment-man-sent-flying-rampaging-bull-seven-people-rushed-hospital-day-Pamplona-festival.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	One of the runners was gored in the chest and six others injured during falls as they were chased down by the half-ton bulls in the streets of Pamplona in Spain.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>See the world through the eyes of someone with Asperger's
Revellers run with Jandilla's fighting bulls along the Calle Estafeta during the second day of the San Fermin Running Of The Bulls festival
Tuesday's run was the first of the eight morning runs that form the highlight of the annual festival  known as San Fermin in Spanish
The bulls took two minutes and 23 seconds to complete the course through the cobbled streets of Pamplona's old town
Fifteen people have been killed at the  festival, made famous by 1926 Ernest Hemingway novel The Sun Also Rises, since records began in 1911
Mowed down: A man is trampled during Tuesday's bull run. The most recent death was in 2009 when 27-year-old Daniel Jimeno, from Madrid, was gored in the neck by a bull called Capuchino
Participants run in front of Jandilla bulls during the fist 'encierro' (bull-run) of the San Fermin Festival
An injured runner gives a thumbs-up as he is attended by medical personnel after being gored by a ''Jandilla'' fighting bull at the festival
He is thought to have been hurt after a black bull grazed his chest with its horn near the famous Mercaderes corner on the 849-metre course.
Red Cross workers were pictured taking several bloodied runners away on stretchers.
A spokesman for the hospital complex said: 'We have one person who has been gored in the chest, who is stable and will be operated on.
'The others have suffered facial traumas or injuries to arms and legs.'
This morning's run was the first of the eight morning runs that form the highlight of the annual festival  known as San Fermin in Spanish.
The bulls took two minutes and 23 seconds to complete the course through the cobbled streets of Pamplona's old town.
Several foreigners, from Australians to Americans through to Brits and Irish, are normally among the injured
Virtually all the revellers wear red and white during the festival
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Alton Towers crash victims Leah Washington and Joe Pugh on 1st post-crash date
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151836/Alton-Towers-crash-survivors-Joe-Pugh-Leah-Washington-pictured-date-accident.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Joe Pugh, left and Leah Washington, right, enjoyed a romantic meal together in their first date since the 17-year-old Miss Washington was released from hospital following the horrific accident.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Earlier, Miss Washington, from Barnsley in South Yorkshire posed for a photograph with family and friends.
Miss Washington was on a first date with new boyfriend when their carriage - carrying 16 people - ploughed into the one in front.
Last month Miss Washington's brother, Luke, described how machines were 'keeping her going' while she was in intensive care.
Luke Washington said she was 'heavily sedated' when he visited her in hospital shortly after the crash.
Horrifying immediate aftermath of Smiler roller coaster accident
Leah Washington, 17, (left) had her left leg amputated above the knee shortly after the crash at Alton Towers
Surprise gift: Notorious British prisoner, who has earned himself the title of 'Britain's most violent prisoner', sent 17-year-old Leah a 'get well soon' card from Wakefield prison, where he is serving a life sentence
He told the BBC: 'She was in intensive care so she had machines keeping her going. It was only the day after they took her off that and she was back to breathing on her own.
'She had a rapid recovery. Each day has gone by and she has improved and improved.'
Speaking about his sister's condition at the time, Mr Washington said: 'Compared to last week when I got to hospital and saw her for the first time, it's a world of difference.
'It's amazing to see her. It was yesterday I walked into the room for the first time that day and she was stood up. To see her from the condition she was in to now being stood up is great.'
He added: 'We've all been there for Leah but she's the one who's kept us going. She's just done amazing.
'I don't know where she's got this strength from but it's really opened our eyes.'
Share or comment on this article
11
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date/>
        <title>
	4 Israeli teachers planning to travel to Syria to support ISIS are arrested
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151898/Four-teachers-planning-travel-Syria-arrested-supporting-ISIS-including-one-young-children-sing-Islamic-State-songs-praised-terror-group-class-Israeli-school.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Shin Bet security agency said the four detainees who worked at schools in Hura - a Bedouin township in the Negev desert - had been using their positions to radicalise students.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Four teachers planning to travel to Syria are arrested for supporting ISIS - including one who made young children sing Islamic State songs and praised the terror group in class at an Israeli school
Two primary and two secondary school teachers among six men arrested
Group are said to have been a pro-ISIS terror cell plotting to go to Syria
But while inIsraelthey forced jihadipropagandaon their young students
Taught them pro-ISIS songs and lavished praised on the sick terror group
Even used maps to teachterritory held by ISISis a legitimate nation state
Published: 08:56 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 10:53 GMT, 7 July 2015
46 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date/>
        <title>
	William Hague warns Greece debacle is a 'minor rehearsal' for coming Euro crash
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151947/This-BEGINNING-Euro-crisis-William-Hague-warns-Greece-debacle-minor-rehearsal-coming-crash.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Mr Hague, who quit politics at the election, said Greece had no chance of turning its economy around within the single currency unless Germany agreed to hand over big subsidies 'forever'.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
173 shares
Elderly Greeks queue up to collect their pensions outside a National Bank of Greece branch in Kotzia Square, Athens
Writing in the Daily Telegraph today, Mr Hague hit out at European leaders for pushing ahead with the single currency despite warnings that it would trap some countries in permanent recession.
In May 1998 Mr Hague used a speech to warn that some countries in the Euro would find themselves 'trapped in a burning building with no exits'.
The then Tory leader predicted 'wage cuts, tax hikes, and the creation of vicious unemployment blackspots'.
Speaking today Mr Hague said: 'I hope the Eurozone leaders meeting today will remember that those of us who criticised the euro at its creation were correct in our forecasts.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel exits her limousine as she arrives at the Chancellery in Berlin
'Otherwise they risk adding to the monumental errors of judgement, analysis and leadership made by their predecessors in 1998.'
Mr Hague said Germany will have to pay Greece 'big subsidies forever' to keep the currency together.
He said that even though the hard-left Syriza government has rejected 'reasonable terms' in return for a bailout the crisis is not the fault of the Greek people.
'Greeks have experienced the loss of one quarter of their entire national income, following an unsustainable inflation of spending and debt which Eurozone membership facilitated.
'The responsibility for this crisis lies with their own former leaders and those around the EU who gave them euro membership when they were not remotely suited to it, a triumph of political desire over dispassionate economic analysis for which ordinary people are now paying the price.
'It is no good now expecting Greeks to sit quietly in a burnt out room of the burning building I described seventeen years ago.'
He urged European leaders to accept that the problem in Greece 'is not a short term crisis, but a permanent one'.
He said the Greeks will not be able to turn round their economy in a 'lifetime' within the Eurozone.
He said: 'This is not because there is something wrong with them; it is because they live in a different economic environment from Germany, and one that is not suited to being in the same currency.
'In such circumstances, it is better to be able to leave sooner, with some generous support, than leave later with even greater resentment and failure.'
But Mr Hague warned the crisis could not be contained in Greece.
He said a 'final truth' was that the crisis 'is not just about one country'.
'Door for talks remains open': Merkel on Greece proposals
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande held crisis talks in Paris last night
Mr Hague warned: 'Across southern Europe, governments such as those in Italy and Spain are making brave efforts to enact long overdue reforms.
'They might not achieve enough, however, for their people to prosper when required to compete equally with their northern neighbours.
'There is a clear risk that the economic performance of the south will diverge from, not converge with, the north.
'Unless this is averted in the coming years, it will bring problems to Europe for which Greece has only been a minor rehearsal.
'In future decades, I believe students will sit down to study the folly of extending a single currency too far.
'Sad though it will be to see it, their textbook is likely to say that the Greek debacle of 2015 was not the end of the euro crisis, but its real beginning.'

Share or comment on this article
173
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Woman dies after Indian police 'set fire to her for failing to pay bribes'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151960/Woman-dies-Indian-police-douse-petrol-set-fire-failing-pay-bribes.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Two policemen have been suspended after Neetu Dwivedi,40, claimed she was ordered to pay a bribe. When she refused, she claimed the officers poured petrol over her body and set her alight.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Both police officers deny the dying woman's allegations. The two men claim that the woman deliberately set fire to herself in a frustrated act of self-immolation.
According to NDTV, the woman told a magistrate and several reporters before she died: 'No one helped me...They all watched.'
According to the dying woman's testimony, she allegedly said that the police officers humiliated her and set her on fire using petrol
'These people used to harass me often. They did it four times. The fifth time, they poured petrol over me and did this,'
Her husband, Ram Narain, told a different story: 'The police took me away and said a murder case had been lodged against me. They told my wife to get money and pick me up.
'I don't know how much they wanted. I was sitting outside when she ran out, engulfed in fire.
'I and some others tried to save her. These people must have set her on fire. Who else could have done it?'
Acccording to the BBC, Mrs Dwivedi was rushed to Lucknow hospital's Trauma Centre, suffering from 80% severe burns to her body. She died at 4am this morning.
The woman's horrific death comes less than a month after Indian journalist Jagender Singh died from severe burns in Shahjahanpur, Uttar Pradesh.
Mr Singh ran a popular facebook page, regularly publishing stories about alleged corruption and malpractice. The journalist's stories led to him suffering harassment from the police, his son claims.
In his dying statement, Jagender Singh claimed that four police officers raided his house and set fire to him. Singh accused state minister, Ram Murti Singh Verma, of setting him alight.
A murder investigation was launched and Verma and the four officers were charged with murder. 

Share or comment on this article
30
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Over 1,000 doctors convicted of sexual offences, drug dealing and fraud still practise in UK 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151764/More-1-000-doctors-convicted-sexual-offences-drug-dealing-fraud-allowed-practise-UK.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The new figures show that a total of 360 doctors currently on the General Medical Council register have been convicted of drink-driving. Others have been in court for fraud, assault and even sex offences.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
At present, doctors are obliged to advise the GMC if they are facing criminal prosecution. This may result in a Fitness to Practice hearing, where conditions may be placed on the doctor's ability to practice. In serious cases, they will be erased from the medical register, which means they can no longer legally practice medicine in the UK.
Roger Goss of Patient Concern told the Daily Mirror: 'They're supposed to protect the safety of patients. If they've been calling for this for so long, why have they not succeeded.'
However, Niall Dickson, chief executive of the GMC claimed some perspective was required when dealing with criminal convictions.
He said: 'We will always push for tough sanctions in response to serious convictions. A driving offence is one thing, a sexual offence is another.'
According to the figures, the most common offence committed by clinicians was drink-driving. There are currently 360 medics on the medical register with convictions for drink-driving.
Share or comment on this article
73
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Dragons' Den star Peter Jones says going to university 'is a waste of time'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151744/Going-university-waste-time-want-run-business-says-Dragons-Den-star-Peter-Jones.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Dragons' Den star Peter Jones,pictured, said would-be entrepreneurs are far better off skipping college because degree courses do not offer enough hands' on business experience.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Peter Jones, pictured, believes that potential business people are wasting their time in university due the lack of hands' on practical experience
Dragons' Den star Peter Jones has advised school leavers to abandon plans of attending university if they are planning to run their own businesses and instead sign up to his own enterprise academy.
The 49-year-old serial entrepreneur believes that hands-on experience is far more valuable to potential business leaders than several years studying theory in a lecture theatre.
Speaking in advance of the new series of the hit BBC2 show, Jones was highly critical about what was on offer inside the nation's universities.
He told the Daily Mirror: 'For entrepreneurs, university is a complete waste of time. You're not gaining any enterprise experience. To be a doctor you have to go through it. But for an entrepreneur? No.'
One of Jones' latest ventures is a chain of 36 academies across Britain where students study part-time, while still working, to learn about how to succeed in business.
He added: 'We've been brought up in this country to believe entrepreneurship can't be taught. That's absolute hogwash.'
Jones, and existing Dragon Deborah Meaden are joined by three new experts when the show returns on Sunday.
However, in interviews with the Radio Times Magazine, the new line-up - which features Touker Suleyman, Sarah Willingham and Nick Jenkins - refused to divulge any specifics on their personal fortunes.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="44">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Grizzly bear shatters barrier with basketball-sized rock at Minnesota Zoo
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151485/Grizzly-bear-shatters-barrier-Minnesota-Zoo.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Startled visitors stood on the other side of the barrier as the bear repeatedly slammed the rock into a pane of glass at the Minnesota Zoo on Monday morning but luckily no one was hurt
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Grizzly bear picks up a 50lb rock and tries to smash the glass of his zoo enclosure with repeated blows as startled visitors watch
The animal picked up the rock and slammed onto a pane of glass at the Minnesota Zoo on Monday morning
No one was hurt and the five-layer pane stayed in place 'like a windshield', zoo manager said
Visitor present during incident said rock had to weigh 50 pounds
The grizzly bear exhibit is now temporarily closed
Published: 20:25 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 10:19 GMT, 7 July 2015
2.7k shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="45">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Toddlers cared for by their families have stronger language skills...but those left in crèches are better with their hands
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-3151957/Toddlers-cared-families-stronger-language-skills-left-cr-ches-better-hands.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Researchers at Maynooth University showed language skills are the only area in which children who are cared for by their own extended family outperformed others by the age of three.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>54
shares
Toddlers cared for by their families have stronger language skills...but those left in crches are better with their hands
Study  used data taken from Ireland's national longitudinal study of children
Researchersfoundbabies in centre-based care have better motor skills such as hand-eye coordination than those at home
While language skills were the only area in which children who are cared for by their own extended family outperformed others by the age of three
This suggests that a mixture of childcare is ideal for pre-school infants
Published: 10:06 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 10:07 GMT, 7 July 2015
54 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="46">
        <date/>
        <title>
	The Wodaabe wife-stealing festival where men dress up to take each other's women
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3149684/The-Wodaabe-wife-stealing-festival-Stunning-images-world-s-vainest-tribe-men-dress-s-women-women-husbands-please.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The polygamous Wodaabe tribe stage the Gerewol festival where men dance for the women hoping to steal one as a wife. The women who choose the men can have a number of husbands
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
The Wodaabe wife-stealing festival: Stunning images from the world's vainest tribe where men dress up to take each other's women - and the women have as many husbands as they please
Wodaabe tribe men put on a spectacular show to impress the tribe's women who can take them as their husband
The put on a mating dance in the hope of stealing another man's husband, but the women have all the power
The tribe's women can have sex with whoever they want before they are married and have have numerous husbands
Wodaabe are the world's vainest people and believe they are the best-looking. Men are rarely found without a mirror
Published: 07:09 GMT, 7 July 2015 | Updated: 09:57 GMT, 7 July 2015
166 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="47">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Tory MP Johnny Mercer poses naked in the shower for Dove TV advert in USA
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151984/That-s-ONE-way-clean-politics-New-Tory-MP-poses-naked-shower-racy-TV-advert-aired-America.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	New Conservative MP and former Army captain Johnny Mercer has caused a splash after he was spotted half naked - in an advert for shower gel on American TV.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The new Plymouth MP shot the advert in London before he was elected but after he was chosen to contest the parliamentary seat for Plymouth Moor View in Devon
Mr Mercer had to prepare for the role by shaving his chest and spent hours in the shower to enable camera crews to capture the best footage
In addition to the shower scene Johnny, 38, is seen showing off his strength with his six-year-old daughter Amalie
Mr Mercer said the shoot was 'really fun', adding: 'They sent me and the girls to London for three days.
'Unfortunately, I think it might be the first in a series of adverts but we'll have to wait and see. Hopefully it will be forgotten about quickly.'
After he was nominated to stand for election, the couple got wind that Dove Men were looking to film an advert with an ex-military family and, after being put forward by a friend, decided to make a 'spoof' family video to send onto the marketing agency.
The agency liked what they saw and invited them to London for the shoot.
Even though the clip currently airing on TV in America is only 15 seconds long, wife Felicity Mercer said her daughter and husband shot hours of footage during February half-term in 2014.
She said: 'They made him shave his chest for the shower scene so he spent the week itching which I don't think he enjoyed.
'He had to spend hours in the shower but he was dressed from the waist down, which obviously you can't see.'
Johnny Mercer (pictured, left, celebrating with his wife Felicity after being elected as a Tory MP) served as a captain in the army before entering Parliament (right)
Watch Johnny Mercer rousing maiden speech in full
Mrs Mercer added: 'It was just something really nice for him and Amalie to do together while me and Joey [their youngest daughter] stood by watching the shooting and editing.
'They really enjoyed it. I don't think Amalie really understood what she was doing until she saw the finished product recently.
'To be honest, once the election campaign kicked-off we didn't think much about the advert but then we received a notification telling us it was on in the States.
'It was an amazing experience and we hadn't done anything like that before.
'I'm really proud of him because it was a father and daughter thing that they shared and I think it was really special.'
Share or comment on this article
11
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="48">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Thai police arrest butchers transporting more than 100 DOG carcasses
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151884/Butchers-caught-transporting-100-DOG-carcasses-arrested-pulled-animal-meat-truck-Thailand.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The consumption of dog and cat meat is outlawed under the Contagious Diseases Act, which deems the meat unsafe due to the risk of fatal diseases like rabies.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Although there is little scientific proof that dog meat is sufficiently better for the human diet, dog meat remains particularly popular with some people from Thailand's ethnic Vietnamese community, predominantly found in rural areas of the country.
In recent years, there has been a crackdown on the dog meat trade in Thailand, leading smugglers to adopt new strategy to bypass the police.
Undercover investigators witnessed the scene, where over 100 dog carcasses were discovered
The dog's skins are usually removed and sold separately. The skin is sometimes used to make golf gloves
Dog traders have previously used the legal dog meat trade in Vietnam, transporting their cargo from Thailand, via Laos, to Vietnam
Dog meat can be found on sale in more rural parts of Thailand despite the recent crackdowns on the trade
Police used to be able to follow the barks of the distressed dogs and track down the delivery lorries, often heading via Laos to Vietnam, where dog meat is legal.
Following a rise in new arrests, smugglers have started to slaughter dogs before throwing the skinned carcasses into a lorry and transporting the sickening delivery late at night to avoid detection.
Dog skin has been known to be made into items like golf gloves in countries like Vietnam.
Dog meat traders traditionally used to transport the dogs alive, cramping up to 10 dogs into cages, leading to many dogs dying from suffocation and dehydration.
The live transportation of dogs was done in the belief that when the dogs arrived at the market and were slaughtered, the meat would be more tender.
The majority of Thai civilians are avid dog lovers, with only a small proportion of people favouring dog meat
Stray dogs and aggressive dogs are often snatched or sold to dog meat traders
Police are finding it harder to track down dog meat smugglers, having previously been able to follow the sound of a dog bark. Now smugglers have turned to slaughtering and transporting their cruel cargo at night
Two laws have been introduced to crackdown on the dog meat trade in Thailand.
Thailand'sNational Legislative Assembly (NLA) passed the country's first Animal Welfare Law in December 2014, voted in by 188-1, with four members abstaining from the vote.
The landmark law now means that it is a legal requirement for animal owners to provide suitable facilities and care for their animals.
According to the Bangkok Post, the first major arrest under the Animal Welfare Law, came on 29 December inTueng district, Chiang Rai province.
The Contagious Diseases Act has also been introduced, designed to outlaw the consumption of dog meat. Under the Act, dog meat can lead to a fine of up to10,000 baht (189), a large amount for a poor family in rural Thailand.
The Act was passed to clamp down on the dog meat trade as well as reduce the spread of rabies through a crackdown on the transportation of live dogs in and across the country's border.
Share or comment on this article
27
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="49">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Kevin Blair's honest ad for Ford Fiesta sells rusty and stinky old car for £100
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151905/Horrendous-rusty-car-stinks-mackerel-failed-MOT-offered-sale-hilariously-honest-online-advert-SELLS-100.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Kevin Blair, 37, advertised his 2002 Ford Fiesta on a community website in the village of Errol, Perthshire, Scotland. He still sold it for £100 despite its flaws - which was £10 above the asking price.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
'There was no point in lying - the car was rubbish.
'I didn't expect to have people wanting to buy it - I got a private message offering me 100 so I accepted it right away. Then someone offered 120 but it had already gone - I was kicking myself.'
In his ad on the Errol Village Facebook page, Mr Blair wrote: 'This is my horrendous car, it could be yours!
Sold: He said he was also surprised by the reaction to his advert. One person offered him 100, before another made the offer of 120. The advert had been posted on the Errol Village Facebook page
'MOT failure - brake pads, burst coil spring, a few wee other things. It runs fine, but there is a leak underneath that wasn't picked up in the test, not sure where it's coming from.
'It's all over the road in Church Lane which will be cleaned up once the car is gone, I promise, for any residents who may be reading this.
There was no point in lying - the car was rubbish
Kevin Blair
'I'll level with you, it's s**** - all rusted and stinks of mackerel. I eat a lot of mackerel.
'Decent stereo, but I'm keeping that.
'I can get 90 at the scrappies for it so if (you) offer me more, you can have it.
'Dunno why you'd want it to be honest, maybe a project, just thought I'd ask, eh.'
Mr Blair bought the car for 300 five months ago, but decided to sell it following the MOT failure.
He said he was also surprised by the reaction to his advert.
'There was about 50 likes on Facebook,' he said. 'I had messages asking me if it was for real or if I was having a laugh. A lot of people seemed to enjoy the ad.'
Share or comment on this article
114
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="50">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Migrant found dead in Channel Tunnel after Eurotunnel terminal is invaded by refugees
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151888/Migrant-dead-Channel-Tunnel-Eurotunnel-terminal-invaded-latest-bid-reach-Britain.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Freight traffic was being disrupted but there were also delays to passenger services following the intrusion near Calais in the early hours of the morning, Channel tunnel operator Eurotunnel said.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The alarm was raised at the Eurotunnel terminal in France in the early hours causing a partial closure of the tunnel.
Kent Police said delays were building around junction 11a of the M20, where lorries are queued as part of Operation Stack when cross-Channel services hit disruption.
The migrant crisis in Calais has escalated in recent months, with around 3,000 people displaced from countries including Eritrea, Syria and Afghanistan setting up camp near the port.
Last week, more than 3,000 truckers had to queue for several days in high temperatures on the M20 following a wildcat strike by ferry workers in France.
Migrants storm lorry on Channel Tunnel in Calais
Freight traffic was being disrupted but there were also delays to passenger services following the intrusion near Calais in the early hours of the morning, Channel tunnel operator Eurotunnel said (file picture)
Industrial action by ferry workers this summer has come on top of the problems faced by hauliers with migrants desperately trying to clamber on board their HGVs to the UK.
French authorities have faced claims they are not doing enough to safeguard lorry drivers from intimidation, violence and attempts by migrants to climb on.
The Road Haulage Association (RHA) has suggested deployment of the French military to boost security in Calais amid fears that a fatality could occur.
The Fresh Produce Consortium estimates that 10 million of fresh fruit and vegetables have been thrown away since the start of the year as a result of the problems in Calais.
And Port of Dover officials said last week's ferry strike cost the UK economy 1billion.
They have joined calls for 'robust contingency plans' to be introduced to ensure the port  a 100 billion trade route  can work unimpeded by others.
Home Secretary Theresa May and her French counterpart Bernard Cazeneuve last week agreed to increase the joint intervention fund to improve security around the port and the Channel Tunnel.
French aid workers have reported a 'catastrophic' situation, with predictions that 2,000 more migrants could arrive over the summer at the camp, dubbed Jungle II.
Volunteers from L'Auberge Des Migrants say up to 50 new migrants are arriving every day at the camp, and there are not enough tents, blankets or food.
Dover Conservative MP Charlie Elphicke has said the problems underlined the need to consider expanding the port at Dunkirk, 45 miles from Calais.
Share or comment on this article
78
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="51">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Malaria cure breakthrough targets key protein 'to kill the parasite'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-3151906/Malaria-breakthrough-Targeting-key-protein-kills-parasite-stops-disease-paving-way-new-treatments.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Scientists from the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine found by preventing the protein kinase from working, the malaria parasite was killed and the disease stopped in its tracks.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
27 shares
The researchers used state-of-the-art methods to dissect the  pathways involved in keeping the malaria parasite alive.
They used an approach called chemical genetics, where synthetic chemicals are used in combination with introducing genetic changes to the DNA of the parasite.
This is a real breakthrough in our understanding of how malaria survives in the blood stream and invades red blood cells
Professor Andrew Tobin

They found that one protein kinase, PfPKG, plays a central role in various pathways that allow the parasite to survive in the blood.
They explained that understanding the pathways the parasite uses means that future drugs could be precisely designed to kill the parasite.
This could be done with limited toxicity, making them safe enough to be used by children and pregnant women.
Study co-lead author Professor Andrew Tobin, from the MRC Toxicology Unit at Leicester University, said: 'This is a real breakthrough in our understanding of how malaria survives in the blood stream and invades red blood cells.
'We've revealed a process that allows this to happen and if it can be targeted by drugs we could see something that stops malaria in its tracks without causing toxic side-effects.'
Professor David Baker, of the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, said: 'It is a great advantage in drug discovery research if you know the identity of the molecular target of a particular drug and the consequences of blocking its function.
'It helps in designing the most effective combination treatments and also helps to avoid drug resistance which is a major problem in the control of malaria worldwide.'
Malaria is caused by a parasite that lives inside an infected mosquito and is transferred into humans through bites. Pictured is a female mosquito engorged with human blood
Malaria currently infects more than 200 million people worldwide and accounts for more than 500,000 deaths per year, according to the World Health Organisation.
Professor Patrick Maxwell, chair of the MRC's Molecular and Cellular Medicine Board, said: 'Tackling malaria is a global challenge, with the parasite continually working to find ways to survive our drug treatments.
'By combining a number of techniques to piece together how the malaria parasite survives, this study opens the door on potential new treatments that could find and exploit the disease's weak spots but with limited side-effects for patients.'
The findings were published in the journal Nature Communications.

Share or comment on this article
27
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="52">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Joshua Harrison-Jones dies after being strangled by onesie during workout
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151848/Teenage-fitness-fanatic-16-throttled-death-ONESIE-using-makeshift-resistance-band-workout.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Joshua Harrison-Jones (pictured) tied the nightwear to an exercise bench and was using it to left weights during a late-night workout session at his home in Stretford, Greater Manchester.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
She told the inquest: 'My daughter had got her iPad and tried to get in touch with various family members to tell them something was wrong with her brother.
'I finished work at 11pm and my mother was due to pick me up, I had missed phone calls and when I tried to ring back they didn't answer.
Bright future: Joshua, pictured, was described by his family as 'very positive and inspirational'
'I then got a call from my brother who told me to come home, he told me Joshua had been in an accident.
'I started panicking and running home but the police came and picked me up. As I arrived home it became apparent that something very bad was occurring.
'Joshua could be socially awkward but he was absolutely normal in every sense of the word. He was very into physical fitness and we got him a training machine which he put up in his bedroom.
'I had never watched him train upstairs but he had fixed a onesie on there. My daughter said he did it all the time.
'Reflecting back to when I told his friends how he died, they knew what I meant straight away and said it was not an uncommon thing for him to do.'
Joshua's grandmother Karen Harrison told the hearing: 'He was very sensitive to other people's feelings, he was hardworking and a loving child. He was bright, funny and we had a giggle.
'On the day it happened he was chatting away about athletic things and how excited he was about going seeing other universities. We had a really good day.
'I spoke to him at 9.30pm because he was worried about his mum getting home on her own so I rung him to tell him I would go and pick her up. I had no concerns, he was laughing at me for ringing him.
'It was about 10:30pm I got the call. We all arrived at the same time and I went into Joshua's room and we all tried to help him before the paramedics arrived.
'He never expressed any views to me about wanting to harm himself. He ate like a horse every day and you couldn't feed him enough.'
Emma Armitage, learning support and safeguarding manager at Salford City College said: 'He was known to the sports department, he impressed us all and stayed beyond the time he was supposed to, he was very helpful as well. There was not a problem with his understanding of it at all. He was the model student.
'He was able to make his classmates laugh with his unique sense of humour. He wanted to learn, not just about the physical but the psychological too.
'He was definitely working towards a distinction grade. He was very friendly, very bubbly and from the start he told me he was going to get an A. He was on track.
On track: The schoolboy, pictured right and left with his mother, who was studying for an A Level in sports psychology at Salford City College, had his 'future mapped out' and was planning on visiting universities
'He was confident and wanted to do well, he said to me 'I'm going to achieve the best results ever at college'
'He never seemed to be a pupil who was a danger to anybody and there was nothing negative recorded about him at all. He was the staff's pupil but he was also considered a friend.'
Det Insp Cheryl Hughes of Greater Manchester Police said: 'We investigated the background issues and there was nothing at all that caused any concerns. His bedroom was quite messy - but it was a typical teenager's bedroom.'
'I saw the exercise frame, there was a onesie tied to it and nothing else on the machine. We made some enquiries as to why it was there, we looked into it to see if we could see any evidence on the internet and saw that this could be used as a resistance band.That is something they do with things that can create that resistance.'
He was definitely working towards a distinction grade. He was very friendly, very bubbly and from the start he told me he was going to get an A. He was on track
Emma Armitage, Salford City College
Recording a verdict of accidental death Stockport coroner John Pollard said: 'I think it was an accident and I think he lost consciousness very quickly.
'If this was intentional then messages on Facebook and other social media would have probably been found but there was nothing. No one was concerned about him and he was a model student. I rule out a deliberate intention.'
In a statement after the hearing, Joshua's family said: 'Joshua was a very positive, inspirational, bright young person, who strived for perfection in everything he set out to achieve. A warm, caring and witty individual, Joshua easily endeared himself to everyone he encountered.'
'His tenacity for life, the dedication showed, both in his academic achievements and his love for athletics meant that he very much had the world at his feet and was there for the taking.'
'This Summer Joshua wanted to visit various universities, as in his mind his future was mapped out.
'Joshua was well liked and respected amongst his peers, friends and tutors; all of which are devastated by his tragic passing.'
'As a family we are absolutely devastated by this loss. He was a wonderful son, brother, grandson, nephew and cousin and his absence is felt every day.
'It is both every parents, and families worst nightmare, and we struggle daily to move forward from this.'
'There is absolutely no doubt in our minds that Joshua's death was nothing more than a tragic accident. Joshua striving once again for physical excellence, with devastating consequences.'
Share or comment on this article
21
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="53">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Vienna brothels report boom in business when Iran nuclear delegates are in town
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3150157/Iran-nuclear-talks-Brothels-bike-rides-Groundhog-Day.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	As the manager of a local brothel said, when the
Iran talks are in town, 'business is booming'. He declined to say who were his most frequent customers were, however.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Vienna's Palais Coburg hotel, a 19th-century palace, has hosted most rounds of the talks since February 2014, and for all that time rumours have circulated about a network of underground tunnels connecting it to brothels and other establishments.
One Western diplomat said they could be just Iran-talks folklore inspired by Carol Reed's classic 1949 film noir 'The Third Man', which features a chase scene through Vienna's sewer system.
Some negotiators opt for a different kind of leisure activity anyway. One took a day off from haggling over uranium centrifuges and the legal technicalities of U.N. inspections to cycle 70 km along the Danube River - seemingly undeterred by the bicycle crash that put U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry on crutches in May, the day after a nuclear meeting with Iran's foreign minister in Geneva.
At work: German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier, Foreign Minister of France Laurent Fabius, and  Foreign Minister of the People's Republic of China Wang Yi converse during the nuclear talks yesterday
Other diplomats shed their business attire and enjoyed a splash in the public pools.
But their impatience is clear. 'These talks have become obsessional,' said one. 'I'd quite like to do something else now. It's enough to make you go crazy.'
Like the food, for instance. Luxury hotel or not, after 10 days of the same lunch buffet, it starts to get repetitive; the Iranian delegation has taken to bringing in main courses from a local Persian restaurant.
Keeping busy: Foreign Affairs Minister of Iran Mohammad Javad Zarif attends the talks yesterday
The talks were supposed to finish by June 30 but, days before the deadline, one delegation was already joking in a beer garden in Vienna's 'Stadtpark' about 'Groundhog Day', the 1993 film about a man who relives the same day over and over again. Sure enough, the talks were extended by another week.
With energy needing to be saved for the long haul, the closest local DIY and garden store rapidly sold out of folding picnic chairs, which have become essential equipment for reporters staking out the talks.
As daytime temperatures have soared towards 40 Celsius (104 Fahrenheit), keeping cool can be difficult.
Many television crews and photographers and a few correspondents are decked out in shorts and t-shirts and, in an attempt to cool the tempers of grumpy reporters, the Austrian Foreign Ministry has been supplying free ice cream.
At least once a day, a ministry employee wheels a cart full of lollies and cones into the media tent, calling out 'Achtung, attention please!' to get the journalists with their laptops to clear a space - before the predictable scrum empties the cart of all but a few unpopular varieties.
But that's still not enough to get some of the reporters through their day.
'I've run out of words,' said a French-language reporter. 'I used my last ounce of strength &#127;to do a story this morning. How many different ways can you say 'inched towards a deal'?'
For an Italian journalist in the tent, where temperatures soared above 40 Celsius after the air conditioning broke down, it was all too much.
Power: U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry (second left) and British Foreign Secretary Phillip Hammond (third left) attends the nuclear talks between the E3+3 group and Iran in Vienna yesterday
John Kerry: Iran nuclear talks could go either way
'You're an idiot!' he screamed down the phone to his editor, 'A moron! A moron! A moron!' And then he hung up.
One local reporter suggested to his foreign minister that keeping foreign correspondents cooped up in a stifling tent might be encouraging them to send home the wrong message about Austrian hospitality.
The minister, fresh-faced 28-year-old Sebastian Kurz, took the warning to heart and invited foreign reporters to Sunday brunch at his ministry, rather improbably making peace among nations in the process.
Iranian reporters came along - even though some of them were unable to enjoy the Viennese pastries because they were fasting for the holy month of Ramadan - and quickly found themselves rubbing shoulders with Israeli journalists, abandoning their usual reciprocal frostiness in the rush to get a 'selfie' with the minister.
Share or comment on this article
44
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="54">
        <date/>
        <title>
	NutriBullet smoothie blender 'explodes as Tysha Stapleton suffers horrific burns'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151930/Mother-one-suffers-horrific-burns-NutriBullet-kitchen-smoothie-blender-explodes-face.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Tysha Stapleton, from South London, claims she suffered second degree burns when her NutriBullet gadget blasted open, and erupted scalding juice across her face, neck and chest.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
She said:'It isn't supposed to be hot but it must have heated up on its own and exploded.
'The pain was horrific. I could feel my skin burning. I thought I was blind.
NutriBullet said they would not comment until it had been inspected.It added: 'We ensure the very highest quality standards are adhered to'
'I could see the skin on my eyelid hanging down. My skin was melting off my face. It was unbearable.'
She said the accident has left her looking like a monster.
NutriBullet said they would not comment until after it had been investigated.
It added: 'We ensure the very highest quality standards are adhered to.'
According to Royal insiders, the Nutribullet is the Duchess of Cambridge's 'secret weapon' for staying in shape.
So it's no surprise that smoothie-maker the NutriBullet has become a must-have device.
The gadget, which pulverises fruit, vegetables, nuts and seeds, is known as an 'extractor' rather than a juicer or blender, due to its unique high-powered blade action.
It's this, manufacturers say, which is the key to retaining the nutritional content in your smoothie.

Share or comment on this article
54
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="55">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Zoella breaks sales records with new Tutti Fruity range for Superdrug
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3151855/Zoella-breaks-sales-records-new-beauty-range-Superdrug.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The 25-year-old's Tutti Fruity range - a collection of bath products - launched at midnight on Superdrug's website and was an instant hit with hundreds of products selling overnight.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
This brings the Zoella beauty range, which she launched last year, to 14 products - and they're all sold in Superdrug alongside big name brands such as Nivea, Head &amp; Shoulders and Vaseline.
The 25-year-old's Tutti Fruity range - a collection of bath products - launched at midnight on Superdrug's website and was an instant hit with hundreds of products selling overnight
Zoella's latest range - the second drop in her beauty collection - consists of purse-friendly bath products such as Candy Cream lotion, 5, Fresh Fizz Bar, 5, and Foam Sweet Foam, 3.50
Excited fans meet YouTuber Zoella at Superdrug beauty launch
A spokesperson for the high street giant said: 'The first Zoella range was successful but this new collection has taken her to the next level.
'This isnt a one-off range from a beauty blogger, but a truly excellent collection from a brand which is trusted by her teenage fan base.
'Zoe has built up an enormous fan base who trust her implicitly, they know that she wouldnt design a product she wouldnt want to use herself.'
Zoe Sugg aka Zoella is pictured at the launch of her debut beauty collection last year, which was attended by Jamie Oliver (whose children are huge fans of the star)
Zoella became the fastest-selling debut novelist since records began, outselling the likes of JK Rowling and Dan Brown at the end of last year
Seven million subs and 12m hits a month: Meet Zoella
Miss Sugg grew up in Lacock, Wiltshire, the daughter of a beautician mother and a property developer father.
She started her channel in 2009 and it quickly became her full-time job, with more than 12 million hits on her vlogs per month.
Miss Sugg now charges 20,000 a month to advertisers who want to place products alongside her fashion tips.
She has also been signed by Radio 1, is the charity Minds digital ambassador and was selected, along with brother Joe and boyfriend Alfie, to take part in Bob Geldofs re-release of the Band Aid single.
Zoella became the fastest-selling debut novelist since records began with her tome, Girl Online, outselling the likes of JK Rowling and Dan Brown at the end of last year.
Miss Suggs also starred on the BBC's Comic Relief Bake Off special alongside celebrity contestants Gok Wan, Jonathan Ross and Abbey Clancy.
The youngest contestant by some distance said: 'I was genuinely a little bit shocked and very excited when I was asked to take part.
This is by no means Zoella's only success this month. Just a few weeks ago, Australian teen magazine Dolly also opted to place YouTube 'vlogging' superstar Zoella on their cover.
Miss Sugg grew up in Lacock, Wiltshire, the daughter of a beautician mother and a property developer father. Her boyfriend Alfie Deyes, pictured, is also a hugely successful YouTube star

Share or comment on this article
102
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="56">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Greece's horror show wouldn't be happening if Europe listened by PETER OBORNE
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-3151687/PETER-OBORNE-Greek-horror-wouldn-t-happening-Europe-listened-Maggie.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Sunday marked a turning point in the history of post-war Europe — the moment when the euro began its inevitable collapse, and the European project itself started to disintegrate, writes PETER OBORNE.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Sunday marked a turning point in the history of post-war Europe  the moment when the euro began its inevitable collapse, and the European project itself started to disintegrate.
The Greek no vote restricts European Central Bank President Mario Draghi and the laughably incompetent European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker to two options, both of them nightmarish.
They can either allow Greece to impose its own terms for staying in the euro and abandon the EU-imposed austerity policies that have destroyed the national economy, or force Greece to abandon the euro and go back to its own currency.
Scroll down for video
Sunday's 'no' vote marked the moment when the euro began its inevitable collapse
Lets examine the first of those two gruesome scenarios, and suppose that President Juncker and the ECB permit Prime Minister Tsipras  now enormously strengthened as a consequence of his bold decision to hold the national referendum  to loosen the national purse strings.
Immediately, Spain, Portugal, Italy, France, Cyprus  and all the other southern European states whose economies have been devastated by eurozone membership  would demand equal treatment. They, too, would insist on debt relief and the end of economic austerity.
Chaos
This in turn would cause chaos right across the Continent. In particular, Germany, the economic dynamo of the EU, could never allow the consequent explosion of spending.
German voters are already furious that, thanks to the eurozone, they are expected to finance what they view as the worthless lifestyles of corrupt Greek businessmen and bone idle Greek workers.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel is renowned for near magical powers. She is the most powerful politician in Europe today. Yet even she could never convince her voters to pay for sweetheart deals for the rest of Europe.
So lets now examine the second and more likely scenario. What would happen if the Greeks demands for a relaxation of austerity measures were rebuffed by the ECB, and the country was forced into what was, until recently, unthinkable  a return to the drachma, established as the national currency after Greece achieved its independence from the Ottoman Empire in 1832?
The rejection by the Greek people of austerity measures demanded by international creditors proves once and for all the hubristic folly of Europes one-size-fits-all single currency
Drone captures thousands celebrating 'no' vote in Athens
The re-emergence of the drachma would take the EU into new and terrifying territory. All Greek banks are bankrupt anyway, and only kept afloat by European support. In the absence of that support, they would immediately collapse.
Greek economic production  already down by 25 per cent since 2010  would fall even further. The Greek unemployment rate, now at a frightening 25.6 per cent, would surge.
Mr Juncker and his fellow commissioners in Brussels would be only human if they half hoped the consequences of leaving the euro would lock Greece in penury for ever.
It would help their cause of European unity if they could hold out Greece as a dreadful example of the punishment awaiting any country that was impertinent enough not to do what it was told by Europe.
In my view, however, there is a more optimistic scenario: that the country would start to recover after a period of chaos. The drachma would depreciate precipitously, making Greece far more competitive than countries still stuck in the eurozone. Tourism, for example, would boom because holidays in Greece would be so much cheaper.
Leaving the euro would certainly bring immense uncertainty to an already chaotic Greece. But at least with its own national bank, Greece could set its own interest rates and make its own spending decisions. No longer under the control of Brussels commissars and foreign bankers, the economy in time would have a fighting chance of flourishing once again.
The re-emergence of the drachma would take the EU into new and terrifying territory. Pictured is a group of 'no' campaigners
Shackles
Crucially, this was the experience of Argentina after its national currency, the peso, sensationally decoupled from the U.S. dollar in 2002.
The economy grew at an amazing annual rate of 9 per cent between 2003 and 2007.
It would, of course, be a total disaster for the European project if Greece, freed from the shackles of the euro, mirrored Argentinas success. Rival European states stuck inside the stagnating eurozone would study the Greek economy at first with disbelief, then amazement and finally with envy. Then, one by one, they would follow the example of Greece and break away from the eurozone.
Perhaps I am being too optimistic. There is no denying that an unpredictable period lies ahead. Indeed, Europe could be about to enter possibly the most dangerous time since the Thirties, when it witnessed the rise of fascism in Germany, Italy and elsewhere.
Already it is being convulsed by some of the same problems: mass unemployment, economic degradation, out-of-touch elites and the consequent rise of extremist political parties, both on the far Left and the far Right.
This is also a very sobering moment for Britain. Europe is our largest market, and the economic consequences for us will be desperate indeed as the eurozone enters a vortex of decline.
It would, of course, have been much worse had Britain joined the euro when it was started  and there is an enormous irony here. The idea of European monetary union, i.e. a single currency, was first seriously discussed at the Rome summit of the EU in 1990, almost 25 years ago.
Margaret Thatcher was then the British Prime Minister, and she spoke out defiantly against French President Mitterrand and German Chancellor Cole as they bulldozed their pet concept through.
Margaret Thatchers act of lonely but heroic defiance towards the proposed single currency led directly to her downfall
Margaret Thatchers act of lonely but heroic defiance led directly to her downfall. Her opposition to the single currency provoked the resignation of Geoffrey Howe from the Cabinet, and then the leadership challenge of Michael Heseltine, forcing her resignation within weeks.
Today, however, Margaret Thatchers last stand looks nothing less than prophetic (and Howe and Heseltines roles appear beneath contempt).
Had other European states listened to her warnings, the Continent would be a very different, less dangerous, more prosperous and much happier place today. Back in the Nineties, Mrs Thatchers enemies, both in Britain and on the Continent, dismissed what she had to say as shrill and bigoted.
In fact, her analysis was compassionate and profound. Unlike almost everybody else, she understood that it was impossible to have a single currency without a single country as well. This is because a single currency requires the same borrowing and spending policies  and therefore an unchallenged political legitimacy  right across the single-currency area.
Tragically, European leaders refused to believe these warnings. They were determined, at whatever human cost, to create a federal Europe and obliterate national boundaries.
This explains their otherwise lunatic decision to impose a single currency across 19 different countries, each with its own history, set of institutions and special economic characteristics.
The British politicians who encouraged this demented project  including Heseltine, Howe, Blair and Kinnock  should hang their heads in shame.
Bullies
They, too, bear their full share of responsibility for an economic and political experiment which has driven tens of millions of people out of work, and destroyed the economies of not just regions, but of entire countries.
The critics of Alexis Tsipras say that he is a deranged Marxist academic. Perhaps. Compared to Juncker or his predecessor Jacques Delors, or even President Mitterrand and Merkel with their obsessive attachment to the euro, he is a model of common sense and sanity.
Marxist or not, his courage stands in a direct line of succession to that of Margaret Thatcher 25 years ago. Like Thatcher, Tsipras has been patriotic and bloody-minded enough to stand up for his own people against the bullies of the European Union.
Terrible risks lie ahead, but he has already achieved something extraordinary. The idea of democracy was invented in Greece 2,500 years ago. Thanks to him, democracy inside the eurozone, snuffed out by the single currency, was reborn in Greece on Sunday.
We in Britain must give Mr Tsipras all the help and support we can as he sculpts a fresh future for his famous and wonderful country  and, let us all hope and pray, saves the continent of Europe in the process.
Share or comment on this article
886
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="57">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Jeremy Clarkson, James May and Richard Hammond blocked from appearing on ITV Top Gear rival for two years
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151731/Jeremy-Clarkson-James-Richard-Hammond-blocked-appearing-ITV-Gear-rival-two-years.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Former Top Gear hosts Jeremy Clarkson, James May and Richard Hammond have been blocked from immediately appearing on a rival motoring show on ITV by their former BBC contracts.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
A TV source told the Daily Mirror: 'Basically they could make a show for ITV, but not one about cars. A clause stops them leaving and making a rival.
'It means Netflix or Amazon are favourites to sign up the team. There is a feeling that if they wait two years it gives Chris Evans a chance to steal a march on them and get his new Top Gear show up and running, which means he would be settled in by then.
'It's a difficult decision but they hope to make up their minds soon after a number of meetings. ITV have made them a great offer.'
The trio met with senior ITV official Peter Fincham in London along with former Top Gear executive producer Andy Wilman to discuss the contract issue.
The BBC has appointed Chris Evans, left, to replace Jeremy Clarkson, right, as Top Gear's main presenter
The final episode of Top Gear featuring Clarkson, May and Hammond had almost six million viewers
The BBC ditched Clarkson following an incident in March involving a Top Gear producer.
However, the BBC could be left extremely embarrassed by their decision to ditch Clarkson.
The last episode, which featured two previously un-broadcast films was watched by 5.8 million people, with many more tuning in later on BBC iPlayer.
The long-running TV show has also been nominated for best entertainment show at the 2015 TV Choice Awards, along with Ant and Dec, ITV 2's Celebrity Juice and The Graham Norton Show.
TV Choice and Total TV Guide's editor-in-chief Jon Peake said: 'Top Gear is a big hit with our readers. Ant and Dec are also very popular and can do no wrong with our readers absolutely adoring them, so coming head-to-head with Ant and Dec could mean it's a fight to the death.'
Lenny Henry will host the TV Choice Awards, which take place at the London Hilton Park Lane hotel on September 7.
Share or comment on this article
367
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="58">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Emma Murphy posts emotional domestic violence video with black eye from ex-lover
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-3151853/Mother-two-left-black-eye-punched-ex-lover-posts-emotional-video-domestic-violence-torture.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	In a video viewed more than two million times in just 15 hours, Emma Murphy, 26, fitness blogger from Dublin, Ireland, claims she was hit  after confronting an ex-boyfriend about cheating.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
She adds: 'For the last year and a half, Ive been told that Im paranoid, Im a psycho, Im nuts, my insecurities will kill me one day.'
Ms Murphy says she was attacked because she confronted her former partner about an affair, after the other woman contacted her in November admitting she was pregnant.
Ms Murphy was pregnant herself at the time and says she went into labour early as a result of the stress, after which her world 'turned upside down'.
Ms Murphy chokes back tears as she describes how her ex-boyfriend and the father of her children punched her in the face after she confronted him about cheating on her
'He was the love of my life,' Ms Murphy says of their three-year relationship, adding that the recent attack was 'not the first time'
The blonde mother, whose children, a boy and a girl, are both under the age of three, explains that it took until now to realise the violence she claims she was enduring was unacceptable.
'I finally realised that no, this is not acceptable,' she says. 'No man has the right to put his hand on a woman. No matter how big, how small, no matter where youre from.
'It is not right to raise a hand to a woman and its only now that Ive realised that.
'Even once is unacceptable, but to be made to feel that it is acceptable is even worse. To be made to feel that youre paranoid or insecure, thats mental torture, and no man should do that to any woman.'
Ms Murphy says she has since left the relationship and describes herself as single mother.
Ms Murphy (pictured) says she thought 'long and hard' before posting the video but hopes it will 'inspire' other women around the world to realize that 'violence is not the answer'
Ms Murphy, pictured in happier times, has since left the relationship and describes herself as single mother
'Unfortunately, when they ask where their daddy is, hes not going to be around, hes not going to be here for them anymore,' she says in between sobs. 'Our lives are completely torn apart.
'And theyre going to know that their daddy hit their mummy, and thats not something that children should see at all.'
She concludes: 'So if anyone out there has gone through something similar to what Ive gone through, you need to find the courage and get away from anything thats an unhealthy as violence.
'Go to your friends and family, people who love you and care about you.'
Share or comment on this article
108
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="59">
        <date/>
        <title>
	British Army appoints Brigadier Susan Ridge as its first female major general
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151789/British-Army-appoints-Brigadier-Susan-Ridge-female-major-general.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Brigadier Susan Ridge, right,  will become the Army's highest ranking female officer in September when she takes over as Director General Army Legal Services (DGALS).
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Brig Ridge, who left the 'mundanity' of a civilian law career to join the Army, said the opportunities for women were now far wider than when she joined.
'Certainly, when I did my infantry attachment, I was the only female in the battalion,' she said of her time with the Queen's Lancashire Regiment in Berlin in 1992.
'That's not now the case. Women are now in a wide range of roles.'
Brig Ridge, who said she expected other senior female officers to progress to the general ranks, added: 'I think it shows that women can progress in the Army.
'In part this stems from the changes made when the Women's Royal Army Corps was dissolved.'
That change took place in 1992 and Brig Ridge said 'it takes about 20 years to make a career at this level and I'm expecting to start seeing women starting to come through now'.
Brig Ridge was working in land and property law before joining the Army.
Earlier the Army appointed Brigadier Sharon Nesmith, right, as commanding officer of a brigade of 5,000 front line troops,, the first time a woman has been put in charge of such a large number of front line soldiers
'I had just been offered a partnership,' she said. 'It suddenly came home to me that would be my next 30 years of working life.
'I just wanted do something before the mundanity of everyday life.'
She signed up for four years and thought 'let's see how it goes', but said it was 'never my aim' to rise through the ranks.
'I didn't join Army Legal Services to make major general. I joined to do something that I wanted to do and was interesting.'
Brig Ridge, who credits her adolescent son for keeping her grounded, said she was 'exceptionally lucky' that her lieutenant colonel husband has been 'hugely supportive of my work'.
He took on 'much of the responsibility of managing family and home life, while also juggling his own career'.
'There have been occasions when he has been posted away, we have done long periods of weekend commuting and he has done tours in the Balkans and Afghanistan. But largely it has worked so well because he has been on-side.'
The DGALS is responsible for the whole of Army Legal Services which provides legal support to the service in barracks, on training and on operations.
General Sir Nicholas Carter, the Chief of the General Staff, said: 'I am very pleased for Sue; she is a talented and committed officer who is widely respected throughout the Army.'
This follows the appointment of married mother-of-two Brigadier Sharon Nesmith to command a brigade of 5,000 frontline soldiers.
Share or comment on this article
36
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="60">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Documents showing Claude Monet's neighbours objected to his garden plans to go on display
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151685/How-Monet-thwarted-nimbys-Documents-artist-s-neighbours-objected-plans-lily-pond-garden-set-display.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Farmers in Giverny, about 50 miles north east of Paris feared that Claude Monet's water garden, subject of many of his greatest works, pictured, would infect the water supply and kill their cows.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Claude Monet, pictured, was an accomplished gardener, but when he bought a new house near Paris in 1883 local farmers were suspicious
It is the lily pond that has inspired some of the greatest works of French art.
But Claude Monets legacy could have been very different had his neighbours had their way.
In 1893, farmers and councillors wrote to Giverny town hall objecting to the painters plans to extend his garden and create the lily pond.
They repeatedly tried to block his scheme because they feared his exotic plants would poison the water supply and kill their cows.
Had they won, Monets water lily series  which includes the Agapanthus Triptych of 19161919  would never have been painted.
He was eventually given permission however to divert the River Epte to create his pond.
The original council documents will be featured at the Royal Academys latest Monet exhibition, Painting the Modern Garden: Monet to Matisse.
After Monet moved to Giverny  50 miles north-west of Paris  in 1883, he bought land on the other side of a railway line that bordered his house. On this land, he planned to create a water garden by diverting the Epte, which is a tributary of the River Seine.
But according to the exhibitions co-curator Ann Dumas, who unearthed the documents, the farmers were suspicious of Monet.
She said: He kept himself to himself so they saw him as an outsider. When they got wind that he wanted to make a water garden they complained.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="61">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Watchdog criticise energy giants for overcharging on standard variable tariffs
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151646/Energy-giants-guilty-rip-bills-won-t-broken-Watchdogs-criticise-firms-hitting-loyal-customers-standard-variable-tariffs.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	British households are overpaying for their energy by around £1.2 billion a year and are failing to switch to get the best deals, the Competition and Markets Authority watchdog said today.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
It is argued that this would create more competition and drive down bills.
The investigation also outlined plans to encourage customers to switch, but stopped short of recommending a break-up of the energy giants, saying competition in wholesale markets was working well.
In recent days there have been rumours that the CMA will stop short of this in favour of more modest efforts to try to encourage families to shop around for a cheaper deal.
Consumer groups and charities were furious that wholesale energy prices had fallen by more than 20 per cent in a year yet the firms made only tiny cuts in tariffs on standard variable rates.
Energy Secretary Amber Rudd has written to the energy firms demanding they reduce prices
Anger intensified when Britain's second biggest energy firm, SSE, recently revealed that its profits from energy supply rose by almost 50 per cent, up from 122.5 million to 368.7 million over the past year.
The industry regulator Ofgem estimates that the average profit margin energy firms are making per household has risen to an all-time high of 120, which is up by 32 per cent in a year.
Before the General Election power company bosses said that they had been reluctant to cut bills because they feared a Labour victory. They argued that Labour's promise of an 18-month price freeze meant that if they reduced tariffs too much they would be forced to keep them at the new low level.
However, this allowed them to keep prices artificially high, so boosting profits.
Labour's drubbing in the polls has removed any excuse the firms have for keeping tariffs at the current high levels, yet they have made no further cuts.
Energy Secretary Amber Rudd has since written to the energy firms demanding they reduce prices. However, the industry continues to refuse to help struggling customers.
Campaigners Fuel Poverty Action fear the CMA will not take any meaningful action to curb bills and profits. Laura Hill, from the group, said: 'When the Big Six pocket billions of pounds in profit every year while one in four families decide whether to eat or heat their homes, I find it hard to understand how the CMA can say that profiteering energy companies have nothing to do with the current energy bill crisis.
'We are all sick and tired of the Government's inaction and excuses on fuel poverty. It's time they take stock and listen to the needs of the people and not profit-hungry companies. We need an energy system that is affordable, clean, public and democratic.'
The GMB union claimed the CMA inquiry would be a damp squib. Its national officer Gary Smith said: 'The inquiry was political cover in an attempt to divert attention from Labour's price freeze promise. If anyone believes the inquiry will deliver lower prices for energy users they will be very disappointed.
'While the heat on energy prices is off at the moment, the long-term trend, as the demand for energy continues to increase, is upwards.'
Share or comment on this article
41
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="62">
        <date/>
        <title>
	After the Mail's expose into cold-callers, the law must protect us from them
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-3151679/DAILY-MAIL-COMMENT-law-protect-cold-callers.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Last night, the ICO vowed an immediate investigation into the Mail’s evidence. How much longer must the vulnerable be left to suffer before the law on cold-calling is rewritten to spell out that No means No?
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
In a chilling investigation, the Mail today exposes how some of the countrys most respected charities use ruthless cold-calling techniques to prey on societys most vulnerable.
True, weve grown all too used to stories of payday lenders and unscrupulous salesmen seeking to extort money from the elderly, confused and hard-up.
But it is shocking when organisations such as the British Red Cross, Oxfam, the NSPCC and Macmillan Cancer Care are caught using immoral methods to target the defenceless.
Scroll down for video
After three weeks undercover, our Investigations Editor reports that fundraisers are instructed by their supervisors to be brutal and ferocious
After three weeks undercover at a call centre used by 40 leading charities, our Investigations Editor reports that fundraisers are instructed to be brutal and ferocious, accepting no excuse from the sick, the elderly, the disabled, the unemployed or those in debt.
Even when donors say they suffer from Alzheimers or dementia, call centre workers are told to press them for more.
In a grimly ironic touch, they are also taught how to handle questions about Olive Cooke, the 92-year-old poppy seller who took her own life after being inundated with charities demands.
Indeed, most frustrating of all for those who are pestered and persecuted is that theyre offered no escape from the barrage of calls.
Those who agree a monthly amount to donate may be phoned again within just six weeks and urged to give more. As for those who refuse, the charities wont take No for an answer  in some cases ringing as many as four times.
Meanwhile, the British Red Cross keeps donors data for up to three years, contacting them repeatedly after they have stopped contributing.
The calls often keep coming even after supporters have registered with the Government-approved Telephone Preference Service, which is supposed to protect us from unsolicited approaches.
Last night, the Information Commissioners Office vowed an immediate investigation into the Mails evidence, saying the charities involved could be breaking the law.
How much longer must the vulnerable be left to suffer before the law on cold-calling is rewritten to spell out that No means No?
Undercover footage in the call center at GoGen
Democracy v the euro
After the Greeks resounding rejection of the eurozones bailout package, it is anyones guess what happens next.
With a great deal of help from its creditors, Greece may yet limp on in the euro
With a great deal of help from its creditors, the country may yet limp on in the euro  though few would dare predict for how long. Or if Angela Merkel sticks to her tough demands for austerity, it may be driven to default on its debts and revert to the drachma.
Either way, the outlook for the birthplace of democracy, even as its people celebrate their cry of defiance through the ballot box, looks bleak for many years to come.
This paper makes one plea: will the champions of the single currency learn a lesson in humility from the suffering theyve caused?
Indeed, the euro was born of hubris (as so often, the Greeks had a word for it)  the political ambition to unite a whole continent under one government, with tax and spending dictated by Brussels.
But as the Mail warned at the time, and Peter Oborne argues on this page, this was putting the cart before the horse. A single currency cannot function without a common fiscal policy. And where nations as disparate as Germany and Greece are concerned, such a policy is incompatible with democracy.
Perhaps it is too much to hope that the eurofanatics will back off from their aim to exert centralised control.
But David Cameron must surely draw strength from the Greek nemesis, redoubling his efforts to repatriate powers and restore true meaning to democracy.

Share or comment on this article
MOST WATCHED NEWS VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="63">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Average British tourist admits spending £220 too much during their time away 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151701/How-two-thirds-overspend-holiday-Average-British-tourist-admits-spending-220-time-away.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Nearly two-thirds of UK tourists admit to overspending, with the most common reasons being because food and drink was too expensive. A third have gone on holiday already with debt.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
The average spend before we've even left the UK reaches a staggering 156, spent on clothes, holiday products and beauty treatments before we depart.
However, many had no money before they even left  a quarter of those asked had gone on a holiday they couldnt really afford in the last year.
While one in five have booked a holiday knowing they will get into financial difficulty - a figure particularly high among young adults aged 25-34.
A quarter of the 25-34 age bracket said they had been on a stag or hen party they couldn't really afford in the past year.
But this isn't limited to younger adults as those with families also feel the strain.
Money woes: The average holiday spend before we've even left the UK reaches a staggering 156, spent on clothes, holiday products and beauty treatments
One in five said the main reason they go away on holidays they can't afford is because it was their duty to provide a family holiday.
The top motive for heading abroad on holidays we can ill-afford is because we feel we 'deserved' the trip, while 22 per cent went on expensive trips because they felt obliged.
But some holiday-makers are also money-savvy.
Two-thirds will save up for part of, if not all, of the holiday, while 58 per cent prepare a budget for certain activities. 
The survey was conducted by the Money Advice Service, an independent body set up by the Government to offer money tips.
Share or comment on this article
7
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="64">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Oxfam and Macmillan Cancer Support hound elderly for money on 'no-call' list
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151533/Shamed-charity-cold-call-sharks-Britain-s-biggest-charities-ruthlessly-hound-vulnerable-cash-try-opt-receiving-calls.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The British Red Cross, NSPCC, Oxfam and Macmillan have all been exploiting loopholes in the Telephone Preference Service, which was set up to protect the elderly from cold callers.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Major charities, including the NSPCC, the British Red Cross and Macmillan, were found to be calling people who were registered with the Telephone Preference Service.
Such people have deliberately opted out of receiving unsolicited calls.
But a loophole means that if they have failed at any point to read the small print in privacy policies, and dont object to receiving calls, they lose the protection of the TPS system.
After reviewing the Mails evidence, Stephen Eckersley, the ICOs Head of Enforcement, said: Wed like to thank the Daily Mail for bringing this to our attention. On the face of it this could be a breach of both the Data Protection Act and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations.
We will be launching an investigation into the call centre and charities involved.
He said charities must follow the same rules on marketing by calls or texts as any other company. Rule breakers face fines of up to 500,000.
Existing supporters are harassed repeatedly to increase their donations  with some Macmillan supporters being called four times in a row, even if they have already said no.
Richard Lloyd, of the consumer group Which?, said: The Government must now carry out a full review of fundraising rules and regulations to put an end to this and save the sectors reputation.
Bernard Jenkin, the Tory chairman of the Commons public administration committee, said: The Daily Mail is right to expose this, and I will be asking my committee to look into it. Dame Esther Rantzen, a trustee at the NSPCC, said she was horrified her charity had been calling vulnerable people on no call lists.
She said: I welcome the investigation, I think it is really important.
The Fundraising Standards Board  the self-regulatory body for charities in the UK  said it was very concerned by the revelations and would investigate fully.
All of the charities denied acting unlawfully but said they would look into the Mails evidence as a matter of urgency.
Undercover footage in the call center at GoGen
Oxfam is among those to have been using London-based GoGen, a company that carries out campaigns for 40 of Britain's biggest charities
A spokesman for the British Red Cross said the charity was deeply concerned by the claims. She said the charity believed it was obeying the law on the TPS but will be seeking clarification from the ICO and Institute of Fundraising. The NSPCC said it had contractual arrangements in place with those that fundraise on our behalf, including strict guidance on vulnerable people, and expect the highest standards of behaviour.
But it added: Any suggestion of inappropriate activity is deeply worrying and we would want any concerns to be raised with us immediately so that they can be quickly addressed.
A Macmillan spokesman said: We take the claims made by the Daily Mail seriously and are looking into these as a priority.
We do not wish to contact people if we are aware this is unwanted. We take the requests of our supporters very seriously and all supporters can choose to unsubscribe from communications at any time.
We would not hesitate to take robust action if we found our agencies were not acting with upmost integrity on our behalf.
Oxfam said it had suspended all telephone fundraising activity to ensure companies who work on our behalf meet not only the regulatory standards but also our own high moral and ethical standards.
It said the dementia and Alzheimers policy was all about enabling people with dementia to live as full a life as possible, including supporting their favourite charity.
Tim Hunter, fundraising director, said: Oxfam fights for the rights of poor and vulnerable people across the world and we apply our values to all aspects of our work. We would never exploit an individuals vulnerability in our marketing.
Our guidelines around telephone fundraising are also aligned to those of the Institute of Fundraising, who consulted the Alzheimers Society, Scope and AgeUK.
Our agencies have clear, regulated policies that help strike the appropriate balance between enabling people with dementia to live as full a life as possible, including supporting their favourite charity, and protecting them from the vulnerability caused by dementia.
Yesterday it also emerged that Save The Children had decided to end cold-calling.
Giuseppe Iantosca of GoGen said he had suspended two members of staff while the firm investigated the Mails evidence.
He also said GoGen would not ask those with dementia for money in future.

Inside the call centre sweatshop: Aggressive, ruthless and cynical, the bosses giving 7.30 an hour staff a ten minute briefing and a script before they hit the phones
By Katherine Faulkner
Inside a sweltering training room in a shabby warehouse we were told exactly what to expect from our jobs as charity telephone fundraisers.
The whole point of it is going to be asking people for money, our trainer, Callum, told us bluntly. That is what were here to do. Were not an information line.
He warned us about the string of protests we should expect from the people we called.
Im a pensioner, Im retired, Im 87 years old, Im unemployed, I just went on maternity leave, our mortgage payments just went up  . Reeling off his list in a bored voice as he swigged from a water bottle, Callum told us that we should become experts in deflecting these objections.
Pep talk: Supervisor Glyn told staff they had to care about the charity's cause 'whether you do or don't'
Undercover footage reveals GoGen training techniques
Then, we should ask them for money again  three times, in fact, in every single call. Situated in a run-down area of Dalston, east London, the GoGen call centre  and its 7.30-an-hour staff  are entrusted by big charities with national campaigns.
The British Red Cross, NSPCC, Oxfam, Macmillan cancer support, Cancer Research UK and Save the Children all rely on the centre. Bosses, who come to work in the stuffy office in shorts and vests, claim the atmosphere is relaxed.
Yet employees are scolded if they are even a minute late  and are ordered not to laugh too loudly in the grubby corridors in case it makes too much noise. And there is nothing casual about the companys attitude to raising money. In a spirit of aggression that seems at odds with charitable giving, bosses demand brutal and ferocious requests for money.
Fundraisers are told to get charity supporters on the back foot, where we need them to be.
We are now going to take it up a level. I want to hear much more ferocious asks, we were told at the beginning of one shift by Hadley, a supervisor.
If you are tempted by any kind of fluffy language, take it out of your vocabulary. More ferocity in your asks  because lets face it, you know it works. Its time to get the persuader out, and hit it really hard.
In a practice that causes misery for families, telephone fundraisers must call people in their homes and on their mobile phones until 9pm.
At the beginning of each call, they must make two attempts to persuade the person to talk to them.
If on the first attempt the person says Im just going out or Im in a bit of a hurry, they must try again, saying something like Oh, itll just be a couple of minutes  is that OK?
Trainer Callum told the undercover Mail reporter that the call centre was 'not an information line' and the whole point of the role was simply asking people for money
Once the person has agreed, they continue with the call, during which they must make three separate attempts to get a donation.
They are supposed to call up to 80 numbers an hour.
In many cases, nobody will even answer the phone  while other calls last just a few seconds because people do not want to talk. Most people we called on behalf of the charities would assume we had a personal connection with the causes. In fact most of the employees of GoGen know next to nothing about the charities.
Most are just scruffily-dressed students, desperate to make some extra cash during the holidays.
And they are given only a short briefing  lasting about ten minutes  on a charitys work before being told to start calling supporters and asking for cash. Sometimes fundraisers will even be switched from one charity campaign to another halfway through a shift.
On one occasion, having spent the first 15 minutes of a shift talking to people about the Nepal earthquake for the British Red Cross, I was suddenly asked to switch campaigns. Within minutes, I had to start talking to Macmillan supporters about Britains cancer care crisis instead. Despite this, we were under huge pressure to sound passionate about the causes we were calling on behalf of  whether or not we actually were.
One supervisor, Glyn, told us: Regardless whether youre an animal lover or not, every single person youre speaking to today  they care about the polar bears, they care about tigers and leopards, they care about the planet.
So today, you do too. Whether you do or dont  today you do.
All the fundraisers will be reading from scripts provided by the charities  which they are told to stick to religiously. There is a different script for every campaign. Some charities will be carrying out several different campaigns at the same time.
And there will often be people in the same room calling on behalf of three or four different charities  such as Macmillan, the British Red Cross and the NSPCC  all at the same time. This often produced a deafening background noise, with overlapping monologues about cancer, child abuse and disasters.
Every single fundraiser could be heard telling someone it was urgent that they donate, right now.
On top of the noise of the other fundraisers reading from scripts were the shouted instructions from supervisors  usually berating us for not making enough money.
'I want more ferocity': Call centre supervisor Hadley
If we were falling behind on our targets, supervisors would shout that it was not good enough and tell us: This next call has got to be a yes.
If they suspected we were not being aggressive enough, they would listen in to our phone calls to make sure we were always asking for money three times.
The scripts are carefully designed to pack the biggest emotional punch possible  and to make it sound like asking for money isnt the main reason for the call.
Were going to be asking for money, Callum explained. But we dont want to be saying  Yeah Im going to be asking for money.
And during the calls, members of the public are assured by telephone fundraisers that their donations go straight to those most in need.
But in fact, tens of thousands of pounds from every campaign must first be paid to the call centre  before a single penny reaches the charity. The public are informed about this fact only at the very end of the call  after they have agreed to donate and handed over bank details.
Legal experts who examined the campaign scripts used by the British Red Cross, Oxfam, Macmillan and the NSPCC said such a practice was concerningly close to a breach of the law.
A lawyer for Which?, who specialises in consumer law, said: Some people might choose not to donate if they had that information before their donation was finalised.
Therefore, providing this information late in the call could be in breach of consumer law  specifically the Consumer Protection from Unfair Trading Regulations.
If it is information that the average person needs to know when choosing whether to donate, then it should not be withheld until the end of the call.
The NSPCC tell donors that 4 a month could help them answer 12 calls to Childline from children suffering family problems, self-harm and abuse. Only after they have agreed are donors told that of the 120,000 the NSPCC expects to raise on the campaign, more than half  65,000  is expected to go to the call centre.
In a script for a Red Cross campaign, callers are told to tell donors that popping an extra 1 on to your monthly gift will buy three foil blankets for those in Nepal.
Donors are told: This means over a year, we can give more than 30 people warmth and comfort in their hour of need.
However, at the end of the call  after their donation has been accepted  fundraisers have to say that the call centre is being paid 150,000 for the appeal.
This is one of four Red Cross campaigns currently run by GoGen  for which the call centre is set to receive 434,100 in total. Each campaign lasts only a few weeks.
Macmillan Cancer Support tells donors that simply adding an extra pound or two to their monthly donations would make a huge difference to ensuring that no one has to face cancer alone.
Then, before the conversation ends and the donor is thanked for their money, the caller adds: GoGen will be paid approximately 55,000 for carrying out this campaign.
Telephone fundraisers are also faced with dozens of people who were angry that they were being called.
GoGen accepts millions every year from the charities for these campaigns and its bosses are thought to take home large salaries.
Chairman Nicholas Smith, 48, who owns more than half of the business, lives in a 1.2million apartment in Blackheath, South East London. He owns a second home in the Midlands.
Finance director Robert Metrebian, 53, owns a 1.3million detached property in Woodford Green, Essex, and often boasts on social media of his lavish lifestyle.
On Facebook he writes of drinking expensive wine to excess and evenings dining out.
Director Giuseppe Iantosca, 36, lives in a 1.2million terrace in Dalston. He said he had suspended two members of staff while they investigated the Mails evidence.
He also said GoGen would not be asking anyone with dementia for money in future.
He said the old policy was approved by the Fundraising Standards Board  and inspired by a belief that age and mental health are not reasons to discriminate against people who want to donate.
Mr Iantosca added: GoGen do not support, condone or agree with any of the alleged statements made by staff members. We will be reviewing the processes and criteria by which members of staff are inducted into our training and supervisory teams.

Share or comment on this article
726
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="65">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Carnival organisers issue warning over rogue gang of clowns who 'rip off parents'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151450/Carnival-organisers-issue-warning-rogue-gang-clowns-rip-parents-selling-overpriced-balloons.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Wiltshire festival organisers are warning the public to watch out for a rogue gang of clowns who they say are ripping off parents with overpriced balloons at street carnivals.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>comments
Pictured are two clowns carnival organisers say have been selling overpriced balloons
Festival organisers are warning the public to watch out for a rogue gang of clowns who they claim are ripping off parents with overpriced balloons at street carnivals.
The rogue entertainers are believed to have targeted a number of large public events in the past year by sneaking into processions uninvited.
They then create sword-shaped balloons before charging parents anything between 2 and 5 for them, as well as money to have their photos taken with kids.
Organisers of next weekend's carnival in Melksham, Wiltshire, who were previously targeted by the alleged fraudsters, have now issued a public warning.
They have also released a picture of the two clowns at last year's event, in a bid to warn them off this year's procession.
A statement from Melksham Carnival Committee said: 'These individuals joined the procession without our prior knowledge or agreement and sold balloons by giving them to children and then asking the parents for money.
'They are nothing to do with carnival and sneak into the procession while we are setting up the entries.
'They also went to the park last year and had photos taken with children and charged parents for the privilege.
'They do not give anything to us or to the town and they make a small fortune from you.
'If you see anyone selling balloons or anything apart from our official programmes then please do not give them your money.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="66">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Flat 24 that was an asylum AND a home to a Duran Duran star goes on sale
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151269/Property-asylum-orphaned-girls-wartime-MI6-interrogation-centre-home-Duran-Duran-star-goes-sale-3million.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Flat 24 - the largest property within London's historic Grade II listed Royal Victoria Patriotic Building - has had an illustrious history since being built as a home for orphans in 1859.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
In 1862, one of the girls, Charlotte Jane Bennette was burned to death while deliberately locked up in a bathroom  it is said that she still haunts the building.
Later during the First World War the building was requisitioned as a hospital to care for thousands of wounded servicemen.
Following the conflict, the building returned to being an orphanage until 1938, when the children were evacuated in anticipation of German bombing raids in the Second World War.
Fascinating history: The flat is part of theRoyal Victoria Patriotic Building, which wasbuilt in 1859 as an asylum for orphaned girls
Celebrity occupant:A recent chapter in the flat's illustrious history saw it owned by a member of Duran Duran in 1981
In deep contrast to its previous use, the building became an MI6 clearing, detention and interrogation centre.
Interrogators, including 'spy catcher' Colonel Oreste Pinto, interviewed over 30,000 immigrants to the UK over a four year period.
It was reported that Hitler's deputy, Rudolf Hess, who flew to Britain on a 'peace mission', was held and questioned there.
After the war the building became a teacher training college and in 1952 was bought by London County Council - five years later becoming Honeywell Secondary Mixed School.
In another twist of fate, the school failed, fell into disrepair and closed in 1974. The empty building soon attracted vandals and thieves, who ransacked the place andstole lead from the roof and water tanks.
The building was marked for demolition, but was instead given Grade II listed status after campaigning by the Victorian Society and Wandsworth Society.
Grade II listed: The property is located in Wandsworth Common andis said to be haunted following the death of a girl here in 1862
Grand interior: The 3million flat has a huge central living area and is located in Wandsworth Common, in south London
Shelter for wounded: During the First World War the building was requisitioned as a hospital to care for thousands of wounded sodliers
In 1980 the Greater London Council put the building up for sale and it was eventually sold for 1 to the company now called South of the Border Holdings, under the agreement that the fabric was fully restored.
Just before the formal handover, the main hall, which has an elaborate hammer beam ceiling, was destroyed by arson. It was fully restored from a photographic survey, which had been made two weeks earlier. Restoration of the building took six years.
In 1985 the Civic Trust awarded a commendation for the hall ceiling and in 1987 the restoration also won the Europa Nostra Order of Merit.
The building is now a mixed-use development, including studios and workshops, a French bar and restaurant 'Le Gothique' and 29 apartments.
The property is being sold on sellmyhome.co.uk , and the company offers a unique virtual tour of the building on their website.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="67">
        <date/>
        <title>
	What Harry Enfield's Stavros the kebab shop owner would think of the Greek crisis by RICHARD LITTLEJOHN
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-3151624/The-bubble-bursts-Banko-Kleftiko-RICHARD-LITTLEJOHN-imagines-Harry-Enfield-s-character-Stavros-kebab-shop-owner-think-Greek-crisis.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	RICHARD LITTLEJOHN: This column decided to consult our own resident expert, one of the most prominent members of the Greek community in Britain, Harry Enfield's character Stavros.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Stavros come here 40 years ago, used to be nice but now it feel like a foreign country. Nobody even speaka the Queen's Inglis, like what I does.
An' doner get me starting on the Muslins, either. Tottingham High Road like downtown Afghanistan, all the pubs shut cos the Muslins don't drink, innit?
As a small busy man, I've always vote Conservatory, ever since Grocer Heathcliffe. Pity we can't bring back Mrs Thatch
Last Friday, I had gang of kids calling themself Al Murray or summink, waving that black Izal flag, an' telling me this was now a Muslin area subjeck to Cherie Amour, whoever she is, so I wasn't allow to sell beers no more or they gonna chop off my head and put me on Bookface.
Had to chase them away with my kebab knife.
All the wimmins in black berks, everything cover up except eyeholes. Is like looking at someone through letter-box.
Someone sez that Mr Akhbar, nice man what runs public convenience store next to where the bookies used to be, anyway his daughter, only a slip of a girl, has run away to join Izal in Syriza and become yee-haw bride.
Every peeps weepin' and wailin' and blamin' Old Bill, like they always do especially over riots an' all. But if you ask me, good rids. Make a change Muslins goin' over there instead of coming over here.
Lol, I say, innit?
Drone captures thousands celebrating 'no' vote in Athens
When I move to Tottingham from Greece, Stavros was only kebab taking-away for miles. Peeps beating path to door from all over. Now kebabs everywhere, Lebanese, Somalis, Moroccos, very bad for my busy. If this is what they call single market, they can stuff it. Too much cheap competition.
These peeps they come over here, they try take my job and most of them getting benefits, and free council houses, too, on account of breeding like radishes.
Is not only Greece in deep doggy-doo, kebab busy is not what it was. My takings well down, even though my dolmades voted best in town three years running by readers of Haringey Shopper.
Just today, I get a cheque sent back from the Banko Kleftiko, mark 'Return to Drawer'. What drawer, I thinking to myself. Cutlery drawer, sock drawer, drawer where I keep my Demis Roussos cassettes?
So I rings Mr Papadopolis, the manager of the Palmers Green branch, only there no reply, just recording mess which say Banko Kleftiko close until further notices.
Same story at Banko Stifado, in Finsbury Park. When I try putting my card in hole-in-wall, it start flashing 'No money left' like that note from Labour peeps at Treasury when Call Him Dave become Prime Minister. What they mean 'no money'? Is bank, innit? How's a bank run out of money? That's like kebab shop running out of lamb.
How am I s'pose pay for my season ticket to the Arse? I always support Arse, even though most peeps round here are supporting Tottingham, or a least they did before they all moved out to Cheshunt to get away from the immigrants.
Tottingham High Road like downtown Afghanistan, all the pubs shut cos the Muslins don't drink, innit?
Good job I still got suitcase full of drachmas, what I brought over when I immigrate from Greece. Accord to Sky on the telly, what I have on in shop for the football, now that Greeks vote 'No' to Urals, they going back to drachma, so could come in handy.
I dunno what Greece doin' in the Urals anyway. Last time I looked, Urals in Russia. Now it say that Russia will bale out Greeks, so maybe it will be roubles in future, not drachmas.
Simple currency always stupid idea. One-size-fit-all, my moustache. How could what fits Germs also fit Greece? You seen size of some of them frauleins? Big birds, they are, struggle to squeeze into a berk.
All that bratwurst, I guess, not like healthy kebab and nice salad what Stavros sells. You wan' chilli sauce with that, missus?
Still, no surprise to me that Greeks go belly-up. I went for holiday, see my family last year. None of my relatives have done an honest day's work for donkey's things.
My cousin Theo, lazy git employ by Ministry of Olives since left school, got 13 month salary ever year, never paid any tax and retired at 50 on three pensions.
I say to Her-Inside-The-Doors, this gotta end in tears, marking my words. One day the Germ prez, Mrs Merton, is going to get fed up with footing the bills. That's when the bubble is gonna burst.
Very fun, Stav, she says. Bubble being what peeps in Tottingham call Greeks. Is Cockerney rhyme slang. Bubble and Squeak rhyme with Greek, innit? But you only use first bit, Bubble, not Squeak.
You the Bubble what's gonna burst unless you lay off the moussaka, Stav, she say. Not me, I say. I'm on 5:2 diet. Some days I eat five kebabs, other days only two.
I'll be voting 'No' when Call Him Dave has his referee on Europe. Might stop foreigners flooding over here at last
Greece is the bursting bubble wrap. Complete chicken-in-a-basket case. Good job we living in Tottingham.
As a small busy man, I work all hours, like Ronnie Barker in that funny prog with Del Boy as delivery man and Nurse Emmanuel with the big bouzoukis.
But apart from me and Mr Akhbar, who I aforemenched a min ago, no one else in Tottingham seem to do any work at all, except robbin', sellin' drugs and claiming the Old Nat King Cole.
If we's not carefree, I sez to Her-Inside-The-Doors, this country could go same way as Greece. Britain got even bigger debts than Greeks and that buy-to-let flat what I bought in Leytonstone with the zero-hours mortgage for my old age is look decidedly dodge.
It's juss as well we got Ian Dunkin-Donuts and Boy George Osborne, not Gormless Brown or Ed Millerband, running things. As a small busy man, I've always vote Conservatory, ever since Grocer Heathcliffe. Pity we can't bring back Mrs Thatch.
I might not be getting Post-It vote in Greece, but I do get vote in Tottingham and I'll be voting 'No' when Call Him Dave has his referee on Europe.
Might stop foreigners flooding over here at last. And there's only one simple currency we need, that's the Great British Pound-in-your-pocket.
Hello, Mr Farage peeps. You was dead right about Greece, innit? Usual? Double shish kebab, six-pack of Greek beer and a litre of Retsina comin' up. You want chilli sauce? Thought not.
That'll be 25.99 for cash. No, sorry, we don't accept cheques. Do you mind your change in drachmas?

Share or comment on this article
439
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="68">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Can you tell the difference between Yoko Ono and CRAIG BROWN?
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-3151632/Who-s-bonkers-Yoko-Ono-CRAIG-BROWN-S-test-tell-difference.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	CRAIG BROWN: Yoko Ono has just won the Observer Lifetime Achievement Ethical Award. Half of these thoughts are hers and half are mine. Can you tell the difference?
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
16) Count the numbers of lights in the city every day. Make a number list and hang it on the wall.
17) Fill your shoes with sand until there is no room for your feet. Now you must walk barefoot.
18) A ladder is for climbing up, as well as climbing down.
19) A ladder without rungs is just two long poles, not joined together.
20) Before you climb up a ladder, remember to check it has rungs.
21) If there are no gaps between the rungs, then your ladder is a plank.
22) Steal all the clocks and watches in the world. Destroy them.
23) Count the numbers of wrinkles on your face or your body or certain parts of your body. Send it to your friend in place of a letter.
24) Take the first word that comes across your mind. Repeat the word until dawn.
The judges honoured the Japanese-born activist for her dedication to ecology, peace and human rights
25) It's Christmas time. Ask a friend to pull on your hair. And another friend to pull on your toes. You have become a cracker.
26) Imagine letting a goldfish swim across the sky. Let it swim from the East to the West. Drink a litre of water.
27) You cannot drink a glass of water. You can only drink the water.
28) A baby is an umbrella. Hold it over your head to keep off the rain.
29) Tape the sound of the moon fading at dawn. Give it to your mother to listen to when she's in sorrow.
30) Peel an apricot. Place it between your toes. Put on a sock and walk to work. When you arrive, your foot will be very messy. But the sky will still be blue. Yoko loves you.
ANSWERS: 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 8, 9, 13, 14, 16, 22, 23, 24, 26, 29 are by Yoko. The rest are mine.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="69">
        <date/>
        <title>
	George Blackstock suing Stoke City claiming he was 'destroyed as a person'
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151357/Ex-apprentice-footballer-suing-Stoke-City-claiming-destroyed-person-physically-abused-players-1980s.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	George Blackstock, from Belfast, who was scouted by the then Second Division side, claims he was subjected to abuse by former goalkeeper Peter Fox, pictured, on two occasions in the 1980s.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Today the hearing heard that trainees at the time were treated as 'skivvies' to first team players and it was 'part of the culture of the club to maintain a distance between first team players and apprentices.'
He was described as feeling 'humiliated' after the 'painful, intrusive and immediately distressing' abuse and is now prescribed Temazepam and sleeping tablets.
Mr Blackstock said: 'I feel, to be honest with you, it has destroyed me as a person over the last years having to deal with him (Fox). It all came back to the forefront, it's been very difficult mentally and psychologically.'
He was asked what he was hoping to achieve in pursuing the case.
He added: 'What am I hoping to achieve? I want these people who inflicted this on me to be held accountable for their actions.'
He said he was left needing therapy which had been helpful in some ways, but explained: 'In others, no, because having to relive it all again is quite traumatic.
He also says that falling short of his first-team duties, he was allegedly held down by a number of first team players while being attacked by Fox, pictured
'I would probably say I will need more treatment when I return home to Belfast.'
Representing Mr Blackstock, Aswini Weereratne QC said: 'It is very much his case that the practice of was unacceptable in 1986 and is unacceptable today.
'His claim for damages, that he had been physically assaulted by Mr Fox between 1986 and 1988.
'It is his case that these two assaults had a profound effect on him psychologically and also that it had an effect on his ability to play professional football.
'It is a type of dispute often referred to as David and Goliath battle. David is Mr Blackstock, who was aged between 15 and 16.'
The court also heard that part of his role was to do 'menial jobs' for first team players such as cleaning their boots, setting out their kits and putting them in the laundry. Trainees were also required to clean up dressing rooms and showers.
Ms Weereratne added: 'The apprentices did all this, they skivvied for the first team players.'
She also told the hearing that the traineeship had been 'a prized apprenticeship at an English football club' with Mr Blackstock leaving his home in Belfast in July 1986 to take the place.
Mr Blackstock must prove the two assaults and also the damages he has suffered as a result. In relation to Stoke City he must prove vicarious liability.
Stoke City Football Club and Fox deny Mr Blackstock's claims.

Share or comment on this article
28
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="70">
        <date/>
        <title>
	New air traffic system will tell aircraft to slow down so they arrive to land at precise time 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151643/Speed-limits-planes-end-airport-stacking-New-air-traffic-tell-aircraft-350-miles-away-slow-arrive-land-precise-time.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The head of the UK's National Air Traffic Services told an aviation conference it is only a matter of time before the new technology is implemented meaning flights land dead on time.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
In future, if there is a risk of a jam, UK air traffic controllers will alert aircraft up to 350 miles away and tell them to reduce their speed so they arrive to land at a precise time.
NATS is working with air traffic controllers in Ireland, France and Holland to control the arrival of planes, and will soon introduce Scandinavian controllers to the system as well.
A plane flies over Heathrow. Experts say the system would work particularly well with the proposed new third runway at Heathrow Airport
They hope to extend the 350-mile range to 550 miles and then to 1,000 miles.
The result should be that flights will arrive more reliably without delays, fly at a higher altitude, waste less fuel and make less noise over homes, meaning an end to holding, or stacking as it is also known.
Mr Rolfe told the RunwaysUK aviation conference in London: Airlines can expect reduced fuel consumption and CO2 emissions.
Getting rid of the holds means well be able to depart modern, efficient, capable aircraft into more efficient higher airspace more quickly  which in turn will help reduce the noise footprint on the ground and the wider environmental impact.
NATS general manager Paul Haskins added: Think of it like the M25 variable speed limit system in the sky.
Just like with the M25s system, slowing down the traffic means you dont get bunching, the flights fly more smoothly, and you dont have planes flying into the back of a traffic jam.
We developed it for UK airspace but are extending it across Europe  first at a range of 350 miles, then 550 miles and ultimately 1,000 miles.
An air traffic controller in the UK can use an electronic tool to tell a plane 350 miles away to slow down so that they arrive at their landing slot when it is clear. It is like giving it a precise appointment.
Mr Rolfe said the system would work particularly well with the proposed new third runway at Heathrow Airport as aircraft become more sophisticated and numerous.
Lets be clear, a new runway will mean new routes and changes to existing routes, and we know that isnt easy, he said.
Traffic levels are expected to increase significantly from todays level until the new runway is operational, and will increase further.
Share or comment on this article
71
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="71">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Portreath bakery drive-thru opens to sell pasty's at a drive-thru
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151562/Pasty-pick-drive-bakery-drivers-stop-snack-opens-Cornwall.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Based in Pool, Cornwall, it opened today and features a 100-seat restaurant, a gluten-free bakery, a state-of-the-art baker-training facility and the first ever pasty drive-thru.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
She said: 'The drive- thru is important - because I don't like queuing.
'I was on my own with my children for a while and I found that I'd have to get out of the car, one of them would have dozed off and I couldn't get a loaf of bread.
'Sometimes I'd think - I need milk and you can't just leave your kids in the car - so, from our drive-thru, you'll be able to get a loaf of bread - and of course a pasty.
'The plans have been in the pipeline for 18 months and I am buzzing.'
She is now hoping to use the new site to export her pasties around the world, as well as selling other bakery products to locals.
She said: 'It's the perfect place for what I'd like to achieve for Cornwall and my business.
'Once you get the craving to bake it's in your blood. But you have to love it because it's a really hard job.'
Malcolm Bell from tourism group Visit Cornwall said: 'It's a great idea. We've been walking in and out of pasty shops for ages to get basically the world's best and earliest fast food.
'It's great to have a drive-thru which draws attention to the great pasty and great to have it in Redruth which is obviously one of the hearts of mining history.
'Anything that gives profile to Cornwall and gets it talked about helps us massively.'
Share or comment on this article
132
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="72">
        <date/>
        <title>
	One in three women admit to binge-drinking during pregnancy: Experts call for new guidelines advising no alcohol at all following findings
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151649/One-three-women-admit-binge-drinking-pregnancy-Experts-call-new-guidelines-advising-no-alcohol-following-findings.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Cambridge University researchers found 33 per cent of British women admitted to drinking the equivalent of two-thirds of a bottle of wine in a single sitting – at least once during their pregnancy.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
They found that 75 per cent of women in Britain had drunk alcohol at some point during pregnancy, compared to 82 per cent in Ireland, 56 per cent in New Zealand and 40 per cent in Australia. Some 33 per cent of British women admitted to bingeing  defined as six units, or three large glasses of wine, at a time  compared to 59 per cent of Irish women, 10 per cent of Australians and 9 per cent of New Zealanders.
The researchers called for a simplified code in which women are advised not to drink at all while pregnant. Since most women who consume alcohol do so at lower levels where the offspring growth and development effects are less well understood, the widespread consumption of even low levels of alcohol during pregnancy is a significant public health concern, they added.
Last month, Professor Sir Al Aynsley Green, president elect of the British Medical Association, criticised the contradictory and inconsistent advice given to women, and said: It has to be concluded that there is no safe limit for alcohol consumption during pregnancy.
Currently the Government warns that all pregnant women should avoid alcohol, but says that if they do drink, they should stick to one or two units once or twice a week.
Meanwhile the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (Nice) says that women should abstain from all alcohol in the first three months of pregnancy, after which point there is no evidence that drinking under three units twice a week will do any harm.
Responding to the Cambridge study, Clare Murphy, from the British Pregnancy Advisory Service, called for reassurance for women, adding: The majority of women in the UK are drinking well within the existing recommendations in the second trimester.
NHS midwife explains the dangers of drinking during pregnancy
FOUR STEPS TO HALVE RISK OF HEART FAILURE
Making just four healthy changes to your lifestyle, including keeping active, watching your weight and drinking only in moderation halves your risk of suffering heart failure in later life, research shows.
Experts tracked 4,490 men and women aged 65 and over for two decades, and found that those who broadly followed public health advice were healthiest.
Scientists from Tufts University in Massachusetts monitored participants diets, walking habits, leisure activities, exercise intensity, drinking, smoking, weight, height and waist circumference, then linked the different lifestyle traits to their health.
During the study, 1,380 participants suffered heart failure. But the data, published in the American College of Cardiology journal Heart Failure, suggested that those who adopted four or more of the healthy behaviours studied were half as likely to have heart failure as those who lived unhealthy lifestyles.
Share or comment on this article
55
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="73">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Alton Tower's crash victim Leah Washington gets card from Charles Bronson
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151429/Girl-17-lost-leg-Alton-Tower-s-crash-receives-soon-card-UK-s-dangerous-prisoner-Charles-Bronson.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Notorious criminal Charles Bronson, known as Britain's most violent prisoner, has sent Leah Washington, 17, a 'get well card' after she lost her leg in the Smiler crash at Alton Towers in June.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
2.2k shares
He claimed to kill off his previous persona Charles Bronson last year, by selling off all of his darker artworks.
The collection of around 100 works, based around the themes of torture and insanity, included satirical images of Simon Cowell and Prince Charles.
The 62-year-old prisoner now creates much calmer and less disturbing artworks, and donates many of them to help sick children in hospital.
He has also donated two pieces of artwork and a signed, self-written book to four-year-old leukaemia patient Frankie Allen.
It was while helping Frankie that Charles pen-pal Darren Holdcroft first heard about Leahs story, which he passed on to the prisoner, according to the Mirror.
Its a side not many people get to see, Darren told the Mirror.
Horrifying immediate aftermath of Smiler roller coaster accident
Changed man?: Charles Bronson changed his name to Charles Salvador last year, in honour of the Spanish surrealist painter Salvador Dali, and transformed his art from disturbing to charitable
Disturbing: Some of the prisoner's previous art works focus on themes such as torture and insanity. A piece of art by Bronson, or Salvador, now fetches anywhere between 400 and 1,000 at auction
Exhibition: A series of Charles Bronson's artworks appeared on the London Underground during a controversial two-week exhibition in 2010. He now donates art works to sick children in hospital to help them raise money for treatment
The amount of art he produces for sick children is unbelievable and he has helped raise thousands of pounds and hopefully now he can help to raise some funds for Leah and her familys charities too.
An artwork by Salvador is said to collect anywhere between 400 and 1,000 at auction, largely due to his very violent reputation.
His intimidating rap sheet includes convictions for wounding, threatening to kill, damaging prison property and taking hostages while behind bars.
Of his 62 years, he has spent more than 40 behind bars, despite never actually committing murder.
He has done time in more than 120 prisons, including Broadmoor, Rampton and Ashworth; has taken at least 11 hostages; done more than half a million pounds in damages; and spent just four months and nine days out of prison since 1974, according to ozy.com.
Reputation for violence: Bronson (left) has spent 40 of his 62 years behind bars, for crimes including wounding, threatening to kill, damaging prison property and taking hostages while behind bars. Although he has never committed murder, he continuously increases his sentences by committing criminal acts while in prison. He was played by actor Tom Hardy (right) in a 2008 biopic entitled 'Bronson'
His prison career began in 1974 when he was arrested for stealing 26.
But his violent behaviour in prison has seen him consistently extending his sentences.
In 1998, for example, seven years were added to his jail sentence after he took two Iraqi hijackers and another inmate hostage at Belmarsh prison in London.
While insisting that the hostages call him General, he told negotiators he would eat one of the hostages unless they gave in to his demands.
He wanted a helicopter to Cuba, two Uzi sub-machine guns, 5,000 rounds of ammo and an axe.
At one point, he demanded one of the hostages hit him over the head with a metal tray, and when the hostage refused, Bronson slashed his own shoulder six times with a razor blade, according to the BBC.
In court he admitted that he was as guilty as Adolf Hitler, but added: I was on a mission of madness, but now Im on a mission of peace and all I want to do now is get home and have a pint with my son.
The criminal has one son, Michael, by his first wife.
When he married a second time, to Bangladeshi-born divorcee Fatema Saira Rehman, he spent a four-year stint as a Muslim.
His wife persuaded to convert and to go by the name of Charles Ali Ahmed, until the couple divorced four years later and he renounced Islam.
Since adopting a more creative and less destructive style of life, he has won 11 Koestler Trust Awards  which honour art by prisoners  and taken part in a controversial two-week exhibition on the London Underground in 2010.

Share or comment on this article
2.2k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="74">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Malaysian mountain closed to tourists after Eleanor Hawkins stripped off
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151363/Malaysian-mountain-closed-tourists-British-student-stripped-photos-jailed-angering-spirits.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The British Government issued advice to travellers today warning that climbing activities on Mount Kinabalu are expected to be suspended until September.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
Eleanor Hawkins, 23, from Draycott in Derbyshire, was thrown behind bars for apparently offending the gods by stripping off with other tourists at the summit of the mountain.
Hours later,18 people were killed and hundreds left stranded when an earthquake struck.
Backpackers including Miss Hawkins stripped naked on top of Mount Kinabalu, a sacred mountain in Malaysia
Climbing activities on Mount Kinabalu, on the island of Borneo, are expected to be suspended until September
Locals blamed a group of tourists - including the British university graduate  - for triggering the quake.
They believed that when she and others posed topless for a photograph, they were 'showing disrespect to the sacred mountain'.
The aeronautical engineering graduate was arrested with three others, fined 5,000 Malaysian ringgit (859) and sentenced to three days in jail,which she had already served, at a court hearing in Kota Kinabalu.
She later travelled back to the UK where she made a tearful public apology.
Speaking outside her home in Derby last month, shesaid: 'I just want to say how relieved and happy I am to finally be home.
'I know my behaviour was foolish and I know how much offence we all caused to the local people of Sabah. For that, I am truly sorry.'
Eleanor Hawkins gives statement outside her family home
Miss Hawkins smiles (pictured centre) with her three co-accused as she sets off on her ill-fated trip
Miss Hawkins (in the red top) and Canadian national Lindsey Petersen (black top) are escorted by police as they were led into court in Kota Kinabalu last month
After serving three days in jail, Miss Hawkins travelled back to the UK where she made a tearful public apology

Share or comment on this article
15
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="75">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Jenus Fiouzi sues Commerzbank AG for £7million
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151109/Hedge-fund-manager-130-000-year-sues-bank-7million-male-colleagues-chatted-German-didn-t-invite-drinks-work.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Foreign exchange manager Jenus Fiouzi, 43, claims key decisions at Commerzbank AG's London office were made during all male drinking sessions to which she wasn't invited.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'It then became evident to me that decisions about work matters were being taken during drinking sessions because when the same matters later came up in the office, I was out of the loop.'
She added: 'The men's social relationships really strengthened their working relationships, so by excluding me from the social side, I felt they put up a barrier at work.
'My team frequently excluded me from business discussions by insisting on communicating in German when I was around.'
She said some colleagues would talk across her in German adding: 'This excluded me and made me feel uncomfortable and marginalised.
Jenus Fiouzi told a Central London Employment Tribunal that her colleagues at the London branch of Commerzbank AG (pictured) often spoke German in front of her, leaving her feeling 'isolated and outnumbered'
'There genuinely were two sets of rules. One for German men and one for me.
'As a woman I was seen as easy to challenge and my achievements were less important than a man's, particularly a German man, and therefore easy to dismiss and redistribute to the wider team.'
Ms Fiouzi said she had never experienced such treatment in the workplace before.
She added: 'I am a woman who does not go around making these accusations lightly.
'I have worked in this industry, and it is a tough industry, for 15 years, where I have worked with lots of different people from lots of different nationalities and they are all mostly men.
'In 15 years I have never [had] this level of discrimination in any workplace.
'I made suggestions about how to make improvements, but no one wanted to hear my suggestions. They said I was rocking the boat.'
Speaking outside the tribunal hearing, Jennifer Sole, of Ms Fiouzi's legal team, said: 'Ms Fiouzi is claiming around 7million from Commerzbank for loss of earnings and injury to feelings.'
There were two sets of rules. One for German men and one for me
Commerzbank denies all the allegations claiming Ms Fiouzi was let go because she failed to meet targets.
In a statement the bank said: 'Commerzbank categorically denies that Ms Fiouzi was subjected to any detriment on the grounds of her race, gender or of any other sort.
'Her descriptions of working life at Commerzbank's London office bear little relationship to the reality and the allegations she makes are all denied.'
In its evidence to the tribunal the company said: 'It quickly became apparent that the claimant was a difficult person to get on with and did little to integrate herself with the team.'
Commerzbank also says Ms Fiouzi's 'conduct at work was often disruptive' and that 'she argued with colleagues' and 'ignored instructions'.
But Trevor Malin, head of the Foreign Exchange Sales in London, said she failed to join in with the team rather than her being shunned.
He told the tribunal: 'Whenever I heard them speaking German, it was clear that they were discussing the work that they were doing together, confirming numeric values and were not discussing matters that would disadvantage Jenus in any way.
'In her claim Jenus seems to suggest that the business of the desk was conducted in German. That is not correct. The business of the desk was conducted in English and all team meetings and discussions were held in English.
'My German would not have been good enough to conduct such meetings in German.
Ms Fiouzi was fired by the bank in October 2014 and is claiming 7million for loss of earnings and injury to feelings after suffering sex and race discrimination and unfair dismissal
'What she says about there being a "band of brothers" or that there was a boyish frat-like atmosphere is incorrect.
'It is paramount that the sales and trading desks work together effectively as a team. Communication and developing relationships with colleagues are key.
'It is not unusual for employees of the bank to meet at the pub after work, especially after some stressful days.
'Having a drink together after work is a great way to build relationships and wind down after a hard day.
'There was no formal invitation to people. There was a standing invitation and it was well known by everyone that employees would go to a bar called the Fine Line, which was very close to the bank's office. I would pop in on my way home about twice a week.
'Jenus in common with everyone else, was invited, but only very rarely attended. That was symptomatic of her overall failure to integrate into the team. Neither sex nor nationality was relevant at all to employees socialising.'
He said Ms Fiouzi 'integrated poorly into the team and continually seemed to have issues' with other staff.
Jenus told me on several occasions that she was unhappy with the way things were going
Managing Director Jessica James, head of quantitative solutions group told the hearing: 'Jenus alleges that there were no senior female managers on the trading side of FIC - fixed income and currencies.
'That is incorrect. There are, I understand, 18 senior females, directors and managing directors in FIC, including me. I work on the trading side.'
She added: 'I ended getting on well with her. Towards the end of her time with the bank, I realised Jenus was unhappy.
'Jenus told me on several occasions that she was unhappy with the way things were going for her in the business sense.
'I understand Jenus is alleging that she was discriminated against because of her sex and race. Jenus did not raise with me at any time any complaint of mistreatment on the grounds of her sex or her race.
She added that she would would have encouraged Ms Fiouzi to go to the bank's HR team if the matter had been raised.
'I understand that Jenus makes general complaints about the bank being discriminatory towards women and non-Germans. I do not believe this is the case. I have never felt that the bank discriminates against women or non-Germans.
'I have never seen any evidence of this and of discrimination against female or non-German colleagues. I have never seen this at all.
'I don't recognise the German speaking club atmosphere at all. The trading floor was very inclusive, diverse and respectful towards women. I don't recognise the picture that has been painted.'
The tribunal continues.
Share or comment on this article
212
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="76">
        <date/>
        <title>
	After man brandishes ISIS flag outside Big Ben now a shopper parks car emblazoned with flag of Hezbollah at an Asda (and, yes, that's allowed too) 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151395/After-man-brandishes-Isis-flag-outside-Big-Ben-shopper-parks-car-Asda-flag-Hezbollah-yes-s-fine-too.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	EXCLUSIVE: The terrorist-linked group's emblem was printed on to a Syria flag on the side of a blue Subaru Impreza, spotted outside an Asda store in London's Wembley Park today.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>After man brandishes ISIS flag outside Big Ben now a shopper parks car emblazoned with flag of Hezbollah at an Asda (and, yes, that's allowed too)
EXCLUSIVE: Blue Subaru Impreza was sighted in car park in Wembley
Hezbollah emblem was printed on to Syria flag visible on side of the car
Lebanon-based group are labelled terrorists by much of developed world
Have been linked to a number of deadly bomb attacks in recent years
Published: 19:51 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 22:20 GMT, 6 July 2015
3k shares
comments
A car was spotted today outside an Asda store bearing the flag of terrorist-associated organisation Hezbollah.
The sighting,in Wembley Park, comes one day aftera man strolled past the Houses of Parliament draped in an Islamic State flag with a young girl on his shoulders.
Both actions have been deemed 'within the law' by police, despite the latter making many feel unsafe on the streets of Britain.
Political statement: The emblem, printed on to a Syria flag, was spotted on the side of a car in an Asda car park in London
Hezbollahis a Shia militant group and political party based in Lebanon, which was formed with Iranian support  in 1982 after an Israeli invasion.
The group's military arm is considered a terrorist organisation by many developed countries in the world including the UK.
Recently Australian security forces decided it would remain  listed as a terrorist organisation as the group is still involved in the 'planning, coordination and execution of terrorist attacks', reports the Guardian.
Hezbollah's external security organisation (ESO) has previously been accused of a number of terrorist attacks against Jewish and Israeli targets.
RELATED ARTICLES
Share this article
Share
This includes the 1994 bombing of an ArgentinianIsraeli institution in Buenos Aires that killed 85.
And three years ago it was accused of blowing up an Israeli tourist bus in Burgas, Bulgaria, killing six.
The organisation has recently been working alongside Syrian government forces to recapture the strategic city of Zabadani, near Damascus, from rebels.
Proud of terrorist-associated group: TheHezbollah flag is visible in the Asda car park in Wembley Park, much to one shopper's surprise
Today, the group's emblem was seen printed on to a Syria flag on the side of aSubaru Impreza parked outside an Asda store.
Responding to the sighting, police said:'Wearing, carrying or displaying of an emblem or flag, by itself, is not an offence unless; the way in which, or the circumstance in which, the emblem is worn, carried or displayed is such as to cause reasonable suspicion that the person is a supporter or member of a proscribed organisation.'
The same legislation was quoted in response to the incident outside the Houses of Parliament yesterday, to the frustration of many witnesses.
One social media user called Gavin tweeted: 'Why are we allowing this to happen on our streets a man walking past big ben with an ISIS flag.
'Walk through London past Big Ben with an ISIS flag nothing done do it with swastika what would be done?'
Tony Lancaster said: 'Man walks round central London with an ISIS flag but wasn't arrested because he broke no laws.Cud only happen here.'
Henry Lawson said: 'Man &amp; child with Isis flag London....hope this is hoax.'
The pictures have caused particular panic as they were taken as Londoners prepare to mark a decade since the July 7 terror attacks.
Terrorist links:Hezbollah's external security organisation (ESO) has previously been accused of a number of terrorist attacks against Jewish and Israeli targets
Hezbollah's military arm is considered a terrorist organisation by most developed countries in the world including the UK
Scotland Yard said officers spoke to the man and considered his actions within the Public Order Act 1986.
A spokesman said: 'This man was spoken to by officers with consideration given to relevant legislation and a decision was taken by officers at the time that the man was acting within the law. He was not arrested.'
The Public Order Act states that a person is guilty if he: 'Displays any writing, sign or other visible representation which is threatening, abusive or insulting within the hearing or sight of a person likely to be caused harassment, alarm or distress thereby.'
A Home Office spokesman said: 'ISIS is a prescribed group. Showing signs you are a supporter of that group is an offence.
'It was an operational decision and we cannot comment on individual cases.'
Last week London became the scene of a mock terrorist attack when emergency services took part in a drill ensuring they are prepared 'should the worst happen'.
Emergency services were faced with a Tunisian-style terrorist gun massacre during the two-day operation.
Former Scotland Yard terror chief Peter Clarke has warned that ISIS poses 'a huge and deadly threat'.
Hezbollah leader says war on Syria has failed
Parading through London: Today's sighting comes just one day after after a man strolled past the Houses of Parliament draped in an Islamic State flag with a young girl on his shoulders
He said: 'At the moment we are arresting one person for terror-related crimes every day. That's the highest rate at any point in 15 years, apart from the immediate aftermath of 9/11 and 7/7. There are 120 people awaiting trial as we speak.'
But he added: 'Every year since 7/7, massive plots to commit terrorist acts have been thwarted.' He called UK counter-terrorism 'the envy of the world'.
Last month a flag decorated with sex toy symbols was mistaken for that of Islamic State in a CNN report on the gay pride parade in London.
Read more:
Share or comment on this article
3k
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="77">
        <date/>
        <title>
	One policeman holds off 150 gatecrashers outside Wireless festival at Finsbury Park
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151205/Amazing-footage-shows-lone-policeman-holding-150-gatecrashers-trying-batter-way-Wireless-music-festival.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The officer charged to the front of a huge crowd as they banged at the green barriers surrounding the Wireless festival grounds at Finsbury Park in London.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
The newspaper reports that more than a million people have seen the video online.
In the film, a police officer can be seen running towards a crowd as they repeatedly strike the metal barrier.
Despite the potentially dangerous situation, the officer bravely pushes his way to the front.
Seconds later, the crowds suddenly move away before festival security guards move in to help secure the area.
One-man show:He went on to single-highhandedly fend off the would-be festival-goers, armed only with a metal baton, until security guards at the event turned up to help
The footage then goes on to show a struggle involving a smaller group in which the officer can be seen holding a metal baton as he works with security to keep the crowd back.
The scenes turn even uglier as missiles appear to be thrown, clattering against the metal barriers inches above their heads.
Some in the crowd appear to wave others over towards the flash point as security guards try to ease tensions.
The Standard quotes an eyewitness as saying: 'The officer was unbelievable. It looked like people were ready to start a riot and he showed no fear. He just bowled in there and dealt with it all single-handedly.'
Chief constable for Surrey Police Lynne Owens tweeted: 'Shocking footage... As ever, officers run towards trouble, even when alone.'
It says Hackney police sergeant Richard Bern then tweeted: 'Just by being there, this officer likely prevented a GBH. Putting the safety of others before his own.'
The officer has yet to be named by Met police.
The unnamed officer was praised for his bravery, having prevented scores of intruders from storming into the three-day festival
Chaos as gatecrashes try to get into Wireless festival
The Standard reports that police are not taking action over the crowd trouble and quotes a Wireless Festival spokesman as saying: 'There were a small number of incidents that were dealt with quickly where no-one was hurt, on an otherwise hugely successful Wireless weekend.
'Organisers of Wireless Festival take security very seriously and work closely with ShowSec Security, Local Police and other agencies to put procedures in place to ensure the event maintains an enjoyable and secure environment for all its customers.'
Wireless festival this year featured the likes of Kendrick Lamar, Drake,DJ David Guetta and singer Jessie J.
Organisers faced embarrassment after American rapper and hip hop star Nicki Minaj missed her supporting slot because of 'travel issues'.
A message which flashed up on screen at the festival saying: 'Special announcement: we are told that she was due to be speeding down the M1 from Luton Airport as we speak but we have lost contact with her, we are hoping that she will be here soon.'
The Starships singer finally made it on stage to perform one song with festival headliner David Guetta, her spokesman said.

Read more:
Share or comment on this article
447
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="78">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Diver Sabrina Belloni holds her breath for two minutes as she swims with whales
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151183/Swimming-giants-Diver-holds-breath-two-minutes-swims-alongside-whales-longer-BUS.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Sabrina Belloni, 49, a senior tourism executive from Italy, spent ten days swimming with the mammals in the waters around the Caribbean, diving up to 50ft down without oxygen.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Swimming with giants: Diver holds her breath for two minutes as she swims alongside whales which are longer than a BUS
Sabrina Belloni dived up to 50ft while holding her breath for more than two minutes to get close to the whales
Spent ten days following a pod of seven, mostly made up of females and their young, off the Caribbean coast
Photographer Franco Banfi, who specialises in underwater photography,capturedher time beneath the waves
Published: 16:22 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 18:48 GMT, 6 July 2015
176 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="79">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Boris Johnson says cut 45p tax rate AFTER bosses pay their staff properly
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3150725/Cut-rate-tax-40p-rich-bosses-pay-staff-properly-says-Boris-Johnson.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The London Mayor said a tax cut for the wealthy cannot be supported until business leaders pay their staff a living wage which means they do not have to rely on welfare to top up their income.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share
34 shares
A study by Citizens UK this year showed that there were 5.2million low paid workers in supermarkets and shops the UK, receiving 11billion in state support through tax credits.
It is argued that if their firms paid them the Living Wage instead of the minimum wage it would save the taxpayer 6.7billion in benefits.
Mr Johnson said it was a 'serious problem' which needed to be sorted out before a cut in the top rate of tax can go ahead.
Writing in the Daily Telegraph , he said: 'It is simply not fair that a Budget should put more disposable income in the pockets of the rich and less disposable income in the pockets of the poor.
'And that, alas, would be the result if we were to cut top-rate tax and simultaneously to cut in-work benefits without any compensating improvements in pay.'
Mr Johnson pointed to figures showing that five of the country's biggest retailers  Tesco, Asda, Sainsbury's, Morrison's and Next  receive '1billion-a-year in taxpayer-funded subsidies for their wages bill'
Reports suggest that workers at five of the country's biggest retailers  Tesco, Asda, Sainsbury's, Morrison's and Next  receive 1billion-a-year in taxpayer-funded subsidies topping up their low wages.
Some businesses have already adopted the Living Wage of 7.85 an hour (9.15 in London), rather than the adult national minimum wage of 6.50.
Mr Johnson insists low pay is not a function of market forces. 'It's being propped up by the taxpayer. That needs to end. And that means business has got to start paying its people a wage they can live on.
'Yes, we should be cutting taxes all round  cutting the top rate as well as lifting the thresholds and taking the poor out of tax.
'We should have the most competitive tax regime in Europe. But we need to make clear to the business leaders of this country that we can only cut tax for them at the top if they do the right thing: treat their workers properly and pay them a living wage.'
George Osborne will use his first Conservative Budget this week to announce plans for deep cuts in tax credits, paid to people in work who earn too little to live on
Government has found 12 billion pounds of welfare cuts
Last week shadow chancellor Chris Leslie said it would be 'an act of gross irresponsibility and unfairness' for the Government to press ahead with a rumoured cut in the 45p rate for those who earned more than 150,000.
Mr Osborne yesterday indicated he is not planning to cut the top rate in the Budget, saying his priority is reducing taxes for lower and middle income earners.
Conservative former Cabinet minister John Redwood said cutting the rate to 40p would encourage the wealthiest to pay more tax.
He told BBC Radio 4's Today programme: 'The way to get more money off the rich is to have tax rates they are prepared to pay.
'We have just seen a big surge of revenues when we cut the 50p rate to 45p and that's very encouraging. Of course, Gordon Brown knew the right answer, the right answer was a 40% rate.'
Share or comment on this article
34
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="80">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Get used to the heat – scorching summers are set to become the norm while winters will be warmer and wetter the Met Office warns
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3151181/Get-used-heat-scorching-summers-set-norm-winters-warmer-wetter-Met-Office-warns.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The Met Office said studies of long-range climate projections for the UK, based on 30-year averages, show a general trend towards hotter, drier summers and milder winters.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Get used to the heat  scorching summers are set to become the norm while winters will be warmer and wetter the Met Office warns
Weather experts predict Britain will see warmer summers and wetter but milder winters by the end of the century
Met Office said: 'The future UK climate can now be described in terms of the extreme hot, cold, wet or dry seasons'
It comes as temperatures will drop this week with rain and thunderstorms in the north but dry conditions in south
But forecasters predict the mercury will begin to climb again from Wednesday as heatwave makes a return with 29C
Published: 16:12 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 16:12 GMT, 6 July 2015
12 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="81">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Leeds rape suspect is arrested and extradited to UK from SLOVAKIA
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3150971/Rape-suspect-feared-carried-horrifying-attack-18-year-old-woman-dragged-bus-stop-Leeds-arrested-extradited-SLOVAKIA.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	According to Slovak Television service Markiza, the 21-year-old man has only been named as Zdenko T, and will arrive in the UK on 10 July.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Rape suspect feared to have carried out horrifying attack on an 18-year-old woman who was dragged from a bus stop in Leeds is arrested and extradited from SLOVAKIA
Slovakian man, 21, will extradited from Slovakia to the UK on 10 July
Arrested over brutal rape of 18-year-old in Leeds on March 30 this year
Victim was dragged from bus stop, raped, and beaten 20 times with a rock
Published: 14:16 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 14:43 GMT, 6 July 2015
88 shares
A 21-year-old man will be extradited to the UK after being arrested in Slovakia for the attempted murder and rape of an 18-year-old woman  at a bus stop in Leeds earlier this year.
According to Slovak Television service Markiza, the man has only been named as Zdenko T, and will arrive in the UK on 10 July.
In a joint operation with British police officers, the suspect was tracked down to a local farm and arrested by police in Kosice, situated in eastern Slovakia.
The man was wanted over the attack of a woman at a bus stop on Beeston Road, Leeds, at 10.50pm on March 30, in which she was dragged into a nearby garden, raped, and beaten with a rock.
West Yorkshire Police released an e-fit of the suspect at the time. A 21-year-old man known as Zdenko T was arrested and will be extradited from Slovakia to the UK
A 21-year-old man has been arrested in Slovakia over the attempted murder and rape of an 18-year-old woman who was dragged from this bus stop in Leeds before being attacked
The Slovakian, who has only been identified as Zdenko T, will be extradited to the UK (pictured, CCTV of the suspected attacker released during the police investigation)
After the attack, the suspect returned to his native Slovakia, where he was found shortly after an arrest warrant was issued.
Following his arrest, the man accepted the choice of extradition to the UK and is expected to arrive by the end of the week.
RELATED ARTICLES
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="82">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Abdul Mosa who killed son spared jail by judge who says he's suffered enough 
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3150884/Dangerous-driver-killed-one-young-son-left-life-changing-injuries-spared-jail-judge-says-suffered-enough.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	Abdul Mosa, 43, (pictured) from Leeds was driving on the wrong side of the road when his family's car hit a lorry head-on, killing his seven-year-old, Alin, and injuring six-year-old Ara.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Next
Dangerous driver who killed his son and left another with life-changing injuries because he was on wrong side of the road coming back from France is spared jail by judge who says he has suffered enough
Abdul Mosa, 43, was driving family car on the wrong side of the road when he crashed into lorry
Alin Mosa, seven, killed in crash on A20 in Kent and Ara Mosa, six, injured
Family were on the way home from France and had just left the Eurotunnel
Mosa will be 'punished every minute of the rest of his life', says judge
Published: 11:07 GMT, 6 July 2015 | Updated: 13:51 GMT, 6 July 2015
41 shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="83">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Match.com conman Adewale Adewole's duped women to be paid back few hundred pounds
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3150694/Four-women-duped-100-000-lonely-hearts-conman-dating-website-Match-com-posed-Royal-Marine-pounds-each.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	The victims paid money to Nigerian Adewale Adewole, 31, of Manchester, after he posed as a Royal Marine commando nicknamed 'Charismatic Brit' on the dating website Match.com.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>Share this article
Share
'There was a profile picture on his Match accounts and he sent some of the women photographs of himself - all of these pictures were actually of a Royal Marine Commander called Joshua McGowan who knew nothing of what was going on.
'Each of the women wanted to find out more about him and were led to believe they were in a relationship with him. Although they arranged to meet, he never kept to the arrangements and never did meet any of the victims.
Miss Brandon added: 'He told the women that on a trip to Africa he was the victim of a crime and needed money. The crime meant he could not access his own funds. He said they would get their money back and would be sent letters from the World Health Organisation to show that he would be able to pay them.
The Match.com victims known only as Miss E, Miss A, Miss W and Miss H will get back just 863.38, 332.07, 199.26 and 819.10 respectively after police auctioned off the spoils of Adewole's fraud
'These letters were sent, but from an M30 Manchester postmark. He also sent them links to websites which, when logging in with details he gave them, appeared to show that he had a huge bank balance and would eventually be able to pay them back.
'One woman was asked to pay for a hotel for him. When she rang the number he gave her for the hotel, they also confirmed the information and she agreed to pay it. She later received a cheque addressed to him for 35,000 to prove he had money, but this was later discovered to be a stolen cheque forged in his own handwriting.
'Over a number of months each woman transferred significant sums of money via bank accounts and Western Union moneygrams and sent items to the defendant's home address. They bought electronic items, took out credit cards and loans and bought clothes from Next. Many of the goods were sent to his home address in Eccles from where the victims believed they would be forwarded on to the defendant in Nigeria.
'When the women stopped sending money they never heard from him again.'
The court heard the total amount stolen including the value of the household goods and Western Union transfers was 98,140.
Adewole was arrested in October 2012 at his flat and 4,500 in cash was found under his bed. A digital camera was found purchased by one of the victims, but containing pictures of the defendant and his wife and children. Designer clothes and shoes were also found worth 2,000 alone.
Adewole's wallet was also seized and contained several SIM cards, some of which contained the phone numbers of the victims. His two Blackberry phones were also seized - on these three different email accounts were in use which were linked to the two Match accounts. He was bailed and later tried to call one of the woman again under the name Timmy Francis and was arrested again.
When questioned he claimed to know nothing of the orphanage but that the 4,500 was his. He said the majority of the items found in his flat were to go to his mother in Nigeria. He admitted he had used Match.com in 2010, 2011 and 2012 but could not remember when exactly.
The victims known only as Miss E, Miss A, Miss W and Miss H will get back just 863.38, 332.07, 199.26 and 819.10 respectively.
Defence counsel Mr Khadim Al'Hassan said: 'I'm surprised by the amount from the auctions, it must have been a really bad day because they were all new items.'

Share or comment on this article
490
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="84">
        <date/>
        <title>
	Clarifications and corrections for extremism on university campuses graphic
      </title>
        <Link>
	http://www.dailymail.co.uk/home/article-3146759/Clarifications-corrections.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490
      </Link>
        <Description>
	To report an inaccuracy, please email corrections@dailymail.co.uk. To make a formal complaint under IPSO rules please go to www.dailymail.co.uk/readerseditor.
      </Description>
        <MainBody>By Daily Mail Reporter
Published: 02:53 GMT, 2 July 2015 | Updated: 03:18 GMT, 2 July 2015
The headline on a graphic which accompanied a report about extremism on university campuses in yesterdays paper wrongly stated that the individuals listed had spoken at the academic institutions concerned. In fact they attended them.

To report an inaccuracy, please email corrections@dailymail.co.uk. To make a formal complaint under IPSO rules please go to www.dailymail.co.uk/readerseditor where you will find an easy-to-use complaints form. You can also write to Readers Editor, Daily Mail, Northcliffe House, 2 Derry Street, London W8 5TT.
Share or comment on this article
438
Sorry we are not currently accepting comments on this article.
Bing
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
