<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Here's what FIFA's corporate partners are saying about the indictments</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150528/heres-what-fifas-corporate-partners-are-saying-about-the-indictments</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Heres what FIFAs corporate partners are saying about the indictments
Brazuca match balls for the FIFA World Cup 2014 lie in a rack in front of the Adidas logo on December 6, 2013 in Scheinfeld near Herzogenaurach, Germany (Lennart Preiss/Getty Images)
By Timothy McGrath, GlobalPost
# Comments
When times get tough, you lean on your friends.
FIFAs best friends are multinational corporations , and theirs is a friendship rooted in helping one another make lots and lots of money.
So what are FIFAs corporate partners and World Cup sponsors saying today  a day when the US Justice Department has indicted 14 people, nine current and former FIFA officials and five sports marketing executives, on charges of racketeering, wire fraud, and money laundering?
Their responses have ranged from silence to carefully crafted press releases. And thats probably wise, considering the alleged corruption seems so metastatic and high-level that youve got to wonder how many places it touches.
Just listen to Kelly T. Currie, acting United States attorney for the Eastern District of New York, whose words might be enough to send many a corporate legal department into a tizzy.
This is the beginning of our effort, not the end, she said. We are looking into individuals and entities in a variety of countries. That includes financial institutions, 25 currently unnamed co-conspirators, and who knows what else.
Until this morning, Coca-Cola, Visa, Adidas et al. probably thought the biggest threat to their FIFA-affiliated profits were human rights concerns surrounding the upcoming World Cups in Russia (2018) and Qatar (2022). Nope.
Heres what FIFAs corporate BFFs are saying about the indictments:
1. Adidas
The German sportswear company wrote in an email to Business Insider :
The Adidas Group is fully committed to creating a culture that promotes the highest standards of ethics and compliance, and we expect the same from our partners. Following todays news, we can therefore only encourage FIFA to continue to establish and follow transparent compliance standards in everything they do.
Adidas is the worlds leading football brand and we will continue to support football on all levels.
2. Coca-Cola
Coke says:
This lengthy controversy has tarnished the mission and ideals of the FIFA World Cup and we have repeatedly expressed our concerns about these serious allegations. FIFA has stated that it is responding to all requests for information and we are confident it will continue to cooperate fully with the authorities.
3. Visa
Visa took longer than Adidas and Coca-Cola to comment. Maybe thats because it took some time to write this strongly worded demand for reform  or else.
Our disappointment and concern with FIFA in light of todays developments is profound. As a sponsor, we expect FIFA to take swift and immediate steps to address these issues within its organization. This starts with rebuilding a culture with strong ethical practices in order to restore the reputation of the games for fans everywhere.
Advertisement
Visa became a sponsor of FIFA because the World Cup is one of the few truly global sporting events with the power to unite people from around the world through a common love of football. Our sponsorship has always focused on supporting the teams, enabling a great fan experience, and inspiring communities to come together and celebrate the spirit of competition and personal achievement  and it is important that FIFA makes changes now, so that the focus remain on these going forward. Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship.
4. Hyundai/Kia Motors
Hyundai, which owns Kia, says :
As a company that places the highest priority on ethical standards and transparency, Hyundai Motor is extremely concerned about the legal proceedings being taken against certain FIFA executives and will continue to monitor the situation closely.
5. McDonalds
A spokesperson told Bloomberg News that McDonalds takes matters of ethics and corruption very seriously and the news from the US Department of Justice is extremely concerning.
6. Budweiser/AB InBev
We expect all of our partners to maintain strong ethical standards and operate with transparency, AFP quoted a Budweiser spokesperson as saying.
7. Gazprom
Russias state-owned oil and gas giant went in another direction.
There is no concrete accusation against us, a spokesperson told AFP.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>United States welcomed as liberators by soccer fans around the world</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150528/united-states-welcomed-as-liberators-by-soccer-fans-around-the-world</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
United States welcomed as liberators by soccer fans around the world
That soccer ball looks a little flat. Here, let Uncle Sam pump it full of freedom. (Jonathan Ferrey/AFP/Getty Images)
By GlobalPost
# Comments
Call it spreading democracy, call it a liberation, call it a toppling of dictators, call it whatever the heck you want. America just saved football  which the whole world can now start calling soccer, thank you very much.
Football fans around the world rejoiced on Wednesday after a US-led coalition, acting on intelligence provided by the FBI, moved to hold accountable several high-level leaders within world footballs notorious governing body, the Fdration Internationale de Football Association (FIFA).
In a series of early morning raids that provoked shock and awe among fans, teams of Swiss security forces apprehended and detained seven FIFA officials at a hotel compound in Zurich.
The Swiss  not know for their willingness to support US foreign interventions  were acting on behalf of the US Justice Department, who had requested the extradition of the officials on charges that include  racketeering, wire fraud and money laundering conspiracies , among other offenses, in connection with the defendants participation in a 24-year scheme to enrich themselves through the corruption of international soccer.
They corrupted the business of worldwide soccer, said US Attorney General Loretta Lynch at a press conference held hours after the arrest.
FIFA, a global organization with cash reserves of more than a billion dollars, has long been plagued by allegations of corruption and a disregard for human rights. The federations Secretary-General, Jerome Valcke, once said that less democracy is sometimes better for organizing a World Cup. (The US federal government and the United Nations have not sought to use sanctions against FIFA, and it does not appear on the State Departments list of Foreign Terrorist Organizations.)
So far, the US operation against FIFA appears to have been markedly better received on the global stage than previous foreign interventions, like those in Iraq, Libya and Afghanistan. The Washington Post, which backed the Iraq War , also found cause to support this latest adventure.
The best American foreign policy action taken in 2015, read the headline on a story on the newspapers website Wednesday.
Josh Barro, a reporter at The New York Times  a newspaper which built the case for the Iraq War with its later discredited reporting on Saddam Husseins WMD program  wrote on Twitter : Dear World: We dont even like soccer and were still going to clean up FIFA for you. Love, America.
Advertisement
Messages of gratitude filled social media as people thanked the US for pumping football full of freedom  most notably from Britain , where the game of football was invented.
Many Americans who had probably never heard of FIFA before Wednesday were nonetheless happy that an enemy of democracy had been smashed.
Absent in the jubilation surrounding the arrests was a solid plan for what would replace FIFA should the investigation go any further. A transitional government perhaps? But for now, its celebration time.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:17:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>These are a few of FIFA's biggest fish now under indictment</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150528/these-are-a-few-of-fifas-biggest-fish-now-under-indictment</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>These are a few of FIFAs biggest fish now under indictment
Soccer's governing body headquarters in Zurich. (Fabrice Coffirini/AFP/Getty Images)
By Simeon Tegel, GlobalPost
# Comments
LIMA, Peru  Todays dawn raid on FIFA executives at a $4,000-a-night Zurich hotel has rocked world soccer, and served up a juicy scandal for people who wouldnt otherwise care about the game.
The joint US-Swiss operation netted seven of FIFAs biggest fish on corruption charges. Now they face extradition to the United States. Several others were indicted .
Perhaps the biggest surprise wasnt the allegations themselves, but that some FIFA executives may now be about to face the music.
Heres a look at some of the highest profile soccer execs named in the case.
Former head of Brazilian Football Confederation (CBF) Jose Maria Marin
Marin, 83, is possibly the biggest name nabbed in Zurich. As CBF president he also headed the organizing committee for last years Brazil World Cup.
That event could hardly have been more polarizing , given the millions of dollars sunk into glittering new stadiums in a country where many still go without three meals a day . Yet it may be the least of the controversies that have long dogged Marin.
He has been accused of colluding with Brazils military dictatorship during a period in which he rose to become governor of Sao Paulo state, the motor of Latin Americas largest economy.
As for Marins honesty, you might want to check out this video (around minute 0:16): He can be seen stealthily pocketing a winners medal he was supposed to hand out at a Sao Paulo state soccer tournament. He later claimed the incident was a joke.
Romario, a Brazilian soccer legend turned senator, summed up the feelings of many Brazilians when he greeted news of Marins arrest in Zurich by calling him a thief and a rat.
FIFA Vice President Jeffrey Webb
Jeffrey Webb is a British national based in the Cayman Islands, from where he also chairs the Confederation of North, Central America and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF). His arrest appears to be the first time hes been publicly tarnished by corruption allegations.
In fact, the 50-year-old veep has actually spoken out against graft within world soccers governing body. Last year he called for FIFAs internal report on corruption, by former US attorney Michael Garcia, to be made public. Garcia was angered enough by FIFAs handling of his report that he quit his post as its chief ethics investigator.
Other than that, Webbs public profile seems to have largely revolved around his role as chair of FIFAs anti-racism task force, which frequently attacks discrimination within the game.
Advertisement
Nicolas Leoz, ex-head of South Americas soccer federation
Leoz was a member of FIFAs executive committee for 15 years, and president of South Americas soccer federation, CONMEBOL, for nearly two decades, until he stood down from both positions in 2013. And the 86-year-old Paraguayan is not new to accusations of graft.
In 2010, the BBC accused him of taking bribes from TV companies to award them rights to air soccer matches. The following year David Triesman, then the head of Englands Football Association, accused Leoz of demanding knighthood in return for supporting Englands bid to host the 2018 World Cup.
If that sounds crazy, Triesman also claimed Leoz asked for the FA Cup, English soccers second most important competition, to be renamed after him. Leoz has denied the allegations and was subsequently cleared over Triesmans claims by an FA investigation.
The Paraguayan government received a US extradition request for Leoz on Wednesday.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 01:41:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pentagon: Military mistakenly shipped live anthrax samples</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150527/pentagon-military-mistakenly-shipped-live-anthrax-samples</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Pentagon: Military mistakenly shipped live anthrax samples
By Robert Burns, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said Wednesday it is investigating what the Pentagon called an inadvertent shipment of live anthrax spores to government and commercial laboratories in as many as nine states, as well as one overseas, that expected to receive dead spores.
At this time we do not suspect any risk to the general public, CDC spokeswoman Kathy Harben said.
A Pentagon spokesman, Col. Steve Warren, said the suspected live anthrax samples were shipped from Dugway Proving Ground, an Army facility in Utah, using a commercial delivery service.
Warren said the government has confirmed one recipient, a laboratory in Maryland, received live spores. It is suspected, but not yet confirmed, that anthrax sent to labs in as many as eight other states also contained live spores, he said. Later he said an anthrax sample from the same batch at Dugway also was sent to a U.S. military laboratory at Osan air base in South Korea; no personnel there have shown signs of exposure, he said, and the sample was destroyed.
There is no known risk to the general public, and there are no suspected or confirmed cases of anthrax infection in potentially exposed lab workers, Warren said.
The anthrax samples were shipped from Dugway to government and commercial labs in Texas, Maryland, Wisconsin, Delaware, New Jersey, Tennessee, New York, California and Virginia.
The Defense Department, acting out of an abundance of caution, has halted the shipment of this material from its labs pending completion of the investigation, Warren said.
Contact with anthrax spores can cause severe illness.
Harben said one of the laboratories contacted the CDC to request technical consultation. It was working as part of a Pentagon effort to develop a new diagnostic test to identify biological threats, she said.
Although an inactivated agent was expected, the lab reported they were able to grow live Bacillus anthracis, she said, referring to the bacteria that cause anthrax disease.
The CDC is working with state and federal agencies on an investigation with the labs that received samples from the Defense Department, she said.
Harben said all samples involved in the investigation will be securely transferred to the CDC or other laboratories for further testing.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This street performer in Cape Town is basically the Mozart of animal sounds</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/media/20150527/this-street-performer-in-cape-town-is-basically-the-mozart-of-animal-sounds</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>This street performer in Cape Town is basically the Mozart of animal sounds
By Timothy McGrath, GlobalPost
# Comments
Screengrab from YouTube video. (Christopher Schofield/YouTube)
Meow, moo, baa-aaa. You can probably call to mind what it sounds like when humans do animal impressions. But the things youre about to witness are no impressions. Theyre something closer to ventriloquism  a kind of mystical, oral animorphism by a street performer with a rare talent.
 Video: Animal sound man
If youre able to do a Google search with your jaw on the ground, youll learn that the star of the video is a man named William Jafta. He lives in Cape Town, South Africa, and thanks to Reddit , hes probably going to wake up tomorrow a viral sensation.
You can find videos scattered around YouTube that show Jafta performing around Cape Town in squares and on trains. Hes totally amazing.
So why animal impressions?
You might have guessed: Jaftas not just doing it for fun. As he explained in a video last summer for the Daily Sun, South Africas largest daily newspaper, he started busking because he was unemployed and needed the money to support his family.
Today brought us this most recent video of Jaftas virtuosic mimicry. Thats great. But it also brought news that South Africas unemployment rate has hit a 10-year high of 26.4 percent. So enjoy Jaftas cats, horses, and roosters. But dont forget whats putting him out in the square.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 16:09:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saudi airstrikes kill 15 in Yemen police commando camp</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150527/saudi-airstrikes-kill-15-in-yemen-police-commando-camp</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Saudi airstrikes kill 15 in Yemen police commando camp
Shiite rebels known as Houthis bury a fellow Houthi who was killed in a Saudi-led airstrike during his funeral in Sanaa, Yemen, Monday, May 25, 2015. A United Nations-sponsored peace conference that was to take place at the end of the month has been indefinitely postponed, senior Yemeni politicians said. (AP Photo/Hani Mohammed)
By Ahmed Al-Haj, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
People look at a vehicle burned out after a truck behind it was hit by crossfire between fighters loyal to the exiled President Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi and Shiite rebels and caused a fire in Taiz city, Yemen, Monday, May 25, 2015. (AP Photo/Abdulnasser Alseddik)
SANAA, Yemen &gt;&gt; Yemeni medical officials say at least 15 people were killed when Saudi-led airstrikes fired missiles targeting a sprawling police commando camp in the capital of Sanaa.
The camp is run by commanders loyal to ousted Yemeni President Ali Abdullah Saleh who has backed the power grab by Yemens Shiite rebels known as Houthis.
The Houthis and Saleh loyalists control Sanaa and much of the northern region.
Officials at the Military Hospital in Sanaa say they received 15 bodies on Wednesday after the airstrikes, and that two other hospitals also took in dead and wounded.
Security officials say 150 troops were present at the camp at the time of the airstrike. All officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the press.
THIS IS A BREAKING NEWS UPDATE. Check back soon for further information. APs earlier story is below.
Dozens of Saudi-led airstrikes rocked Yemens capital early Wednesday, targeting a sprawling police commando camp, sending black smoke billowing into the air and causing panic among residents in the early morning while the World Health Organization announced that 2,000 people have died in the conflict in the past two months.
The airstrikes are part of a Saudi-led military operation that began March 26 to target Shiite rebels known as Houthis, along with army units loyal to ousted President Ali Abdullah Saleh. The two groups are allied and occupy the capital, Sanaa, and much of the north.
Wednesdays strikes targeted the police camp located in central Sanaa, close to the presidential palace. An Associated Press reporter saw ambulances rushing to the scene and thick black smoke covering the whole area, obstructing visibility.
Blocks away, administrative buildings and shops suffered damage, with metal shutters twisted off their frames, windows broken and doors blown off their hinges. Streets were littered with shattered glass, toppled street lights and overturned cars.
Many of Sanaas residents sought shelter in basements and shops were closed, while city streets were deserted.
Witnesses say planes also bombed a naval base in western Hodeida controlled by the Houthis. Saudi and allied jets also bombed the northern Houthi srongholds of Saada and Hajjah.
Advertisement
In a new report Wednesday, World Health Organization Chief Margaret Chan said that Yemens conflict has left up to 2,000 people dead and 8,000 wounded, including hundreds of women and children. She did not specify how many of the dead were civilian.
Most recent U.N. estimates said that at least 1,037 civilians, including 130 women and 234 children, have been killed in the fighting.
Chan also said that the killings sometimes included whole families, giving the example of a 65-year-old woman named Fathiya who lost 13 members of her family in an attack that left her the only guardian of three surviving grandchildren.
There is a shortage of fuel, water, fuel and medical supplies, in addition to destroyed f health facilities, and 7.5 million people are in urgent need of medical help.
Earlier this week, international humanitarian group Oxfam warned that some 16 million people in Yemen dont have access to clean water. Half a million people have been displaced across the country.
The campaign of airstrikes has devastated rebel positions, ammunition depots and bases, but it has largely failed to pave the way for the recapture of the strategic southern city of Aden. The internationally-recognized president of Yemen, Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi, declared Aden the countrys temporarily capital before fleeing to Saudi Arabia.
Hadis allied southern fighters managed on Tuesday to recapture the strategic city of Dhale, located near Aden.
Dhale and Aden were among top cities that suffered the most and the government branded them as disaster zones. On Wednesday, residents said that communications were down, except for landlines, as fighting intensified in the outskirts of the city between militias supporting President Hadi and the Houthis and Salehs forces.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Money, politics, power struggles -- Pakistan's media scandal has it all</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/money-politics-power-struggles-x2014-pakistans-media-scandal-has-it-all</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Money, politics, power struggles  Pakistans media scandal has it all
Pakistan Federal Investigation Agency (FIA) deputy director Kamran Attaullah speaks to media after leaving the Axact in Karachi on May 20, 2015, after conducting an investigation. (RIZWAN TABASSUM/AFP/Getty Images)
By Lawrence Pintak, GlobalPost
# Comments
KARACHI, Pakistan  A government raid on the company that is bankrolling Pakistans newest media conglomerate has highlighted the corruption and infighting within the countrys news industry.
A front-page article in The New York Times early last week accused Karachi-based Axact  which calls itself the worlds leading IT company  of selling fake diplomas in an internet-era scheme on a global scale.
The story broke as BOL, the media company financed by Axact, was preparing its long-delayed launch in mid-summer. The wheels are now coming off the project. Over the weekend, BOLs top two news executives and some staffers resigned.
[T]his is a massive conspiracy by the seths of the Pakistani media industry to defame BOL and Axact and derail the launch of BOL, the company said in a statement on its website after the Times story broke. (Seth is a South Asian term for chief or merchant.) In defiance of the resulting media furor, BOL moved up the TV channels launch date to mid-June. Its English- and Urdu-language newspapers were scheduled to follow in the fall.
The controversy underlines the deep divide in Pakistans media, with corporate owners beholden to powerful forces in the civilian and military wings of the government, which are in a constant struggle for control.
Storm against BOL is war of media moguls, tweeted political analyst Fawad Hussain. #Axact corrupt or innocent. Whatever. But BOLtv gave sleepless nights2 media owners who feared losing monopoly, wrote Rauf Klasra, a journalist at ARY television.
The Express Tribune, which publishes the international edition of The New York Times as an insert, had long known about the allegations against Axact  which calls its employees Axactians  but was prevented from publishing by a court order prompted by an Axact lawsuit, according to media sources in Karachi.
The Times story unleashed an avalanche of articles in the Pakistani media, with headlines like,  Who is the real owner of Axact? ;  Why I left Axact: The Inside Picture ; and  Employees were berated, threatened if they did not meet their targets  (DunyaNews).
But some media houses  with different political allegiances  took a more measured approach. My hats off to newspapers like @dawn_com and the @The_Nation because they kept the banner of fair coverage of #Axact, tweeted Murtaza Solangi, former director general of Radio Pakistan, referring to two of Pakistans largest media companies.
Advertisement
Rumors have long swirled around the impending launch of BOL, many centering on the question of who was really behind the nascent media group. Some in Pakistans media and political circles speculated that the military was using BOL, which recruited many of the top figures in Pakistani journalism, to force other media groups into line. In a nation rife with conspiracy theories, there was even speculation BOL was an elaborate ruse that would never actually launch.
Axact and BOL vehemently denied all those claims.
We will be the first organization where editorial decisions will be made in the newsroom, not at the owners desk, Kamran Khan, president and editor-in-chief of the BOL Media Group, told GlobalPost in a meeting at BOLs partially complete headquarters building last month. At those other media houses, he said, business interests come first.
For us, its a legacy; we want to make a real difference in the paradigm of media thinking, added his colleague Azhar Abbas, president of BOL News.
But over the weekend, Khan and Abbas announced their resignations on Twitter. Previously, both were senior executives at rival GEO TV, which ended up in a major confrontation with the military after it blamed the Armys intelligence wing for the 2014 attempted assassination of one of its anchors.
The resignations came three days after the channel defiantly moved up its launch date and began test transmissions. Screenshots from the BOL website with the faces of high-profile journalists crossed out began making the rounds on social media even as Axact filed suit against a blogger for aggregating the many tweets making fun of the companys travails.
Meanwhile some of the other high profile journalists hired by Axact/BOL stayed on the offensive. Anchor Mubasher Lucman announced he would remain with the channel after issuing a warning to the competition: #Axact #BOL TV story from media houses is sickening, there is a lot beneath the skin &amp; they would wish they had never started this campaign.
The Axact/BOL scandal highlights the murky finances and complicated political relationships that underpin the Pakistani media landscape. Top editors say it is common for media companies to owe millions in unpaid taxes and debts to banks, or to generate profits under the table while saying they lose money. These sources claim that leaves media houses open to pressure from the rival civilian and military wings of the government to shape coverage. The government also ultimately controls a large portion of the countrys advertising expenditures.
They immediately say yes, when the military orders them to report or suppress a story, because the military has their dirty laundry, said Badr Alam, editor of The Herald, a monthly magazine that is part of the rival Dawn media group.
Its so easy to control those organizations because its easy to control the owners, BOLs Khan said in Karachi last month. They are making money but not showing it or paying their taxes. If you are not officially making money for six months, you are making it somewhere else.
But the subsequent scandal, which led Khan to resign, raises the question of whether the man Khan and many others in the Pakistani media elite went to work for was any different. Pakistani newspapers reported last week that Axacts chief executive, Shoaid Shaikh, paid the equivalent of 25 cents in taxes last year. And the government tax office has launched a full investigation into the companys finances.
As for the conspiracy theory that BOL would never launch: its looking more and more credible by the day.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uber just found another way to anger Mexico City's taxi drivers</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/uber-just-found-another-way-to-anger-mexico-citys-taxi-drivers</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Uber just found another way to anger Mexico Citys taxi drivers
Taxis and a bus ride along the streets of Mexico City. (Omar Torres/AFP/Getty Images)
By Sara Yasin, GlobalPost
# Comments
Taxi drivers in Mexico City are going on strike today, so naturally the people over at Uber decided to offer free rides.
The publicity-hungry company made the announcement on their Mexico City blog  promising their customers that they wouldnt allow a little labor dispute interfere with their services.
Mexicos capital  like some other cities in Latin America  has been considering a ban on the popular service, which has drawn outrage from its taxi drivers.
According to Excelsior, a Mexican daily newspaper, approximately 5,000 taxi drivers are on strike today . According to CNNs Spanish language channel, the taxi drivers are protesting against the car sharing service.
Back in March, the fight between Uber and local taxi drivers turned violent. A group of taxi drivers used baseball bats to attack an Uber drivers car.
The citys 140,000 taxis have been the focus of reforms as a part of a plan to regularize transportation.
Hailing a taxi in Mexico City and elsewhere in Latin America can be dangerous. As GlobalPosts Simeon Tegel explains, in some cases passengers risk crossing paths with violent criminals who carry out what is known as an express kidnappings:
Mexico City is perhaps the world capital of this kind of crime, and no self-respecting guidebook fails to warn of the danger. Passengers are taken at gunpoint on a forced ATM tour.
The battle between taxi drivers and Uber isnt exclusive to Latin America  its a face-off taking place around the world . Well see if Mexico City becomes the next place to crackdown on the ride sharing app.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt's military government has started executing people on overtly political charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/egypts-military-government-has-started-executing-people-on-overtly-political-charges</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Egypts military government has started executing people on overtly political charges
The Muslim Brotherhood's Safwat Hegazy (C) shouts from behind the defendants' cage as a judge reads out the verdict sentencing him and more than 100 other defendants to death on May 16, 2015 at the police academy in Cairo. (KHALED DESOUKI/AFP/Getty Images)
By Laura Dean, GlobalPost
# Comments
CAIRO, Egypt  Next Tuesday, a lawyer will plead for a Cairo court to suspend the execution of six men, arguing that their death sentences were unconstitutional. The only trouble is, the defendants are already dead.
Since the coup that swept Muslim Brotherhood President Mohamed Morsi from power, hundreds of his supporters have been handed death sentences in a rash of mass trials. But until this month, only one had been carried out  against a man convicted of throwing another man off a roof.
A little over a week ago, however, six men sentenced to death by a military court were executed on charges of belonging to militant group Ansar Beit al-Maqdis and attacking security forces.
The day before, a Cairo court sentenced ousted president Morsi and 120 others to death on charges related to a mass prison break during the 2011 uprisings. Some were sentenced in absentia, including Sondos Asem, a young Oxford University student who used to work as a media coordinator for Morsi, and Emad Shahin, a well-known professor at the American University in Cairo.
The six executions of political opponents mark the first overtly political killings ordered under Abdel Fattah el-Sisis leadership. They recall other killings of political opposition figures after violent power shifts  Iran in 1979, Liberia in 1980  but it remains to be seen how deep the similarities will go.
A key question now being debated: Will they really kill Morsi?
The precedent set by the court-ordered killings is already worrying monitors. Now that they have been executed this paves the way for other executions to take place, said Mohamed Elmessiry, Egypt researcher with Amnesty International.
It is a sign that some parts of the state are in a very bloody-minded mood; at times it seems as if there is a vendetta between parts of the state and an increasingly militant opposition, said Nathan Brown, professor of political science and international affairs at George Washington University.
In this case it appears that a serious miscarriage of justice took place. Three of the six convicted men have an alibi  they were already in prison on the dates they allegedly carried out their attacks on the army. Ahmed Helmy, a lawyer who represented the men, said the court seemed unwilling to listen to the evidence. The judge was shown official documents that proved that they were arrested before the crimes allegedly took place, he said. The documents included times and places of arrest and the fact that they were in Azouli prison, a military detention facility known for human rights abuses.
Advertisement
Helmy said the outcome of the trial seemed like a foregone conclusion from the start.
There is a sense that the sentences were already decided. The defendants told me not to bother [defending them]. They said, We know we will get the death penalty, dont trouble yourself. They knew this would happen, he said.
The whole trial was flawed, rights groups say. Elmessiry describes the proceedings as procedurally completely null and void because they were held in enforced disappearance [not official detention] and they were not held in an official place of detention. The civilian defendants were also tried in a military court. The administrative case on June 2 will challenge the sentences on these grounds.
Helmy sees the executions as a warning to those still in jail.
It was a kind of threat  they will apply this sentence to scare the other prisoners into negotiating with them and solving the crisis.
What do Egypts friends have to say?
The United States gave a milquetoast response to Morsis death sentence, saying they were deeply concerned  a sentiment that didnt get in the way of a meeting in Cairo last Wednesday between General Lloyd James Austin, the head of US Central Command, and Sisi. The presidency said the two men were talking about counterterrorism efforts.
I think Western actors  the Europeans and the US  have essentially come to terms with the fact that the new Egyptian regime is following a repressive path, said Brown. He added that it is unlikely to pose a serious barrier to relations.
But if politically motivated death sentences continue  and particularly, if Morsi does end up being executed  the US and other Western governments who have supported the Sisi government will have some explaining to do.
If the Egyptian government actually executed all those who have death sentences passed on them, the bloodletting would be hard to ignore. I think it would lead to a bit of international isolation, Brown said. If instead we see selected executions it will lead to more tension in their relationship but will not completely disrupt it.
Already, Egypts increasingly poor record on human rights is causing Cairo to lose friends in some European capitals. The president of the German parliament canceled a June meeting with Sisi, citing human rights abuses and lack of parliamentary elections in Egypt. Egypt, meanwhile, denied that it had requested a meeting in the first place.
What weve seen from the West is disappointing but expected, said Sarah Leah Whitson, head of the Middle East division at Human Rights Watch. The Obama administration has routinely set aside the rights of Egyptian citizens in favor of its so-called strategic interests in Egypt, she said.
That doesnt mean US officials arent keeping an eye on the Egyptian judiciary, however.
I think a lot of diplomats are waiting to see whether the Court of Cassation [the final line of legal appeal] continues to function as a pressure valve or whether it begins finalizing the hundreds of preliminary death sentences currently before it, Whitson said.
Helmy said it is too soon to tell what will happen in those cases. But he doesnt think the former president will actually be executed.
I dont expect they will carry out Morsis sentence. They want to negotiate with the Muslim Brotherhood and they dont need to kill him now, he said.
What will happen in Egypts courts is increasingly difficult to predict. Under former president Hosni Mubarak there were sometimes faulty sentences, but usually not in cases carrying the death penalty, Helmy said.
Now you have the feeling that the whole system is lost, that the sentences comes from above and are already decided.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:09:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faulty fan, smoke blamed in brief evacuation of U.S. Capitol</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/faulty-fan-smoke-blamed-in-brief-evacuation-of-us-capitol</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Faulty fan, smoke blamed in brief evacuation of U.S. Capitol
By Alan Fram, The Associated Press
Posted:
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; Police briefly evacuated hundreds of workers and tourists from the U.S. Capitol and its adjacent visitors center on Tuesday in a problem officials tentatively blamed on a faulty exhaust fan in a visitor center kitchen.
Within an hour after alarms sounded, employees returned to the building. Tourists were readmitted shortly after that.
Lawmakers are in recess this week for the weeklong Memorial Day break.
The U.S. Capitol Police told congressional workers in an email that two alarms were triggered in the visitors center, which they said was apparently caused by a known problem with environmental controls with the kitchen exhaust fan. It provided no additional detail.
Kimberly Schneider, a Capitol Police spokeswoman, said there were no signs of smoke or fire. An email sent later to House staff by the chambers sergeant at arms office said the triggering of alarms was most likely caused by smoke in the kitchen; there was no fire.
The evacuation occurred two days after a bomb squad destroyed a pressure cooker found in an unattended, suspicious vehicle on the National Mall near the Capitol and the vehicles Virginia owner was arrested. Almost six weeks earlier, a Florida man was arrested after he flew his gyrocopter through restricted air space and onto the Capitol grounds.
In Tuesdays incident, police cleared the East Lawn and closed First Street between the Capitol and the Library of Congress until the buildings were reopened.
Denise Grandits of Buffalo, New York, said she and 70 eighth-graders were touring the Capitol and heard the alarms. She said the guide escorted them out of the building.
We just walked. It was pretty calm, she said.
According to the police email, officials initially thought one of the two triggered alarms was in the Capitol and they began evacuating that building.
In a moment of confusion, police soon advised people in the Capitol that they could remain inside because the alarms were not coming from that building. They reversed themselves again minutes later and resumed evacuating the Capitol.
The police email said once officials determined both alarms were in the visitor center, they decided to continue emptying the Capitol to ensure staff and members did not receive conflicting information.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 05:36:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida Police: 3 kids hurt when waterspout uproots bounce house</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/florida-police-3-kids-hurt-when-waterspout-uproots-bounce-house</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Waterspouts
Florida Police: 3 kids hurt when waterspout uproots bounce house
In this photo provided by Burt Osteen, glass is scattered around a toppled basketball hoop after a waterspout made landfall at Fort Lauderdale Beach, Fla. on Monday, May 25, 2015. Authorities say three children were injured when the waterspout uprooted a bounce house and sent it across a parking lot into the road. Burt Osteen via AP
By JENNIFER KAY, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
MIAMI &gt;&gt; A waterspout uprooted an inflatable bounce house with three children inside it on a South Florida beach Monday, but the youngsters were tossed to the sand before it flew above palm trees and over four lanes of traffic, police said.
All three children were quickly thrown to the beach while another nearby bounce house, which was unoccupied, also took flight over the state road, authorities said. Both inflatables crashed won in a parking lot.
The children were injured, but alert and conscious when they were taken to a hospital, Fort Lauderdale Police spokesman Keven Dupree said.
A police statement later Monday evening said two of the children were treated for minor fractures and released while a third was in stable condition and held overnight for observation at Broward Health Medical Center.
Their identities werent released and police said no vehicles or pedestrians were hit by the bounce houses.
Video on local television stations showed the waterspout  a whirling column of air and water mist  moving from the ocean onto the sand of Fort Lauderdale beach, tossing a canopy and rolling one of the bounce houses before lifting it into the air.
The house flew above the tree line, but the children fell out when it first flipped over the beach, Dupree said. They were immediately dropped out of the bounce house onto the sand, he said.
Both bounce houses had been secured to a basketball court as part of a city-sponsored family activity zone set up for a Memorial Day holiday event. The waterspout snapped a concrete pole holding a basketball hoop.
Burt Osteen, a 37-year-old flooring installer from Fort Lauderdale, and his family dove to the sand on their stomachs as they saw the waterspout spinning toward them.
It came right over us. We laid on the ground; we were right in front of the bounce house. We watched it pick up the bounce house and snap a basketball hoop, Osteen said.
He barely felt anything, though, when the waterspout passed over them. The tablecloths on nearby picnic tables werent even disturbed by the wind, he said.
The only thing was the sand, getting stung by the sand, he said.
Unlike tornadoes, waterspouts dont need thunderstorms for their funnel clouds to form. On Monday afternoon, a band of clouds was moving in from the ocean had winds favorable for waterspout formation, said Jeral Estupinan, a meteorologist with the National Weather Service in Miami.
Advertisement
It developed very close to the coastline and moved onshore, and it dissipated very quickly onshore, like any other waterspout, Estupinan said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 05:15:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man diagnosed with Lassa fever dies in US after Liberia trip</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/health/20150525/man-diagnosed-with-lassa-fever-dies-in-us-after-liberia-trip</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man diagnosed with Lassa fever dies in US after Liberia trip
By MIKE STOBBE, AP Medical Writer
Posted:
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; A New Jersey man died Monday evening after been diagnosed with Lassa fever  a frightening infectious disease from West Africa that is rarely seen in the United States, a federal health official said.
The man recently returned from Liberia, arriving at New York Citys JFK International Airport on May 17. He grew critically ill after his return, suffering from multiple organ failure, said Dr. Tom Frieden, director of the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Atlanta.
Health officials said they dont think the case is cause for public alarm. Lassa fever is not spread through casual contact. About a half dozen other cases have been diagnosed in travelers from West Africa in the past, and none of them ever spread the illness person-to-person, Frieden said.
But as a precaution, the CDC and New Jersey health officials are trying to track down and monitor anyone the man was in contact with during the past week, including health workers at two New Jersey hospitals and people who sat close to him on his recent flight from Morocco to New York.
The illness is commonly seen in West Africa, in some of the same countries struck by the recent Ebola epidemic. This last confirmed case of Lassa fever seen in a traveler returning to the United States was in Minnesota last year. The one before that was in Pennsylvania in 2010.
Generally speaking, Lassa fever is far less likely to be fatal than Ebola and less likely to be spread from person to person. About 80 percent of cases are mild. But in severe cases, patients can suffer fever, vomiting, organ failure, shock and even bleeding from the eyes, nose and gums. Its fatal in about 1 percent of cases. Sometimes, those who survive are deaf for the rest of their lives.
Like Ebola, it can spread through contact with blood, feces or vomit of an infected person. In West Africa, Lassa virus is carried by rodents and transmitted to humans through contact with urine or droppings of infected rodents.
CDC officials declined to give the name or identifying information about the man, other than to say he frequently traveled to Liberia on business and had worked in the mining industry. CDC officials on Monday also declined to name the New Jersey hospital where the man first went for care, or to a second New Jersey hospital where he was subsequently treated with ribavirin, an antiviral medication given intravenously.
The patient had no symptoms during the flight, but a day later went to a New Jersey hospital suffering from a sore throat and lethargy.
Advertisement
Hospital officials said they had asked the man about his travel history and that he did not say he had recently been to West Africa, CDC officials said.
Three days later he had returned to the hospital with more severe symptoms. He was transferred to the second hospital Saturday. On Monday, CDC lab tests of the patients blood confirmed Lassa fever.
The CDC plans to send a special response team including a Lassa fever expert and specialists in occupational safety and waste management to the second hospital Tuesday.
Health officials regularly note that exotic illnesses are only a plane ride away.
We expect to see Lassa fever and other infections like this. Because of Ebola, were now better prepared to deal with it, Frieden said.
Lassa fever was named after a Nigerian town where Western-trained doctors first noted it in 1969. An estimated 100,000 to 300,000 infections occur in West Africa each year, including about 5,000 deaths. In some areas of Sierra Leone and Liberia, 10 to 15 percent of people admitted to hospitals every year have Lassa fever.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:50:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anonymous threats against airliners prompt searches; all OK</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/anonymous-threats-against-airliners-prompt-searches-all-ok</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Anonymous threats against airliners prompt searches; all OK
By Associated Press
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; Anonymous telephone threats against commercial airliners on Monday, possibly from the same source, caused a scare involving at least six international flights at airports in New York, New Jersey and Massachusetts.
Authorities said the threats did not appear to be credible. They described searches done on the jets as a precaution.
In one instance Monday morning, U.S. military jets escorted an Air France flight into New York City after someone claimed a chemical weapon was aboard the aircraft, the FBI said.
Out of an abundance of caution, Air France flight number 22 was escorted to John F. Kennedy airport by U.S. Air Force fighter jets following a phone threat, the FBI said in a statement. There were no incidents or hazards reported on board the flight by either the passengers or its crew. The plane has been cleared.
A Saudi Arabian Airlines flight arriving at Kennedy also was being checked out because of another threat, authorities said.
A third threat was made against an American Airlines jet flying from Birmingham, England, to Kennedy while it was still in the air, airline spokesman Kent Powell said. Authorities initially told the pilot to land and taxi to a remote area away from the terminal but later radioed that the threat was not credible and cleared the plane to go to the terminal, Powell said.
At Newark Liberty International Airport, passengers were removed from a United Airlines flight after it arrived from Madrid, United spokeswoman Mary Clark said. The plane was inspected Monday afternoon at a spot away from the terminal.
Atlanta-based Delta Air Lines Inc. said two of its international planes were threatened: a Paris-to-Boston flight and a London-to-Newark flight.
A threat made against a Paris-to-Boston airliner was deemed not credible, Massachusetts Port Authority spokesman Matthew Brelis said, but he didnt say if that was Deltas plane. He said he didnt know the circumstances of the threat or if the plane was searched.
Maryland State Police said they received an anonymous call at the McHenry barracks in the western part of the state threatening commercial aviation about 6:30 a.m. Monday and referred it to the FBI. They declined to comment further.
___
Associated Press writer David Koenig in Dallas contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:33:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyer says allegations B.B. King was poisoned 'ridiculous'</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150525/lawyer-says-allegations-bb-king-was-poisoned-ridiculous</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Celebrity deaths
Lawyer says allegations B.B. King was poisoned ridiculous
FILE-In this Aug. 22, 2012 photograph, the  then 86-year-old B.B. King thrills a crowd of several hundred people at the annual B.B. King Homecoming, a free concert on the grounds of an old cotton gin where he worked as a teenager many years ago, in Indianola, Miss. Festival organizers said this years festival was to have been a tribute to the then living King, who died May 14, 2015. Now they are calling it  a memorial celebration. AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, File
By KEN RITTER, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
LAS VEGAS &gt;&gt; Two B.B. King heirs whove been most outspoken about the blues legends care in his final days are accusing Kings two closest aides of poisoning him, but the attorney for Kings estate is calling the claims ridiculous.
Three doctors determined that King was appropriately cared-for, and King received 24-hour care and monitoring by medical professionals up until the time that he peacefully passed away in his sleep, attorney Brent Bryson told the AP on Monday.
Daughters Karen Williams and Patty King allege that family members were prevented from visiting while Kings business manager, LaVerne Toney, and his personal assistant, Myron Johnson, hastened their fathers death.
Toney is named in Kings will as executor of an estate that, according to court documents filed by lawyers for some of Kings heirs, could total tens of millions of dollars.
Johnson was at B.B. Kings bedside when he died May 14 in hospice care at home in Las Vegas at age 89. No family members were present.
I believe my father was poisoned and that he was administered foreign substances, Patty King and Williams say in identically worded sections of affidavits provided to The Associated Press by their lawyer, Larissa Drohobyczer.
I believe my father was murdered, they say.
Toney and Johnson each declined to comment on the accusations.
Theyve been making allegations all along. Whats new? said Toney, who worked for King for 39 years and had power-of-attorney over his affairs.
A week before Kings death, a judge in Las Vegas dismissed a request from Williams to take over as Kings guardian.
An April 29 petition alleged that Toney had blocked Kings friends from visiting him and had put her family members on Kings payroll. It also alleged that large sums of money had disappeared from Kings bank accounts.
But Clark County Family Court Hearing Master Jon Norheim said on May 7 that police and social services investigations in October and April uncovered no reason to take power-of-attorney from Toney.
Williams, Patty King and another daughter Rita Washington  vowed to keep fighting.
We lost the battle, but we havent lost the war, Williams said then.
This weeks allegations come days after a public viewing in Las Vegas drew more than 1,000 fans and mourners and a weekend family-and-friends memorial drew 350. A Beale Street procession and memorial are scheduled Wednesday in Memphis, Tennessee, followed by a Friday viewing and Saturday burial in Kings hometown of Indianola, Mississippi.
Advertisement
Clark County Coroner John Fudenberg said Monday the investigation shouldnt delay Kings final trip home to the Mississippi Delta.
Fudenberg said an autopsy was performed Sunday and Kings body was then returned to a Las Vegas mortuary. Test results will take up to eight weeks to obtain, and shouldnt be affected by the fact that Kings body had been embalmed, he said.
This is extremely disrespectful to B.B. King, Bryson said on Monday. He did not want invasive medical procedures. He made the decision to return home for hospice care instead of staying in a hospital. These unfounded allegations have caused Mr. King to undergo an autopsy, which is exactly what he didnt want.
Las Vegas police homicide detectives are investigating, Lt. Ray Steiber said Monday. He declined to provide details.
Drohobyczer said she represents Williams, Patty King and most of Kings nine other adult children and heirs.
The family is sticking together ... to oust Ms. Toney based on her illegal conduct, conflicts of interest and self-dealing, she said. She alleged that Toney hastened Kings death by misconduct, or by failing to properly attend to his medical needs.
An affidavit from Patty King, who used to live at Kings home, says she saw Johnson administer to King two drops of an unknown substance on his tongue during evenings for several months before his death, and that Toney never told her what the substance was.
Bryson called Drohobyczers claims ridiculous.
I hope they have a factual basis that they can demonstrate for their defamatory and libelous allegations, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:32:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charter nears $55 billion deal for Time Warner Cable</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/business/20150525/charter-nears-55-billion-deal-for-time-warner-cable</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mergers and acquisitions
Charter nears $55 billion deal for Time Warner Cable
This photo shows a Charter Communications van in St. Louis. Charter Communications is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, two people familiar with the negotiations said Monday. Jeff Roberson  The Associated Press
By Tali Arbel and David Koenig, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
This file photo shows a Time Warner Cable truck in New York .Charter Communications is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, two people familiar with the negotiations said Monday. Mark Lennihan  The Associated Press file
Charter Communications Inc. is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, according to two people familiar with the negotiations.
The people spoke on condition of anonymity Monday because of the private nature of the talks.
One person said the deal will be announced early this morning.
Charter had wanted to buy Time Warner Cable Inc. earlier, but Time Warner Cable chose a $45 billion offer from Comcast Corp. instead.
Comcast walked away from the Time Warner Cable deal after regulators pushed back against it. Regulators had concerns that the two companies together would undermine online video competition. The combined company would have served more than half the countrys broadband subscribers, and consumer advocates said a merger would limit choices and lead to higher prices.
Time Warner Cable representative Ellen East and Charter spokesman Justin Venech both declined to comment on the talks between their companies.
Cable companies are losing cable subscribers and facing more pressure from online services such as Netflix and Amazon for consumers who watch TV over broadband connections.
Consumer advocates were waiting to learn more details about the deal but seemed initially to regard it with less hostility than the failed Comcast bid for Time Warner Cable, which would have created a behemoth controlling much of the Internet access in the U.S.
I cant say that were a big fan of industry consolidation, but realistically this doesnt really raise the same level of concern, said John Bergmayer, a lawyer with Public Knowledge.
If antitrust regulators approve the deal, Bergmayer said, they should attach conditions addressing broadband affordability, customer service and other issues.
Cable companies argue that their mergers dont hurt TV consumers because their systems dont overlap much  an argument that is disputed by consumer groups.
Matt Wood, policy director of the Internet-consumer group Free Press, said the money that the cable companies spend on mergers doesnt go to helping customers.
Rather than buying each other up and cementing in place the local monopolies they already enjoy, they could be investing in their own networks to improve their customer service, Wood said.
They could even go outside their current markets and compete against each other in more places, he said.
Shares of Time Warner Cable closed Friday at $171.18. They have climbed 13 percent so far in 2015, compared with a 3 percent gain in the Standard &amp; Poors 500 index.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
