<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="dailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Money, politics, power struggles -- Pakistan's media scandal has it all</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/money-politics-power-struggles-x2014-pakistans-media-scandal-has-it-all</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Money, politics, power struggles  Pakistans media scandal has it all
Pakistan Federal Investigation Agency (FIA) deputy director Kamran Attaullah speaks to media after leaving the Axact in Karachi on May 20, 2015, after conducting an investigation. (RIZWAN TABASSUM/AFP/Getty Images)
By Lawrence Pintak, GlobalPost
# Comments
KARACHI, Pakistan  A government raid on the company that is bankrolling Pakistans newest media conglomerate has highlighted the corruption and infighting within the countrys news industry.
A front-page article in The New York Times early last week accused Karachi-based Axact  which calls itself the worlds leading IT company  of selling fake diplomas in an internet-era scheme on a global scale.
The story broke as BOL, the media company financed by Axact, was preparing its long-delayed launch in mid-summer. The wheels are now coming off the project. Over the weekend, BOLs top two news executives and some staffers resigned.
[T]his is a massive conspiracy by the seths of the Pakistani media industry to defame BOL and Axact and derail the launch of BOL, the company said in a statement on its website after the Times story broke. (Seth is a South Asian term for chief or merchant.) In defiance of the resulting media furor, BOL moved up the TV channels launch date to mid-June. Its English- and Urdu-language newspapers were scheduled to follow in the fall.
The controversy underlines the deep divide in Pakistans media, with corporate owners beholden to powerful forces in the civilian and military wings of the government, which are in a constant struggle for control.
Storm against BOL is war of media moguls, tweeted political analyst Fawad Hussain. #Axact corrupt or innocent. Whatever. But BOLtv gave sleepless nights2 media owners who feared losing monopoly, wrote Rauf Klasra, a journalist at ARY television.
The Express Tribune, which publishes the international edition of The New York Times as an insert, had long known about the allegations against Axact  which calls its employees Axactians  but was prevented from publishing by a court order prompted by an Axact lawsuit, according to media sources in Karachi.
The Times story unleashed an avalanche of articles in the Pakistani media, with headlines like,  Who is the real owner of Axact? ;  Why I left Axact: The Inside Picture ; and  Employees were berated, threatened if they did not meet their targets  (DunyaNews).
But some media houses  with different political allegiances  took a more measured approach. My hats off to newspapers like @dawn_com and the @The_Nation because they kept the banner of fair coverage of #Axact, tweeted Murtaza Solangi, former director general of Radio Pakistan, referring to two of Pakistans largest media companies.
Advertisement
Rumors have long swirled around the impending launch of BOL, many centering on the question of who was really behind the nascent media group. Some in Pakistans media and political circles speculated that the military was using BOL, which recruited many of the top figures in Pakistani journalism, to force other media groups into line. In a nation rife with conspiracy theories, there was even speculation BOL was an elaborate ruse that would never actually launch.
Axact and BOL vehemently denied all those claims.
We will be the first organization where editorial decisions will be made in the newsroom, not at the owners desk, Kamran Khan, president and editor-in-chief of the BOL Media Group, told GlobalPost in a meeting at BOLs partially complete headquarters building last month. At those other media houses, he said, business interests come first.
For us, its a legacy; we want to make a real difference in the paradigm of media thinking, added his colleague Azhar Abbas, president of BOL News.
But over the weekend, Khan and Abbas announced their resignations on Twitter. Previously, both were senior executives at rival GEO TV, which ended up in a major confrontation with the military after it blamed the Armys intelligence wing for the 2014 attempted assassination of one of its anchors.
The resignations came three days after the channel defiantly moved up its launch date and began test transmissions. Screenshots from the BOL website with the faces of high-profile journalists crossed out began making the rounds on social media even as Axact filed suit against a blogger for aggregating the many tweets making fun of the companys travails.
Meanwhile some of the other high profile journalists hired by Axact/BOL stayed on the offensive. Anchor Mubasher Lucman announced he would remain with the channel after issuing a warning to the competition: #Axact #BOL TV story from media houses is sickening, there is a lot beneath the skin &amp; they would wish they had never started this campaign.
The Axact/BOL scandal highlights the murky finances and complicated political relationships that underpin the Pakistani media landscape. Top editors say it is common for media companies to owe millions in unpaid taxes and debts to banks, or to generate profits under the table while saying they lose money. These sources claim that leaves media houses open to pressure from the rival civilian and military wings of the government to shape coverage. The government also ultimately controls a large portion of the countrys advertising expenditures.
They immediately say yes, when the military orders them to report or suppress a story, because the military has their dirty laundry, said Badr Alam, editor of The Herald, a monthly magazine that is part of the rival Dawn media group.
Its so easy to control those organizations because its easy to control the owners, BOLs Khan said in Karachi last month. They are making money but not showing it or paying their taxes. If you are not officially making money for six months, you are making it somewhere else.
But the subsequent scandal, which led Khan to resign, raises the question of whether the man Khan and many others in the Pakistani media elite went to work for was any different. Pakistani newspapers reported last week that Axacts chief executive, Shoaid Shaikh, paid the equivalent of 25 cents in taxes last year. And the government tax office has launched a full investigation into the companys finances.
As for the conspiracy theory that BOL would never launch: its looking more and more credible by the day.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Uber just found another way to anger Mexico City's taxi drivers</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/uber-just-found-another-way-to-anger-mexico-citys-taxi-drivers</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Uber just found another way to anger Mexico Citys taxi drivers
Taxis and a bus ride along the streets of Mexico City. (Omar Torres/AFP/Getty Images)
By Sara Yasin, GlobalPost
# Comments
Taxi drivers in Mexico City are going on strike today, so naturally the people over at Uber decided to offer free rides.
The publicity-hungry company made the announcement on their Mexico City blog  promising their customers that they wouldnt allow a little labor dispute interfere with their services.
Mexicos capital  like some other cities in Latin America  has been considering a ban on the popular service, which has drawn outrage from its taxi drivers.
According to Excelsior, a Mexican daily newspaper, approximately 5,000 taxi drivers are on strike today . According to CNNs Spanish language channel, the taxi drivers are protesting against the car sharing service.
Back in March, the fight between Uber and local taxi drivers turned violent. A group of taxi drivers used baseball bats to attack an Uber drivers car.
The citys 140,000 taxis have been the focus of reforms as a part of a plan to regularize transportation.
Hailing a taxi in Mexico City and elsewhere in Latin America can be dangerous. As GlobalPosts Simeon Tegel explains, in some cases passengers risk crossing paths with violent criminals who carry out what is known as an express kidnappings:
Mexico City is perhaps the world capital of this kind of crime, and no self-respecting guidebook fails to warn of the danger. Passengers are taken at gunpoint on a forced ATM tour.
The battle between taxi drivers and Uber isnt exclusive to Latin America  its a face-off taking place around the world . Well see if Mexico City becomes the next place to crackdown on the ride sharing app.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Egypt's military government has started executing people on overtly political charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/egypts-military-government-has-started-executing-people-on-overtly-political-charges</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nation and World
Egypts military government has started executing people on overtly political charges
The Muslim Brotherhood's Safwat Hegazy (C) shouts from behind the defendants' cage as a judge reads out the verdict sentencing him and more than 100 other defendants to death on May 16, 2015 at the police academy in Cairo. (KHALED DESOUKI/AFP/Getty Images)
By Laura Dean, GlobalPost
# Comments
CAIRO, Egypt  Next Tuesday, a lawyer will plead for a Cairo court to suspend the execution of six men, arguing that their death sentences were unconstitutional. The only trouble is, the defendants are already dead.
Since the coup that swept Muslim Brotherhood President Mohamed Morsi from power, hundreds of his supporters have been handed death sentences in a rash of mass trials. But until this month, only one had been carried out  against a man convicted of throwing another man off a roof.
A little over a week ago, however, six men sentenced to death by a military court were executed on charges of belonging to militant group Ansar Beit al-Maqdis and attacking security forces.
The day before, a Cairo court sentenced ousted president Morsi and 120 others to death on charges related to a mass prison break during the 2011 uprisings. Some were sentenced in absentia, including Sondos Asem, a young Oxford University student who used to work as a media coordinator for Morsi, and Emad Shahin, a well-known professor at the American University in Cairo.
The six executions of political opponents mark the first overtly political killings ordered under Abdel Fattah el-Sisis leadership. They recall other killings of political opposition figures after violent power shifts  Iran in 1979, Liberia in 1980  but it remains to be seen how deep the similarities will go.
A key question now being debated: Will they really kill Morsi?
The precedent set by the court-ordered killings is already worrying monitors. Now that they have been executed this paves the way for other executions to take place, said Mohamed Elmessiry, Egypt researcher with Amnesty International.
It is a sign that some parts of the state are in a very bloody-minded mood; at times it seems as if there is a vendetta between parts of the state and an increasingly militant opposition, said Nathan Brown, professor of political science and international affairs at George Washington University.
In this case it appears that a serious miscarriage of justice took place. Three of the six convicted men have an alibi  they were already in prison on the dates they allegedly carried out their attacks on the army. Ahmed Helmy, a lawyer who represented the men, said the court seemed unwilling to listen to the evidence. The judge was shown official documents that proved that they were arrested before the crimes allegedly took place, he said. The documents included times and places of arrest and the fact that they were in Azouli prison, a military detention facility known for human rights abuses.
Advertisement
Helmy said the outcome of the trial seemed like a foregone conclusion from the start.
There is a sense that the sentences were already decided. The defendants told me not to bother [defending them]. They said, We know we will get the death penalty, dont trouble yourself. They knew this would happen, he said.
The whole trial was flawed, rights groups say. Elmessiry describes the proceedings as procedurally completely null and void because they were held in enforced disappearance [not official detention] and they were not held in an official place of detention. The civilian defendants were also tried in a military court. The administrative case on June 2 will challenge the sentences on these grounds.
Helmy sees the executions as a warning to those still in jail.
It was a kind of threat  they will apply this sentence to scare the other prisoners into negotiating with them and solving the crisis.
What do Egypts friends have to say?
The United States gave a milquetoast response to Morsis death sentence, saying they were deeply concerned  a sentiment that didnt get in the way of a meeting in Cairo last Wednesday between General Lloyd James Austin, the head of US Central Command, and Sisi. The presidency said the two men were talking about counterterrorism efforts.
I think Western actors  the Europeans and the US  have essentially come to terms with the fact that the new Egyptian regime is following a repressive path, said Brown. He added that it is unlikely to pose a serious barrier to relations.
But if politically motivated death sentences continue  and particularly, if Morsi does end up being executed  the US and other Western governments who have supported the Sisi government will have some explaining to do.
If the Egyptian government actually executed all those who have death sentences passed on them, the bloodletting would be hard to ignore. I think it would lead to a bit of international isolation, Brown said. If instead we see selected executions it will lead to more tension in their relationship but will not completely disrupt it.
Already, Egypts increasingly poor record on human rights is causing Cairo to lose friends in some European capitals. The president of the German parliament canceled a June meeting with Sisi, citing human rights abuses and lack of parliamentary elections in Egypt. Egypt, meanwhile, denied that it had requested a meeting in the first place.
What weve seen from the West is disappointing but expected, said Sarah Leah Whitson, head of the Middle East division at Human Rights Watch. The Obama administration has routinely set aside the rights of Egyptian citizens in favor of its so-called strategic interests in Egypt, she said.
That doesnt mean US officials arent keeping an eye on the Egyptian judiciary, however.
I think a lot of diplomats are waiting to see whether the Court of Cassation [the final line of legal appeal] continues to function as a pressure valve or whether it begins finalizing the hundreds of preliminary death sentences currently before it, Whitson said.
Helmy said it is too soon to tell what will happen in those cases. But he doesnt think the former president will actually be executed.
I dont expect they will carry out Morsis sentence. They want to negotiate with the Muslim Brotherhood and they dont need to kill him now, he said.
What will happen in Egypts courts is increasingly difficult to predict. Under former president Hosni Mubarak there were sometimes faulty sentences, but usually not in cases carrying the death penalty, Helmy said.
Now you have the feeling that the whole system is lost, that the sentences comes from above and are already decided.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:09:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Faulty fan, smoke blamed in brief evacuation of U.S. Capitol</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150526/faulty-fan-smoke-blamed-in-brief-evacuation-of-us-capitol</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Faulty fan, smoke blamed in brief evacuation of U.S. Capitol
By Alan Fram, The Associated Press
Posted:
WASHINGTON &gt;&gt; Police briefly evacuated hundreds of workers and tourists from the U.S. Capitol and its adjacent visitors center on Tuesday in a problem officials tentatively blamed on a faulty exhaust fan in a visitor center kitchen.
Within an hour after alarms sounded, employees returned to the building. Tourists were readmitted shortly after that.
Lawmakers are in recess this week for the weeklong Memorial Day break.
The U.S. Capitol Police told congressional workers in an email that two alarms were triggered in the visitors center, which they said was apparently caused by a known problem with environmental controls with the kitchen exhaust fan. It provided no additional detail.
Kimberly Schneider, a Capitol Police spokeswoman, said there were no signs of smoke or fire. An email sent later to House staff by the chambers sergeant at arms office said the triggering of alarms was most likely caused by smoke in the kitchen; there was no fire.
The evacuation occurred two days after a bomb squad destroyed a pressure cooker found in an unattended, suspicious vehicle on the National Mall near the Capitol and the vehicles Virginia owner was arrested. Almost six weeks earlier, a Florida man was arrested after he flew his gyrocopter through restricted air space and onto the Capitol grounds.
In Tuesdays incident, police cleared the East Lawn and closed First Street between the Capitol and the Library of Congress until the buildings were reopened.
Denise Grandits of Buffalo, New York, said she and 70 eighth-graders were touring the Capitol and heard the alarms. She said the guide escorted them out of the building.
We just walked. It was pretty calm, she said.
According to the police email, officials initially thought one of the two triggered alarms was in the Capitol and they began evacuating that building.
In a moment of confusion, police soon advised people in the Capitol that they could remain inside because the alarms were not coming from that building. They reversed themselves again minutes later and resumed evacuating the Capitol.
The police email said once officials determined both alarms were in the visitor center, they decided to continue emptying the Capitol to ensure staff and members did not receive conflicting information.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 05:36:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida Police: 3 kids hurt when waterspout uproots bounce house</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/florida-police-3-kids-hurt-when-waterspout-uproots-bounce-house</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Waterspouts
Florida Police: 3 kids hurt when waterspout uproots bounce house
In this photo provided by Burt Osteen, glass is scattered around a toppled basketball hoop after a waterspout made landfall at Fort Lauderdale Beach, Fla. on Monday, May 25, 2015. Authorities say three children were injured when the waterspout uprooted a bounce house and sent it across a parking lot into the road. Burt Osteen via AP
By JENNIFER KAY, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
MIAMI &gt;&gt; A waterspout uprooted an inflatable bounce house with three children inside it on a South Florida beach Monday, but the youngsters were tossed to the sand before it flew above palm trees and over four lanes of traffic, police said.
All three children were quickly thrown to the beach while another nearby bounce house, which was unoccupied, also took flight over the state road, authorities said. Both inflatables crashed won in a parking lot.
The children were injured, but alert and conscious when they were taken to a hospital, Fort Lauderdale Police spokesman Keven Dupree said.
A police statement later Monday evening said two of the children were treated for minor fractures and released while a third was in stable condition and held overnight for observation at Broward Health Medical Center.
Their identities werent released and police said no vehicles or pedestrians were hit by the bounce houses.
Video on local television stations showed the waterspout  a whirling column of air and water mist  moving from the ocean onto the sand of Fort Lauderdale beach, tossing a canopy and rolling one of the bounce houses before lifting it into the air.
The house flew above the tree line, but the children fell out when it first flipped over the beach, Dupree said. They were immediately dropped out of the bounce house onto the sand, he said.
Both bounce houses had been secured to a basketball court as part of a city-sponsored family activity zone set up for a Memorial Day holiday event. The waterspout snapped a concrete pole holding a basketball hoop.
Burt Osteen, a 37-year-old flooring installer from Fort Lauderdale, and his family dove to the sand on their stomachs as they saw the waterspout spinning toward them.
It came right over us. We laid on the ground; we were right in front of the bounce house. We watched it pick up the bounce house and snap a basketball hoop, Osteen said.
He barely felt anything, though, when the waterspout passed over them. The tablecloths on nearby picnic tables werent even disturbed by the wind, he said.
The only thing was the sand, getting stung by the sand, he said.
Unlike tornadoes, waterspouts dont need thunderstorms for their funnel clouds to form. On Monday afternoon, a band of clouds was moving in from the ocean had winds favorable for waterspout formation, said Jeral Estupinan, a meteorologist with the National Weather Service in Miami.
Advertisement
It developed very close to the coastline and moved onshore, and it dissipated very quickly onshore, like any other waterspout, Estupinan said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue May 26 05:15:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man diagnosed with Lassa fever dies in US after Liberia trip</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/health/20150525/man-diagnosed-with-lassa-fever-dies-in-us-after-liberia-trip</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man diagnosed with Lassa fever dies in US after Liberia trip
By MIKE STOBBE, AP Medical Writer
Posted:
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; A New Jersey man died Monday evening after been diagnosed with Lassa fever  a frightening infectious disease from West Africa that is rarely seen in the United States, a federal health official said.
The man recently returned from Liberia, arriving at New York Citys JFK International Airport on May 17. He grew critically ill after his return, suffering from multiple organ failure, said Dr. Tom Frieden, director of the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Atlanta.
Health officials said they dont think the case is cause for public alarm. Lassa fever is not spread through casual contact. About a half dozen other cases have been diagnosed in travelers from West Africa in the past, and none of them ever spread the illness person-to-person, Frieden said.
But as a precaution, the CDC and New Jersey health officials are trying to track down and monitor anyone the man was in contact with during the past week, including health workers at two New Jersey hospitals and people who sat close to him on his recent flight from Morocco to New York.
The illness is commonly seen in West Africa, in some of the same countries struck by the recent Ebola epidemic. This last confirmed case of Lassa fever seen in a traveler returning to the United States was in Minnesota last year. The one before that was in Pennsylvania in 2010.
Generally speaking, Lassa fever is far less likely to be fatal than Ebola and less likely to be spread from person to person. About 80 percent of cases are mild. But in severe cases, patients can suffer fever, vomiting, organ failure, shock and even bleeding from the eyes, nose and gums. Its fatal in about 1 percent of cases. Sometimes, those who survive are deaf for the rest of their lives.
Like Ebola, it can spread through contact with blood, feces or vomit of an infected person. In West Africa, Lassa virus is carried by rodents and transmitted to humans through contact with urine or droppings of infected rodents.
CDC officials declined to give the name or identifying information about the man, other than to say he frequently traveled to Liberia on business and had worked in the mining industry. CDC officials on Monday also declined to name the New Jersey hospital where the man first went for care, or to a second New Jersey hospital where he was subsequently treated with ribavirin, an antiviral medication given intravenously.
The patient had no symptoms during the flight, but a day later went to a New Jersey hospital suffering from a sore throat and lethargy.
Advertisement
Hospital officials said they had asked the man about his travel history and that he did not say he had recently been to West Africa, CDC officials said.
Three days later he had returned to the hospital with more severe symptoms. He was transferred to the second hospital Saturday. On Monday, CDC lab tests of the patients blood confirmed Lassa fever.
The CDC plans to send a special response team including a Lassa fever expert and specialists in occupational safety and waste management to the second hospital Tuesday.
Health officials regularly note that exotic illnesses are only a plane ride away.
We expect to see Lassa fever and other infections like this. Because of Ebola, were now better prepared to deal with it, Frieden said.
Lassa fever was named after a Nigerian town where Western-trained doctors first noted it in 1969. An estimated 100,000 to 300,000 infections occur in West Africa each year, including about 5,000 deaths. In some areas of Sierra Leone and Liberia, 10 to 15 percent of people admitted to hospitals every year have Lassa fever.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:50:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anonymous threats against airliners prompt searches; all OK</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/anonymous-threats-against-airliners-prompt-searches-all-ok</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Anonymous threats against airliners prompt searches; all OK
By Associated Press
# Comments
NEW YORK &gt;&gt; Anonymous telephone threats against commercial airliners on Monday, possibly from the same source, caused a scare involving at least six international flights at airports in New York, New Jersey and Massachusetts.
Authorities said the threats did not appear to be credible. They described searches done on the jets as a precaution.
In one instance Monday morning, U.S. military jets escorted an Air France flight into New York City after someone claimed a chemical weapon was aboard the aircraft, the FBI said.
Out of an abundance of caution, Air France flight number 22 was escorted to John F. Kennedy airport by U.S. Air Force fighter jets following a phone threat, the FBI said in a statement. There were no incidents or hazards reported on board the flight by either the passengers or its crew. The plane has been cleared.
A Saudi Arabian Airlines flight arriving at Kennedy also was being checked out because of another threat, authorities said.
A third threat was made against an American Airlines jet flying from Birmingham, England, to Kennedy while it was still in the air, airline spokesman Kent Powell said. Authorities initially told the pilot to land and taxi to a remote area away from the terminal but later radioed that the threat was not credible and cleared the plane to go to the terminal, Powell said.
At Newark Liberty International Airport, passengers were removed from a United Airlines flight after it arrived from Madrid, United spokeswoman Mary Clark said. The plane was inspected Monday afternoon at a spot away from the terminal.
Atlanta-based Delta Air Lines Inc. said two of its international planes were threatened: a Paris-to-Boston flight and a London-to-Newark flight.
A threat made against a Paris-to-Boston airliner was deemed not credible, Massachusetts Port Authority spokesman Matthew Brelis said, but he didnt say if that was Deltas plane. He said he didnt know the circumstances of the threat or if the plane was searched.
Maryland State Police said they received an anonymous call at the McHenry barracks in the western part of the state threatening commercial aviation about 6:30 a.m. Monday and referred it to the FBI. They declined to comment further.
___
Associated Press writer David Koenig in Dallas contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 03:33:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyer says allegations B.B. King was poisoned 'ridiculous'</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150525/lawyer-says-allegations-bb-king-was-poisoned-ridiculous</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Celebrity deaths
Lawyer says allegations B.B. King was poisoned ridiculous
FILE-In this Aug. 22, 2012 photograph, the  then 86-year-old B.B. King thrills a crowd of several hundred people at the annual B.B. King Homecoming, a free concert on the grounds of an old cotton gin where he worked as a teenager many years ago, in Indianola, Miss. Festival organizers said this years festival was to have been a tribute to the then living King, who died May 14, 2015. Now they are calling it  a memorial celebration. AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, File
By KEN RITTER, Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
LAS VEGAS &gt;&gt; Two B.B. King heirs whove been most outspoken about the blues legends care in his final days are accusing Kings two closest aides of poisoning him, but the attorney for Kings estate is calling the claims ridiculous.
Three doctors determined that King was appropriately cared-for, and King received 24-hour care and monitoring by medical professionals up until the time that he peacefully passed away in his sleep, attorney Brent Bryson told the AP on Monday.
Daughters Karen Williams and Patty King allege that family members were prevented from visiting while Kings business manager, LaVerne Toney, and his personal assistant, Myron Johnson, hastened their fathers death.
Toney is named in Kings will as executor of an estate that, according to court documents filed by lawyers for some of Kings heirs, could total tens of millions of dollars.
Johnson was at B.B. Kings bedside when he died May 14 in hospice care at home in Las Vegas at age 89. No family members were present.
I believe my father was poisoned and that he was administered foreign substances, Patty King and Williams say in identically worded sections of affidavits provided to The Associated Press by their lawyer, Larissa Drohobyczer.
I believe my father was murdered, they say.
Toney and Johnson each declined to comment on the accusations.
Theyve been making allegations all along. Whats new? said Toney, who worked for King for 39 years and had power-of-attorney over his affairs.
A week before Kings death, a judge in Las Vegas dismissed a request from Williams to take over as Kings guardian.
An April 29 petition alleged that Toney had blocked Kings friends from visiting him and had put her family members on Kings payroll. It also alleged that large sums of money had disappeared from Kings bank accounts.
But Clark County Family Court Hearing Master Jon Norheim said on May 7 that police and social services investigations in October and April uncovered no reason to take power-of-attorney from Toney.
Williams, Patty King and another daughter Rita Washington  vowed to keep fighting.
We lost the battle, but we havent lost the war, Williams said then.
This weeks allegations come days after a public viewing in Las Vegas drew more than 1,000 fans and mourners and a weekend family-and-friends memorial drew 350. A Beale Street procession and memorial are scheduled Wednesday in Memphis, Tennessee, followed by a Friday viewing and Saturday burial in Kings hometown of Indianola, Mississippi.
Advertisement
Clark County Coroner John Fudenberg said Monday the investigation shouldnt delay Kings final trip home to the Mississippi Delta.
Fudenberg said an autopsy was performed Sunday and Kings body was then returned to a Las Vegas mortuary. Test results will take up to eight weeks to obtain, and shouldnt be affected by the fact that Kings body had been embalmed, he said.
This is extremely disrespectful to B.B. King, Bryson said on Monday. He did not want invasive medical procedures. He made the decision to return home for hospice care instead of staying in a hospital. These unfounded allegations have caused Mr. King to undergo an autopsy, which is exactly what he didnt want.
Las Vegas police homicide detectives are investigating, Lt. Ray Steiber said Monday. He declined to provide details.
Drohobyczer said she represents Williams, Patty King and most of Kings nine other adult children and heirs.
The family is sticking together ... to oust Ms. Toney based on her illegal conduct, conflicts of interest and self-dealing, she said. She alleged that Toney hastened Kings death by misconduct, or by failing to properly attend to his medical needs.
An affidavit from Patty King, who used to live at Kings home, says she saw Johnson administer to King two drops of an unknown substance on his tongue during evenings for several months before his death, and that Toney never told her what the substance was.
Bryson called Drohobyczers claims ridiculous.
I hope they have a factual basis that they can demonstrate for their defamatory and libelous allegations, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:32:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charter nears $55 billion deal for Time Warner Cable</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/business/20150525/charter-nears-55-billion-deal-for-time-warner-cable</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Mergers and acquisitions
Charter nears $55 billion deal for Time Warner Cable
This photo shows a Charter Communications van in St. Louis. Charter Communications is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, two people familiar with the negotiations said Monday. Jeff Roberson  The Associated Press
By Tali Arbel and David Koenig, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
This file photo shows a Time Warner Cable truck in New York .Charter Communications is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, two people familiar with the negotiations said Monday. Mark Lennihan  The Associated Press file
Charter Communications Inc. is close to buying Time Warner Cable for about $55 billion, according to two people familiar with the negotiations.
The people spoke on condition of anonymity Monday because of the private nature of the talks.
One person said the deal will be announced early this morning.
Charter had wanted to buy Time Warner Cable Inc. earlier, but Time Warner Cable chose a $45 billion offer from Comcast Corp. instead.
Comcast walked away from the Time Warner Cable deal after regulators pushed back against it. Regulators had concerns that the two companies together would undermine online video competition. The combined company would have served more than half the countrys broadband subscribers, and consumer advocates said a merger would limit choices and lead to higher prices.
Time Warner Cable representative Ellen East and Charter spokesman Justin Venech both declined to comment on the talks between their companies.
Cable companies are losing cable subscribers and facing more pressure from online services such as Netflix and Amazon for consumers who watch TV over broadband connections.
Consumer advocates were waiting to learn more details about the deal but seemed initially to regard it with less hostility than the failed Comcast bid for Time Warner Cable, which would have created a behemoth controlling much of the Internet access in the U.S.
I cant say that were a big fan of industry consolidation, but realistically this doesnt really raise the same level of concern, said John Bergmayer, a lawyer with Public Knowledge.
If antitrust regulators approve the deal, Bergmayer said, they should attach conditions addressing broadband affordability, customer service and other issues.
Cable companies argue that their mergers dont hurt TV consumers because their systems dont overlap much  an argument that is disputed by consumer groups.
Matt Wood, policy director of the Internet-consumer group Free Press, said the money that the cable companies spend on mergers doesnt go to helping customers.
Rather than buying each other up and cementing in place the local monopolies they already enjoy, they could be investing in their own networks to improve their customer service, Wood said.
They could even go outside their current markets and compete against each other in more places, he said.
Shares of Time Warner Cable closed Friday at $171.18. They have climbed 13 percent so far in 2015, compared with a 3 percent gain in the Standard &amp; Poors 500 index.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 00:35:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tornado kills 13 in Mexico border city; 12 missing in Texas</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/tornado-kills-13-in-mexico-border-city-12-missing-in-texas</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Storms
Tornado kills 13 in Mexico border city; 12 missing in Texas
A carving of St. Francis of Assisi stands amid debris next to a destroyed home on River Road in Wimberley, Texas, on Monday. Around a dozen people were reported missing in flash flooding from a line of storms that stretched from the Gulf of Mexico to the Great Lakes. Jerry Lara  The San Antonio Express-News via AP
By Seth Robbins and Mark Stevenson, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A bulldozer clears away debris after a powerful tornado swept past in Ciudad Acuna, northern Mexico, on Monday. A tornado raged through the city on the U.S.-Mexico border Monday, destroying homes and flinging cars like matchsticks. At least 13 people were killed, authorities said. The twister hit a seven-block area, which Victor Zamora, interior secretary of the northern state of Coahuila, described as devastated. The Associated Press
CIUDAD ACUNA, Mexico &gt;&gt; A tornado raged through a city on the U.S.-Mexico border Monday, destroying homes, flinging cars like matchsticks and ripping an infant from its mothers arms. At least 13 people were killed, authorities said.
In Texas, 12 people were reported missing after the vacation home they were staying in was swept away by rushing floodwaters in a small town popular with tourists.
The baby was also missing after the twister that hit Ciudad Acuna, a city of 125,000 across from Del Rio, Texas, sent its infant carrier flying. Rescue workers began digging through the rubble of damaged homes in a race to find victims.
The twister hit a seven-block area, which Victor Zamora, interior secretary of the northern state of Coahuila, described as devastated.
Mayor Evaristo Perez Rivera said 300 people were being treated at local hospitals and up to 200 homes had been destroyed. Three people were unaccounted for.
Theres nothing standing, not walls, not roofs, said Edgar Gonzalez, a spokesman for the city government, describing some of the destroyed homes in a 1-square mile stretch.
By midday, 13 people were confirmed dead: 10 adults and three infants.
Family members and neighbors gathered around a pickup truck where the bodies of a woman and two children were laid out in the trucks bed, covered with sheets. Two relatives reached down to touch the bodies, covered their eyes and wept.
Photos from the scene showed cars with their hoods torn off, resting upended against single-story houses. One cars frame was bent around the gate of a house. A bus was seen flipped and crumpled on a roadway.
The twister struck not long after daybreak, around the time buses were preparing to take children to school, Zamora said.
Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto said he planned to travel to Acuna with officials from government agencies.
In the U.S., a line of storms that stretched from the Gulf of Mexico to the Great Lakes dumped record rainfall on parts of the Plains and Midwest, spawning tornadoes and causing major flooding that forced at least 2,000 Texans from their homes.
Witnesses reported seeing the swollen Blanco River push the vacation house off its foundation and smash it into a bridge. Only pieces of the home have been found, according to Hays County Judge Bert Cobb.
Advertisement
One person who was rescued from the home told workers that the other 12 inside were all connected to two families, Cobb said.
The house was in Wimberley Valley, an area known for its bed-and-breakfast inns and weekend rental cottages.
Dana Campbell, a retired engineer who lives on a bluff above the river, said the floodwaters left behind damage that resembled the path of a tornado as far as the eye can see.
The storms were blamed for three deaths Saturday and Sunday, including two in Oklahoma and one in Texas, where a mans body was recovered from a flooded area along the Blanco River, which rose 26 feet in an hour and created huge piles of debris.
Texas Gov. Greg Abbott flew over parts of the Blanco on Monday, a day after heavy rains pushed the river into surrounding neighborhoods.
Abbott said the storms had relentless tsunami-type power. He urged communities downstream to monitor flood levels and take the threat seriously.
The governor added 24 counties to his disaster declaration, bringing the total to 37, most in the eastern half of the state.
Among the worst-affected communities were Wimberley and San Marcos, along the Blanco in the corridor between Austin and San Antonio.
About 1,000 homes were damaged throughout Hays County. Five police cars were washed away, and the firehouse was flooded, said Kristi Wyatt, a spokeswoman for San Marcos.
Rivers swelled so quickly that whole communities awoke Sunday surrounded by water. The Blanco crested above 40 feet  more than triple its flood stage of 13 feet. The river swamped Interstate 35 and forced parts of the busy north-south highway to close. Rescuers used pontoon boats and a helicopter to pull people out.
Hundreds of trees along the Blanco were uprooted or snapped, and they collected in piles of debris that soared 20 feet high.
Weve got trees in the rafters, said Cherri Maley, property manager of a house where the structures entire rear portion collapsed with the flooding, carrying away furniture.
We had the refrigerator in a tree, she said. I think its a total loss.
A tornado briefly touched down Sunday in Houston, damaging rooftops, toppling trees, blowing out windows and sending at least two people to a hospital. Fire officials said 10 apartments were heavily damaged and 40 others sustained lesser damage.
Dallas faced severe flooding from the Trinity River, which was expected to crest near 40 feet Monday and lap at the foundations of an industrial park. The Red and Wichita rivers also rose far above flood stage.
Stevenson reported from Mexico City. Associated Press Writer Paul Weber in San Marcos contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon May 25 19:27:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama pays tribute to fallen service members at Arlington</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/lifestyle/20150525/obama-pays-tribute-to-fallen-service-members-at-arlington</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Memorial Day
Obama pays tribute to fallen service members at Arlington
President Barack Obama, accompanied by Maj. Gen. Jeffrey S. Buchanan, left, Commander of the U.S. Army Military District of Washington, and the with the aid of  Sgt. 1st Class John C. Wirth, lays a wreath at the Tomb of the Unknowns, on Memorial Day, Monday at Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Va. Pablo Martinez Monsivais  The Associated Press
By Darlene Superville, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
A member of the U.S. Armys 3rd Infantry Regiment The Old Guard stands at attention during the arrival of President Barack Obamas motorcade at Arlington National Cemetery, Monday in Arlington, Va., for Memorial Day ceremonies. Pablo Martinez Monsivais  The Associated Press
ARLINGTON, Va. &gt;&gt; President Barack Obama on Monday saluted Americans who died in battle, saying the country must never stop trying to fully repay them for their sacrifices. He noted it was the first Memorial Day in 14 years without U.S. forces engaged in a major ground war.
Speaking under sunny skies to some 5,000 people in an amphitheater on the hallowed grounds of Arlington National Cemetery, Obama said the graveyard is more than a final resting place of heroes.
It is a reflection of America itself, he said, citing racial and religious diversity in the backgrounds of the men and woman who paid the ultimate sacrifice to preserve the ideals that bind us as one nation.
His appearance is an annual rite for presidents at the cemetery nestled among verdant hills overlooking the Potomac River. It came months after the end of the U.S. combat mission in Afghanistan, where the number of stationed troops has been reduced to about 10,000 from a peak of more than 100,000.
His tribute also took place against a backdrop of the increasingly complex U.S.-led effort to help Iraq defeat the Islamic State extremist group, which has been gaining momentum in recent weeks by capturing Ramadi there and taking Palmyra in neighboring Syria.
Obama made no mention of Americas participation with other nations in the effort to stop the Islamic State. His effort there has come under intensifying criticism since the fall of Ramadi with lawmakers calling for a bigger show of American force there, including ground troops.
Vice President Joe Biden spoke Monday with Iraqi Prime Minister Haider al-Abadi and pledged full U.S. support for Iraqi efforts to reclaim territory from the Islamic State, including by speeding up the provision of U.S. training and equipment, the White House said.
Defense Secretary Ash Carter had said in a nationally broadcast interview aired Sunday that Iraqi forces showed no will to fight and fled as the Islamic State advanced on Ramadi. The White House said in a statement that Bidens call recognized the enormous sacrifice and bravery of Iraqi forces over the past 18 months in Ramadi and elsewhere.
In his remarks at Arlington National Cemetery, Obama said most of the remaining troops should be removed from Afghanistan by the end of 2016.
He recognized the more than 2,200 patriots who sacrificed themselves in Afghanistan, including the final two to be killed before the U.S. combat mission ended late last year. He also recognized the first American killed during the new mission to train Afghan forces, an Army medic who died in April.
Advertisement
Earlier, troops stationed in that war-wracked country observed a moment of silence in honor of fallen comrades there.
The Arlington observance was among a host of Memorial Day events nationwide featuring parades, picnics and tributes.
Presaging Mondays solemn event at Arlington was the roar of motorcycle engines throughout the nations capital on Sunday as thousands of bikers saluted veterans with Rolling Thunders Ride for Freedom. That was followed by a concert of patriotic music Sunday evening and Obamas private breakfast Monday at the White House with representatives of veteran and military family service organizations. A Memorial Day parade also was held Monday in downtown Washington.
North Dakota marked the 25th anniversary of the groundbreaking for the states Veterans Cemetery south of Mandan. Gov. Jack Dalrymple directed all state agencies to fly the U.S. and state flags at half-staff, a practice put in place across the country.
Obama traveled by motorcade in late morning from the White House to Arlington and began his outing by laying a wreath at the Tomb of the Unknowns. He bowed his head briefly and listened with others to the playing of Taps.
Obama said most Americans dont understand the sacrifice made by the 1 percent of the population that serves in the all-volunteer Armed Forces. But when he meets with Gold Star families that have lost loved ones through military service, Obama said he hears their pride through their tears.
I see that their hearts are still broken, and yet still full of love, he said. They do not ask for awards or honors. They do not ask for special treatment. They are unfailingly humble. In the face of unspeakable loss, they represent the best of who we are.
Obama said the markers at Arlington signify the blessings many Americans enjoy.
Its a debt we can never fully repay, he said, but it is a debt we will never stop trying to fully repay.
Introducing Obama, Carter, the defense secretary, said, We, your fellow Americans, lack the words to describe what you feel today because try as we may, and try as we do, we can never fully know. But we do know what your sacrifice means to us.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon May 25 21:07:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Tomorrowland' takes top spot at box office on slow weekend</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/arts-and-entertainment/20150525/tomorrowland-takes-top-spot-at-box-office-on-slow-weekend</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Box office receipts
Tomorrowland takes top spot at box office on slow weekend
This photo released by Disney shows, George Clooney, as Frank Walker, in a scene from Disneys Tomorrowland. The film releases in U.S. theaters. Film Frame  Disney via AP
By Lindsey Bahr, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
LOS ANGELES &gt;&gt; The future doesnt look so bright for Tomorrowland.
Disneys expensive fantasy adventure essentially had Memorial Day weekend to itself, and still only pulled in a modest $41.7 million in its first four days in theaters according to Rentrak estimates on Monday.
Its a disappointing debut for a film that cost a reported $180 million to produce. Disney put their full weight behind the Brad Bird-directed film with an ambitious George Clooney-led promotional campaign.
Its not ever ideal to be below your estimate before the weekend starts, but it feels like its too early to judge the run, said Disneys Distribution EVP Dave Hollis.
Going into the weekend, tracking put the film in the $40 to $50 million range. And yet, he said, this is the gamble that studios must take when trying to introduce an original film to the marketplace.
Hollis noted that Tomorrowland will be one of the only PG-rated family films in theaters until Disney and Pixars Inside Out opens on June 19, which could be promising for its longevity  especially considering that many schools have yet to close for the summer.
We are optimistic that originality and the vision that Brad Bird put on the screen is something that people will find and evangelize and hopefully get other folks to show up, said Hollis.
Rentraks Senior Media Analyst Paul Dergarabedian said that the mystery behind Tomorrowlands plot might have hurt the film.
When audiences are spending their hard earned cash on a blockbuster or tent-pole movie, they kind of want to know what theyre getting going in, for better or worse, he said.
Last weekends well-received holdovers Pitch Perfect 2 and Mad Max: Fury Road helped prop up the holiday weekend totals. Both films experienced modest drops and earned $38.5 million and $32.1 million respectively.
Avengers: Age of Ultron placed fourth with $27.8 million.
Meanwhile, Foxs Poltergeist remake debuted in fifth place, with an estimated $26.5 million.
Director Gil Kenans update of Tobe Hoopers 1982 horror classic cost $35 million to produce. The studio expected an opening in the low $20 million range.
I think for our filmmakers, who had set out not to just remake a classic but to introduce a new generation of fans to the genre, it was very successful, said Foxs domestic distribution chief Chris Aronson.
Advertisement
Audiences for the PG-13 rated film were 59 percent under the age of 25.
Overall, though, there wasnt much to celebrate over this holiday weekend. Memorial Day weekends are usually reserved for high-earning franchise fare.
The past two years saw the over $100 million debuts of X-Men: Days of Future Past and Fast &amp; Furious 6. When box office totals are finalized on Tuesday, this could prove to be one of the worst performing in recent years.
The industry went into this weekend knowing we werent going to break any records, said Dergarabedian. This is more of a case of audiences, somewhat, turning their back on original content when it comes to big blockbusters.
But, hope is certainly not lost for a banner 2015 at the box office, with more surefire blockbusters like Jurassic World and Mission: Impossible-Rogue Nation yet to open.
Summer is not going to be a bummer this year. This is a bump in the box office road, said Dergarabedian.
Estimated ticket sales for Friday through Monday at U.S. and Canadian theaters, according to Rentrak. Final domestic figures will be released Tuesday.
1. Tomorrowland, $41.7 million.
2. Pitch Perfect 2, $38.5 million.
3. Mad Max: Fury Road,$32.1 million.
4. Avengers: Age of Ultron, $27.8 million.
5. Poltergeist, $26.5 million.
6. Hot Pursuit, $4.6 million.
7. Far From the Madding Crowd, $3 million.
8. Furious 7,$2.8 million.
9. Paul Blart: Mall Cop 2, $2.5 million.
10. Home, $2.4 million.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon May 25 20:36:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South African rhino survives horrific attack by poachers</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/south-african-rhino-survives-horrific-attack-by-poachers</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Wildlife poaching and smuggling
South African rhino survives horrific attack by poachers
In this photo taken Friday and supplied by Saving the Survivors, a rhino named Hope, stands in her pen in the Eastern Cape province, treated with a dressing where her horns used to be. Poachers had darted the rhino with a tranquilizer and then hacked off its horns while it was sedated, leaving the animal with a horrific wound covering much of its face. Suzanne Boswell Rudham  Saving the Survivors via AP
By Christopher Torchia, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
JOHANNESBURG &gt;&gt; The rhinos rescuers gave her a name: Hope.
Poachers in South Africa had darted the rhino with a tranquilizer and hacked off her horns while she was sedated, leaving the animal with a horrific wound covering much of her face. A couple of days later, staff on a wildlife reserve found the grievously injured rhino  alive.
Last week, veterinarians operated on the 4-year-old female, a rare survivor of increasing attacks by poachers who killed more than 1,200 rhinos last year in South Africa, home to most of the worlds rhinos. They removed maggots and dead tissue, applied dressing and fastened a fiberglass cast with steel screws. The wound measures 50 by 28 centimeters (19.6 by 11 inches), the biggest of 10 similar cases that the team has treated in the last three years.
If we can save Hope and she can go back and produce more offspring, then in her lifetime she would have contributed to the survival of the species, said Dr. Gerhard Steenkamp, a veterinarian from the University of Pretoria. He is a member of Saving the Survivors, a South African group that treats rhinos with gunshot wounds, facial gouges and other injuries inflicted by poachers.
Demand for rhino horn is high in parts of Asia where it is seen as a status symbol and a cure for illness despite a lack of evidence that it can heal.
The rhino called Hope was attacked in Lombardini, a wildlife reserve in Eastern Cape province where several rhinos were poached recently.
Hopes nasal bone was badly fractured and part was removed, exposing the sinus cavities and nasal passage. Surgery occurred May 18 after the rhino was transferred to another reserve. It could take at least a year for Hopes wound to heal after multiple treatments, Steenkamp said.
It cost $75,000 to treat Lions Den, a rhino with a similar but less severe injury, and Thandi, a rhino whose horns were hacked off in 2012, recovered and gave birth in January, according to Saving the Survivors.
Group spokeswoman Suzanne Boswell Rudham said Monday of Hope: Shes doing really well.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon May 25 20:33:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fewer students study botany, more plant collections closing</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/science/20150525/fewer-students-study-botany-more-plant-collections-closing</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Botany
Fewer students study botany, more plant collections closing
In this photo, botanist Theo Witsell examines a plant near Mount Ida, Ark. Witsell, the botanist for the Arkansas Natural Heritage Commission, and a handful of other commission staff have combed the state in recent years to find, collect and preserve more than 70,000 native plant species. Danny Johnston  The Associated Press
By Claudia Lauer, The Associated Press
Posted:
# Comments
In this photo, George Yatskievych of the Missouri Botanical Garden is interviewed near Mount Ida, Ark. Yatskievych is the curator, and director of Flora of Missouri Project Research. Since 1988, the number of research universities offering botany degrees has dropped by half, according to National Science Foundation research funding statistics. And the National Center for Education Statistics reports that fewer than 400 undergraduate, graduate and doctoral botany degrees were awarded in 2012. Danny Johnston  The Associated Press
MOUNT IDA, Ark. &gt;&gt; The teeming plant world could become a virtual mystery in the coming decades as college students increasingly shy away from studying botany and universities across the U.S. shutter their long-standing herbaria.
Since 1988, the number of research universities offering botany degrees has dropped by half, according to National Science Foundation research funding statistics. And the National Center for Education Statistics reports that fewer than 400 undergraduate, graduate and doctoral botany degrees were awarded in 2012. Educators say thats because students are being pushed into more modern, technology-related majors.
Current botanists fear that will lead to a dearth of people able to teach about, identify and use plants, which could harm conservation efforts and even the ability to develop alternate fuels and important medicines. At the same time, universities and states struggling under budget cuts are closing the sometimes-expensive task of maintaining herbaria collections of plant species that botanists can reference or use for genetic material.
We arent going to understand what we have in the world. By some estimates only 20 percent of the (plant and animal) species in the world have been identified, said Joe Miller, a program officer at the National Science Foundations Division of Environmental Biology.
In a clearing on the side of a rural Arkansas highway, about a dozen researchers scoured the rocky glade for a threatened annual called the Missouri bladderpod, which blooms with clusters of small yellow flowers. Only 75 populations of the threatened species exist in the world, and all are close enough to urban centers to be in danger, Arkansas Natural Heritage Commission botanist Theo Witsell said.
The 39-year-old, carrying a small shovel and a handful of large plastic bags, plucked a few purple flowering plants from the ground by the root.
I think one of the things thats happening in this field of study is there arent a lot of open jobs, Witsell said. But as people get older and they retire, you then have fewer people who are qualified for those jobs.
Witsell hopes to conserve some of the glades, where he said scientists are still finding new species of plants. Thats where botanists skills are irreplaceable, Miller said.
If we are able to name a plant, then we understand its biology, Miller said. If we understand its biology, then we can use the comparative method to understand and predict how it could be used.
Advertisement
For example, Quinine is a malaria treatment that occurs naturally in cinchona trees. He said if botanists identify plants with similar taxonomies that react similarly to their surroundings, plant biologists could do genetic research to find medical uses.
Herbaria are a major reference source for botanists, but increasingly, such repositories are dwindling as several states and universities have closed or consolidated their collections, including the University of Iowa and the University of Nebraska State Museum. Researchers acknowledge the bulky collections of plant specimens that are mounted, dried, dated and tagged with pivotal information can be hard to maintain. They require temperature and moisture control and space for the preparation process.
The University of Missouri announced May 18 that it would donate its more than 200,000 plant specimens to the Missouri Botanical Garden in St. Louis.
The facility on campus that was housing them, it outlived its lifespan, said Jordan Yount, a spokesman for the universitys College of Arts and Science. Regulating the humidity and temperature was critical and getting to be a problem. And we reached a point where we had to decide, do we spend a lot of money renovating this facility or find another home for the collection.
From his 14th-floor office in downtown Little Rock, Witsell is fighting the trend. After the University of Arkansas at Fayetteville herbarium narrowly escaped closure in 2003 and the University of Arkansas at Little Rock closed its collection a few years later, he decided the commission needed its own.
A handful of commission staff and Witsell have combed the state over the past 12 years to find, collect and preserve more than 70,000 native plant species. The commissions herbarium is now the most actively growing in Arkansas.
This is the physical record of the plant life of the planet, of this state, he said. You cant get all of the information from a photograph.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon May 25 20:32:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Company lowers worst-case scenario for California oil spill</title>
        <Link>http://www.dailynews.com/general-news/20150525/company-lowers-worst-case-scenario-for-california-oil-spill</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Oil spills
Company lowers worst-case scenario for California oil spill
Staff members and volunteers work to clean oil off a brown pelican at the International Bird Rescue office in the San Pedro area of Los Angeles, on Friday. A broken onshore pipeline in near Santa Barbara spewed oil down a storm drain and into the ocean for several hours Tuesday before it was shut off. Chris Carlson  The Associated Press
By The Associated Press
# Comments
Cleanup crews rake and shovel oil-contaminated sand into bags at El Capitan State Beach, north of Goleta Friday. Officials say the sheen of oil is now thinner than a coat of paint and is becoming harder to skim from choppy, wind-driven waters. A state parks official says Refugio and El Capitan state beaches and campgrounds will be closed until June 4. Thats a week longer than originally announced. The spill from the May 19 break now covers nearly 10 square miles. Michael A. Mariant  The Associated Press
GOLETA &gt;&gt; Plains All American Pipeline is downgrading the amount of oil it says spilled off a California coastline in a worst-case scenario.
The company now says the estimate of the worst-case volume of oil released is up to 101,000 gallons  about 4,200 gallons less than previously believed.
Plains All American is still cleaning up the spill along the Santa Barbara County coastline and recovering oil from the pipeline so the calculations arent final.
Oil blackened beaches in the area and created a 10-square-mile slick in the ocean after the onshore pipeline leaked up to 101,000 gallons on May 19.
The Coast Guard said Monday that the spill has killed one sea lion, nine pelicans and untold numbers of fish.
El Refugio and El Capitan beaches are closed until June 4.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
