<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Start of WW3? Putin could force the West to use NUCLEAR WEAPONS against Russia, warns NATO</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/vb84PHWfwT8/Vladimir-Putin-NATO-nuclear-weapons-Russia-Ukraine</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Start of WW3? Putin could force the West to use NUCLEAR WEAPONS against Russia, warns NATO
VLADIMIR PUTIN could seize power of the three ex-Soviet Baltic states in just TWO DAYS, forcing the West to use NUCLEAR WEAPONS against Russia, a top NATO general has warned.
02:45, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 03:03, Fri, May 29, 2015
GETTY
Vladimir Putin could force the West to use nuclear weapons against Russia
Europe and the United States are "embarrassingly" unprepared for Russian aggression, claimed General Petr Pavel.
The warning comes amid concerns the Russian president is massing military firepower and troops close to the Ukrainian border.
Today Putin banned revealing information about troop deaths in "special operations" during peacetime, as the Kremlin continues to rebuff accusations its soldiers are fighting in Ukraine.
Czech general Pavel, next chairman of the NATO Military Committee, issued a warning to Western leaders expressing his concern they are not ready for military action by Putin.
He said: "Russia could seize the Baltic countries in two days.
"NATO wouldn't be able to react to the situation in that time."
The Alliance would be forced to "weigh its positions regarding whether it would start a war - maybe even a nuclear war - against Russia for the Baltic states," he said.
Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia were all incorporated into the USSR by Stalin in June 1940, but are now members of NATO and the EU.
GETTY
The Ukraine-Russia crisis continues
Russia could seize the Baltic countries in two days. NATO wouldn't be able to react to the situation in that time
General Petr Pavel
General Pavel added that measures taken by Europe against threats from Russia, including Islamic State, were "embarrassingly ineffective".
He warned that NATO was hit by "weaknesses" such as a "complicated decision-making process" because it requires the agreement of 28 member states.
He said: "Russia on the other hand can make decisions very quickly, in a couple of hours."
EPA
The warning comes amid concerns the Russian president is massing military firepower near Ukraine
Putin was last year quoted as boasting: "If I wanted, Russian troops could not only be in Kiev in two days, but in Riga, Vilnius, Tallinn, Warsaw or Bucharest, too."
The warning comes as reports have pointed to a massing of Russian equipment close to the Ukraine border.
Hundreds of pieces of weaponry including mobile rocket launchers, tanks and artillery at a makeshift have been spotted.
Many vehicles have removed number plates and identifying marks, while servicemen have taken insignia off their fatigues.
AP
Putin pictured swimming. He previously boasted about marching Russian troops into Kiev
AP
A NATO general warned the West are not ready for military intervention by Vladimir Putin
The scene at the base on the Kuzminsky firing range - only 30 miles from the Ukrainian border - is said to offer "some of the clearest evidence to date of what appeared to be a concerted Russian military build-up in the area".
Ukraine and the West insist Russia has not only armed and equipped rebels, but also sent in troops to spearhead fighting against Kiev's forces.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Incredible moment woman sees dead brother's face on another man's body</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/PWhASIx4_6k/Face-transplant-woman-sees-dead-brothers-face-another-man-s-body-surgery</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Incredible moment woman sees dead brother's face on another man's body
THIS is the emotional moment a woman whose brother died in a tragic car crash saw and touched his face again - on another man's body.
02:43, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 03:03, Fri, May 29, 2015
IG
Rebekah touches Richard's new face
Rebekah Aversano's 21-year-old brother Joshua died in a horror car accident in 2012, but thanks to groundbreaking life-saving transplant surgery, she was able to look at his face once more.
Her family agreed to give Joshua's face to Richard Norris, 39, who was left horribly disfigured almost 18 years ago when he accidentally blew most of his face off with a shotgun.
Mr Norris, from Virginia, underwent one of the most complex and face transplants of all time, receiving a teeth, jaw and even tongue from his donor.
The incredible footage shows Mr Norris thanking Ms Aversano and her family for "saving my life".
SPLASH
Richard Norris with his new face
Wow, this is the face I grew up with
Rebekah Aversano
As the pair met for filming of 60 Minutes on Nine, Ms Aversano asked: "Do you mind if I touch it?"
She then stepped back in amazement and said: "Wow, this is the face I grew up with".
Mr Norris' accident left him so disfigured he had battled with suicidal thoughts.
He had undergone more than 30 operations to try and correct the damage and restore his features.
But three years ago the Aversano family offered him hope - and a chance to transform his life.
Joshua's mother Gwen Aversano said: "We can definitely see our son in him. Some of the facial features would definitely be our son, so we could see similarities, very much so.
"We are just so pleased we have been able to help him, even though we had such a tragic loss, we are able to give someone else the benefit of our son.
IG
Joshua Aversano died in a tragic car crash
"I asked him if it really was worth the risk, he said 'absolutely', even though there was a 50 per cent chance it would fail".
But the complex surgery has not been an easy journey for Mr Norris.
He suffered with severe sunburning and spent three weeks recovering in hospital after surgery.
And before the 36-hour controversial surgery he was warned he had a 50 per cent chance of survival - but now he has a new life.
Eduardo Rodriguez, the doctor who performed the operation at the Maryland Medical Centre, said:" He never really thought about himself in all of this.
"He's always thought about helping the wounded warriors and the other people and providing hope. He's a remarkable man."
IG
The pair embrace during the emotional meeting
The world's first partial face transplant of this kind was performed in France in 2005 on a woman who was mauled by her dog.
Of 27 other transplants that followed, four people have died.
Mr Norris' mother, Sandra has been behind her son every step of the way.
"We looked at Richard and we told him we loved him the way he was and it didn't matter to us, but it was his life.
"That as what he wanted to do and we supported him," she added.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hope for people with amnesia as scientists make breathrough into retrieving lost memories</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/oEYLqa0i8nE/Amnesia-treatment-scientists-retrieve-lost-memories-light-mice</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Hope for people with amnesia as scientists make breathrough into retrieving lost memories
HOPES for patients with severe amnesia have been raised after scientists discovered the use of LIGHT could retrieve lost memories.
22:25, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:30, Thu, May 28, 2015
GETTY
Mice were used in the experiment into the treatment of amnesia
Research carried out on mice has discovered that a lost memory is still stored within the brain cells even though the animal had apparently lost the ability to retrieve it.
In a series of experiments involving a technique called optogenetics, when blue light is used to activate a specific nerve cell in the brain, scientists found that the mice's memory was jogged.
Susumu Tonegawa of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Massachusetts, said: "The majority of researchers have favoured the storage theory, but we have shown in this study that this majority theory is probably wrong.
"Amnesia is a problem of retrieval impairment."
This could be a breakthrough in the widely-discussed treatment of amnesia, as scientists have long debated its nature, with some suggesting the problem lies within the storage of the memory rather than an inability to retrieve a lost memory.
The majority of researchers have favoured the storage theory, but we have shown in this study that this majority theory is probably wrong
Susumu Tonegawa of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Massachusetts
However, amnesia comes in many forms.
In some cases people have trouble forming memories after sustaining a brain injury, while others are unable to recall the events that led up to a brain injury.
The latter is called retrograde amnesia, a condition which occurs after traumatic injury, stress or disease such as Alzheimer's, which is due to the damage of the brain cells involving memory retrieval rather than where the memories are stored.
The study, published in the journal Science, discovered that the storage of the memory is caused by building new connections between nerve cells in the brain.
While the ability to retrieve the memory involves the strengthening of these connections, which can be blocked when the brain is damage by injury or disease.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Restaurant staff surprise as customer leaves £1,300 tip for £60 meal</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/mF7uOrC9H8M/Washington-DC-diner-1300-tip</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Restaurant staff surprise as customer leaves 1,300 tip for 60 meal
RESTAURANT staff got more than they bargained for when they got a 1,300 tip for a customer's 60 meal.
22:18, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:22, Thu, May 28, 2015
GOOGLE MAPS
Staff at this small diner got a 1,300 tip
Waiters and waiteresses got the extra bonus after a customer, believed to be a regular at the eatery, had a three-course meal with a friend.
The pair had eaten fried chicken and gumbo and drank Old Chub Scotch Ale before leaving.
And it was only as workers at the restaurant started to get ready to close that bartender Laura Dally made the amazing discovery.
She picked up the holder of the bill, which contained a credit card slip which showed the man making a tip for $2000 - the equivalent of 1,300.
And on the slip was a note saying "thank you for the gumbo".
Ms Dally told the Washington Post: "I was in utter shock.
"I was completely speechless. I had to do a double take."
CHRISTOFER NARDELLI
The tip given to staff at Blue 44
This is the kind of stuff you see in the restaurant business that happens to some guy in the Midwest or the West Coast.
Christofer Nardelli
Having seen the tip, she went to speak to restaurant owner Christofer Nardelli, who runs the Blue 44 eatery in Washington, US.
Mr Nardelli, who has run the business since 2011, said that he didn't want to name his benefactor.
He said: "This is the kind of stuff you see in the restaurant business that happens to some guy in the Midwest or the West Coast.
"You think, who are these people who give these extraordinarily generous tips that just made a server or bartenders day? And then sure enough, it happened to us."
The patron, who has been in regular contact with the diner about recipe ideas and suitable beers to go with food, left instructions as to how his gift should be split up.
He wanted Ms Dally and Mr Nardelli to both get $500 (326) each and for chef James Turner to get $1,000 (652).
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First picture of tragic toddler pushed in swing by mother for hours while dead</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/WhUsuEWS7lU/Picture-dead-American-toddler-JiAire-Lee-pushed-swing-mother-Romechia-Simms</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
First picture of tragic toddler pushed in swing by mother for hours while dead
THIS is the first picture of a toddler who was found dead in a swing being pushed by his dazed mother.
21:23, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 21:43, Thu, May 28, 2015
FACEBOOK
Ji'Aire was found dead in a swing being pushed by his mother in a park
Romechia Simms, 24, was found by police swinging her dead son Ji'Aire Lee, three, for what investigators described as a "unusual amount of time".
Detectives think she may have been there all night.
She will not be charged in relation to the incident and is being treated at a local hospital.
Her mother Vontasha Simms said her daughter would never do anything to hurt her son as she spoke for the first time since the discovery last Friday in Maryland, United States.
It is understood the family were homeless and living in a hotel. Ms Simms's mother said she was diagnosed with depression about three months ago while struggling to care for her son.
She said: "[Romechia] would never harm my grandson in any type of way. You know, I just believe she had some type of mental illness, some type of mental break that came upon her where she wasn't able to get herself out of that situation.
WUSA
Police believe Ji'Aire and his mother may have been in the park all night
WUSA
Tributes have been left at the park
That's my little man - he loved having fun just like me
James "Donnell" Lee
"I don't want people to look down upon her I want people to use the situation as an opportunity to grow, learn from it. Like I said, help your neighbour, if you suffer from mental issues and you need help, don't be afraid to reach out to somebody."
It is understood Ji'Aire was at the centre of a custody battle between Ms Simms and father James "Donnell" Lee.
He said he felt angry that a court judge didn't look closer at Ms Simm's issues.
He said he was due to see Ji'Aire for the first time in a month on Saturday. But as he tried to call her over the Wednesday and Thursday he became concerned.
He said: "That's my little man - he loved having fun just like me.
He'll always be - that's my little man."
Two GoFundMe pages have been set up to pay for Ji'Aire's funeral, raising more than $10,000 between them.
GOFUNDME
Ji'Aire's dad James Donnell Lee revealed he had recently lost a custody battle
One explains how they want to give their "angel" a "proper homecoming.
The other writes: "He was adored by a huge family including a brother, grandparents, aunts, uncles, and cousins. He loved being outdoors, sports especially basketball, pizza, McDonald's french fries, the color red, and was the center of attention at social gatherings."
Police are still compiling a full timeline of events to work out how Ji'Aire came to his death.
A post-mortem examination has been conducted but findings are incomplete as toxicology tests are still to be returned.
Diane Richardson, of the Charles County Sherrif's Office, said: "This is a top priority for us.
"This is a three-year-old boy that's deceased. We don't know the cause of death. There are no obvious signs of trauma, but he is deceased and our detectives are working around the clock trying to put information together to answer the question as to how this child died."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EXCLUSIVE: Holidaymakers warned they risk returning to UK with deadly CAMEL FLU virus</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/HOySC7wU7yM/MERS-outbreak-Holidaymakers-warned-risk-returning-UK-DEADLY-VIRUS</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
EXCLUSIVE: Holidaymakers warned they risk returning to UK with deadly CAMEL FLU virus
HOLIDAYMAKERS have been warned they risk returning home with a deadly virus after a new outbreak of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) saw British patients tested.
02:47, Fri, May 29, 2015
| UPDATED: 03:03, Fri, May 29, 2015
GETTY
MERS is spread through camels and humans
Authorities in the Middle East are being urged to do more to stop the infection spreading between camels, which then pass it on to humans.
MERS  also dubbed camel flu  has been spreading among those in the region since it was first discovered in 2012.
While the majority of cases have been recorded in Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Ermirates and surrounding nations, cases have also been reported in Britain, France, Holland, Austria and Italy, with a Briton tested as recently as three weeks ago.
Starting off as flu-like symptoms, victims can then suffer pneumonia and kidney failure, and nearly 40 per cent of those contaminated end up dying.
It then spreads to those in close contact, such as relatives and hospital workers.
Jonathan Ball, a professor in virology at the University of Nottingham, said: Anything that increases the amount of travel is going to increase the chance you see sporadic infections.
GETTY
Tighter rules on the testing of camels are needed in the Middle East
People going on holiday could be at risk
Jonathan Ball
People going on holiday could be at risk. Travel isnt a great thing as it helps the virus spread but thankfully its not the most infectious virus.
If you are out to ride a camel in Saudi Arabia in particular, yes, you could be at risk. 
The disease has now spread as far as South Korea with seven elderly people infected within two weeks.
Authorities have isolated more than 70 people to try and stop the spread. But one man, aged 44, has travelled against advice to China for a business trip a day after his father was diagnosed.
All infected are connected to a 68-year-old man who was diagnosed two weeks ago after a trip to Bahrain in Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates.
His 63-year-old wife has now tested positive, as has a 76-year-old man who shared a hospital room with him.
GETTY
Muslim pilgrims arriving at Mecca's Grand Mosque for the Hajj festival poses risk of spreading MERS
In Britain patients have also been tested.
Professor Ball said: Just three weeks ago in Nottingham we had someone who had travelled to the Middle East and had severe respiratory problems. The first thing they agreed was a MERS test.
"Public Health England has measures in place.
"People in primary healthcare situations are aware that someone with severe respiratory problems need to be asked whether they have travelled to the Middle East.
There is also a risk of increased infection in Britain as people make the annual pilgrimage to Mecca in Saudi Arabia to mark the Muslim festival of Hajj in September.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barman found guilty of killing customer after serving him 56 shots in one sitting</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/ngKkgNY3_KA/Barman-56-shots-manslaughter-Clermont-Ferrand-France</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Barman found guilty of killing customer after serving him 56 shots in one sitting
A BAR OWNER has escaped jail after being found guilty of killing a man by serving him 56 shots of spirits in a lethal drinking challenge.
19:03, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 19:06, Thu, May 28, 2015
IG
The Le Starter bar, Clermont-Ferrand
No one forced the client to take on the challenge
Renaud Portejoie
Landlord Giles Crepin served Renaud Prudhomme, 57, as he tried to beat a drinking record of 55 shots in a single.
The 47-year-old told Mr Prudhomme that he only had "12 to go" as neared the end of his drinking session in October 2014.
After successfully downing his shots, he was carried home by his daughter and friends.
However, Mr Prudhomme had a heart attack and died the next day following the tragic incident in Clermont-Ferrand, France.
Mr Crepin's lawyer Renaud Portejoie told the court that a "leader board" in the Starter bar displaying the existing record for shots was "a mistake".
But he added: "No one forced the client to take on the challenge.
"When you are the owner of a bar and an order has been placed, you cannot always verify who is drinking what.
"The customers are responsible for themselves, as are their families and friends."
Barman Mr Crepin was convicted of manslaughter and handed a four-month suspended sentence and banned from tending bar for a year by the court in Clermont-Ferrand yesterday. 
Mr Portejoie said his client intended to appeal the sentence, adding: "It's a decision guided by emotion and the unconscious desire to set an example.
"The victim already had existing respiratory and alcohol abuse problems.
"Bar keepers can't ask every customer who buys alcohol to present their medical certificates."
Mr Prudhomme's daughter's lawyer said she was "relieved" by the ruling.
The manslaughter hearing comes as a new law set to come into force in France will make it illegal to encourage minors to "drink until they become drunk".
Earlier this year, a French health watchdog spokesman blamed Britain for their recent steep rise in binge-drinking.
Francis Bourdillon, head of the National Institute of Prevention and Health Education, said: "This is an Anglo-Saxon phenomenon that's starting to creep into the generation of the 15-24-year-olds."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Barbaric Islamic State militants execute 20 in front of crowd in Roman amphitheatre</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/NQueLqaBS5M/Islamic-State-execute-20-in-front-of-crowd-in-Roman-amphitheatre</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Barbaric Islamic State militants execute 20 in front of crowd in Roman amphitheatre
BLOODTHIRSTY Islamic State (ISIS) terrorists carried out 20 executions in a Roman amphitheatre in the ancient city of Palmyra in Syria.
17:02, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 17:52, Thu, May 28, 2015
GETTY
The theatre at Palmyra where the executions were carried out
The shootings took place in front of crowds of people and there are fears the slaughter is a precursor to the destruction of the prized ruins, some of the most culturally significant in the world.
ISIS had already killed around 300 of those in the city since it took over last week, while many more citizens fled for their lives.
The latest executions are believed to be that of government forces and allied militiamen.
Rami Abdel Rahman, head of the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said: "ISIS executed 20 men by firing on them in front of a crowd gathered in Palmyra's Roman theatre, after accusing them of fighting for the Syrian regime.
"ISIS gathered a lot of people there on purpose, to show their force on the ground."
ISIS gathered a lot of people there on purpose, to show their force on the ground
Rami Abdel Rahman
Syria's antiquities director Maamoun Abdulkarim said he was "shocked to learn that a 2,000-year treasure had been used to kill people" and added he believed the killings were a harbinger of the destruction of Palmyra, a UNESCO heritage site.
But he denied any vandalism had already taken place despite reports emanating from the territory.
His denial was backed up by hotographs released by Islamic State on Twitter appearing to show ancient ruins unharmed.
However, these images, which include the amphitheatre, are yet to be independently verified.
The 2,000-year-old structure appeared to have an Islamic State flag flying on top of it. There were also pictures of columns and arches.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Med migrants: UK rejects quota but how many will come from France?</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/pdUsADRCugs/Med-migrants-UK-rejects-quota-but-how-many-will-come-from-France</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Med migrants: UK rejects quota but how many will come from France?
THE European Union (EU) wants France to take in thousands of asylum seekers crossing the Mediterranean from Africa - raising questions over how many will then come to Britain.
16:16, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 16:24, Thu, May 28, 2015
AP
Immigrants wait outside the police station to receive temporary traveling papers at kos yesterday
The European Commission (EC) revealed yesterday how many migrants each country would have to take on out of a total of 40,000 if proposals for a quota system to relieve pressure on Greece and Italy were implemented.
The plans would apply to Syrian and Eritrean nationals landing in Greece and Italy after perilous journeys across the Mediterranean.
France was told it would have to take 6,752 (16.88 per cent) of the 40,000 migrants and has retracted its original support for the quota system, while Germany will have to take the most at 8,764 (21.91 per cent).
The UK Government has said it will not take part in a system which forces member states to take on migrants from other countries, but this does not stop migrants settling in neighbouring countries from potentially coming to seek asylum in the UK afterwards.
Spain, Hungary, Slovakia and Estonia have joined in voicing their opposition to the final decision which will be taken by EU governments after a vote by MEPs.
Ireland and the UK can decide whether to opt in while Denmark has the right to opt out.
Justine Greening, the UK's International Development Secretary rejected the EC's initial call for mandatory quotas, saying it would be a "pull for migrants".
I'm urging European leaders to address this issue in a more comprehensive way and a collective way
Ban Ki-moon
Prime Minister David Cameron also voiced his concerns, and said: "My fear is, if we have a repatriation programme to distribute migrants across the European Union, all it will do is act as a new draw for the criminal gangs and for people to get on those unsafe boats in the first place and head off into the Mediterranean.
"What we need to do is focus on the two things that will make the biggest difference: one is trying to get a competent government in Libya that has authority, that we can deal with.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 17:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malaysia Airlines MH370: 'Inexperienced team and wrong equipment will EASILY MISS plane'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/c0qKs2uw6ik/Malaysia-Airlines-MH370-flight-crash-inexperienced-wrong-equipment-miss-plane</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
Malaysia Airlines MH370: 'Inexperienced team and wrong equipment will EASILY MISS plane'
MISSING Malaysia Airlines Flight MH370 has not been found because search teams are "inexperienced" and equipment is "inappropriate", experts have warned.
15:41, Thu, May 28, 2015
| UPDATED: 15:56, Thu, May 28, 2015
GETTY
Calls are now being made for a rethink into the way the search mission is conducted
The Australian-led search is already the most expensive in aviation history with no trace of the Boeing 777 or any of its 239 passengers and crew yet to be found.
Calls are now being made for a rethink into the way the mission is conducted.
Deep-water search experts have said the current mission to find Flight MH370 could easily miss the aircraft.
This is because Dutch company Fugro NV, the firm at the forefront of the official operation, is using "inappropriate" technology for some terrain and "inexperienced" personnel for the highly specialised task of hunting man-made objects.
On March 8 last year, Flight MH370 - from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing - vanished off radar at 2.20am after deviating from its course over the South China Sea just an hour after take-off.
Former French naval officer Paul-Henry Nargeolet was hired by official investigators to co-ordinate the search and recovery of Air France flight AF447 in 2009, which crashed into the Atlantic Ocean killing all 228 passengers and crew.
Expressing his fears over the search for Flight MH370, bankrolled by Australia, China and Malaysia, he said: "Fugro is a big company but they don't have any experience in this kind of search and it's really a very specialised job.
Fugro is a big company but they don't have any experience in this kind of search and it's really a very specialised job
Former French naval officer Paul-Henry Nargeolet
"This is a big job.I'm not an Australian taxpayer, but if I was, I would be very mad to see money being spent like that."
Fugro was contracted by the Australian government to operate ships pulling sonar across the vast search zone, currently taking place thousands of miles off the coast of Perth in the Southern Indian Ocean.
It rejected claims it is using the wrong equipment, claiming its gear is rigorously tested.
But this has not stopped other experts echoing Mr Nargeolet's concerns.
Three of the bidders rejected for the FlightMH370 search contract - U.S. firm Williamson &amp; Associates, France's ixBlue SAS and Mauritius-based Deep Ocean Search Ltd - have taken the unusual step of detailing their concerns directly to Australian officials.
They are worried that unless the search ships pass directly over the wreckage, the sonar scanning either side of the vessels will not pick it up.
Experts have also questioned the lack of data released by the Australian Transport Safety Bureau (ATSB) regarding the activities of the Fugro ships.
Several other experts have been critical of the close knit nature of the deep-sea search industry, which has just a few companies capable of conducting the searches.
Mike Williamson, founder and president of Williamson &amp; Associates, said: "I have serious concerns that the MH370 search operation may not be able to convincingly demonstrate that 100 per cent seafloor coverage is being achieved."
His vice-president, Rob McCullum, said it makes no sense to use fine scale tools to cover a massive area, adding: "It is like mowing an entire wheat field with a household mower".
Fugro has denied its equipment is inappropriate, with deputy managing director Paul Kennedy insisting the sonar is running within its capabilities and that the system identified five "debris-like" objects in 700m deep water at a test range off the West Australian coast.
He said: "The test range gives us full confidence the sonars will see the debris field when we cross it."
He added that earlier this month Fugro had found a previously uncharted shipwreck, which is evidence the company is capable of finding the plane.
Fugro has been involved in 17 search and recovery efforts for aircraft or ships over 15 years.
However, some of the other bidders search for four to five aircraft every year.
Yesterday, Australian authorities heightened fears Flight MH370 may never be found after revealing one of the three search vessels, the Go Phoenix - the world's best deep sea search equipment - and its crew would pull out within weeks.
No reason was given for withdrawing the vessel from the quest.
Australian officials have routinely released detailed data from Go Phoenix, but never for the two ships provided by Fugro.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
