<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BREAKING: Passenger plane gets mid-air BOMB THREAT – day after mass chemical terror scare</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/vQZ73YYqAh0/Eva-Air-Los-Angeles-airport-US-bomb-threat-chemical-scare-Memorial-Day-terrorism</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
BREAKING: Passenger plane gets mid-air BOMB THREAT  day after mass chemical terror scare
A PASSENGER plane is being searched by authorities after it received a bomb threat  just a day after six flights were caught up in a mass terror scare.
00:04, Wed, May 27, 2015
| UPDATED: 00:50, Wed, May 27, 2015
TWITTER  GETTY FILE PICTURE
The FBI investigated the apparent threat to the Eva Air passenger plane
Police surrounded the Eva Air flight at Los Angeles Airport after it landed at 3.30pm local time.
It is thought that an anonymous bomb threat was phoned in while the plane was on-route from Taipei in Taiwan.
The aircraft was moved to an isolated location to be searched when it landed.
An FBI spokesman told Express.co.uk: "Bureau and airport officials are investigating a telephonic threat to an aircraft incoming to LAX.
"All threats, regardless of known credibility, are taken seriously."
The incident comes just one day after six flights across the US faced chemical weapons threats  including planes flying in from London and Birmingham.
The problems started whenUS military jets escorted an Air France flight into New York City after someone claimed a chemical weapon was aboard the aircraft.
"Out of an abundance of caution, Air France flight number 22 was escorted to John F. Kennedy airport by US Air Force fighter jets following a phone threat," the FBI said in a statement.
"There were no incidents or hazards reported on board the flight by either the passengers or its crew. The plane has been cleared."
Authorities said the threats did not appear to be credible. They described searches done on the jets as a precaution.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fury at French and German plot for EU tax rate than threatens British jobs</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/6uT3OGwuR9Q/Fury-French-German-plot-EU-tax-rate-threatens-British-jobs</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Labour wants to manipulate voting rules to win on EU
Their push for closer ties is at odds with Mr Camerons hopes of repatriating powers back from Brussels to Westminster.
He is almost certain to face resistance to his demands for changes to EU treaties when he holds separate talks with the two leaders in Paris and Berlin later this week.
A leaked document, disclosed by the French newspaper Le Monde, showed that President Hollande and Chancellor Merkel believe EU reforms can be developed in the framework of the current treaties.
The two leaders are set to put their plan to a summit of European leaders in Brussels on June 25, when the Prime Minister is also expected to reveal his shopping list for a new EU deal for Britain.
He plans to put that deal to voters in an in-out EU referendum by the end of 2017.
The blueprint for a harmonised EU corporation tax was revealed by the German financial magazine Handelsblatt Global yesterday, quoting a source close to the European Commission.
And an official in the German finance ministry said: The discussion of tax rates has begun.
GETTY
Cameron is on a whirlwind tour around Europe to drum up support for his reform plans
When Germany and France say the EU imperative for ever closer union must stand, they mean it  closer political union, closer economic union and closer fiscal union
Ukip deputy leader Paul Nuttall
French and German finance officials believe a harmonised corporation tax could make multinational giants such as Amazon and Starbucks less able to move bases around so they benefit from the lowest rates.
Britains corporation tax is currently 20 per cent, one of the lowest in Europe. It is significantly lower than the 33.33 per cent rate in France and 29.65 per cent in Germany, raising fears the UK rate will have to rise.
Alan Murad, of the cross-party Eurosceptic campaign Get Britain Out, said: Brussels imposing a common corporation tax will be the most brazen power grab we have witnessed.
This is using the EU to undercut competitive countries like Britain. The outcome will be to reduce our competitiveness in global trade. Jobs will be lost and wages reduced.
It is a policy based on resentment of Britains economic performance.
It sets a terrifying precedent when decisions about our tax rates are made by faceless bureaucrats in Brussels instead of elected officials in Westminster. This demonstrates why we should get Britain out.
The Prime Ministers EU charm offensive began on Monday evening with a dinner at Chequers with European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker.
Mr Camerons official spokesman said: The British Government has a long-standing view on tax harmonisation, which is not to support it.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PICTURED: The amazing moment a SEAGULL flies with the Red Arrows</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/03QXGjiHk88/seagull-Red-Arrows-planes-Jade-Coxon-photographer-student</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PICTURED: The amazing moment a SEAGULL flies with the Red Arrows
THIS is the amazing moment a seagull flew with the world-famous Red Arrows.
00:01, Wed, May 27, 2015
| UPDATED: 00:17, Wed, May 27, 2015
SWNS
An intrepid seagull holds the Red Arrows' formation in place
The stunning snap  captured by a photography student  has already been viewed one million times online.
It shows eight of the Red Arrows in tight formation trailing their famous vapour.
But where the ninth plane should be, there is an intrepidseagullholding the formation in place  and he even has his own vapour trail.
Jade Coxon, 18, said she could not believe her luck snapping the bird at the Llandudno Air Show.
SWNS
Photography student Jade Coxon took the incredible snap
People have seen it from across the world, people have seen it in Australia and New Zealand
Jade Coxon
She said: "It was mainly luck but I was really happy with it.
"I saw theseagullfly in the way of the picture before I took it.
"It is completely covering the plane so you can't see it and the airtrail is behind theseagull."
Coxon described the past few days  in which the photo has gone viral  as "really busy".
She said: "People have seen it from across the world, people have seen it in Australia and New Zealand.
"It has given me a real boost to keep putting content up."
Jade added that her family are proud of her  including her dad, who is a professional photographer.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kelly and Sharon Osbourne join forces with Cancer Research UK for fun Race For Life shoot</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/ihdP9tGgZbw/Kelly-Sharon-Osbourne-join-forces-fight-against-cancer-Race-For-Life</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SHOWBIZ
Kelly and Sharon Osbourne join forces with Cancer Research UK for fun Race For Life shoot
SHE'S a cancer survivor herself and now Sharon Osbourne is keen to fight against the disease, teaming up with daughter Kelly for this year's Race For Life.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Wed, May 27, 2015
Cancer Research UK
Sharon and Kelly promote Cancer Research's Race For Life
It's a cause that means a heck of a lot to both Sharon and Kelly and the duo have clearly put their everything into helping Cancer Research promote this year's Race For Life.
Sharon survived colon cancer in 2002 and then underwent a double mastectomy in 2012 after being diagnosed with the BRCA1 gene, which Kelly recently announced she also had.
So, to help raise awareness of the disease, the duo have now come together to ask women across the UK to sign up to Cancer Research UKs Race for Life.
With the pair both being known for their fun personalities, it comes as no real shock that they added their own twist to the accompanying photoshoot.
Cancer Research UK
Mother and daughter have some fun during charity photoshoot
Cancer Research UK
Kelly and Sharon add some colour to the black and white shot
The images see both Kelly and Sharon playing around in a photo booth, brandishing pink army helmets, war paint and even donning warrior headdresses.
The famous twosome are encouraging women of all ages, shapes and sizes, to get together and join the Race for Life Pink Army and raise vital funds to help beat cancer sooner.
Sharon said of the fantastic cause: Im honoured to be supporting Cancer Research UKs Race for Life this year.
"As a cancer survivor myself, I know it takes all your strength and the support of your family and friends to overcome this disease."
The former X Factor judge continued: Im asking every woman - mother, daughter, grandmother, sister and auntie in the UK to step forward and unite to defy cancer. Lets show cancer that hell hath no fury like a woman in pink.
Cancer Research UK
Sharon survived colon cancer back in 2002
Cancer Research UK
Kelly looks like she means business in Race For Life shot
Cancer Research UK
Famous family members join fight against cancer
Her daughter Kelly added: After watching my mum go through colon cancer and the recent news that Im carrying the BRCA1 gene, just like my mum, I wanted to show my support for Cancer Research UKs Race for Life.
"By signing up to your local Race for Life event, every pound you raise will help bring forward the day when all cancers are cured.
"So whether you walk, jog or charge, lets uniteso we can one day end the suffering cancer causes millions of people around the world," she finished up by saying.
Cancer Research UK is urging all women to stand with Sharon and Kelly by signing up to take part in Race for Life, in partnership with Tesco. All funds raised will go towards beating over 200 different types of cancer.
For more information click here .
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>End of the Human Rights Act? Tories 'to SCRAP controversial legislation in Queen's Speech'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/DO7y9xLY_9Y/Human-Rights-Act-Conservatives-Queens-Speech-Tories-David-Cameron</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>End of the Human Rights Act? Tories 'to SCRAP controversial legislation in Queen's Speech'
THE Conservatives are expected to outline plans to scrap the Human Rights Act in tomorrow's Queen's Speech.
00:05, Wed, May 27, 2015
| UPDATED: 00:17, Wed, May 27, 2015
GETTY
David Cameron has pledged to scrap the Human Rights Act
David Cameron's majority government will look to replace the controversial legislation with a British Bill of Rights.
The proposals "will restore common sense to the application of human rights in the UK", according to the party's manifesto.
The manifesto also insisted that the Bill will remain faithful to the basic principles in the original convention.
The Human Rights Act, introduced in 1998, has faced widespread criticism for giving European judges the power to overrule British laws.
Attempts to deport the Muslim cleric Abu Qatada were repeatedly thwarted by human rights laws before he returned to Jordan in 2013.
Last month a judge ruled an alcoholic Libyan criminal with 78 different convictions cannot be deported because alcohol is banned in his homeland.
The European Court of Human Rights has also ruled against the UK's ban on voting for prisoners.
However, Justice Secretary Michael Gove is prepared for substantial resistance  and not only from Labour and the Liberal Democrats.
The Council of Europe has said it is "inconceivable" that the UK, as a founding member, could leave and that the proposals are "not consistent" with the convention.
GETTY
Michael Gove will face resistance from the Council of Europe
I have great reservations
Lord Judge
Conservative figures such as former attorney general Dominic Grieve and MP David Davis have also attacked the plans.
But the proposals are backed by Lord Judge, a former lord chief justice.
Earlier this week he admitted to having "great reservations" about meddling in British affairs by European judges.
And he claimed the Government's move to introduce a British Bill of Rights should not be "fudged".
His remarks were seen as a significant intervention in the Westminster row about the future of human rights laws.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The house where people go to die: Inside the Dignitas clinic of assisted suicide</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/9DRQU-DJ_kY/house-people-go-to-die-Dignitas-clinic-assisted-suicide</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
The house where people go to die: Inside the Dignitas clinic of assisted suicide
FATHER-of-three Jeffrey Spectors death at Dignitas may have prompted fresh debate on assisted suicide but shockingly almost 300 Britons have ended their lives at the Zurich clinic
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Wed, May 27, 2015
REX
Dignitas founder Ludwig Minnelli outside of the clinic
Not many people would choose to live next door to a Dignitas clinic. As a purveyor of assisted suicide services it attracts a never-ending procession of people who are suicidally depressed, terminally ill or in the grip of a degenerative neurological disease. Once they have achieved the aim of ending their lives police officers and undertakers get involved.
The regular to-ing and fro-ing of police cars, ambulances and hearses led to so many complaints from neighbours in the Swiss organisations early days that it had to give up a number of apartments in which it was based. One of these early bases was so bleak and utilitarian that the brother of a female client described it as a most horrible factory, next to the biggest brothel in Zurich.
Dignitas was forced at one point to supervise suicides in hotel rooms. A few German clients even decided they would prefer to die in their own cars in a motorway lay-by.
It wasnt until 2009, 11 years after it was established, that it found a permanent base for its operations by buying an 880,000 two-storey house in the Zurich suburb of Pfaffikon. While much is made of the way guests enter the property via a wooden decked walkway over a goldfish pond there are fewer references to the grimness of the neighbourhood.
The Dignitas house  a modern building with metal walls painted blue  stands between two factories on an industrial estate and overlooks a football pitch.
The interior, with its tiled floor, cheap furniture and bland paintings of flowers, has all the charm of a badly-decorated three-star hotel.
And yet more and more desperate Britons are making the journey to this clinic every year, the latest being Jeffrey Spector, the 54-year-old advertising executive who killed himself last Friday rather than face being paralysed from the neck down by an inoperable tumour on his spine. B etween 1998 and 2014, 273 UK citizens killed themselves with the help of Dignitas. This made them the second biggest national grouping behind the Germans on 920.
This is because while assisting a person to commit suicide is a criminal offence in this country punishable by up to 14 years in jail, in Switzerland it is legal as long as the individual providing the assistance has no selfish motives such as financial gain, the person concerned is of sound mind and he or she administers the fatal dose of drug.
Given the potential pitfalls of getting involved in such an enterprise perhaps it is no surprise that the founder of Dignitas is a lawyer rather than a doctor. And Ludwig Minelli, 82, does everything by the book.
The first step for anyone intending to avail themselves of Dignitass services is to become a member. This involves payment of a 162 joining fee plus a minimum annual fee of 65.
What happens next is described by one journalist who carried out a rare interview with Minelli in 2009: When you are ready to die you need to send in copies of your medical records, a letter explaining why things have become intolerable and 1,860.
Once they arrive in Zurich the individual must pay 620 for two appointments with the doctor and a further 1,860 to pay for two Dignitas staff members to organise and witness the death
These files are dispatched to one of Dignitass affiliated doctors, who considers on the basis of the medical history whether or not he would be ready to write a prescription for the fatal dose. If he agrees in principle, then a green light is given to the member and they can contact staff at the Dignitas HQ, who will schedule a date and offer advice on hotels.
Once they arrive in Zurich the individual must pay 620 for two appointments with the doctor and a further 1,860 to pay for two Dignitas staff members to organise and witness the death.
As Dignitas makes clear: In every case, for legal reasons, the patient must be able to undertake the last act him or herself. If this is not possible Dignitas is unfortunately unable to help.
All deaths are videoed by the Dignitas companions  trained carers  who supervise each death and stay behind to deal with the police and undertakers in the hours that follow. One of the reasons that the number of Germans who have killed themselves with the help of Dignitas is so much higher than the number of Britons may be because Mellini opened a branch offering advice in Hanover in 2005.
While the UK has long resisted attempts to change the law on assisted suicide a number of high-profile supporters of change have flocked to the cause in recent years, including novelist Ian McEwan, former Archbishop of Canterbury Lord Carey and actor Hugh Grant.
Former Lord Chancellor Lord Falconers Assisted Dying Bill is now at the committee stage in the House of Lords, which means that the possibility of a Dignitas clinic opening up in Britain has never been more real.
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nicola Sturgeon’s ‘double lock’ demand to keep Britain in the EU</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/AuokbkvjJgI/Nicola-Sturgeon-s-double-lock-demand-keep-Britain-EU</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UK
Nicola Sturgeons double lock demand to keep Britain in the EU
NICOLA Sturgeon yesterday stepped up demands for Scotland to be given a veto over the UKs exit from the European Union.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Wed, May 27, 2015
PA
Scotland Nicola Sturgeon at Tyncastle Stadium for first economic speech since election
The First Minister vowed to fight for a double lock, whereby a majority in each of the four home nations would be needed before Britain left the international club.
Details of the proposed 2017 in-out referendum will be unveiled in todays Queens speech.
But Prime Minister David Cameron has already rejected the SNPs demand, saying Britain will vote as one nation.
Ms Sturgeon also appeared to slap down her predecessor Alex Salmond, who has said he could work alongside Chancellor George Osborne to keep Britain in Europe.
She told an audience of business leaders in Edinburgh that she had no plans to share a platform with senior Tories.
The SNP leader also used her first major economic speech since the general election to condemn the speed and scale of UK Government public spending cuts.
But the First Minister admitted she faces a significant challenge to wring concessions out of a majority Tory administration.
Speaking at Heart of Midlothian FCs Tynecastle stadium, Ms Sturgeon said: The result of the general election provides an opportunity and a challenge for the Scottish Government. There is clearly an opportunity to ensure that Scotlands priorities are better understood.
But there is also a significant challenge in working with a majority Government at Westminster many of whose policies we disagree with.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scottish building trade threatened by skills shortage</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/kLC6ITLLdpc/Scottish-building-trade-threatened-skills-shortage</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Britain's house building drive 'undermined' by Government cuts to council planning budgets
According to him there are a number of factors affecting the situation, including an ageing workforce and the ongoing impact from the recent financial meltdown.
Mr Mickel said: There is certainly a shortage of skills in trade and we are seeing that on sites on a daily basis.
More recently, it has been a struggle to get the level of person or the actual criteria that you want filled.
We are fortunate that we have a lot of our trades in-house so can work sites and move people around.
We do not use sub-contractors much more than we used to but it is becoming more of a necessity.
He continued: The profile of the trades seem to have been lost in the last seven years. When I was growing up we would have conversations about brickies and plumbers.
Now, when you read the papers it is the next generation of people inventing a game for a console or a software billionaire or something like that. There is not the good stories about the profession.
However, in England, it is a different story, with the chief executive of Barratt, Britains largest housebuilder, confident about the future.
Mark Clare said the election result created a positive political and economic environment for the industry.
But he warned about the impact of the recession, mirroring Mr Mickel by saying: A massive constraint on growth in the next five years will be our ageing workforce and that training new site workers took a back seat during the downturn.
Most Read Stories in UK
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How our lack of pensions knowledge could cost us thousands of pounds</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/iyRPPGLDCnY/lack-pensions-knowledge-cost-us-thousands-pounds</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UK
How our lack of pensions knowledge could cost us thousands of pounds
WORKERS on the verge of retirement have a lack of understanding of the state pension system despite an increasing number of pensioners relying on it.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Wed, May 27, 2015
GETTY
Half of those that recieve state pension rely on it for more than half their retirement income
And these people are in danger of making decisions which could cost them thousands of pounds over the course of their retirement, experts will warn today.
Half of those who receive the state pension now rely on it for more than half of their income.
A survey found six in 10 did not know that delaying taking their pension could increase it by as much as 10 per cent.
Forty-three per cent were unaware that they could pay voluntary national
insurance contributions to make up for any years missed.
Many people who plan to retire abroad did not realise that the country they move to could affect how much money they get.
For example, three-quarters of those aged 40 to 70 did not realise their pension could be frozen if they retire outside of Europe.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>David Cameron: We have a mandate from British people to deliver plans in Queen's Speech</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/NQoh7Dvm3Lo/David-Cameron-have-mandate-British-people-deliver-plans-Queen-s-Speech</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>POLITICS
David Cameron: We have a mandate from British people to deliver plans in Queen's Speech
DAVID Cameron promised not to be deflected from his Government's "one nation" programme due to be announced in the Queen's Speech today.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Wed, May 27, 2015
REUTERS
Cameron has vowed to avoid the policy U-turns that plagued the Coalition
Signalling his desire to avoid the policy U-turns that bedevilled the Coalition, the Prime Minister insisted his Tory-only administration had a "mandate" to deliver his plans in full.
He said: "We have a mandate from the British people, a clear manifesto and the instruction to deliver.
"And we will not waste a single moment in getting on with the task."
His pledge came as it emerged that Tory MPs are being ordered to minimise their travel plans over the coming weeks to ensure key legislation can be passed through the Commons.
Party whips are understood to be concerned that a series of tight Commons votes are expected given Mr Cameron's narrow 12-seat majority.
The Prime Minister is understood to be determined to avoid a repeat of the mistakes of the early years of his last government including embarrassing U-turn on taxes on hot takeaway food and caravans, minimum pricing on alcohol, the sale of forests and a string of other issues.
At the annual State Opening of Parliament today, the Queen will formally announce the Government's proposed new laws for the next Parliamentary year.
The legislation is expected to include a Europe Referendum Bill, a legal guarantee of a rise in the income tax threshold to 12,500 by 2020, the scrapping of the Human Rights Act to curb meddling by European judges and a Housing Bill to widen home ownership.
In a statement last night, Mr Cameron said: "Behind this Queens Speech is a clear vision for what our country can be; a country of security and opportunity for everyone, at every stage of life.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
