<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Families face holiday CHAOS: Greece euro crisis could wreck travel plans this week</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/5jvh4Y4yzgw/Tourists-warned-Greece-euro-exit</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Families face holiday CHAOS: Greece euro crisis could wreck travel plans this week
Families face holiday CHAOS: Greece euro crisis could wreck travel plans this week
A MASSIVE airlift will be staged to rescue tens of thousands of British holidaymakers if Greece goes bust and the country is thrown into economic meltdown.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 21:02, Thu, Jun 25, 2015
NC
Greece are on the verge of dropping out of the Euro
Whitehall officials and tour operators are ready to bring home up to 110,000 tourists if the cash-strapped country crashes out of the euro.
It would be the largest peacetime evacuation of Britons.
Already Ministers and travel agents are warning travellers to the country to carry cash and credit cards to cover any situation that emerges.
Details emerged as last-ditch talks on Greeces huge debt continue today, following fears that local banks will run out of money forcing hotels and airports to close.
A run on the banks could mean no money in cash machines, a shortage of food and problems with medical supplies and treatment, possibly leading to riots.
Yesterday the Foreign Office admitted officials had been in talks with the Association of British Travel Agents to formulate evacuation plans.
A spokesman said: We hope for the best but contingency plans are in place. These plans cover a wide range of scenarios. We update our travel advice and are liaising with Abta.
AP
Greece's PM Alexis Tsipras is welcomed with a friendly tap by European boss Jean-Claude Juncker
AP
People read newspapers' headlines in central Athens
Holidaymakers heading out to Greece are advised to take some cash in euros as well as other payment methods so that they are covered for all situations
Abta
Around two million Britons fly to Greece every year and there are currently around 110,000 staying on the mainland or its islands.
Tour operators say that customers are already arming themselves with large amounts of cash.
The Foreign Office advises visitors to take enough money to cover emergencies and any unexpected delays and avoid relying on bank cards or cash machines.
Last night Abta urged travellers to carry cash and take out insurance to cover costs incurred by flight cancellations.
Any changes would be highly unlikely to happen overnight, any switch to a new currency would take time and euros would likely be accepted in the interim, it said.
Holidaymakers heading out to Greece are advised to take some cash in euros as well as other payment methods so that they are covered for all situations.
Abta do not anticipate tour operators having to move customers to different destinations.
INTIME/ATHENA
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras sees his country in crisis
INTIME/ATHENA
High-powered talks: Yanis Varoufakis in Athens yesterday
At present we have no indication that holidaymakers will be disrupted however, as with all destination matters, we will continue to monitor the situation. This is an unusual situation but the industry is experienced in handling unusual situations, it added.
Thomson and First Choice have said they expect no impact on holidaymakers if Greece leaves the euro.
Thomas Cook said it expected the likely devaluation of the Greek currency could make the country an even more attractive destination.
Greeces economic woes have already affected island airports.
Night flights in and out of Lesbos were stopped after its airport ran out of money to maintain electronic landing systems.
At least three other popular tourist destinations  Kos, Skiathos and Santorini  face similar problems.
The islands vital tourism industry has also been hit by asylum seekers arriving by boat from Turkey.
Customers searching for flights to Greece plummeted last week, down 53 per cent on the same week last year.
Sunvil has slashed up to 50 per cent off hundreds of holidays, and Thomson has cut prices by up to 30 per cent.
AP
A man collects recyclable items in Athens
Today Greeces Left-wing government is holding eleventh-hour bail out talks with its creditors over its expected 1.1billion debt default on June 30.
Finance minister Yanis Varoufakis said the EU faced a stark choice on whether to strike a deal to save Greece from bankruptcy.
On Friday George Osborne said Britain must now be prepared for the worst.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calais migrant crisis: Illegal camp of 4,000 to become PERMANENT site with €500k makeover</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/YPKufhVZP9U/Calais-migrant-crisis-Illegal-camp-The-Jungle-2-OFFICIAL</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Calais migrant crisis: Illegal camp of 4,000 to become PERMANENT site with 500k makeover
Calais migrant crisis: Illegal camp of 4,000 to become PERMANENT site with 500k makeover
THE French government will install water and electricity into an illegal migrant shanty town near Calais, raising fears the already 4,000-strong population will quickly double in size.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 21:46, Thu, Jun 25, 2015
GETTY
Migrants camp in squalid conditions on a dusty site dubbed The Jungle 2 in Calais
About 360,000 (500,000) is being pumped into the site for men, branded The Jungle2, after a previous makeshift camp was destroyed.
Plans to add running water, street lighting, public toilets and pre-fabricated shelters, will make the site "official".
They are part of plans to make 10,500 more lodgings for asylum seekers across France.
The work is in response to pressure from aid groups - who will now run the camps - who described the site as a humanitarian crisis.
But critics believe the comfortable conditions will act as a magnet for illegal immigrants who will do anything to reach British soil.
PA
A migrant hangs washing in the dirty surroundings
PA
Migrants queue for food handouts at the Jungle 2 migrant camp in Calais
We have to take steps to improve their conditions
Sylvia Pinel
France's housing minister, Sylvia Pinel, said: "There are nearly 3,000 people living in an unacceptable and unhealthy way on this wasteland... We have to take steps to improve their conditions."
Calais has turned to violent chaos in recent weeks, with horror scenes showing migrants throwing rocks at lorries, tearing into cargo, and dragging debris into the roads to slow traffic.
Tensions are high between locals and migrants, as well as between the different nationalities of migrants.
A group of migrants were beaten with iron bars over the weekend. They are investigating whether the attack was by people traffickers seeking revenge.
PA
A group of migrants collect donated food
There are now thought to be at least 3,000 migrants living in the crime-ridden Calais ghetto dubbed the Jungle 2 or New Jungle.
Within the camps are vast numbers of children, who are being exposed to the elements, with only flimsy tents for shelter.
But as the refugee crisis across Europe spirals out of control experts say that could double in size within weeks.
Most of those living in the camps are from Syria, Eritrea, Ethiopia and Afghanistan, having crossed the Mediterranean from Libya to Italy.
Steve Reigate
The detritis left after the first jungle camp was cleared
The Jungle 2 is a 40 acre stretch of industrial wasteland three miles north of the port town of Calais
It popped up after migrants were moved from the first "Jungle" five years ago.
Before that the Red Cross ran an authorised site called Sangatte, which closed in 2002.
A shelter for migrant women and children opened earlier this year.
Steve Reigate
The devastation left after the first Jungle Camp was cleared
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tragedy as budding baseball star dies from 'Black Death'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/OgUjtS5oFqA/Taylor-Gaes-dead-Black-Death-plague-baseball-star</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tragedy as budding baseball star dies from 'Black Death'
Tragedy as budding baseball star dies from 'Black Death'
A BUDDING baseball star has died after contracting a rare form of the dreaded plague that killed millions of people in Medieval times.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 17:07, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
FACEBOOK
Taylor Gaes was a budding baseball player
Taylor Gaes, a high school quarterback, died a day after his 16th birthday in northern Colorado, US.
His friends and family initially suspected that the young sports star had caught the flu after he picked up a fever, aching muscles and swollen glands.
But two weeks after his death on June 8, local health authorities ruled that he died from the plague after contracting the bacteria from a flea bite.
The disease, often referred to as 'The Black Death' , killed as many as 50million people in the 14th century but is thought to be relatively easy to treat today.
Of the three different types of plague - bubonic, septicaemia and pneumonic - officials say Mr Geas contracted the septicemic plague, according to the Center for Disease Control and Prevention.
We should all be thankful we had a chance to know such a generous soul. He was the most handsome boy I'd ever seen in my life
Taylor's girlfriend Chloe Brown
It is suspected that the bacteria came from a flea bite from a rodent which wandered into his family's rural property.
His death marks the third person and the first fatality from the bacteria in 30 years in Colorado.
A total of seven cases are registered in the US each year.
However, those close to Mr Gaes have now been told to seek medical attention immediately to ensure they have not contracted the disease.
The chances of passing the disease on are slim, but those who attended the scattering of his ashes have been told to be vigilant.
Larimer County Health Department spokeswoman Katie O'Donnell said: "It's a pretty far reach, but it's possible.
"There is a small chance that others might have been bitten by infected fleas, so anyone who was on the family's land in the last seven days should seek medical attention immediately if a fever occurs."
The family and friends of Mr Gaes have spoken of their shock over his death.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 18:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN accuses Israel and Hamas of 'unprecedented' war crimes during recent Gaza conflict</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/nwFKgEWPvlk/UN-Israel-Hamas-unprecedented-war-crimes-Gaza-conflict</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>High Court judges halt conference questioning right of Israel's existence
While Foreign Ministry Spokesman Emmanuel Nachshon added: "This report was commissioned by a notoriously biased institution, given an obviously biased mandate.
"The UN Human Rights Council has a singular obsession with Israel, passing more country specific resolutions against Israel than against Syria, Iran and North Korea combined. The commission of inquiry's mandate presumed Israel guilty from the start."
The report revealed a "huge increase" in firepower used in the Gaza strip, with more than 6,000 airstrikes by Israel and approximately 50,000 tank and artillery shells fired - in just 51 days.
Palestinian armed groups, including Hamas, fired 4,881 rockets and 1,753 mortars towards Israel's 'Iron Dome' missile defence system , killing six civilians and injuring at least 1,600.
The commission of inquiry's mandate presumed Israel guilty from the start
Foreign Ministry Spokesman Emmanuel Nachshon
The 27 Palestinians killed and 3,020 injured in the West Bank between June and August 2014 has raised serious concerns from the commission as they said it "appears to be the increasing use of live ammunition for crowd control by the Israeli Security Forces, which raises the likelihood of death or serious injury".
More than 280 interviews were conducted and 500 written submissions were received by the commission which pointed out hundreds of Palestinian civilians were killed in their own homes, especially women and children.
GETTY
Many Palestinian women and children were killed in their own homes
A member of the Al Najjar family who survived an attack in Khan Younis which killed 19 of his relatives, said: "I woke up in the hospital, and I later learned that my sister, mother and my children had all died.
We all died that day even those who survived.
The report criticises Israel for "not revising its practice of air-strikes, even after their dire effects on civilians became apparent", and has questioned whether this was part of a "broader policy" approved at the highest level of government.
It said there was a pattern of the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) issuing warnings to people to leave a neighbourhood and then "automatically considered anyone remaining to be a fighter".
Justice Davis said: "When the safety of an Israeli soldier is at stake, all the rules seem to be disregarded."
In Israel, the report said the hostilities caused immense distress and disruption to the lives of civilians in the country, with witnesses living near Gaza speaking of being disturbed by seeing bombing from their sitting room windows and struggling to reach shelters in time with children when the rocket sirens went off.
GETTY
Gaza was left devastated while Hamas launched nearly 5,000 rockets towards Israel
It said: "The indiscriminate firing of thousands of rockets and mortars at Israel appeared to have the intention of spreading terror among civilians there."
The report reveals the Israeli military found 14 tunnels from Gaza into Israel which were being used to attack their soldiers during the war, causing fear among civilians concerned about being attacked at any moment by "gunmen bursting out of the ground."
It said: "Israel must break with its lamentable track record in holding wrong doers accountable and accountability on the Palestinian side is also woefully inadequate.
The report also raises concerns about Israel closing a criminal investigation into the case of four children killed on a Gaza beach and said international journalists and "many Palestinian eyewitnesses do not appear to have been interviewed by the Israeli authorities, which raises questions about the thoroughness of their investigation".
Israeli authorities did not respond to requests by the commission for information and direct access to Israel, the report says, so the commission had to obtain "harrowing first hand testimony" by video calling and telephone interviews as well as face-to-face interviews with victims and witnesses from the West Bank.
Justice Davis added: We were deeply moved by the immense suffering and resilience of the victims.
"We just hope our report contributes in some small way to ending the cycle of violence.
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS social media accounts targeted by new police unit</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/dLVxIo66Vm8/ISIS-police-unit</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>ISIS social media accounts targeted by new police unit
ISIS social media accounts targeted by new police unit
SOCIAL media accounts used by ISIS terrorist are to be targeted by a new police unit.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 15:44, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
IGGETTY
The new police unit will be tasked with discovering and shutting down ISIS social media accounts
The European police agency Europol estimates up to 50,000 accounts could be linked to Islamic State.
A new Europe-wide police unit will work with social media companies to shut down the accounts within two hours of them being discovered.
Calls for more to be done to tackle online radicalisation have mounted in recent weeks after claims that Talha Asmal, who was reported to have become Britain's youngest suicide bomber, was groomed over the internet.
The 17-year-old is alleged to have fled his home in Dewsbury, West Yorkshire, in March to join ISIS and reportedly detonated a vehicle while fighting for the group in Iraq.
His family said he had been exploited by extremists on the internet "in a process of deliberate and calculated grooming".
Rob Wainwright, Europol's director, said the new unit, which comes into force on July 1, would work to identify the key accounts being run in a number of languages that "underpin" what ISIS is doing and would aim to "identify the ringleaders online".
He told the Guardian it would also monitor social media to identify any activity targeting people who might be vulnerable, as well as those preying on them.
He said: "Who is it reaching out to young people, in particular, by social media, to get them to come, in the first place? It's very difficult because of the dynamic nature of social media."
Mr Wainwright added that money used to fund ISIS would be tracked down, saying: "Where you follow the money trail, it helps find who they are, what they are doing and who their associates are."
Who is it reaching out to young people, in particular, by social media, to get them to come, in the first place? It's very difficult because of the dynamic nature of social media.
Rob Wainwright, director of Europol
Europol believes up to 5,000 people from the EU, including those from the UK, France, Belgium and the Netherlands, have travelled to IS-held areas. Around 700 Britons are thought to have travelled to ISIS-controlled regions of Syria and Iraq.
The former reviewer of anti-terrorism legislation, Lord Carlile, has called on the Government to work with computer programmers and social media companies to counter extremist propaganda online.
Mr Wainwright said that ISIS had proved to be "very technologically adept" and had exploited the internet and social media in a much bigger way than other terrorist organisations had in the past.
"We will have to combine what we see online with our own intelligence that is shared with us by European police services so, therefore, we can be a bit more targeted, identifying who the key user accounts are and concentrating on closing them down and then pursuing the more conventional counter-terrorism investigation around them," he told the BBC Radio 4 Today programme.
"So in the end what we are hoping to have is strategic impact against the problem as a whole rather than just playing a simple numbers game."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: ISIS train young boys by forcing them to CAGE fight</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/xY-jT-cta4M/Video-ISIS-train-young-boys-forcing-cage-fight</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WATCH: ISIS train young boys by forcing them to CAGE fight
WATCH: ISIS train young boys by forcing them to CAGE fight
BOYS as young as six are being trained as the next generation of Islamic State killers are being locked in steel cages and forced to fight each other.
PUBLISHED: 00:00, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:22, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
IG
The young boys are forced into a caged ring to fight
A horrifying new propaganda video released by the terror group on social media shows very young boys wrestling inside a ring as their armed commander beats them with a stick.
They tackle an assault course and grown men walk across their stomachs as they are forced to lie on the floor in a line.
Masked boys are also shown breaking tiles with their heads and crawling through metal tubes as ISIS fighters fire bullets over their heads.
The seven-minute video is thought to have been filmed at a base in Iraq and is aimed at recruiting foreign fighters, an intelligence expert said.
Professor Anthony Glees, from Buckingham University, said: "Mothers elsewhere could be vulnerable, thinking their child could be a failure in Britain - or join IS and become a warrior.
"This is sickening glorification of the brutalisation of kids for IS.
"It is designed to appeal to mothers and fathers but children are also the target."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 16:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>They just want to be loved…but Yulin Dog Meat Festival brutes slaughter thousands to eat</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/09fYVQxFzSU/Sick-pictures-of-roasted-pets-at-Yulin-Dog-Meat-Festival-Ricky-Gervais-condemned</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Images show dogs left in cages in the dirt
REUTERS
Vendors cut butchered dogs at a dog meat market
The event has seen support from animal rights activists across the globe.
Actor and animal lover Ricky Gervais has been raising awareness of the event and tweeted: It's misleading to call Yulin a Dog Meat Festival. It should be called a Dog Torture Festival. Because that's what it is. #StopYuLin2015
He also said: If you are outraged &amp; disgusted by pics of animal abuse, don't just demand that the pics stop, demand that the abuse stops. #StopYuLin2015
But an employee of the Longmen Dog Meat Restaurant said: "Eating dog meat is a local tradition, it has nothing to do with the local government.
GETTY
Animal right activists scuffle with residents as they protest against the dog meat festival
GETTY
A dog carrying a basket with a message in Chinese "Child for sale"
Adam Parascandola, of Humane Society International, which has been campaigning in Yulin, described the scenes of early morning slaughters which had to be carried out in darkness as daytime killings have been banned in a bid to reduce criticism.
He saw dogs brutally beaten to death with clubs in front of each other, their screams and howls breaking the silence.
Later he saw live animal markets in full swing with dogs, cats, puppies and kittens crammed into tiy cages fully exposed in the hot sun without water or shade.
He said: "As well as the obvious animal cruelty aspect of this horrific festival, campaigners are also raising very serious public health concerns about the transmission of rabies and other diseases in this completely unregulated and often criminal trade. Theft of pet dogs and cats plays a huge role in sustaining this industry.
REUTERS
Dogs for sale are kept in a cage in Dashichang dog market
REUTERS
Dogs are piled high so vendors can sell their meat
"It's been a real challenge to be here in Yulin over the past few days.
"I've witnessed truly heartbreaking animal suffering of dogs and cats that I will never forget, but at the same time I've also had the honour of working alongside really inspiring Chinese activists and ordinary animal-loving citizens who care deeply about ending this horrific trade.
"They give me hope for the future, and they in turn are feeling hopeful because they finally feel that their voices are being heard around the world. I sincerely hope the Chinese authorities listen too, and this will be the last we see of this brutal festival."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 10:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terrorists attack Afghanistan parliament - six Taliban gunmen killed</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/axcmn2qEBUw/Taliban-terrorists-attack-Afghanistan-parliament-suicide-bombers-siege</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Terrorists attack Afghanistan parliament - six Taliban gunmen killed
Terrorists attack Afghanistan parliament - six Taliban gunmen killed
A TALIBAN suicide bomber and several gunmen have attacked the Afghanistan parliament.
PUBLISHED: 08:11, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 09:32, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
IG
The moment the first bomb struck
About 25 people have been wounded including five woman and three children in the attack in Kabul.
A dramatic video shows the government about to welcome the new defence minister inside a hall when the first explosion took place.
Chilling screams fill the room from those inside, while dust falls from the ceiling.
The first explosion was believed to be a car bomb parked by the parliament entrace. There were up to seven further blasts.
Windows shattered from the force of the explosion, and government officials then fled the building.
Six other insurgents with machine guns took hold of neighbouring buildings and tried to fire shots from there.
REUTERS
A vehicle is seen on fire after a blast near the Afghan parliament in Kabul, Afghanistan
EPA
Afghan police officers secure the scene
AP
The first explosion was a suicide bomb in a car
We have launched an attack on parliament as there was an important gathering to introduce the country's defence minister
taliban spokesman
Afghan police and the army have scrambled to try and control the area.
It is the second district in the country which has fallen to the Islamist group in just two days. Districts Kunduz and Dasht-e-Archi have now been taken over.
The Taliban had been surrounding the city for days, government officials said.
Violence has spiralled in Afghanistan since foreign forces left the country at the end of last year.
Insurgents are pushing to take territory more than 13 years after the American-led military intervention toppled the Taliban from power.
AP
The army and police scrambled to the scene and shot dead six gunmen
NAQIBULLAH FAIQ
Pictures from inside parliament show rooms filled with dust
NAQIBULLAH FAIQ
No MPs were injured
Ebadullah Karimi, a spokesman for Kabul police, said: "A suicide bomber blew himself up just outside the parliament building and several fighters took positions in a building close to parliament.
Taliban spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid claimed responsibility and said: We have launched an attack on parliament as there was an important gathering to introduce the country's defence minister.
Kabul police said they have shot dead six gunmen.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS terrorists 'sneak into Europe disguised as migrants' – sparking fears of bomb attacks</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/_aNX9i8a5nM/ISIS-Islamic-State-jihadi-terror-attack-migrant-crisis-Europe-Italy-North-Africa</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>ISIS terrorists 'sneak into Europe disguised as migrants'  sparking fears of bomb attacks
ISIS terrorists 'sneak into Europe disguised as migrants'  sparking fears of bomb attacks
HORDES of Islamic State members have reportedly sneaked into Europe along with desperate migrants  sparking fears of terror attacks on the continent.
PUBLISHED: 00:08, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 01:00, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
EXPRESS
Europe is at risk from a terror attack by ISIS, experts have warned
ISIS fanatics have taken advantage of porous borders by travelling from North Africa to Italy on boats packed with refugees, according to terrorism experts.
Now it is feared that the notorious group, which controls much of Iraq and Syria, could target Europe within months.
A counter-terrorism insider said: "Once in Europe they can go through the asylum process or disappear off the radar of the authorities by linking up with even more smuggling networks."
"This means they can penetrate deeper into Europe and avoid detection from the police and security services.
"Nobody knows just how many there are."
There are thought to be around a million migrants looking to sneak across the Mediterranean from North Africa, mostly from war-torn Sudan, Somalia and Eritrea.
Last year David Cameron warned that Britain was at threat from the group's "extreme Islamist regime".
He said:"The people in that regime, as well as trying to take territory, are also planning to attack us here at home in the United Kingdom."
Soon after the UK's terror threat level was raised from 'substantial' to 'severe'  meaning that an attack is highly likely.
And last month Express.co.uk reported that Britainis at "huge risk of an attack" from jihadists seeking revenge after a US airstrike injured leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi.
His wounds were thought to be so severe that he may have been left paralysed for life and unable to lead the barbaric group ever again.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jun 22 02:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>33 taken to hospital after chemical leak in swimming pool</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/9-xFsV_YSgo/33-hospital-chemical-leak-swimming-pool</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>33 taken to hospital after chemical leak in swimming pool
33 taken to hospital after chemical leak in swimming pool
A HOLIDAY park swimming pool was sealed off last night after 33 people were taken to hospital following a chemical leak.
PUBLISHED: 00:01, Mon, Jun 22, 2015
| UPDATED: 20:50, Thu, Jun 25, 2015
ALBANPIX.COM
The chemical leak forced 33 people to hospital
The alarm was raised after swimmers reported a stinging sensation in their eyes in the indoor pool, which was packed with children.
The casualties were taken to three hospitals after the incident at the Wild Duck Holiday Park, near Great Yarmouth, Norfolk, at 2.35pm.
A three-year-old child was among the walking wounded who went to hospital.
The 33 people were taken to Norfolk and Norwich Hospital, James Paget Hospital in Great Yarmouth and Ipswich Hospital.
A spokesman for park owners Haven Holidays said: There was a chemical leak in the swimming pool in the entertainment complex and it was evacuated while police and fire and rescue were on their way.
The immediate area has been evacuated and a cordon has been put in place around the building while emergency services deal with the incident
Spokesman for park owners Haven Holidays
Thirty-three people have been taken to three local hospitals as a precaution. They include one three-year-old child and a member of staff. The casualties have been described to me as walking wounded. The park is now in lockdown while they try to source the chemical leak.
Fire crews were also sent to the park to discover the cause of the leak.
It is understood chlorine gas leaked from a plant room at the indoor pool. The holiday park is set in 98 acres of woodland and has indoor and outdoor pools.
Witnesses reported seeing people lying outside the building wrapped in blankets. A Norfolk Police spokesman said officers had been called to reports of a chemical leak.
The spokesman added: The immediate area has been evacuated and a cordon has been put in place around the building while emergency services deal with the incident.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
