<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Royal baby: Looks like today’s the day! Police convoy 'seen heading to hospital'</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/lhCZFxw5bek/Royal-baby-Looks-like-today-s-the-day-Crowd-control-measures-at-dawn-fuels-speculation</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>ROYAL
Royal baby: Looks like todays the day! Police convoy 'seen heading to hospital'
A POLICE convoy is reportedly heading towards St Mary's Hospital in Paddington, where the Duchess of Cambridge is due to give birth.
08:25, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 14:08, Fri, May 1, 2015
XPOSURE
Police convoy reportedly heading to St Mary's hospital
The cars are headed north bound on Edgware Road from Marble Arch, turned left onto Sussex Gardens in the direction of the royal baby hospital  sparking huge excitement that the great Kate Wait appeared to be over
Jubilant royalists were always confident today was going to be the day the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge welcome their prince or princess into the world.
Additional no-waiting signs had been added to the street outside St Marys Hospitals private Lindo Wing, while extra cones have also been placed to control a media scrum.
Fanatics have also been camping out for more than a week so they can be some of the first to catch a glimpse of the latest addition to the royal family.
One seasoned royal baby watcher, who has cheered no less than FOUR royal babies into the world, said: Ive seen this before. When the police start bringing in barriers and stuff to control the media pack you know something is about to happen.
XPOSURE
The police convoy said to be heading to St Mary's Hospital
IG
Kate could be induced as she is believed to be six days overdue
Kate is believed to have been due on Saturday, April 25, meaning she is now six days late.
Experts told Express.co.uk they believed she could be induced over the next couple of days.
While NHS hospitals induce at 42 to 43 weeks, private hospitals generally induce at 41 weeks.
The media scrambled to the Lindo Wing on Tuesday after royal press officers and a police sniffer dog were seen buzzing around the hospital.
But it was a false alarm, with some medical experts believing she may have had false labour contractions Braxton Hicks .
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State terrorists brutally execute men by smashing concrete blocks onto their heads</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/42-hsbVBzpQ/Islamic-state-execute-men-concrete-blocks</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Islamic State terrorists brutally execute men by smashing concrete blocks onto their heads
ISLAMIC State terrorists brutally executed two men accused of murder by smashing concrete blocks onto their heads.
04:47, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:10, Fri, May 1, 2015
IG
An Islamic State militant is shown about to throw a large concrete block onto a man
Horrific images have emerged showing the Islamists lifting the large blocks above their heads as they shadow over the men cowering on the ground with their hands tied behind their backs.
The next photos show horrendous images of blood spattered across the road and dripping down the side of a pavement as a shouting crowd cheers the executors on.
Both men were bludgeoned to death in Nineveh province in northern Iraq after the Islamic police arrested them for allegedly robbing and killing three women.
The execution is known as a 'qisas' punishment, or an 'eye for an eye' retribution.
The pictures come in the same week as two other men were shown on social media being beheaded by Islamic State militants with a huge machete in the Syrian village of Jarnyah, west of Raqqa.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 06:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brussels backlash: MEPs provoke anger by BLOCKING move to fully reveal expenses spending</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/QWBVK3rSJRc/MEPs-provoke-anger-BLOCKING-move-reveal-expenses</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>POLITICS
Brussels backlash: MEPs provoke anger by BLOCKING move to fully reveal expenses spending
MEPs have provoked anger by voting against moves to increase public scrutiny over their claims for lavish Brussels expenses.
04:01, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:29, Fri, May 1, 2015
GETTY
MEP's have blocked plans to allow more scrutiny into their expenses
Proposals to force the politicians to publish annual accounts of their use of a 3,000 monthly office allowance were discussed at the European Parliament earlier this week.
But MEPs backed an amendment watering down the proposal.
Critics said the move will block voters from getting a full breakdown of how around 28million of European taxpayers' money is spent annually.
Under the original proposal from the parliament's budgetary control commitee, MEPs were expected to submit an end-of-year public report on the allowance.
But the amendment passed at a sessioh of the parliament in Strasbourg on Wednesday removed the obligation and called for any change to be delayed pending more work on the definition of more precise rules regarding the accountability of expenditures authorised under this allowance.
The amendment also removed a paragraph which expressed "concern" that the monthly allowance is not audited and that it is paid without proper supporting documents.
Another paragraph expressing regret that there are no precise rules for the expenditures that may be covered by the allowance" was also removed.
Also deleted was a section saying the committee was "astonished that Members do not have to account for the way they have used the allowance.
The European Parliament's general expenditure allowance (GEA) is equivalent to around 37,000 a year per MEP 187,000 over the course of a five-year term in the European Parliament.
It is meant to pay for office costs, which include office rent, phones, computers and utility bills.
The GEA is only one among many allowances available to MEPs.
They are also entitled to a subsistence allowance for each day an MEP signs in to work in Parliament and for attending meetings in Europe and a monthly allowance of 15,380 to pay for parliamentary staff and assistants.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EXCLUSIVE Shock pics of hopeful Labour MP fondling woman's breast emerge in smear campaign</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/AkLKBUhpyCw/EXCLUSIVE-Photos-hopeful-Labour-MP-cupping-woman-s-breast-emerge-smear-campaign</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>POLITICS
EXCLUSIVE Shock pics of hopeful Labour MP fondling woman's breast emerge in smear campaign
A YOUNG rising Labour star has been branded "not fit for Parliament" after pictures emerged of him wearing pink skimpy knickers on his head and appearing to cup a woman's breast.
07:22, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 12:16, Fri, May 1, 2015
TWITTERGavinCallaghan
Labour rising star is caught up in Twitter photo storm
Gavin Callaghan, 26, is vying for the key seat of Basildon and Billericay  currently held by Tory MP John Baron - and is an outspoken councillor within the Labour group on Basildon Council.
But the emergence of pictures of Mr Callaghan in compromising positions with an unidentified woman, believed to be in her 20s, so close to next week's General Election, will be an embarrassment for Labour.
Ed Miliband's party prides itself on pressing for equality, supporting feminism and bringing an end to sexism.
The pictures, taken when Mr Callaghan was a 19-year-old Labour Party member studying at Newcastle University in 2008, have been posted on social media site Twitter and discussed by rival politicians.
In one photo Mr Callaghan - who has worked as a researcher for Labour MPs Steve Rotheram and Dan Jarvis and campaigns on issues of disability, housing and law and order - is pulling a face as he appears to cup the blonde woman's chest from behind.
There is no suggestion that she did not welcome the young councillor's advances and she is seen to be smiling in the unedited picture.
Express.co.uk have obscured her identity.
In another image, Mr Callaghan is seen posing with pink skimpy knickers on his head and what appears to be a lollipop in his mouth.
A third picture shows him, still wearing the ladies garment on his head, on top of a lady on a sofa.
GavinCallaghan
Mr Callaghan in a more traditional look
TWITTER
The hopeful MP sports an original look unlikely to catch on with Labour
It is not clear if it is the same woman as the first image.
The images are unlikely to be welcomed by Labour stalwarts such as Harriet Harman, who has long championed for women's rights and an end to sexism.
The pictures were posted to an anonymous Twitter account called Political Truth. There are no other postings on this account other than the pictures, suggesting they have emerged as part of a smear campaign.
The person behind the Political Truth account sent the images to Mr Callaghan's own Twitter account and two rival politicians the Labour candidate was arguing with online.
The photos were sent by the Political Truth account in February this year with the message: "Cllr Callaghan is trying to sensor (sic) these pics".
Mr Callaghan and former Tory MP Michael Gordon Banks, now a policy advisor to Tim Farron, the Lib Dem Foreign Office spokesman, were arguing on February 19 when the posting was made.
Mr Banks, 54, retweeted them and they were referenced by Dan Jukes, 19, a UKIP activist and elections officer for its youth branch Young Independence, who had also spatted with Callaghan online.
TWITTER
Snapped in another compromising position, the prospective MP still wears unusual attire
TWITTER
Gavin Callaghan in party mode as seen on Twitter
BBC
Harriet Harman is unlikely to be amused by the antics
People do silly things when they are young. Remember David Cameron and the Bullingdon Club. While I am sure Gavin regrets teenage excesses, the fact remains that he has been a hard working local councillor and will make an excellent MP for Basildon and Bi
Byron Taylor, Basildon Labour Group leader
There is no suggestion Mr Banks or Mr Jukes were involved in the original leaked pictures.
Commenting on the pictures, George Konstantinidis, UKIP candidate for the Basildon and Billericay seat, said if Mr Callaghan were an ordinary member of the public it would be no real issue.
However, because Mr Callaghan is running for office, Mr Konstantinidis claimed the emergence of the photos made him "unfit" to represent the constituency in Parliament.
He added: "People can be whoever they want to be, and I respect their privacy and liberties. However, where they are soliciting votes, and expecting us to trust them and trust the future of our country into their hands, they should be able to demonstrate a degree of seriousness and maturity.
"I do not think Gavin is mature enough to represent his own party, never mind the constituency."
However, Mr Callaghan dismissed the photos as part of growing up at university.
He also warned current undergraduates to be wary of what they were photographed doing, if they are considering a subsequent career in politics.
He said: "They were taken when I was 19 at private parties while at university. I know some people spend their whole lives preparing and expecting to become an MP from the age of four, but that's not the case with me.
"What relevance this has to my standing for Parliament seven years later, I'm not quite sure, but I suppose this a lesson to any working-class kid growing up who thinks they may stand for public office one day.
"Whatever you do, don't have a life before you enter the world of Westminster. Embarrassing photos could come back to bite you."
Byron Taylor, leader of Basildon Council's Labour group, stood by the young candidate, and likened Mr Callaghan's party antics to those of Prime Minister David Cameron in his Bullingdon Club days.
TWITTER
Screen grab of Twitter debarcle
ELLE
Labour leader Ed Milliband, a staunch feminist, has yet to comment
TWITTERMichaelGordonBanks
Former MP Michael Banks retweets pictures
He said: "People do silly things when they are young. Remember David Cameron and the Bullingdon Club. While I am sure Gavin regrets teenage excesses, the fact remains that he has been a hard working local councillor and will make an excellent MP for Basildon and Billericay."
It is not the first time social media has got the young politician in hot water.
In Essex, and even further afield, Mr Callaghan has previously been criticised for offending people on Twitter, despite working for Mr Jarvis on beefing up internet troll laws.
At one stage there were seven standards investigations underway into his online conduct at Basildon Council, including a number brought by the Tory mayor Mo Larkin, after he falsely accused her of getting taxpayers to fund a new portrait for her office.
The case was closed after council officers mediated between the pair and no further action was taken following the other complaints.
The Labour Party has not yet responded to requests for comment.
BasildonCouncil
Mr Callaghan wants to be MP for Basildon and Billericay which has its own Hollywood-style sign
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 08:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EXCLUSIVE: Calls to halt Britain's £400m aid after Malawi leader vows to buy PRIVATE JET</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/3TOxhy52KkM/EXCLUSIVE-Calls-halt-Britains-400m-aid-Malawi-leader-buy-PRIVATE-JET</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>WORLD
EXCLUSIVE: Calls to halt Britain's 400m aid after Malawi leader vows to buy PRIVATE JET
THE president of one of the world's poorest nations has vowed to buy himself a PRIVATE JET - as British taxpayers' prepare to take their spending on foreign aid for the country close to 400m.
06:59, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:50, Fri, May 1, 2015
GETTY
The President of Malawi said he wanted the jet to avoid queuing at airports
Malawi's leader Peter Mutharika has revealed he wants an Air Force One-style presidential jet in order to avoid airport queues or the "inconvenience" of waiting for flights.
After returning from a recent trip abroad, the east African country's president said: "Imagine spending seven hours at Tambo Airport in Johannesburg [South Africa] just to connect to [Malawi's capital] Lilongwe? How inconveniencing."
The country's Information Minister, Kondwani Nankhumwa, also attempted to justify the need for the president of one of the poorest countries in the world to have his own private plane.
"In all fairness every country needs a presidential jet for convenient travelling," he said.
"The President experiences a lot of time losses in flight connections whenever he is on public flights, hence affecting his schedules."
The remarks have sparked an angry response both in Britain and Malawi, with critics branding the request absurd- not least because more than half of Malawians live on less than a $1 a day.
The UK Government sends millions of pounds in aid to the impoverished African state, with this year's budget estimated at more than 83million  equating to 1.18 per cent of Britain's total foreign aid budget.
Between 2009 and 2013, Britains overseas aid allowance for Malawi topped 300million.
But the Department for International Development (DfID) stressed no UK aid money had been given to the government of Malawi since 2013, when it was suspended over claims of corruption.
Instead, millions in taxpayer funding was funnelled to projects carried out by independent aid agencies.
IG
A previous Malawian president blew 8.3m on a new jet
Mr Mutharika gained notoriety after he struck up a friendship with pop star Madonna during her last trip to the country , when she adopted two children.
Madonna always arrives in Malawi on her private Gulfstream jet.
However, Mr Mutharika himself is forced to rely on a mixture of chartered and commercial flights.
Air Force One, the name given to the US president's aircraft, costs an estimated 118,000 an hour to run.
Officials in Washington claim a replacement for the jumbo jet would set the US taxpayer back 254million.
It's because so much aid goes to leaders like him that countries like Malawi remain so poor even after billions have been donated by the West
Jonathan Foreman, expert in UK aid
Mr Mutharika is likely to opt for a more modest jet, similar to those used by neighbouring African presidents, but it could still severely dent the national budget of one of the world's poorest nations by millions of pounds.
Malawi ranks as the 174th poorest nation out of 187 in the Human Development Index  a universally-accepted benchmark that takes into account average income and life expectancy.
Nathan Gill, UKIP's development spokesman, said: "A new Gulfstream [aircraft] costs 42million, more than 50 per cent of the UK's aid to that troubled country.
"This just highlights UKIP's policy of reducing our development spending and concentrating on dropping trade barriers.
"If we did that maybe the people of Malawi would benefit and not just their ridiculous elite".
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Michael Sheen says there's 'no room for snobbishness' in Hollywood </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/nREtNG3x4g0/Michael-Sheen-no-room-snobbishness-Hollywood</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SHOWBIZ
Michael Sheen says there's 'no room for snobbishness' in Hollywood
DON'T ever expect actor Michael Sheen to bite the hand that feeds him because he can't stand superiority complexes within the profession.
14:02, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 14:10, Fri, May 1, 2015
GETTY
Michael Sheen likes to take on a variety of roles
"People tell me that I do things like The Queen and Frost/Nixon and then do Twilight, Tron and Underworld," says the 46-year-old, who has earned critical acclaim for playing Kenneth Williams, Tony Blair, Brian Clough and David Frost.
"There's no room for snobbishness.
"It doesn't matter what genre you're working in you make a connection with the work and, if it gets you going, it excites you.
"I have a wide range of tastes."
Hear, hear!
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inside the mind of a stalker: Elliot Fogel's 12-year hate campaign against Claire Waxman</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/2NF6FiuoPl4/Inside-mind-stalker-Elliot-Fogel-12-year-hate-campaign-Claire-Waxman</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UK
Inside the mind of a stalker: Elliot Fogel's 12-year hate campaign against Claire Waxman
THIS weeks case of a man jailed for his obsessive harassment of a former classmate offers a chilling insight into how far such offenders are prepared to go.
13:43, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:52, Fri, May 1, 2015
NATIONAL NEWS AND PICTURES
Elliot Fogel became fixated on Claire Waxman, ruining her and her familys life in the process
Like so many of us Elliot Fogel used a wedding picture as the screensaver image on his computer.
Only in his case the photograph was not of him and his wife but of another couple entirely.
Fogel was in fact a sad loner and the bride in the picture was a woman called Claire Waxman, who'd had the misfortune to catch his eye as a sixth former at Oaklands College in St Albans some years earlier.
In 2003 he embarked on a 12-year campaign of stalking that was so relentless and intrusive that Waxman developed insomnia and a stomach ulcer, lost large amounts of weight and suffered a miscarriage.
In one year alone Fogel googled her name 40,000 times - sometimes at a rate of 20 an hour.
He bombarded her with late-night phone calls, letters, flowers and bizarre gifts. He also spent countless hours following her and on one occasion broke into her car.
Waxman, a 38-year-old mother-of-two, and her husband were forced to move house five times in a bid to shake off her deranged stalker but each time he succeeded in tracking her down to their new address.
This week the law caught up with Fogel, 40, a former producer at Sky Sports and Capital Radio, and he was jailed for three and a half years for breaching a life- time restraining order banning him from contacting her.
"Stalkers wreck their victims' lives," said Waxman after the verdict.
"My family and I have had to endure 12 years of persistent stalking and we just wish that Fogel would desist so that we can lead a normal life."
And the Waxmans are not alone.
While celebrity stalking incidents involving big names such as Newsnight presenter Emily Maitlis, actress Catherine Zeta-Jones and actor Martin Shaw attract widespread coverage complete unknowns are equally vulnerable.
Even if Fogel does nothing else he will still control the rest of Claire Waxman's life because she will always be looking over her shoulder
Neil Addison, barrister
Indeed Britain is experiencing a stalking epidemic with an estimated 1.2 million women and 900,000 men being victims of what one campaigner calls "a very insidious form of violence" every year.
One of these was Alexis Bowater, a former presenter of the Six O'Clock News on ITV West-country.
"I was cyber--stalked by Alexander Reeve," she says.
"We didn't know who he was at the time.
"We just knew that threatening emails were coming into the newsroom regarding myself because I was pregnant."
When Bowater returned from maternity leave the threats resumed with redoubled violence after she became pregnant with her second child.
"Stalkers don't go backwards in their threats, they escalate.
"This time they included threats of rape. He threatened to blow up myself and my colleagues while we were on air and the final one said that I would be found hanging nine months pregnant.
"It was extraordinarily traumatic. I was heavily pregnant, I had extra police patrols going past my house, I had a panic alarm installed at home and we were in talks with the police about having a panic room put in."
Bowater, who is now an anti-stalking campaigner, turned out to be fortunate in the sense that her police force understood the gravity of stalking as a crime and by dint of inspired detective work tracked down her tormentor.
Reeve was jailed in 2009 with one of the longest sentences that's ever been handed down in this country for cyber stalking: four years and one month.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supermodel Bar Refaeli goes underwear free and flashes her bottom in sexy shoot</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/92HpOXnJ_5o/Bar-Refaeli-underwear-free-bottom-sexy-shoot</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>SHOWBIZ
Supermodel Bar Refaeli goes underwear free and flashes her bottom in sexy shoot
SUPERMODEL Bar Refaeli has been showing off her saucy side on Instagram with a nearly-nude shot for her fans.
13:36, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:54, Fri, May 1, 2015
INSTAGRAM
Bar Refaeli showed off her saucy side in an underwear-free Instagram picture
The 29-year-old Israeli model flashed her bare bottom as she jumped into a car wearing little more than a knitted boob tube.
Wearing roller skates and hopping into a vintage car, the shoot had a 1970s feel to it - confirmed by Bar's picture caption.
She said: "That 70's show."
With her blonde hair tousling down her back, the model looks undeniably gorgeous as she perches on the edge of her seat.
INSTAGRAM
The model dared to bare all as she sat down in a vintage car
The star posted an equally nude picture of herself in just a denim jacket - nothing else.
Clearly proud of her well-honed body, Bar said: "Nude diamonds &amp; jeans, oh my! @hsternofficial card collection."
The youngster recently revealed she is engaged to marry her Israeli businessman boyfriend Adi Ezra, 40.
Her representative confirmed the fabulous news in March, saying: "We are pleased to tell you that she is engaged."
A photo posted by Bar Refaeli (@barrefaeli) on
Feb 14, 2015 at 2:44pm PST
The pair were introduced to one another through mutual friends last year and it appears they're going from strength to strength.
The model has frequently posted pictures of the two of them together and refers to Adi as 'hot'.
It looks like she's torn herself away from her fabulous new man long enough to take part in the saucy photoshoot.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OUT – the bobby on the beat: IN – Twitter policing – cops come clean on the grim future</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/J-ibURbpgAI/Policing-bobby-on-beat-Twitter</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UK
OUT  the bobby on the beat: IN  Twitter policing  cops come clean on the grim future
THE era of the bobby on the beat is over  and Britain faces a new era of policing by Twitter, a senior police officer admitted today.
13:13, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:49, Fri, May 1, 2015
GETTY SWNS
The era of the bobby on the beat is over
Sergeant Andy Stewart painted a shocking picture of the future of policing where crippling cuts mean the traditional reassuring presence of bobbies on patrol are instead replaced by social media interaction.
Austerity measures at his Devon and Cornwall force have seen 51million slashed from the budget.

And Sgt Stewart, from Wadebridge in Cornwall, warned a town council meeting the cuts would have disastrous consequences.

He said: "I could toe the corporate line but instead I want to tell you the truth.

"The days of seeing a police officer walking through the town, smiling at people, have gone, completely, sad though it is.

"Part of my job is managing expectations, so I need to speak to you to renegotiate what visibility means.

"In future reading a Twitter message from me might be the closest that local residents get to seeing a police presence in the town.

The days of seeing a police officer walking through the town, smiling at people, have gone, completely, sad though it is
Sergeant Andy Stewart
"If nobody's going to be harmed, then we're unlikely to become involved."

The Police Federation called Sgt Stewart's assessment a "backlash" driven by "frustration" and called for "honesty and transparency" from senior officers about the effect of the spending cuts.

Nigel Rabbitts, chairman of the federation for Devon and Cornwall, said officers were no longer prepared to be "brow beaten by managers who are not telling the public the truth".

He said: "We are going to see more of this. It is the backlash from staff expected to do more with less when it is simply not possible.

"Of course emergency response will be maintained as the public have to be protected but other activities are suffering.

"You cannot cut the numbers of police officers any more - we are at the limit. If we make policing more sparse even that emergency response will come under threat.

"What we need is honesty and transparency with the public."

Devon and Cornwall Police Inspector Robin Hogg, said: "We have always been clear that with fewer officers and less resources, the public would see a change in the way that we approach policing across the force."

Earlier this year, Tom Winsor, the Inspector of Constabulary, voiced "growing concerns" that officers were being tied to their desks by paperwork.

He warned that smaller forces could struggle to cope with major incidents such as rioting or multiple murders over the next few years because of the way staff numbers are being slashed to save cash.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charity warns of growing gap between children and nature</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-news-showbiz/~3/lNrsQXlNuyQ/Charity-warns-growing-gap-children-nature</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>NATURE
Charity warns of growing gap between children and nature
YOUNGSTERS are so cut off from nature that half of them do not know what a bluebell is, the charity Plantlife warned yesterday.
13:15, Fri, May 1, 2015
| UPDATED: 13:24, Fri, May 1, 2015
GETTY
Plantlife claims today's children don't know what a bluebell is
And just one in 10 of the nation's children can identify a primrose.
Plantlife warned that modern generations are growing up without the simple pleasures of making daisy chains or finding out if they like butter by holding a buttercup under their chins.
The growing gap between nature of children was revealed as Plantlife celebrated its 25th birthday by launching its first ever Wildflower Weekend for the Bank Holiday break.
It urged the public to get out and see the peak of the floral calendar with woodland flowers such as bluebells in their full glory and meadow plants such as cowslips just beginning to come into bloom.
And it urged the public to take part in the vote for the national flower.
The vote, which runs until June 11 at plantlife.org.uk , currently has the bluebell in the lead with the primrose hot on its heels.
in a close second.
Other close contenders include the poppy, snowdrop, cowslip and cornflower.
When I was little I vividly remember the bluebell woods behind by my grandmas house in Wiltshire
Dr Trevor Dines, Plantlifes Botanical Specialist
As part of its Wildflower Weekend, Plantlife is also offering via plantlife.org.uk a free downloadable ID guide of the commonest wild flowers via its website's homepage.
Dr Trevor Dines, Plantlifes Botanical Specialist, says, When I was little I vividly remember the bluebell woods behind by my grandmas house in Wiltshire.
"Shed get us hunting for white bluebells  the one or two special ones in the sea of blue - and little games like this helped sparked my lifelong passion for wild plants.
Bluebells are an iconic British flower with half the world population found in the nation's woods.
Cowslips get their name from their habit of often growing near cowpats or where a cow has slupped.
Plantlife said that if you are walking through a wood and notice a strong smell of onions, you are probably near wild garlic
It can carpet the woodland floor and has distinctive white flowers.
Also in flower at the moment are violets which were Napoleon's favourite. When he died some were found in a locket as a memento of his first wife, Josephine. 
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
