<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="express">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Holiday fears for Brits as Tunisia president admits country is on brink of collapse</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/CC9MamYCG7g/Tunisia-terror-attack-collapse-not-safe-state-emergency-beach-massacre</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>As we see in other countries, if attacks like Sousse happen again, the country will collapse
President Beji Caid Essebi
In a nationwide televised addressed, he said: "Tunisia faces very serious danger and it should take any possible measures to maintain security and safety.
"As we see in other countries, if attacks like Sousse happen again, the country will collapse."
The president went on to blame the poor security in Libya for Tunisia's problems and the lack of international resolve in targeting ISIS throughout the region.
He said Tunisia had been specifically targeted due to its functioning, secular democracy.
It comes after Tunisia's Government promised new laws to increase police powers and provide harsher penalties for terror convictions.
Immediately after the beach attack, the prime minister pledged to post armed guards at tourist sites and close mosques outside Government control.
The country has previously been under a state of emergency from January 2011, due to the outbreak of the Arab Spring, until March this year.
AP
Islamic State gunman Seifeddine Rezgui opened fire on innocent tourists
This initially included curfews and a ban on meetings of more than three people.
However these were relaxed and police and military took control of powers to intervene in unrest or security reasons.
Twelve suspects have been arrested in connection with the horrifying terror attack carried out by crazed gunman Seifeddine Rezgui.
Tunisian authorities are still hunting two more men suspected of training in a Libyan terror camp with crazed Rezgui, who was believed to be high on cocaine at the time of the bloody massacre.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stars and STRIFE: How US church massacre is a reminder of hated behind confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/21JcBDiEw2o/Dylann-roof-church-massacre-confederate-flag-hatred</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Stars and STRIFE: How US church massacre is a reminder of hated behind confederate flag
Stars and STRIFE: How US church massacre is a reminder of hated behind confederate flag
THEY take their symbols very seriously in the US so it was only a matter of time before showbiz got involved.
PUBLISHED: 12:06, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
| UPDATED: 12:22, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
KOBAL
The Dukes of Hazzard, with it's Confederate flagged car, is now off TV
Less than a month after nine people were shot dead in a church in Charleston, South Carolina, the US TV channel TV Land has dropped The Dukes Of Hazzard. The reason? The prominent role played in the comedy action series by the Confederate flag.
During the 1980s this was one of the most popular shows on TV. Set in fictional Hazzard County in rural Georgia, it featured two rascally but good-hearted cousins, Bo and Luke Duke.
They spent their time outwitting authority, haring about in a souped-up Dodge Charger named General Lee (after the great Confederate commander in the Civil War, Robert E Lee) sporting a painted Confederate flag on its roof.
Once a proud symbol of the Deep South's rebellion against the Yankee North, the flag and its meaning are now under scrutiny as never before since the shooting of the black worshippers and their minister on June 17. Photographs of the alleged gunman, 21-year-old Dylann Roof, often show him waving a Confederate flag. The emblem was also on his car number plates.
Long a divisive political symbol because of the South's associations with slavery, the flag - and whether it should be allowed to keep flying - is now one of the hottest topics of discussion in the US. Six days after the shooting, the Governor of Alabama, Robert Bentley, ordered four Confederate flags to be removed from the grounds of the state Capitol building.
It resembles the Yankee flag and that is enough to make it unutterably detestable
George Bagby, editor of the Southern Literary Messenger
The state parliament of South Carolina has agreed to debate whether the flag should be removed from its premises. Texas has refused to issue car number plates bearing the Confederate emblem and Virginia and North Carolina have pledged to do the same.
Mississippi senator Roger Wicker - whose ancestors fought on the Confederate side - said it was time to remove the rebel cross from the state flag. Some of the biggest US retailers including eBay, Amazon and Walmart have stopped selling merchandise which bears the emblem.
Meanwhile others say the flag question is a diversion from the really important issue: tighter gun controls.
Now Bo and Luke Duke have become part of the fall-out. As well as The Dukes Of Hazzard being pulled from TV schedules, US golf champion Bubba Watson, who bought the iconic General Lee in 2012, has announced he is covering the Confederate flag on its roof: "I believe all men ARE created equal so I will be painting the American flag over the roof of the General Lee."
Clearly, flags are important to Americans. They swear allegiance to their flag and leave it planted in their gardens year-round. But the Confederate one, the so-called Stars and Bars, has become imbued with many different meanings.
The name is wrong for a start.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Real life UP: Man attaches 100 PARTY BALLOONS to deck chair and takes to the skies </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/-v3CPPZZal4/Up-man-balloons-chair-Canada-skies-parachute-real-life-up</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Real life UP: Man attaches 100 PARTY BALLOONS to deck chair and takes to the skies
Real life UP: Man attaches 100 PARTY BALLOONS to deck chair and takes to the skies
THIS is the shocking moment a man flew over the skies of Canada in a garden chair tied to 100 PARTY BALLOONS.
PUBLISHED: 10:30, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:39, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
But Dan Boria's hopes of publicising his cleaning company with the brave stunt were cut short when he spotted a police airplane waiting in the wings.
And when the balloons took him too high, the daredevil from Calgary was forced to safely parachute down to the ground, where he was arrested.
Speaking about his flight, Mr Boria, 26, said: "The winds were pretty fierce up there, no doubt.. the winds were so strong, it pushed me back.
IG
Dan Boria flies over the skies of Canada
It was a surreal experience
Dan Boria
"I jumped out of the chair and landed about a mile away from the grounds.
"I can't specify the altitude I went to.. I was looking down at a 747. It was a surreal experience."
Mr Boria had planned to crash the chuck wagon races at Stampede Park to promote his cleaning company All Clean Natural, whose banner he had attached to the chair.
However the stunt did not come cheap and while the chair cost just $20 (12.88) , the cost of the balloons and helium to fill them cost a staggering $36,000(23,000).
And miraculously the $20 chair survived the flight and was found miles outside the city by Justin Jamison, with 15 helium-filled balloons still somehow attached.
IG
Dan was hoping to promote his cleaning company
Mr Jamison said: "It was just a chair and some balloons and we thought someone fell out of the sky.
"We were wondering 'should we be looking for someone?'"
Despite Mr Boria being arrested and charged with causing mischief and an injured ankle, the stunt doesn't appear to have put him off.
He added: "It was awesome, it was the most fun thing I've ever done."
The scenes are reminiscent of Disney favourite 'UP', in which elderly widower attaches his whole house to thousands of balloons to fulfil his dreams to see the wilds of South America.
IG
Dan lands where he is arrested by police
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World's oldest man Sakari Momoi dies at the age of 112 in Japan </title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/lpmmRoMN1vQ/World-s-oldest-man-dies-Sakari-Momoi-112-Japan</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>World's oldest man Sakari Momoi dies at the age of 112 in Japan
World's oldest man Sakari Momoi dies at the age of 112 in Japan
THE world's oldest man, Japanese Sakari Momoi, has died at the ripe old age of 112.
PUBLISHED: 09:12, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
| UPDATED: 09:18, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
AP
Sakari Momoi died at a care home on Sunday
Mr Momoi, who cited healthy eating and a good night's sleep as the secrets to a very long life, died of kidney failure at a care home in Tokyo on Sunday.
The former high school principal and father-of-five was born on February 5, 1903 - the year the teddy bear was introduced and the Wright brothers made their first powered flight.
He was 42 when the Second World War ended.
Mr Momoi was named the oldest man by Guinness World Records in August.
Born in Fukushima, Mr Momoi first worked as a teacher and later become a principal in high schools across his home town as well as neighbouring Saitama.
AP
Sakari Momoi with his Guinness World Records certificate
Sakari Momoi was named the oldest man by Guinness World Records in August.
He enjoyed reading, especially Chinese poetry, and also travelling around Japan with his late wife.
On receiving his Guinness World Record title, Mr Mamoi said: "I want to live about two more years."
In April the world's oldest person and oldest woman, Misao Okawa from Japan died at the age of 117.
Her titles are now held by 116-year-old American Susannah Mushatt Jones.
Guinness has not yet announced who is now the world's oldest an - although it may well be 112-year-old Japanese Yasutaro Koide who was born a month after Mr Mamoi.
The oldest person who has ever lived according to Guinness was Jeanne Calment from France, who lived 122 years and 164 days.
She died in August 1997.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Briton among 11 injured as savage Running of the Bulls festival begins in Pamplona</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/VMIiWQyJ41I/Seven-rushed-hospital-annual-Running-of-the-Bulls-festival-begins-Pamplona</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Briton among 11 injured as savage Running of the Bulls festival begins in Pamplona
Briton among 11 injured as savage Running of the Bulls festival begins in Pamplona
A BRIT was among 11 people injured at the start of the annual Running of the Bulls festival in Spain today
PUBLISHED: 08:38, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
| UPDATED: 11:16, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
GETTY
Fifteen people have been killed at the annual festival since 1911
The 30-year-old was rushed to hospital after being gored in the pelvic area by a half-ton bull.
Medics only identified the Brit only by the initials A.B.O. His injuries are not thought to be serious.
Five Americans aged 21 to 28 and five Spaniards were also among the casualties in the first of the eight morning runs through the streets of Pamplona.
One of the Americans, a 38-year-old man, was gored in the armpit.
We have one person who has been gored in the chest
Hospital spokesperson
He is thought to have been hurt after a black bull grazed his chest with its horn near the famous Mercaderes corner on the 849-metre course.
Red Cross workers were pictured taking several bloodied runners away on stretchers.
The bulls took two minutes and 23 seconds to complete the course through the cobbled streets of Pamplonas old town.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraq jet accidentally kills 12 with bomb meant for Islamic State jihadists</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/Kgf_rKmAR_k/Iraq-bomb-Sukhoi-plane-ISIS-Islamic-State-jihadists-Russia-Iran-airstrikes</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Iraq jet accidentally kills 12 with bomb meant for Islamic State jihadists
Iraq jet accidentally kills 12 with bomb meant for Islamic State jihadists
AT LEAST 12 people have been killed after a bomb accidentally fell from an Iraqi warplane while carrying out strikes against the Islamic State.
PUBLISHED: 01:08, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
| UPDATED: 02:16, Tue, Jul 7, 2015
AFP
The bomb came loose from the Sukhoi Su-25 fighter jet
The Sukhoi are very old now and should have been retired from service a long time ago
Mohammed al-Iraqi
The bomb came loose from the Sukhoi Su-25 fighter jet as the plane overflew Baghdad to land at its base.
Three houses were destroyed in the New Baghdad area of the capital, with rubble left piled in the street.
The pilot had tried six times to drop the bomb but it was stuck due to a "technical problem", according to the Iraqi defence ministry.
The plane was returning from the Haditha area in Anbar province, which is surrounded by Islamic State jihadists.
Mohammed al-Iraqi, a former military aircraft technician, said: "Those kind of mistakes can happen, especially as the Sukhoi are very old now and should have been retired from service a long time ago."
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eurogeddon: Greece told to make decision on future TONIGHT or face expulsion from the euro</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/j0khq0L5sGk/Greece-told-make-decision-international-bailout-tonight-face-expulsion-euro</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Eurogeddon: Greece told to make decision on future TONIGHT or face expulsion from the euro
Eurogeddon: Greece told to make decision on future TONIGHT or face expulsion from the euro
GREECE has been told it must decide whether to accept the terms of an international bailout TONIGHT or risk imminent expulsion from the euro.
PUBLISHED: 22:27, Mon, Jul 6, 2015
| UPDATED: 22:48, Mon, Jul 6, 2015
REUTERS
Newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos will have to negotiate with creditors
In a series of dire warnings to the crisis-ravaged country European leaders said time is running out to save its place in the single currency bloc.
Rhetoric against Greece from Europe's leading economic powers has ratcheted up significantly in the last 24 hours since its people unanimously rejected continued austerity in a snap referendum.
Tonight Dutch prime minister Mark Rutte issued the most robust warning yet to the beleaguered country, telling it to agree to the bailout terms now or "it is over".
Mr Rutte said his government was unwilling to give any new funding to Greece unless it committed to spending reforms set out by its international creditors.
Asked what would happen if Greek premier Alexis Tsipras tried to use last night's referendum result to wrestle concessions other European countries, he replied: "Then I think it is over".
He told the Dutch parliament: "If things stay the way they are, then we're at an impasse. There is no other choice, they must be ready to accept deep reforms.
"They must make a decision, this evening or tonight, what they are going to do. Whether they are going to come with a serious plan or not."
There is no other choice, they must be ready to accept deep reforms
Dutch prime minister Mark Rutte
His blunt intervention followed similarly forthright statements from the leaders of the eurozone's two biggest economies.
Germany Chancellor Angela Merkel told Greece that "time is of the essence" if a deal is to be salvaged.
She said: "It will be important tomorrow that the Greek prime minister tells us how things should proceed and what precise suggestions he can submit to us for a medium-term programme that will lead Greece to prosperity and growth again."
The German leader made the remarks in Paris after meeting with Francois Hollande to discuss a common stance on Greece.
Opinion on the crisis is hardening back in her homeland, with a member of her ruling coalition stating that it is up to the Greeks to bend to the demands of its creditors.
Sigmar Gabriel, leader of the Social Democrats, said: "If Greece wants to stay in the euro, the Greek government must quickly make a substantive offer that goes beyond its willingness thus far.
"For the Greek population, life will get even more difficult in the coming days and weeks. The definitive insolvency of the country now is an imminent threat."
Following the meeting at the Elysee Palace, Mr Hollande said: "The door is open for discussion.
It's now up to the government of Alexis Tsipras to offer serious, credible proposals so that this will can be turned into a programme which gives a long-term perspective, because Greece needs a long-term perspective in the euro zone with stable rules, as the euro zone itself does.
REUTERS
Angela Merkel and Francois Hollande issued strong statements on Greece
REUTERS
The French and German leaders met in Paris today to coordinate their response
Meanwhile the International Monetary Fund (IMF), one of Greece's main financial backers, warned the country today that it could not provide funds to countries that had missed payments.
IMF Managing Director Christine Lagarde held talks with Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras after his people effectively voted to renege on their debts to the organisation in last night's referendum.
A spokesman for the IMF said: "The managing director explained the fund's inability to disburse under its arrears policy."
The Greek people last night roundly rejected the terms of the international bailout in a move expected to fire the starting gun on Greece's exit from the eurozone.
Official figures published by the interior ministry showed a landslide 61 per cent voted 'No' against austerity imposed by the country's creditors, against 39 per cent who voted 'Yes'.
Hailing the result, Mr Tsipras said: "With the difficult circumstances prevailing today you made a very brave choice. I'm fully aware the mandate you gave me is not one of a rupture with Europe but a mandate to strengthen our negotiating position to seek a viable solution.
REUTERS
The day after the night before: Greece is holding its breath with uncertain times ahead
REUTERS
No voters took to the streets in jubilation following last night's referendum result
Despite the result deemed a victory for his party, Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis resigned this morning.
The departure is an effort to help Mr Tsipras reach a deal, the controversial politician had riled euro leaders with his outspoken views during previous talks and is thought to have been a barrier to finding an agreement.
In a final shot at the creditors, he said he would wear their "loathing with pride."
In a statement he said: "I was made aware of a certain preference by some Eurogroup participants, and assorted partners, for my absence from its meetings; an idea that the Prime Minister judged to be potentially helpful to him in reaching an agreement.
"For this reason I am leaving the Ministry of Finance today.
"I consider it my duty to help Alexis Tsipras exploit, as he sees fit, the capital that the Greek people granted us through yesterdays referendum.
"And I shall wear the creditors loathing with pride."
A senior Greek political figure last night insisted that the government is not considering re-issuing the Drachma, but many commentators have insisted that a 'No' vote will make it almost impossible for the country to remain in the euro.
Greek banks, which have been closed all week and rationing withdrawals from cash machines, are expected to run out of money within days unless the European Central Bank (ECB) provides an emergency lifeline.
However central bankers warned before the vote that a 'No' would make it almost impossible for the ECB to turn on the taps, leaving the Greek financial system without funds and facing imminent collapse.
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malaysia Airlines MH370: Toddler led wild goose chase in Maldives search for missing plane</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/GIqEYfeC9w4/Malaysia-Airlines-MH370-toddler-wild-goose-chase-Maldives-search-missing-plane</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>There's nothing to convince us that it could have been MH370: neither the route nor the timing support that theory
Ibrahim Faizal
Although planes do not normally fly straight over Kuda Huvadhoo, local flyers said the pilot of the Maldivian aircraft could have made an unusual approach to the airport due to unfamiliarity, because it had only been operational for a few months or unusually strong wind which other locals mentioned to investigators.
There is no control tower at the airport and radar systems in the capital, Male, are not strong enough to cover the area so nobody apart from the pilot - and a few Kuda Huvadhoo islanders - would have noticed the change in flightpath.
Ibrahim Faizal, chairman of the board of directors of the Maldives Civil Aviation Authority, said: "In all probability, the plane that the islanders saw was this domestic flight."
He said he is annoyed with the whole mystery of the missing plane and just wants to get to the bottom of it.
He added: "There's nothing to convince us that it could have been MH370: neither the route nor the timing support that theory."
A Maldivian police spokesman said all the witness statements regarding the plane seen over Kuda Huvadhoo "were highly inconsistent".
Express
The missing Malaysia Airlines plane is a Boeing 777
A fire extinguisher found on the island of Baarah, 310mi north of Kuda Huvadhoo, two weeks after MH370 went missing last year became a lifeline of hope for the families of the missing passengers after several experts said it was "very probably a Boeing fire extinguisher".
But Captain Ibrahim Rasheed, director of flight operation's at the Civil Aviation Authority, is certain it did not come from an aircraft and said: "A boat would be more likely."
According to local experts working for him, none of the serial numbers on the extinguisher match parts used by Boeing.
The revelation of the Maldivian plane flying over Kuda Huvadhoo has now deepened the mystery for the relatives of the 239 passengers and crew of MH370 - and the world.
The plane vanished while on a flight from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing and despite the most expensive search in aviation history no trace of it has been found.
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia terror attack: Is this the SECOND killer in Sousse beach massacre?</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/7luYW_5YtBI/Tunisia-terror-attack-second-killer-beach-massacre</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>I'm as sure as I can be that there were two, and possibly three, involved
Jim Stevenson
Mr Stevenson was interviewed by police at Manchester Airport when he arrived back from Tunisia, where he had been holidaying with his wife Karen, 90, 16-year-old son Mitchell, and mother Nessie, 85.
He said: "I'm as sure as I can be that there were two, and possibly three, involved.
"My son and I saw the one who had on grey shorts and a grey T-shirt. He was carrying a Kalashnikov.
"We saw the photographs of Rezgui afterwards - and he definitely wasn't the person we saw.
"Rezgui had on black clothing - the man we saw did not."
The Islamic State (ISIS) terror group has claimed responsibility for the attack in which three Irish nationals, two Germans, one Belgian, one Portuguese and one Russian were also murdered.
And several British witnesses have also prevoiusly claimed Rezgui, 23, did not act alone.
The crazed gunman was killed after he massacred innocent holidaymakers as they sunbathed on the beach, while dressed in black shorts and a T-shirt.
MB
At least one other gunman is thought to have taken part in the brutal attack
Two ex-police officers have told how they saw a third gunman.
Steve Johnson, 65 and Michael Perry, 66, spotted a gunman who they insist wasn't Rezgui.
Survivor Kirsty Murray, 35, of Braintree in Essex said she was blasted in the leg by a man with a pistol and not the Kalashnikov carried by Rezgui.
Twelve suspects have been arrested in connection with the horrifying terror attack.
Tunisian authorities are still hunting two more men suspected of training in a Libyan terror camp with crazed Rezgui, who was believed to be high on cocaine at the time of the bloody massacre.
Photos of Mohamed bin Abdallah, 24, and 28-year-old Rafikhe Tayari were posted on the internet in a bid to trace them.
Met Police Assistant Commissioner Mark Rowley, the national policing lead for counter terrorism, asked anyone who witnessed the attack in Tunisia to get in touch.
He added: "I would like to appeal to anyone who was in Sousse and witnessed the attack to contact us on 0800 789 321 to help with the investigation, if they haven't done so already.
"We have also set up a dedicated email addresses for people to send any images and information that may assist."
Most Read Stories in World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 11:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>American dies after launching Independence Day firework from own head</title>
        <Link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/daily-express-world-news/~3/md18pHNB96I/American-Firework-head-launch-death-dies-dead-die</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>American dies after launching Independence Day firework from own head
American dies after launching Independence Day firework from own head
AN AMERICAN was killed after he tried to launch a Fourth of July firework from the top of his HEAD.
PUBLISHED: 09:29, Mon, Jul 6, 2015
| UPDATED: 10:07, Mon, Jul 6, 2015
IGGETTY
Devon Staples died after he launched a firework from his head
Related articles
Chaos in Calais as 150 migrants STORM Channel Tunnel in desperate...
Devon Staples, of Calais, Maine, had been drinking and celebrating Independence Day when he decided to place a rocket on his head and set it off.
The 22-year-old and his friends had been drinking and setting off fireworks on Saturday night in the backyard of a friend's home in Calais, close to the Canadian border when he put a fireworks mortar tube on his head and set it off.
The firework exploded, killing him instantly.
His death is the first fireworks fatality in Maine since the state legalized fireworks after a 2011 vote to repeal a 1949 law banning fireworks.
At the time, it was believed the new fireworks industry would create jobs and generate additional revenue.
Related articles
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
