<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:58:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean customs workers end strike that has halted exports by fruit and salmon industries</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/reehR2WR7CI/</Link>
        <Description>Chilean customs workers are returning to work after reaching a deal to end a nationwide strike that halted shipments causing losses for the fruit and salmon industries.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chilean customs workers end strike that has halted exports by fruit and salmon industries
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
SANTIAGO, Chile  Chilean customs workers are returning to work after reaching a deal to end a nationwide strike that halted shipments causing losses for the fruit and salmon industries.
Customs workers began the stoppage May 20, demanding improvements in infrastructure and more staff over the next three years. Unions representing the workers reached a deal with the government Thursday.
The SalmonChile group said earlier this week that the strike had blocked exports of about 11 metric tons of salmon and caused more than $30 million in losses for the industry.
Chile's ASOEX fruit exporting association estimated $16 million in losses in fresh fruit due to shipping problems since the beginning of the strike.
Chile is the world's top copper producer and a major global exporter of wine, salmon and fruit.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:05:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iraqi officials say 2 car bombs kill 10 people in Baghdad</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/CwbqFGiudY8/</Link>
        <Description>Authorities in Iraq say two separate car bombs inside parking lot of two hotels have killed 10 people in the capital Baghdad.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraqi officials say 2 car bombs kill 10 people in Baghdad
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BAGHDAD  Authorities in Iraq say two separate car bombs inside parking lot of two hotels have killed 10 people in the capital Baghdad.
Police officials say a car bomb exploded in the parking lot of Babil Hotel late Thursday, killing six people and wounding 14 others.
About one minute later, a second car bomb blast inside the parking lot of Cristal Hotel, formerly Sheraton, killed four people and wounded 13 others.
Medical officials confirmed the causality figures from both attacks. All officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they are not authorized to speak to the media.
Nobody claimed responsibility, but Iraq is seeing almost daily attacks that have been frequently claimed by Islamic State group that seized large swath of the country during a blitz last year.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:46:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former FIFA vice president Jack Warner leaves jail in ambulance, Trinidad official says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/qSlSCxeWdJ0/</Link>
        <Description>Former FIFA vice president Jack Warner has left a jail in Trinidad by ambulance a day after he was charged in a U.S. corruption case that has led to the arrests of more than a dozen international soccer officials and businessman.</Description>
        <MainBody>Former FIFA vice president Jack Warner leaves jail in ambulance, Trinidad official says
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
PORT-OF-SPAIN, Trinidad  Former FIFA vice president Jack Warner has left a jail in Trinidad by ambulance a day after he was charged in a U.S. corruption case that has led to the arrests of more than a dozen international soccer officials and businessman.
Judicial officer Abraham Ali said Thursday that Warner complained of exhaustion and was not able to face questions from reporters gathered outside the jail.
Warner surrendered to authorities Wednesday and was granted a $395,000 bond but spent the night in jail.
He is facing eight counts in the U.S., including conspiracy to defraud and engaging in racketeering. He has not entered a plea and is expected to appear in court in July.
Warner was forced out of FIFA in 2011 over a bribery scandal. He has denied any wrongdoing.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:29:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>200,000 shark fins seized at Ecuadorean port; were to be exported illegally to Asia</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/p622RIgwGY8/</Link>
        <Description>Police in the Ecuadorean port city of Manta say they have seized about 200,000 shark fins destined to be illegally exported to Asia where they would fetch up to $1.5 million.</Description>
        <MainBody>200,000 shark fins seized at Ecuadorean port; were to be exported illegally to Asia
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
This photo released by Ecuador's Attorney General, shows hundreds of shark fins seized by the police in Manta, Ecuador, Wednesday, May 27, 2015. According to the Interior Minister of Ecuador, the police siezed about 200 thousand shark fins that where about to be exported illegaly to Asia. (Fiscalia General del Ecuador via AP)(The Associated Press)
QUITO, Ecuador  Police in the Ecuadorean port city of Manta say they have seized about 200,000 shark fins destined to be illegally exported to Asia where they would fetch up to $1.5 million.
Col. Rommel Tapia, head of the judicial police in Manta, said Thursday that nine properties were raided in the city and six people were arrested, including one of Chinese nationality. Those arrested face charges of damaging wildlife.
Interior Minister Jose Serrano told the Democracia radio station that authorities in Ecuador had "dealt a major blow to an international network that trafficked shark fins."
The fins are often used to make shark fin soup, a traditional Chinese dish.
Manta is 260 kilometers (160 miles) southwest of the capital, Quito.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:09:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alleged Nazi war criminal wanted by Russia dies in Quebec at 93</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/9_r4sA-SFtU/</Link>
        <Description>The lawyer for the man in the No.</Description>
        <MainBody>Alleged Nazi war criminal wanted by Russia dies in Quebec at 93
Published May 28, 2015
MONTREAL  The lawyer for the man in the No. 2 spot on the Simon Wiesenthal Center's list of most wanted Nazi war criminals says his client has died at 93.
Vladimir Katriuk passed away last week after a long illness, his lawyer Orest Rudzik said Thursday.
Russia charged Katriuk earlier this month with genocide in connection with the 1943 killing of civilians in Khatyn, now part of Belarus. According to war reports, Katriuk was a member of a Ukrainian battalion of the SS, the elite Nazi storm troops, between 1942 and 1944. He had denied the accusations against him.
Katriuck moved to Canada in 1951 and eventually became a Canadian citizen.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:47:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK's Cameron begins tour of EU states to push for reform</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/QxAsf__fT5M/</Link>
        <Description>British Prime Minister David Cameron met with the leaders of the Netherlands and France on Thursday, as Cameron began a whirlwind visit to four European capitals, pressing his case that the U.K. needs to renegotiate its relationship with the European Union.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK's Cameron begins tour of EU states to push for reform
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
May 28, 2015: Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron, left,  leaves with French President Francois Hollande, after their meeting, at the Elysee Palace in Paris. (AP)
PARIS  British Prime Minister David Cameron met with the leaders of the Netherlands and France on Thursday, as Cameron began a whirlwind visit to four European capitals, pressing his case that the U.K. needs to renegotiate its relationship with the European Union.
Speaking in Paris at the Elysee Palace before a dinner, Cameron urged the bloc's 27 other members to be "flexible" and "imaginative" about the EU's future -- saying that his priority is "to make it more competitive and to address the concerns of the British people about our membership."
Cameron's newly-elected government plans a referendum by the end of 2017 on the question: "Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union?"
Cameron wants Britain to stay in the EU, if he manages to negotiate a new, looser relationship with the group.
French President Francois Hollande, meanwhile, made reference to the planned referendum, saying that "France hopes that Great Britain stays in the European Union... We think that it's in the interests of Europe and in the interests of the United Kingdom to be together. But there is always respect for the people's wishes."
Both leaders highlighted common ground such as a wish to defeat international terrorism and tackle climate change -- and skirted over differences in their visions for the EU.
"So we have different priorities but we share a common objective: which is to find solutions to these problems (in the EU)," Cameron said.
Earlier in the day, Cameron started his tour in the Netherlands, having lunch with Dutch counterpart Mark Rutte, a center-right leader Cameron described as a "very good friend and very strong partner in Europe."
Cameron said he discussed with Rutte his reform agenda.
"The need for flexibility. The need to focus on growth and jobs. The need to make sure we complete the single market the need to make sure that, as you put it, Europe where necessary, but nation-states wherever possible," Cameron said.
Cameron will continue his tour Friday, meeting with the leaders of Poland and Germany, as part of his efforts to talk with all of the leaders of the EU member states before a European Council meeting late next month. A planned trip to Denmark was canceled because Prime Minister Helle Thorning-Schmidt called a snap election.
European leaders have expressed a desire to accommodate Britain, but it's unclear how far they will go to meet Cameron's desire for change -- especially to the right of EU citizens to live and work anywhere in the bloc.
Other leaders have warned Cameron that free movement within the bloc is non-negotiable, but he hopes to gain agreement to restrict immigrants' right to claim benefits for a period of up to several years.
Hours before Cameron arrived in Paris, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius warned Thursday that Cameron's plan for a referendum is "very risky."
Speaking on France-Inter radio, he said France is open to "improvements" in the way the EU functions, but "if it's about creating a specific status for Britain, so that it has advantages without constraints, then it's `No."'
British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said it was understandable that "some of our partners will adopt a hard line at the start of the negotiations."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:43:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pro-Israel critics claim Hamas front group nearing coveted UN status</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/qnPRr2O855s/</Link>
        <Description>A pro-Palestinian group critics describe as a front for Hamas is set to win key status from a UN panel stacked with anti-Israel human rights violators, according to a watchdog group.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pro-Israel critics claim Hamas front group nearing coveted UN status
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh, (l.),  with Majed Al-Zeer, director-general of the Palestinian Return Centre. (UN Watch)
A pro-Palestinian group critics describe as a front for Hamas is set to win key status from a UN panel stacked with anti-Israel human rights violators, according to a watchdog group.
The UN Committee on Non-Governmental Organizations, a 19-member panel that includes Iran, Sudan, Venezuela, Russia and China, was to vote on granting observer status to the Palestinian Return Centre. The designation would allow the group to acquire official UN badges, full access to UN facilities and to participate in debates in New York, Geneva and Vienna.
Despite its pose as pro-Palestinian human rights group, the PRC is one of the few Palestinian advocacy groups to have been banned by Israel, on account of its deep entanglement with top leaders of the Hamas terrorist organization based in Gaza and abroad, UN Watch said in a news release.
The UK-based group was established in 1996 and claims its mission is to offer expert advice to various actors and agencies on the question of Palestinian Refugees within the context of the Nakba - The catastrophe following the forced displacement of Palestinians in 1948.
UN Watch claims the group has regularly hosted Palestinian officials, including Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh, at its annual conferences and has strong ties to top Hamas officials.
PRCs alleged ties to Hamas were detailed in an 80-page report by the Israeli-based research institute Meir Amit Intelligence and Terrorism Information Center. The study, which included photos of PRC leaders with Hamas officials, called the PRC a propaganda arm of Hamas and the Muslim Brotherhood.
Its foundation was based on rejection of the Oslo Accords, a strong denial of the right of the State of Israel to exist and the concept of the "right" of the Palestinian refugees and their descendants to return to the places abandoned in 1948, all to be used as tools to fight Israel and the peace process, the report said.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:39:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, Kurdish fighters in Syria on march against IS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/gZfcp68XO4E/</Link>
        <Description>In contrast to the Iraqi army's failures, Kurdish fighters in Syria are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes.</Description>
        <MainBody>In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, Kurdish fighters in Syria on march against IS
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
In this photo released on May 20, 2015, provided by the Kurdish fighters of the People's Protection Units (YPG), which has been authenticated based on its contents and other AP reporting, Kurdish fighters of the YPG, flash victory signs as they sit on their pickup on their way to battle against the Islamic State, near Kezwan mountain, northeast Syria. In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, in Syria Kurdish fighters are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast in recent days, under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes. (The Kurdish fighters of the People's Protection Units via AP)(The Associated Press)
In this photo released on May 16, 2015, provided by the Kurdish fighters of the People's Protection Units (YPG), which has been authenticated based on its contents and other AP reporting, Kurdish female fighters of the YPG, carry their weapons as they walk in the frontline of Kery Sabee village, northeast Syria. In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, in Syria Kurdish fighters are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast in recent days, under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes. (The Kurdish fighters of the People's Protection Units via AP)(The Associated Press)
In this photo released on May 24, 2015, provided by the Kurdish fighters of the Peoples Protection Units (YPG), which has been authenticated based on its contents and other AP reporting, Kurdish female fighters of  the YPG, carry their weapons as they prepare for a battle against the Islamic State militants near the village of Mabrouka, northeast Syria. In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, in Syria Kurdish fighters are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast in recent days, under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes. (The Kurdish fighters of the People's Protection Units via AP)(The Associated Press)
In this photo released on May 20, 2015, provided by the Kurdish fighters of the Peoples Protection Units (YPG), which has been authenticated based on its contents and other AP reporting, Kurdish fighters of the YPG stand on their vehicles on their way to battle against the Islamic State, near Kezwan mountain, northeast Syria. In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, in Syria Kurdish fighters are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast in recent days, under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes. (The Kurdish fighters of the Peoples Protection Units via AP)(The Associated Press)
In this photo released on March 23, 2015, by a militant website, which has been verified and is consistent with other AP reporting, an Islamic State militant uses his binocular as he looks to the Kurdish fighters, at a frontline near Tel Abyad town, northeast Syria. In contrast to the failures of the Iraqi army, in Syria Kurdish fighters are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast in recent days, under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes. (Militant website via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
BEIRUT  In contrast to the Iraqi army's failures, Kurdish fighters in Syria are on the march against the Islamic State group, capturing towns and villages in an oil-rich swath of the country's northeast under the cover of U.S.-led airstrikes.
As the Kurds close in on Tel Abyad, a major commercial center on the Turkish border, their advance highlights the decisive importance of combining airstrikes with the presence of a cohesive and motivated ally on the ground  so clearly absent in Iraq.
In Syria, a country now split mostly between al-Qaida-style militants and forces loyal to President Bashar Assad, the U.S. has found a reliable partner in the country's main Kurdish fighting force, known as the YPG. They are moderate, mostly secular fighters, driven by revolutionary fervor and deep conviction in their cause.
Since the beginning of May, they have wrested back more than 200 Kurdish and Christian towns in northeastern Syria, as well as strategic mountains seized earlier by IS. Along the way, they have picked up ammunition, weapons and vehicles left behind by Islamic State fighters.
The push has gotten them closer to Tel Abyad, a major avenue for commerce for the extremist group through which it smuggles foreign fighters and sells black-market oil to help fund its conquests. The city is also a key link between Turkey and the northern Syrian city of Raqqa, the Islamic State group's de-facto capital in its self-declared caliphate.
"The YPG doesn't lack a will to fight, like soldiers in the Syrian army, or soldiers in the Iraqi army who mostly fight for a salary," said Wladimir van Wilgenburg, a Middle East analyst at the Jamestown Foundation in Washington. "The YPG is much more motivated than other forces in the region, and doesn't lack cohesion and doesn't have coordination problems."
"The YPG is quite ideological, while the Syrian and Iraqi army aren't very well motivated," van Wilgenburg added.
The Iraqi military has struggled to make gains after its humiliating defeats last year, when it virtually crumbled in the face of the militant onslaught in northern Iraq. Poor training, corruption and sectarian politics have all been cited as reasons for the military's shortcomings. The U.S. spent billions of dollars training Iraqi forces from 2003 to 2011, but much of that training did not reach the foot soldiers battling the Islamic State group today.
Last week, U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter criticized the Iraqi army following the fall of Ramadi, the strategic capital of the country's largest Sunni province of Anbar, saying the Iraqi military lacked the "will to fight."
Within days, IS fighters had also dealt a major blow to Assad's forces in Syria, seizing the historic city of Palmyra, a major crossroads linking the capital, Damascus, with territory to the east and west. In images reminiscent of the Iraqi defeat in Ramadi, Syrian soldiers fled the city, leaving behind tanks and ammunition.
By contrast, Syria's Kurds have shown remarkable cohesiveness. Spurred by ideology and nationalistic fervor, they fought ferociously to claw back territory after Islamic State militants captured the Kurdish town of Kobani and dozens of surrounding villages last fall. The IS descent on Kobani led the U.S. to widen its air campaign from Iraq into Syria to assist the Kurds.
Despite the fact that IS had heavy weapons and far more fighters, the Kurds resisted the offensive on Kobani, conducting fierce street battles until the U.S. air-dropped weapons and intensified the airstrikes.
In January, the YPG liberated Kobani from the Islamic State militants and began a wide offensive in which they regained much of the territory they had lost.
On May 6, the Kurdish fighters and their allies launched an offensive from the northeastern province of Hassakeh and in less than three weeks captured the strategic Abdul-Aziz Mountain along with 221 Kurdish and Christian villages that were held by IS.
The mountain had been a key militant base for sending vehicles rigged with explosives into Kurdish areas, said Ghalia Nehme, a member of the Kurdish Women's Protection Units.
"The airstrikes were a major help for the fast advance," Nehme said, adding that 425 square miles (1,100 square kilometers) were taken from IS over the past three weeks alone.
Nasser Haj Mansour, a defense official in Syria's Kurdish region, said the YPG is in close contact with the U.S.-led coalition and sometimes asks for airstrikes targeting IS positions after its fighters locate them.
"Warplanes are not enough to liberate a region, but without the air force it will be more difficult," said Haj Mansour. "The push won't be as easy and fast."
The Kurds are now closing in on Tel Abyad with fighters moving east from Kobani and west from Hassakeh  an offensive that, if successful, would open a direct line between Kurdish-controlled territory along the border with Turkey.
Such a move is likely to anger Turkey, which sees the YPG as part of the Kurdish PKK movement that has waged an anti-government insurgency in southeastern Turkey.
"Tel Abyad is going to be the next target. We want to strangle Daesh," said Nawaf Khalil, a Kurdish official who currently heads the Europe-based Center for Kurdish Studies, using an Arabic acronym for IS.
The latest village to fall was Mabrouka on Tuesday, bringing the Kurdish force closer to Tel Abyad. The fighting has killed 532 Islamic State militants, the YPG said.
The Kurds are backed by Arab tribesmen, Assyrian Christian gunmen and members of the rebel faction known as Burkan al-Furat  Arabic for the "Volcano of the Euphrates."
U.S.-led coalition airstrikes have concentrated on areas around Kobani and Hassakeh, only rarely hitting Raqqa or other Islamic State-held areas in the Aleppo countryside.
But in mid-May activists said the U.S.-led coalition dropped leaflets on Raqqa with this warning in Arabic: "We killed many of your commanders and fighters. We can carry out raids against you anytime and anywhere, and you don't have the power to stop us and we will not stop."
"There is no doubt that the liberation of Tel Abyad, will be the pass for the liberation of Raqqa," said Idriss Naasan, a Kurdish official in Kobani.
The Islamic State group's leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, indicated as much in an audio message released earlier this month.
"The battle of Raqqa will come before the battle of Mosul," he said, referring to the Islamic State's stronghold in Iraq, which Iraqi forces have been preparing a major offensive to try to retake.
___
Associated Press writer Vivian Salama in Baghdad contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:37:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin orders all Russian military deaths be classified as state secrets</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/WnYoEG2C_Pk/</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has signed a decree to make losses of Russian troops in peacetime a secret.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin orders all Russian military deaths be classified as state secrets
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
MOSCOW  Russian President Vladimir Putin has signed a decree to make losses of Russian troops in peacetime a secret.
The decree published on the official government website and signed by Putin on Wednesday makes it a state secret to divulge information about peacetime losses of Russian troops in "special operations."
The decree comes as evidence of Russian involvement in the conflict in eastern Ukraine is mounting.
Ukraine last week captured two men who it said were Russian officers operating on the side of the separatists in eastern Ukraine. The Russian defense ministry said the two are no longer active servicemen. The two men, however, insisted in several video interviews that they were in Ukraine on their commanders' orders.
The measure brought strong criticism from Amnesty International.
"Not only is this decree a blatant attack on freedom of expression, it also has sinister undertones that will intensify speculation President Putin has something to hide - specifically losses incurred by Russia's military in Ukraine," John Dalhuisen, the organization's Europe and Central Asia director, said in a statement.
More on this...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:17:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kidnapped Nigerian girls likely being used by Boko Haram as suicide bombers, experts fear</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/CayoGul74qM/</Link>
        <Description>Fears are mounting in Nigeria that the so-called "Chibok girls" kidnapped by Boko Haram more than a year ago are being used in the Islamist terror group's stepped-up campaign of suicide bombings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Expand / Contract
These girls escaped from Boko Haram, but hundreds more are unaccounted for and may be being used as suicide bombers.(AP Photo/ Haruna Umar)
Although bombers are typically not identified by Nigerian forensics experts, national publications have published side-by-side photos of dead suicide bombers and missing Chibok girls, suggesting they are the same people. Experts believe it is highly likely.
The numbers are just not out there; but if you see what has been happening in the region, it makes sense, Scott Stewart, vice president of tactical analysis for global intelligence and advisory firm Stratfor, told FoxNews.com. Now we need the forensics to prove it.
Women and children have carried out the vast majority of recent suicide attacks, with girls between the ages of 7 and 17 years blamed for nine bombings since last July, according to the humanitarian agency.
Related Image
Expand / Contract
A young girl carried out the February suicide bombing of a bus station in the northern Nigeria city of Kano. (Reuters)
Recent attacks include a May 16 bombing at a bus station in the northeastern city of Damaturu, where a 12-year-old girl detonated an explosive device hidden underneath her clothing, killing seven and injuring 31. Last November, five people were killed and more than 30 wounded when two girls set off bombs in a crowded market in Maiduguri, the capital of Borno state.
We have never seen another Jihadi group use these many suicide bombers," Stewart said. "And as far a volume, we have never seen this many of them be young women.
Experts say Boko Haram is likely brainwashing young women into carrying out the attacks, or forcing them to endure such misery that they are willing to kill and die to escape it.
Children are not instigating these suicide attacks; they are used intentionally by adults in the most horrific way, Jean Gough, UNICEF representative in Nigeria, told FoxNews.com. They are first and foremost victims  not perpetrators.
Its not clear how many thousands of children and women have been kidnapped by Boko Haram, as new abductions have become a weekly occurrence in the northern region of Nigeria. UNICEF said it estimates that 743,000 children have been uprooted by the nearly 6-year-old Islamic uprising, with as many as 10,000 separated from their families.
Related Image
Expand / Contract
People carry an injured victim from the scene of a Feburary bomb explosion in the northeastern Nigerian city of Gombe. (Reuters/Afolabi Sotunde)
Many children have been separated from their families when they fled the violence, with no one to look after them, Gough also said in the statement. Without the protection of their families, these children are at greater risk of exploitation by adults, and this can lead to involvement in criminal or armed group activities.
Perry Chiaramonte is a reporter for FoxNews.com. Follow him on Twitter at @perrych
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
