<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:37:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Gisele Bundchen deflates out of Forbes&amp;#8217; Top 100 Most Powerful Women&amp;#8217;s List</title>
        <Link>http://latino.foxnews.com/latino/entertainment/2015/05/26/gisele-bundchen-deflates-out-forbes-top-100-most-powerful-womens-list/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Gisele Bundchen deflates out of Forbes Top 100 Most Powerful Womens List
Published May 26, 2015
Gisele Bndchen takes one last stroll down the runway
The Brazilian beauty bid farewell to the catwalk, closing out a stellar 20-year career.
Gisele Bundchen may be the worlds most famous model-entrepreneur, but it was not enough to keep her on this years list of Forbes Top 100 Most Powerful Women .
The Brazilian bombshell, who has appeared on this list since at least 2010, was one of the 19 women who were left off this year.
She was joined by the likes of Margaret Hamburg, Amy Pascal, Gail Kelly and Lady Gaga.
Bundchens drop from the top 100 list may come as a surprise to many as she has consistently been part of Forbes rankings since her rise to stardom. Yet, her position on the powerful womens list has been going down every year since she topped at 60th place in 2012.
The 34-year-old mother of two, ranked 72nd in 2010, 83rd in 2011, 95th in 2013 and 89th in 2014.
As of right now, however, Bundchen is still ranked No. 1 as the highest-paid model in the world  for the eighth year in a row.
While Bundchen, who retired from the catwalk last month , is out of the list, several other Latinas made it into the Top 100 list in 2015.
Brazilian President topped the Latinas on the list at No. 7, with Argentina President Christina Fernandez following at No. 16. Chilean President Michelle Bachelet came in at No. 27.
Colombians Sofia Vergara and Shakira remained on the list for the third year in a row, ranking in on No. 57 and No. 81, respectively.
The two beauties premiered on the list in 2012 and have remained solid contenders since then.
Forbes included singer Taylor Swift to the 2015 list, making her the youngest among these group of women.
Like us on Facebook
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:37:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Charter Communications announces $55B deal to buy Time Warner Cable</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxbusiness.com/industries/2015/05/26/charter-snags-time-warner-cable-in-55-billion-deal/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Charter Snags Time Warner Cable in $55 Billion Deal
Published May 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
(REUTERS)
Charter Communications Inc. has struck a $55 billion cash-and-stock deal for Time Warner Cable Inc., giving cable mogul John Malone the prize he has been chasing for two years.
The offer is valued at about $195 a share, a 14% premium to Time Warner Cable's last closing price. Including debt, the deal is valued at $78.7 billion.
Shares of Charter gained 3.2% to $181 in premarket trading, while Time Warner's shares gained 11.3% to $190.50 a share.
The acquisition by Charter, which is backed by Mr. Malone's Liberty Broadband Corp., would vault the cable operator into the ranks of the biggest U.S. broadband and pay-television companies.
The deal comes only a month after Time Warner Cable went back on the block after Comcast terminated the companies' planned $45.2 billion merger in the face of serious pushback from Washington regulators. A Charter-TWC deal could be in for a stringent review in Washington as well, some analysts have said.
As part of the transaction, Charter will also merge with small operator Bright House Networks. The combined cable giant would have 23 million total customers, second only to Comcast's 27 million among cable operators.
Charter, which has 5.9 million residential subscribers in more than 25 states, and Mr. Malone are betting that increased scale will help the company navigate the industry's choppy waters. Operators must contend with the onset of cable "cord-cutting" as frustrated consumers drop connections, the rise of streaming-video competitors from Netflix Inc. to Apple Inc. and expected fights with TV-channel owners over which networks are worth keeping in a bundle.
"No one has ever had a better sense of the multichannel world than John" Malone, said Leo Hindery, a veteran cable-industry executive who is managing partner at the private-equity firm InterMedia Partners. "Obviously he sees in Charter and Time Warner Cable a way to perpetuate a legacy that is unrivaled."
In 2013, Charter made multiple offers to buy Time Warner Cable but was rebuffed. Its efforts culminated in a hostile bid early last year that was headed off when Comcast struck its ill-fated TWC deal.
This time, Charter took a more light-handed approach. Mr. Malone got more involved, people familiar with the matter say, calling Time Warner Cable Chief Executive Rob Marcus in the early stages of Charter's pursuit to indicate he wanted a friendly deal. Charter's camp made a point of not submitting a lowball bid that would put off Time Warner Cable, the people said.
Time Warner Cable shareholders can choose $100 a share in cash and about $95 in Charter stock, or $115 in cash and the remainder in stock. The price tag represents a 14% premium to Time Warner Cable's closing price of $171.18 on Friday.
If regulators block the deal, Charter could owe Time Warner Cable about $2 billion, or Time Warner Cable could be responsible for the breakup fee if it accepts an offer from a rival suitor, a person familiar with the matter said. Comcast's deal with Time Warner Cable had no breakup fee.
The backlash to Comcast's bid for Time Warner Cable at the Federal Communications Commission and Justice Department left many cable executives and investors wondering whether any transformational cable-industry deal could withstand regulatory review.
FCC Chairman Tom Wheeler called cable executives including Time Warner Cable's Mr. Marcus and Charter CEO Tom Rutledge in recent days to convey that they shouldn't assume the agency is against any and all future deals just because of what happened with Comcast, according to a person familiar with the matter.
Liberty will help fund the deal by buying $5 billion of new Charter shares, and Mr. Malone's stake in the combined entity will fall below 25%.
Mr. Malone will be joined as a significant shareholder by the Newhouse family. When Charter originally agreed to buy Bright House before the Time Warner Cable deal was reached, the transaction would have given the Newhouse family, which controls Bright House owner Advance/Newhouse, a larger equity stake than Mr. Malone but a smaller voting stake.
Liberty will probably still retain a larger voting stake in the agreement for the bigger entity, said Craig Moffett, an analyst with MoffettNathanson.
For Mr. Malone, the deal would mark his return as a force to be reckoned with in U.S. cable, putting him in a position to influence how the industry transitions into a media world dominated by streaming video and broadband. Since taking a big stake in Charter in early 2013, he has been preaching the gospel of consolidation to investors, emphasizing how cable operators aren't collaborating the way they used to in the early days of the industry and are therefore missing out on opportunities to fight back against Netflix and other competitive threats. The 74-year-old was a formative figure in the early days of the cable industry. He took over debt-ridden Tele-Communications Inc. in his early 30s, guiding it through a period of uncertainty and through hundreds of acquisitions in the 1970s and 1980s that made it the largest U.S. cable-TV operator.
In 1998, he sold TCI at its height for $48 billion to AT&amp;T and turned his attention to investments in Europe.
AT&amp;T later sold its cable assets to Comcast.
Along the way, Mr. Malone developed a reputation for ruthless negotiating with lenders and TV programmers--former U.S. senator Al Gore labeled him "Darth Vader." He tangled with lawmakers in congressional hearings over rising rates and customer-service complaints. He also fought with municipalities over the renewal of "franchises" allowing TCI to offer service, sometimes taking them to court.
But at pivotal moments for the cable industry--such as when the government enacted laws governing the business in 1984 and 1992 and when broadcasters and cable channels began demanding a slice of monthly fees--he was also viewed as a leader and champion for cable operators' interests.
The cable-TV market that Mr. Malone and others raced to build at a breakneck pace is now fully mature--and it has actually begun to contract. Consumers frustrated by rising cable-TV prices are dropping service in favor of relatively inexpensive streaming-video services.
Now, Mr. Malone will be tested at another crucial moment for cable. The new colossus formed by the merger of Charter and Time Warner Cable would be far bigger than TCI's 11 million subscribers and would face very different challenges.
"There are lots of challenges this time around but there is no better visionary to address them," said Mr. Hindery, who ran TCI for Mr. Malone for many years.
To be successful in the coming years, cable operators will need to lean heavily on their broadband businesses to generate profit growth while limiting shrinkage in their TV business. That means investing in broadband infrastructure, streaming video services and other technologies.
For Time Warner Cable, the pact with Charter continues a wild ride over the past two years. The company was struggling last year with video-subscriber losses and other problems, and Comcast's $45.2 billion buyout looked like a good exit for shareholders. Then the surprising turn of events in Washington left the company in the lurch--only to result in what looks like another deal in short order.
A combined Comcast-TWC would have served about 35 million residential and business Internet customers. It also would have had at least 57% of the market for broadband Internet service, defined by the FCC as speeds of 25 megabits a second and higher. A Charter-TWC-Bright House combination would serve nearly 20 million residential and business Internet customers.
Before a deal was struck, competition threatened to once again derail the plans of Charter and Mr. Malone: European telecommunications group Altice SA, backed by French cable baron Patrick Drahi, was in hot pursuit of Time Warner Cable in recent days. Mr. Drahi met with Mr. Marcus on May 20 to discuss a potential cash-and-stock deal, The Wall Street Journal reported.
Now that Charter and Time Warner Cable have agreed to a price as high as $195 a share, Altice doesn't plan to submit a higher offer, according to people familiar with the matter.
For Altice, a deal the size of TWC would have been a bold move just days after the company surprised investors with its agreement to buy a 70% stake in U.S. midsize cable operator Suddenlink in a deal valued at $9.1 billion including debt.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ray McDonald: Who's to blame?</title>
        <Link>http://video.foxnews.com/v/4258118205001/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Live
Mark Hulme: Bears fell to temptation in signing Ray McDonald
May. 26, 2015 - 4:55 - Co-Founder of National Fantasy Football Convention on what led the Chicago Bears to think signing Ray McDonald was a good idea
Fox Business Channel Finder
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>5 weight loss tricks</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/health/2015/05/26/5-really-simple-new-rules-for-weight-loss/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>5 really simple new rules for weight loss
By Ellen Seidman
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
The news is bloated with information on weight lossbut as it turns out, there are some simple key rules to keep in mind. Researchers at Tufts University looked at more than 16 years of data from 120,000 men and women who were included in three long-term studies.
According to their results, which were published in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, these are the things that might help you drop pounds for good, and keep them off:
1. Load up on low-glycemic foods
Diets with a high glycemic load (GL)think refined grains, starches, and sugarswere linked to more weight gain. The reason: Foods that rank high on the glycemic index can cause rapid spikes in blood sugar and a resulting surge in insulin, the hormone that helps the body use or store blood sugar. While thats not a new finding, past research hasnt shown how an inflated GL relates to weight gain over time.
RELATED: 10 Easy Ways to Slash Sugar from Your Diet
2. Eat more of these protein-rich foods
Boosting consumption of yogurt, seafood, skinless chicken and nuts best helped stave off extra weight, researchers observed. The more people downed, the fewer pounds they gained.
3. Dont worry so much about full-fat dairy
An increase in eating full-fat cheese and whole milk did not relate to weight gain or weight loss. In fact, when people consumed more low-fat dairy productions, they increased their consumption of carbs, which may promote weight gain, primary study author Jessica Smith, PhD, said in a statement. This suggests that people compensate, over years, for the lower calories in low-fat dairy by increasing their carb intake.
RELATED: 30 Healthy Foods That Could Wreck Your Diet
4. Balance your meals
Researchers also examined the relationship between protein-rich foods and GL of the diet. They discovered that decreasing GL by eating red meat (commonly linked to weight gain) with veggies (instead of with, say, refined white bread) helped offset gain. And when people ate more eggs and cheese in combination with lower glycemic foods, participants lost weight (while combining them with high glycemic foods was linked to weight gain).
5. Quit obsessing over calories
All of the aforementioned tactics matter more. Most interestingly, the combination of foods seems to make a big difference, senior author Dariush Mozaffarian, MD, DrPH, in a statement. Our study adds to growing new research that counting calories is not the most effective strategy for long-term weight management and prevention.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>March wants Flay's winnings?</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/05/26/bobby-flay-and-stephanie-march-reportedly-feuding-over-horse-race-winnings/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Bobby Flay and Stephanie March reportedly feuding over horse race winnings
Published May 26, 2015
Actress Stephanie March and her husband, chef Bobby Flay, attend the amfAR Inspiration Miami Beach Party at Soho Beach House in Miami Beach, Florida December 6, 2012.(Reuters)
There was a lot of horsing around in Stephanie March and Bobby Flay 's marriage.
The Law and Order: SVU actress, 40, reportedly claims Flay kept the money earned from a race horse given to her as a fourth wedding anniversary present back in 2009.
March says Flay, 50, pocketed the horses winnings totaling $130,000, according to TMZ .
But it doesnt end there, she also accuses the chef of pocketing $60,000 earned from selling the horse as well.
Flay apparently has affinity for the race track, his other horse named America, won him $65,550 back in December .
The former couple has been fighting over terms of their decade-old prenuptial agreement which gives March $5,000 a month and a $1 million buyout for their former home.
More on this...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What did Kaley do now?</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/slideshow/2015/05/26/fox411-celeb-pic-day/#/slide/kaley-cuoco-pink-instagram-eyebrows</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FOX411's star snaps of the day
What are those kooky celebs up to now?
FoxNews.com
http://www.foxnews.com/
Kaley dyes her eyebrows
Kaley Cuoco-Sweeting shocked fans with her pink hair , and the actress took her look to the next level when she debuted wacky pink eyebrows over Memorial Day weekend.
Instagram
kaley-cuoco-pink-instagram-eyebrows
Natalie Portman
Natalie Portman caused a stir in Cannes. The actress' cheeky dress raised eyebrows when Portman turned around to reveal her black underwear underneath the sheer "Black Swan"-inspired dress.
AP/Reuters
natalie-portman-dress
Hannah Davis
The Sports Illustrated cover girl is ready for the summer. The new face of OP's summer line , showed off her bikini body in one of the collections' two-pieces. Oddly enough for someone so celebrated for cavorting in a bikini, Davis says that actually she prefers one-piece suits.
OP
hannah-davis-op
Kelly Bensimon
Kelly Bensimon stepped out looking exhausted in NYC's Soho neighborhood. The reality star had bags under her eyes with her brunette locks loose and natural. Click here for more pictures of Bensimon on X17online.com .
X17
kelly-bensimon-days
Cindy Crawford and Kaia Gerber
Cindy Crawford walked the red carpet at the premiere of "Tomorrowland" with her mini-me daughter by her side. Can you believe Kaia is only 13?
Getty
cindy-crawford-tomorrowland
Danica McKellar
Danica McKellar dared to bare in a strange outfit at the LA Premiere of "Where Hope Grows" held at Arclight Cinemas Hollywood. The actress' grey outfit, while flattering, failed to impress especially coupled with a black hat. McKellar should seek a new stylist pronto!
AP
danica-mckellar-outfit
Eric Decker and Jessie James Decker
Eric Decker plants one on his very pregnant wife Jessie James Decker. The couple, who recently announced they are having a boy, couldn't seem to keep their hands off of each other at the iHeartRadio Country Festival this weekend.
Getty on behalf of iHeartMedia
jessie-james-decker-iheart
Vanessa Milano, Nick Lachey and Sarah Hyland
The stars put on their Kentucky Derby best this weekend. Sarah Hyland, of "Modern Family," and Vanessa Milano along with her husband Nick Lachey looked Southern chic in their formal spring attire while signing a three-liter bottle of G.H.MUMM, the official champagne of the Derby, for charity.

derby-stars
Kate and Oliver Hudson
Too close for comfort? Kate Hudson and her brother Oliver shared a smooch on the lips after enjoying lunch together. The siblings are close, but the awkward kiss couldn't help but give us the creeps. Click here for more pictures of the smooching siblings on X17online.com .
X17
kate-hudson-oliver
Salma Hayek
Salma Hayek looked sultry in silver at the screening of "The Prophet" in Beirut. The actress turned director showed off her curves in the glamorous gown as she celebrated the film that was inspired by the book that helped Hayek to explore her relationship with her late Lebanese grandfather.
Reuters
salma-hayek-silver
Kaley Cuoco
Kaley Cuoco changed up her hairdo yet again. "The Big Bang Theory" actress showed off her new hair color on Instagram. "Have wanted to do this for years! Finally went pretty in pink!" she wrote . Click here to see what all the stars are up to on Instagram.
Instagram
kaley-pinkhair-instagram
Kate Hudson
Kate Hudson rang in her 36th birthday looking like one hot mess. The mom-of-two threw a "hot mess"-themed party to celebrate with her friends and she definitely dressed the part. Jewelry designer and wife of actor Toby McGuire, Jennifer Meyer, also joined in on the fun as she celebrated her 38th.
Instagram
kate-hudson-hot-mess-party
Cindy Crawford
Cindy Crawford donned a sexy black dress for date night with her equally handsome hubby Rande Garber. The two spent their evening dining with Jim Belushi at Craig's Restaurant in West Hollywood. Click here for more pictures of the couple on X17online.com .
X17
cindy-crawford-date-night
Melissa Joan Hart
Melissa Joan Hart rang in her 39th birthday with her family by her side. The actress, her husband and their three kids enjoyed the Caribbean sun at Generations Riviera Maya by Karisma. The family-orientated former child star couldn't think of a better way to celebrate.
mjh-family-vacation
Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox
Reunited and it feels so good! Former "Friends" costars Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox goofed around at a screening of the film "Just Before I Go" in Los Angeles. Click here for more pictures of the star on HollywoodLife.com .
Getty
jennifer-aniston-courtney-cox
Sadie Robertson
Sadie Robertson walked the camouflage carpet at the premiere of the "Duck Commander Musical" in Las Vegas. The " Dancing With the Stars " runner up looked stunning in an elegant teal dress.
Getty
sadie-duck-commander-musical
Crystal Hefner
Hugh Hefner's wife Crystal showed off her DJing skills at Coachella while guests enjoyed Caffeinated Club at the Influential House in Rancho Mirage, CA this weekend. The 28-year-old couldn't help but add some Playboy flare to her headphones.
The Influential House
harris-playboy
Rebel's raunchy style
Rebel Wilson shows off her racy outfit at the MTV Movie Awards at the Nokia Theatre on Sunday, April 12, 2015, in Los Angeles.
AP
rebel-wilson-mtv-awards-ap
Jennie Garth and Dave Abrams
Jennie Garth is off the market! The 43-year-old actress celebrated her birthday at the Dreams Tulum Resort &amp; Spa in Mexico with her love Dave Abrams. The couples' reps confirmed their engagement to People Thursday. Click here for more pictures of the happy couple on vacation on X17online.com.
X17
jennie-garth-dave-abrams
Kate Hudson
Kate Hudson is ready for spring! The mom-of-two was spotted looking flawless in a low-cut floral dress picking up fresh juice. Click here for more pictures of Hudson from X17online.com .
X17online.com
kate-hudson-x172
Ireland Baldwin in hospital
Alec Baldwin's daughter tweeted the hospital picture above on April 3 and wrote "appendicitis swag thanks for all of your concern."

ireland-baldwin-hospital
Deborah Ann Woll
The "True Blood" actress has ditched her red locks for a lighter look. Woll showed off her new blond do at the premiere of the Netflix original series "Marvel's Daredevil" in Los Angeles. Tell us which look you prefer on Twitter @FOX411 .
AP/Reuters
deborah-ann-woll-hair
Katy Perry
Katy Perry showed off her pup Butters at the premiere screening of "Katy Perry: The Prismatic World Tour" in Los Angeles.
Reuters
katy-perry-puppy
Joanna Krupa
Krupa, of "Real Housewives of Miami" fame is ready for summer in a little white dress. The 35-year-old enjoyed dinner in West Hollywood while showing off her new shorter hairdo. Click here for more photos of the Polish beauty from X17online.com .
X17
krupa-white-dress
Christina Hendricks
Christina Hendricks shocked fans when she ditched her famous red locks for a blonde due in her new Clairol ad. The actress, who plays Joan Holloway on "Mad Men," has been a redhead for 20 years but it looks like she was ready for a change.
Reuters/Instagram/Clairol
hendricks-change
Chrissy Teigen
Justin Bieber might have been the one getting roasted, but it was Chrissy Teigen that looked smoking at the Comedy Central event. She posed in a sultry, black dress at the Sony Studios in Culver City, California.
Reuters
chrissy-teigen-roast
Taylor Swift
Ouch! Taylor Swift's cat Meredith gave the singer a nasty scratch on her leg. The "Blank Space" singer poked fun at reports that she had her legs insured for $40 million dollars by saying , "Great work Meredith. I was just trying to love you and now you owe me 40 million dollars." Photos: Stars and their adorable pets
Instagram
taylor-swift-cat-scratch
Sean Penn and Charlize Theron
Charlize Theron and Sean Penn looked like a happy couple at the premiere of his new movie "The Gunman." The couple of one year have gotten serious very quickly with reports that Penn plans to adopt Theron's son, Jackson. The actor recently said he could see himself marrying the South African native .
Reuters
theron-penn
Lindsay Lohan
Lindsay Lohan went a little overboard with Photoshop in a new Instagram pic. The actress wrote, "My feet look red lol- had to take that out. Only real red is my hair." Perhaps she was trying to distract from her obvious Photoshop fail?The area behind her behind appears to be totally warped and her fans called her out for the editing. "Biggest Photoshop fail of all time," one user commented.
Instagram
linday-lohan-photoshop-fail
Matthew Lewis
Neville Longbottom is all grown up! A new picture of British actor Matthew Lewis, who got his start as the nerdy and adorable "Harry Potter" character, is setting the Internet on fire. His "Harry Potter" costar Emma Watson shared the pic of Lewis as a hunky solider in BBC Three's "Bluestone 42." Matt's definitely left his awkward stage behind.
Reuters/BBC Three
matthew-lewis-grown-up
Jared Leto
Is that you Jared Leto ? The musician and actor made a drastic change to his look. Leto channeled his inner Draco Malfoy by chopping off his long locks and dying them platinum blonde.
Instagram/Twitter/Reuters
jared-leto-hair
Michael Richards, Jason Alexander and Jerry Seinfeld
It's a (mini) "Seinfeld" reunion! While they were short one Julia Louis-Dreyfus, "Seinfeld" stars (from left) Michael Richards, Jason Alexander and Jerry Seinfeld were reunited for a good cause. The actors met up Wednesday for a charity event to benefit Baby Buggy. It's great to see the crew back together again after 17 years.
Getty
seinfeld-reunion
Jessie James Decker
Jessie James Decker announced over Instagram that she's got another bun in her oven! The country singer gave birth just under a year ago to her first child, Vivianne, with husband Eric Decker. "Vivianne is so excited because she is going to be a big sister! We are over the moon about having another baby!!!" she wrote.
Instagram
jessie-james-decker-pregnant
Miranda Lambert, Gwen Sebastian and RaeLynn
Miranda Lambert and her tour mates got matching tattoos in Tulsa over the weekend. The country queen (l), her backup vocalist Gwen Sebastian (c) and opening act RaeLynn (r) debuted their new ink on Instagram. "Inked in perfect harmony," Lambert wrote with a picture of their new musical note tattoos. PICS: Seeing Double? Stars Who Have the Same Tattoos
Instagram
miranda-raelynn-gwen-tattoo
Chrissy Teigen
Chrissy Teigen debuted a new look on Instagram. The model traded in her lighter locks for a dark brown. She snapped a pic of her new do and coupled with her intense eyeliner, it made for a scary snap. MORE: Chrissy's shocking Oscars confession
Instagram
chrissy-teigen-brown-hair
Lisa Rinna
Lisa Rinna displayed some diva behavior when she visited New York City this week. The "Real Housewives of Beverly Hills" star had a friend carry her over the snow because she didn't want to mess up hers shoes. Click here for more pictures of Rinna from X17online.com .
X17
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dairy Queen shockers</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/leisure/2015/05/26/things-didnt-know-about-dairy-queen/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Things you didn't know about Dairy Queen
By Dan Myers
Previous Next
Dairy Queen is one of those chains thats impossible to dislike. The chain that put not only soft-serve ice cream but also the legendary Blizzard on the map has thousands of locations across the globe, and new openings are still treated as special occasions. But even if youve got your perfect Blizzard order down pat, we bet that there are still some things you didnt know about this legendary chain.
Dairy Queen got its start with an ice cream store in Moorehead, Minnesota, owned by a man named Sheb Noble. When his friend John Fremont Grandpa McCullough and McCulloughs son Bradley convinced him to start selling soft-serve in 1938, the guys realized that they were onto something after more than 1,600 servings were sold in two hours. Two years later the trio opened the first Dairy Queen in Chicago suburb Joliet, and they never looked back.
Dairy Queen is truly as American as apple pie, and the company brings that distinctly American style of cuisine and service around the globe. Read on for 10 things that you most likely didnt know about this beloved chain, and the next time you order a cup of that soft serve, remember that theres more than 80 years of history behind it.

1.&amp;nbspThe First Location Is a City-Designated Landmark
iStock
Even though it hasnt been a Dairy Queen since the 1950s, the first location, at 501 North Chicago Street in Joliet, is landmarked.
2.&amp;nbspThe founders also invented soft serve
Dairy Queen
The concept of soft serve was developed in 1938 by John Fremont McCullough and his son Bradley. They partnered with ice cream shop owner Sheb Noble to open the first Dairy Queen in Joliet, Illinois, in 1940.
3.&amp;nbspIt Was a Pioneer of Franchising
AP Photo
Not many restaurants were selling franchise rights in the 1940s, but Dairy Queen used that strategy to expand from 10 stores in 1941 to 100 stores in 1947 and 1,600 by 1955.
4.&amp;nbspDairy Queen Owns Orange Julius
Dairy Queen
Dairy Queen purchased the chain, best known for its namesake orange-flavored drink, in 1987. Many locations now also offer Orange Julius items.
5.&amp;nbspThe Blizzard Was Inspired by a St. Louis Shop
Dairy Queen
Ted Drewes is a famous frozen custard shop located in Route 66 in St. Louis, a local landmark since the 1930s. The shop is best known for its concretes, in which frozen custard is blended with any of dozens of ingredients. DQ took its inspiration from this legendary creation, as did Shake Shack, who calls their creations concretes in homage.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Best (and worst) beach bods</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/slideshow/entertainment/2015/05/26/celeb-beach-bodies-best-worst-bella/#slide=1</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ancient aqueduct found</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/science/2015/05/26/2000-year-old-water-supply-systemuncovered-injerusalem/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>2,000-year-old water supply systemuncovered inJerusalem
By Denise Chow
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
The 13-mile-long aqueduct carried water into Jerusalem.(Assaf Peretz, courtesy of the Israel Antiquities Authority)
Part of an ancient aqueduct built more than 2,000 years ago to transport water into the city of Jerusalem was uncovered during a recent construction project, according to the Israel Antiquities Authority.
A section of the so-called Lower Aqueduct was discovered in the modern-day neighborhood of Umm Tuba, in East Jerusalem, during efforts to construct a new sewer line. The Lower Aqueduct was originally built more than 2,000 years ago by kings in the Hasmonean dynasty, who ruled Judea and its surrounding regions from about 140 B.C. to 37 B.C., and preceded King Herod the Great.
The sprawling, 13-mile-long aqueduct carried water to the capital, and "operated intermittently until about 100 years ago," Ya'akov Billig, director of the aqueduct excavation with the Israel Antiquities Authority (IAA), said in a statement . [ The Holy Land: 7 Amazing Archaeological Finds ]
The Lower Aqueduct fed from the En Eitam spring, which is located near three ancient reservoirs known as Solomon's Pools that are about 3 miles southwest of Bethlehem. As water passed through the channel, it flowed down a gentle slope to Jerusalem, passing through the modern-day neighborhoods of Umm Tuba, Sur Bahar, East Talpiot and Abu Tor, according to the IAA.
"At first, the water was conveyed inside an open channel, and about 500 years ago, during the Ottoman period, a terra cotta pipe was installed inside the channel in order to better protect the water," Billig said.
For nearly 2,000 years, the Lower Aqueduct remained one of Jerusalem's principal sources of water, IAA officials said, which is why city rulers kept the structure so well preserved. About 100 years ago, the channel was replaced by an electrically operated water-distribution system.
The Umm Tuba section of the aqueduct was uncovered by workers at Gihon Company Ltd., who are constructing the new sewer line. Archaeologists at the IAA conducted an excavation of the site following its discovery, but the remains have since been covered up again to preserve the structure and prevent any damage, agency officials said.
Other sections of the extensive aqueduct have been uncovered in the past, including in the Armon Ha-Natziv tunnels in the City of David, on the Sherover promenade in southern Jerusalem and around the Sultan's Pool along the west side of Mount Zion in Jerusalem, IAA officials said.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ceres &amp;#8216;bright spots&amp;#8217; mystery</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/science/2015/05/26/ceres-bright-spots-still-shrouded-in-mystery/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Ceres bright spots still shrouded in mystery
Published May 26, 2015
This image is part of a sequence taken by NASA's Dawn spacecraft May 16 2015.(NASA/JPL-Caltech/UCLA/MPS/DLR/IDA)
The mysterious spots on Ceres shine brightly in NASAs latest images of the dwarf planet.
The images, taken by NASAs Dawn spacecraft from 4,500 feet above Ceres, provide the closest view yet of the planets surface. Taken on May 16 and released by NASA on May 20, the images clearly show the group of bright spots that have been mystifying scientists.
NASA has even invited the public to give their thoughts on the spots via an online poll .
An earlier set of images , taken by Dawn on May 3 and 4, revealed that the brightest spots in a crater within Ceres northern hemisphere are actually composed of many smaller spots. While the exact nature of the spots is unknown, scientists believe that they may be caused by ice.
An animation produced by NASA also showed a sequence of Ceres images taken during Dawns first mapping orbit. Dawn will enter its second mapping orbit June 9, circling Ceres every three days at a distance of 2,700 miles. The spacecraft will remain at that distance until June 30, when it will make its way to lower orbits.
During the second mapping orbit, which is also known the survey orbit, the spacecraft will comprehensively map Ceres' surface, according to NASA. It will also assess whether Ceres is geologically active.
NASAs Dawn spacecraft successfully entered Ceres ' orbit March 6, making history as the first mission to achieve orbit around a dwarf planet. Scientists hope that NASAs investigation of Ceres will boost our understanding of how the solar system formed.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amazing catch goes viral</title>
        <Link>http://video.foxnews.com/v/4257863866001/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>High school star's incredible one-handed catch goes viral
May. 26, 2015 - 0:06 - Raw video: 16-year-old Marco Wilson has no shortage of college suitors
Fox Business Channel Finder
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
