<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:13:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy holds funeral for 13 migrants recovered from April shipwreck that killed up to 800</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/gcGelpZwb30/</Link>
        <Description>Italian officials have held a funeral for 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy holds funeral for 13 migrants recovered from April shipwreck that killed up to 800
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Ismail Bouchnafa, vice president of the Sicilian Islamic Community, third left, and Archbishop of Catania Salvatore Gristina, second left, attend the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Archbishop of Catania Salvatore Gristina delivers his speech during the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Catania Mayor Enzo Bianco delivers his speech during the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Ismail Bouchnafa, vice president of the Sicilian Islamic Community, center, Archbishop of Catania Salvatore Gristina, third left, and Catania Mayor Enzo Bianco, left, attend the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
CATANIA, Italy  Italian officials have held a funeral for 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April.
The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy.
Among those who attended the ceremony on Tuesday in Catania were the mayor of the Sicilian city, Enzo Bianco, and Bouchnafa Ismail, vice president of the Sicilian Islamic Community.
Premier Matteo Renzi has pledged that Italy would do everything possible to try to bring up the bodies. Survivor accounts and undersea examination indicate that hundreds were crammed inside the hold of the smuggler's fishing boat, which capsized when rescuers aboard a nearby container ship approached in waters off Libya on April 18.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:05:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN rights chief worried by breadth of China security law</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/a3LhRxPRjVo/</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN rights chief worried by breadth of China security law
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
BERLIN  The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.
Zeid Raad al-Hussein said Tuesday that the National Security Law "raises many concerns due to its extraordinarily broad scope coupled with the vagueness of its terminology and definitions."
He added in a statement that "it leaves the door wide open to further restrictions of the rights and freedoms of Chinese citizens, and to even tighter control of civil society by the Chinese authorities than there is already."
The new legislation reinforces government controls over cyberspace and covers a wide range of other areas including the economy, social stability, territorial integrity, the military, culture, finance, technology, the environment and food safety.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:02:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN human rights chief raises concern over breadth, vagueness of China's new security law</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/HlViTNSje3Q/</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN human rights chief raises concern over breadth, vagueness of China's new security law
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BERLIN  The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.
Zeid Raad al-Hussein said Tuesday that the National Security Law "raises many concerns due to its extraordinarily broad scope coupled with the vagueness of its terminology and definitions."
He added in a statement that "it leaves the door wide open to further restrictions of the rights and freedoms of Chinese citizens, and to even tighter control of civil society by the Chinese authorities than there is already."
The new legislation reinforces government controls over cyberspace and covers a wide range of other areas including the economy, social stability, territorial integrity, the military, culture, finance, technology, the environment and food safety.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:46:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisian govt says some limits on freedoms needed to ensure security</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/-gHpr8gAQCI/</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's government is urging its citizens to sacrifice some of their freedoms to better protect the country from attacks like the mass shooting at a beach resort last month that killed 38 people, mostly tourists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisian govt says some limits on freedoms needed to ensure security
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
TUNIS, Tunisia  Tunisia's government is urging its citizens to sacrifice some of their freedoms to better protect the country from attacks like the mass shooting at a beach resort last month that killed 38 people, mostly tourists.
Government minister Kamel Jendoubi on Tuesday defended the president's decision to impose a state of emergency Saturday in response to the June 26 attack, fearing new extremist violence. As Tunisia's Parliament resumes debate on an anti-terrorism law, Jendoubi told reporters "we must accept ... that some limits must exist to face these threats."
Rights groups have said some measures in the new law  such as long detention periods and a broad definition of terrorism  could threaten the freedoms gained in Tunisia's Arab Spring uprising and its ensuing transition to democracy.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:39:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HSBC staff sacked over mock ISIS beheading video</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/lTLgz1PjQb8/</Link>
        <Description>Six staff from Britain's biggest bank have been sacked after a video appeared online showing them taking part in a mock Islamic State style killing.</Description>
        <MainBody>HSBC staff sacked over mock ISIS beheading video
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Six staff from HSBC were fired after a video appeared online showing them taking part in a mock Islamic State style killing.
Six staff from Britain's biggest bank have been sacked after a video appeared online showing them taking part in a mock Islamic State style killing.
The footage is believed to have been taken during a team-building day and showed the workers dressed in overalls and balaclavas at a go-karting center.
They were seen staging a beheading scene with five of them laughing and joking as a colleague in an orange jumpsuit knelt at their feet.
One clutched a coat hanger, apparently as a fake knife, while another held the man in the jumpsuit by the shoulders.
According to The Sun newspaper a worker shouted "Allahu Akbar" - meaning God is greatest in Arabic.
An HSBC spokesman said: "We do not tolerate inappropriate behavior.
"As soon as The Sun brought this video to our attention we took the decision to sack the individuals involved.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:29:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jewish officials protest art installation at Polish museum</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/a1M-SemUjzo/</Link>
        <Description>Jewish officials are furious over a video installation at a Polish museum that shows naked men and women playing a game of tag in a gas chamber.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jewish officials protest art installation at Polish museum
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
WARSAW, Poland  Jewish officials are furious over a video installation at a Polish museum that shows naked men and women playing a game of tag in a gas chamber.
Efraim Zuroff, director of the Simon Wiesenthal Center in Jerusalem, called the exhibit at the Museum of Contemporary Art in Krakow "so offensive and so disgusting that we found it necessary to protest."
"Game of Tag," made in 1999 by Polish artist Artur Zmijewski, has for years been accused of violating the dignity of Holocaust victims.
In response to protests, the museum put it behind an enclosure with a warning.
But Zuroff and other Jewish officials say it isn't enough. He said it is "simply incomprehensible" that the video is being shown in Poland, where Nazi Germany killed millions of Jews and non-Jews.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:17:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>civilian death toll from conflict in Yemen rises to more than 1,500, over 3,600 injured</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/jz1PJLxhlmU/</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations' human rights office says the number of civilians killed in three months of violence in Yemen has risen above 1,500.</Description>
        <MainBody>civilian death toll from conflict in Yemen rises to more than 1,500, over 3,600 injured
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BERLIN  The United Nations' human rights office says the number of civilians killed in three months of violence in Yemen has risen above 1,500.
The U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights said Tuesday that, between June 17 and July 3, at least 92 civilians were killed and another 179 injured.
It said that brings the total number of civilians killed since March 27 to 1,528, while 3,605 have been injured.
Yemen's fighting pits Houthi rebels and troops loyal to the former president against southern separatists, local and tribal militias, Sunni Islamic militants and loyalists of President Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi, who is now based in Saudi Arabia.
The rebels seized the capital, Sanaa, in September. In March, a Saudi-led coalition began launching airstrikes against the rebels and their allies.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:36:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>German prosecutors ask for 3½ years in prison for 94-year-old former Auschwitz guard</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/mcNgzpKRigk/</Link>
        <Description>German prosecutors are asking for 3½ years in prison for a 94-year-old former SS sergeant who served at the Auschwitz death camp in Nazi-occupied Poland.</Description>
        <MainBody>German prosecutors ask for 3 years in prison for 94-year-old former Auschwitz guard
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Former SS officer Oskar Groening , 94, sits in the courtroom in Lueneburg , northern Germany, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Groening is charged with 300,000 counts of accessory to murder on allegations he helped the Auschwitz Nazi death camp function by sorting cash and valuables seized from Jews. (Philipp Schulze/Pool Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Former SS officer Oskar Groening , 94, sits in the courtroom in Lueneburg , northern Germany, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Groening is charged with 300,000 counts of accessory to murder on allegations he helped the Auschwitz Nazi death camp function by sorting cash and valuables seized from Jews. (Philipp Schulze/Pool Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Former SS officer Oskar Groening , 94, sits in the courtroom in Lueneburg , northern Germany, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Groening is charged with 300,000 counts of accessory to murder on allegations he helped the Auschwitz Nazi death camp function by sorting cash and valuables seized from Jews. (Philipp Schulze/Pool Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
BERLIN  German prosecutors are asking for 3 years in prison for a 94-year-old former SS sergeant who served at the Auschwitz death camp in Nazi-occupied Poland.
Oskar Groening has admitted guarding prisoners' baggage after they were unloaded from cattle cars onto the camp's ramps, and collecting and counting money stolen from the new arrivals and sending it to Berlin.
The dpa news agency reported prosecutors said in closing arguments Tuesday that his role helped the camp function, and he should be convicted of 300,000 counts of accessory to murder for those killed while he was there.
When his trial began in April, Groening said he felt moral guilt but it was up to the court to decide if he was legally guilty of a crime.
A verdict is expected this month.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:12:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek coast guard searches for up to 21 missing migrants after boat sinking in Aegean</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/Tnt06svtK5s/</Link>
        <Description>Greek authorities have launched a search and rescue operation in the eastern Aegean after a sailboat carrying dozens of migrants sank between the small islands of Agathonisi and Farmakonisi, near the Turkish coast.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek coast guard searches for up to 21 missing migrants after boat sinking in Aegean
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ATHENS, Greece  Greek authorities have launched a search and rescue operation in the eastern Aegean after a sailboat carrying dozens of migrants sank between the small islands of Agathonisi and Farmakonisi, near the Turkish coast.
The Greek coast guard said six people were rescued by a Greek helicopter, and another 10 by the Turkish coast guard while between 17 and 21 people were missing after the boat sank Tuesday.
Those rescued by the Turkish crews said there had been between 33 and 37 people on board. It was not clear why the boat sank, or what the migrants' nationalities were.
Tens of thousands of migrants have made their way from the Turkish coast to Greek islands so far this year, hoping to make their way to more prosperous European Union countries.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:09:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latest bomb blast blamed on Boko Haram kills 20 in northern Nigerian university town of Zaria</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/hDLp8t57zrc/</Link>
        <Description>The state governor says a bomb blast in Nigeria's northern university town of Zaria has killed 20 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Latest bomb blast blamed on Boko Haram kills 20 in northern Nigerian university town of Zaria
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
LAGOS, Nigeria  The state governor says a bomb blast in Nigeria's northern university town of Zaria has killed 20 people.
Gov. Nasir el-Rufai of Kaduna state is urging citizens to avoid crowded public places including mosques and churches as Islamic extremists Boko Haram extend the breadth and tempo of attacks that have killed some 300 people in a week.
El-Rufai used Twitter to report Tuesday's "terrorist bomb attack." Local media said the explosion occurred at the government headquarters as civil servants were assembling for a training course.
Nigeria's police force announced increased security around mosques and churches after Boko Haram bomb and shooting attacks Sunday killed more than 60 people in a mosque and posh Muslim restaurant in central Jos city and at an evangelical Christian church in northeastern Potiskum town.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
