<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FATAL RIDE? Freddie Gray reportedly suffered broken neck while in cop van</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/05/01/many-questions-still-remain-in-death-freddie-gray/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Freddie Gray's fatal injuries reportedly may have been caused by impact with bolt in police van
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
The fatal broken neck Freddie Gray suffered, apparently while riding in the back of a Baltimore police van last month, may have been caused when his head hit a bolt inside the vehicle, according to local reports citing sources familiar with a police report now in the hands of state prosecutors.
Sources familiar with the report said the medical examiner found the injury that caused Gray's death a week later, on April 19, was likely caused when he slammed his head into the interior wall of the police transport van and that his head injury reportedly matched a bolt in the back of the van. That explanation could jibe with a fellow passenger's account in a police affidavit that Gray was thrashing around in an effort to injure himself, although that witness went on the city's CBS affiliate to say his words were taken out of context and that he now fears for his life after his statement was used to bolster the police version of events.
The Medical Examiner's Office declined to comment on this open investigation and said it does not release preliminary findings. State officials are reviewing the report and determining whether there is sufficient evidence to charge as many as six police officers who were involved in Gray's arrest and transport. Gray's lawyer has said the 25-year-old's spine was nearly severed, but results of an autopsy, like the police report, remained under wraps. That has fueled frustration and suspicion in the community, where peaceful protests devolved into rioting and looting, culminating in a night of chaos on Monday.
"The transparency is just not there," the Rev. Cortly "C.D." Witherspoon said after Police Commissioner Anthony Batts refused to answer any questions Thursday.
An explosive Washington Post report on Wednesday night that said the witness riding in the back of the van heard Gray banging against the interior of the van also came into question, as that witness, Danta Allen, who had been arrested for allegedly stealing a cigarette, told WJZ he doesnt believe Gray was trying to hurt himself.
When I was in the back of that van it did not stop or nothing," Allen said. "All it did was go straight to the station, but I heard a little banging, like he was banging his head, Allen said.  I didnt even know he was in the van until we got to the station.
Among the few details officially released from the report in a brief press conference Batts conducted Thursday was the revelation that the police van made a previously undisclosed stop, one of three stops made while transporting Gray to a hospital. The mystery stop was captured by a privately-owned security camera, and could be crucial to the police investigation into Gray's death.
Although Gray was reportedly shackled to the bed of the van by leg irons, police sources told ABC affiliate WJLA that he was standing, without a seat belt on. Just over a week prior to Gray's arrest - for running from police who tried to stop him, the Baltimore Police Department issued a new policy making it obligatory to buckle in all inmates being transported in police vans.
Batts said his departments report was delivered a day ahead of time to the States Attorney Marilyn Mosby, and the commissioner said any questions about it should go to her.
Mosby decline to speak publicly Thursday as she issued a statement asking for "for the public to remain patient and peaceful and to trust the process of the justice system."
Last week, Batts said the additional passenger who was picked up along the way had told investigators the driver did not speed, make sudden stops or "drive erratically" during the trip, and that Gray was "was still moving around, that he was kicking and making noises" up until the van arrived at the police station.
Other than the chronology of events, police have not discussed any evidence, details or statements from the six suspended officers.
"I understand there are questions people want to have answered, but unfortunately, we can't release any more about it," Capt. J. Eric Kowalczyk said.
The forensic pathologists who studied Gray's body for clues also aren't making official statements.
Bruce Goldfarb, a spokesman for the Maryland State Medical Examiner's Office, told The Associated Press on Thursday that the office has completed Gray's autopsy, but the forensic investigation is still in process and no conclusions have been sent to police or prosecutors. When the report is complete, Goldfarb said, a copy will be sent to the Baltimore State's Attorney's Office.
"The autopsy has been done, it only takes about two and a half hours," Goldfarb said. "The autopsy is only one part of the forensic investigation. The whole point is to determine cause and manner of death, and there are lab tests and lots of other things that have to be done."
Legal experts and the Gray family lawyers say secrecy is appropriate at this point in the probe, when it's still possible that some witnesses haven't been questioned, or even found.
"By releasing too many details, you run the risk that witnesses' testimony will change to mirror the details you have released," said David Weinstein, a former federal prosecutor now in private practice in Miami. He said investigators must verify or corroborate much of the information they receive, and meanwhile the public could be misled that the probe is leading to a particular outcome.
Investigators are facing the challenge of determining whether an officer acted reasonably in the death of a civilian. Investigators cannot simply force officers to give statements because that would mean their testimony is coerced and would not hold up in court, Weinstein said.
If they are compelled to give a statement as a condition of their employment, you cannot then use those statements against them in a criminal proceeding," he said. "This is where the decision to grant immunity comes into play."
The Gray family's lawyers sought to dispel the idea that the police report would be made public at this point.
"This family wants justice, and they want justice that comes at the right time and not too soon," attorney Hassan Murphy said Wednesday.
Meanwhile, protesters over Grays death continue to spread across the nation. Aside from gatherings in Baltimore, demonstrations spread into Philadelphia and New York Thursday.
Philly.com reports that Philadelphia police made three or four arrests after hundreds of protesters marched through the city to show support for Gray.
More demonstrations are planned through the weekend.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LUNCH OLDER THAN THEM?  6-year-old meat reportedly served to Tenn. students</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/05/01/6-year-old-meat-reportedly-served-to-tennessee-students/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>6-year-old meat reportedly served to Tennessee students
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Meat dating back to 2009 was reportedly served to students in one Tennessee school district.
Students in Hawkins County were served a 6-year-old pork roast that had been frozen and then thawed, according to WCYB.
"I'm disappointed the school system let this happen," Hawkins County Commissioner Michael Herrell told the station after learning about the outdated pork. "To me, if we've got meat that old, I don't understand why."
"These high schoolers know when to not eat something, but elementary schoolers -- do they know if meat is bad or not?" Herrell said.
WATE.com reported that school officials called for a special meeting to discuss the issue that affects nearly all of the cafeterias in the county. The roasts were all supplied by the same vendor, the report said.
USDA guidelines state that uncooked meat should not be frozen for more than 12 months.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PLANE DUMB  LAX police left dynamite near museum after training</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/05/01/stick-dynamite-left-out-by-los-angeles-airport-police-after-training/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Stick of dynamite left out by Los Angeles airport police after training
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
A live stick of dynamite was accidentally left on an old plane at an airport museum for four days, a law enforcement officer at Los Angeles International Airport said Thursday.
The official, who spoke to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because the person was not authorized to speak publicly, said workers on the tarmac found the dynamite Tuesday when they noticed the bright colors on the stick.
The stick was left behind after a Saturday training exercise for K9 officers and their dogs who work at the airport. Though live, the dynamite would have required a detonator or explosive to be set off.
Sgt. Belinda Joseph, a spokeswoman, said the object was a training aid and "there was a certain amount of TNT contained in it" but denied that it was a stick of dynamite.
She said airport police are investigating and have notified the Transportation Security Administration.
The stick was checked out from a TSA explosive storage container for training.
The stick was left in a compartment underneath the Spirit of Seventy Six plane, the official said. The plane was featured at the Flight Path Learning Center and Museum on the airports southern edge.
The plane is outside the museum and is run by volunteers and frequently hosts school groups and other visitors.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>THE FALL GUY? Christie ally reportedly to cop Bridgegate guilty plea</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/05/01/former-christie-ally-reportedly-set-to-plead-guilty-amid-bridgegate-probe/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Former Chris Christie ally expected to plead guilty in Bridgegate probe
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
A pal and political ally of New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie is expected to plead guilty Friday for his alleged role in causing gridlock on the George Washington Bridge in 2013, in what Christie's opponents say was retaliation against a local mayor who did not endorse Christie's re-election.
David Wildstein, a Christie appointee who was director of interstate capital projects for Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, which operates the bridge, is expected to enter the guilty plea at a New Jersey federal courthouse Friday morning, where he is on trial for his alleged role in the scandal that has dogged the New Jersey governor and possible Republican presidential candidate.
Bloomberg News, citing a person close to the matter, reported that the decision by Wildstein may signal that he is cooperating with prosecutors in the probe. A guilty plea from Wildstein would be the first conviction in the scandal that put the outspoken Garden State governor under intense scrutiny that some believed hurt his presidential hopes. A separate investigation ordered by Christie and conducted by a law firm with ties to him determined that he played no role in the affair.
The federal investigation was launched after two of the three access lanes to the bridge in Fort Lee were shut down for four mornings in September 2013, causing massive delays.
The simmering scandal erupted a year ago, with the disclosure of an email from Christie's deputy chief of staff, Bridget Kelly, to Wildstein. It read, "Time for some traffic problems in Fort Lee." Wildstein's reply was, "Got it."
By the time that email was made public, Wildstein had already resigned, as had Bill Baroni, Christie's top appointee to the Port Authority. The governor fired Kelly and cut ties with Bill Stepien, his two-time campaign manager, amid the scandal.
Christie, the chairman of the Republican Governors Association and an active GOP fund-raiser, has not announced that he will run for the 2016 Republican presidential nomination, but has been widely viewed as a potential candidate. Christie has launched a political action committee that allows him to pay for travel and a staff, for a presidential run.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FRENZY AT UN  'THEY'RE SO RUDE' NK diplomats storm out of UN after spat with defectors</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/05/01/north-korean-diplomats-storm-out-un-after-spat-with-defectors/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>North Korean diplomats storm out of UN after spat with defectors
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
April 30, 2015: A North Korean defector, left, yells to try and drown out a statement being read by North Korean diplomats, right, during a panel on North Korean human rights abuses, at United Nations headquarters.(AP)
North Korean diplomats stormed out of a U.S.-organized event on the countrys human rights at the United Nations Thursday after they insisted on reading a statement of protest, amid shouts from defectors.
The U.S. ambassador to the U.N., Samantha Power, tried to quiet the diplomats at the end that featured more than 20 North Korean defectors. Power called the countrys statements totally self-discrediting.
The North Korean diplomats did not comment as they stormed out of the chamber following Ri Song Chois statement in protest of the event, even as North Korean defectors stood and shouted in their faces.
Nuclear-armed North Korea has been on the defensive since a groundbreaking U.N. commission of inquiry detailed vast human rights abuses in the country. North Korea has continuously referred to defectors who cooperated with the inquiry as human scum.
Defectors stood up and shouted in Korean as Power and others called for calm and a U.N. security team assembled. An observer who speaks Korean said the shouts included "Shut up!" ''Free North Korea!" ''Down with Kim Jong Un!" and "Even animals know to wait their turn."
"There is no need for a microphone," Power said as one North Korean diplomat persisted in reading out a statement that referred to "ungrounded allegations" and "hostile policy" toward his country. A microphone was briefly turned on for the diplomats.
Power continued: "Please shut the mike down because this is not an authorized presentation. ... Please ensure that the microphone is not live. ... We are calling U.N. security."
As soon as the North Korean diplomat stopped his speech and the next defector stepped up, the North Korean diplomats walked out.
"They're so rude," Jay Jo, a North Korean defector, said later, adding that she wished that the diplomats had stayed so she could have spoken with them. The U.S. said North Korea had been informed before the event that it would have a chance to speak.
The brief chaos came minutes after U.N. Assistant Secretary-General for Human Rights Ivan Simonovic told the audience that North Korea had shown "new signs of engagement" on human rights issues in recent months.
But after the uproar, South Korean Ambassador Oh Joon told the crowd that "we thought there was a glimmer of hope ... but the delegation of the DPRK today disappointed us. I think it's a pity." He was referring to the country's official name, the "Democratic People's Republic of Korea."
International pressure last year led the U.N. Security Council to place the issue on its agenda of matters of international peace.
As the event came to a close, Power said the true weapons of mass destruction in North Korea was the tyranny of its government against its citizens.
Power also called on countries in the region, particularly China, to stop sending North Koreans seeking asylum back into the country, which was one of the inquiry's concerns. China did not allow the commission of inquiry to visit China for its work.
"What is most striking here is not North Korea's attempt to chill speech, but that its increasing willingness to export its policies, including the Sony Pictures hack, to the U.S," said Daniel Aum a fellow with the Robert F. Kennedy Human Rights who attended the event.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Navy to accompany US-flagged ships in Persian Gulf after Iran seizes vessel - Danish shipper: Iran's seizure of cargo ship could be related to 2005 case - VIDEO: Navy to escort US ships through Strait of Hormuz, official says </title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/us-navy-to-accompany-us-flagged-ships-in-persian-gulf-after-iran-seizes-vessel/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>US Navy to accompany US-flagged ships in Persian Gulf after Iran seizes vessel
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
U.S. Navy ships will begin to accompany U.S. flagged commercial ships as they travel the Strait of Hormuz, a defense official confirmed to Fox News, on the heels of Iran seizing a cargo ship.
The Obama administration is closely monitoring Iran's takeover of the ship, as it involved a Marshall Islands-flagged vessel. The Marshall Islands and the U.S. have a longstanding security agreement, and officials said Thursday the two nations are in contact.
But, in a clear response to that incident, a defense official said the U.S. Navy will now accompany all U.S.-flagged ships going through the area.The move is the latest development in a high-stakes chess match in the region, with the Iran nuclear talks continuing to play out in the background.
The Navy makes a distinction between accompanying ships and escorting them. Officials told the AP the Navy won't technically escort these ships but will let them know in advance that they will monitor the situation as they transit the narrow Strait from the Persian Gulf toward the Arabian Sea.
The Navy already has dispatched a guided-missile destroyer, the USS Farragut, to the region. Pentagon spokesman Col. Steve Warren said Wednesday the destroyer is "keeping an eye on things," and in close enough proximity to the seized ship that they "will be able to respond if a response is required."
When pressed on what kind of incident aboard the ship would elicit a U.S. Navy response, he was vague, saying: "These [U.S. military] assets give commanders options." He said he didn't know "what the possibilities are," and the U.S. government is "in discussions with the Marshall Islands on the way ahead."
More on this...
Why did Iran seize cargo ship?
Earlier this week Iranian naval vessels reportedly fired warning shots near the Marshall Islands-flagged cargo ship and detained it and its crew. Iranian officials say the Maersk shipping line owes it money.
Maersk Line, the Danish shipper that chartered the cargo vessel, acknowledged in a written statement that the reason for stopping the ship could be related to a 2005 cargo case.
Maersk Line spokesman Michael Storgaard said the company learned Thursday that an Iranian appeals court had ruled Maersk must pay $3.6 million for a 10-container cargo delivered a decade ago on behalf of an Iranian company in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. However, the cargo never was collected, according to Storgaard, adding it eventually was disposed of by local authorities.
"As we do not have the details of the ruling, we are not able to comment hereon, nor at this point speculate on our options," Maersk Line said of the latest ruling.
"Our paramount concern remains the safety of the crew and the safe release of the vessel. We will continue to do everything we can to resolve this matter with the relevant Iranian authorities."
Storgaard told The Associated Press that the ship and crew aren't theirs. MV Maersk Tigris, operated by Rickmers Ship Management in Singapore, was boarded on Tuesday.
Cors Radings, a spokesman for Rickmers, told Fox News that as of Thursday, there has been no change in the status of the ship and her crew, and that the company has not spoken with the crew in the past 24 hours.
The Marshall Islands -- officially known as the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and a former U.S. trust -- enjoy "associate state" status with the United States, meaning the U.S. agrees to defend the islands, and provide economic subsidies and access to federally funded social services. The U.S. initially gained military control of the Marshall Islands from Japan in 1944.
According to the State Department, "The security compact between the United States and the Republic of the Marshall Islands gives the U.S. authority and responsibility for security and defense matters that relate to the Marshall Islands, including matters related to vessels flying the Marshallese flag."
Fox News' Lucas Tomlinson and The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>2 Kentucky boys charged after bringing guns to elementary school</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/05/01/2-kentucky-boys-charged-after-bringing-guns-to-elementary-school/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>2 Kentucky boys charged after bringing guns to elementary school
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
April 30, 2015: In this photo provided by Kentucky State Police, handguns sit on a table.(AP)
A first-grade student and his brother in kindergarten brought two handguns to school, one of them loaded, on a bus to a Kentucky elementary school Thursday after apparently mistaken them for toys, authorities said.
Police said no one was hurt and the firearms were seized when the boys reached school.
The boys, ages 6 and 7, had a gun each in their school backpacks and showed them to other students on the bus to Dewitt Elementary School in Flat Lick, Kentucky State Police Trooper Shane Jacobs said Tuesday. Jacobs said one student alerted a teacher and the school was placed on lockdown briefly.
"We never felt that the kids' intent was to hurt anyone at the school," Jacobs said by phone. "We feel the kids didn't know that they were actually a firearm. They thought they were toy guns."
Each boy has been charged with possession of a firearm on school property, Jacobs said.
"Due to the seriousness of a firearm being brought to a school, state police felt like charges had to be filed," he told The Associated Press.
Local prosecutor Jackie Steele said the boys cases were expected to be handled as juvenile court matters. Investigators are still trying to determine how the boys obtained the guns.
The boys' parents face charges in the case, as does the school bus driver, Jacobs said.
The parents have been charged with endangering the welfare of a minor, police said. They were released, but the boys were placed with grandparents, police said.
The bus driver was arrested at the elementary school and charged with facilitation to unlawfully possess a weapon on school property, state police said. The driver was told by a student about the guns on the bus but failed to alert school staff or stop the vehicle to check for weapons, police said. He was being held in a jail Thursday.
The boys were questioned by investigators but did not understand the seriousness of the incident.
In a letter to the parents of children at the school, Knox County schools Superintendent Kelly Sprinkles said the school staff acted quickly once they were alerted.
"At no time do we feel that students were in danger, Sprinkles said. "This was a violation of state law; therefore the students involved will be subject to school board policy and appropriate laws that govern weapons on school property."
The superintendent urged parents to discuss the incident with their children, to check their kids' backpacks regularly and to emphasize that it's illegal to bring weapons to school.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US envoy responds to Turkish mayor who called State's Marie Harf 'stupid blonde'</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/05/01/us-envoy-hits-back-with-humor-at-turkish-mayor-who-called-american-official/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>US envoy hits back with humor at Turkish mayor who called American official 'stupid blonde'
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ISTANBUL  The U.S. ambassador to Turkey is fighting back with humor after Ankara's mayor called a U.S. state department spokeswoman a "stupid blonde."
John Bass posted a picture on his Instagram account with his normally dark hair digitally altered to a reddish blond. The caption said: "American Diplomats: We Are All Blonde."
Ankara Mayor Melih Gokcek had taken to social media to go after State Department spokeswoman Marie Harf for criticizing Turkish police tactics during demonstrations.
Earlier this week, Gokcek posted a tweet with an image of police in Baltimore forcibly subduing someone during the recent unrest with a caption that said: "Where are you stupid blonde, who accused Turkish police of using disproportionate force?"
The Tweet included a picture of Harf and said: "Come on blonde, answer now."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NASA&amp;#8217;s Messenger spacecraft crashes into Mercury - Amazon CEO's space company launches first unmanned test flight</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/science/2015/04/30/nasas-messenger-spacecraft-crashes-into-mercury/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>NASAs Messenger spacecraft crashes into Mercury
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
An artist's impression of the Messenger spacecraft is shown flying over Mercury's surface displayed in enhanced color.(Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory/Carnegie Institution of Washington)
Messenger, NASAs Mercury-orbiting spacecraft, reached the end of its historic 11-year mission Thursday when it crashed into the little planet closest to the sun.
The spacecraft, which was out of fuel, slipped out of orbit and slammed into Mercury at 3:26 p.m. ET, according to mission controllers at the Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory (APL) in Laurel, Md.
Messenger slammed into Mercurys surface at about 8,750 mph, according to NASA, creating a new crater on the planets surface. The crater is estimated to be as wide as 50 feet.
Mission control confirmed end of operations at 3:40 p.m. ET, when no signal was detected by NASAs Deep Space Network (DSN) station in Goldstone, Calif., at the time the spacecraft would have emerged from behind the planet.
Because Messenger hit the side of Mercury facing away from the earth, ground-based telescopes were unable to capture the moment of impact. Mercury's proximity to the Sun, which could damage optics, also meant that space-based telescopes were unable to pick up the crash.
At 3:16 p.m. ET, the mission's @MESSENGER2011 Twitter account had tweeted: "Well I guess it is time to say goodbye to all my friends, family, support team. I will be making my final impact very soon."
At 3:23 p.m. ET @MESSENGER2011 tweeted "#thatsmessenger" and an image of Mercury's surface, with the message "Messenger's last act? That's smashing!"
 MESSENGER (@MESSENGER2011) April 30, 2015
Messenger made history in March 2011 when it became the first probe to orbit Mercury.
The crash ended a successful mission for Messenger, which was launched in August 2004. The spacecraft has undertaken extensive mapping of Mercury during its journey, and has sent a slew of data on the planet back to earth. Messenger, for example, found vast troves of sulfur on the planets surface. The probe also discovered that Mercury's internal magnetic field is offset from the planets center, and verified its polar deposits are dominantly water ice.
Messengers original goal was to take 2,500 images of the planet, but it has returned more than 270,000 to earth.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama picks Chicago to host his presidential library</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/obama-picks-chicago-to-host-his-presidential-library/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obama picks Chicago to host his presidential library
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Apr. 20, 2015: President Barack Obama speaks at Anacostia Library in Washington as he participates in a live "virtual field trip" with middle school students to announce two initiatives to improve education through digital connectivity. (AP)
WASHINGTON  President Barack Obama has chosen his hometown of Chicago to host his future presidential library, two individuals with knowledge of the decision said Thursday, placing the permanent monument to his legacy in the city that launched his improbable ascent to the White House.
Obama's library will be built on Chicago's South Side, where the University of Chicago has proposed two potential sites not far from the Obama family's home. It was unclear which of the two sites had been selected, but officials were expected to make an announcement within weeks.
The decision brings to a close a hard-fought competition that kicked off in the earliest days of Obama's second term. From an initial list of about a dozen proposals, the Barack Obama Foundation chose four universities to vie for the library. In recent months it became increasingly clear that the Obamas were leaning toward the University of Chicago, the elite private school where Obama taught law before becoming president.
The University of Chicago's victory marks a harsh letdown for the other three schools on the short list: The University of Hawaii, New York's Columbia University and the University of Illinois at Chicago, a public school that proposed building the library on Chicago's West Side.
Still, the president has signaled that the library may be only one component of the post-presidential project; presidential libraries often have accompanying policy institutes, presidential centers or museums. Obama has signaled an interest in spending time in New York and Hawaii after leaving the White House, and individuals familiar with the decision said Obama was likely to base other types of programming at the universities that lost out on the library itself.
The presidential library is expected to cost hundreds of millions of dollars to build and serve as an economic engine for the surrounding area.
Obama's decision to place the library in Chicago was conveyed to The Associated Press by two individuals with direct knowledge of the decision. Both spoke on condition of anonymity because the decision has yet to be publicly announced.
Obama's foundation, the University of Chicago and the White House all declined to comment.
Although the Obamas had intended to announce the winning site by the end of March, a messy confluence of Chicago politics and Obama's busy schedule led to multiple delays.
After Chicago Mayor Rahm Emanuel, Obama's former chief of staff, failed to win enough votes in his March re-election to avoid a runoff, the foundation opted to hold off on a final decision until the runoff vote in April, the AP reported. The library had become a potent issue in the mayoral race as Emanuel worked to secure access to the land where the University of Chicago wanted to build.
The foundation's chairman, Obama's close friend and Chicago businessman Marty Nesbitt, spoke with the president earlier in the week about the announcement, individuals familiar with the conversation said. But a news conference that had been scheduled for Wednesday to announce the decision was postponed at the last minute, and is now expected to be rescheduled for mid-May.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Winston, Mariota picked first and second in NFL draft</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/sports/2015/04/30/winston-mariota-picked-first-and-second-in-nfl-draft/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Winston, Mariota picked first and second in NFL draft
Published April 30, 2015
This split shows Jameis Winston posing with a Tamp Bay Buccaneers cap and NFL football, left, and former Oregon quarterback Marcus Mariota, right. (AP)
CHICAGO  You don't pass up a potential franchise quarterback.
Not in today's pass-happy NFL.
So Jameis Winston is headed to Tampa Bay as the first overall selection and Marcus Mariota goes to Tennessee at No. 2. They'll take their Heisman Trophies (Winston in 2013, Mariota last year) and try to turn two downtrodden franchises into contenders, maybe even champions.
It was the sixth time since 1967 that quarterbacks went 1-2, and this was no surprise. The biggest question was whether Florida State's Winston had too much off-field baggage for the Bucs. Obviously not.
His college coach, Jimbo Fisher, has no doubts either.
"There are always bumps in the road," Fisher said. "But as far as on the field, he'll learn. He has an unbelievable ability to learn and learn fast.
"Off the field he's an extremely great guy. People will be shocked with how he represents (the Bucs)."
Some questioned Mariota having barely taken any snaps behind center in Oregon's quick-tempo attack, but Titans coach Ken Whisenhunt, who has done big things with such veteran quarterbacks as Ben Roethlisberger, Kurt Warner and Philip Rivers, clearly isn't concerned.
"He's a talented young man who has a very good feel for the position and how to process those things," Whisenhunt said, "and we're excited to get a chance to work with him."
Winston and Mariota each had a year of eligibility remaining. So did the next two picks, when linebacker Dante Fowler Jr. of Florida headed upstate a bit to Jacksonville, then Oakland grabbed Alabama wide receiver Amari Cooper.
The first senior taken was Iowa tackle Brandon Scherff by Washington in the fifth spot, a bit of a surprise.
Tampa has the receivers to help Winston in Vincent Jackson and Mike Evans, both of whom went over 1,000 yards last year despite shoddy quarterbacking. Tennessee can't make the same claim.
Each of those teams went 2-14 in 2014, but coaches Lovie Smith and Whisenhunt, in their first seasons in charge, survived the awful record. Now, they presumably have the main building tool.
After Scherff, the Jets, normally heavily cheered when the draft was held in New York -- it's in Chicago for the first time since 1965 -- were loudly booed when they went on the clock. And when they went for Southern Cal DT Leonard Williams, rated by some as the best overall player in this crop, the jeers increased exponentially.
Why? Because the Bears were next up and need a dynamic player at the position.
Still, the local team was cheered as if Jay Cutler had just thrown for a TD when it grabbed West Virginia's game-breaking receiver, Kevin White. After trading top wideout Brandon Marshall to the Jets, the Bears had a big void there.
Dan Quinn, the Falcons' new coach after he helped build Seattle's dynamic defense, got a nice tool in Clemson linebacker Vic Beasley. The Giants selected Miami offensive tackle Ereck Flowers and St. Louis finished off the top 10, in which there were no trades, by taking Georgia running back Todd Gurley, who comes off a major knee injury.
The pick drew some reactions of disbelief from the crowd; no RBs went in the first round of the past two drafts.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House approves compromise GOP budget that targets ObamaCare</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/house-approves-compromise-gop-budget-that-targets-obamacare/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House approves compromise GOP budget that targets ObamaCare
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
The House has adopted a compromise GOP budget that promises to speed repeal of the new health care law while channeling a 7 percent budget hike to the Pentagon.
The 226-197 vote sends the non-binding budget plan to the Senate for a vote next week. It promises to balance the budget in nine years with more than $5 trillion in spending cuts, though Republicans make clear they aren't interested in actually imposing controversial cuts to programs like Medicare, food stamps, Pell Grants or the traditional Medicaid program with follow-up legislation.
Instead, the House-Senate budget framework increases defense spending in the near term by padding war accounts by almost $40 billion next year. Senate Republicans blocked a House plan to dramatically rewrite Medicare for future retirees.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IRS takes steps to stop targeting of conservative groups, report says</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/irs-takes-significant-steps-to-stop-targeting-conservative-groups-report-says/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>IRS takes steps to stop targeting of conservative groups, report says
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
March 22, 2013: This file image shows the exterior of the Internal Revenue Service building in Washington. (AP)
The IRS has taken "significant actions" to stop agents from targeting political groups based on their names and policy positions, according to a report issued Thursday by the government watchdog who disclosed the inappropriate activity two years ago.
The agency's inspector general says the IRS is doing a better job of processing applications for tax-exempt status. His report said the IRS has eliminated intrusive, unnecessary questions, and has cleared a backlog of applications that had languished for months and years.
The IRS has improved training for agents, the report said, although the inspector general recommended even more training.
The report is a follow-up to the inspector general's 2013 audit, which said agents had inappropriately singled out tea party and other conservative groups for extra scrutiny when they applied for tax-exempt status during the 2010 and 2012 elections.
The 2013 audit blamed poor management. It ignited a firestorm that led to numerous congressional investigations and the replacement of much of the agency's top management.
John Koskinen, a former turnaround specialist, was confirmed as the new IRS commissioner in December 2013. He has vowed to restore trust in the agency, though he has sparred with Republican lawmakers over the IRS budget and the agency's efforts to cooperate with congressional investigations.
Most of those investigations continue, including another one by the inspector general looking into thousands of lost IRS emails that could be related to the tea party controversy.
"The IRS has taken significant actions in response to the recommendations made in" the 2013 report, said J. Russell George, the Treasury inspector general for tax administration.
The 2013 audit found that agents were singling out groups with "tea party" or "patriot" in the name. They also singled out groups that talked about "limiting/expanding government, educating on the Constitution and Bill of Rights, social economic reform/movement," the audit said.
These terms appeared on "be on the lookout" lists that agents used when scrutinizing applications for tax-exempt status under section 501 (c) (4) of the federal tax code, which is for social welfare groups.
Some progressive and liberal groups also faced long delays in having their applications processed, and several progressive terms appeared on the "be on the lookout" lists. However, investigators have said it does not appear that progressive groups faced the same level of scrutiny as conservative ones.
George said the IRS no longer uses these lists.
The IRS issued a statement saying it appreciates the inspector general's "acknowledgement of the significant actions we took" to address the recommendations in the 2013 audit.
The American Center for Law and Justice, which represents dozens of conservative groups that say they were harassed by the IRS, dismissed Thursday's report.
"To suggest that the unlawful IRS targeting scheme has somehow been resolved is not accurate," said Jay Sekulow, chief counsel at ACLJ.
Despite the report, Sekulow said, "The IRS still remains institutionally incapable of self-correction. No one has been held accountable. And the unconstitutional targeting continues, with one of our clients still waiting  after more than five years  for a determination on their application."
The inspector general said 296 groups were originally singled out for extra scrutiny. Among them, 215 have had their applications approved and seven have been rejected. A total of 36 withdrew and 27 stopped responding to IRS inquiries, the report said.
Of the remaining 11, six have sued the IRS and five are appealing an "adverse" ruling as part of the agency's internal appeals process, the report said.
The scandal erupted just as many of these so-called social welfare groups were playing a bigger role in electoral politics. Unlike other charitable groups, social welfare groups can participate in political activity, but it can't be their primary mission.
Donations to these groups are not tax deductible. But groups can keep the names of their donors private.
It is up to the IRS to determine whether a group qualifies as a social welfare group.
The Treasury Department is in the process of drafting new rules for these groups. Treasury's first stab at new rules was criticized by both conservatives and liberals, generating a record 150,000 comments.
The department pulled the rules back last year and decided to try again. It is unclear when new rules will be unveiled.
Thursday's report was limited to assessing how well the IRS has implemented recommendations from the inspector general's 2013 audit. The inspector general is also investigating thousands of lost emails to and from a central figure in the controversy.
The IRS said it lost an untold number of emails by former IRS official Lois Lerner, who led the division that processes applications for tax-exempt status. The IRS said the emails were lost when Lerner's computer hard drive crashed in 2011.
The inspector general's office is in the process of trying to recover more than 6,000 of Lerner's lost emails that were found on old backup tapes. The IG is expected to issue a report after its work is complete.
Lerner has since retired from the IRS. Last year, the House voted mostly along party lines to hold Lerner in contempt of Congress for refusing to answer questions a pair of committee hearings. In March, Ronald Machen, the outgoing U.S. attorney for the District of Columbia, announced that the Justice Department won't seek criminal contempt charges against Lerner.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sea lion pup rescued after wandering on streets of San Francisco</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/05/01/sea-lion-pup-rescued-after-wandering-on-streets-san-francisco/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Sea lion pup rescued after wandering on streets of San Francisco
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
April 30, 2015: This photo provided by The Marine Mammal Center shows a stranded sea lion pup lying next to a car on a San Francisco street.(AP)
A sea lion pup that was released earlier this year after being nursed back to health was found wandering on a San Francisco sidewalk Thursday and was captured by marine rescuers.
Video from the Marine Mammal Center in nearby Sausalito shows the male sea lion, nicknamed Rubbish, hiding under a car and trying to scurry away from rescuers. They eventually got a net around it and move it into a crate, taking it back to the center.
KTVU reports that a veterinarian noticed the sea lion, which was rescued in February. Then, the sea lion was treated for pneumonia and malnutrition. The animal weighed just 30 pounds when it was rescued.
After spending five weeks on its own, it lost 17 pounds. Veterinarians at the marine center will examine the sea lion and see if it has any other health issues that caused it to restrand.
The San Francisco Chronicle reports experts at the center have released 159 sea lions back into the wild this year.
Marine Mammal Center officials said the sea lion is just one of thousands of California sea lion pups that have stranded along the states coast this year as a result of warm waters that have affected food availability.
The Associated Press contributed to this report
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3 teens to be tried as adults in rock maiming of teacher</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/04/30/3-teens-to-be-tried-as-adults-in-rock-maiming-teacher/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>3 teens to be tried as adults in rock maiming of teacher
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
LEWISBURG, Pa.  A judge ruled Thursday that three teenagers will be tried as adults in a rock-throwing incident last summer that severely harmed an Ohio schoolteacher who watched the daylong pretrial hearing as she wore a plastic helmet to protect her still healing injuries.
Judge Michael Sholley said he was not willing to put them back into the juvenile system, where they would age out in less than three years, when an adult could get as much as 25 years for the most serious charges they face. Now 18, they were 17 last July when a rock was dropped from an Interstate 80 overpass and crushed the head of Sharon Budd of Uniontown, Ohio.
Budd said she agreed with the judge's decision and noted she never saw defendants Keefer McGee, Dylan Lahr or Tyler Porter look her in the eye.
The court proceedings were "saddening and sickening," said Budd, who faces a seventh surgery in the coming months. "It's hard to hear all that. I just think that when you're 17 or 18 years old, you know consequences of your actions."
The defense called psychologists and a psychotherapist  one testified in private  as they argued the defendants were good candidates for rehabilitation and that jail or prison time would do more harm than good.
Psychologist John Kelsey said Porter seemed to understand the seriousness of the crime and predicted that with treatment there would be no chance of something similar happening again.
Anthony Butto, McGee's psychotherapist, said he had a strong family and had expressed sorry and empathy for Budd.
"Putting someone like Keefer McGee in jail would almost guarantee that something bad is going to happen to him," Butto said. "He's not going to be a good person coming out."
Lahr's psychologist, who did not appear in open court, said Lahr faces a set of challenges and recommended he be sent to a treatment facility, said his lawyer, Bruce Manchester.
"The impact on the Budd family is horrific. No ifs, ands or buts. Horrific. That is a major consideration to be taken in by the court. But that I submit has to be balanced off against what is going to take place with or without the court's intervention," Manchester said, noting all three defendants are likely to be out of custody eventually.
Sholley said that if it wasn't for modern medicine, the three defendants would probably have been facing some sort of homicide charges instead of aggravated assault.
A fourth defendant, Brett Lahr, who was 18 at the time, began serving jail time earlier this month even though Sholley hasn't yet accepted his no contest plea to a conspiracy charge. The prosecutor said that could happen in June.
Budd's husband Randy, who supported the judge's decision, said after the hearing that punishment "can be a very good fix."
"And after the punishment, they always have the opportunity for rehabilitation if that didn't do it," Randy Budd said.
The four were arrested shortly after the nearly 5-pound rock crashed through the windshield of the vehicle in which the Budds had been riding. They were driving through Pennsylvania, late at night, on their way to see a show in New York.
Sharon Budd has required intensive treatment and a series of surgeries to address severe brain injuries and massive damage to her skull. She said Thursday she has begun to ponder an eventual return to the classroom  she taught middle school language arts before the attack.
During a preliminary hearing in August, McGee testified for the prosecution that he and the other three planned to do some damage but did not anticipate they would cause the injuries that Sharon Budd suffered.
Union County District Attorney Pete Johnson said that despite the juvenile court request, McGee has continued to cooperate with prosecutors.
The defendants face charges of aggravated assault, conspiracy, trespassing, propelling missiles into occupied vehicles, agricultural vandalism and reckless endangerment.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kid interviewer to Obama: 'I think you've sort of covered everything about that question'</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/05/01/kid-interviewer-cuts-obama-off-i-think-youve-sort-covered-everything/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>April 30, 2015: President Obama, sitting next to 6th-grader Osman Yaya, a student at Bennett Middle School in Salisbury, Md., speaks at Anacostia Library in Washington.(AP)
President Obama participated in a virtual field trip with students Thursday.
Well, everybodys had writers block, he explained to the kids, talking to them extensively about writing.Even the best writers, its usually not that good the first time you write it.
And then the student interviewer, Osman Yaha, cut him off: I think youve sort of covered everything about that question, he said smoothly when Obama was going on and on about his affection for reading.
[He] thinks Ive been talking too long, Obama replied. Lets move it along. Ive got you.
White House reporters could easily try this, right?
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Father given 2 hours to live after bike accident survives with heart pump implant</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/health/2015/05/01/new-dad-given-2-hours-to-live-survives-bike-accident-after-heart-pump-implant/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Curtis and Heather help their son CJ blow out the candles at his first birthday party. They found out Heather was pregnant with CJ only three days before Curtis went into cardiac arrest.(Judy Italiano, Heathers mom)
Curtis' wife Heather snapped this photo just minutes before Curtis went into cardiac arrest while biking in San Francisco Bay.(Heather Broome, Curtis' wife)
Dr. Richard Chang (left) and Dr. Andreas Kamlot (right) reunite with Curtis after his recovery. Dr. Chang and Dr. Kamlot implanted the Impella pumps that supported Curtis' heart and gave it time to heal.(Heather Broome, Curtis' wife)
The Impella 2.5, considered the world's smallest heart pump, measures only 5 millimeters in diameter and has an electric motor that pumps about 2.5 liters of blood per minute.(Abiomed)
Previous Next
Nearly three years ago, 47-year-old Curtis Broome and his wife, Heather, set off on a 32-plus-mile bike ride along a route called The Three Bears in Northern California. While the couple had scheduled the ride in an attempt to play matchmaker for friends who had come along, about five miles into the trip Curtis began to fall behind.
He had been wearing a heart monitor for nearly nine months after a routine doctors visit showed he had high blood pressure, but he was otherwise healthy. Heather, then 38, slowed her pace to make sure he was OK, and he said he was until the two came to a descending portion of the route where they surpassed speeds of over 30 miles per hour for at least one mile. The rest of the group was farther ahead, and the pair got caught at a red light before they would need to hustle across the Highway 24 entrance.
I went into a sprint, and thats the last thing I remember, Curtis told FoxNews.com, and not until the Golden Gate Bridge. Theres nothing in between.
First responders who arrived on the scene thought Curtis, who was on the ground with his body beat up and bruised, might have gotten hit by a car. Rather, he went into cardiogenic shock after his heart rate surpassed 200 beats per minute. When the Silicon Valley entrepreneur lost consciousness, he did a head-dive and fractured his eye socket, suffering contusions in the front part of his brain.
I think he had a couple of hours to live, Dr. Richard Chang, an interventional cardiologist at John Muir Medical Center in Walnut Creek, Calif., and of the Society for Cardiovascular Angiography Interventions (SCAI), told FoxNews.com. Most patients who have sudden cardiac arrest outside the hospital the statistics are less than 1 percent leave the hospital functional.
He was lucky
When Curtis fell, Darlene Vendegna-Guare, a cycling coach and spinning instructor at the downtown Berkeley YMCA, was on a 12-mile bike ride with a group of about 30 people to train for a sprint distance triathlon. Their route, along the San Pablo Dam Road, overlapped with Curtis and Heathers along The Three Bears.
One of Vendegna-Guares riders chains fell off her bike, so she stayed back to help her fix it. As she did, she stood stationary on a path parallel to two riders stopped at a red light people she would later identify as Heather and Curtis who were headed in the opposite direction.
I heard the distinctive sound of a bike falling over, Vendegna-Guare told FoxNews.com, and I chuckled to myself because I figured that one of the riders had not started quickly enough when they were clipped in and that happens sometimes, and the worst injury is a bruised ego. But I heard somebody frantically screaming: a woman yelling, No, no, no! I jumped off my bike and ran over.
Vendegna-Guare is required to renew her CPR certification every two years for her job at the YMCA. Shed never performed the life-saving exercise, so when she saw Curtis on the pavement, with eyes rolled back in his head, she thought, I hope I remember how to do this, and let me just give it a try.
It seemed like forever, she said, but it was probably only a couple of minutes because the fire station was very close by.
EMTs transported Curtis to the John Muir Medical Center, where doctors observed that he had gone into cardiogenic shock from ventricular fibrillation, an electrical event that causes the heart to beat wildly and induces cardiac arrest. The condition usually the result of a heart attack rendered Curtis heart unable to pump blood to his bodys vital organs, leaving him at risk of dying from poor blood flow or multi-organ failure.
Of the various risk factors that exist for cardiac arrest, high blood pressure was the only one Curtis had.
When I came in, I even told his wife, Heather, Hes dying; were gonna try to do this and see if we can pull him back, Chang recalled.
Chang, who hadnt been on call that day, was at his partners Memorial Day barbecue when the hospital called. Chang was the only one on the hospital staff who knew how to input the mechanism that the team deemed may help save his life: the Impella 2.5, a device only 5 millimeters in diameter with an electric motor that pumps about 2.5 liters of blood per minute. Chang threaded the pump through Curtis groin artery to his hearts main pumping chamber.
The Impella 2.5 which was relatively new at the time doctors implanted it in Curtis chest, but has since been used in thousands of patients sucks blood from the hearts main chamber and propels it to the main heart valve. Chang and his team used a fluoroscopy, or a real-time X-ray, to place the device in his chest.
Heather remembers Chang consulting her prior to the surgery: They explained this is what theyre going to do, she told FoxNews.com, And I asked, What happens if it doesnt work? And then he said, Well, he dies.
Like playing chess
Next, Chang and his team sent Curtis to their centers sister site, in Concord John Muir Medical Centers main cardiac institute to receive a larger, 5 liter heart pump called the Impella 5.0.
Doctors had studied Curtis heart on ultrasounds with the smaller pump daily, but scans were showing that his heart wasnt squeezing well. The CPR, the arrhythmia, and the trauma from his head injury led Chang to diagnose him with stress-induced cardiomyopathy.
The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) had approved implantation of the Impella 5.0 via the femoral artery, in the groin area, but Chang and his team wanted Curtis to be able to sit up in his hospital bed, so they opted to input the device in a way that would allow him to do so. 
We did what we call a cut-down: We opened up a big artery in the shoulder area and surgically tied in a graft-conduit, Chang said. That allowed me to put in the 5-liter pump into the shoulder area through a graft, and pull the other one out from the groin. That ultimately I think is like playing chess you gotta plan for the next move.
After inputting the Impella 5.0, doctors put Curtis on a cooling protocol and froze his body for 24 hours, a method that can compromise circulation but also help prevent brain injury from trauma.
Throughout his time in the hospital, Heather, who had learned three days prior to the accident that she was expecting their first child, never left Curtis side. She forewent three nights of sleep. Her mother flew in from Wisconsin, and a guard let them sleep in an empty hospital room.
I had to compartmentalize that this baby is inherent and baking, but I thought given what had happened and the trauma I was going through mentally, theres a strong chance he wouldnt survive  I have to give everything I can to him (Curtis) for the time being, and hopefully well have something to show for this, Heather said.
As a precaution, doctors transferred Curtis to the University of California, San Francisco (UCSF) Medical Center after spending a week at the John Muir Medical Center. He was also struggling with kidney and lung complications, and if he ended up needing a heart transplant, he could recieve one at that hospital but not at the John Muir Medical Center.
If he recovers on his own, we can remove it (the Impella 5.0), Chang said, recalling his thought process. It would have allowed him to leave the hospital and be functional. If that wasnt the case, he could have gotten a heart transplant, which isnt a good, ideal long-term solution.
Within a few days, doctors were able to remove the heart pump, as his heart resumed beating on its own.
I could see the Golden
When Curtis opened his eyes and came to, it was a sunny, clear-blue-skied day, stunningly similar to the one when he fell. He looked out the window to see a sight hed known all his life: the Golden Gate Bridge and the Pacific Ocean.
I didnt know where I was, he said, but I could see the Golden.
Curtis hadnt remembered that he and Heather were expecting, but when Heather reminded him, the news gave him the strength to persevere through recovery.
It was something we had put off, but its something I really wanted to experience. Seeing my wife, her helping to calm me down, although being in an unfamiliar environment  shes my rock, if you will. And for her to tell me we were going to be parents was tremendously powerful, Curtis said.
Today, Curtis, now 50, leads a life he describes as his new normal. He wears sunglasses indoors to reduce sensitivity to light, but the daily cocktail of drugs he takes has been reduced from 14 to only six pills plus a vitamin D supplement: Prozac, two blood pressure pills, a water pill, a statin and a baby aspirin. He also has an implantable cardioverter defibrillator that doctors input after removing the Impella 5.0. The device monitors every one of Curtis heart beats, and in the event of arrhythmia the defibrillator will shock his heart out of it and restore a healthy heartbeat.
Pre-injury, Curtis would sleep six hours a night, but during recovery, his daily sleep schedule increased to about 12 hours a night and two hours during the day. In total, he spent 30 days in the hospital and underwent multiple surgeries.
You think the same just for everything, but it always seems to be a diminished result where you have to make compromises, Curtis said. Im not just talking physical activity but also mental activity even in doing something technical, I still only have the mental strength to do it 80 to 90 percent before I start getting mentally tired, which didnt happen before.
About six months after undergoing cardiac arrest, Curtis attempted to return to his job at Seofficient.com, an e-commerce company for which he served as president. But when he started to forget about emails with specific directions that hed sent his team, he realized his injury had taken a bigger toll on his short-term memory than he thought. 
He finally accepted there was something going on, Heather said. He had been through so much.
What else is going to go wrong?
Shortly before their childs birth, Curtis noticed a bump on his chest where the Impella 5.0 had been implanted then removed. He thought the mark was a sign of the wound healing, but when it became progressively itchy, and in the months following protruded to about the size of an egg and a half, he and Heather knew something wasnt right.
In December 2013, doctors at UCSF conducted blood tests and an ultrasound, and then drew tissue from his chest to discover it had become infected. In removing the heart pump, doctors inserted synthetic material that Curtis body ended up rejecting.
Four days before his sons birth, Curtis had surgery to remove the infected tissue and replace the synthetic material with organic tissue from the lung of a lamb. Curtis ended up losing 80 percent of his bodys blood during the procedure because the necrotic, or dead, tissue was deeper and more widespread than doctors originally thought. Instead of taking an hour as doctors predicted, the procedure took four.
It was extremely frustrating, and yes, I was downtrodden about it, Curtis said. I remember asking myself, What else is going to go wrong?
The miracle in this
Heather and Curtis welcomed their baby boy, C.J. Broome, on Jan. 19, 2013. Since leaving his job, Curtis has become a stay-at-home dad to care for C.J. full time in the couples Montclair, Calif., home, while Heather is self-employed in executive search for technology companies. 
The Broomes have started a technology network organization for alumni of the University of California, Berkeley called Berkeley Technology, which theyd planned to launch around the time Curtis collapsed. Life today for Curtis is less about career and more about spending time with C.J. reading him Curious George and Thomas the Tank Engine, and spending as much time as possible outdoors.
He and Heather still bike together on flatland but not as frequently as they did before less so because of the potential health risks involved and more so because theyre busy with C.J. They began teaching him to ride tricycle when he was about 16 months old.
Heather grew up a gymnast  so he certainly has her sense of balance, Curtis said. The first time he completely shocked us with his tricycle was when he literally stood up on the seat and raised his hands. He wasnt even 2 years old when this happened, and he absolutely blew our minds.
While the prospect of being a father helped Curtis endure the days following his surgeries, of all the circumstances and people that contributed to his recovery, he said he owes the most credit to Heather.
I never would have dreamed I wouldve put her through the hell I unintentionally put her through, Curtis said, and the simple fact that she carried our child and didnt lose our child despite an unimaginable amount of stress and anxiety  I have such a deep, deep level of respect and admiration for her.
(My doctors) tell me its amazing how Ive survived with amazing neurological damage, but for me its beyond amazing what Heather has accomplished, and I dont want that to get lost in all of this. She kept our family together: It wasnt me, it wasnt C.J., it was Heather. If theres a miracle in this, its that.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado governor: Legalizing marijuana helps state's fiscal health - VIDEO: Clearing the haze on legalization of pot in Colo. </title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/colorado-gov-now-says-legalizing-marijuana-helps-state-fiscal-health/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Colorado gov now says legalizing marijuana helps state's fiscal health
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Colorado Gov. John Hickenlooper seems to be softening his anti-pot stance.
The Democratic governor recently told Fox Business Network that the issue is not as vexing as he feared it would be, and partly ties Colorados strong fiscal health to the popularity and economic opportunities connected with the legal pot industry.
Its all those young people coming and they look at marijuana and say, hey, we can drink whiskey, why cant we have a legalized system with marijuana? he said on FBN.
He added, If you look back, it has turned out to be not as vexing as some of the people like myself initially anticipated it would be.
Hickenlooper had spoken out against legalizing the drug in the past and said Colorado is known for many great things  marijuana should not be one of them.
Now, though, he seems to have come around. He told FBN the state has been busy building a regulatory system, making sure we keep it out of the hands of kids, making sure we keep our streets and roads safe.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Almost-extinct fish keeping water off limits amid Calif. drought, farmers weigh challenge - VIDEO: Battle brewing over California's Delta Smelt </title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/tiny-fish-becoming-big-issue-in-calif-water-shortage/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
At three inches long, the delta smelt is one of the smallest fish in California -- but ounce for ounce, no species statewide carries more weight.
Endangered since 1993, the plankton-eating silver minnow is blamed by farmers, lawmakers and water officials up and down the Golden State for locking down billions of gallons of water that otherwise would go to them. That's because, since the smelt's listing as a protected species, biologists have tried saving the fish, in part, by withholding fresh river runoff annually to maintain smelt-friendly temperature and salinity levels.
Farmers and downstate cities -- already suffering the effects of the drought -- claim that water was allocated to them, and withholding it for a fish with no commercial purpose is bad policy.
California fruits and vegetables are sent all over the world, said Republican state Assemblyman Travis Allen. When we are diverting our water to save a few pinky-size fish and leaving hundreds of thousands of acres fallow  there is something wrong with our priorities.
But major farm organizations are exploring a new option in the increasingly contentious fight, as the fish population continues to plummet despite conservation efforts: Declare the species extinct, and delist it as an endangered species, thus allowing regulators to turn on the pumps that appear lethal to the tiny minnows.
The numbers suggest the delta smelt, indeed, could be wiped out soon anyway.
In a March 2012 trawl survey, wildlife officials found 296 fish. An identical sampling a month later found 143. But in April 2015, officials found a single fish, not enough to propagate the species.
Dr. Peter Moyle, an expert at UC Davis, predicts the smelt will likely be gone for good in about two years.
But those considering a push to delist could be in for a fight.
Moyle and other fish biologists say the U.S. has a moral obligation to save the species, and making it the poster child for Californias drought is unfair.Trying to blame fish for a shortage of water just isnt right and isnt true, Moyle said. The delta smelt is in decline because the delta is in decline.
The Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta is the largest estuary of its kind between Alaska and Argentina  a giant intersection of snowmelt and ocean that supplies water to 25 million Californians. Once the most plentiful fish in the delta, the smelt has been in decline for decades, the victim of predators, urbanization and changing conditions.
It is a very delicate fish, Moyle said. But its just the first fish on the chopping block if we dont manage the delta properly.
But Allen said that when pitting the "bait fish" against California families, "I think that is a pretty easy decision to make.
Figuring out a way forward won't be easy. The delta is the most contentious body of water in California, pulled in all directions by powerful interests. But the smelt, steelhead and salmon have a trump card in their pocket  the Endangered Species Act, which says the federal government must do everything it can to stop the species from going extinct. That's why some are considering a push to delist the fish.
The mandate, meanwhile, underpins the UC Davis Fish Conservation and Cultural Laboratory, a ramshackle outpost of trailers on the southern shore of the delta outside Sacramento. There, biologists successfully raise the smelt in dozens of temperature-controlled tanks. Beginning with 160 fish in 2006, the labs produce 250 pairs a year using artificial insemination, squeezing eggs from each female into a bowl, then fertilizing them with male sperm. Two months later, the tiny larvae emerge from beakers full of eggs.
Problem is the fish, which live no longer than a year, have nowhere to go. Unable to survive in the delta, most are handed over to researchers trying to figure out how to save the species.
Is farming more important than fisheries? Is fisheries more important than farming? Personally, I think fisheries has gotten the short end of stick for years, Moyle said.
Environmental groups claim more than just smelt depend on a healthy delta and adequate downstream flows, from salmon to sturgeon.
We have 80 fish species in California, like the delta smelt, that are in trouble, Moyle said. There are other species deserving of protection.
In the meantime, farmers, cities and conservationists will fight over water they claim is rightfully theirs as California heads into a fourth summer of severe drought.
William La Jeunesse joined FOX News Channel (FNC) in March 1998 and currently serves as a Los Angeles-based correspondent.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NYU faculty senate recommends ending fossil fuel investments</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/science/2015/04/30/nyu-faculty-senate-recommends-ending-fossil-fuel-investments/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
File photo.(REUTERS/Peter Andrews/Files)
New York Universitys faculty senate voted Thursday afternoon to recommend that the university divest and strip its $3.5 billion endowment of investments of major fossil fuel stocks in order to make a statement about the dangers of global warming.
If the universitys Board of Trustees signs off, NYU will join more than a dozen universities across the country -- from Stanford to Syracuse -- that have responded to pressure from environmental activists and promised to reduce or end their fossil fuel investments.
Some 50 other universities, such as Harvard, Yale, and the University of Colorado, have decided not to do so.
Some, such as Harvards president, see divestment as hypocritical because nearly everything students use  from plastic bottles to air conditioning and computers  are the products of fossil fuels.
We are extensively relying on those companies products and services for so much of what we do every day, Harvard President Drew Faust has explained.Given our pervasive dependence on these companies for the energy to heat and light our buildings, to fuel our transportation, and to run our computers and appliances, it is hard for me to reconcile that reliance with a refusal to countenance any relationship with these companies through our investments, she said.
But proponents, who applaud the senates vote, say there is no hypocrisy.
It is not hypocritical to use fossil fuels in order to try to get ourselves off of fossil fuels, particularly since this is simply unavoidable! David Frank, NYU assistant professor of environmental studies, told FoxNews.com by email earlier this week.
Economists say that divestment will not noticeably hurt oil company stocks because, when a university sells its fossil-fuel stock and the price falls, independent traders see that the stock has become undervalued and snap it up.
But supporters say their goal is simply to send a message.
The point is not really to devalue the stock, rather to make a statement to those companies, our students, and those who might be paying attention (including you!) that it is prudent to wean ourselves off of fossil fuels. It is a tactic, a means of calling attention to the problem, Frank told FoxNews.com. He added that its needed due to a looming danger of climate change.
The poorest people in the world (particularly in low-lying areas) will suffer the most if we do not take action on climate change that calls for any tactic that might call attention to the problem, Frank said.
Experts debate how harmful global warming could be. U.N. models have consistently overestimated the amount of warming in the past, but their current prediction is that the globe will warm between 2.5 to 5.5 degrees Fahrenheit over the next century and that warming in that range would cause the worlds GDP to be about 1.1% lower in the year 2100 .
The NYU faculty vote came despite a recommendation by an NYU faculty working group studying the issue not to divest for financial reasons.
In order to eliminate the $139 million in fossil fuel investments, NYU would have to [end] relationships with 39 funds this [is] not financially prudent, the report concluded.
At a college that charges $66,000 a year in tuition, some students are also upset about the financial impact on the college.
This is about making a feel-good statement. But the university is the one that has to pay for it. This would mean forgoing millions in funding for scholarships and facilities, NYU junior Eli Nachmany told FoxNews.com earlier this week.
The author, Maxim Lott , can be reached on Facebook or at maxim.lott@foxnews.com
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colorado company refuses service to 'colored people' in 'Mount Ghetto'</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/04/30/colorado-company-refuses-to-service-colored-people-in-mountghetto/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Colorado company refuses service to 'colored people' in 'Mount Ghetto'
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
A Colorado heating and cooling company was caught refusing to do business in a Denver neighborhood because residents there are "colored people" and "they don't pay their bills," according to an undercover investigation by Fox affiliate KDVR.
A hidden camera set up by the station recorded a female employee with Mile High Heating and Cooling in Westminster, Colo., saying the company will not service those living in Montbello. The workers allegedly said, "They call it Mount Ghetto."
The station's investigation was prompted by allegations from another worker who claimed the company did not service minority residents in one of Denver's largest neighborhoods -- despite claiming on its website that it serves the entire metro area.
After watching the video, ACLU's legal director Mark Silverstein told the station race-based discrimination policies are against the law.
"There are local ordinances, there are statutes and there are even federal laws that forbid this kind of discrimination based on race," Silverstein said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chilean volcano erupts for third time, sends out new blasts of ash</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/05/01/chilean-volcano-erupts-for-third-time-sends-out-new-blasts-ash/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Chilean volcano erupts for third time, sends out new blasts of ash
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
April 30, 2015: A thick plume pours from the Calbuco volcano, near Puerto Varas, Chile.(AP)
SANTIAGO, Chile  The Calbuco volcano erupted again Thursday, sending dark bursts of ash and hot rock billowing 2.5 miles into the air and prompting Chilean officials to order a new evacuation of nearby residents.
Thick clouds boiled out of 6,500-foot cone, bringing the threat of new, heavy ash fall over villagers struggling to clean up from two huge blasts last week. The surrounding area was evacuated after the volcano first erupted last Wednesday afternoon, but many people had begun to return to their ash-drowned homes.
"We were working, cleaning the ash and sand from our homes when this third eruption took place. I feel so much anger and impotence it just breaks me apart," Horacio Camano said sobbing after evacuating the town of Ensenada with his family.
"There are no words for having to live this over again  having our families worried about us, all phones collapsed. I just want this to calm down so we can return home."
The eruptions at Calbuco are the first in more than four decades. More than 4,500 people have been evacuated since the Calbuco roared back to life April 22, sending ash about 11 miles into the sky. Hours later, it produced a second, spectacular outburst that turned the nighttime sky reddish orange.
The ash from those eruptions spread across the southern part of the continent, disrupting flights all the way to Argentina's capital, Buenos Aires, and causing widespread economic damage by turning cattle pastures barren and choking fish in one of the world's top salmon-producing countries.
"This latest eruption is much smaller than the other two," Deputy Interior Minister Mahmud Aleuy said at a news conference, but he said 1,500 people were being evacuated as a precaution.
Rodrigo Alvarez, director of the National Mining and Geology service, said that new eruptions stronger than those last week were not expected. But he warned that rains, which are expected to fall beginning Friday, could lead to devastating volcanic mud flows, known as lahars, which are capable of leveling anything in their path once in motion.
"Lahars are possible if we get heavy rains, so it's still a concern," Alvarez said.
Volcano expert Moyra Gardeweg said the wet weather also could mean acid rain that damages metal and plant life and pollutes water sources.
Last week, LATAM and other airline companies cancelled several flights since ash can severely damage jet engines. But LAN, the Chilean unit of LATAM, said its flights were not disrupted by the latest eruption.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesla CEO unveils home battery system</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/tech/2015/05/01/tesla-ceo-unveils-home-battery-system/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tesla CEO unveils home battery system
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
April 30, 2015: Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla Motors Inc., unveils the companys newest product, Powerpack in Hawthorne, Calif.(AP)
FOSTER CITY, Calif.  Tesla CEO Elon Musk is trying to steer his electric car company's battery technology into homes and businesses as part of an elaborate plan to reshape the power grid with millions of small power plants made of solar panels on roofs and batteries in garages.
Musk announced Tesla's expansion into the home battery market amid a party atmosphere at the company's design studio near Los Angeles International Airport. The festive scene attended by a drink-toting crowd of enthusiasts seemed fitting for a flashy billionaire renowned for pursuing far-out projects. For instance, colonizing Mars is one of Musk's goals at Space X, a rocket maker that he also runs.
Now, he is setting out on another ambitious mission. "Our goal here is to fundamentally change the way the world uses energy," Musk told reporters gathered in Hawthorne, California.
Although Tesla will make the battery called "Powerwall," it will be sold by a variety of other companies. The list of partners includes SolarCity, a solar installer founded by Musk's cousins, Lyndon and Peter Rive. Musk is SolarCity's chairman and largest shareholder.
As with Tesla's electric cars, which start around $70,000, the battery might be too expensive for most consumers. The system will carry a suggested price of $3,000 to $3,500, depending on the desired capacity. That could discourage widespread adoption, especially for a product that may only have limited use.
"I don't believe this product in its first incarnation will be interesting to the average person," conceded Peter Rive, SolarCity's chief technology officer. Rive, though, still expects there to be enough demand to substantially increase the number of batteries in homes.
Musk is so encouraged by the initial demand that he believes Tesla and other future entrants in the market will be able to sell 2 billion battery packs around the world  roughly the same number of vehicles already on roads. Although that may sound like a "super crazy" goal, Musk insisted it "is within the power of humanity to do."
It will take a long time to get there. Tesla hopes to begin shipping a limited number of Powerwall batteries this summer in the U.S. before expanding internationally next year.
The long-term goal is to reduce the world's reliance on energy generate from fossil fuels while creating regional networks of home batteries that could be controlled as if they were a power plant. That would give utilities another way to ensure that they can provide power at times of peak demand.
For now, the battery primarily serves as an expensive backup system during blackouts for customers like David Cunningham, an aerospace engineer from Foster City, California. He installed a Tesla battery late last year to pair with his solar panels as part of a pilot program run by the California Public Utilities Commission to test home battery performance.
Although Cunningham's home has not endured a blackout in the six months that he has had the battery, it's capable of running critical home appliances like lights and refrigeration and can be recharged by solar panels during the day.
"As long as a person has solar panels, it's just a natural fit for the two to go together," Cunningham, 77, said. "I consider it to be a whole power system right here in my home."
Cunningham took advantage of state incentives that sharply reduced the battery's $18,300 sticker price under the pilot program. He still paid $7,500.
"The value proposition now is around reliability and backup power more than it is around savings, but over time that may change," said Shayle Kahn, an analyst at GTM Research.
The batteries are likely to become more useful if, as expected, more utilities and regulators allow power prices to change throughout the day based on market conditions. That way, the software that controls the solar and battery system will allow customers to use their home-generated power  and not expensive grid power  when grid prices spike.
Many commercial customers already buy power this way, and Tesla also announced battery systems designed for them, along with bigger battery packs that utilities can use to manage their grids. Analysts say these utility and commercial markets will probably be more promising for Tesla during the next few years than residential customers.
Several businesses, including Amazon.com and Target, plan to use Tesla's battery storage system on a limited basis. Southern California Edison is already using Tesla batteries to store energy.
Tesla is building a giant factory in Nevada that will begin churning out batteries in 2017, so Musk needs to begin drumming up customers now. The spotlight may help Musk push policy makers and utilities to consider reshaping regulations so solar and battery storage could be more easily incorporated into the larger electric system, Kahn said.
Tesla's ambitions already have intrigued homeowners like Mike Thielen, who installed one of the prototype batteries with SolarCity panels on his Redondo Beach, California, home last year. Although he hasn't needed the backup power yet, he has embraced the concept.
"I think it's brilliant," he said. "I would consider upgrading to a more powerful home battery if they could figure out a way to get me totally off the grid."
Advertisement
Subscribe to the daily Geek Sheet for top science and technology stories
Thank you! Your subscription has been submitted.
Trending in Tech
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French soldiers raped African children, refugee camp residents say</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/05/01/french-soldiers-raped-african-children-refugee-camp-residents-say/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>French soldiers raped African children, refugee camp residents say
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
April 11, 2014: Image shows French forces patrolling in Sibut, some 140 miles northeast of Bangui, Central African Republic.(AP)
BANGUI, Central African Republic  Residents of a squalid refugee camp said Thursday that French soldiers tasked with protecting civilians had sexually abused boys as young as 9 years old, luring the children with army rations and small change when their families had nothing to feed them.
The accounts given to The Associated Press by one of the boys' mother and another woman living in the camp came a day after French authorities acknowledged that investigations into the allegations had been underway for months. The children  who described to investigators last year how they were given bottles of water after being sodomized  are still living in the refugee camp, relatives said.
The French government has not explained why the probe was kept quiet, though France's president promised tough punishment for any soldier found guilty. The probe came to light Wednesday in a report in Britain's the Guardian newspaper after the alleged whistleblower at the United Nations was removed from his duties.
Details also emerged Thursday of similar accusations against soldiers from Chad and Equatorial Guinea.
"For the moment, we don't know if the facts have been proven," French military spokesman Col. Gilles Jaron said Thursday, stressing the importance of the French military operation in limiting the bloodshed in Central African Republic where thousands died amid fighting between Muslims and Christians.
France, the former colonizer of Central African Republic, sent several thousand additional troops to Bangui in late 2013 and in early 2014 amid sectarian violence that prompted tens of thousands to seek refuge on the grounds of the capital's airport.
The mother of one of the children told AP that her son was just 9 years old when he was assaulted by French soldiers. She spoke on condition of anonymity so as not to identify her son as a victim of sexual abuse.
Her family had fled to the airport the first day of the sectarian clashes in December 2013, and she and her son are still living there.
"The children were vulnerable because they were hungry and their parents had nothing to give them, so the children were forced to ask the soldiers for food," she recalled.
"They took advantage of the children forcing them to perform oral sex and also sodomizing them," she said. "The moaning of children in the area often started around 10 p.m. or 11 p.m."
Another resident said other abused children ranged in age from 10 years old to 13.
"In exchange for cookies, the soldiers demanded oral sex," she said, recounting what the children told her. "Afterward they were given bottles of water. They even sodomized the children."
Paula Donovan, whose group AIDS-Free World has been looking into abuse by peacekeeping personnel, said she had been given a copy of the U.N. internal report that detailed the accusations. She said that 16 soldiers were cited, including one or two who the children said had been on the lookout while the abuses happened.
Children also accused soldiers from Chad and Equatorial Guinea, Donovan said. "A child reported that he had watched from a hiding place as his friend was raped by two soldiers from Equatorial Guinea," she said in an email. "One soldier stood watch while the other demanded oral sex and then sodomized the boy, and then the two soldiers switched roles."
She added, "At another point in the interviews, a boy reported seeing a child he knew being sodomized by two soldiers from Chad while a third Chadian soldier watched."
French military officials refused Thursday to say whether the soldiers have been identified or whether any were still serving in Central African Republic.
The U.N. later set up a 12,000-strong peacekeeping force in September, taking over from regional peacekeepers who hailed from neighboring countries. The U.N. says the investigation is now in the hands of French prosecutors. The chief prosecutor in Bangui's capital says a local inquiry is being launched as well.
French President Francois Hollande, speaking Thursday to reporters in western France, said if the allegations are proven true, the sanctions against the soldiers should be "very serious" and "set an example."
About 18,000 people are still living on the grounds of the airport nearly 1 years after the violence erupted, in some cases seeking shelter under rusty decommissioned planes. At the height of the crisis, more than 100,000 internally displaced people were living there.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>COLORADO MASSACRE TRIAL: Defense begins cross examination of witnesses on day 4 </title>
        <Link>http://video.foxnews.com/v/4207168280001/james-holmes-trial---day-4/?#sp=show-clips</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Live
James Holmes trial - Day 4
Apr. 30, 2015 - 3:07 - Alicia Acuna and Lis Wiehl recap today's testimonies during the James Holmes trial in Aurora, Colorado.
Fox Business Channel Finder
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="25">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More women, children freed in Nigeria from Islamic extremists</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/04/30/more-women-and-children-freed-in-nigeria-from-extremists/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>More women and children freed in Nigeria from extremists
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
In this 2015 file photo, Nigerian Soldiers man a check point in Gwoza, Nigeria, a town newly liberated from Boko Haram. Nigeria's military says it is moving 200 girls and 93 women from a northeastern forest where they were rescued from Boko Haram extremists.(AP Photo/Lekan Oyekanmi,File)
MAIDUGURI, Nigeria  More women and children have been rescued from Islamic extremists in the remote Sambisa Forest by Nigerian troops amid reports that some of the women have fought their rescuers.
A community leader from the area of northeast Nigeria said Thursday that a senior army officer who was at the scene described the women opening fire on shocked troops at the village of Nbita a week ago, with Boko Haram Islamic insurgents using the women to shield their main fighting force.
He said he was told that 12 women fighters and seven soldiers died in that firefight. The community leader spoke only on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the issue and personal security risks.
The Nigerian military first reported rescuing almost 300 women and children in the Sambisa Forest on Tuesday after deploying ground troops into the forest more than a week ago. The army spokesman, Col. Sani Usman, told The Associated Press on Thursday that more than 100 girls and more than 50 women were rescued, apart from the first reported group.
He also said in a statement that several lives were lost, including that of a soldier and a woman, during shootouts in nine separate extremist camps in the forest.
He said eight women sustained gunshot wounds and four soldiers were seriously injured. Who shot the women was not clear. The rescued women and children were evacuated to a safety zone for further processing, Usman said in the statement.
The army spokesman also said several Boko Haram field commanders and foot soldiers were killed and combat tanks and munitions of high caliber used by Boko Haram were recovered while others were destroyed.
The military was flying in medical and intelligence teams to evaluate the former captives, many of whom were severely traumatized, Usman said earlier.
It remained unclear if any of the schoolgirls kidnapped from the northeastern town of Chibok a year ago were among those rescued.
The plight of the schoolgirls, who have become known as "the Chibok girls," aroused international outrage and a campaign for their release under the hashtag #BringBackOurGirls. Their kidnapping brought Boko Haram, whose nickname means "Western education is forbidden" in the local Hausa language, to the world's attention. Of the Chibok girls, 219 remain missing.
Nigerian military and counter-insurgency spokesmen have said they have information indicating at least some of the Chibok girls still are being held in the Sambisa Forest.
Some captives have reportedly become indoctrinated into believing the group's Islamic extremist ideology, while others established strong emotional attachments to militants they had been forced to marry.
Amnesty International said earlier this month that at least 2,000 women and girls have been taken by Boko Haram since the start of 2014.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="26">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Photos show purported ISIS training camp in Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/05/01/photos-show-purported-isis-training-camp-in-afghanistan/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Photos show purported ISIS training camp in Afghanistan
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
New photos purport to show ISIS fighters training at a terrorist camp in Afghanistan, near the Pakistani border, in what may be yet another sign of the black-clad jihadist army's expanding reach.
The pictures, obtained by a Pakistani journalist earlier this month and published by the military blog The Long War Journal , show apparent ISIS radicals training, marching in formation and brandishing heavy artillery.
"These are guys that likely spun off from the Taliban.
- Scott Stewart, Stratfor
Pakistani journalist Saleem Mehsud originally tweeted out the photos on his Twitter page on April 18, but would not divulge details about their origin. Two of the three images show more than a dozen ISIS fighters standing in formation with assault rifles in front of armored SUVs draped in the extremist groups black standard flag. A third image shows a pickup truck with a heavy machine gun turret mounted in the bed.
Related Image
Expand / Contract
The photos were allegedly taken in the Ustad Yasir camp in the Logar province in Eastern Afghanistan which is operated by the Saad bin Abi Waqas Front. (Long War Journal)
The photos were allegedly taken in the Ustad Yasir camp in the Logar province in eastern Afghanistan. The camp is believed to be operated by the Saad bin Abi Waqas Front -- a group named for an Al Qaeda leader who was killed by a U.S. airstrike in 2011. The camp is named for a key Taliban ideologue and top recruiter who was one of more than two dozen senior and mid-level Taliban officials killed in a 2012 purge.
The photos raise questions about who the fighters are and how closely they are aligned with the Islamic State leadership in Syria and Iraq. Analysts said they could be disaffected former Taliban fighters -- as naming their camp for an accused Taliban turncoat might suggest -- of unaffiliated terrorists whose sympathies lie with the infamous jihadist army.
Related Image
Expand / Contract
A Pakistani journalist originally tweeted out the photos on his twitter page on April 18th showing what appears to be ISIS fighters standing in formation at a new camp set up in eastern Afghanistan. (Long War Journal)
This isnt core ISIS fighters, Scott Stewart, vice president of tactical analysis for global intelligence firm Stratfor , told FoxNews.com. These are guys that likely spun off from the Taliban.
Stewart said infighting has plagued the Talibans many sects for years.
For them, aligning themselves with the Islamic States ideology is much more in line for them, more so than with Al Qaedas ideology, he said.
The camp's name is evidence that Taliban members and other jihadists in the region are dissatisfied with Taliban leaders in both Afghanistan and Pakistan, but there is no indication among the intelligence community that ISIS commanders are managing groups like these across the region, Stewart said.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="27">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Arizona Democrats push for debt-free college</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/04/30/arizona-dems-push-for-debt-free-college-learning/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Arizona Dems push for debt-free college
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
This 2014 photo provided by The University of Texas at Dallas shows, a cap worn by a student at her graduation.(AP)
Two Arizona Democrats are pitching a plan that would ensure debt-free college -- though the likelihood of passing such legislation remains slim.
Reps. Ral Grijalva and Ruben Gallego are helping lead the charge in Congress.
Their proposal has snagged the support of influential Democratic Sens. Elizabeth Warren and Chuck Schumer, but faces a tough sell in the GOP-controlled Congress, which generally opposes expensive expansions of government, according to The Arizona Republic.
The plan reportedly goes beyond prior efforts to reduce debt, and could rely on taxing top earners and corporations to the tune of billions of dollars -- to pay for expanded federal grants and more university funding.
The issue has made it into the presidential race as well.
Florida Sen. Marcio Rubio, who announced his bid to be the GOP nominee for the 2016 presidential race, supported a plan in the past that relies less on the federal government and more on private-sector solutions.
Hillary Clinton, who is running to be the Democratic nominee, is also said to be weighing the benefits of a debt-free college plan.
Arizona leads the nation in cuts to its higher-education budget, according to the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, a Washington think tank.
Republican Gov. Doug Ducey and the state legislature cut $100 million  or about 13 percent of funding -- from state universities for fiscal 2016.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="28">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Strong quake shakes Papua New Guinea, no damage reported</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/world/2015/05/01/quake-shakes-papua-new-guinea-no-damage-reported/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Quake shakes Papua New Guinea, no damage reported
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
SYDNEY  A powerful earthquake rattled the South Pacific island nation of Papua New Guinea on Friday, but no tsunami was seen and there were no immediate reports of damage or injuries.
The 6.8-magnitude quake struck about 66 miles southwest of the town of Kokopo in northeastern Papua New Guinea, the U.S. Geological Survey reported. It also said the quake's strength was lower than the initial measurement of 7.1.
The Pacific Tsunami Warning Center said hazardous tsunami waves were possible within 186 miles of the epicenter, but the risk passed shortly thereafter and the advisory was lifted.
There were no reports of damage or injuries, said Chris McKee, assistant director Geophysical Obervatory in the capital, Port Moresby. The area closest to the epicenter is sparsely populated, and it was unlikely the quake caused any structural damage, he said.
There were also no reports of any tsunami sightings. Given the quake's depth of about 37 miles, officials believed the risk of a tsunami was slim, said observatory official Mathew Moihoi. Shallower quakes tend to cause more damage, and have a higher potential for generating a tsunami.
Papua New Guinea sits on the Ring of Fire, the arc of seismic faults around the Pacific Ocean where earthquakes are common.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="29">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>House adopts bill to trump local DC policy on abortion</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/05/01/house-adopts-bill-to-trump-local-dc-policy-on-abortion/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>House adopts bill to trump local DC policy on abortion
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
WASHINGTON  Republicans pushed legislation through the House Thursday that would revoke a District of Columbia law barring discrimination in the city against workers who have abortions, the latest clash pitting claims of religious freedom against reproductive rights.
House passage was largely symbolic because the capital city's law takes effect Saturday unless Congress first approves legislation blocking it that is also signed by President Barack Obama. The Senate is unlikely to consider the measure by then, and for good measure the White House threatened a veto should it ever reach the president's desk.
"This legislation would give employers cover to fire employees for the personal decisions they make about birth control and their reproductive health," the White House said in a written statement.
Thursday's House approval by a mostly party-line 228-192 vote served as a prelude to a renewed effort likely later this year, when conservatives are expected to use budget legislation financing the city government to try blocking the local statute. Lawmakers cast the clash as one that was larger than a dispute over one community's ordinances.
"The goal here is to resume the war against women," said Eleanor Holmes Norton, a Democrat who is the district's non-voting representative in Congress. "This bill or a version of it is pending all over the country. Stop it here or it will spread throughout the United States of America."
Norton and other supporters said the measure would forbid companies from discriminating against employees who seek abortion or contraceptives or make other reproductive health decisions.
They argued that the GOP effort to annul the city's law contradicted the usual Republican argument that Congress should not impose its will on local governments.
"Most Republicans cannot pass up an opportunity to meddle in personal reproductive decisions or D.C.'s right to govern itself," said Rep. Jim McGovern, D-Mass.
Opponents of the local law said it would force employers like churches, religious schools and anti-abortion organizations to violate their own religious beliefs and provide contraceptive coverage to their workers. They said it could also prevent such groups from acting against employees who privately undermine their employer's mission, such as by volunteering at abortion clinics.
"I stand here to defend the rights of religious institutions and pro-life companies to honor their faith and respect the sanctity of life," said Rep. Ann Wagner, R-Mo.
Rep. Virginia Foxx, R-N.C., said the city's law "promotes intolerance of anyone who disagrees with the world view of the majority of the D.C. City Council."
Sen. Ted Cruz, R-Texas, a conservative presidential candidate, has introduced Senate legislation that would overturn the district's law, saying it "undermines religious liberty."
By law, federal lawmakers can block measures approved by the District of Columbia government and usually do that using Congress' annual spending bills that finance the city's budget.
They haven't used the separate process the House attempted Thursday  in which Congress has a limited time to revoke a law the city has already enacted  since 1991. That is when Congress, then controlled by Democrats, prevented the city from allowing buildings to exceed a maximum height, which federal law caps at 160 feet.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="30">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Carplane fly?</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/leisure/2015/04/30/carplane-is-exactly-what-it-sounds-like/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Carplane is exactly what it sounds like
Published April 30, 2015
Previous Next
Sometimes, the name says it all.
Germanys Carplane is the latest entrant into the ongoing, enduringly quixotic competition to build a practical flying car.
The two-seater features a novel design with individual compartments for each passenger split down the middle by an open space where its wings are stored when its in automobile mode. According to Aviation Week , its designers say this allows for better aerodynamics and visibility on the road than other wing retraction methods.
On the prototype revealed this week, the wings need to be manually installed and removed, like some gliders, but the company has developed a powered mechanism that can accomplish it at the press of a button that comes with the penalty of extra weight.
As it is now, the Carplane weighs just over 1,000 pounds, has the footprint of a midsize car, and uses a 151 hp two-cylinder piston engine to power the propeller, the rear wheels, or both simultaneously. The last of those should allow it to take off in less than 300 feet. It can land in the same distance, thanks in part to its four wheel design, which employs automobile tires and brakes. Its top speed is projected to be 109 mph as a car, and 138 mph as a plane, with a cruising speed of 125 mph.
The vehicle is still in development, but the company believes it can get it certified as a very light aircraft by 2018, or, if the weight limits are raised to accommodate it as a light sport aircraft, possibly by 2017.
This means it already meets the main qualification of every flying car: fitting into the meme that its just two years away.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="31">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother of all fights on 'Bang'</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/05/01/big-bang-theory-recap-mother-all-fights/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Christine Baranski and Laurie Metcalf return to 'The Big Bang Theory' (Michael Yarish/Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.)(? 2015 WBEI. All rights reserved.)
Christine Baranski and Laurie Metcalf made an epic return to The Big Bang Theory in an episode that finally allowed the two women that gave birth to Leonard and Sheldon to meet. Fans have waited years for the ladies paths to cross and their interaction did not disappoint.
The moms have come to town to celebrate Sheldon and Leonard receiving an award for their paper, though both have very unique ways of showing their sons how proud they are. Knowing this, both guys try to prepare their mother for meeting one another. Sheldon asks Mary Cooper to dial down the bible babble and Leonard asks his psychiatrist mother Beverly to keep her negative opinions on religion under-wraps.
Mary of course immediately dotes on Shelly, recalling childhood adventures of the boy genius, in between explaining how the lions managed to stay alive without eating any of other animal inhabitants on Noahs Ark. (They consumed the floating bodies of drowned sinners, of course.) Meanwhile, Beverlys attempts at catching up with her son involve questioning the stability of his relationship with Penny and later asking whether or not the two are having satisfactory intercourse.
After the Mrs. Cooper and Dr. Hofstadter exchange pleasantries, Beverly immediately begins praising Sheldon for all of his recent success, completely disinterested in the role Leonard has played in it. Leonard pulls Sheldon into the bedroom to chastise him for hogging the spotlight, leaving Penny to carry on a conversation with the moms. Before you know it, Beverly is referring to religion as superstition and Mary is insulting the theories of Sigmund Freud. Penny tries to bring the two together by reminding them they both share a deep belief in a Jewish bearded guy but the damage is done.
The fight does allow Beverly to rethink some of her parenting techniques. A conversation with Sheldon over hot beverages leads her to question whether or not Leonard would have been better off receiving the kind of unconditional love Sheldon had growing up. Sheldon admits it didnt do much for the mouth breathing idiots he has for a brother and sister, but Leonard might have benefited from it.
This leads to a reluctant truce between the two mothers and a promise of unconditional love from Beverly to Leonard, followed by the most awkward mother/son hug of all time.
Speaking of mothers, Bernadette is tired of playing mom to Howard, Raj and Stewart, who has become so comfortable in their home that he no longer feels the need to wear pants. After watching the guys waste away the day playing video games and eating junk food, she puts them to work.
Her simple request that they clean the kitchen proves to be more work than husband Howard expected, but he does take a leap into adulthood by taking out the garbage all by himself! Well, at least he tries to, the bag breaks open all over the kitchen floor.
The episode ends with the three guys scrubbing away at the kitchen before breaking into a charming song and dance number. The guys joyfully sing along to the show tune Its A Hard Knock Life, which proves to be too much for Bernadette, who enters in the middle of the performance and immediately exits, shaking her head in disbelief.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="32">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britney takes a tumble</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/05/01/britney-spears-suffers-ankle-injury-after-embarrassing-stage-fall/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Britney Spears injured in embarrassing stage fall
Published May 01, 2015
Singer Britney Spears smiles during the launch of her lingerie collection 'The Intimate Britney Spears Spring/Summer 2015', at a shopping mall in Oberhausen September 25, 2014.(Reuters)
Oops, she did it again!
NEWS: 6 Reason We Love Britney Spears on Instagram
During her performance of "(You Drive Me) Crazy" (at the very end of the video), the 33-year-old pop princess toppled over in her sky-high heels and then sat there for a moment, clearly injured from the fall.
The embarrassing moment was caught on video by a few fans in the audience, and Spears even took to her Twitter to address the injury.
Click here to subscribe to FOX411s YouTube channel
"Thank you for all of the sweet wishes!" she wrote on Thursday. "Had a little scare on stage tonight with my ankle but I'm ok!"
Thank you for all of the sweet wishes! Had a little scare on stage tonight with my ankle but Im ok! 
VIDEO: Britney Spears Puts Cheating Ex on Blast During Vegas Show
Will the show go on? Spears is a resident at Planet Hollywood for her "Piece of Me" show, and her next show is scheduled for May 1. The "Pretty Girls" singer has a two year deal with the venue that reportedly earns her $15 million per year ($310,000 per show).
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="33">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dave: CBS had right to fire me</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/04/30/david-letterman-on-sex-scandal-cbs-had-good-reason-to-fire-me/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>David Letterman on sex scandal: CBS 'had good reason to fire me'
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
David Letterman is getting ready to end his 33-year-run as a late-night TV host, but the comedian told The New York Times there was a time when his days on CBS could have been numbered.
After his 2009 sex scandal broke, when it was revealed that the married host had sexual relationships with several of his staffers, he said the network could have let him go.
"I think [CBS] would have had good reason to fire me," he said.
He added that he was "largely ignorant as to what, really, I had done."
It just seemed like, O.K., well, heres somebody who had an intimate relationship with somebody he shouldnt have had an intimate relationship with. And I always said, Well, who hasnt? to myself. But then, when I was able to see from the epicenter, the ripples, I thought, yeah, they could have fired me. But they didnt. So I owe them that.
Letterman ended up addressing the affair on the air and delivered an apology to his wife and his staff.
Now, this month, the 68-year-old will sign off of The Late Show with David Letterman. His last day at the franchise will be May 20 and Stephen Colbert will take over his hosting duties.
Colbert will appear as the Late Show host beginning Sept. 8, 2015.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="34">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Megan Fox better blonde?</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/05/01/megan-fox-rocks-blonde-wig-on-set-tmnt-2/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Megan Fox rocks a blonde wig on the set of 'TMNT 2'
Published May 01, 2015
(Splash)
Megan Fox, is that you?!
The 28-year-old actress recently donned a blonde wig on the set of "Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 2" at Grand Central Station in New York City, proving what a difference a different hairdo can make.
PHOTOS: Biggest Celebrity Hairstyle Changes
Reprising her role as reporter April O'Neil for the sequel, clearly, the movie is taking full-advantage of Megan's sex-symbol status. Check out the "Transformers" actress showing off her slim stomach in a sexy school girl ensemble, complete with a plaid miniskirt and black thigh-high stockings.
Megan reflected on her Hollywood image last month, telling Harper's Bazaar Arabia, "I would say most people assume that Im not very smart or educated or earnest, because I have this image that Im sort of narcissistic, chasing attention, and wanting people to like me," she mused. "It makes me laugh because I've done plenty of interviews and when you read the article from beginning to end you can see that I'm not your typical music video model."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="35">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grilling tools you should own</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/leisure/2015/05/01/grilling-tools-everyone-should-own/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Grilling tools everyone should own
By Clint Cantwell
Previous Next
If America had a national food category, its safe to say that it would be barbecue and grilling
According to the Hearth, Patio, and Barbecue Association, an organization that collects industry statistics and identifies trends, the countrys passion for live-fire cooking is so strong that we purchased nearly 14 million grills in 2014 alone  and that means that well be purchasing just as many (if not more) gadgets and tools to go along with all of those smokers, barbecues, and outdoor grills.
As the editor of Kingsford.com and the recently launched BBQ and grilling site Grillocracy, I frequently travel around the country and can attest to the fact that all you have to do to start a lively conversation with virtually any stranger is bring up the topic of barbecuing and grilling. The nuances that define outdoor cooking in various regions of the United States  tangy vinegar-based sauces in North Carolina, mayonnaise-based white barbecue sauce in Alabama, or dry-rubbed ribs in Memphis and beef brisket in Texas, for example  are always a topic for friendly debate, and the holy trinity (smoke, fire, and food) is the universal truth in which all committed live-fire cooks believe.
For die-hards like me, firing up the smoker or grill isnt limited to the warm days of spring and summer (its not uncommon to find me flipping steaks or tending to a smoked pork butt in the middle of torrential rainstorms or blinding snow), but for most of us, peak grilling season is just getting underway. If you want to succeed in your outdoor cooking adventures, youre going to need a few tools of the trade. Here are a few grilling tools that will help you make the most out of grilling season.
1.&amp;nbspAluminum Foil
iStock
Certainly the cheapest accessory for the grill, heavy-duty foil can be used as a makeshift smoker box (simply wrap wood chips in foil, poke a few holes, and place it directly above the heat source), foil packets for fish or vegetables, a cover for grill side tables to ensure quick cleanup, or a simple grate cleaner (when balled up and held with long handled tongs).
2.&amp;nbspApron
iStock
Grillings a dirty job but we all love to do it. That doesnt mean that you have to ruin your favorite T-shirt and shorts with sauce and grease stains, though. A good-quality apron (like the Memphis Adjustable Apron from Chef Works) will not only keep you clean at the grill, but youll look like a pro, too.
3.&amp;nbspBBQ and Grilling Cookbooks
Ten Speed Press
Burgers and hot dogs are great, but grilling can be so much more  including countless appetizers, side dishes, desserts, and even cocktails! Get inspired with a collection of barbecue and grilling cookbooks like Melissa Cookstons "Smokin in the Boys Room," Bon Apptits "The Grilling Book", and Chris Lillys "Fire and Smoke."
4.&amp;nbspCharcoal Grill
iStock
Gas grills are great when youre short on time and want to grill up a few steaks or burgers, but nothing beats the thrill of cooking with a charcoal grill like the Kingsford charcoal or Weber Original Kettle grills. Plus, charcoal grills add a nice, smoky flavor to everything that you cook on them.
5.&amp;nbspChimney Starter
AD BBQ Tools
When it comes time to fire up a charcoal grill, there really is no replacement for a chimney starter. Simply fill the metal cylinder with charcoal briquettes, place a lit, crumpled sheet of newspaper or a Weber firestarter cube under the chimney, and in just a few minutes youll be ready to start cooking.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="36">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Youtube star's shocking secret</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/health/2015/05/01/youtube-star-reveals-has-two-vaginas/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>YouTube star reveals she has two vaginas
Published May 01, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Cassandra Bankson
Cassandra Bankson, 22, uses YouTube to offer make-up tutorials, inspire people with her story of acne and bullying and even talk about her two vaginas.
The unique discovery came after experiencing back pain that she and her mother feared was a sign of kidney problems.
An MRI revealed that she had only one kidney, but to her surprise, two vaginas, two cervixes and two fallopian tubes.
The condition known as uterus didelphys develops in utero. According to the Mayo Clinic, the uterus starts out as two small tubes that normally join together to create one whole intact uterus. In the case of Bankson, however, the tubes didnt join completely, creating her two vaginas.
The condition is rare and may be associated to kidney abnormalities. In a YouTube post addressing her diagnosis Bankson said, this explains my 21-day periods, this explains my unruly mood swings!
According to the Mayo Clinic, a double uterus can lead to infertility or miscarriages. It also may cause premature birth or babies being born in the breech position.
In her YouTube post, Bankson said that she has lived with her two vaginas without a problem and hopefully it wont be in the future!
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="37">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sperm whale mystery </title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/science/2015/04/30/rare-sperm-whale-fossils-shed-light-on-mysterious-family-tree/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Rare sperm whale fossils shed light on mysterious family tree
By Laura Geggel
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
The skull of the newly discovered species of pygmy sperm whale, found in Panama.(Velez-Juarbe et al.)
Rare, 7-million-year-old fossils of two extinct pygmy sperm whales are helping researchers learn about the evolution of the ocean's largest toothed whale, a new study finds.
An analysis of the fossilized skulls indicates that even though they were pygmies, the newly discovered species actually had larger spermaceti, an organ that sits on top of the head and is involved in sound production and echolocation (finding an object's location via sound), than their modern-day relatives.
It's unclear why the sperm whales' spermaceti organ shrank over time  twice in the evolutionary record, according to an analysis of several fossils  but perhaps at one time, larger spermaceti were used to attract mates, said the study's lead researcher, Jorge Velez-Juarbe, a curator of marine mammals at the Natural History Museum of Los Angeles County. [ Whale Album: Giants of the Deep ]
"We really need to test this hypothesis," Velez-Juarbe told Live Science. "We need to find more complete fossils."
Another idea is that the enlarged spermaceti organs helped these prehistoric whales find prey, "because they used echolocation to hunt," said Nicholas Pyenson, a curator of fossil marine mammals at the National Museum of Natural History in Washington, D.C., who wasn't involved with the study.
Caribbean fossils
The researchers found the pygmy sperm whale fossils buried in a sea cliff along the Caribbean coast of Panama in 2012 and 2013. After determining that the two unique individuals were a new species, the researchers named them Nanokogia isthmia; "Nano" from the Latin "nanus," which means dwarf, and "kogia" for the whale's genus, "Kogiid." The species name comes from the Isthmus of Panama, the strip of land where the fossils were found.
The findings have electrified the world of marine paleontology: many whales, dolphins and porpoises have comprehensive fossil records that help scientists study their evolution. But only a few fossils of sperm whales and their elusive living relatives, the pygmy and dwarf sperm whales, have been recorded, the researchers said.
"It's exciting to know more about the evolution of this enigmatic group," Pyenson said. "An entire description of a new fossil pygmy sperm whale  that's really valuable."
N. isthmia was small, measuring about 6.6 feet long. In fact, it's smaller than modern-day pygmy and dwarf sperm whales, which measure between 8 feet and 12 feet long, Velez-Juarbe said. The behemoth of the family, the sperm whale (Physeter macrocephalus), made famous by Herman Melville's "Moby Dick" (1851), can reach about 52 feet in length. Female sperm whales are typically even larger, measuring about 36 feet long.
After analyzing the two N. isthmia skulls, the researchers found that they likely sported large spermaceti organs. The organs are made of fatty tissue, muscles and air sacs, and don't last in the fossil record. But the bone that attached them to the skull remains, allowing scientists to measure it and use it as a proxy for spermaceti size.
Other features on the ancient skulls could provide clues about Kogiid evolution. For instance, "The two living species of pygmy sperm whales have among the most bizarre skulls of any mammal," but it's unclear "how their unusual skull shape evolved," said Jonathan Geisler, an associate professor of anatomy at the New York Institute of Technology, who was not involved in the study. [ The 12 Weirdest Animal Discoveries ]
Modern pygmy sperm whales lack nasal bones, and the right side of the skull is different from the left side, meaning it's asymmetric.
"The new fossil species these authors describe show a transitional state between other fossil Kogiids and the two living species," Geisler told Live Science in an email. "Its skull is like those of the living species except that it has a longer snout that is not downturned."
However, since modern Kogiids are similar to one another, it's likely that there are more fossil species yet to be discovered, he added.
"New insights into the evolution of this group will primarily come from the fossil record, not additional study of the living species," Geisler said.
The findings were published online April 29 in the journal PLOS ONE .

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="38">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kate smooches bro on lips</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/slideshow/2015/05/01/fox411-pic-day/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FOX411's pic of the day
What are those kooky celebs up to now?
FoxNews.com
http://www.foxnews.com/
Kate and Oliver Hudson
Too close for comfort? Kate Hudson and her brother Oliver shared a smooch on the lips after enjoying lunch together. The siblings are close, but the awkward kiss couldn't help but give us the creeps. Click here for more pictures of the smooching siblings on X17online.com .
X17
kate-hudson-oliver
Salma Hayek
Salma Hayek looked sultry in silver at the screening of "The Prophet" in Beirut. The actress turned director showed off her curves in the glamorous gown as she celebrated the film that was inspired by the book that helped Hayek to explore her relationship with her late Lebanese grandfather.
Reuters
salma-hayek-silver
Kaley Cuoco
Kaley Cuoco changed up her hairdo yet again. "The Big Bang Theory" actress showed off her new hair color on Instagram. "Have wanted to do this for years! Finally went pretty in pink!" she wrote . Click here to see what all the stars are up to on Instagram.
Instagram
kaley-pinkhair-instagram
Kate Hudson
Kate Hudson rang in her 36th birthday looking like one hot mess. The mom-of-two threw a "hot mess"-themed party to celebrate with her friends and she definitely dressed the part. Jewelry designer and wife of actor Toby McGuire, Jennifer Meyer, also joined in on the fun as she celebrated her 38th.
Instagram
kate-hudson-hot-mess-party
Cindy Crawford
Cindy Crawford donned a sexy black dress for date night with her equally handsome hubby Rande Garber. The two spent their evening dining with Jim Belushi at Craig's Restaurant in West Hollywood. Click here for more pictures of the couple on X17online.com .
X17
cindy-crawford-date-night
Melissa Joan Hart
Melissa Joan Hart rang in her 39th birthday with her family by her side. The actress, her husband and their three kids enjoyed the Caribbean sun at Generations Riviera Maya by Karisma. The family-orientated former child star couldn't think of a better way to celebrate.
mjh-family-vacation
Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox
Reunited and it feels so good! Former "Friends" costars Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox goofed around at a screening of the film "Just Before I Go" in Los Angeles. Click here for more pictures of the star on HollywoodLife.com .
Getty
jennifer-aniston-courtney-cox
Sadie Robertson
Sadie Robertson walked the camouflage carpet at the premiere of the "Duck Commander Musical" in Las Vegas. The " Dancing With the Stars " runner up looked stunning in an elegant teal dress.
Getty
sadie-duck-commander-musical
Crystal Hefner
Hugh Hefner's wife Crystal showed off her DJing skills at Coachella while guests enjoyed Caffeinated Club at the Influential House in Rancho Mirage, CA this weekend. The 28-year-old couldn't help but add some Playboy flare to her headphones.
The Influential House
harris-playboy
Rebel's raunchy style
Rebel Wilson shows off her racy outfit at the MTV Movie Awards at the Nokia Theatre on Sunday, April 12, 2015, in Los Angeles.
AP
rebel-wilson-mtv-awards-ap
Jennie Garth and Dave Abrams
Jennie Garth is off the market! The 43-year-old actress celebrated her birthday at the Dreams Tulum Resort &amp; Spa in Mexico with her love Dave Abrams. The couples' reps confirmed their engagement to People Thursday. Click here for more pictures of the happy couple on vacation on X17online.com.
X17
jennie-garth-dave-abrams
Kate Hudson
Kate Hudson is ready for spring! The mom-of-two was spotted looking flawless in a low-cut floral dress picking up fresh juice. Click here for more pictures of Hudson from X17online.com .
X17online.com
kate-hudson-x172
Ireland Baldwin in hospital
Alec Baldwin's daughter tweeted the hospital picture above on April 3 and wrote "appendicitis swag thanks for all of your concern."

ireland-baldwin-hospital
Deborah Ann Woll
The "True Blood" actress has ditched her red locks for a lighter look. Woll showed off her new blond do at the premiere of the Netflix original series "Marvel's Daredevil" in Los Angeles. Tell us which look you prefer on Twitter @FOX411 .
AP/Reuters
deborah-ann-woll-hair
Katy Perry
Katy Perry showed off her pup Butters at the premiere screening of "Katy Perry: The Prismatic World Tour" in Los Angeles.
Reuters
katy-perry-puppy
Joanna Krupa
Krupa, of "Real Housewives of Miami" fame is ready for summer in a little white dress. The 35-year-old enjoyed dinner in West Hollywood while showing off her new shorter hairdo. Click here for more photos of the Polish beauty from X17online.com .
X17
krupa-white-dress
Christina Hendricks
Christina Hendricks shocked fans when she ditched her famous red locks for a blonde due in her new Clairol ad. The actress, who plays Joan Holloway on "Mad Men," has been a redhead for 20 years but it looks like she was ready for a change.
Reuters/Instagram/Clairol
hendricks-change
Chrissy Teigen
Justin Bieber might have been the one getting roasted, but it was Chrissy Teigen that looked smoking at the Comedy Central event. She posed in a sultry, black dress at the Sony Studios in Culver City, California.
Reuters
chrissy-teigen-roast
Taylor Swift
Ouch! Taylor Swift's cat Meredith gave the singer a nasty scratch on her leg. The "Blank Space" singer poked fun at reports that she had her legs insured for $40 million dollars by saying , "Great work Meredith. I was just trying to love you and now you owe me 40 million dollars." Photos: Stars and their adorable pets
Instagram
taylor-swift-cat-scratch
Sean Penn and Charlize Theron
Charlize Theron and Sean Penn looked like a happy couple at the premiere of his new movie "The Gunman." The couple of one year have gotten serious very quickly with reports that Penn plans to adopt Theron's son, Jackson. The actor recently said he could see himself marrying the South African native .
Reuters
theron-penn
Lindsay Lohan
Lindsay Lohan went a little overboard with Photoshop in a new Instagram pic. The actress wrote, "My feet look red lol- had to take that out. Only real red is my hair." Perhaps she was trying to distract from her obvious Photoshop fail?The area behind her behind appears to be totally warped and her fans called her out for the editing. "Biggest Photoshop fail of all time," one user commented.
Instagram
linday-lohan-photoshop-fail
Matthew Lewis
Neville Longbottom is all grown up! A new picture of British actor Matthew Lewis, who got his start as the nerdy and adorable "Harry Potter" character, is setting the Internet on fire. His "Harry Potter" costar Emma Watson shared the pic of Lewis as a hunky solider in BBC Three's "Bluestone 42." Matt's definitely left his awkward stage behind.
Reuters/BBC Three
matthew-lewis-grown-up
Jared Leto
Is that you Jared Leto ? The musician and actor made a drastic change to his look. Leto channeled his inner Draco Malfoy by chopping off his long locks and dying them platinum blonde.
Instagram/Twitter/Reuters
jared-leto-hair
Michael Richards, Jason Alexander and Jerry Seinfeld
It's a (mini) "Seinfeld" reunion! While they were short one Julia Louis-Dreyfus, "Seinfeld" stars (from left) Michael Richards, Jason Alexander and Jerry Seinfeld were reunited for a good cause. The actors met up Wednesday for a charity event to benefit Baby Buggy. It's great to see the crew back together again after 17 years.
Getty
seinfeld-reunion
Jessie James Decker
Jessie James Decker announced over Instagram that she's got another bun in her oven! The country singer gave birth just under a year ago to her first child, Vivianne, with husband Eric Decker. "Vivianne is so excited because she is going to be a big sister! We are over the moon about having another baby!!!" she wrote.
Instagram
jessie-james-decker-pregnant
Miranda Lambert, Gwen Sebastian and RaeLynn
Miranda Lambert and her tour mates got matching tattoos in Tulsa over the weekend. The country queen (l), her backup vocalist Gwen Sebastian (c) and opening act RaeLynn (r) debuted their new ink on Instagram. "Inked in perfect harmony," Lambert wrote with a picture of their new musical note tattoos. PICS: Seeing Double? Stars Who Have the Same Tattoos
Instagram
miranda-raelynn-gwen-tattoo
Chrissy Teigen
Chrissy Teigen debuted a new look on Instagram. The model traded in her lighter locks for a dark brown. She snapped a pic of her new do and coupled with her intense eyeliner, it made for a scary snap. MORE: Chrissy's shocking Oscars confession
Instagram
chrissy-teigen-brown-hair
Lisa Rinna
Lisa Rinna displayed some diva behavior when she visited New York City this week. The "Real Housewives of Beverly Hills" star had a friend carry her over the snow because she didn't want to mess up hers shoes. Click here for more pictures of Rinna from X17online.com .
X17
rinna-snow
Jessica Simpson
Jessica Simpson has long been criticized for her fluctuating weight. The fashion mogul, who credits her most recent weight loss to Weight Watchers, might have gone too far this time. The mom-of-two looked extremely thin in a new Instagram photo. Tell us what you think on Twitter @FOX411 . Related: NSFW! Dakota Johnson Goes Completely Nude
Instagram
jessica-simpson-thin
Katie Holmes
Katie Holmes' sleek hair and arched brows made the actress nearly unrecognizable at the Zac Posen show at New York Fashion Week. The 36-year-old also showed off her slim figure in a body-hugging black dress paired with simple black heels.
AP
holmes-event
Carrie Underwood
It's hard to imagine Carrie Underwood as anything but beautiful, but the singer shared a throwback pic on Instagram during her less-than stylish days. The momma-to-be shared the picture of herself in braces and pigtails and wrote , "No wonder I never had a Valentine!" We think she's don't just fine since. Click here for more photos of the star from Hollywoodlife.com .
Instagram/Reuters
carrie-underwood-throwback
Kim Kardashian
What do you wear when the temperature is in the single digits? If you are Kim Kardashian , the answer apparently is a low-cut dress with no bra and some sort of light jacket, because that's what she was wearing in New York City on February 15, when the temperature was plummeting to around zero. For more pics of Kim's outfit go to X17Online.
17Online
kim-k-cold-nyc
Blake Lively
Motherhood definitely suits Blake Lively. The new mom stepped out for her first post-baby red carpet appearance in a form-fitting black and white dress paired with a yellow clutch. Can you believe she gave birth to her daughter with Ryan Reynolds in early January? Click here for more pictures of Lively from Hollywoodlife.com .
Getty
blake-lively-post-baby
Kendall Jenner
Don't call her Kim's little sis. Kendall Jenner told her older sister to stay away from her Marc Jacobs fashion show because she wanted the attention on her. "As selfish as this sounds, I wanted the attention to be on me for five seconds rather than my family," she told Allure . "If they were sitting front row, it would have been all about, 'Oh, Kim goes to Kendall's first fashion show!'" Click here for more photos of Kendall's racy shoot.
Mario Testino for Allure
kendall-jenner-monkey
Sadie Robertson
"Duck Dynasty" star Sadie Robertson is in love. The 17-year-old shared a picture of herself and her boyfriend of more than one year Blake Coward on Instagram to her 1.7 million followers. "I just love this man so much :-)," she wrote. PHOTOS: Reality star couples who are still together
Instagram
sadie-in-love
Charlotte McKinney
Move over little black dress, the little white dress is in. "The Next Kate Upton," of Super Bowl commercial fame, made a splash in a revealing white number at the MSG Networks Original Programming Party. Don't call her Kate though. "I hope its Charlotte McKinney and not the next Kate Upton," she told FOX411 . Click here for more pictures of the blonde bombshell.
Getty
charlotte-mckinney-gt
Tom Hanks and 'Wilson'
Tom Hanks and his "Cast Away" costar were finally reunited! The 58-year-old actor was handed a volleyball painted to look like Wilson from the award-winning film. We're glad to see the old pals found their way back to each other. MORE: Favorite TV, movie and music reunions
Instagram
tom-hanks-wilson
Rihanna
That shark did it's best job to take a bite of Rihanna. The singer swam with sharks for a photo shoot with Harper's Bazaar . "I try my best to avoid the sharks of life, but I have had my share of experiences with them, and in those cases I just have to handle them accordingly," Rihanna told Harper's Bazaar. "But I do not swim with sharks...sharks swim with sharks."
Norman Jean Roy for Harpers BAZAAR
rihanna-harpers-cover
Kylie Jenner
The youngest of the Jenner clan has been making headlines lately for her attention-grabbing selfies. From plumper lips, to over-the-top makeup, Kylie Jenner has been known to change up her look often. Now Kim's little sis is trying out a new hair color with a blonde wig. PHOTOS: One star, two looks
Instagram/Reuters
kylie-jenner-hair
Mila Kunis
This new mom made her first post-baby red carpet appearance since giving birth to daughter Wyatt Isabelle in October. Mila Kunis chose the perfect gown to accentuate her curves at the "Jupiter Ascending" premiere. The strapless black dress featured a corset top with a billowing skirt that ended around her shins. Fianc Ashton Kutcher was not at the event, but we're sure he approved this look.
Reuters
mila-kunis-post-baby
Alyssa Milano
New mom for the second time, Alyssa Milano, looked stylish and stunning when she arrived at Maxim's Super Bowl party Saturday. The 42-year-old showed off her figure in a white collared dress and silver sandals. She polished off her outfit with a fresh, dewy-look and laid-back updo.
AP
alyssa-milano-maxim2
Rosie Huntington-Whiteley
Rosie Huntington-Whiteley was a vision in white at a perfume launch in London. The model-turned-actress showed off her figure in a floor-length silk gown. Click here for more pictures of the model on HollywoodLife.com .
Getty
rosie-huntington-whiteleygty
Jill and Derick Dillard
Jill and Derick Dillard celebrated their one year hug-iversary on Instagram. Derick wrote, "It's hard to believe that it's just 2 days short of a year ago that Jill and I embraced at this same place when I returned home from Nepal!" One year later and the newlyweds are expecting their first child together. PHOTOS: Jill Duggar's pregnancy album
Instagram
jill-duggar-hug
Candice Swanepoel
Ever wonder what it's like for a Victoria's Secret Angel on one of their photoshoots? Well now viewers can watch a CBS special Feb. 26 to get a behind-the-scenes look at models including CandIce Swanepoel's Puerto Rico swim wear shoot (above).
Full Picture
victorias-secret-show
Nick Offerman
Who is that? Nick Offerman looks like a different person without his signature mustache. The "Parks and Recreation" star showed off his new look at the Sundance Film Festival in Utah. Let us know what you think of Offerman's stache-free look at @FOX411 .
AP/Reuters
nick-offerman-no-mustache
Rose McGowan
What is that on Rose McGowan's head? The actress donned a strange purple helmet made of what appears to be felt at the Daily Front Row's Fashion Los Angeles Awards held at Sunset Towers Hotel on Thursday. Maybe she was trying to hide a bad hair day?
AP
rose-mcgowan-purple
Chanel Beckenlehner
What? Miss Canada Chanel Beckenlehner donned a wacky costume during the 63rd annual Miss Universe Competition's costume portion Wednesday. The 26-year-old wore 10 hockey sticks, a scoreboard, a goal and a Stanley Cup on top of a white wig.
AP
chanel-beckenlehner
Kim Kardashian: 'Selfish'
Kim Kardashian sent the cover of her book of seflies, called "Selfish," to her Instagram followers . So all of her selfies are on the Internet already, but now you can have them in a book, too?
Rizzoli/Instagram
kim-k-selfie-book-cover-rizzoli
Farrah Abraham
Farrah Abraham stepped out for the first time since her botched lip procedure. The reality star told HollywoodLife.com that she had an allergic reaction to a medication made to relax her lip prior to receiving a lip implant. She said she never had the lip implant because she needed to heal.
Getty/Twitter
farrah-abraham-lips
Jaime King
Jaime King appeared shockingly thin at the Elle Magazine annual Women in Television dinner in Los Angeles Tuesday. The actress' face looked sunken in and her frame looked too frail, giving the 35-year-old an overall unhealthy look.
Reuters
jaime-king-thin
Audrina Patridge
It took the reality star 8 hours and a whole lot of tin foil to transform her brown locks into a greyish-lavender color. She shared the new look on Instagram saying she was happy for the change. Click here for more pictures of Audrina on Hollywoodlife.com .
Instagram/Reuters
audrina-patridge-hair-change
Chris Daughtry
No, that's not a fifth hipster "Duck Dynasty" brother, it's rocker Chris Daughtry! The "American Idol" alum is completely unrecognizable with his long beard. The singer debuted his new look at a Golden Globes after party.
Reuters
who-is-this-star-cd
Hyland: Blondes have more fun
Sarah Hyland showed off her blonde locks at the People's Choice Awards on Wednesday night. The formerly brunette actress paired her lighter hair with a sparkly dress.
AP
sarah-hyland-ap-660
Ellie Goulding shows off fit bod
Singer Ellie Goulding ditched the cold weather in the U.K. and turned up in Miami wearing nothing more than a sports bra and fitted shorts. Goulding was snapped leading a workout class at hotspot Barrys Bootcamp alongside celeb trainer Derek DeGrazio.
Seth Browarnik/WorldRedEye
ellie-goulding-handout-barrys-bootcamp
Kirstie Alley shows off new look
After her "Today" show sit down, Kirstie retweeted a photo NBC posted, showing off her 50-pound weight loss.
NBC
kirstie-alley-today-show-skinny
Lady Gaga really bald?!
Lady Gaga shared a photo on her Instagram account of her posing with some wigs and revealing a very bald head. We always knew Gaga's wild mane was not entirely real, but who knew just how much help she was getting from her wigs. (Instagram)
lady-gaga-bald-instagram
January Jones
This "Mad Men" star put on her bravest face when she had an emergency visit at the dentist. "You have got to be kidding me with this sh*t. Emergency dentist appt. #donteatDOTScandyifyouwanttokeepyourfillingsin #gasmeupscotty." Click here for more pictures of Jones.
Instagram
january-jones-snap
Jinger Duggar
Jinger Duggar celebrated her 21 birthday yesterday with lots of love from family members on social media. "We are so thankful for [Jinger's] love for Jesus and her sweet personality. She is precious to us in every way," the family shared on their Facebook page alongside a picture of Jinger holding a birthday sign next to her mom Michelle. While the celebrations did not include any alcohol, we're sure Jinger indulged in some ginger ale. Click here for more Duggar family photos. 
Facebook
jinger-duggar-21
Sadie Robertson
Bye-bye long hair! Sadie Robertson chopped off her long locks saying she was "ready for a change." Let us know on Twitter at @FOX411 if you like Sadie before or after her new hairdo. News: Sadie gets a big surprise .
Instagram/ABC
sadie-robertson-hair
Cheryl Hines
Cheryl Hines embraced her new role as a Kennedy as she attended the Robert F. Kennedy Ripple of Hope Award ceremony in New York with her husband Robert Jr. The "Curb Your Enthusiasm" alum stole the show in a strapless floral dress paired with strappy high heels.
AP
cheryl-hines-day
Brooke Shields
Brooke Shields turned herself into a human Barbie. The 49-year-old shared a creepy photo of herself inside of a large glittery box. She captioned the pic, "I made this thanks to you #ContainerStore!!" Click here for more pictures of Shields.
Instagram
brooke-shields-barbie-doll-gift-ig
Brad Pitt and Pax, Shiloh and Maddox Jolie-Pitt
Half of Brad Pitt's brood came out to support their mom Angelina Jolie at the Los Angeles premiere of her film "Unbroken" after the director fell ill with chicken pox. Pax Jolie-Pitt, from left, Brad Pitt, Shiloh Jolie-Pitt and Maddox Jolie-Pitt looked dapper at the TCL Chinese Theatre on Monday.
AP
brad-pitt-family
Maisie Williams
Little Arya Stark is all grown up! "Game of Thrones" actress Maisie Williams looked well-beyond her 17 years at the premiere of the film "Night at the Museum, Secret of the Tomb" in London.
AP
maisie-williams-premiere
David Arquette
What was he thinking? David Arquette was all smiles at Bootsy Bellows in West Hollywood as he showed off his new gold grills. The actor told the New York Post that he kept on breaking his teeth so hid dentist came up with the golden solution. Arquette said his new grills are even personalized with his initials. David Arquette welcomes son with Christina McLarty
Getty
david-arquette-grills
Mindy Kaling
Mindy Kaling shared a selfie of herself as her "Mindy Project" character Mindy Lahiri. The 35-year-old actress looked very different in a wig with short bangs and blue eye contacts. "In 2004 Mindy Lahiri wore color contacts. She asked for "Alexis Bledel blue," Kaling wrote on Instagram. We assume the new look is for a flashback scene in her hit FOX show. Mindy Kaling: I don't beat myself up over my weight .
Reuters/Instagram
mindy-kaling-different
Alyssa Milano
What was she thinking? In what looked like an ode to her "Charmed" days, Alyssa Milano looked a little witchy in a green corseted dress at the "Into The Woods" premiere in New York. Milano finished off the strange look with too-dark lipstick and heavy eye makeup.
AP
alyssa-milano-day
Amanda Bynes
Amanda Bynes broke her Twitter silence by posting a new picture of herself. "I'm loving Boutique Jules!" the troubled star wrote. Bynes showed off a slimmer frame in a black, white and yellow color-blocked outfit complete with large sunglasses. Amanda Bynes: Is she really engaged?
Twitter
amanda-bynes-boutique
Jake Owen
Country crooner Jake Owen shocked his fans when he cut off his signature locks. The 33-year-old singer revealed his transformation on Twitter with a selfie. The "Beachin" singer has had shoulder-length hair since the release of his debut album in 2006. Click here for more pictures of Owen.
Reuters/Courtesy of Jake Owen, Twitter
jake-owen-hair
Jana Kramer and Michael Caussin
Jana Kramer rang in her 31st birthday with a new ring. The country singer's NFL boyfriend Michael Caussin proposed to Kramer after four months of dating. "It was a beautiful surprise," the singer said. It's the fourth engagement for Kramer, so here's hoping the fourth time's the charm. Click here for more on Kramer's engagement.
Getty
jana-kramer-engaged
Bob Saget and Ashley Olsen
It's a mini "Full House" reunion! Ashley Olsen and her former on-screen dad reunited at the "Stand Up" for Scleroderma Research event in NYC on Tuesday, Dec. 2. Click here for more photos of Olsen.
Getty
ashley-olsen-bob-saget
Taylor Swift
Taylor Swift looked lovely in London as she arrived for the Victoria's Secret fashion show. The "Blank Space" singer sparkled in a white and silver mini dress.
AP
taylor-swift-london
Paul Walker and Meadow Walker
Paul Walker's 16-year-old daughter Meadow shared a touching tribute to her late dad on Instagram one year after his untimely death. "I love you," Meadow wrote alongside a photo of her as a baby sitting on her dad's lap. In Memoriam: Paul Walker's Childhood Photo Album
Reuters/Instagram
paul-walker-daughter
Katy Perry
Pop star Katy Perry makes a statement on the red carpet as she arrives for the Australian Recording Industry Association (ARIA) awards in Sydney.
AP
perry-katy
Kate Middleton
We spy a tiny baby bump! A pregnant Kate Middleton is finally showing. The Duchess of Cambridge looked radiant in red as she left a fund raising event for a children's hospice at the Norfolk Show ground in eastern England.
Reuters
kate-middleton-red
Angelina Jolie and Geoff Evans
Hey, that's not Brad Pitt! Angelina Jolie received a kiss from actor Geoff Evans after a press conference for their new film "Unbroken."
AP
angie-cheeky
Jessica Simpson and Eric Johnson
Jessica Simpson and her husband Eric Johnson showed off their love at the "Hunger Games" premiere in Los Angeles, California. The newlyweds, both decked out in their finest, looked like they were still in their honeymoon phase.
Reuters
simpson-hunger-games
Jennifer Aniston
Is that you Jen? Jennifer Aniston, who opted to wear a wig for her role in "Horrible Bosses," is barely recognizable without her signature locks. In fact, the producers of the first film were concerned no one would recognize the actress with her new do, but Aniston insisted.Do you prefer Jen as a blonde or brunette?
AP
jen-aniston-pic
Sadie Robertson and Mark Ballas
When Sadie Robertson signed on to compete in "Dancing With The Stars," the 17-year-old refused to compromise her beliefs, especially when it came to picking costumes. The "Duck Dynasty" star sported a modest (and daddy-approved) gown that sparkled as she danced with her partner Mark Ballas on the ABC show.
ABC
sadie-trot
Heidi Klum
Heidi Klum is no stranger to showing a little skin on camera. This time, the 41-year-old mom-of-four stripped down for a Sharper Image holiday shoot. The supermodel answered questions like, "What turns Heidi Klum on?" and answered with, "A USB charger."
Cornelius Kss
heidi-klum-sharper
Adrienne Bailon
Former Disney star and Cheetah Girl Adrienne Bailon flaunted her curves in a body-hugging dress at Aventine in Hollywood. Rob Kardashian's ex completed her look with sleek, blown-out hair and bright red lipstick. Click her for more pictures of Bailon on X17online.com .
X17online
bailon-pic
Sadie Robertson
It's "ducky" love for Sadie Robertson. The "Duck Dynasty" star shared an adorable picture of her and her boyfriend Blake on Instagram putting their own spin on the famous upside "Spiderman" kiss. "I am so blessed to have spent the past 10 months calling you mine :-)" she wrote. Click here for more photos of Sadie.
Instagram
sadie-spiderman
RaeLynn
Country singer RaeLynn saluted our troops at the 51st Annual Green Beret Wreath laying ceremony at JGK's grave site at Arlington National Cemetery. "Such an honor to be invited to attend," she said.
raelynn-veterans
Kris Jenner
Kris Jenner and her much younger (rumored) beau Corey Gamble celebrated the famous momager's 59th birthday at 1 OAK Nightclub at The Mirage Las Vegas. Jenner had pictures of her children who were missing from the celebration set up behind her while she posed for pictures. Really Kris?
Denise Truscello/WireImage
kris-jenner-birthday
Salma Hayek
Phew that was close! Salma Hayek nearly suffered a wardrobe malfunction while on a photo shoot in Los Angeles. The actress had to quickly grab the top of her black strapless dress while she was getting into pool to keep from exposing herself. Click here for more photos of Salma's close call here.
FameFlynet
hayek-pic-day
Scarlett Johansson and Eddie Redmayne
New mom Scarlett Johansson made her first public appearance since welcoming daughter Rose Sept. 3. The 29-year-old looked stunning as she helped friend Eddie Redmayne promote his new film"The Theory of Everything." Click here for more pictures of Johansson post-baby.
/Marion Curtis/StarPix
scarjo-pic
Victoria's Secret
Angels Adriana Lima and Alessandra Ambrosio modeled Victoria's Secret's Fantasy Bras, each worth a cool $2 million each. The super models looked like a million bucks themselves in the bejeweled bras. Click here for more from HollywoodLife.com.
Victoria's Secret
victorias-secret-pic
Kaley Cuoco Sweeting
A crying Kaley Cuoco leans on her husband Ryan Sweeting for support after getting a bit teary-eyed at her Hollywood Walk of Fame star dedication ceremony. The "Big Bang Theory" actress' star was placed next to her former "8 Simple Rules" costar John Ritter who died in 2003. Click here for more pictures of Cuoco on X17online.com .
X17online/Reuters
cuoco-sweeting
Bryana Holly
Playmate Bryana Holly's greek costume didn't leave very much to the imagination. The 22-year-old model was seen enjoying dinner with Leonardo DiCaprio and Australian businessman James Packer in California. Click here for more pictures from X17online.com .
X17online.com
dicapriogirls102414-02-x17
Maria Menounos
Maria Menounos donned a blond wig for a Halloween bash in Beverly Hills. Click here for more on X17online.com .
X17online.com
maria-menunos-halloween
Hilary Duff
Hilary Duff looked angelic at a Halloween party with husband David Comrie (not pictures) in tow. Click here for more pictures of the reunited couple on X17online.com .
X17online.com
hilaryduffhalloween
Michelle Trachtenberg
Talk about a spooky costume. Actress Michelle Trachtenberg stepped out with fake blood and a scary wig at Tequila Halloween party in Beverly Hills. Click here for more on X17online.com .
X17online.com
michelletrachtenberghalloween
Raquel Pomplun and Irina Voronina
Playmates Raquel Pomplun (L) and Irina Voronina had a lot of fun playing dress up at Playboy's Annual Halloween Bash. The models sampled Sugar Factorys Playboy candy collection and donned their best costumes.
Jonathan Leibson/Getty Images for Playboy
irena-v-raquel-pomplun
Naya Rivera
Newlywed Naya Rivera showed off her sultry side at the Opening Of Famed Photographer Brian Bowen Smith's WILDLIFE in California. The "Glee" actress donned a low-cut purple gown with a leg slit.
AP
naya-rivera-purple
Jennifer Hudson
That's no wardrobe malfunction. Jennifer Hudson showed off a little too much at the W Hotels' Turn it up for Change Ball at W Union Square in a strange silk robe that exposed her black bra.
Angela Pham/BFAnyc.com
judson-w-hotel
Kris Jenner
Well, that's embarrassing! Kris Jenner posted a clearly photoshopped picture of herself and chef Gordon Ramsey on her Instagram page. But when Ramsay posted the same photo, it was obvious Jenner had airbrushed the pic. Nice try Kris. Click here to see what Jenner had to say about Bruce's changing looks.
Instagram
kris-jenner-instagram
Kim Kardashian
Kim's definitely bringing something back. The Kardashian sister found a new way to show off her most famous asset. Click here for more pictures of the reality star on X17online.com .
X17online
kim-back-outfit
Amal Alamuddin Clooney
Just call me Mrs. Clooney. Amal Alamuddin added her husband George Clooney's last name to hers according to the human rights lawyer's office's website. Fresh from her marriage to the Hollywood heart-throb last month, she arrived in Athens to advise the Greek government in its battle to repatriate the ancient Elgin Marbles statues from Britain.
Reuters
amal-clooney
Elizabeth Hurley
Elizabeth Hurley proved she's still got it at 49! The British actress showed off her toned physique in a low-cut bodycon dress paired with nude high heels.
Reuters
elizabeth-hurley-pic-day
Jason Aldean and Brittany Kerr
Country music's controversial couple just announced their engagement on Sept. 25, but have the two already eloped? Brittany Kerr, who started dating Jason Aldean while he was still married to high school sweetheart Jessica Ussery , posted a picture of her and the singer on Instagram while they were in Las Vegas. "Me, the hubs and my #hydedolss!!" she wrote. Was she admitting the two got hitched in Vegas or merely trying out calling Aldean her husband ahead of their big day?
Instagram
jason-aldean-brittany-kerr-day
Natalie Dormer
"Game of Thrones" star Natalie Dormer opted for a sleek black suit with a plunging neckline at the British Film Institute London Film Festival Gala Dinner. The actress completed her look with by curling her voluminous blonde locks.
AP
natalie-dormier-suit
Selena Gomez
Out with the little black dress! Selena Gomez looks stunning in a red satin dress at the Los Angeles VIP screening of "Rudderless" at The Vista Theater.
AP
selena-gomez-red-dress
Naomi Grossman
"American Horror Story: Freak Show" actress Naomi Grossman got cheeky with the cameras at the show's premiere in Hollywood, California. The daring look featured strips of mesh on both sides of her body with only a small amount of fabric covering her up. PHOTOS: Stars without their underwear.
Reuters
naomi-grossman-pic-day
What's that on Amanda's finger?
Amanda Bynes was spotted with bleach blonde hair smoking in New York City, but what's that on her ring finger? We spotted a large diamond-looking ring on Bynes' left hand. Could this be Amanda's wildest pic yet? Click here to see some of her other bizarre pics.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="39">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Where is 'boob grabber' now?</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/04/30/tbt-viral-sensation-rebecca-grant-parlayed-video-into-two-new-gigs/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>#TBT: Viral sensation Rebecca Grant parlayed video into two new gigs
Published April 30, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
A year ago, Rebecca Grant became known across the country as "the boob grabber" after a clip of her adjusting her top at a Los Angeles Clippers playoff game on national television went viral.
Fast forward to 2015, and Grant's beloved Clippers are back in the playoffs, fighting elimination in their series against defending champion San Antonio Spurs. Since the Clippers are on the road in San Antonio, Grant said she will be relegated to posting videos of support from home.
"I like to engage fans on social media," she said. "I'll do different kinds of Clippers videos, different pictures, get the team riled up."
But Grant isn't just a basketball superfan accidentally caught on camera anymore. Her viral video fame -- the clip was seen by millions -- led to a dream gig for her: starring in an action series.
"I'm doing an action series that I'm really excited about called 'Gun Girls,'" she said. "It's a little bit sadistic, it's a little bit on the dark side.... She doesn't necessarily use guns. She'll use anything from staples to scissors."
She also got the call to go back to the Game Show Network, where she got her first big break.
More on this...
Viral video star Rebecca Grant has mini meltdown on camera
"I'm doing a show called 'Which Is Worse?' It's very fun and its going to be on Game Show Network's YouTube Channel, Door 3, premiering the first week of June."
One thing you won't see her doing though is adjusting her top at a Clippers game on national television.
"I'm a lot more conscious of that," she said. "I'm not doing anything like that at games whatsoever anymore."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="40">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Demi: Doc was inapropriate</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/05/01/demi-lovato-says-her-gynecologist-asked-for-autograph-during-her-exam/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Demi Lovato recalls inapropriate gynecologist appointment
Published May 01, 2015
(2014 Getty Images)
Not cool!
Demi Lovato recently described a super-awkward encounter at her gynecologist's office, and it'll definitely make you cringe .
"There's been so many uncomfortable, and actually violating moments, where I've been to the gynecologist and the doctor's like, 'Can I have an autograph for my daughter?'" she recalls in a new interview with New Zealand radio station ZM. "I'm like, 'F**k you, what the hell is wrong with you?'"
PHOTOS: Star Sightings
And her embarrassing moments don't stop at doctor visits.
"Or I'll get like, a laser, and someone will be like, same thing ... "My such and such is a big fan,' and I'm just like, great, well you can now tell them that you've seen my vagina."
But at least the 22-year-old singer isn't afraid to stick up for herself -- on Thursday, she wrote a lengthy response to tattoo artist Ashley McMullen, who gave her a pink lips tattoo she recently covered up. Demi referred to it as a "vagina tattoo" on Instagram, and hashtagged, "#kidsdontdodrugs."
VIDEO: Demi Lovato Dedicates a Song to 'American Hero' Bruce Jenner
Obviously, McMullen wasn't happy with Demi's diss. "Thanks for getting the tattoo covered up I did for free that you specifically asked for," she wrote in a now-deleted Instagram. "Not to mention you didn't even have the courtesy to offer me any money in the first place. You pissed all over our toilet seat and you made a fool of yourself. What a shame that people look up to you."
Demi's response? Basically, "sorry not sorry."
"I apologize for making fun of your work.. But... if I were you, I wouldn't claim that one because it looked more like an open vagina (or even a butt hole as my 8 year old little sister called it at the time.)," she wrote . "I also wouldn't be admitting to the fact that you tattooed a very intoxicated 18 year old on a tour bus without the proper judgement that most legit tattoo artists have of saying 'Hmm... This underage kid is wasted, maybe I shouldn't permanently ink a hot pink kiss mark on this girl's wrist....? Oh well... F--k it, she's famous.'"
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="41">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Perks for non-baseball fans</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/travel/2015/05/01/baseball-park-perks-even-non-sports-fans-will-love/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baseball park perks even non-sports fans will love
By Jennifer M. Wood
Courtesy of Union Square Hospitality Group
Deanne Fitzmaurice /Sports Illustrated/Getty Images
Courtesy of Safeco
Whether you're looking for a pool to swim in before or after the game, or need a quick encounter with a marine animal during the seventh inning stretch, these famous ballparks offer more than just the diamond.
1.&amp;nbspA Party Bar at Marlins Park
Courtesy of Clevelander
Miamians are as fanatical about their partying as they are their sports teams. So when the team formerly known as the Florida Marlins unveiled a new stadium to go along with a new monikerthe Miami Marlinsin 2012, it only made sense that they would combine the citys two passions. Like its Ocean Drive counterpart, The Clevelander bar inside Marlins Park offers a large menu of brightly colored cocktails, scantily clad female staffers, the occasional body painting stage show and, of course, a pool. Because what sort of sexy SoBe nightclub housed within an MLB stadium wouldnt have a place for its wilder patrons to take a dip? Oh, theres also a viewing area, for those who actually want to watch the game. You can buy group tickets in The Clevelander section ahead of time, or check Marlins.com just before the game to grab one of the few standing-room-only tickets that go on sale. The Clevelander is open for business up to two hours before and after every home game.
2.&amp;nbspA Pool at Chase Field
Christian Petersen/Getty Images
Of course, a swimming pool is nothing new to fans of the Arizona Diamondbacks. The team unveiled onecomplete with a hot tub, for those particularly chilly eveningsin 1998, a mere 415 feet from home plate. The difference is that this pool is located smack dab in right-center field, where its elevated four feet above ground. It, too, has a bar area, plus a lifeguard, changing rooms, a pool deck for watching the game, and a plasma TV for getting an even better view. Its a private lounge space, which can be reserved for up to 35 guests for a cool $4,500 to $7,000 per game. But the real question is: Do you want to take the chance that a video of you sunbathing could end up on ESPN?
3.&amp;nbspAn Upscale Barbecue Joint at Citifield
Courtesy of Union Square Hospitality Group
We're not about to take sides on a Yankees versus Mets debate, but we will say that the Mets six-year-old home field does a lot to keep New York Citys reputation as a culinary powerhouse intact. Much of this is thanks to Danny Meyer, the restaurateur who brought outposts of his upscale barbecue concept Blue Smoke and burger-and-frozen-custard obsession Shake Shack to the parks Taste of the City concession area. . Meat king Pat La Friedas various eateries around the park are also helping to please baseball-loving carnivores.
4.&amp;nbspA Waterfront View at AT&amp;T Park
Deanne Fitzmaurice /Sports Illustrated/Getty Images
Technically, you dont even need a ticket to watch the San Francisco Giants play. Dozens of game-crashers prefer to cruise to this waterfront park via boat, kayak, or any other sea-worthy vessel and wait for a home run ball to splash its way into China Basin, a.k.a. McCovey Cove, nicknamed in honor of super-slugger Willie McCovey.
5.&amp;nbspAn Art Gallery at Safeco Field
Courtesy of Safeco
Safecos Art in the Park program showcases the work of some seriously talented Pacific Northwest artists, with 43 hardball-inspired paintings, photographs, and sculptures installed throughout the stadium and parking garage. Among the most impressive pieces is Linda Beaumont, Stuart Keeler and Michael Machnics The Tempest, a chandelier made of 1,000 glowing bats that hangs above the Home Plate Gate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="42">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal's disaster relief drones</title>
        <Link>http://www.foxnews.com/tech/2015/04/30/how-drones-are-helping-nepal-earthquake-relief-effort/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Video taken from a drone Saturday April 25 2015 shows devastation in the Nepalese capital Kathmandu.(AP Photo / KISHNOR RANA)
Drones are proving a crucial high-tech tool for aid workers in the aftermath of the devastating Nepal earthquake.
With the death toll from Saturdays 7.8-magnitude quake now over 5,000, rescuers and relief workers are scrambling to get aid to the countrys worst-hit areas.
Experts from Etobicoke, Ontario-based GlobalMedic, which manages a fleet of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) for international disaster relief missions, is already in the Himalayan nation. Our UAV team is tasked with aerially mapping crisis-affected areas, then compiling and cross-stitching the collected imagery into maps that provide a superior snapshot of needs on the ground, wrote a GlobalMedic spokeswoman, in an email to FoxNews.com. Identifying flooded areas, obstructed roads, population movements, and damaged infrastructure, the possibilities for UAV use in an emergency setting are extensive.
The aid organization is using three high-end UAVs in Nepal. The SkyRanger and Scout drones, built by Aeryon Labs, are controlled via a touchscreen interface. Equipped with thermal cameras, the devices can identify people who are trapped or injured.
Haunting drone footage from Nepal reveals a patchwork of collapsed buildings and wrecked temples, underlining the scale of the destruction. The U.N. says the disaster has affected 8.1 million people  more than a fourth of Nepal's population of 27.8 million  and that 1.4 million needed food assistance.
Officials and foreign aid workers who have rushed to Nepal following the earthquake are struggling against stormy weather, poor roads and a shortage of manpower and funds to get assistance to the needy.
GlobalMedic told FoxNews.com that its drones record and transmit information in real time, helping to assign priority areas for humanitarian aid and identifying accessibility issues. These maps are vital in the assessment of humanitarian needs, said the spokeswoman. All mapping information and results will be shared with the U.N., the Nepalese government and all coordinating agencies responding in Nepal. The aim is to disseminate this invaluable information so the humanitarian network can coordinate effectively, eliminate gaps and overlaps in programming, and save more lives.
The Canadian organization also used its UAVs during the relief efforts after Typhoon Hagupit struck the Philippines last year.
GlobalMedic Director Rahul Singh told FoxNews.com that information is key in any emergency scenario. In an emergency if you call 911  help is sent. But the right help is sent based on the information gleaned from the caller, he wrote, in an email. Nepal has called for a Global 911 response - the images from these UAVs will be that information. This is crucial to ensuring aid is delivered more effectively.
Follow James Rogers on Twitter @ jamesjrogers
The Associated Press contributed to this report.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="43">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pacquiao: I'm not nervous</title>
        <Link>http://video.foxnews.com/v/4207639564001/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Live
Pacquiao: I'm not worried, not nervous about Mayweather
Apr. 30, 2015 - 4:41 - In a battle between two boxing icons, Manny Pacquiao more than ready for long-awaited, historic showdown with Floyd 'Money' Mayweather. #MayPac
Fox Business Channel Finder
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
