<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:17:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill at least  19 in Tunisia beach attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/D0fn8OPnsec/</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's Interior Ministry and state TV said two gunmen opened fire Friday on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least 19 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gunmen kill at least  19 in Tunisia beach attack
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
TUNIS, Tunisia  Tunisia's Interior Ministry and state TV said two gunmen opened fire Friday on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least 19 people.
Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other.
Tunisian state TV said 19 people were killed in the attack.
Sousse, some 90 miles from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
Tunisia has been battered by attacks by militants, most recently in March when two Tunisians returning from Libya killed 22 people at the national museum.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:07:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>THE LATEST: 2 gunmen kill at least 7 in attack on beach in Tunisia; 1 gunman killed, 1 hunted</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/BztJ2n20P4o/</Link>
        <Description>The latest news from an attack at hotels in Tunisia (all times local): ___ 1 p.m.</Description>
        <MainBody>TUNIS, Tunisia  The latest news from an attack at hotels in Tunisia (all times local):
___
1 p.m.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least seven people.
Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
Aroui said the death toll could rise.
Tunisia has been battered by attacks by militants, most recently in March when two Tunisians returning from Libya killed 22 people at the national museum.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:03:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Zimbabwe jails journalist for starting newspaper without government permission</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/gs14NFMeLqw/</Link>
        <Description>The attorney for a Zimbabwe journalist says his client was convicted of publishing a newspaper in a southern town without government permission and sentenced to eight months in prison.</Description>
        <MainBody>Zimbabwe jails journalist for starting newspaper without government permission
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
HARARE, Zimbabwe  The attorney for a Zimbabwe journalist says his client was convicted of publishing a newspaper in a southern town without government permission and sentenced to eight months in prison.
Several newspapers and radio stations have already been closed under Zimbabwe's harsh media laws and dozens of journalists have been arrested over the past 15 years.
Defense lawyer Martin Mureri said his client Patrick Chitongo was only putting together a dummy version of the paper to apply for a license. They plan to appeal the conviction.
Although several privately owned newspapers are in circulation, the government is the largest media owner, running over a dozen national and community newspapers as well as enjoying television monopoly.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:42:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swiss court denies appeal for release on bail by 1 of 7 men arrested in FIFA bribery case</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/G-mX5y9P-Z4/</Link>
        <Description>Switzerland's Federal Criminal Court has rejected a request for release on bail by one of the seven men arrested on corruption charges last month in a raid on FIFA's luxury hotel in Zurich.</Description>
        <MainBody>Swiss court denies appeal for release on bail by 1 of 7 men arrested in FIFA bribery case
Published June 26, 2015
BELLINZONA, Switzerland  Switzerland's Federal Criminal Court has rejected a request for release on bail by one of the seven men arrested on corruption charges last month in a raid on FIFA's luxury hotel in Zurich.
The Swiss court said "there was a risk that the appellant would abscond if released."
The court did not identify the man, who was among seven football and marketing officials arrested on May 27 at the request of American authorities investigating bribery and racketeering.
He was the only one who appealed against detention in Zurich-area prisons as the seven await extradition to the United States.
The court says the man's arguments for release of "advanced age and poor state of health, were not regarded as sufficient to counter the risk of absconding."
Formal extradition requests must be filed by July 3.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:27:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus overturns, hit by truck on highway in eastern China, killing at least 10 people</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/KAm-OdEDcbo/</Link>
        <Description>Chinese officials say a bus overturned on a highway and then was hit by an oncoming truck in eastern China, killing at least 10 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus overturns, hit by truck on highway in eastern China, killing at least 10 people
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BEIJING  Chinese officials say a bus overturned on a highway and then was hit by an oncoming truck in eastern China, killing at least 10 people.
The government of Wuhu city in Anhui province said a number of other people were injured in the accident Friday and that its cause is being investigated.
State broadcaster China Central Television said the bus overturned into the opposite lane of the highway and was hit by the truck.
The number of people in the two vehicles was not immediately known.
Road accidents in China are often caused by poor driving habits, inadequate maintenance, overloading and dangerous mountain roads. The number of motorists has been rapidly increasing.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:12:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican signs treaty with "State of Palestine," hopes it will encourage peace with Israel</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/4aGXHEtIbf4/</Link>
        <Description>The Vatican has signed a treaty with the "State of Palestine" and said it hopes the official recognition will help stimulate peace with Israel.</Description>
        <MainBody>Vatican signs treaty with "State of Palestine," hopes it will encourage peace with Israel
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
VATICAN CITY  The Vatican has signed a treaty with the "State of Palestine" and said it hopes the official recognition will help stimulate peace with Israel.
Vatican Foreign Minister Paul Gallagher and his Palestinian counterpart, Riad al-Malki, signed the treaty at a ceremony Friday in the Vatican.
Israel had expressed its disappointment when the Vatican announced last month that it had reached final agreement with the "State of Palestine" on the treaty regulating the life of the Catholic Church in the Palestinian territories.
Gallagher said he hoped the Vatican's recognition "may in some way be a stimulus to bringing a definitive end to the long-standing Israeli-Palestinian conflict." He added the treaty could be a model for other Mideast countries.
It marks the first legal recognition by the Vatican of the Palestinian state.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protesters in Armenia remain on capital's main avenue as standoff with government continues</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/kO8WcLwqPOE/</Link>
        <Description>Demonstrators protesting against a hike in electricity prices are dancing and singing on the Armenian capital's main avenue, maintaining pressure on the government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Protesters in Armenia remain on capital's main avenue as standoff with government continues
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Armenian protesters shout anti-government slogans during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian protesters sing folk songs while waving a national flag during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian protesters dance during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian riot police block the road next to protesters during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian protesters wave a national flag during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
YEREVAN, Armenia  Demonstrators protesting against a hike in electricity prices are dancing and singing on the Armenian capital's main avenue, maintaining pressure on the government.
Hundreds of protesters gathered on the road for a fifth straight day Friday behind a barricade of large trash containers separating them from police. Others were hiding from sweltering heat under roadside trees and umbrellas.
Following Monday's unsuccessful attempt to end the protest by force, authorities have taken a wait-and-see approach and police didn't interfere with the protest.
There was no end in sight, however, to the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years as the government rejected the protesters' demand to annul the price hike. The country's power grid is controlled by a Russian electricity giant, and Moscow watched the protest with concern.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:46:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bomb strikes Shiite mosque in Kuwait after Friday prayers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/Cp7wafGjffU/</Link>
        <Description>A bomb has exploded in a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bomb strikes Shiite mosque in Kuwait after Friday prayers
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
KUWAIT CITY  A bomb has exploded in a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital.
The bomb struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque in a busy area of Kuwait City's al-Sawabir district. Witness Abdullah al-Saffar was at the mosque at the time. He says the explosions took place on the mosque grounds following Friday prayers, and that there were casualties.
There was no claim of responsibility, however the Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for bombings at two different Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
Friday midday prayers are typically the most crowded of the week, and attendance increases during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, which started last week.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police arrest Pakistani man, suspected Qaida member, accused in 2009 Peshawar market attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/jX40KoG05sA/</Link>
        <Description>Police say they have arrested a Pakistani man suspected of helping organize the 2009 attack on a market in Peshawar that killed more than 100 people, the latest arrest in a decade-long investigation into an Italy-based terror network with ties to al Qaida.</Description>
        <MainBody>Police arrest Pakistani man, suspected Qaida member, accused in 2009 Peshawar market attack
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ROME  Police say they have arrested a Pakistani man suspected of helping organize the 2009 attack on a market in Peshawar that killed more than 100 people, the latest arrest in a decade-long investigation into an Italy-based terror network with ties to al Qaida.
State police said in a statement Friday that the suspect, identified as a member of al Qaida, was arrested late Thursday at Rome's Leonardo da Vinci airport as he arrived on a flight from Islamabad.
On April 24, Italy's anti-terrorism police announced they had arrested nine people and issued arrest warrants for another nine as part of a probe into the network. Prosecutors said its members had plotted a 2010 attack on the Vatican that was never carried out.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:49:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>1 dead in attack, explosion at French gas factory; Arabic banners found near decapitated body</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/thgXQgyb6wY/</Link>
        <Description>One person was beheaded Friday in an attack and explosion at a gas factory in southeastern France that left multiple people wounded, two officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>1 dead in attack, explosion at French gas factory; Arabic banners found near decapitated body
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
PARIS  One person was beheaded Friday in an attack and explosion at a gas factory in southeastern France that left multiple people wounded, two officials said. Banners with Arabic writing were found near the body, one of the officials said.
Details of the attack were sketchy but two French officials said it began mid-morning in the Isere region when the men crashed a car into the entrance of the factory and into gas canisters, touching off the explosion. One attacker was arrested, they said.
The decapitated body and the banners were found near the factory entrance, one of the officials said.
Both officials spoke condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the news media.
France went on high alert after an attack in January that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including the Islamic extremist attackers.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
