<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="FOX News">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:13:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Italy holds funeral for 13 migrants recovered from April shipwreck that killed up to 800</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/gcGelpZwb30/</Link>
        <Description>Italian officials have held a funeral for 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy holds funeral for 13 migrants recovered from April shipwreck that killed up to 800
Published July 07, 2015
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:17:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill at least  19 in Tunisia beach attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/D0fn8OPnsec/</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's Interior Ministry and state TV said two gunmen opened fire Friday on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least 19 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gunmen kill at least  19 in Tunisia beach attack
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
TUNIS, Tunisia  Tunisia's Interior Ministry and state TV said two gunmen opened fire Friday on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least 19 people.
Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other.
Tunisian state TV said 19 people were killed in the attack.
Sousse, some 90 miles from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
Tunisia has been battered by attacks by militants, most recently in March when two Tunisians returning from Libya killed 22 people at the national museum.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:27:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British families, friends mourn loss of loved ones in Tunisia beach attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/jP8rfwh2SnA/</Link>
        <Description>Three men from the same British family, a recently engaged lifestyle blogger and a couple whose children launched a desperate social media campaign to find them were among those feared killed in the Tunisian beach attack.</Description>
        <MainBody>British families, friends mourn loss of loved ones in Tunisia beach attack
Published June 28, 2015
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Ismail Bouchnafa, vice president of the Sicilian Islamic Community, third left, and Archbishop of Catania Salvatore Gristina, second left, attend the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Archbishop of Catania Salvatore Gristina delivers his speech during the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Catania Mayor Enzo Bianco delivers his speech during the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Ismail Bouchnafa, vice president of the Sicilian Islamic Community, center, Archbishop of Catania Salvatore Gristina, third left, and Catania Mayor Enzo Bianco, left, attend the funeral of 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April in Catania, Sicily, Italy, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy. (AP Photo/Carmelo Imbesi)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
<<<<<<< HEAD
CATANIA, Italy  Italian officials have held a funeral for 13 migrants who were among up to 800 people who died in a shipwreck in April.
The 13 are the first victims of the shipwreck to be recovered by deep-sea operations being carried out by the Italian navy.
Among those who attended the ceremony on Tuesday in Catania were the mayor of the Sicilian city, Enzo Bianco, and Bouchnafa Ismail, vice president of the Sicilian Islamic Community.
Premier Matteo Renzi has pledged that Italy would do everything possible to try to bring up the bodies. Survivor accounts and undersea examination indicate that hundreds were crammed inside the hold of the smuggler's fishing boat, which capsized when rescuers aboard a nearby container ship approached in waters off Libya on April 18.
=======
LONDON  Three men from the same British family, a recently engaged lifestyle blogger and a couple whose children launched a desperate social media campaign to find them were among those feared killed in the Tunisian beach attack.
Britain's government says at least 15 Britons were among the 38 killed when a university student opened fire Friday at the Sousse beach resort. Officials haven't officially confirmed the names of the victims, but families and friends have released details of those killed to British media. Other families were still fearing the worst Sunday.
Tunisian authorities have said other victims include people from Germany, Ireland, Belgium and Portugal.
Here is a look at some of those believed killed:
___
Joel Richards, a 19-year-old student and active soccer player, was reportedly killed along with his uncle, Adrian Evans, as well as his grandfather, 78-year-old Charles Evans. All three were keen soccer fans who were holidaying together at the beach.
"A young, talented referee with the world at his feet. He was highly thought of and will be sadly missed," Ian Murphy of the Birmingham County Football Association said of Richards. "He was such a talented lad," he added to Sky News.
Another Birmingham-based club, James Connolly's GFC, said Richards was an "exceptionally talented footballer" who represented his club and county on numerous occasions.
Joel's 16-year-old brother, Owen, who was also at the beach, reportedly fled the scene, surviving a bullet wound to his shoulder.
A local council paid tribute to Adrian Evans, 49, described as a popular and long-serving employee who managed gas services.
___
Carly Lovett, 24, was a budding lifestyle blogger on holiday with her fiance Liam Moore.
Lovett, a University of Lincoln graduate and a photographer, had just recently launched a blog sharing her love for beauty products.
The university's school of film and media confirmed Lovett graduated in 2013, and tweeted it was saddened to hear news reports about her.
As friends and fellow bloggers paid tribute to her on social media, a poignant message Lovett wrote on Wednesday is still on Twitter: "Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing..."
Her fiance was reportedly traveling home.
___
Like others, 23-year-old Conor Fulford turned to social media for help when he became increasingly worried about his missing mother Sue Davey, 44.
Fulford, who thought he may have seen his mother on television as she was being taken away on a stretcher, repeatedly tweeted pleas for information.
So did Ross Nayler, whose father, 42-year-old Scott Chaulkley, was on holiday in Tunisia together with Davey.
"I'm checking Twitter and all the other social media just for anything really, just for any update," Nayler told ITV News.
But by Saturday night, both sons learned the truth. Fulford wrote: "Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight." He added: "Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight. Rest easy."
Severn Trent Water, where Davey and Chaulkley worked, paid tribute to the pair Sunday. "Sue and Scott had a passion to help others however they could, they cared enormously for all those they worked with and were totally committed to our customers and our company," the company said in a statement.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:05:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN rights chief worried by breadth of China security law</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/a3LhRxPRjVo/</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN rights chief worried by breadth of China security law
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
BERLIN  The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.
Zeid Raad al-Hussein said Tuesday that the National Security Law "raises many concerns due to its extraordinarily broad scope coupled with the vagueness of its terminology and definitions."
He added in a statement that "it leaves the door wide open to further restrictions of the rights and freedoms of Chinese citizens, and to even tighter control of civil society by the Chinese authorities than there is already."
The new legislation reinforces government controls over cyberspace and covers a wide range of other areas including the economy, social stability, territorial integrity, the military, culture, finance, technology, the environment and food safety.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:07:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>THE LATEST: 2 gunmen kill at least 7 in attack on beach in Tunisia; 1 gunman killed, 1 hunted</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/BztJ2n20P4o/</Link>
        <Description>The latest news from an attack at hotels in Tunisia (all times local): ___ 1 p.m.</Description>
        <MainBody>TUNIS, Tunisia  The latest news from an attack at hotels in Tunisia (all times local):
___
1 p.m.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry says two gunmen opened fire on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, killing at least seven people.
Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
Aroui said the death toll could rise.
Tunisia has been battered by attacks by militants, most recently in March when two Tunisians returning from Libya killed 22 people at the national museum.
___
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:03:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Zimbabwe jails journalist for starting newspaper without government permission</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/gs14NFMeLqw/</Link>
        <Description>The attorney for a Zimbabwe journalist says his client was convicted of publishing a newspaper in a southern town without government permission and sentenced to eight months in prison.</Description>
        <MainBody>Zimbabwe jails journalist for starting newspaper without government permission
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
HARARE, Zimbabwe  The attorney for a Zimbabwe journalist says his client was convicted of publishing a newspaper in a southern town without government permission and sentenced to eight months in prison.
Several newspapers and radio stations have already been closed under Zimbabwe's harsh media laws and dozens of journalists have been arrested over the past 15 years.
Defense lawyer Martin Mureri said his client Patrick Chitongo was only putting together a dummy version of the paper to apply for a license. They plan to appeal the conviction.
Although several privately owned newspapers are in circulation, the government is the largest media owner, running over a dozen national and community newspapers as well as enjoying television monopoly.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:17:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armenian demonstrators to decide whether to halt weeklong protest against electricity hikes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/kN3pQAXiMKU/</Link>
        <Description>Demonstrators protesting higher household electricity rates are blocking the Armenian capital's main avenue for a seventh straight day, but they plan to decide Sunday evening whether to call a halt to their protest after the president promised to suspend the rate hikes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Armenian demonstrators to decide whether to halt weeklong protest against electricity hikes
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Armenian newly weds adjust leaflets reading, "Armenian electricity network to Armenia", to a barricade across a street in downtown Yerevan , Armenia, Sunday, June 28, 2015. The president of Armenia on Saturday suspended hikes in household electricity rates in an effort to end the protests that have blocked the capital's main avenue for six straight days. The demonstrators, however, didn't disperse. (Areg Balayan/ PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Demonstrators wave national flags during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The president of Armenia on Saturday suspended hikes in household electricity rates in an effort to end the protests that have blocked the capitals main avenue for six straight days. The demonstrators, however, didnt disperse. (Karo Sahakyan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Demonstrators sing patriotic songs during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The president of Armenia on Saturday suspended hikes in household electricity rates in an effort to end the protests that have blocked the capitals main avenue for six straight days. The demonstrators, however, didnt disperse. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Demonstrators wave national flags during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The president of Armenia on Saturday suspended hikes in household electricity rates in an effort to end the protests that have blocked the capitals main avenue for six straight days. The demonstrators, however, didnt disperse. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Demonstrators sing songs during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Saturday, June 27, 2015. The president of Armenia on Saturday suspended hikes in household electricity rates in an effort to end the protests that have blocked the capitals main avenue for six straight days. The demonstrators, however, didnt disperse. (Karo Sahakyan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
YEREVAN, Armenia  Demonstrators protesting higher household electricity rates are blocking the Armenian capital's main avenue for a seventh straight day, but they plan to decide Sunday evening whether to call a halt to their protest after the president promised to suspend the rate hikes.
President Serzh Sargsyan announced late Saturday that the government would bear the burden of the higher electricity costs until an international audit of the power company could be done. The protesters claim the Russian-owned utility is riddled with corruption.
Protest organizer Vaghinak Shushanian said Sunday the demonstrators could claim success in battle, if not a complete victory, and it made sense for them to take a break. But he said the decision on whether to halt the protest would be made by the demonstrators in the evening.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:02:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UN human rights chief raises concern over breadth, vagueness of China's new security law</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/HlViTNSje3Q/</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN human rights chief raises concern over breadth, vagueness of China's new security law
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
<<<<<<< HEAD
BERLIN  The United Nations' human rights chief says he is worried by the breadth and vagueness of new national security legislation approved last week by China's legislature.
Zeid Raad al-Hussein said Tuesday that the National Security Law "raises many concerns due to its extraordinarily broad scope coupled with the vagueness of its terminology and definitions."
He added in a statement that "it leaves the door wide open to further restrictions of the rights and freedoms of Chinese citizens, and to even tighter control of civil society by the Chinese authorities than there is already."
The new legislation reinforces government controls over cyberspace and covers a wide range of other areas including the economy, social stability, territorial integrity, the military, culture, finance, technology, the environment and food safety.
=======
KABUL, Afghanistan  An Afghan official says the Islamic State group now has a presence in three provinces but that the government is determined to drive it out.
Zafar Hashimi, the Afghan president's deputy spokesman, said Sunday that the group  which controls large areas of Iraq and Syria  is active in the eastern Nangarhar, western Farah and southern Helmand provinces.
Hashimi says security forces have launched successful operations against the IS group but gave no further details.
The Taliban, which have been at war with the government for nearly 14 years and are also active in the three provinces, have warned the IS group to stay out of the country. Both groups want Islamic rule but the Taliban do not recognize the IS group's self-styled caliphate.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:46:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisian govt says some limits on freedoms needed to ensure security</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/-gHpr8gAQCI/</Link>
        <Description>Tunisia's government is urging its citizens to sacrifice some of their freedoms to better protect the country from attacks like the mass shooting at a beach resort last month that killed 38 people, mostly tourists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisian govt says some limits on freedoms needed to ensure security
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
TUNIS, Tunisia  Tunisia's government is urging its citizens to sacrifice some of their freedoms to better protect the country from attacks like the mass shooting at a beach resort last month that killed 38 people, mostly tourists.
Government minister Kamel Jendoubi on Tuesday defended the president's decision to impose a state of emergency Saturday in response to the June 26 attack, fearing new extremist violence. As Tunisia's Parliament resumes debate on an anti-terrorism law, Jendoubi told reporters "we must accept ... that some limits must exist to face these threats."
Rights groups have said some measures in the new law  such as long detention periods and a broad definition of terrorism  could threaten the freedoms gained in Tunisia's Arab Spring uprising and its ensuing transition to democracy.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:42:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Swiss court denies appeal for release on bail by 1 of 7 men arrested in FIFA bribery case</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/G-mX5y9P-Z4/</Link>
        <Description>Switzerland's Federal Criminal Court has rejected a request for release on bail by one of the seven men arrested on corruption charges last month in a raid on FIFA's luxury hotel in Zurich.</Description>
        <MainBody>Swiss court denies appeal for release on bail by 1 of 7 men arrested in FIFA bribery case
Published June 26, 2015
BELLINZONA, Switzerland  Switzerland's Federal Criminal Court has rejected a request for release on bail by one of the seven men arrested on corruption charges last month in a raid on FIFA's luxury hotel in Zurich.
The Swiss court said "there was a risk that the appellant would abscond if released."
The court did not identify the man, who was among seven football and marketing officials arrested on May 27 at the request of American authorities investigating bribery and racketeering.
He was the only one who appealed against detention in Zurich-area prisons as the seven await extradition to the United States.
The court says the man's arguments for release of "advanced age and poor state of health, were not regarded as sufficient to counter the risk of absconding."
Formal extradition requests must be filed by July 3.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:57:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis encourages members of many religions to work together to care for the Earth</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/UjFHlXZNoz0/</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis is encouraging people of different religions to work together to care for the Earth, which he calls our "common house." Greeting people Sunday from his studio window, Francis praised a few hundred people who marched to St. Peter's Square under the banner "One Earth, one family." Marchers included Christians, Muslims, Jews, Hindus and others.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis encourages members of many religions to work together to care for the Earth
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
People hold a banner reading ' Climate action Now ' in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greeting people Sunday from his studio window, Francis praised a few hundred people who marched to St. Peter's Square under the banner "one Earth, one family." Marchers included Christians, Muslims, Jews, Hindus and others. Their route began near the French embassy to remind people of a climate change conference in Paris later this year. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)(The Associated Press)
People hold banners reading ' Climate action Now ' and ' Many Faiths, One Planet ' in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greeting people Sunday from his studio window, Francis praised a few hundred people who marched to St. Peter's Square under the banner "one Earth, one family." Marchers included Christians, Muslims, Jews, Hindus and others. Their route began near the French embassy to remind people of a climate change conference in Paris later this year. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)(The Associated Press)
People hold banners reading ' Climate action Now ' and ' Many Faiths, One Planet ' in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greeting people Sunday from his studio window, Francis praised a few hundred people who marched to St. Peter's Square under the banner "one Earth, one family." Marchers included Christians, Muslims, Jews, Hindus and others. Their route began near the French embassy to remind people of a climate change conference in Paris later this year. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)(The Associated Press)
Bolivian pilgrims dressed in traditional costumes arrive to follow Pope Francis' Angelus noon prayer in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Pope Francis' trip to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay is set for July 6-12. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)(The Associated Press)
Bolivian pilgrims dressed in traditional costumes arrive to follow Pope Francis' Angelus noon prayer, in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Pope Francis' trip to Ecuador, Bolivia and Paraguay is set for July 6-12. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
VATICAN CITY  Pope Francis is encouraging people of different religions to work together to care for the Earth, which he calls our "common house."
Greeting people Sunday from his studio window, Francis praised a few hundred people who marched to St. Peter's Square under the banner "One Earth, one family."
Marchers included Christians, Muslims, Jews, Hindus and others. Their route began near the French embassy to remind people of an important climate change conference in Paris in December.
Francis said "I encourage the collaboration between persons and associations of different religions on behalf of an integral ecology." He offered good wishes to young people who are discussing "the care of the common house."
In a recent encyclical, or teaching document, Francis wrote passionately about the world's moral duty to save the Earth.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:39:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HSBC staff sacked over mock ISIS beheading video</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/lTLgz1PjQb8/</Link>
        <Description>Six staff from Britain's biggest bank have been sacked after a video appeared online showing them taking part in a mock Islamic State style killing.</Description>
        <MainBody>HSBC staff sacked over mock ISIS beheading video
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
Six staff from HSBC were fired after a video appeared online showing them taking part in a mock Islamic State style killing.
Six staff from Britain's biggest bank have been sacked after a video appeared online showing them taking part in a mock Islamic State style killing.
The footage is believed to have been taken during a team-building day and showed the workers dressed in overalls and balaclavas at a go-karting center.
They were seen staging a beheading scene with five of them laughing and joking as a colleague in an orange jumpsuit knelt at their feet.
One clutched a coat hanger, apparently as a fake knife, while another held the man in the jumpsuit by the shoulders.
According to The Sun newspaper a worker shouted "Allahu Akbar" - meaning God is greatest in Arabic.
An HSBC spokesman said: "We do not tolerate inappropriate behavior.
"As soon as The Sun brought this video to our attention we took the decision to sack the individuals involved.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:27:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus overturns, hit by truck on highway in eastern China, killing at least 10 people</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/KAm-OdEDcbo/</Link>
        <Description>Chinese officials say a bus overturned on a highway and then was hit by an oncoming truck in eastern China, killing at least 10 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus overturns, hit by truck on highway in eastern China, killing at least 10 people
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BEIJING  Chinese officials say a bus overturned on a highway and then was hit by an oncoming truck in eastern China, killing at least 10 people.
The government of Wuhu city in Anhui province said a number of other people were injured in the accident Friday and that its cause is being investigated.
State broadcaster China Central Television said the bus overturned into the opposite lane of the highway and was hit by the truck.
The number of people in the two vehicles was not immediately known.
Road accidents in China are often caused by poor driving habits, inadequate maintenance, overloading and dangerous mountain roads. The number of motorists has been rapidly increasing.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:27:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officials: Suspect in beheading of French businessman admits to investigators that he did it</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/yInRTXeAikE/</Link>
        <Description>French officials say the main suspect in the beheading of a French transportation company manager has admitted to police he carried out the killing that authorities have called a terror attack.</Description>
        <MainBody>Officials: Suspect in beheading of French businessman admits to investigators that he did it
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
PARIS  French officials say the main suspect in the beheading of a French transportation company manager has admitted to police he carried out the killing that authorities have called a terror attack.
Yassine Salhi, a deliveryman with a history of ties to Islamic extremists, remained in custody Sunday along with his wife and sister.
Security officials say investigators have found no links to any international terror group in the attack Friday. They spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation is continuing.
Salhi, arrested Friday, was to be transferred to counterterrorism police headquarters outside Paris. He allegedly crashed a truck into a U.S.-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employer's head on the factory's gate. Officials say he sent a "selfie" of himself and the victim to a Canadian mobile phone number.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:29:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jewish officials protest art installation at Polish museum</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/a1M-SemUjzo/</Link>
        <Description>Jewish officials are furious over a video installation at a Polish museum that shows naked men and women playing a game of tag in a gas chamber.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jewish officials protest art installation at Polish museum
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 livefyre Email Print
WARSAW, Poland  Jewish officials are furious over a video installation at a Polish museum that shows naked men and women playing a game of tag in a gas chamber.
Efraim Zuroff, director of the Simon Wiesenthal Center in Jerusalem, called the exhibit at the Museum of Contemporary Art in Krakow "so offensive and so disgusting that we found it necessary to protest."
"Game of Tag," made in 1999 by Polish artist Artur Zmijewski, has for years been accused of violating the dignity of Holocaust victims.
In response to protests, the museum put it behind an enclosure with a warning.
But Zuroff and other Jewish officials say it isn't enough. He said it is "simply incomprehensible" that the video is being shown in Poland, where Nazi Germany killed millions of Jews and non-Jews.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:12:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican signs treaty with "State of Palestine," hopes it will encourage peace with Israel</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/4aGXHEtIbf4/</Link>
        <Description>The Vatican has signed a treaty with the "State of Palestine" and said it hopes the official recognition will help stimulate peace with Israel.</Description>
        <MainBody>Vatican signs treaty with "State of Palestine," hopes it will encourage peace with Israel
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
VATICAN CITY  The Vatican has signed a treaty with the "State of Palestine" and said it hopes the official recognition will help stimulate peace with Israel.
Vatican Foreign Minister Paul Gallagher and his Palestinian counterpart, Riad al-Malki, signed the treaty at a ceremony Friday in the Vatican.
Israel had expressed its disappointment when the Vatican announced last month that it had reached final agreement with the "State of Palestine" on the treaty regulating the life of the Catholic Church in the Palestinian territories.
Gallagher said he hoped the Vatican's recognition "may in some way be a stimulus to bringing a definitive end to the long-standing Israeli-Palestinian conflict." He added the treaty could be a model for other Mideast countries.
It marks the first legal recognition by the Vatican of the Palestinian state.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:33:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mayor: Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; media report 1 adult killed</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/tkxDW-j_sWA/</Link>
        <Description>A bus carrying British schoolchildren has gone off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mayor: Bus carrying British schoolchildren crashes in Belgium; media report 1 adult killed
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BRUSSELS  A bus carrying British schoolchildren has gone off the highway and overturned near the Belgian coast.
The mayor of Middelkerke, Janna Rommel-Opstaele, said one person was killed in the Sunday morning accident on the E-40 highway. The mayor said all of the children survived.
Belgian media said the person killed was an adult accompanying the children and the driver was also reportedly hurt.
Belgian highway authorities said the vehicle apparently went out of control, struck the pillar of a bridge, then shot off the road.
The Flemish broadcasting company VTM said the bus had been carrying 34 children and six adults. Some of the children were taken to Middelkerke to be treated for minor injuries.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:17:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>civilian death toll from conflict in Yemen rises to more than 1,500, over 3,600 injured</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/jz1PJLxhlmU/</Link>
        <Description>The United Nations' human rights office says the number of civilians killed in three months of violence in Yemen has risen above 1,500.</Description>
        <MainBody>civilian death toll from conflict in Yemen rises to more than 1,500, over 3,600 injured
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BERLIN  The United Nations' human rights office says the number of civilians killed in three months of violence in Yemen has risen above 1,500.
The U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights said Tuesday that, between June 17 and July 3, at least 92 civilians were killed and another 179 injured.
It said that brings the total number of civilians killed since March 27 to 1,528, while 3,605 have been injured.
Yemen's fighting pits Houthi rebels and troops loyal to the former president against southern separatists, local and tribal militias, Sunni Islamic militants and loyalists of President Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi, who is now based in Saudi Arabia.
The rebels seized the capital, Sanaa, in September. In March, a Saudi-led coalition began launching airstrikes against the rebels and their allies.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:02:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protesters in Armenia remain on capital's main avenue as standoff with government continues</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/kO8WcLwqPOE/</Link>
        <Description>Demonstrators protesting against a hike in electricity prices are dancing and singing on the Armenian capital's main avenue, maintaining pressure on the government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Protesters in Armenia remain on capital's main avenue as standoff with government continues
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Armenian protesters shout anti-government slogans during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian protesters sing folk songs while waving a national flag during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian protesters dance during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian riot police block the road next to protesters during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Armenian protesters wave a national flag during a protest rally against a hike in electricity prices in Yerevan, Armenia, Thursday, June 25, 2015. Armenia's premier has rejected demonstrators' demand to annul a hike in electricity prices, a stance that signals no end in sight for the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years. (Hrant Khachatryan/PAN Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
YEREVAN, Armenia  Demonstrators protesting against a hike in electricity prices are dancing and singing on the Armenian capital's main avenue, maintaining pressure on the government.
Hundreds of protesters gathered on the road for a fifth straight day Friday behind a barricade of large trash containers separating them from police. Others were hiding from sweltering heat under roadside trees and umbrellas.
Following Monday's unsuccessful attempt to end the protest by force, authorities have taken a wait-and-see approach and police didn't interfere with the protest.
There was no end in sight, however, to the worst unrest the ex-Soviet nation has seen in years as the government rejected the protesters' demand to annul the price hike. The country's power grid is controlled by a Russian electricity giant, and Moscow watched the protest with concern.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:25:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece awaits ECB decision on keeping emergency liquidity assistance for Greek banks</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/SDVesDMxJMA/</Link>
        <Description>Greece is anxiously awaiting a decision by the European Central Bank on whether to increase the emergency liquidity assistance banks can draw on from the country's central bank.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece awaits ECB decision on keeping emergency liquidity assistance for Greek banks
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
FILE - In this Sept. 9, 2014 file photo barbed wire is fixed on the fence around the new headquarters of the European Central Bank in Frankfurt, Germany, Tuesday, Sept.9, 2014. Greece is anxiously awaiting a decision by the European Central Bank on whether to increase the emergency liquidity assistance banks can draw on from the countrys central bank, as worried Greeks continue to line up at ATM machines after the prime minister called for a referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in return for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Michael Probst, File)(The Associated Press)
A man walks past a graffiti made by street artist N_Grams  that  read ''NO'' in German but also ''YES, IN'' in Greek language in Athens, on Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans.(AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
ATHENS, Greece  Greece is anxiously awaiting a decision by the European Central Bank on whether to increase the emergency liquidity assistance banks can draw on from the country's central bank.
Worried Greeks on Sunday kept lining up at ATM machines after the prime minister called Saturday for a referendum on creditors' financial proposals in return for rescue loans. Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' move has startled Greece's European partners and thrown the country's bailout negotiations with international lenders into turmoil.
If the ECB decides Sunday not to increase the emergency liquidity, which currently stands at just under 90 billion euros ($100 billion), Greece's banks will soon run out of cash and restrictions on transactions will likely be imposed.
Parliament approved Tsipras' referendum call early Sunday, with the national vote set for July 5.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:36:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>German prosecutors ask for 3½ years in prison for 94-year-old former Auschwitz guard</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/mcNgzpKRigk/</Link>
        <Description>German prosecutors are asking for 3½ years in prison for a 94-year-old former SS sergeant who served at the Auschwitz death camp in Nazi-occupied Poland.</Description>
        <MainBody>German prosecutors ask for 3 years in prison for 94-year-old former Auschwitz guard
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Former SS officer Oskar Groening , 94, sits in the courtroom in Lueneburg , northern Germany, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Groening is charged with 300,000 counts of accessory to murder on allegations he helped the Auschwitz Nazi death camp function by sorting cash and valuables seized from Jews. (Philipp Schulze/Pool Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Former SS officer Oskar Groening , 94, sits in the courtroom in Lueneburg , northern Germany, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Groening is charged with 300,000 counts of accessory to murder on allegations he helped the Auschwitz Nazi death camp function by sorting cash and valuables seized from Jews. (Philipp Schulze/Pool Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Former SS officer Oskar Groening , 94, sits in the courtroom in Lueneburg , northern Germany, Tuesday, July 7, 2015. Groening is charged with 300,000 counts of accessory to murder on allegations he helped the Auschwitz Nazi death camp function by sorting cash and valuables seized from Jews. (Philipp Schulze/Pool Photo via AP)(The Associated Press)
Previous Next
BERLIN  German prosecutors are asking for 3 years in prison for a 94-year-old former SS sergeant who served at the Auschwitz death camp in Nazi-occupied Poland.
Oskar Groening has admitted guarding prisoners' baggage after they were unloaded from cattle cars onto the camp's ramps, and collecting and counting money stolen from the new arrivals and sending it to Berlin.
The dpa news agency reported prosecutors said in closing arguments Tuesday that his role helped the camp function, and he should be convicted of 300,000 counts of accessory to murder for those killed while he was there.
When his trial began in April, Groening said he felt moral guilt but it was up to the court to decide if he was legally guilty of a crime.
A verdict is expected this month.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:46:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bomb strikes Shiite mosque in Kuwait after Friday prayers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/Cp7wafGjffU/</Link>
        <Description>A bomb has exploded in a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bomb strikes Shiite mosque in Kuwait after Friday prayers
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
KUWAIT CITY  A bomb has exploded in a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital.
The bomb struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque in a busy area of Kuwait City's al-Sawabir district. Witness Abdullah al-Saffar was at the mosque at the time. He says the explosions took place on the mosque grounds following Friday prayers, and that there were casualties.
There was no claim of responsibility, however the Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for bombings at two different Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
Friday midday prayers are typically the most crowded of the week, and attendance increases during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, which started last week.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:54:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait names Saudi citizen as bomber in deadly Shiite mosque attack, says he flew in at dawn</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/25G58OTsQ9U/</Link>
        <Description>Kuwaiti authorities are identifying the suicide bomber behind Friday's attack on a Shiite mosque that killed 27 people as a Saudi citizen who flew into the Gulf nation just hours before he blew himself up.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait names Saudi citizen as bomber in deadly Shiite mosque attack, says he flew in at dawn
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
KUWAIT CITY  Kuwaiti authorities are identifying the suicide bomber behind Friday's attack on a Shiite mosque that killed 27 people as a Saudi citizen who flew into the Gulf nation just hours before he blew himself up.
The Interior Ministry on Sunday named the bomber as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa and said he was born in 1992, making him 22 or 23 years old.
It said in a statement carried by the official Kuwait News Agency that he arrived on a flight to Kuwait International Airport at dawn Friday.
The ministry said earlier it arrested several suspects, including a Kuwaiti, in connection with the attack.
A local affiliate of the Islamic State group claimed responsibility for the attack during midday Friday prayers inside one of Kuwait's oldest Shiite mosques.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:12:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek coast guard searches for up to 21 missing migrants after boat sinking in Aegean</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/Tnt06svtK5s/</Link>
        <Description>Greek authorities have launched a search and rescue operation in the eastern Aegean after a sailboat carrying dozens of migrants sank between the small islands of Agathonisi and Farmakonisi, near the Turkish coast.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek coast guard searches for up to 21 missing migrants after boat sinking in Aegean
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ATHENS, Greece  Greek authorities have launched a search and rescue operation in the eastern Aegean after a sailboat carrying dozens of migrants sank between the small islands of Agathonisi and Farmakonisi, near the Turkish coast.
The Greek coast guard said six people were rescued by a Greek helicopter, and another 10 by the Turkish coast guard while between 17 and 21 people were missing after the boat sank Tuesday.
Those rescued by the Turkish crews said there had been between 33 and 37 people on board. It was not clear why the boat sank, or what the migrants' nationalities were.
Tens of thousands of migrants have made their way from the Turkish coast to Greek islands so far this year, hoping to make their way to more prosperous European Union countries.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police arrest Pakistani man, suspected Qaida member, accused in 2009 Peshawar market attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/jX40KoG05sA/</Link>
        <Description>Police say they have arrested a Pakistani man suspected of helping organize the 2009 attack on a market in Peshawar that killed more than 100 people, the latest arrest in a decade-long investigation into an Italy-based terror network with ties to al Qaida.</Description>
        <MainBody>Police arrest Pakistani man, suspected Qaida member, accused in 2009 Peshawar market attack
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
ROME  Police say they have arrested a Pakistani man suspected of helping organize the 2009 attack on a market in Peshawar that killed more than 100 people, the latest arrest in a decade-long investigation into an Italy-based terror network with ties to al Qaida.
State police said in a statement Friday that the suspect, identified as a member of al Qaida, was arrested late Thursday at Rome's Leonardo da Vinci airport as he arrived on a flight from Islamabad.
On April 24, Italy's anti-terrorism police announced they had arrested nine people and issued arrest warrants for another nine as part of a probe into the network. Prosecutors said its members had plotted a 2010 attack on the Vatican that was never carried out.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:32:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Latest: Greece wants European Central Bank to keep giving its banks emergency help</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/swC284Ayp-4/</Link>
        <Description>The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations: ___ 12:25 p.m.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Latest: Greece wants European Central Bank to keep giving its banks emergency help
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
A traffic police officer looks the newspapers' front pages as the paper on the left reads ''NO'' with photo of the Greek Prime minister Alexis Tipras and the next one ''Dignity'' in Athens, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)(The Associated Press)
An elderly man passes a sign reads ''Greeks can't be blackmailed'' at a flea market in the port of Piraeus, near Athens, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)(The Associated Press)
An elderly man passes a shut gift shop as the sign reads ''Great Bargains - Low Prices'' in the port of Piraeus, near Athens, Sunday, June 28, 2015.  Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)(The Associated Press)
Crew members and passengers of a ferry prepare for departure to Aegean Sea islands from the port of Piraeus, near Athens, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)(The Associated Press)
A vendor hangs products which all cost one euro, at a market in the port of Piraeus, near Athens, Sunday, June 28, 2015. Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)(The Associated Press)
ATHENS, Greece  The latest developments on Greece's bailout negotiations:
___
12:25 p.m.
A Greek finance official says the government expects the European Central Bank to continue approving emergency liquidity assistance that Greek banks can draw even after Tuesday, when Greece's international bailout officially expires.
The ECB was expected to meet Sunday to decide what action to take about Greece. The central is bank is under pressure to end that emergency assistance.
A decision by Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras to call for a national referendum on creditor demands in exchange for bailout loans has thrown Greece's negotiations with its international lenders into turmoil. In response, other nations in the 19-nation eurozone are refusing to extend Greece's bailout program beyond its Tuesday expiration date.
Alternate Greek Finance Minister Nadia Valavani told private Mega television on Sunday "we are expecting the funding of Greek banks to continue normally via the ELA after Tuesday."
Worried Greeks have formed lines at ATM machines all weekend and some machines were running out of cash Sunday morning.
Valavani said the country's banks could see "business as usual" next week if they receive the emergency support "so long as there is calm" and Greeks don't attempt to withdraw all their savings.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:09:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Latest bomb blast blamed on Boko Haram kills 20 in northern Nigerian university town of Zaria</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/hDLp8t57zrc/</Link>
        <Description>The state governor says a bomb blast in Nigeria's northern university town of Zaria has killed 20 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Latest bomb blast blamed on Boko Haram kills 20 in northern Nigerian university town of Zaria
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
LAGOS, Nigeria  The state governor says a bomb blast in Nigeria's northern university town of Zaria has killed 20 people.
Gov. Nasir el-Rufai of Kaduna state is urging citizens to avoid crowded public places including mosques and churches as Islamic extremists Boko Haram extend the breadth and tempo of attacks that have killed some 300 people in a week.
El-Rufai used Twitter to report Tuesday's "terrorist bomb attack." Local media said the explosion occurred at the government headquarters as civil servants were assembling for a training course.
Nigeria's police force announced increased security around mosques and churches after Boko Haram bomb and shooting attacks Sunday killed more than 60 people in a mosque and posh Muslim restaurant in central Jos city and at an evangelical Christian church in northeastern Potiskum town.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:49:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>1 dead in attack, explosion at French gas factory; Arabic banners found near decapitated body</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/thgXQgyb6wY/</Link>
        <Description>One person was beheaded Friday in an attack and explosion at a gas factory in southeastern France that left multiple people wounded, two officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>1 dead in attack, explosion at French gas factory; Arabic banners found near decapitated body
Published June 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
PARIS  One person was beheaded Friday in an attack and explosion at a gas factory in southeastern France that left multiple people wounded, two officials said. Banners with Arabic writing were found near the body, one of the officials said.
Details of the attack were sketchy but two French officials said it began mid-morning in the Isere region when the men crashed a car into the entrance of the factory and into gas canisters, touching off the explosion. One attacker was arrested, they said.
The decapitated body and the banners were found near the factory entrance, one of the officials said.
Both officials spoke condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the news media.
France went on high alert after an attack in January that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including the Islamic extremist attackers.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:24:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Burundi: 2 civilians killed in overnight grenade attacks blamed on police in the capital</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/world/~3/lNmrisEtDBU/</Link>
        <Description>Witnesses say two people have been killed in overnight attacks that they believe were carried out by Burundian police.</Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi: 2 civilians killed in overnight grenade attacks blamed on police in the capital
Published June 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
BUJUMBURA, Burundi  Witnesses say two people have been killed in overnight attacks that they believe were carried out by Burundian police.
Witnesses in Jabe neighborhood in the nation's capital of Bujumbura, reported intense gunfire Saturday night in an apparent police crackdown on areas seen as hosting anti-government protesters.
Mohamed Masumbuko said his brother, Masumbuko Prime Abdul, was killed in a grenade attack, his "face completely shredded."
Another victim, Patrick Ndikumana, was first hit by a bullet but was killed in a subsequent grenade attack, according to witness Joshua Ngendakumana.
It was not immediately possible to get a comment from the police, who have previously blamed an escalation of violence on protesters opposed to a third term for President Pierre Nkurunziza.
Parliamentary elections are scheduled to take place Monday despite the violence.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
