<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:24:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alleged Winnipeg bomber Guido Amsel to appear in court Tuesday</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096097/alleged-winnipeg-bomber-guido-amsel-to-appear-in-court-tuesday/</Link>
        <Description>A man accused of sending letter bombs to Winnipeg lawyers and his ex-wife is scheduled to make his first court appearance Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 9:24 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 9:29 am
Alleged Winnipeg bomber Guido Amsel to appear in court Tuesday
By   Staff The Canadian Press
Guido Amsel, 49, is shown in this undated handout photo. Winnipeg police investigating the bombing of a law firm say if there are any more suspicious packages in the mail they will likely be found in the next day or so. THE CANADIAN PRESS/HO - Winnipeg Police Service
Winnipeg Police Service handout / Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Google’s new pod-like self-driving cars hit streets of California</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077146/googles-new-pod-like-self-driving-cars-hit-streets-of-california/</Link>
        <Description>The latest models of Google's self-driving cars are now cruising the streets near the Internet company's Silicon Valley headquarters.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 8:34 am
Googles new pod-like self-driving cars hit streets of California
By   Michael Liedtke The Associated Press
Google's new self-driving prototype car drives around a parking lot during a demonstration at Google campus in Mountain View, Calif. The car, which needs no gas pedal or steering wheel, has made its debut on public roads.
AP Photo/Tony Avelar
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
SAN FRANCISCO  The latest models of Googles self-driving cars are now cruising the streets near the Internet companys Silicon Valley headquarters as an ambitious project to transform the way people get around shifts into its next phase.
Story continues below
This marks the first time that the pod-like, two-seat vehicles have been allowed on public roads since Google unveiled the next generation of its self-driving fleet more than a year ago. The cars had previously been confined to a private track on a former Air Force base located about 120 miles southeast of San Francisco.
Google announced last month that it would begin testing the curious-looking cars last month , but hadnt specified the timing until Tuesday when it disclosed the vehicles are driving up to 25 miles per hour on the roads around its Mountain View, California, office.
READ MORE: Googles driverless car looks cool, but could it handle a Canadian winter?
Google had installed its robotic driving technology in Lexus sports utility vehicles and Toyota Priuses during the first few years of testing before developing the smaller prototype. The new models are designed to work without a steering wheel or brake pedal, although the vehicles will be equipped with those features during the initial runs on public roads.
A human will also ride in the cars to take control in emergencies, just as has been the case with the self-driving Lexus vehicles during the past six years.
The debut of the pod-like car will help Google get a better understanding on how well its technology works around other vehicles steered by people.
Last year, Google Inc. told reporters it hoped to have a 100 of the self-driving prototypes in its fleet by now , but the company said it has only built 25 of them so far. All 25 have received permission from Californias Department of Motor Vehicles to drive neighbourhood roads.
If all goes well, Google hopes to gain regulatory clearance to remove the steering wheel, brake pedal and emergency driver from the prototype. Company executives have expressed hope that self-driving cars using its technology will be joining the flow of daily traffic by the end of this decade.
READ MORE: Google acknowledges 11 accidents involving self-driving cars in 6 years
The earlier models of Googles self-driving cars had been involved in 13 minor accidents through more than 1.8 million miles on the roads, according to the company. Google blamed the collisions on other vehicles in every instance except one when the company says one of its own employees was steering.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:26:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Portage Avenue fire forces ladder rescue of elderly Winnipeg man</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077151/portage-avenue-fire-forces-ladder-rescue-of-elderly-winnipeg-man/</Link>
        <Description>Firefighters used a ladder truck to rescue an elderly man from a St. James apartment block during a blaze Thursday night, a witness says.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 8:26 am
Portage Avenue fire forces ladder rescue of elderly Winnipeg man
By Lara Schroeder Web Producer Global News
A fire at the Park West Apartments caused $1 million damage, fire officials say.
Rudi Pawlychyn / Global News
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:10:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: SpaceX to launch supplies to space station</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2080270/watch-spacex-to-launch-supplies-to-space-station/</Link>
        <Description>Astronauts aboard the International Space Station are getting ready to receive more supplies.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WINNIPEG  A man accused of sending letter bombs to Winnipeglawyers and his ex-wife is scheduled to make his first courtappearance Tuesday on charges including attempted murder.
Police allege Guido Amsel became so enraged over perceivedmistreatment at the hands of his former wife and lawyers who hadbeen involved in the dispute, he sent explosive devices to theiroffices though Canada Post.
READ MORE: Winnipeg letter bombs hidden in voice recorders: police
Maria Mitousis, his ex-wifes lawyer, lost one of her hands whenthe first letter bomb went off last Friday.
Police detonated two more devices over the weekend and warnedjustice officials that more could be found in the next day or so.
The situation has unnerved many city residents and prompteddozens of reports of suspicious packages.
City hall and a nearby Canada Post office were briefly evacuatedMonday.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:20:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sinkhole closes eastbound lanes on Eglinton Ave.</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096147/sinkhole-closes-eastbound-lanes-on-eglinton-ave/</Link>
        <Description>Several lanes of eastbound Eglinton Ave. are closed Tuesday morning as a result of a large sinkhole.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 9:20 am
Sinkhole closes eastbound lanes on Eglinton Ave.
By   Staff Global News
Jeremy Cohn / Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO  Several lanes of eastbound Eglinton Ave. are closed Tuesday morning as a result of a large sinkhole.
HAZARD:  Large sinkhole on Eglinton east of Keele near Richardson, witnesses indicate hole is approx. 20 feet, use alternative routes^dm
 Toronto Police OPS (@TPSOperations) July 7, 2015
Toronto police issued an advisory over Twitter just after 8 a.m. asking motorist to avoid the area east of Keele near Richardson.
Witnesses indicate the hole is approximately six metres in length.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:57:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Minivan crashes into southwest Calgary home</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096043/van-crashes-into-southwest-calgary-home/</Link>
        <Description>Police are searching for the driver of a silver minivan that crashed into a home in Upper Mount Royal on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:57 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 9:01 am
Minivan crashes into southwest Calgary home
By Melissa Ramsay Online Reporter Global News
Police hunt for the driver that smashed into a Calgary home on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
Global News
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:42:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officers hunt for escaped NY prisoner near Quebec border</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2080259/officers-hunt-for-escaped-ny-prisoner-near-quebec-border/</Link>
        <Description>Police hope the solo escapee will finally succumb to the stress of little sleep, scant food and biting bugs.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 28, 2015 9:42 am
Updated: June 28, 2015 9:50 am
Officers hunt for escaped NY prisoner near Quebec border
By   Michael Balsamo And John Kekis The Associated Press
A New York State Police trooper stands in the rain at a roadblock on Sunday, June 28, 2015, in Malone, N.Y.
AP Photo/Mike Groll
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
WINNIPEG  Firefighters used a ladder truck to rescue an elderly man from a St. James apartment block during a blaze Thursday night, a witness says.
Firefighters evacuated the Park West Apartments after they were called to fight a blaze in a seventh-floor suite at about 11 p.m.
Flames shot out of the back windows of the building at 2366 Portage Ave., a resident told Global News.
He saw firefighters use a ladder truck to remove a man in a wheelchair from his suite, said the witness, who didnt give his name. He believes the elderly resident is 93 years old.
Firefighters quickly got the flames under control and no one was seriously injured, although some residents were treated at the scene for smoke inhalation, police said.
Fire officials estimate damages at roughly $1 million, including extensive water damage.
 With files from Rudi Pawlychyn
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:23:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Trey Lyles first Saskatoon-born player to be drafted into the NBA</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077154/trey-lyles-first-saskatoon-born-player-to-be-drafted-into-the-nba/</Link>
        <Description>Utah Jazz select Kentucky forward Trey Lyles, the first Saskatoon-born player to be drafted into the NBA.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saskatoon-born Trey Lyles tops Canadians in March Madness
His playmaking with the ball, his handle  ability to keep his head up and play unselfish basketball is superior, Lindsey said. Trey made some sacrifices not playing as many minutes at the four, which is his natural position. But playing the three, he learned to handle the ball, learned to execute. A big part of our game going forward is bigs that can guard smalls.
Lyles, who was born in Saskatoon but moved to Indianapolis at a young age, is the first Saskatoon-born player to be drafted into the NBA.
READ MORE: Timberwolves take Kentuckys Karl-Anthony Towns with No. 1 pick in NBA draft
The Jazz then took another Canadian, 6-foot-4, 186-pound Boston College guard Olivier Hanlan of Aylmer, Que., with the No. 42 pick. He averaged 19.5 points, 4.2 rebounds and 4.2 assists as a junior and led the Atlantic Coast Conference in points per game. Daniel Diez from Spain was selected with the No. 54 pick and traded to the Trail Blazers for cash considerations.
Lyles averaged 8.7 points and 5.2 rebounds for the Wildcats and was named to the Southeastern Conference All-Freshman team after his lone collegiate season. He has a 7-1 wingspan with large hands and Lindsey believes he can get bigger.
I know its a young team and I feel  going to that situation is perfect, Lyles said. Im a guy that can step in and help contribute immediately.
Being able to contribute offensively and defensively, just being a guy that goes out there and if they need a bucket, Ill be able to be a guy that can go get one. And just be a high-character guy thats going to fit in.
The Jazz went into the off-season needing shooting after averaging the fifth-fewest points per game last season. Frontcourt depth became a priority after the team moved Enes Kanter to the Thunder.
Lyles, 19, could fill a stretch-four role one day, though he shot just 13.8 per cent from 3-point range. He worked out with the Jazz on June 13 and said he wasnt able to show all of his game on a Kentucky roster that had four players selected in the first 13 picks. He knocked down 25 of 40 corner 3-point shots during his workout with the Jazz.
Lindsey said Lyles is a better rebounder than his numbers show and called him a good midrange shooter that should be able to improve. He also thinks Lyles can be a very solid corner-3 shooter in time.
Im able to knock it down consistently, Lyles said. Coach and managers for Jazz were able to see that. Its something I have confidence in.
Lyles has the mobility to guard multiple positions and the pick-and-roll while his length is something the Jazz covet. Point guard Trey Burke is the only player projected to be in the top-eight rotation, not including Lyles, that is under 6-foot-6.
More playmaking ability for myself and my teammates, Lyles said when asked what he couldnt show at Kentucky. Being able to score more. Post up a little bit more. I didnt get to play a lot of the four. Just a whole lot of versatility.
The Jazz finished the season with a 38-44 record, a 13-game improvement from the 2013-14 season, and were slotted No. 12 after a tiebreak drawing with the Pacers. The improvement was the second-best in the Western Conference and the sixth-best in the NBA.
Lyles said he can fill any role.
Im a guy whos pretty flexible on the court and pretty much can do whatever the coach asks of me, Lyles said. I feel comfortable in any kind of lineup. It doesnt matter to me. I just know that Ill be able to transform to anything thats needed of me.
The Jazz had the sixth-best win percentage (.655) after the All-Star break and aspires to be in the playoff race next season. The five teams in front of them  Warriors, Clippers, Cavaliers, Spurs and Rockets  were all playoff teams.
Defence was the Jazzs calling card during their post All-Star success. The Jazz ranked No. 1 in the league, holding teams to 89.0 points per game and No. 2 in opponent field goal percentage (42.2) during that period. The emergence of 7-foot-1 shot blocker Rudy Gobert after Kanter was traded solidified the defence.
The offence, however, was the second-worst in the league after the break and where the biggest strides can be made during the off-season.
The Associated Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:22:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man dead following shooting in Reserve Mines, Cape Breton</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077145/man-dead-following-shooting-in-reserve-mines-cape-breton/</Link>
        <Description>Cape Breton Regional Police were called to a residence on Sydney Road around 8:15 Thursday evening after reports of a shooting. </Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 8:22 am
Man dead following shooting in Reserve Mines, Cape Breton
By Natasha Pace Reporter Global News
Investigators say a male victim in his late 20s was found suffering from gunshot wounds. He was treated by EHS but pronounced dead at the scene.
Courtesy of Jason Dawe
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
CALGARY  Police are searching for the driver of a silver minivan that crashed into a home in Upper Mount Royal on Tuesday.
The collision took place in the 1000 block of Frontenac Avenue S.W. just before 4:30 a.m.
Officers say the garage suffered most of the damage.
The driver allegedly reversed the vehicle and drove off. He was last seen travelling east on 30th Avenue S.W.
We were sleeping we heard the loud bang and looked out the window and I saw a silver minivan taking off and I knew exactly what happened, said the homeowner. You can see he sped right through the traffic circle and hit the garage.
The Calgary Police Service and the Calgary Fire Department are investigating.
 With files from Sarah Offin
Police hunt for the driver that smashed into a Calgary home on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
Global News
=======
HALIFAX Cape Breton Regional Police were called to a residence on Sydney Road around 8:15 Thursday evening after reports of a shooting.
Investigators say a male victim in his late 20s was found suffering from gunshot wounds. He was treated by EHS but pronounced dead at the scene.
Police were looking for a suspect who fled the scene in a small red vehicle with no hub caps on the passenger side.
Overnight, officers were able to identify a 25-year-old suspect who had traveled to the Halifax area. He was arrested by Halifax Regional Police and remains in custody, no charges have been laid yet.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:12:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill 19 in attack on Tunisian coastal resort</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077121/gunmen-kill-at-least-7-people-in-attack-on-2-hotels-on-tunisia-coast/</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen opened fire on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, Tunisia, killing at least seven people.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 8:12 am
Updated: June 26, 2015 8:44 am
Gunmen kill 19 in attack on Tunisian coastal resort
By Staff The Associated Press/Global News
Global News
=======
MALONE, N.Y.  Officers scouring dense and boggy woods for a surviving escaped killer took floodlights into the search area overnight, and others carrying rifles manned checkpoints and examined vehicles, opening trunks and peering into windows.
Franklin County Sheriff Kevin Mulverhill said late Saturday tips continued to pour in and he was optimistic David Sweat would be captured, perhaps within 48 hours.
Its going to be one of those phone calls that turns this case around, he said.
READ MORE: 1 of 2 escaped inmates killed by law enforcement, other on the run
Richard Matt  who once vowed never to be taken alive  was fatally shot Friday during an encounter with border patrol agents about 30 miles west of the prison he escaped from with Sweat on June 6. Sweat remained on the lam early Sunday, and about 1,200 searchers focused intensely on 22 square miles encompassing thick forests and heavy brush around where Matt was killed.
Police hoped the solo escapee would finally succumb to the stress of little sleep, scant food and biting bugs.
Anyone in the woods and on the run from the law so to speak is not getting a full eight hours sleep, theyre not eating well and they have to keep moving, Mulverhill said. Hes fatigued, tired, and hes going to make a mistake.
Sweat could have an even tougher time now without someone to take turns resting with and to watch his back, Clinton County Sheriff David Favro said.
Now its a one-man show and it makes it more difficult for him, Favro said. And Im sure fatigue is setting in for him as well, knowing the guy he was with has already been shot.
The manhunt broke open Friday afternoon when a person towing a camper heard a loud noise and thought a tire had blown. Finding there was no flat, the driver drove eight miles before looking again and finding a bullet hole in the trailer. A tactical team responding to the scene of the shot smelled gunpowder inside a cabin and saw evidence that someone had fled out the back door.
A noise  perhaps a cough  ultimately did Matt in. A border patrol team discovered Matt, who was shot after failing to heed a command to raise his hands.
Matt had a 20-gauge shotgun that was believed to have been taken from another cabin. The pair had apparently been relying on the remote regions many hunting camps and seasonal dwellings for supplies.
Matt, who turned 49 the day before he died, was serving 25 years to life at Clinton Correctional Facility for the killing and dismemberment of his former boss. Local residents were relieved that one killer was no longer roaming the woods, but the constant commotion of speeding police cruisers and helicopters pointed to the continued danger.
Half the threat is taken care of, but obviously David Sweat is on the loose, said Matt Maguire, who was waiting for a police escort to pick up some clothes from his house inside the search area. Maguire and his fiancee decided a week ago to stay with nearby relatives.
Sweat, 35, was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriffs deputy in Broome County in 2002. Mulverhill said investigators believe he may be armed.
Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a 2-foot-thick brick wall, squirmed through pipes and emerged from a manhole outside the prison.
While there have been no confirmed sightings of Sweat, police said investigators saw a second set of tracks near where Matt was shot.
Ultimately, how the chase ends is up to Sweat, Mulverhill said.
If hes willing to surrender to law enforcement then well place him in handcuffs and well bring him back into custody, he said.
If he chooses to resist or he chooses not to comply, then the results are his.
Associated Press writers Jim Fitzgerald in New York City and Michael Hill in Albany, New York, contributed to this report.
The Canadian Press, 2015
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:42:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RCMP looking for two suspects in Surrey home invasion</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096094/rcmp-looking-for-two-suspects-in-surrey-home-invasion/</Link>
        <Description>A report of an assault in the 14300-block of 72 Avenue came in to police at about 1:30 a.m. and upon arrival found a 35-year-old male suffering from injuries from an assault.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:42 am
RCMP looking for two suspects in Surrey home invasion
By Paula Baker Online News Producer Global News
File photo
File/Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
RCMP is at a home in the Newton neighbourhood of Surrey following an assault and a home invasion early Tuesday morning.
A report of an assault in the 14300-block of 72 Avenue came in to police at about 1:30 a.m. and upon arrival found a 35-year-old male suffering from injuries from an assault. The victim was taken to the hospital in stable condition with non-life threatening injuries.
An initial investigation has shown that two males broke into the home and assaulted on of the residents before fleeing. After speaking to neighbours and witnesses, police have found indications the incident was targeted and the involved individuals are known to each other.
Anyone with more information is asked to contact Surrey RCMP at 604-599-0502 or Crime Stoppers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:36:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seniors get free admission to the Calgary Stampede for Western Heritage Day</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096072/seniors-get-free-admission-to-the-calgary-stampede-for-western-heritage-day/</Link>
        <Description>If you’re planning on heading to the Calgary Stampede on Tuesday, there are some deals and discounts you may wish to take advantage of.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:36 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 8:46 am
Seniors get free admission to the Calgary Stampede for Western Heritage Day
By Melissa Ramsay Online Reporter Global News
The Calgary Stampede grounds on July 5th, 2014.
THE CANADIAN PRESS IMAGES/Larry MacDougal
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:59:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France beheading suspect sent gruesome ‘selfie’ to Canadian phone number</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2080244/france-beheading-suspect-sent-gruesome-selfie-to-canadian-phone-number/</Link>
        <Description>Canadian authorities are now involved in the case.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 28, 2015 8:59 am
France beheading suspect sent gruesome selfie to Canadian phone number
By   Jamey Keaten The Associated Press
Guards stand at the entrance of a street where criminal investigation police carried out a search at the home of a suspect in the Moines neighborhood of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, on June 26, 2015.
JEAN-PHILIPPE KSIAZEK/AFP/Getty Images
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
CALGARY  If youre planning on heading to the Calgary Stampede on Tuesday, there are some deals and discounts you may wish to take advantage of.
July 7th marks Western Heritage Day at the Stampede grounds, a time dedicated to the citys seniors.
As such, anyone age 65 and older will get free admission all day long.
READ MORE: How to save money at the 2015 Calgary Stampede
The park opens at 9 a.m. to seniors and their paying guests.
There will also be free coffee and doughnuts (while supplies last) in the Agrium Western Event Centre from 9 a.m. to 10:30 a.m.
While there, guests can see a free show staring Canadian Trick Rider, Nikki Flundra, a feature performance by the Calgary Stampede Showriders and the music stylings of Herb Williams and Trevor Panczak.
On Monday, over 8,800 people passed through the turnstiles to enter the Calgary Stampede.
More than 462,800 people have visited the Stampede so far this year.If youre planning on heading to the Calgary Stampede on Tuesday, there are some deals and discounts you may wish to take advantage of.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:36:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Soldiers arrive in northern Sask. to help battle wildfires</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096090/soldiers-arrive-in-northern-sask-to-help-battle-wildfires/</Link>
        <Description>Soldiers start to receive training to help fight wildfires in northern Saskatchewan as flames inch closer to La Ronge.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:36 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 9:15 am
Soldiers arrive in northern Sask. to help battle wildfires
By David Giles Senior Web Producer Global News
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
Gunmen opened fire on a beach near two hotels in the coastal resort city of Sousse, Tunisia, killing at least 19 people.
Tunisia state television said 19 people were killed Friday during the attack on the hotels.
Tunisias Interior Ministry Spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said that one of the gunmen was killed and police are pursuing the other, the Associated Press reported.
Aroui said the death toll could rise.
Speaking with Sky News, a British tourist said there was an explosion at a hotel complex.
There was a mass exodus off the beach, Gary Pine told the news station.
No details on the nationalities of the victims have been released.
Sousse, some 150 kilometres from Tunis, is a popular resort for Tunisians, Europeans and North Americans.
More to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:10:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Verdict expected in 2009 deadly scaffolding collapse</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077119/verdict-expected-in-2009-deadly-scaffolding-collapse-on-christmas-eve/</Link>
        <Description>Court heard project manager held onto a 13th-floor balcony when the swing stage split in two, sending five workers plummeting to the ground.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 8:10 am
Updated: June 26, 2015 8:15 am
Verdict expected in 2009 deadly scaffolding collapse
By   Staff The Canadian Press
FIL
(AP Photo/Nikolas Giakoumidis)
=======
PARIS  French officials say the main suspect in the beheading of a French transportation company manager has admitted to police he carried out the killing that authorities have called a terror attack.
Yassine Salhi, a deliveryman with a history of ties to Islamic extremists, remained in custody Sunday along with his wife and sister.
READ MORE: Suspect in French terror attack took selfie with beheading victim
Security officials say investigators have found no links to any international terror group in the attack Friday. They spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation is continuing.
Salhi, arrested Friday, was to be transferred to counterterrorism police headquarters outside Paris. He allegedly crashed a truck into a U.S.-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employers head on the factorys gate. Officials say he sent a selfie of himself and the victim to a Canadian mobile phone number.
A spokesman for Public Safety Minister Steven Blaney confirmsCanadian authorities are involved in the case.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:12:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two people dead after shooting near Queen and Dovercourt</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2080213/two-people-shot-in-torontos-west-end-possibly-fatal/</Link>
        <Description>Global News is on the scene and hearing reports that two people have died following a shooting at a condo in the West Queen West area.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 28, 2015 8:12 am
Updated: June 28, 2015 8:37 am
Two people dead after shooting near Queen and Dovercourt
By Tania Kohut Web Writer Global News
The scene of a shooting in Toronto's West Queen West area.
Jeremy Cohn / Global News
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
WATCH ABOVE: 500 troops arrive in Prince Albert to battle wildfires. Joelle Tomlinson reports.
PRINCE ALBERT, Sask.  Soldiers started rolling into Saskatchewan on Monday to double firefighting efforts in the north. By 10 p.m., 500 members of the rapid response unit of the Canadian Forces based in Edmonton were in Prince Albert.
About 200 received eight hours of training when they arrived late Monday afternoon and the remainder will likely be trained on Tuesday.
Obviously we are not professional firefighters, but we are getting some great and valuable training tonight (Monday) and into the week to set us up in addition to the other valuable skills we bring to the table, said Lt.-Col. Mason Stalker.
Theyre going to get things like coveralls, goggles, ear protection, hard hats, etc. and once theyre issued those, add that to the training and the basic skill sets they already bring to the table, well get them projected north in support of the Government of Saskatchewan.
Wildfires inch closer to Saskatchewan communities
READ MORE: Situation very critical as crews battle northern Sask. wildfires
Initially, it was reported 1,000 troops would be coming to assist with wildfire fighting efforts. The other 500 troops will be deployed from Shilo, Man. if needed.
Weve deliberately done a phased approach into this zone, because we certainly dont want to overwhelm and we want to bring what is required to assist the people of Saskatchewan, said Stalker.
So if the Government of Saskatchewan, in consultation with the fire centre here, determines that more is needed, there are additional, as I mentioned that other immediate response unit thats based in Shilo, my commander would start the process based on the recommendations from, of course the wildfire centre here and the Government of Saskatchewan if they are needed.
Colin King, with Saskatchewans Emergency Management department, described the fire situation as critical and said people evacuated from more than 50 communities wouldnt be returning soon.
The threat has not been reduced in any of those communities. We are advising all community leadership to remain out until it is safe, he said.
La Ronge Fire Situation Update (July 6/2015 8:00pm) pic.twitter.com/rORkQa2xHq
 Thomas Sierzycki (@TSierzycki) July 7, 2015
As of Monday evening, the most significant of 112 fires burning in the province was north of La Ronge, one of the largest communities in north. Mayor Thomas Sierzycki issued a fire update on Twitter about 8 p.m. local time saying the flames were just 1.5 kilometres from residential areas.
Residents were evacuated on the weekend from the town, as well as neighbouring Air Ronge and the Lac La Ronge Indian Band.
READ MORE: Fire evacuation largest in Saskatchewans history
Fires and thick smoke forced others in the north to start leaving their homes 11 days earlier.
Flames have destroyed about a dozen homes, remote cabins and other buildings in Montreal Lake, Weyakwin and Wadin Bay. One building also burned north of La Ronge.
About 300 square kilometres are burning in what officials are calling high-priority fire zones, about 10 times the yearly average.
Scott Wasylenchuk with the Provincial Fire Centre had some good news, however. An area near La Ronge burned in an old forest fire is acting as a natural barrier and wind was expected to shift flames away from the town.
Which means some of the fire lines closest to the community wont be as hot and well be able to get on them and make good progress, he said.
Premier Brad Wall, who visited La Ronge last week, said hes glad soldiers are on hand to help and hes not worried fire will spread into the town.
Right now were in a pretty good spot  Were feeling cautiously optimistic after a difficult weekend.
READ MORE: Hundreds forced from homes by Saskatchewan wildfires staying in Cold Lake
Nearly 700 evacuees from La Ronge were being housed in Cold Lake, Alta. The Alberta government had said it was preparing to receive up to 5,000 after centres in Saskatoon, Regina, Prince Albert and North Battleford were filling up.
Karri Kempf with Saskatchewans Social Services Ministry said slightly more than 7,000 have registered as evacuees and she estimates another 2,000 others are staying with friends and family.
With files from The Canadian Press
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vancouver mayor to talk climate change with Pope</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096089/vancouver-mayor-to-talk-climate-change-with-pope/</Link>
        <Description>Gregor Robertson will join about 30 other representatives of big cities from Europe, Africa, Asia and the Americas for a two-day visit with Pope Francis in Vatican City on July 21. </Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:32 am
Vancouver mayor to talk climate change with Pope
By   Geordon Omand Canadian Press
Pope Francis waves to faithful during his weekly general audience, in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican.
THE CANADIAN PRESS/AP, Andrew Medichini
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
TORONTO  A Toronto judge is expected to rule today in the case of a project manager who oversaw a construction crew involved in a deadly scaffolding collapse in 2009.
Vadim Kazenelson faces four counts of criminal negligence causing death and one count of criminal negligence causing bodily harm. He has maintained his innocence.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:00:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Motorcyclist killed in parking lot crash on Stampede grounds</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2076724/motorcyclist-dead-after-crashing-into-cement-barrier-in-se-calgary/</Link>
        <Description>A 53-year-old motorcyclist was killed in a crash in a southeast parking lot on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 8:00 am
Updated: June 26, 2015 8:16 am
Motorcyclist killed in parking lot crash on Stampede grounds
By Erika Tucker and Melissa Ramsay Global News
Emergency crews respond to a fatal crash in the city's southeast on Thursday, June 25, 2015.
Global News
=======
TORONTO  Police are on the scene of a shooting in the Queen Street and Dovercourt Road area of Toronto.
Police are responding to a shooting in the area of Queen and Dovercourt, anyone w/info please call 14 Division at 416-808-1400^cf
 Toronto Police OPS (@TPSOperations) June 28, 2015
Global News hasheard multiple reports that two people have died and another person has been seriously injured. Police have not confirmed that information.
The shooting occurred Sunday morning in a high rise building on Lisgar Street, where there are a number of newer condominiums.
On scene @ double fatal shooting on Lisgar St near Dufferin &amp; Queen Sts. 2 people dead in a condo building. #Toronto pic.twitter.com/pHcOfJLv4I
 Jeremy Cohn (@JeremyGlobalTV) June 28, 2015
West Queen West is a popular, high-density area with shops, art spaces, restaurant and bars.
Police are asking anyone with information to call416-808-1400.
More to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:25:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Some Canadian towns giving away land to attract new residents</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2080205/some-canadian-towns-giving-away-land-to-attract-new-residents/</Link>
        <Description>Small communities have to compete for residents by offering something special.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 28, 2015 7:25 am
Updated: June 28, 2015 7:35 am
Some Canadian towns giving away land to attract new residents
By   Morgan Lowrie The Canadian Press
Some small towns are giving their land away for free in order to attract new residents.
File / Global News
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
VANCOUVER  The mayor of Vancouver says he plans on encouraging the Pope to ramp up pressure on national governments across the globe to take action on climate change when he meets with the Catholic leader later this month.
Gregor Robertson will join about 30 other representatives of big cities from Europe, Africa, Asia and the Americas for a two-day visit with Pope Francis in Vatican City on July 21. He will be the only Canadian representative in the delegation of global municipal leaders.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
CALGARY  A 53-year-old motorcyclist was killed in a crash in a southeast parking lot on Thursday.
Police say the driver was approaching a pay booth when he lost control of his bike and fell over, crashing into a concrete barrier.
It happened just before 6 p.m. in a lot on the Stampede grounds.
The driver was pronounced dead at the scene.
Investigators dont believe the rider was wearing a helmet, and say excessive speed is believed to be a factor in the collision.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:00:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Okanagan forecast: Stay hydrated</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2076729/okanagan-forecast-stay-hydrated/</Link>
        <Description>Today's highs: 30 to 37C
</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Weather update: Friday June 26 at 8am
Its heating up!!
Extreme heat will be experienced right across the BC Southern Interior from now and through the weekend.
A very strong upper ridge will keep daytime high temps 10to 15 degrees above seasonal under mainly sunny conditions.
Todays highs: 30 to 37C
More details coming up on the 5pm, 6:30pm and 11pm shows.
~Wesla/Duane
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:58:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly explosion at Shiite mosque in Kuwait’s capital</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077111/deadly-explosion-at-shiite-mosque-in-kuwaits-capital/</Link>
        <Description>A deadly explosion ripped through a Shiite mosque in a busy neighbourhood of Kuwait's capital after Friday prayers, witnesses said.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 7:58 am
Deadly explosion at Shiite mosque in Kuwaits capital
By   Hussain Al-Qatari The Associated Press
Security forces, officials and civilians gather outside of the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a deadly blast struck after Friday prayers in Kuwait City, Kuwait, Friday, June 26, 2015.
AP Photo
=======
MONTREAL  Large parts of Canada were settled thanks to a government policy of giving out free land to anyone willing to show up and farm it.
And although the federal government largely stopped giving out Crown land in the 1930s, some small towns are continuing the tradition by giving their land away for free.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Story continues below
Its telling that the Pope is reaching out to mayors as part of his direct-action agenda to tackle climate action and poverty because were on the front lines of it and were committed to dealing with these challenges, Robertson said in an interview.
The Pope recognizes that mayors play a key role in leading communities to a better future  were where the rubber hits the road in taking care of cities and weve largely been left out of the conversation.
Robertson levelled harsh words for the current Canadian government, saying it has been in the bad books globally because of inaction on the environmental front. National governments in general have failed to deliver solutions on climate change, he said.
But at a city level theres serious action and commitment and its important that the rest of the world understands that, Robertson said.
Ill be sharing stories from our work in Vancouver and encouraging global cities and the Vatican to continue pressing for more urgent and aggressive action.
Robertson referenced Vancouvers commitment to converting the city to 100-per-cent renewable energy, the citys calls for binding targets on climate pollution and its ambition at being recognized as the worlds greenest city.
The mayor, who isnt Catholic and doesnt follow any organized religion, said he was humbled to be included on the pontiffs invite list.
Its a responsibility that I dont take lightly.
The invitation comes in the wake of the Popes unprecedented encyclical on climate change, released last month, which blamed climate change on an unequal, fossil fuel-based, structurally perverse economy that favours a culture of consumption at the expense of the worlds poor.
The landmark document was heralded as a call to action in framing climate change as the moral challenge of our era.
Many lauded the Vaticans foray into environmental issues, while critics lambasted the church for stepping outside its area of expertise.
I dont get economic policy from my bishops or my cardinal or my Pope, said U.S. Republican presidential contender and converted Catholic Jeb Bush during a campaign stop in New Hampshire.
Others commended the Pope for his outspoken stance on climate-change action, including Robertson.
I think the Popes leadership is fantastic and much needed from an important religious leader on what is essentially a moral issue and the toughest challenge in human history, he said. Its crucial for political, religious, business and community leaders to be rallying aggressively right now  its so urgent.
World leaders are slated to meet later this year in Paris for the United Nations Climate Change Conference.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:29:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Longtime Hollywood producer Jerry Weintraub dies at 77</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096085/longtime-hollywood-producer-jerry-weintraub-dies-at-77/</Link>
        <Description>One of the last of the classic Hollywood showmen, Jerry Weintraub built his show business empire on a Rolodex and chutzpah.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:29 am
Longtime Hollywood producer Jerry Weintraub dies at 77
By   Jake Coyle The Associated Press
Jerry Weintraub, pictured on June 8, 2015.
Frazer Harrison / Getty Images
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
NEW YORK  One of the last of the classic Hollywood showmen, Jerry Weintraub built his show business empire on a Rolodex and chutzpah.
The Brooklyn-born son of a Bronx jeweler, Weintraub rose from the mailroom of a talent agency to become a top concert promoter before shifting into a decades-long career as a top Hollywood producer.
Story continues below
Along the way, Weintraub worked with the most famous of stars  Elvis Presley, Frank Sinatra, George Clooney, Brad Pitt  and was a close friend of former President George H.W. Bush. He relished his insider status, just as they savored the stories that eagerly poured out of him.
Weintraub, the dynamic producer and manager who pushed the career of John Denver and produced such hits movies as Nashville, Karate Kid and Oceans Eleven, died Monday in Santa Barbara, California. He was 77. A publicist for Weintraub said he died of cardiac arrest.
Jerry was an American original who earned his success by the sheer force of his instinct, drive, and larger-than-life personality, said Bush, a longtime friend. He had a passion for life, and throughout the ups and downs of his prolific career, it was clear just how much he loved show business.
Weintraub failed in one of his most ambitious gambits. His attempt to found his own studio, Weintraub Entertainment Group, ended in bankruptcy after only three years. But his long career  very much alive at the time of his passing  was marked by savvy innovation (he was among the first to stage arena tours) and old-school class.
Weintraub had his choice lunch spots in Los Angeles, his desert home in Palm Springs and his favored places to moor his yacht off the French Riviera. A self-made man, he fashioned himself in the mold of old Hollywood showman like Mike Todd, Cecil B. DeMille and P.T. Barnum. He titled his 2011 memoir: When I Stop Talking, Youll Know Im Dead.
At the time, he joked he might write another: Dead, But Still Talking.
In the coming days there will be tributes about our friend Jerry Weintraub, said Clooney, a star of the Oceans movies. Well laugh at his great stories and applaud his accomplishments. And in the years to come, the stories and accomplishments will get better with age, just as Jerry would have wanted it. But not today. Today our friend died.
One of Weintraubs most recent successes was the 2013 Liberace drama Behind the Candelabra. After the studios passed, he took it to HBO, where it won 11 Emmys.
He left numerous projects behind, including the recently debuted HBO series The Brink with Jack Black, and an upcoming big-budget remake of Tarzan.
If asked my philosophy, it would be simply this: Savor life, dont press too hard, dont worry too much. Or as the old-timers say, Enjoy,' he wrote his book. But  I never could live by this philosophy and was, in fact, out working, hustling, trading, scheming, and making a buck as soon as I was old enough to leave my parents house.
Growing up, Weintraub said he father, a successful gem salesman, taught him only two things are important at the end of the week: how much you owe the bank and how much you have in it.
Hired to work in the mailroom of the William Morris Agency, Weintraub then landed a job with Lew Wassermans MCA, where he worked as advance man for the agencys stars.
His career as a promoter took a giant step in 1970 when after a lengthy courtship he persuaded Elvis Presleys manager, Col. Tom Parker, to let him promote Presley concerts. It was at a time when Presley was beginning to do live shows after years of concentrating on movies.
Weintraub and partner Tom Hulett introduced such improvements as a modern sound system for Presley, an experience that propelled Weintraub into the top ranks of promoters.
Around the same time, Weintraub saw Denver at a small Greenwich Village nightclub and was overwhelmed by the mountaineers easy manner. He took on Denver as a client.
He would be a test case for all my theories on selling and packaging, for everything I had learned since I left home, Weintraub said.
After enormous success followed, Denver bought Weintraub a Rolls-Royce as a thank-you gift. Weintraub said, I couldnt help thinking that it wasnt too long ago that neither of us had bus fare.
Weintraub produced a dozen Denver musical specials on television  winning an Emmy for one of them  and the hit 1977 movie Oh, God! It starred George Burns as God and Denver as the young grocer whom God approaches to spread his message.
He also set up successful tours for Sinatra and produced the television special Sinatra  the Main Event, as well as joint appearances with Denver. Among other musicians Weintraub worked with were Bob Dylan, Neil Diamond and the Beach Boys.
After his first marriage (which resulted in a son, Michael), Weintraub married torch singer Jane Morgan in 1965. They had three adopted children: Julie, Jamie and Jordy. The pair separated but never divorced.
Weintraubs emphasis shifted to movies with 1975s Nashville, Robert Altmans acclaimed comedy-drama of American life as seen through the eyes of 24 characters in and around the country music business. It landed five Oscar nominations, including best picture.
In his memoir, Weintraub said he didnt understand the complicated script, but he was eager to produce it because Altman did, and it was Altman who was going to make the movie.
Weintraub went on to produce such notable films as Barry Levinsons Diner, All Night Long, The Karate Kid, and William Friedkins controversial, gay-themed Cruising.
He became chief of United Artists in 1985 but was ousted after just five months amid reports of disagreements with financier Kirk Kerkorian. He later reached a settlement with the company.
In 1987, he attempted to establish his own studio, WEG, but it went belly up in 1990 after a string of flops including My Stepmother Is an Alien.
I had, in a sense, promoted myself out of the job I always wanted, which was telling stories, producing, he wrote in his memoir. (The films) now were being made for me instead of by me.
After the WEG bankruptcy, Weintraub continued producing, putting out such films as Vegas Vacation and Oceans Eleven and its starry sequels. He remade The Karate Kid in 2010, setting the project up in China and starring the young Jaden Smith, Will Smiths son. Weintraub said he questioned it 150,000 times before backing it.
Starting in the 1980s, Weintraub became known as one of the Republican Partys most loyal supporters in Hollywood. He had been close to Bush years before he became president, and in 1991, he hosted a star-studded party for the president at his Malibu home and played golf with Bush and former President Ronald Reagan.
 with files by the late Bob Thomas of The Associated Press
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:20:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Introducing Hero4 Session: GoPro’s tiny cube-shaped camera</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096041/introducing-hero4-session-gopros-tiny-cube-shaped-camera/</Link>
        <Description>GoPro has unveiled its smallest camera yet – a cube-shaped, waterproof camera that weighs in at just 2.6 ounces.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO  GoPro has unveiled its smallest camera yet  a cube-shaped, waterproof camera that weighs in at just 2.6 ounces.
The Hero4 Session is about the size of a large ice cube and will retail for US$399. According to the company, the Hero4 Session is 50 per cent smaller and 40 per cent lighter than the rest of GoPros high-end Hero4 range.
Unlike GoPros other cameras, the Hero4 Session only has one button to turn it on and start recording  allowing for the smaller design. The camera is also waterproof up to 33 feet thanks to its fully sealed design.
Although its smaller, the camera still packs the same capabilities as other GoPro models.
It can record video at full HD resolution at up to 60 frames per second and features the companys Protune mode, designed for a more cinematic look.
In May, GoPro announced it was getting into the drone and virtual reality business. By 2016 the company plans to come out with a quadcopter drone geared toward consumers.
The Hero4 Session will be available starting July 12.
Shaw Media, 2015
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:46:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>36 daily temperature records set in B.C. as campfire ban begins on South Coast</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2080070/36-daily-temperature-records-set-in-b-c-as-campfire-ban-begins/</Link>
        <Description>It was hard to ignore British Columbia's historic heat wave today.
</Description>
        <MainBody>June 28, 2015 12:46 am
Updated: June 28, 2015 12:49 am
36 daily temperature records set in B.C. as campfire ban begins on South Coast
By Justin McElroy Web Producer Global News
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
KUWAIT CITY  A deadly explosion ripped through a Shiite mosque in a busy neighbourhood of Kuwaits capital after Friday prayers, witnesses said.
Mohammed al-Faili, 32, told The Associated Press that his 70 year-old father was killed in what appeared to be a bombing attack. Two of his brothers were also wounded by the explosion. Speaking to the AP by telephone, he said he was not at the mosque at the time of the explosion but was heading to the morgue to identify his fathers body.
Story continues below
The official Kuwait News Agency reported that an explosion struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque, which is located in the neighbourhood of al-Sawabir, a residential and shopping district of Kuwait City. The agency confirmed that there were multiple casualties and injuries, but did provide any figures.
Paramedics at the mosque say at least two people were killed. Police formed a cordon around the mosques complex immediately after the explosion, banning people from entering or gathering near the area. Ambulances could be seen ferrying the wounded from the site.
Abdullah al-Saffar, who was at the mosque, said the explosion took place just after midday Friday prayers.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility for what appears to be a bombing that targeted the mosque. The extremist Islamic State group, which regards Shiite Muslims as heretics, has claimed responsibility for bombings at two different Shiite mosques in neighbouring Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
Friday midday prayers are typically the most crowded of the week, and attendance increases during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, which started last week.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:56:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Harry Potter play opening in London next summer</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2077106/harry-potter-play-opening-in-london-next-summer/</Link>
        <Description>Harry Potter is going to have a new adventure — one that takes him from page and screen to stage.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 26, 2015 7:56 am
Harry Potter play opening in London next summer
By   Staff The Associated Press
Author J.K. Rowling, pictured in 2013.
Danny E. Martindale / Getty Images
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
LONDON  Harry Potter is going to have a new adventure  one that takes him from page and screen to stage.
Author J.K. Rowling announced Friday that a new play called Harry Potter and the Cursed Child will open at Londons Palace Theatre about a year from now in the summer of 2016.
Rowling tweeted that the play explores an untold part of Harrys story and is not a prequel.
Story continues below
The first-ever play about the bespectacled boy wizard it is based on a new story by Rowling, Jack Thorne and John Tiffany.
The script is by Thorne, a stage and screen writer whose work includes vampire story Let the Right One In. The director is Tiffany, who helmed the critically lauded war play Black Watch and multiple Tony Award-winning musical Once. The production will also feature music by British songwriter Imogen Heap.
Ive had countless offers to extend Harrys story over the years, but Jack, John and (producer) Sonia Friedman are a dream team! Rowling tweeted.
Rowling has long insisted there will be no new Harry Potter novels, but she has kept fans happy with spin-off works including the magical encyclopedia Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them, which is set to be a film starring Eddie Redmayne.
Rowling said she thought that once audiences saw Harry Potter and the Cursed Child they would agree that the stage was the only proper medium for the story.
Rowlings seven Harry Potter novels have sold more than 450 million copies around the world and been made into eight successful films.
Tickets for Harry Potter and the Cursed Child will go on sale this fall.
The Canadian Press, 2015
=======
It was hard to ignore British Columbias historic heat wave today.
In total, 36 communities across the province hit record highs for June 27, including a blistering 40.4 degrees Celsius in Osoyoos.
Here are the 36 places in B.C. where record high temperatures were hit today. pic.twitter.com/BTGtkI2JWe
 Global BC (@GlobalBC) June 28, 2015
Were basically on target right now to be the second warmest June in the history of record keeping [in B.C.], which started back in 1937, says Global News weather anchor Kate Gajdosik.
Story continues below
The record highs came on the same day that a campfire ban went into effect for much of the south coast.
It made for a melancholy Friday night for campers at Alice Lake Provincial Park in the north end of Squamish, who knew they were putting out campfires for likely the final time this summer.
I wouldnt be surprised if it was on all summer. Id be shocked. The only way theyre taking it off is if we get any major amounts of precipitation, which doesnt look like its going to [happen], said Matt Vandenraadt.
WATCH: Julia Foy speaks to Vancouverites who found ways to beat the heat on Saturday
The hot, dry weather continues to be a concern for plenty of people , including firefighters.
Squamish to Whistler is an extreme [zone]. Theres a large area expanding just to the east of Chilliwack. With these high temperatures and the dry weather we expect those areas to expand even further, says Marg Drysdale, Fire Information Officer for the South Coast.
More than $62 million has already been spent on fires so far this year  and Drysdale wants people to remember that individuals can be found liable if theyre found responsible for any themselves.
If it cause a wildfire, and contributes to a wildfire, the person responsible may be ordered to pay all the firefighting and associated costs of that wildfire.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:18:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Northern Manitoba to get $31-million marine observatory</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096055/northern-manitoba-to-get-31-million-marine-observatory/</Link>
        <Description>A multimillion-dollar marine observatory is being built in Churchill, Manitoba.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
<<<<<<< HEAD
CHURCHILL, Man.  A multimillion-dollar marine observatory is being built in Churchill, Man.
More than $22 million in federal and provincial funding has been announced for the facility.
READ MORE: Manitoba eyes lifting limits on park eco-tourism
It will offer reasearchers the chance to study the impact of oil spills in sea ice and look into issues facing Arctic marine transportation.
The centre will bring together researchers from Manitoba, as well as the universities of Calgary, Victoria, Laval, Dalhousie and Washington.Federal government departments will also be involved.
David Barber, an associate dean at the University of Manitoba, will lead the research.
Total cost of the observatory is around $31 million.
The Canadian Press, 2015
=======
Watch the online edition of the Global BC News Hour with Randene Neillon Saturday, June 27.
View more Global BC videos by clicking here .
Shaw Media, 2015
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
