<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:43:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FBI agent wounded while searching for 9-year-old girl</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019295/fbi-agent-wounded-while-searching-for-9-year-old-girl/</Link>
        <Description>Authorities say an FBI agent was wounded when gunfire broke out at a Louisiana motel as authorities were searching for a missing 9-year-old girl from Texas.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
EW ORLEANS  Authorities say an FBI agent was wounded when gunfire broke out at a Louisiana motel as authorities were searching for a missing 9-year-old girl from Texas.
The agent was shot in the leg and the girl was found safe. There were conflicting reports on the condition of the suspect.
The gunfire erupted Tuesday afternoon at a Days Inn in Bossier City, Louisiana. Agents from the Shreveport FBI office were there looking for the girl, who was the subject of an Amber Alert issued by the Benbrook, Texas, police department.
Benbrook is about 220 miles west of Bossier City.
Neither the FBI nor the Benbrook police released the name of the agent or the suspect.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:36:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Edmonton man headed to first CFL training camp</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019226/edmonton-man-headed-to-first-cfl-training-camp/</Link>
        <Description>Edmonton's Dexter Janke is hoping to make an impression at his first CFL camp, after being drafted this year by the Calgary Stampeders. </Description>
        <MainBody>May 26, 2015 8:36 pm
Edmonton man headed to first CFL training camp
By Quinn Phillips Global News
Former U of S Husky Dexter Janke hopes to make an impression at the Calgary Stampeders rookie camp.
File / Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
EDMONTON  Edmontons Dexter Janke has been playing football since he was seven-years-old. His dedication tothe sport is now paying off, as the 22-year-old is in Calgary for his first CFL training camp.
As everyones been saying to me hard work pays, said Janke, who was selected in the fifth round by the Stampeders. Ive definitely worked for this and it feels that much better that it hasnt been given to me.
Story continues below
The free safety and returner isreferring to a tumultuous few years. In Grade 11 he tore theACL in his knee. He did it again in Grade 12, and once again in his third-year at the University of Saskatchewan.
I had a decision to make; I could sit there and wallow and be freaked out about it, or I could do what I love and put it behind me, so thats what I decided to do.
He spent four years in Saskatoon with the Huskies, but two years were as a red shirt because of his injury. Last season he played for the Canadian Junior Football Leagues Okanagan Sun.
Janke was the only Edmonton-born player selected from the CFLs regional combine to go to the main combine in Toronto.
I was happy to go against the higher competition, said Janke. Those are the best players in the country and I definitely felt I held my own and other teams did as well.
Janke now needs to make an impression at rookie camp. He feels set.
Ive talked with a couple of guys that are in the league now and the biggest thing theyve really emphasized is just be in shape, be in shape, be in shape, said Janke. I was in Kelowna training with the Okanagan Suns I was there with my head coach and strength coach Shane Beatty.
He was on me, sometimes we were going seven times a week.
In meetings with CFL teams leading up to the draft, the message was clear: Canadian born athletes need to be able to produce on special teams.
I just have to show that I am athletic, so that I can run down on specials, show that I can produce on specials. Thats the biggest thing.
Janke and fellow first-year hopefuls take the field for rookie camp on Thursday morning at McMahon Stadium.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:30:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: Global National – May 26</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1148831/watch-global-national/</Link>
        <Description>Watch the full broadcast of the Global National hosted by Dawna Friesen on Tuesday, May 26.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Watch the full broadcast of the Global National hosted by Dawna Friesenon Tuesday, May 26.
View more Global National videos by clicking here .
To submit a photo for our Your Canada segment, click here
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:27:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calgary woman honoured for secret service in WWII</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019198/calgary-woman-honoured-for-secret-service-in-wwii/</Link>
        <Description>Marion Booth was just 17 years old when she began her work as a decoder in the Second World War, and was celebrated Tuesday with the Bletchley Park Commemorative Badge.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 26, 2015 8:27 pm
Calgary woman honoured for secret service in WWII
By Tracy Nagai Reporter Global News
Marion Booth, far left, joined the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service ("Wrens") in 1944.
Handout
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CALGARY  Marion Booth was just 17 years old when she began her work as a decoder in the Second World War, and was celebrated Tuesday with the Bletchley Park Commemorative Badge in recognition of her vital, secret service, as an employee of Britains Government Code and Cypher School.
In 1944, Booth joined the Womens Royal Canadian Naval Service (the Wrens) in Ontario. In spring 1945, she began intercepting Japanese radio messagestyping code on a Japanese typewriter.
When the war ended, Booth was sent to Russia, and sworn to secrecy for 25 years. There, she gathered and interpreted information obtained from the Soviet Union. Despite her pivotal role in two major conflicts, Booth remains very modest.
I dont think I ever really knew what my work ended up, where it ended up or why, she said. But I knew somebody somewhere was taking care of it.
Booth moved to Calgary in 1972. She has three children and says none of them really asked about her workso she never had to lie to them.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:18:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: John Hufnagel talks 2015 expectations, new CFL rules</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019254/watch-john-hufnagel-talks-2015-expectations-new-cfl-rules/</Link>
        <Description>Stampeders' head coach John Hufnagel talks expectations for 2015, training camp battles and the new CFL rules.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CALGARY The reigning Grey Cup champs return to work this week.
The Calgary Stampeders open training camp Thursday, when the rookies hit the field for the first time.
The veterans report on Saturday, and main camp begins on Sunday.
Watch above for video of Stampeders head coach John Hufnagel meeting with reporterson Tuesday, when he discussed expectations for 2015, training camp battles and the new CFL rules.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:43:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Should 16-year-olds be allowed to vote?</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019157/should-16-year-olds-be-allowed-to-vote/</Link>
        <Description>A Lethbridge city councillor wants to see the voting age in municipal elections lowered to 16.</Description>
        <MainBody>On Monday he presented a resolution to council asking that the idea be brought before the Alberta Urban Municipality Association (AUMA).
Coffman wants the age restriction dropped from 18 to 16.
Its about expanding the franchise to municipalities and creating an opportunity to engage a new generation, a younger cohort of individuals into the system, said Coffman.
He says the resolution addresses voter apathy and declining turnout by giving teenagers a chance to learn and participate.
That develops that sticky habit of voting throughout their life, said Coffman.
The resolution did pass, but 16 and 17-year-olds wont be casting a ballot anytime soon.
Once the resolution goes before AUMA, members have to debate and vote on whether or not to accept it. If its accepted, it will then be put forward to the Alberta government.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:36:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Edmonton firefighters tackle gruelling 100-mile race for mental health</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019162/edmonton-firefighters-tackle-gruelling-100-mile-race-for-mental-health/</Link>
        <Description>Taking part in the Sinister 7 Ultra Marathon is not just a personal goal; the eight runners will also be raising funds and awareness for the Mental Health Foundation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Firefighters compete in FireFit Games, raise funds for PTSD treatment
Taking part in the 30-hour race is not just a personal goal; the eight runners will also be raising funds and awareness for the Mental Health Foundation, which is why theyre calling themselves Team Mental Rescue .
In recent months, PTSD and mental illness have been brought to the forefront for the team after members of Edmontons Emergency Services have died by suicide.
READ MORE: Depression made that choice': Wife of Edmonton paramedic who took his own life
Its such an invisible illness, said local firefighter and team leader Paul Semeniuk.
In emergency response, individuals, on a daily basis, deal with traumatic injuries and situations the average citizen doesnt have to see or be put through.
Semeniuk said it reaches far beyond the fire hall.
Its affecting everyone in different ways.
Throughout their training, at various local events and on race day, Team Mental Rescue will be wearing bright green as a way to bring light to what Semeniuk called an invisible disease.
It says Im in support of it, and its not so invisible anymore.'
I see a lot of people suffer with it. They dont know what they can do. They dont know whats out there, Kozlowski added.
The group is also using social media to help raise awareness of the resources out there for those living with mental illness.
Come race day, Kozlowski said the funds and the support theyve received so far will help motivate them to cross the finish line.
You dont sign up to get halfway through. You sign up to finish.
Team Mental Rescue trains for the Sinister 7 Ultra Marathon.
Quinn Ohler, Global News
Team Mental Rescue trains for the Sinister 7 Ultra Marathon.
Quinn Ohler, Global News
If you, a family member or someone you know is having suicidal thoughts, or you believe they may be suffering from severe depression and/or anxiety, there are many organizations available to help including the Canadian Association for Suicide Prevention . A lengthy list can be found here .
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:23:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calgary students ‘walk blind’ to raise funds for Alberta guide dogs</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2018764/calgary-students-walk-blind-to-raise-funds-for-alberta-guide-dogs/</Link>
        <Description>Students at Olympic Heights Elementary School were "walking blind" on Tuesday, as part of an effort to raise money for Alberta Guide Dog Services.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 26, 2015 7:23 pm
Updated: May 26, 2015 8:19 pm
Calgary students walk blind to raise funds for Alberta guide dogs
By Gil Tucker Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Watch above:GlobalsGil Tucker visitsCalgary students whoregetting a sense of what its like to be without a sense.
CALGARY  Grade 3 students at Olympic Heights Elementary School were walking blind on Tuesday,as part ofaneffort to raise money for Alberta Guide Dog Services.
Using everything from bandanas to toques, the kids covered their eyes to get a sense of the challenges facing blind people.
They were joined by service dog-in-training, Button, and her volunteer trainer.
The students presented them with a donation cheque for $2,345.50, money theyd raised by selling crafts and setting up lemonade stands.
The money will go toward providing dogs like Button for blind people in the Calgary area.
Take a look at some of the blindfolded students in the gallery below:

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:21:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How looking over photos of your child could save their eyesight</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2018921/how-looking-over-photos-of-your-child-could-save-their-eyesight/</Link>
        <Description>A Saskatoon family warns others about a simple way to check your child's eye health and stop them from going blind.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 26, 2015 7:21 pm
Updated: May 26, 2015 7:49 pm
How looking over photos of your child could save their eyesight
By Meaghan Craig Reporter Global News
A Saskatoon family warns others about a simple way to check your child's eye health and stop them from going blind.
Eric Karmark / Supplied
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
SASKATOON  If you are a parent of a young child particularly a little boy, youll want to flip through your photos.
Experts say something as simple as a camera flash can help you detect if theres something really wrong with your childs eye health, possibly preventing them from going blind.
Something one Saskatoon family says they wish they had known sooner after their childs vision in one eye deteriorated over a matter of months because of Coats Disease.
This is what Coats Disease looks like, 70 per cent of cases are boys diagnosed before their tenth birthday.
The retina is is like film inside of the camera so its the part of the eye that takes the picture back to the brain and with Coats Diseases theres a problem with the blood vessels, said Dr. Nigel Rawlings, retina specialist with Saskatoon Retina Consultants.
Saskatchewan expands vision care for diabetics
The blood vessels in the back of the eye are very leaky and they leak protein and fluid and as a result you can have swelling in the retina and some of these kids can end up with a partial or a total retinal detachment.
According to Rawlings, Coats Disease usually only affects one eye and treatment depends on the severity which means early detection is key.
If its diagnosed early no treatment is required at all, added Rawlings.
In some kids we can treat the abnormal blood vessels by using a laser or by using a freezing treatment but then for more advance situations we sometimes have to do surgery and sometimes we have to inject a medicine into the eye to make the blood vessels leak less.
There are three warning signs Rawlings recommends parent look for; a decrease in your childs vision and strabismus, simply put when the eye turns inward or outward.
The third is knowing the glow or looking for cat-like eyes when using flash photography.
In most people when we use flash and you look at the eyes, theres what you call a red reflex so human eyes normal show a nice red reflex with Coats Disease instead of seeing a normal red reflex you can see what we call a yellow or a white reflex.
Rawlings warns that childhood eye cancer also presents with an abnormal red reflex.
While a picture tells a thousand words, one family says they didnt know to look for the glow.
If we had know about the white-eye sooner perhaps we would have been more aware to take him to a medical professional sooner, said Eric Karmark, father of three little boys.
Last summer, Eric and his wife Anita say they noticed their second oldest son Jonathans right eye was wandering a bit but thought it was nothing an eye-patch couldnt correct.
 In Jonathans case he went from having vision in the eye, albeit was greatly reduced to complete loss of vision over a matter of months, added Karmark.
The sooner you can treat your child, the sooner you can hopefully have a more positive outcome.

Too young to articulate that there was something wrong with his eye, little Jonathan was diagnosed with Coats Disease in December 2014 at the age of two.
A condition so rare experts say on average they see only one case in Saskatchewan every year.
In terms of vision hell probably never receive vision in that eye again, said Anita Karmark.
At this point, Jonathan has undergone laser therapy, freezing treatments and injections in order to save his eye as the family holds out hope experts will one day find a cure.
Hes a normal, healthy, functioning child and even with one eye he can still do everything that a normal three-year-old can do, the only thing he may not have is depth-perception, said Anita Karmark.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:20:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Okanagan forecast: sun &amp; cloud with afternoon shower risk</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2019176/okanagan-forecast-sun-cloud-with-afternoon-shower-risk/</Link>
        <Description>Wednesday’s daytime high range: 21 to 27C</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Weather update: Tuesday May 26th 4:30pm
An upper low continues to circulate bands of clouds and showers over parts of the BC Southern Interior. This low will slowly shift to the east on Wednesday, giving way to brighter conditions. However, afternoon showers will remain in the forecast.
A second upper low will track down the coast and into the BC Interior on Thursday. The low will stall over the interior as we head into the weekend, and this feature will keep the risk of isolated showers in the forecast for the rest of the work week and Saturday as well.
Wednesdays daytime high range: 21 to 27C
More details coming up at 5, 6:30 and 11pm!
~ Duane/Wesla
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
