<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:10:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iconic Stanley Park statue gets superhero make-over</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973272/iconic-stanley-park-statue-gets-superhero-make-over/</Link>
        <Description>An iconic Vancouver statue has received a superhero make-over.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
An iconic Vancouver statue has received a superhero make-over.
The Harry Jerome statue along the Stanley Park seawall was seen sporting an Iron Man mask.
It was noticed by park workers early yesterday morning.
Its not known if it was the work of a prankster or a guerilla marketing campaign.
The park board said the superhero makeover was unsanctioned.
The second installment of Avengers opens inmovie theatres today.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:07:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NDP support in Alberta continues to surge: poll</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973196/ndp-support-in-alberta-continues-to-surge-poll/</Link>
        <Description>A new poll shows the NDP continuing to gain support across the province just days before the provincial election. </Description>
        <MainBody>PC and Wildrose tied for support among voters: poll
The plan to campaign on a budget that an overwhelming majority of the population disliked at a time that an overwhelming majority of the population did not want, has been a disaster for Jim Prentice. says Mainstreet Technolgies President Quito Maggi.
The dynasty in Alberta will come to an end on Tuesday with the election of an NDP government,
The poll suggests 73% of decided voters in Edmonton will vote for the NDP, while only 35% of decided voters in Calgary will support the party.
Outside of Edmonton and Calgary, the NDP lead with 39% of the vote, over the Wildrose (33%) and PCs (22%).
However, when asked which party Albertans think will actually win the election on May 5th, most respondents said the PCs (32%) followed closely by the NDP (29%).
The poll also found 14% of respondents still hadnt decided who they would vote for.
BELOW: See the complete poll from Mainstreet Technologies.The president of Greece, France and England attacked Pakistan with Iran while USA was sleeping in Hungary.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:59:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother’s Day recipe for pepper-scampi Alfredo</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973261/mothers-day-recipe-for-pepper-scampi-alfredo/</Link>
        <Description>If you really want to show Mom how much you care on Mother's Day, the recipe is pretty simple - carbs and fat.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 1, 2015 8:59 am
Mothers Day recipe for pepper-scampi Alfredo
By   J.M. Hirsch The Associated Press
This April 6, 2015 photo shows pepper-scampi Alfredo in Concord, N.H. In this recipe, chopped, cooked chicken breasts, crispy hunks of bacon or strips of smoked salmon can be substituted for the shrimp.
AP Photo/Matthew Mead
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
If you really want to show Mom how much you care on Mothers Day, the recipe is pretty simple  carbs and fat.
After all, its what the rest of us crave on special days. So why fuss with breakfast in bed (which inevitably spills, anyway), when you could just embrace the fatty-carby formula that is almost guaranteed to make the moms in your life happy? My favourite expression of this winning formula? Fettuccine Alfredo.
Not only is it rich and delicious, its also fast and easy to make. And that means the kids can get in on the cooking action. The grating of the cheese, the cutting of the butter and the tossing of the shrimp are all tasks perfect for delegating to Moms dearest little ones.
To gussy up this dish a bit, I added pepper-roasted shrimp, which are tossed in with the pasta just at the end. But if shrimp doesnt suit your mom, you could easily substitute chopped cooked (and hot) chicken breasts, crispy hunks (make them big) of bacon, or strips of smoked salmon.

Start to finish: 30 minutes
Servings: 6
2 pounds raw, shelled extra-large or jumbo shrimp
Olive oil
1/2 cup (1 stick) butter, cut into small pieces
3 1/4 cups (about 8 ounces) grated Parmesan cheese
Recipe ideas for Mothers Day tea sandwiches
Heat the oven to 400 F. Place a large stainless steel serving bowl on the ovens bottom shelf to warm. Line a rimmed baking sheet with foil. Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil.
While the water heats, pile the shrimp on the prepared baking sheet, then drizzle a generous amount of olive oil over them. Toss to coat. Sprinkle the shrimp liberally with pepper, then arrange in a single layer. Bake for 10 minutes, or until just pink and firm.
While the shrimp cooks, add the pasta to the boiling water and cook according to package directions. When the pasta is finished, reserve 3/4 cup of the cooking water, then drain the pasta.
Carefully remove the bowl from the oven. Place the butter in the bowl, then add the drained pasta. Using tongs or 2 wooden spoons, toss the pasta, melting the butter and mixing it with the pasta. Be careful of the hot bowl. A bit at a time, add the cheese and the reserved pasta cooking water (you dont need to use it all), continuing to toss until all of the cheese is added and melted. Add the shrimp and toss well. Season with pepper.
Nutrition information per serving: 720 calories; 300 calories from fat (42 per cent of total calories); 33 g fat (17 g saturated; 1 g trans fats); 265 mg cholesterol; 64 g carbohydrate; 1 g fiber; 3 g sugar; 41 g protein; 1,550 mg sodium.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:45:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Huskies spring camp kicks off after successful Dogs’ Breakfast</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973236/huskies-spring-camp-kicks-off-after-successful-dogs-breakfast/</Link>
        <Description>The 15th annual Dogs’ Breakfast, one of the most anticipated mornings of the year, was yet another success for the Saskatchewan Huskies.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 1, 2015 8:45 am
Huskies spring camp kicks off after successful Dogs Breakfast
By Kim Thue Sports Director/Anchor Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Watch above: The 15th annual Dogs Breakfast, one of the most anticipated mornings of the year, was yet another success for the Saskatchewan Huskies. Kim Thue introduces us to some of the new recruits.
SASKATOON  Twenty-five new recruits were introduced early Thursday morning at the 15th annual Dogs Breakfast. The young men put on the Saskatchewan Huskies jersey for the very first time.
Saskatchewan Huskies already deep into off-season
Its an honour, says linebacker Eric Thakurdeen, who comes to the Huskies from the Notre Dame Hounds. Im excited for the next five years. Its going to be good.
Defensive back Jacob Solie, whos dad Greg played for the Huskies from 83 to 85, says suiting up for the Huskies is a dream come true.
Starting from Grade 8, when I first starting playing tackle football, I wanted that ultimate goal of playing at the college level. When I got offered that opportunity I jumped on board.
The 2015 recruiting class features a healthy dose of both high school stars and junior football standouts. The Huskies welcome eight former juniors from the Prairie Football Conference and four of them were All-Canadians: Wayndell Lewis, Ben Hodson, Brooks Falloon and Vince Greco.
Its more of the same in regards to the high school kids coming in, which includes a trio of players who suited up for Canadas U-18 team: Ben Whiting, Payton Hall and Eric Thakurdeen.
The overall theme of this recruiting class however was defense. In specific; defensive backs and linebackers, which were 13 of the 25 players introduced on Thursday.
READ MORE: Huskies, Hilltops set for spring camp in Saskatoon
We didnt have a lot of depth last year at either of those spots, head coach Brian Towriss says of his defensive back and linebacker positions, making that a priority in this recruiting class.
We got the three best high school kids that we thought were available, plus three All-Canadian juniors in those spots too.
The eight junior players will have an opportunity to step in and make an impact right away. The players coming out of high school will have a tougher road in year one, but that road begins at this weekends spring camp.
They wouldnt have recruited me if they didnt like my style of play, says a confident Ben Whiting, who heads into spring camp looking to earn a spot in the defensive backfield.
Everyone is good at this level, its just a matter of being consistent now and I think I can bring that to the team.
Huskies spring camp resumes Friday, before wrapping up with Sundays Green and White scrimmage, which will be a great opportunity for the new recruits to leave a lasting impression heading into the summer.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:33:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shoal Lake 40 declares emergency after losing lifeline ferry</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973220/shoal-lake-40-declares-emergency-after-losing-lifeline-ferry/</Link>
        <Description>Shoal Lake 40, made an island by construction of Winnipeg's aqueduct, is cut off from the mainland after its ferry failed to pass inspection.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 1, 2015 8:33 am
Shoal Lake 40 declares emergency after losing lifeline ferry
By   Chinta Puxley The Canadian Press
Shoal Lake 40 First Nation was cut off from the mainland when the aqueduct that supplies Winnipeg's drinking water was built. The First Nation has been under a boil water advisory for 17 years.
John Woods / The Canadian Press
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
SHOAL LAKE, Ont.  A reserve under one of the longest boil-water advisories in Canada has declared a state of emergency after the ferry connecting it to the outside world failed to pass inspection.
The Shoal Lake 40 First Nation was cut off from the mainland a century ago to build an aqueduct which supplies the city of Winnipeg with fresh water. The reserve, which straddles the Ontario-Manitoba border, has no all-weather road and has been under a boil-water advisory for 17 years.
READ MORE: The price of Winnipegs water: A First Nations misery
Chief Erwin Redsky says that without the ferry, people on the man-made island have no way to get groceries, bottled water or immediate medical attention, and normal life on the reserve is virtually impossible.
We have elders at risk, he said Thursday. Weve been cut off for 100 years and weve barely been hanging on by our fingernails. Loss of water delivery, health services and vehicle access threatens our very survival.
This injustice needs to end.
The reserve has been calling for the construction of an all-weather road  dubbed Freedom Road by residents  for years. The community estimates an all-weather road would cost about $30 million.
The federal government, Manitoba and the city of Winnipeg have chipped in $1 million each for a feasibility study, but there are no firm commitments beyond that.
READ MORE: Shoal Lake 40 First Nation by the numbers
Reserve officials have said that every winter, people from Shoal Lake 40 fall through the ice trying to get into the community. In the summer, the ferry is their only lifeline.
The ferry failed to pass its four-year Transport Canada inspection due to a leaky and rusty hull, said Redsky, who added its not clear how much it will cost to get the ferry seaworthy again.
The reserve wants Ottawa to help pay for the repairs and for a shuttle service in the meantime that will restore the communitys connection to the mainland, he said.
But thats only a temporary solution, Redsky said. Without an all-weather road, garbage and liquid waste is piling up on the reserve.
We want a commitment to build Freedom Road. Thats the ultimate solution.
Emily Hillstrom, spokeswoman for federal Aboriginal Affairs Minister Bernard Valcourt, said in an email that department officials are in touch with the reserve to determine what their needs are and what assistance is required.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:30:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: ‘Weird Al’ Yankovic unpacks his Grammy Award</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973229/watch-weird-al-yankovic-unpacks-his-grammy-award/</Link>
        <Description>"Weird Al" Yankovic got to do something this week that only a few thousand people have been able to do -- and he shared the experience on YouTube.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Grammys were almost three months ago so, if you can help it, try not to use NARAS as a delivery service, he jokes. If you can get your Grammy off of Amazon instead, I say go for it.
Yankovic opens the box and removes the foam packing material encasing the gold-plated gramophone.
I can make my own moulds of Grammys from now on, he says excitedly. I can start my own little Grammy factory!
Finally, the Grammy  which Yankovic earned for Best Comedy Album  is revealed.
Mandatory Fun, Yankovics 14th studio album, features parodies of hits by artists like Iggy Azalea, Lorde , Robin Thicke and Pharrell Williams .
At the end of the video, the musician lays the award on top of the ones he won in 1984 (Best Comedy Recording), 1988 (Best Concept Music Video) and 2004 (Best Comedy Album).
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:14:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to watch the Pacquiao-Mayweather fight in Canada</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1971175/how-to-watch-the-pacquiao-mayweather-fight-in-canada/</Link>
        <Description>Where Canadians can watch the much anticipated fight between Floyd "Money" Mayweather Jr. and Manny Pacquiao for the World Boxing Council belt at the MGM Grand in Las Vegas.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boxer Floyd Mayweather Jr. released from Vegas jail after 2 months in domestic battery case
Oh, its going to be crazy. The phones have literally not stopped ringing. The day they announced the fight we started getting phone calls, she said, adding that theyre also telling eager fans to line up before 7 p.m. at the latest or face a standing-room-only situation.
I think itll fill in, people are usually pretty happy to be here theyll sit or stand anywhere.
READ MORE: Mayweather v. Pacquiao could be fight of the century, heres what you should know
Oasis Pub in Halifax is offering the fightfor $15 per person, but again theres no hope for a reservation.
Were not doing reserve seating its first come, first serve. So your chances are better the earlier you come, said manager Danny Mullock, adding that he thinks the event will be standing-room-only by the time the fight is on.
This is a huge fight, we havent seen a card like this in 20 years probably, since Tyson-Holyfield. Boxing has been kind of going downhill and hopefully this will rejuvenate the sport a little bit.
For those in Vancouver, Red Card Sports Bar is offering a chance to view the fight for $20, but its fully booked for reservations and expects walk-ins as early as 4 p.m.
Im pretty sure its going to be hectic but thats a good thing, we all love when its busy in here, it gets the atmosphere going so its a good thing rather than a hassle, bartender Owen Duffy said.
Were playing it by ear, we have no idea whos going to show up or at what time.
The Dogs Bollocks bar in Toronto is also expecting a large crowd, even with a cover charge of $20 at the door with no reservations ahead of time.
Well be a full house, I think anywhere thats showing it is going to be a full house, said bartender Jesse Davids, adding that a fight like this will draw almost as big of a crowd as the Stanley Cup Finals or the Super Bowl.
If you do make it to a bar, youre probablyin for a long wait as themain event likely wont start until after 11 p.m.
Nearly 4 million people are expected to order whats being called the fight of the century on TV.
But if youre quick on your feet, you can fight for a spot at one of many bars across the country.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:10:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More mid-rise buildings should be built in place of high-rises: report</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973188/more-mid-rise-buildings-should-be-built-in-place-of-high-rises-report/</Link>
        <Description>High-rise condominium developments currently litter major urban centres such as downtown Toronto but it doesn't have to be that way.</Description>
        <MainBody>READ MORE: Home ownership for millennials  are they dreaming?
To tackle the GTAs growing rental and home ownership problem, the Pembina Institute has teamed up with other groups, such as the Ontario Home Builders Association to help come up with solutions.
Mid-rise, mixed-use development is a valuable tool when creating neighbourhoods that support healthy lifestyles and local economies, since
it can help increase walkability and put more people close to transit, while also supporting local business, the report says.
READ MORE: What bubble? Renters underpin Toronto, Vancouver condo markets
The study points to a City of Toronto planning study which found that if only one-tenth of all properties now zoned for mixed use were redeveloped at six storeys, that would generate about 120,000 new housing units.
Not enough of these developments are being built because of rules and incentives that tilt the playing field against mid-rise, the report says.
The report recommended several solutions to make mid-rise development more economically viable such as eliminating minimum parking requirements, pre-approving mid-rise development along avenues and transit corridors and requiring retail planning before any mid-rise is built.
You can view the full report here.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:10:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Arrest after fatal crash in New Brunswick</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1972095/arrest-after-fatal-crash-in-new-brunswick/</Link>
        <Description>The RCMP in New Brunswick have arrested a man after a fatal collision near Fredericton.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 1, 2015 8:10 am
Arrest after fatal crash in New Brunswick
By   Staff The Canadian Press
The RCMP in New Brunswick have arrested a man after a fatal collision near Fredericton.
Kevin Godwin/Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
ROYAL ROAD, N.B.  The RCMP in New Brunswick have arrested a man after a fatal collision near Fredericton.
Police say the head-on collision between a pickup truck and a car happened on Route 620 in Royal Road on Wednesday around 11 p.m.
A 33-year-old man from Cardigan was pronounced dead at the scene.
The Mounties say a man was seen fleeing from the scene and was later located by investigators, taken to hospital and into police custody.
Const. Derek Black declined to specify what the 39-year-old mans connection was to the crash, adding that no charges have been laid.
The name of the victim has not been released pending the notification of family.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:07:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Machete fight in Winnipeg alley sends 2 men to hospital</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1973189/machete-fight-in-winnipeg-alley-sends-2-men-to-hospital/</Link>
        <Description>Four men were arrested and two sent to hospital, one in critical condition, following a machete fight in a Winnipeg back lane Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 1, 2015 8:07 am
Machete fight in Winnipeg alley sends 2 men to hospital
By Lara Schroeder Web Producer Global News
A Pritchard Avenue back lane is taped off on Friday morning. Police say two groups battled with machetes in the Winnipeg alley.
Gage Fletcher / Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WINNIPEG  Four men were arrested and two sent to hospital, one in critical condition, following a machete fight in a Winnipeg back lane Friday.
The fight between two groups of people took place in the back lane of 200 Pritchard Avenue just after 1 a.m., police said.
The man who was in critical condition following the fight has been upgraded to stable condition, police said.
Police continue to investigate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
