<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:24:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alleged Winnipeg bomber Guido Amsel to appear in court Tuesday</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096097/alleged-winnipeg-bomber-guido-amsel-to-appear-in-court-tuesday/</Link>
        <Description>A man accused of sending letter bombs to Winnipeg lawyers and his ex-wife is scheduled to make his first court appearance Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 9:24 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 9:29 am
Alleged Winnipeg bomber Guido Amsel to appear in court Tuesday
By   Staff The Canadian Press
Guido Amsel, 49, is shown in this undated handout photo. Winnipeg police investigating the bombing of a law firm say if there are any more suspicious packages in the mail they will likely be found in the next day or so. THE CANADIAN PRESS/HO - Winnipeg Police Service
Winnipeg Police Service handout / Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WINNIPEG  A man accused of sending letter bombs to Winnipeglawyers and his ex-wife is scheduled to make his first courtappearance Tuesday on charges including attempted murder.
Police allege Guido Amsel became so enraged over perceivedmistreatment at the hands of his former wife and lawyers who hadbeen involved in the dispute, he sent explosive devices to theiroffices though Canada Post.
READ MORE: Winnipeg letter bombs hidden in voice recorders: police
Maria Mitousis, his ex-wifes lawyer, lost one of her hands whenthe first letter bomb went off last Friday.
Police detonated two more devices over the weekend and warnedjustice officials that more could be found in the next day or so.
The situation has unnerved many city residents and prompteddozens of reports of suspicious packages.
City hall and a nearby Canada Post office were briefly evacuatedMonday.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:20:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sinkhole closes eastbound lanes on Eglinton Ave.</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096147/sinkhole-closes-eastbound-lanes-on-eglinton-ave/</Link>
        <Description>Several lanes of eastbound Eglinton Ave. are closed Tuesday morning as a result of a large sinkhole.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 9:20 am
Sinkhole closes eastbound lanes on Eglinton Ave.
By   Staff Global News
Jeremy Cohn / Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO  Several lanes of eastbound Eglinton Ave. are closed Tuesday morning as a result of a large sinkhole.
HAZARD:  Large sinkhole on Eglinton east of Keele near Richardson, witnesses indicate hole is approx. 20 feet, use alternative routes^dm
 Toronto Police OPS (@TPSOperations) July 7, 2015
Toronto police issued an advisory over Twitter just after 8 a.m. asking motorist to avoid the area east of Keele near Richardson.
Witnesses indicate the hole is approximately six metres in length.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:57:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Minivan crashes into southwest Calgary home</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096043/van-crashes-into-southwest-calgary-home/</Link>
        <Description>Police are searching for the driver of a silver minivan that crashed into a home in Upper Mount Royal on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:57 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 9:01 am
Minivan crashes into southwest Calgary home
By Melissa Ramsay Online Reporter Global News
Police hunt for the driver that smashed into a Calgary home on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CALGARY  Police are searching for the driver of a silver minivan that crashed into a home in Upper Mount Royal on Tuesday.
The collision took place in the 1000 block of Frontenac Avenue S.W. just before 4:30 a.m.
Officers say the garage suffered most of the damage.
The driver allegedly reversed the vehicle and drove off. He was last seen travelling east on 30th Avenue S.W.
We were sleeping we heard the loud bang and looked out the window and I saw a silver minivan taking off and I knew exactly what happened, said the homeowner. You can see he sped right through the traffic circle and hit the garage.
The Calgary Police Service and the Calgary Fire Department are investigating.
 With files from Sarah Offin
Police hunt for the driver that smashed into a Calgary home on Tuesday, July 7, 2015.
Global News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:42:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RCMP looking for two suspects in Surrey home invasion</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096094/rcmp-looking-for-two-suspects-in-surrey-home-invasion/</Link>
        <Description>A report of an assault in the 14300-block of 72 Avenue came in to police at about 1:30 a.m. and upon arrival found a 35-year-old male suffering from injuries from an assault.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:42 am
RCMP looking for two suspects in Surrey home invasion
By Paula Baker Online News Producer Global News
File photo
File/Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
RCMP is at a home in the Newton neighbourhood of Surrey following an assault and a home invasion early Tuesday morning.
A report of an assault in the 14300-block of 72 Avenue came in to police at about 1:30 a.m. and upon arrival found a 35-year-old male suffering from injuries from an assault. The victim was taken to the hospital in stable condition with non-life threatening injuries.
An initial investigation has shown that two males broke into the home and assaulted on of the residents before fleeing. After speaking to neighbours and witnesses, police have found indications the incident was targeted and the involved individuals are known to each other.
Anyone with more information is asked to contact Surrey RCMP at 604-599-0502 or Crime Stoppers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:36:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seniors get free admission to the Calgary Stampede for Western Heritage Day</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096072/seniors-get-free-admission-to-the-calgary-stampede-for-western-heritage-day/</Link>
        <Description>If you’re planning on heading to the Calgary Stampede on Tuesday, there are some deals and discounts you may wish to take advantage of.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:36 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 8:46 am
Seniors get free admission to the Calgary Stampede for Western Heritage Day
By Melissa Ramsay Online Reporter Global News
The Calgary Stampede grounds on July 5th, 2014.
THE CANADIAN PRESS IMAGES/Larry MacDougal
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CALGARY  If youre planning on heading to the Calgary Stampede on Tuesday, there are some deals and discounts you may wish to take advantage of.
July 7th marks Western Heritage Day at the Stampede grounds, a time dedicated to the citys seniors.
As such, anyone age 65 and older will get free admission all day long.
READ MORE: How to save money at the 2015 Calgary Stampede
The park opens at 9 a.m. to seniors and their paying guests.
There will also be free coffee and doughnuts (while supplies last) in the Agrium Western Event Centre from 9 a.m. to 10:30 a.m.
While there, guests can see a free show staring Canadian Trick Rider, Nikki Flundra, a feature performance by the Calgary Stampede Showriders and the music stylings of Herb Williams and Trevor Panczak.
On Monday, over 8,800 people passed through the turnstiles to enter the Calgary Stampede.
More than 462,800 people have visited the Stampede so far this year.If youre planning on heading to the Calgary Stampede on Tuesday, there are some deals and discounts you may wish to take advantage of.
Related
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:36:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Soldiers arrive in northern Sask. to help battle wildfires</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096090/soldiers-arrive-in-northern-sask-to-help-battle-wildfires/</Link>
        <Description>Soldiers start to receive training to help fight wildfires in northern Saskatchewan as flames inch closer to La Ronge.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:36 am
Updated: July 7, 2015 9:15 am
Soldiers arrive in northern Sask. to help battle wildfires
By David Giles Senior Web Producer Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH ABOVE: 500 troops arrive in Prince Albert to battle wildfires. Joelle Tomlinson reports.
PRINCE ALBERT, Sask.  Soldiers started rolling into Saskatchewan on Monday to double firefighting efforts in the north. By 10 p.m., 500 members of the rapid response unit of the Canadian Forces based in Edmonton were in Prince Albert.
About 200 received eight hours of training when they arrived late Monday afternoon and the remainder will likely be trained on Tuesday.
Obviously we are not professional firefighters, but we are getting some great and valuable training tonight (Monday) and into the week to set us up in addition to the other valuable skills we bring to the table, said Lt.-Col. Mason Stalker.
Theyre going to get things like coveralls, goggles, ear protection, hard hats, etc. and once theyre issued those, add that to the training and the basic skill sets they already bring to the table, well get them projected north in support of the Government of Saskatchewan.
Wildfires inch closer to Saskatchewan communities
READ MORE: Situation very critical as crews battle northern Sask. wildfires
Initially, it was reported 1,000 troops would be coming to assist with wildfire fighting efforts. The other 500 troops will be deployed from Shilo, Man. if needed.
Weve deliberately done a phased approach into this zone, because we certainly dont want to overwhelm and we want to bring what is required to assist the people of Saskatchewan, said Stalker.
So if the Government of Saskatchewan, in consultation with the fire centre here, determines that more is needed, there are additional, as I mentioned that other immediate response unit thats based in Shilo, my commander would start the process based on the recommendations from, of course the wildfire centre here and the Government of Saskatchewan if they are needed.
Colin King, with Saskatchewans Emergency Management department, described the fire situation as critical and said people evacuated from more than 50 communities wouldnt be returning soon.
The threat has not been reduced in any of those communities. We are advising all community leadership to remain out until it is safe, he said.
La Ronge Fire Situation Update (July 6/2015 8:00pm) pic.twitter.com/rORkQa2xHq
 Thomas Sierzycki (@TSierzycki) July 7, 2015
As of Monday evening, the most significant of 112 fires burning in the province was north of La Ronge, one of the largest communities in north. Mayor Thomas Sierzycki issued a fire update on Twitter about 8 p.m. local time saying the flames were just 1.5 kilometres from residential areas.
Residents were evacuated on the weekend from the town, as well as neighbouring Air Ronge and the Lac La Ronge Indian Band.
READ MORE: Fire evacuation largest in Saskatchewans history
Fires and thick smoke forced others in the north to start leaving their homes 11 days earlier.
Flames have destroyed about a dozen homes, remote cabins and other buildings in Montreal Lake, Weyakwin and Wadin Bay. One building also burned north of La Ronge.
About 300 square kilometres are burning in what officials are calling high-priority fire zones, about 10 times the yearly average.
Scott Wasylenchuk with the Provincial Fire Centre had some good news, however. An area near La Ronge burned in an old forest fire is acting as a natural barrier and wind was expected to shift flames away from the town.
Which means some of the fire lines closest to the community wont be as hot and well be able to get on them and make good progress, he said.
Premier Brad Wall, who visited La Ronge last week, said hes glad soldiers are on hand to help and hes not worried fire will spread into the town.
Right now were in a pretty good spot  Were feeling cautiously optimistic after a difficult weekend.
READ MORE: Hundreds forced from homes by Saskatchewan wildfires staying in Cold Lake
Nearly 700 evacuees from La Ronge were being housed in Cold Lake, Alta. The Alberta government had said it was preparing to receive up to 5,000 after centres in Saskatoon, Regina, Prince Albert and North Battleford were filling up.
Karri Kempf with Saskatchewans Social Services Ministry said slightly more than 7,000 have registered as evacuees and she estimates another 2,000 others are staying with friends and family.
With files from The Canadian Press
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:32:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vancouver mayor to talk climate change with Pope</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096089/vancouver-mayor-to-talk-climate-change-with-pope/</Link>
        <Description>Gregor Robertson will join about 30 other representatives of big cities from Europe, Africa, Asia and the Americas for a two-day visit with Pope Francis in Vatican City on July 21. </Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:32 am
Vancouver mayor to talk climate change with Pope
By   Geordon Omand Canadian Press
Pope Francis waves to faithful during his weekly general audience, in St. Peter's Square, at the Vatican.
THE CANADIAN PRESS/AP, Andrew Medichini
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
VANCOUVER  The mayor of Vancouver says he plans on encouraging the Pope to ramp up pressure on national governments across the globe to take action on climate change when he meets with the Catholic leader later this month.
Gregor Robertson will join about 30 other representatives of big cities from Europe, Africa, Asia and the Americas for a two-day visit with Pope Francis in Vatican City on July 21. He will be the only Canadian representative in the delegation of global municipal leaders.
Story continues below
Its telling that the Pope is reaching out to mayors as part of his direct-action agenda to tackle climate action and poverty because were on the front lines of it and were committed to dealing with these challenges, Robertson said in an interview.
The Pope recognizes that mayors play a key role in leading communities to a better future  were where the rubber hits the road in taking care of cities and weve largely been left out of the conversation.
Robertson levelled harsh words for the current Canadian government, saying it has been in the bad books globally because of inaction on the environmental front. National governments in general have failed to deliver solutions on climate change, he said.
But at a city level theres serious action and commitment and its important that the rest of the world understands that, Robertson said.
Ill be sharing stories from our work in Vancouver and encouraging global cities and the Vatican to continue pressing for more urgent and aggressive action.
Robertson referenced Vancouvers commitment to converting the city to 100-per-cent renewable energy, the citys calls for binding targets on climate pollution and its ambition at being recognized as the worlds greenest city.
The mayor, who isnt Catholic and doesnt follow any organized religion, said he was humbled to be included on the pontiffs invite list.
Its a responsibility that I dont take lightly.
The invitation comes in the wake of the Popes unprecedented encyclical on climate change, released last month, which blamed climate change on an unequal, fossil fuel-based, structurally perverse economy that favours a culture of consumption at the expense of the worlds poor.
The landmark document was heralded as a call to action in framing climate change as the moral challenge of our era.
Many lauded the Vaticans foray into environmental issues, while critics lambasted the church for stepping outside its area of expertise.
I dont get economic policy from my bishops or my cardinal or my Pope, said U.S. Republican presidential contender and converted Catholic Jeb Bush during a campaign stop in New Hampshire.
Others commended the Pope for his outspoken stance on climate-change action, including Robertson.
I think the Popes leadership is fantastic and much needed from an important religious leader on what is essentially a moral issue and the toughest challenge in human history, he said. Its crucial for political, religious, business and community leaders to be rallying aggressively right now  its so urgent.
World leaders are slated to meet later this year in Paris for the United Nations Climate Change Conference.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:29:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Longtime Hollywood producer Jerry Weintraub dies at 77</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096085/longtime-hollywood-producer-jerry-weintraub-dies-at-77/</Link>
        <Description>One of the last of the classic Hollywood showmen, Jerry Weintraub built his show business empire on a Rolodex and chutzpah.</Description>
        <MainBody>July 7, 2015 8:29 am
Longtime Hollywood producer Jerry Weintraub dies at 77
By   Jake Coyle The Associated Press
Jerry Weintraub, pictured on June 8, 2015.
Frazer Harrison / Getty Images
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
NEW YORK  One of the last of the classic Hollywood showmen, Jerry Weintraub built his show business empire on a Rolodex and chutzpah.
The Brooklyn-born son of a Bronx jeweler, Weintraub rose from the mailroom of a talent agency to become a top concert promoter before shifting into a decades-long career as a top Hollywood producer.
Story continues below
Along the way, Weintraub worked with the most famous of stars  Elvis Presley, Frank Sinatra, George Clooney, Brad Pitt  and was a close friend of former President George H.W. Bush. He relished his insider status, just as they savored the stories that eagerly poured out of him.
Weintraub, the dynamic producer and manager who pushed the career of John Denver and produced such hits movies as Nashville, Karate Kid and Oceans Eleven, died Monday in Santa Barbara, California. He was 77. A publicist for Weintraub said he died of cardiac arrest.
Jerry was an American original who earned his success by the sheer force of his instinct, drive, and larger-than-life personality, said Bush, a longtime friend. He had a passion for life, and throughout the ups and downs of his prolific career, it was clear just how much he loved show business.
Weintraub failed in one of his most ambitious gambits. His attempt to found his own studio, Weintraub Entertainment Group, ended in bankruptcy after only three years. But his long career  very much alive at the time of his passing  was marked by savvy innovation (he was among the first to stage arena tours) and old-school class.
Weintraub had his choice lunch spots in Los Angeles, his desert home in Palm Springs and his favored places to moor his yacht off the French Riviera. A self-made man, he fashioned himself in the mold of old Hollywood showman like Mike Todd, Cecil B. DeMille and P.T. Barnum. He titled his 2011 memoir: When I Stop Talking, Youll Know Im Dead.
At the time, he joked he might write another: Dead, But Still Talking.
In the coming days there will be tributes about our friend Jerry Weintraub, said Clooney, a star of the Oceans movies. Well laugh at his great stories and applaud his accomplishments. And in the years to come, the stories and accomplishments will get better with age, just as Jerry would have wanted it. But not today. Today our friend died.
One of Weintraubs most recent successes was the 2013 Liberace drama Behind the Candelabra. After the studios passed, he took it to HBO, where it won 11 Emmys.
He left numerous projects behind, including the recently debuted HBO series The Brink with Jack Black, and an upcoming big-budget remake of Tarzan.
If asked my philosophy, it would be simply this: Savor life, dont press too hard, dont worry too much. Or as the old-timers say, Enjoy,' he wrote his book. But  I never could live by this philosophy and was, in fact, out working, hustling, trading, scheming, and making a buck as soon as I was old enough to leave my parents house.
Growing up, Weintraub said he father, a successful gem salesman, taught him only two things are important at the end of the week: how much you owe the bank and how much you have in it.
Hired to work in the mailroom of the William Morris Agency, Weintraub then landed a job with Lew Wassermans MCA, where he worked as advance man for the agencys stars.
His career as a promoter took a giant step in 1970 when after a lengthy courtship he persuaded Elvis Presleys manager, Col. Tom Parker, to let him promote Presley concerts. It was at a time when Presley was beginning to do live shows after years of concentrating on movies.
Weintraub and partner Tom Hulett introduced such improvements as a modern sound system for Presley, an experience that propelled Weintraub into the top ranks of promoters.
Around the same time, Weintraub saw Denver at a small Greenwich Village nightclub and was overwhelmed by the mountaineers easy manner. He took on Denver as a client.
He would be a test case for all my theories on selling and packaging, for everything I had learned since I left home, Weintraub said.
After enormous success followed, Denver bought Weintraub a Rolls-Royce as a thank-you gift. Weintraub said, I couldnt help thinking that it wasnt too long ago that neither of us had bus fare.
Weintraub produced a dozen Denver musical specials on television  winning an Emmy for one of them  and the hit 1977 movie Oh, God! It starred George Burns as God and Denver as the young grocer whom God approaches to spread his message.
He also set up successful tours for Sinatra and produced the television special Sinatra  the Main Event, as well as joint appearances with Denver. Among other musicians Weintraub worked with were Bob Dylan, Neil Diamond and the Beach Boys.
After his first marriage (which resulted in a son, Michael), Weintraub married torch singer Jane Morgan in 1965. They had three adopted children: Julie, Jamie and Jordy. The pair separated but never divorced.
Weintraubs emphasis shifted to movies with 1975s Nashville, Robert Altmans acclaimed comedy-drama of American life as seen through the eyes of 24 characters in and around the country music business. It landed five Oscar nominations, including best picture.
In his memoir, Weintraub said he didnt understand the complicated script, but he was eager to produce it because Altman did, and it was Altman who was going to make the movie.
Weintraub went on to produce such notable films as Barry Levinsons Diner, All Night Long, The Karate Kid, and William Friedkins controversial, gay-themed Cruising.
He became chief of United Artists in 1985 but was ousted after just five months amid reports of disagreements with financier Kirk Kerkorian. He later reached a settlement with the company.
In 1987, he attempted to establish his own studio, WEG, but it went belly up in 1990 after a string of flops including My Stepmother Is an Alien.
I had, in a sense, promoted myself out of the job I always wanted, which was telling stories, producing, he wrote in his memoir. (The films) now were being made for me instead of by me.
After the WEG bankruptcy, Weintraub continued producing, putting out such films as Vegas Vacation and Oceans Eleven and its starry sequels. He remade The Karate Kid in 2010, setting the project up in China and starring the young Jaden Smith, Will Smiths son. Weintraub said he questioned it 150,000 times before backing it.
Starting in the 1980s, Weintraub became known as one of the Republican Partys most loyal supporters in Hollywood. He had been close to Bush years before he became president, and in 1991, he hosted a star-studded party for the president at his Malibu home and played golf with Bush and former President Ronald Reagan.
 with files by the late Bob Thomas of The Associated Press
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:20:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Introducing Hero4 Session: GoPro’s tiny cube-shaped camera</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096041/introducing-hero4-session-gopros-tiny-cube-shaped-camera/</Link>
        <Description>GoPro has unveiled its smallest camera yet – a cube-shaped, waterproof camera that weighs in at just 2.6 ounces.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
TORONTO  GoPro has unveiled its smallest camera yet  a cube-shaped, waterproof camera that weighs in at just 2.6 ounces.
The Hero4 Session is about the size of a large ice cube and will retail for US$399. According to the company, the Hero4 Session is 50 per cent smaller and 40 per cent lighter than the rest of GoPros high-end Hero4 range.
Unlike GoPros other cameras, the Hero4 Session only has one button to turn it on and start recording  allowing for the smaller design. The camera is also waterproof up to 33 feet thanks to its fully sealed design.
Although its smaller, the camera still packs the same capabilities as other GoPro models.
It can record video at full HD resolution at up to 60 frames per second and features the companys Protune mode, designed for a more cinematic look.
In May, GoPro announced it was getting into the drone and virtual reality business. By 2016 the company plans to come out with a quadcopter drone geared toward consumers.
The Hero4 Session will be available starting July 12.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:18:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Northern Manitoba to get $31-million marine observatory</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2096055/northern-manitoba-to-get-31-million-marine-observatory/</Link>
        <Description>A multimillion-dollar marine observatory is being built in Churchill, Manitoba.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
CHURCHILL, Man.  A multimillion-dollar marine observatory is being built in Churchill, Man.
More than $22 million in federal and provincial funding has been announced for the facility.
READ MORE: Manitoba eyes lifting limits on park eco-tourism
It will offer reasearchers the chance to study the impact of oil spills in sea ice and look into issues facing Arctic marine transportation.
The centre will bring together researchers from Manitoba, as well as the universities of Calgary, Victoria, Laval, Dalhousie and Washington.Federal government departments will also be involved.
David Barber, an associate dean at the University of Manitoba, will lead the research.
Total cost of the observatory is around $31 million.
The Canadian Press, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
