<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Global News">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:00:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Convicted Surrey Six murderers sue B.C. government</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2023011/convicted-surrey-six-murderers-sue-b-c-government/</Link>
        <Description>Cody Haevischer and Matthew Johnston say they were held in solitary confinement without adequate cause for 14 months after their arrests in April 2009.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 10:00 pm
Updated: May 28, 2015 10:03 pm
Convicted Surrey Six murderers sue B.C. government
By   Laura Kane The Canadian Press
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
VANCOUVER  Two men convicted of first-degree murder in a mass execution that left six dead are suing the British Columbia government for alleged abuses they suffered while awaiting trial.
Cody Haevischer and Matthew Johnston say they were held in solitary confinement without adequate cause for 14 months after their arrests in April 2009.
The men claim they were kept in cells smeared with feces and blood, denied visits with family, exposed to light 24 hours a day and video recorded constantly even when using the toilet.
The plaintiffs emotions would fluctuate suddenly between anger, bitterness and fear. The plaintiff began to feel like he was no longer the same person, Johnstons statement of claim says.
He became despondent and was wholly powerless to change his circumstances.
Haevischer and Johnston were each convicted of conspiracy and six counts of first-degree murder in the deaths of six people in a highrise condo unit in Surrey, B.C., in October 2007.
The Crowns theory was that the Red Scorpions gang plotted to murder a rival drug trafficker but that five others, including a neighbour and a fireplace repairman, were also killed to eliminate witnesses.
READ MORE: Timeline of Surrey Six shootings and trial
Haevischer and Johnston have since appealed the verdicts, and on Wednesday filed separate notices of civil claim seeking damages for violations of their Charter rights.
Haevischer said that after his arrest he was placed in solitary confinement in the Surrey Pretrial Centre, where he was moved between filthy cells, had no access to a television or radio and was denied visits with his daughter for two months.
After he was moved to the Vancouver Island Regional Correction Centre, he was kept in segregation and spent one month in an observation cell with a glass wall that allowed guards and inmates to see him at all times, the claim alleges.
Johnston said in his claim that when he complained about the blood and feces smeared on cell walls at Fraser Regional Correction Centre, he was told to clean it up with toilet paper and tap water.
He suffered panic attacks and memory problems and began singing and talking to himself, the claim said.
Both say they suffer from anxiety and mental health problems as a result.
None of the allegations has been tested in court.
The Justice Ministry said it could not comment as the case is before the courts, but B.C. Corrections has the authority to confine individuals if they are believed to be a danger to themselves or others, are at risk of harm or are a security risk to a facility.
The men claim they were told on various occasions that they were being segregated because they faced harm from other inmates or posed a danger to others. But both men dispute these reasons, saying they had no behavioural problems.
The lawsuits allege that wardens were acting on orders from the RCMP team that had investigated the so-called Surrey Six killings.
Both men were released from solitary confinement in June 2010, after a judge ruled that Jamie Bacon, the alleged Red Scorpion gangster who is still awaiting trial, was treated cruelly and unusually while in segregation.
In that case, a B.C. Supreme Court judge ruled that the warden at Surrey Pretrial Centre acted improperly by placing Bacon in confinement and restricting his mail, visits and phone calls under police influence.
After Haevischer and Johnston were convicted in October 2014 , their lawyers applied for a stay of proceedings because of the alleged abuses they suffered. But a judge ruled the matter was best dealt with in civil court.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:31:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Atwater Library celebrates Quebec’s English language writers</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024196/atwater-library-celebrates-quebecs-english-language-writers/</Link>
        <Description>Called AWE, an acronym for Atwater Writers Exhibition, the display features some of the works and personal effects of great Quebec writers.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 9:31 pm
Updated: May 28, 2015 9:37 pm
Atwater Library celebrates Quebecs English language writers
By Peter Anthony Holder Anchor Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH ABOVE:The Atwater Library is hosting a special event to celebrate Quebecs English language writers. Globals Peter Anthony Holder was there.
MONTREAL  Quebec has a strong history of English writers, and an exhibit at The Atwater Library in Westmount proudly has a taste of it on display. Called AWE, an acronym for Atwater Writers Exhibition, the display features some of the works and personal effects of great Quebec writers.
Story continues below
The exhibit, which organizers hope will run through the summer and beyond, is just a small part of what they would like to see in the future. The goal is to one day have a permanent Montreal Writers Museum at The Atwater Library.
There have been a few events leading up to this exhibit since late autumn, but Thursday nightwas the launch, complete with a 5--7 hosted by Montreal Gazette cartoonist, Terry Mosher.
The event was a bit of a homecoming for Mosher, since as an eight-year-old The Westmount Library was his first library. He was genuinely thrilled to be able to help out in a building that for him held such fond memories.
This [exhibit] is a tremendous effort and is something that was absolutely necessary in support of English language writers in Quebec. We have a wonderful tradition and it continues, said Mosher.
Many of those in attendance were members of Montreals literati and writing community, eager to acknowledge this history and the works of some of their own. In putting together the exhibit, Project Coordinator Elise Moser says she worked hard to make sure there was a broad representation of talent from, as she called them, some of the titans of English writing, such as Irving Layton, Leonard Cohen or Mordecai Richler, to the lesser known talents.
You dont get a whole community out of a couple of titans. You need everybody else whos doing everything around them. And I wanted to try to make sure that that development was represented, said Mosher.
The project was put together with the help of some funding from the Community Cultural Action Fund (CCAF) of Canadian Heritage and can be seen at the Atwater Library, located at 1200 Atwater Avenue in Westmount.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:24:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Okanagan symposium tackles cultural safety in health care</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024211/okanagan-symposium-tackles-cultural-safety-in-health-care/</Link>
        <Description>“History has shown that [Aboriginal peoples] engagement in health care services is really low and the experiences that we have had can be negative, so cultural safety is about working together to identify practices that are safe for everyone to access health care services.” </Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 9:24 pm
Okanagan symposium tackles cultural safety in health care
By Megan Turcato Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
KELOWNA  It may not be a household phrase, but the topic of cultural safety drew over 200 people to UBC Okanagan today for the second (annual?) Okanagan Cultural Safety Symposium. The one day event gave health care workers, Aboriginal people and others a chance to talk about cultural safety and how it impacts the way aboriginal people interact with the health care system.
Story continues below
History has shown that our engagement in health care services is really low and the experiences that we have had can be negative, so cultural safety is about working together to identify practices that are safe for everyone to access health care services, says Jennifer Houde, child and family and health services manager for the Okanagan Nation Alliance.
UBC Okanagan researchers were also on hand to talk about their studies .
What that first study showed very persuasively is that Aboriginal people do not have positive experiences with health and social service delivery organizations especially and particularly those that are run by non-Aboriginal organizations, says Mike Evans, a UBCO professor.
Evans added that the research shows the situation is turned around when an effort is made.
When [Aboriginal people] were made to feel respected [and] when they were made to feel welcome as Aboriginal people, the positive impact of that was profound, he said.
Houde is quick to point out that a lot has already been done locally to tackle the issue of cultural safety.
However, we still have experiences in health care that are based within racism, she says. What we hope comes out of this is a real focused approach to cultural safety.
Medical health officer, Dr. Rob Parker, didnt seem surprised to hear about Aboriginal people having negative experiences with the health care sector.
I think all those examples of either implicate or explicate racism still occur far too frequently. I think non-Aboriginal people,  physicians [and] nurses, we see examples of it at times and it is important for us to bring it to light and talk to the person who is doing it, says Parker.
The Interior Health Authoritys board of directors endorsed an Aboriginal Health and Wellness Strategy this week. There are other initiatives underway , including patient navigators that Interior Health says support Aboriginal patients, caregivers and their families while in the health-care system.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:20:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One final push for departing Kelowna Rockets</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024212/one-final-push-for-departing-kelowna-rockets/</Link>
        <Description>The Kelowna Rockets are just two wins away from taking it all. Every game from here on out is do or die...</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 9:20 pm
One final push for departing Kelowna Rockets
By Lauren Pullen Anchor/Reporter/Web Producer Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
The Kelowna Rockets are just two wins away from taking it all. Every game from here on out is do or die.
For a handful of departing players, its their last chance to bring home the Memorial Cup.
You come in when you are 15 and you think, oh Ive got five years, and you kind of take it for granted, and the next thing you know youre 21, says overager Tyrell Goulbourne.
This run will be the last for overagers Goulbourne, Cole Martin and Chance Braid. Josh Morrissey and Leon Draisaitl will also be moving on from the Rockets, and chances are with the impressive play of captain Madison Bowey, he wont be back next year either.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:20:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Students take part in P.A.R.T.Y program at KGH</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024210/students-take-part-in-p-a-r-t-y-program-at-kgh/</Link>
        <Description>Dozens of central Okanagan high school students were invited to attend a party at Kelowna General Hospital on Wednesday and Thursday...</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 9:20 pm
Students take part in P.A.R.T.Y program at KGH
By Neetu Garcha Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
KELOWNA  Dozens of central Okanagan high school students were invited to attend a party at Kelowna General Hospital on Wednesday and Thursday. However, it wasnt the kind of party youre thinking of.
Story continues below
P.A.R.T.Y stands for Preventing Alcohol and Risk-Related Trauma in Youth Program, says Blake Birnie, Coordinator of the Central Okanagan P.A.R.T.Y program. Its a program to kind of educate the younger generation about the risks involved with texting and driving, drinking and driving, smoking marijuana and driving and just educate them on how they can avoid getting into a situation that might cause them or someone else harm.
Birnie says its a program that is implemented in various schools across the province. Right now, it is just a pilot program in Kelowna, but organizers hope to continue the initiative in the Okanagan going forward.
The long-term goal is to get every grade 11 student in the central Okanagan through this program at one point, says Birnie.
The students took part in several eye-opening sessions like visiting a morgue and learning what the experience is like for a family member called in to identify a lost loved one. Birnie says there are four stations in total.
Theres a crash station where theres a wrecked vehicle and you have the firefighters, police officer and also a paramedic there to describe what its like at the scene of the crash, says Birnie.
Theres also a trauma room simulation so that the students get an idea for what its like to be a trauma patient and what its like to have to resuscitate someone.
We average one case per day of these traumas that come all throughout the Interior Health Authority, explains Michael Humer, thoracic surgeon and medical director of trauma at Kelowna General Hospital. A significant number of them come from KGH.
The experience left many of the students with a new perspective on safety, especially while driving.
Just seeing the after-effects of what goes wrong when you drink and drive and in motor vehicle accidents, it just it affects so many people it causes such problems to many poeples lives, says grade 12 student Laura Martinez.
According to Statistics Canada, Kelowna ranked highest in the country for the number of impaired driving incidents per 100,000 residents in 2011.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:20:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kelowna no longer “Best of the Best” for tap water taste</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024209/kelowna-no-longer-best-of-the-best-for-tap-water-taste/</Link>
        <Description>The City of Kelowna is the defending champion and it was trying to retain that crown Thursday. </Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 9:20 pm
Kelowna no longer Best of the Best for tap water taste
By Blaine Gaffney Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
KELOWNA  The City of Kelowna is the defending champion and it was trying to retain that crown Thursday.
At stake: the right to claim the best tasting tap water in the province.
The Best of the Best Tap Water Challenge was held at the annual convention of the BC Water &amp; Waste Association in Kelowna.
Fifteen domestic water purveyors from around the province participated in the competition.
Were looking for clarity of water, aroma, appearance and how it feels in the mouth. But mostly the taste and odour, how palatable it is, says Gene Koontz, one of the four judges.
Bragging rights were on the line, but beyond that, theres an underlying message to the event.
The purpose of the taste test is to raise awareness of the value of our water supplies and the fact there really is no substitute for this precious resource we rely on every day, says Tanja McQueen, the BCWWAs executive director.
This year, the title Best of the Best was claimed by the City of Chilliwack which draws its tap water from a high quality aquifer.
Were lucky the water quality is so high we dont even have to, like many of the municipalities, give pre-treatment before its even pumped into the pipes. Its a little bit of chlorine and away we go, says Chilliwack Director of Operations Glen Macpherson.
The other Okanagan entrants were Penticton, the Regional District of the North Okanagan and the Rutland Waterworks District.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:19:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>YVR’s Vantage Airport Group to redevelop LaGuardia Airport</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024058/yvrs-vantage-airport-group-to-redevelop-laguardia-airport/</Link>
        <Description>Vantage Airport Group Ltd., a subsidiary of the Vancouver Airport Authority, has been selected to oversee the development of a new $3.6 billion terminal at LaGuardia Airport.
</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 9:19 pm
Updated: May 28, 2015 9:20 pm
YVRs Vantage Airport Group to redevelop LaGuardia Airport
By Justin McElroy Web Producer Global News
A ticket agent waits for customers in a lightly trafficked LaGuardia Airport on Monday morning, Jan. 26, 2015, in New York.
AP Photo/Seth Wenig
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Vantage Airport Group Ltd., a subsidiary of the Vancouver Airport Authority, has been selected to oversee the development of a new $3.6 billion terminal at LaGuardia Airport.
We look forward to partnering with the Port Authority on this significant project for the city and state of New York, said Stewart Steeves of Vantage Airport Group in a statement. Vantage is the leader of a consortium that was announced as the bid winner today.
Story continues below
The Port Authoritys Board of Commissioners today voted unanimously to begin the first phase of their vision, part of an overall plan for revitalizing the airport.
LaGuardia has often been the subject of jokes in comparison to other New York-area airports. Vice President Joe Biden once compared it to a Third World Country.
For too long, LaGuardia has been the stepchild of our regions airports compared to JFK and Newark International, said Port Authority Vice Chairman Scott Rechler in a statement. Today we took the first step in moving forward with a comprehensive master plan to redevelop LaGuardia into a 21st century, world-class airport that the State of New York deserves.
Vantage, which draws on the expertise YVR officials have in growing and developing airports around the world, manages several airports. They began aggressively vying for the LaGuardia Airport in 2014.
WATCH: YVR airport operators eye Laguardia terminal redesign
Its a great opportunity for us to take all of our collective experience, build a really nice terminal that works for the passengers and airlines, and then who knows what other opportunities might come about, said Vancouver Airport Authority CEO Craig Richmond last year.
Its a large project, its a complex project, but that excites us, said George Case, Vantage Airport Group President.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:57:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>University of Lethbridge students celebrate convocation</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024121/university-of-lethbridge-celebrates-convocation/</Link>
        <Description>Over 1,400 graduates at the University of Lethbridge are celebrating their achievements at convocation and looking forward to the next chapter in their lives.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 8:57 pm
Updated: May 28, 2015 9:00 pm
University of Lethbridge students celebrate convocation
By Blake Lough Videographer Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
WATCH ABOVE:University of Lethbridge celebrates convocation. Blake Lough reports.
CALGARY Over 1,400 graduates at the University of Lethbridge are celebrating their achievements at convocation and looking forward to the next chapter in their lives.
Jenni Karl is one of those graduates, completing a decade-long chapter in her academic life by obtaining her PhD in neuroscience.
Lethbridge College convocation returns to Enmax Centre
It represents a lot of years of hard work and academic study, said Karl. A lot of delayed gratification and lots of excitement about the future.
It wasnt just graduates who were recognized and honoured. Janice Varzari was named the 13th chancellor of the university in March. For Varzari, it wasnt until she was sitting in front of the hundreds of graduates that the role really sunk in. Varzari is the very first graduate of the University of Lethbridge to become its chancellor.
Its almost fairy tale-like. I never expected that after I graduated with a Masters degree I would have another chance to be involved with the university.
[But] there I am sitting on stage as the chancellor.
Janice is really symbolic of what the university is all about, said university president Mark Mahon. An undergrad and a grad degree, has worked in healthcare, [and] has worked in business.
For Karl, the hard work has paid off. To mark the end of her time as a student, shes been awarded the Gold Medal of the Governor General.
A lot of hard work and perseverance, said Karl. Just kind of sticking it out through the difficult and not-so-rewarding times. But its worth it in the end.
Four ceremonies will be held in total with the final two taking place onFridayat 9:30 a.m. for the Faculty of Education and at and 1:30 p.m. for the Faculty of Management.
Shaw Media, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:41:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Difficult timing for Regina water rationing</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/2024054/difficult-timing-for-regina-water-rationing/</Link>
        <Description>Despite urging resident to conserve water, the city has only seen a modest reduction in use and it appears not everyone is doing their part to cut back.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28, 2015 8:41 pm
Difficult timing for Regina water rationing
By Teri Fikowski Reporter Global News
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' editorial staff without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
REGINA  Despite urging resident to conserve water, the city has only seen a modest reduction in use and it appears not all resident aredoing their part to cut back.
Officials are asking residents to cut water use by 25 per cent and say its especially important heading into the weekend.
The restrictionincludes not watering lawns, reducing toilet flushing and running full loads of dishes and laundry.
The city is doing its part: Until the issue is resolved outdoor pools sit empty, spray pads stay off and even street sweeping is on hold.
However despite the efforts, usage rates have only improved modestly.
One reason is that for an already short gardening season, timing isnt ideal.
We go through a lot of water in a day, explained Brad Crassweller with Cedar Creek Gardens &amp; Outdoor Expressions Landscapping. We try and do our best but if you try and leave your (flower) basket out in the sun and wind you wont have a basket for long.
According to Crassweller, this is one the busiest times of the year at his business, with clients starting to pour in.
He adds that for residents who just laid fresh sod, no water is out of the question.
Its a tough balance right now to have people buy all their stuff, spend all that money and then say dont water as much because its imperative that it gets enough water.
Some residents have taken their frustrations to social media.
City officials dont have plans for mandatory water rationing but say if they dont see usage rates improve soon, they could be forced to consider the option.
Officials from the Water Security Agency are expected to provide details on the support theyll be offering to the Buffalo Pound Water Treatment Plant Friday morning.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:35:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WATCH: Global National – May 28</title>
        <Link>http://globalnews.ca/news/1148831/watch-global-national/</Link>
        <Description>Watch the full broadcast of the Global National hosted by Dawna Friesen on Thursday, May 28.</Description>
        <MainBody>X
What is this?
Sponsored content is written by Global News' without any editorial influence by the sponsor. If you'd like to learn more...
Watch the full broadcast of the Global National hosted by Dawna Friesenon Thursday, May 28.
View more Global National videos by clicking here .
To submit a photo for our Your Canada segment, click here
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
