<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:50:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Justice and Cleveland reach deal to monitor police - USA TODAY</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH06_i8E40pqppFEpWg2hg-0WZMDw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778854753809&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2015/05/26/justice-police-monitor/27953553/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Justice and Cleveland reach deal to monitor police
WASHINGTON--The Justice Department and the city of Cleveland's troubled police department are expected to announce an agreement as soon as today that would subject local public safety operations to the
Post to Facebook
Justice and Cleveland reach deal to monitor police WASHINGTON--The Justice Department and the city of Cleveland's troubled police department are expected to announce an agreement as soon as today that would subject local public safety operations to the Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Huba2B
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
20
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Justice and Cleveland reach deal to monitor police
Kevin Johnson and Yamiche Alcindor , USA TODAY 7:41 p.m. EDT May 26, 2015
A Cleveland police officer looks on as people take to the streets and protest in reaction to Cleveland police officer Michael Brelo being acquitted of manslaughter charges after he shot two people at the end of a 2012 car chase in which officers fired 137 shots.
(Photo: Ricky Rhodes, Getty Images)
533 CONNECT 190 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 20 COMMENTEMAILMORE
The Justice Department and the city of Cleveland announced an agreement Tuesday that would place the troubled local police department under the direction of an independent monitor to ensure reforms following a string of deadly encounters involving officers.
The agreement comes following the weekend acquittal of an officer in the 2012 fatal shooting of  two unarmed residents, which prompted a wave of protests in the city, and the November shooting of a 12-year-old boy who was killed while playing with a toy gun in a local park.
Mayor Frank Jackson described the settlement as "a defining moment'' for the city, adding that he hoped it would serve as a "catalyst'' for broad reforms in the police department's relationship with a wary community.
Tanis Quach of Cleveland protests in front of the Justice Building. People took to the streets and protested in reaction to Cleveland police officer Michael Brelo being acquitted of manslaughter charges after he shot two people at the end of a 2012 car chase.
(Photo: Ricky Rhodes, Getty Images)
Vanita Gupta, who directs Justice's Civil Rights Division, said the 105-page agreement outlined needed improvement in virtually every aspect of the policing operation, from how Cleveland recruits its officers and how they are trained to the way it disciplines those officers who break the rules. A centerpiece of the federally monitored program is the creation of a community police commission composed of local civil rights advocates, business leaders, police union representatives and others to address such concerns as racial bias and whether officers are being held accountable for their actions.
A December Justice review of policing in Cleveland found the use of unreasonable force was part of a pattern of behavior among police that was in some cases endorsed by supervisors.
The Justice report mirrored recent findings in other cities, including Ferguson, Mo., and Albuquerque that have contributed to a national re-examination of policing in the U.S. Justice officials have reviewed the operations of more than 20 departments since 2009. This month, Justice launched a review of the Baltimore Police Department after last month's death of Freddie Gray. The 25-year-old man suffered severe spinal cord injuries and died while in police custody, touching off violent protests in that city. Six officers have been charged by state authorities in connection to Gray's arrest and death.
A person holds up a sign for justice for 12-year-old  Tamir Rice during a news conference Dec. 8, 2014, in Cleveland.
(Photo: Tony Dejak, AP)
"Constitutional policing is key to building trust between police departments and the communities they serve,'' Gupta said, appearing with Jackson to outline the agreement. "As you know, the difficult task of rebuilding trust between police and the community is one that communities around the country are struggling with, and it is also one that is not new.''
The Justice review of the Cleveland agency examined 600 incidents in which police used some method of force between 2010 and 2013. It concluded in part that law enforcement is "sometimes chaotic and dangerous  and frequently deprives individuals of their constitutional rights.''
Among the most troubling of last year's Justice disclosures was that in addition to the fatal shootings, excessive force sometimes involved victims who were struck in the head with the butts of police-issued firearms. And some of those incidents involved the mentally ill or emotionally disturbed.
Part of Tuesday's agreement specifically calls for additional training related to police encounters with the mentally ill. It calls on the Cleveland police to form a cadre of officers equipped to respond at all hours of the day to incidents involving "people in crisis.''
The Justice deal also requires officers to engage in "de-escalation techniques'' to avoid inappropriate applications of force, lethal and otherwise.
"If force is used,'' Gupta said, "officers will immediately provide emergency first aid as necessary.''
The recently concluded trial of Michael Brelo, 31, was connected to a frenzied chase in which officers fired 137 times, allegedly mistaking the pursued vehicle's back-fires for gunshots.
Brelo was acquitted of manslaughter charges, sparking a wave of protests that resulted in dozens of local arrests.
Patrick D'Angelo, Brelo's attorney at trial and the former attorney for the Cleveland Police Patrolmen's Association, called the agreement "a waste of time" and said it was the result of "armchair quarterbacking" by federal officials who don't understand the day-to-day experiences of officers.
"All these efforts are superficial," D'Angelo said Tuesday afternoon. "Sometimes there may be tragedies where deadly force has to be used. You don't see that too much when you are working in the Department of Justice in an ivory tower or in a building in the FBI because you're not out there in the streets."
D'Angelo said instead of focusing on the conduct of officers, leaders need to look into how top officials like the mayor and city council have contributed to the problems in the department and the lack of training for the rank and file. He also said there needs to be more community policing, better police supervision and more diversity in the department.
Charlotte Robinson's cousin Malissa Williams along with Timothy Russell were both killed during the 2012 fatal police chase and shooting involving Brelo. Robinson isn't sure having the federal government monitoring the police department will change what she believes are deeply rooted racist policing practices.
The Justice Department is still part of a broken criminal justice system that discriminates against blacks and federal officials may carry the same bias as local officers, Robinson said.
"It's like they are still on the same team," she said of Justice Department and Cleveland city officials. "I don't know if they are going to do what we asked them to do. Police are supposed to  protect and serve us and they keep killing us and it's like no one cares."
In the separate shooting of Tamir Rice, the 12-year-old boy, the officer identified as the shooter reportedly displayed emotional problems and poor firearm skills in his former job with a neighboring law enforcement agency before joining the Cleveland force where he was a rookie officer at the time of the November incident.
"You need to create a climate of trust," said Khalid Samad, a longtime Cleveland activist and co-founder of Peace in the Hood, a local civil rights group. "Who would want to live in a city without a police department? No one. You have to have order. But people just want good policing."
Basheer Jones, 30, a community activist and author who lives in Cleveland, is excited yet cautious about the agreement. He said the amount of time the agreement stays in place as well as the community police commission's composition and the authority it has will heavily influence the agreement's success.
"You could have a consent decree but if you don't have true oversight and enforcement, you just have a piece of paper," Jones said. "We want a structure that does not support racism."
533 CONNECT 190 TWEET 2 LINKEDIN 20 COMMENTEMAILMORE
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Huba2B
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:27:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Storms kill 16 in Texas, Oklahoma; Houston flooded - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHjtveWpsQAH8G771If2biIvKkdvQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778856208404&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/05/27/us-usa-storms-idUSKBN0OA19020150527</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Storms kill 16 in Texas, Oklahoma; Houston flooded
HOUSTON | By Kristen Hays and Amanda Orr
HOUSTON Torrential rains have killed at least 16 people in Texas and Oklahoma, including four in Houston where floods turned streets into rivers and led to about 1,000 calls for help in the fourth-most populous U.S. city, officials said on Tuesday.
The death toll is set to rise with numerous people still missing in Texas after the storms slammed the states during the Memorial Day weekend, causing record floods that destroyed hundreds of homes, swept away bridges, and even unearthed a coffin from a Houston cemetery. It washed ashore on the banks of a bayou.
"A lot of folks drove their car into high water and had to abandon those vehicles," Mayor Annise Parker said at a news conference.
Two of the dead in Houston were found in their cars and another two were found in a bayou. One was likely to be a male victim lost when an evacuation boat capsized during a water rescue by emergency crews in the morning.
The Oklahoma Medical Examiner's office said six people have died in weather-related incidents over the holiday weekend in the state.
Though Parker said parts of the city were unscathed, more than 1,000 vehicles were submerged in the Houston floods and people took instead to bicycles, kayaks and surfboards to navigate water-covered streets.
The Houston Fire Department brought about 500 people to safety in boats, local media reports said.
President Barack Obama said on Tuesday he had assured Texas Governor Greg Abbott that he could count on help from the federal government as the state recovers from the floods.    Abbott has declared a state of disaster in at least 40 Texas counties, including Harris County, home to Houston.
Abbott said he has deployed the state's National Guard and was worried the death toll could rise.
"It's devastating to see what I saw on the Blanco River when this tidal wave of water just swept away neighborhoods," he said, recalling a disaster area in central Texas.
Twelve people are confirmed missing and about another 30 are unaccounted for due to flooding that hit along the Blanco River, county officials said. The missing were from two families whose vacation home was swept off its foundation in Wimberley, a town about 30 miles (50 km) southwest of Austin.
Search dogs and boats were being used to search for the missing. The river rose so quickly and with such force, it caused a flood gauge to break, Hays County officials said.
There was no damage estimate available for the state, which has a $1.4 trillion-a-year economy and is the country's main domestic source of energy as well as an agricultural and manufacturing power.
Houston resident Dutch Small, 40, climbed onto the roof of his car when the water came up to his knees inside his vehicle and was eventually rescued by a passing tow truck driver.
"It happened so fast. Every person that died in the flooding, I know what was going through their minds. They didn't measure the threat accurately. They were like me," Small told Reuters.
The National Weather Service issued tornado and thunderstorm watches for later on Tuesday and said more rain is expected this week in Texas and Oklahoma.
More than 200 flights had been canceled by early on Tuesday evening at airports in Houston and Dallas, some of the nation's busiest, as blocked roads made it difficult for workers to get to their jobs. A sinkhole also closed a runway at the Dallas/Fort Worth International airport.
Roughly 100,000 customers lost power throughout the state after the storm due to high winds and rising waters that caused power poles to snap.
In Houston, about 11 inches (28 cm) of rainwater fell on Monday while parts of Austin were hit by as much as 7 inches (18 cm). Helicopter crews in both cities plucked people to safety who had been stranded in cars and on top of buildings.
(Writing by Jon Herskovitz ; Additional reporting by Terry Wade and Amanda Orr in Houston, Jim Forsyth in San Antonio, Lisa Maria Garza in Dallas, Suzannah Gonzales in Chicago, Scott DiSavino in New York, and Eric M. Johnson in Seattle; Editing by Bill Trott and Sandra Maler )
An American flag, a remnant of Memorial Day holiday one day earlier, waves despite being caught in a tree, while Martin Bali, a resident of Austin, Texas, cleans his shoes after visiting a friend at his flood damaged home in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Tamir Kalifa
1 of 40
right
Larry Bowls surveys the flood damage to his friend's neighborhood in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Tamir Kalifa
2 of 40
right
DerryAnn Krupinsky (3rd L) coordinates where to send crews of volunteers helping with flood relief efforts from a shopping center parking lot in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Tamir Kalifa
3 of 40
right
Bill Taylor helps clean and remove debris from the interior of a friend's flood damaged home in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Tamir Kalifa
4 of 40
right
Sarah Alvarez and her mother Janie De Los Santos (R), take a break from cleaning their flood damaged house in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Tamir Kalifa
5 of 40
right
Dustin Nichols helps clean up his parents' flood damaged home in San Marcos, Texas May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Tamir Kalifa
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:15:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Draft | Bernie Sanders Challenges Hillary Clinton at His First Rally - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGLIRKnimbTzcNUTkDn8slOuyyNgQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778850621929&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/05/26/bernie-sanders-challenges-hillary-clinton-at-his-first-rally/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:26:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore's deadliest month in 15 years: May counts 35 homicides, so far - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHiBRwGibJwhrsMIvVSJyb0hC_iGQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778855813500&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/05/26/us/baltimore-deadliest-month-violence-since-1999/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Baltimore police chief on decreased number of arrests 05:12
PLAY VIDEO
"I hope that there is not a slowdown and what kind of message that sends to the community and to the government if that's the case," Batts said.
The numbers are up, Batts said, because "multiple people" have been "shot in groupings ... leading us to believe there is a gang nexus to the shootings that have taken place."
'We can't tolerate this'
Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake found the trend distressing and said additional police would be sent to communities with the most crime.
The mayor held an emergency meeting Sunday with police commissioner and command staff to address escalating violence, the station reported.
"We can't tolerate this ... on any level," the mayor said, according to the outlet. "My hope is the police will have the support they need from the community to be able to get some answers and bring some of these individual(s) to justice."
Police Commissioner Batts said getting answers and community help won't be easy, the station reported.
"We can't demand that of citizens. We have to go out and earn their trust," Batts said, according to the affiliate.
'Tragedy unfolding in our backyard'
Cornell William Brooks, president and CEO of NAACP, said the community and the police need to work together to reduce the violence. The NAACP, a civil rights group, is headquartered in Baltimore.
"Well, this is a tragedy unfolding in our backyard, the hometown of the NAACP," Brooks said. "We don't know why we see this horrific spike in murders and shootings.
"There is no excuse, none whatsoever for any kind of slow down or work stoppage," Brooks said. "The officers have taken an oath, and that oath is not to be abdicated."
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
People help clean up a CVS pharmacy in Baltimore on Tuesday, April 28, the morning after riots broke out during protests on Monday, April 27. The unrest followed the funeral for Freddie Gray , who died of a severe spinal cord injury he got while in police custody. There were more than 230 arrests, 144 vehicle fires and 15 structure fires, a city official said.
Hide Caption
1 of 13
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Members of the community clean up debris on April 28 from the CVS that was burned and looted in the riots.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
A neighborhood cleanup crew works to clear trash from the streets on April 28.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Caroline Byrd helps with cleanup efforts on April 28.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Volunteers help clear trash from a looted business on April 28.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
A man sweeps the street as law enforcement officers stand guard on April 28.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Baltimore firefighters inspect a burned store on April 28.
Hide Caption
7 of 13
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
People helping clean debris are seen in the reflection of a broken window on April 28.
Hide Caption
8 of 13
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Jason Park, left, and business owner Sung Kang survey the damage to his store on April 28.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Men wearing work gloves help clear debris on April 28.
Hide Caption
10 of 13
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Kailah Johnson, 5, joins her mother in a neighborhood cleanup on April 28. Schools were closed across the city.
Hide Caption
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Volunteers help clear the wreckage from damaged stores on April 28.
Hide Caption
12 of 13
Cleaning up after Baltimore riots 13 photos
Employee Sam Wirtz, left, surveys the damage to his store that came during the unrest on Monday, April 27.
Hide Caption
13 of 13
EXPAND GALLERY
But CNN law enforcement analyst Tom Fuentes said officers may be thinking twice about taking risks and showing aggressive policing in the wake of prosecutors filing charges against so many officers in the Gray case.
"These are legitimate concerns that the police have of being backed, trying to stop these murders that are in the streets," said Fuentes, a former FBI assistant director.
He also urged the community and police to engage in a discussion about public safety.
"This is a crisis that's being manufactured, I think, by the fact the community is not supporting the police," Fuentes said.
Overall this year, police report that Baltimore's homicides amount to 108 so far this year, compared with 79 at the end of May 2014, police figures show. There have also been 205 nonfatal shootings so far this year, compared with last year's figure of 115, the affiliate said.
CNN's Wesley Bruer and Chuck Johnston contributed to this report.
&lt;div id="ad_rect_atf_01" class="ad-ad_rect_atf_01"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
More from US
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:16:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Governor vetoes bill to abolish Neb. death penalty - USA TODAY</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHUSNTm_WTPX4b5cHetqv0Cp9nMlA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778850388789&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2015/05/26/nebraska-death-penalty-repeal/27987333/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
Governor vetoes bill to abolish Neb. death penalty
LINCOLN, Neb. (AP)  Gov. Pete Ricketts vetoed a bill Tuesday that would make Nebraska the first traditionally conservative state in more than four decades to abolish the death penalty, sending it back to lawmakers who will attempt an override.
Post to Facebook
Governor vetoes bill to abolish Neb. death penalty LINCOLN, Neb. (AP)  Gov. Pete Ricketts vetoed a bill Tuesday that would make Nebraska the first traditionally conservative state in more than four decades to abolish the death penalty, sending it back to lawmakers who will attempt an override. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1Hv7Zro
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Join the Nation's Conversation
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
Governor vetoes bill to abolish Neb. death penalty
AP 8:16 p.m. EDT May 26, 2015
Gov. Pete Ricketts speaks during a news conference Tuesday, accompanied by a group of state senators and other supporters, regarding his veto of a bill passed by the legislature that would repeal the death penalty in Nebraska.
(Photo: AP/Kristin Streff, Lincoln Journal Star)
5 CONNECT 38 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
LINCOLN, Neb. (AP)  Gov. Pete Ricketts vetoed a bill Tuesday that would make Nebraska the first traditionally conservative state in more than four decades to abolish the death penalty, sending it back to lawmakers who will attempt an override.
Nebraska lawmakers passed the bill last week with a veto-proof, 32-15 majority. At least 30 senators are needed for the veto override scheduled for Wednesday afternoon, but the Republican governor has been talking to individual senators to try to keep the death penalty in place.
Nebraska hasn't executed a prisoner since 1997, when the electric chair was used. The state has never imposed the punishment under the lethal injection process now required by state law, and the state lost its ability to do so when a key lethal injection drug expired in December 2013. Ricketts announced this month that the state had purchased new drugs to resume executions, but the state hasn't yet received them and civil liberties groups are expected to challenge the purchases in court.
Ricketts reiterated his support for capital punishment during a Capitol news conference with law enforcement, Nebraskans whose relatives were killed by current death-row inmates, and 11 state senators who support the death penalty.
"Nebraskans expect their public officials to strengthen public safety, not weaken it," Ricketts said. Abolishing capital punishment "sends the message to criminals that Nebraska will be soft on crime."
Nebraska Attorney General Doug Peterson, a fellow Republican, said state officials should keep the death penalty for the most heinous of criminals. Peterson, who took office in January, said his office was committed to overcoming the legal hurdles to allow executions to proceed.
"Give us this opportunity now to show our commitment, to do everything we can to carry out the death penalty in Nebraska," Peterson said.
The state's action to repeal the death penalty is unusual because of its traditionally conservative leanings. Maryland was the last state to end capital punishment, in 2013. Three other moderate-to-liberal states have done so in recent years: New Mexico in 2009, Illinois in 2011 and Connecticut in 2012. The last traditionally conservative state to eliminate the death penalty was North Dakota in 1973.
Thirty-two states and the federal government allow capital punishment.
Nebraska lawmakers haven't passed a death penalty repeal bill since 1979. Senators at the time didn't have enough votes to override then-Gov. Charles Thone.
The bill's lead sponsor, independent Sen. Ernie Chambers of Omaha, has said he's confident the bill will maintain enough support for the override. Many senators argued that they oppose the ultimate punishment for religious reasons. Others said it was too costly and inefficient, and questioned whether government could be trusted to manage it.
But some lawmakers said they still believed the veto could be sustained  and at least one senator who previously voted for the repeal said Tuesday he had changed his mind.
"You wouldn't see an effort like this if all hope was lost," said Sen. Beau McCoy, an Omaha Republican who supports capital punishment.
Sen. Jerry Johnson, a Republican who voted for the repeal, said he decided to switch votes because he believes the new governor's administration needs more time to carry out an execution. Johnson said he took calls all weekend from constituents who support the death penalty.
If new problems arise in carrying out the punishment, Johnson said Nebraska's current senators will have another chance to repeal it when they return for next year's session.
The veto came two days after one of Nebraska's 11 death-row inmates died in prison of natural causes. Michael Ryan spent three decades on death row for the 1985 cult killings of two people, including a 5-year-old boy. During a legislative hearing earlier this year, Chambers testified that Ryan had been diagnosed with terminal brain cancer.
Vivian Tuttle, whose daughter Evonne was murdered in a 2002 bank robbery in Norfolk, said she still wants the three robbers executed. They were sentenced to death for the killings of five people in the bank.
"I want justice for my grandchildren," Vivian Tuttle said. "I want justice for all the other families. They need to have that. So we need to keep the death penalty."
__
5 CONNECT 38 TWEET LINKEDIN COMMENTEMAILMORE
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Read or Share this story: http://usat.ly/1Hv7Zro
TOP VIDEOS
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:21:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US playwright, actor Sam Shepard arrested on drunken driving charge - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNE-9KBWUoMSSP6w7cPJf3zFWtOAag&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778856123686&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/05/26/us-usa-shepard-arrest-idUSKBN0OB2NM20150526</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Related: Entertainment, People
U.S. playwright, actor Sam Shepard arrested on drunken driving charge
Pulitzer Prize winning playwright and actor Sam Shepard is shown in this booking photo from the Santa Fe County Adult Detention Facility in Santa Fe, New Mexico in this handout photo released to Reuters May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Santa Fe County Adult Detention Facility/Handout via Reuters
left
Actor Sam Shepard in Pasadena, California, January 9, 2014.
Reuters/Lucy Nicholson
2 of 2
right
Actor and Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright Sam Shepard was arrested in New Mexico on suspicion of drunken driving, police said on Tuesday.
Shepard, 71, told police he had consumed roughly two tequila drinks at a downtown Santa Fe restaurant on Monday evening, police spokeswoman Andrea Dobyns said.
He refused a breath test and was arrested outside the eatery after failing a field sobriety test, Dobyns said.
The restaurant's security staff had called police to report an intoxicated patron trying to drive a pickup truck with the vehicle's emergency brake engaged,
"The officers said he was compliant, but had bloodshot watery eyes and the officers were able to smell the alcohol," Dobyns said.
Shepard was booked into the Santa Fe County Jail on a charge of aggravated driving while intoxicated, according to online records.
The records showed he spent the night in jail, and a clerk said he was being arraigned in Santa Fe Magistrate Court on Tuesday.
A representative for Shepard did not immediately respond to requests for comment.
Shepard's plays include "Buried Child," for which he won a Pulitzer Prize in 1979, "True West," "Curse of the Starving Class" and "Fool for Love."
He was nominated for an Academy Award for his portrayal of test pilot Chuck Yeager in the 1983 movie "The Right Stuff."
He has appeared in dozens of other films, including "August: Osage County," "The Notebook," "Black Hawk Down" and "Steel Magnolias."
In 2009, Shepard was arrested in central Illinois and charged with speeding and drunken driving after telling police he had stopped at a tavern before heading to a hotel, the Bloomington, Illinois, Pantagraph newspaper reported.
(Reporting by Eric M. Johnson in Seattle; Editing by Ellen Wulfhorst and Peter Cooney )
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:10:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Data thieves gain access to 100000 US taxpayers' information: IRS - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH7an0TrBxuKuH1nuxGS7BrzxPepQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778856128731&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/05/26/us-usa-tax-cybersecurity-idUSKBN0OB2H520150526</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Related: U.S., Politics
Data thieves gain access to 100,000 U.S. taxpayers' information: IRS
United States Internal Revenue Service Commissioner John Koskinen appears before a House Oversight and Government Reform Government Operations Subcommittee hearing on ''Examining Solutions to Close the $106 Billion Improper Payment Gap'' in Washington July 9, 2014.
Reuters/Gary Cameron
Tax return information for about 100,000 U.S. taxpayers was illegally accessed by cyber criminals over the past four months, U.S. IRS Commissioner John Koskinen said on Tuesday, the latest in a series of data thefts that have alarmed American consumers.
From February to May, attackers sought to gain access to personal tax information 200,000 times through the agency's "Get Transcript" online application, which calls up information from previous returns, he told a news conference. About half of those attempts were successful.
The breach did not affect any IRS data outside the "Get Transcript" application, and the agency said it would strengthen its security measures.
Koskinen said he could not comment on who the attackers might be, and a criminal investigation was ongoing.
"We're confident these are not amateurs. These are actually organized crime syndicates that not only we but everyone in the financial industry are dealing with," Koskinen said.
The data theft was largely intended to steal taxpayers' information to submit fraudulent returns next year, he said.
The agency currently believes that fewer than 15,000 fraudulent returns were processed as a result of the breach, likely resulting in refunds of less than $50 million.
The IRS security problem is the latest in a string of breaches. JPMorgan Chase as well as mega-retailers Target  and Home Depot have all suffered cyber attacks.
The IRS data theft differs in that it did not involve a computer hack. Criminals used information they had gathered about individuals to access the system as it was designed to be used, the IRS said.
The agency, which will begin to send notification letters to affected taxpayers this week, will provide free credit monitoring and protection for the victims.
Koskinen said the attackers must have had a significant amount of information already about the taxpayers.
In addition to names, addresses and Social Security numbers, the attackers would have needed so-called "out of wallet" data, personal information such as a person's first car or high school mascot, he said.
Koskinen said it was possible that identity thieves could get answers to these questions from individuals' social media accounts and compile them into searchable databases.
Koskinen said the tax agency was originally alerted to the problem by unusual activity in mid-April, which marks the end of the annual tax-filing season.
(Reporting by Brendan Pierson in New York; Editing by Sandra Maler , Richard Cowan , Mohammad Zargham and Cynthia Osterman )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:17:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Appeals court refuses to lift hold on Obama immigration action - Fox News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEVbY5CzL6jHwq-K5GvEX1S6g4QVw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778855938725&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/05/26/appeals-court-refuses-to-lift-hold-on-obama-immigration-action/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Appeals court refuses to lift hold on Obama immigration action
Published May 26, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
A federal appeals court refused Tuesday to allow the implementation, for now, of President Obama's executive action that could shield from deportation as many as 5 million illegal immigrants.
The U.S. Justice Department had asked the 5th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals to reverse U.S. District Judge Andrew Hanen's earlier decision temporarily halting the administration's plan. Hanen issued the temporary hold in February, after 26 states filed a lawsuit alleging Obama's action was unconstitutional.
Two out of the three judges on a court panel, though, voted Tuesday to deny the government's request, as the underlying case is argued.
White House Spokesperson Brandi Hoffine said after the ruling, "today, two judges of the Fifth Circuit chose to misinterpret the facts and the law in denying the government's request for a stay." 
The majority opinion reasoned that lifting the temporary hold -- known in judicial parlance as issuing a "stay" -- could cause serious problems for states should they ultimately win their challenge. It said the states have shown that "issuance of the stay will substantially injure" them.
It continued: "A stay would enable DAPA beneficiaries to apply for driver's licenses and other benefits, and it would be difficult for the states to retract those benefits or recoup their costs even if they won on the merits. That is particularly true in light of the district court's findings regarding the large number of potential beneficiaries, including at least 500,000 in Texas alone."
Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton praised Tuesday's decision.
"The separation of powers and check and balances remain the law of the land, and this decision is a victory for those committed to preserving the rule of law in America," he said in a written statement.
The White House has said the program is intended to primarily help immigrants brought to the U.S. as children and those with children who are U.S. citizens.
It wasn't immediately clear if the government would appeal, either to the full appeals court in New Orleans or to the U.S. Supreme Court.
The states suing to block the plan, led by Texas, argue that Obama acted outside his authority and that the changes would force them to invest more in law enforcement, health care and education.
The White House has repeated its position that the president has exclusive authority to enforce immigration laws and can adjust policies to fix a "broken immigration system." Fourteen states have sided with Obama in the case, and say the benefits of immigration outweigh the costs.
Justice Department lawyers sought a stay while they appealed the injunction. They argued that keeping the temporary hold interfered with the Homeland Security Department's ability to protect the U.S. and secure the nation's borders.
They also said immigration policy is a domain of the federal government, not the states.
But, in Tuesday's ruling, 5th Circuit judges Jerry Smith and Jennifer Walker Elrod denied the stay, saying in an opinion written by Smith that the federal government lawyers are unlikely to succeed on the merits of that appeal. Judge Stephen Higginson dissented.
"The president's attempt to do this by himself, without a law passed by Congress and without any input from the states, is a remarkable violation of the U.S. Constitution and laws," Paxton said.
Obama announced the executive action in November, saying lack of action by Congress forced him to make sweeping changes to immigration rules on his own. Republicans said Obama overstepped his presidential authority.
The first of Obama's orders -- to expand a program that protects young immigrants from deportation if they were brought to the U.S. illegally as children -- was set to take effect Feb. 18. The other major part, extending deportation protections to parents of U.S. citizens and permanent residents who have been in the country for some years, had been scheduled to begin May 19.
Hanen issued his injunction believing that neither action had taken effect. But the Justice Department later told Hanen that more than 108,000 people had already received three-year reprieves from deportation as well as work permits. Hanen said the federal government had been "misleading," but he declined to sanction the government's attorneys.
The Justice Department has also asked the 5th Circuit to reverse Hanen's overall ruling that sided with the states. A decision on that appeal, which will be argued before the court in July, could take months.
Along with Texas, the states seeking to block Obama's action are Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Louisiana, Maine, Michigan, Mississippi, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia and Wisconsin.
Fox News' Shannon Bream and The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:28:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Diary's Pages May Help Jurors Decide if Theater Gunman Was Methodical or Mad - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEJ2-xtCfVezN5tgFyXLmj3etKadw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778855377271&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/27/us/diarys-pages-may-help-jurors-decide-if-james-holmes-theater-gunman-was-methodical-or-mad.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:42:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jeb Bush Re-Writes the History of the Iraq War - Huffington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFQ4MFKHz1yjCW-8KoyIyrEJgan1g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778852830766&amp;ei=sRRlVYiyJoXAaqvEgZAD&amp;url=http://www.huffingtonpost.com/joseph-a-palermo/jeb-bush-iraq-war_b_7445472.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Nothing illustrates better the moral and intellectual bankruptcy of the Republican war hawks who call themselves presidential candidates than their attempts to whitewash the history of how this nation went to war in Iraq.
John Ellis "Jeb" Bush stood by his brother's side while he demolished a nation of 28 million people in the heart of the Arab world he knew nothing about.  Out on the stump, Jeb and other GOP candidates try to shift responsibility for the worst U.S. foreign policy disaster since the Vietnam War from George W. to President Barack Obama.
Jeb and Co. claim that everything was fine in Iraq until Obama failed to keep George W.'s ill-conceived war of aggression running on full throttle.  They pretend the 2007  "surge" in Iraq of about 10,000 American soldiers had all but "won" the war and the rise of ISIL/ISIS is Obama's fault.  They skip over the pesky fact that it was George W. who negotiated the U.S. troop withdrawal with the Nouri al Maliki regime.  (Bush announced the deal at a memorable press conference with Maliki when an Iraqi journalist hurled his shoes at the Leader of the Free World.)
Jeb and Co. also love pointing out that Hillary Rodham Clinton and other big name Democrats voted in favor of the congressional resolution granting W. carte blanche to go to war.  But they leave out the fact that just about everybody on the left in America had denounced the war before it began, and that 133 Democrats in the House and 23 Democrats in the Senate voted against Bush's war.
They also airbrush out of the historical record that one of their conservative heroes, Pope John Paul II (the Polish Pope who stood up to the Communists) emphatically opposed Bush's war, as did the Arab League, the Islamic Conference, the U.S.'s Sunni allies in the region (Egypt, Jordan, Saudi Arabia), the Organization of African Unity, Germany, France, Russia, China, the United Nations, and 15 million people who marched worldwide on February 15, 2003.
They omit these facts because they don't support the idea that "everybody got it wrong."
Although it has been dropped down a memory hole, the Downing Street Memo of July 23, 2002 pretty much confirms that the Bush administration deliberately lied the nation into war.  The top secret minutes of a summer meeting of the highest-ranking intelligence officials in British Prime Minister Tony Blair's government shows that George W. had already decided to go to war using whatever garbage about Iraqi "weapons of mass destruction" his administration could manufacture. One paragraph stands out:
"C reported on his recent talks in Washington.  There was a perceptible shift in attitude. Military action was now seen as inevitable.  Bush wanted to remove Saddam, through military action, justified by the conjunction of terrorism and WMD. But the intelligence and facts were being fixed around the policy. The NSC had no patience with the UN route, and no enthusiasm for publishing material on the Iraqi regime's record. There was little discussion in Washington of the aftermath after military action." [Italics added]
The sentence -- "there was little discussion in Washington of the aftermath after military action" -- has turned out to be one of the biggest understatements in the history of American military interventions.
Then there was the Valerie Plame/Joseph Wilson scandal whereby Karl Rove and Dick Cheney decided to out Ambassador Wilson's wife as a secret CIA operative working on international nuclear issues.
This cynical ploy was retribution for Wilson's op-ed in the New York Times, "What I Didn't Find in Africa," that exposed the Bush administration's lies about the Iraqi government seeking "yellow cake" uranium from Niger.
The exotic sounding "yellow cake" line was the scariest part of President Bush's doom-laden State of the Union Address of January 2003, which he later blamed on "bad intelligence."
Then there was the aluminum tubes fiasco whereby the Bush administration, with an assist from the ever-eager Judith Miller of the New York Times, hyped a shipment of tubes going to Iraq as only suitable for nuclear applications.
It took United Nations weapons experts about 30 seconds to determine that the tubes were not machine tooled for any nuclear program but were for some kind of mortar or simpler use (the tubes were nowhere near the calibrations needed in nuclear research).
Yet the Bush people pumped up the volume on the aluminum tube story.  President Bush conjured up terrifying images of "mushroom clouds" and Saddam's "nuclear mujahideen."
And that might be the worst aspect of the whole sordid story: A U.S. president cynically exploited the American people's genuine fear and trepidation of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks in New York City and Washington to launch an illegal and ill-conceived war of aggression.
In a speech in Cincinnati Ohio on October 7, 2002, while aggressively campaigning for Republican Congressional candidates as the Commander-in-Chief, Bush elaborated on the Iraqi "nuclear threat":
"The evidence indicates that Iraq is reconstituting its nuclear weapons program.  Saddam Hussein has held numerous meetings with Iraqi nuclear scientists, a group he calls his 'nuclear mujahedeen' -- his nuclear holy warriors.  Satellite photographs reveal that Iraq is rebuilding facilities at sites that have been part of its nuclear program in the past.  Iraq has attempted to purchase high-strength aluminum tubes and other equipment needed for gas centrifuges, which are used to enrich uranium for nuclear weapons."
When the fantastic "aluminum tube" story was juxtaposed with the false report of "yellow cake" from Niger, it enabled Condi Rice , Bush and other like-minded souls to scare the hell out of the American people (and the Congress) with the vivid image of "a smoking gun that could come in the form of a mushroom cloud."
In reality, over 20 years earlier, the Israelis had eliminated any potential Iraqi nuclear threat when they blew to bits the French built Osirak nuclear reactor , the only one Iraq ever had.  And during the 1991 Gulf War, the United States finished the job when it pulverized Iraq's infrastructure.
Throughout the 1990s, the United States and Great Britain imposed no-fly zones on the northern and southern parts of Iraq where bombing Iraq became "routine," along with crippling economic sanctions that killed an estimated half million Iraqi children. Secretary of State Madeliene Albright famously said that the loss of innocent life due to the harsh sanctions imposed on Iraq was "worth it."
President Bush even went so far as to tell the world that the Iraqis might position "floating platforms" off the coast of the United States where they could station Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) capable of spraying chemical or biological agents on U.S. cities on the East Coast.  This preposterous claim was in response to the questions that arose after Secretary of State Colin Powell's February 5, 2003 U.N. presentation (which he has since renounced) where he made a big deal out of UAVs in Iraq that might emit chemical or biological agents.
The only problem was that the range for these fearsome UAVs was not even close to being a "threat" to the United States.  Foreign journalists asked Bush: How can these Iraqi UAVs attack the United States when their range was measured in hundreds of kilometers?  You can see Bush's "floating platform" answer in the superb documentary Leading to Wa r (2008).
Somehow, like something out of a Rambo movie, those cunning Iraqis were going to figure out a way to evade the U.S. Navy and Coast Guard and then outmaneuver the Air Force and U.S. air defenses to deploy UAVs to spray Americans with chemical and biological agents as they walked to Starbucks in Manhattan.
Remember, the Bush people, including White House Press Secretary Ari Fleischer (who became a commentator for corporate media), Deputy Defense Secretary Paul Wolfowitz (now a Jeb Bush adviser), and Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld, were not saying they believed there "was a chance" there "might be" WMDs in Iraq.  They were spoon-feeding the public exact figures: numbers of barrels of chemical agent, numbers of potential chemical and biological warheads, numbers of caches of prohibited weapons.
Dick Cheney told the Veterans of Foreign Wars in August 2002, "There is no doubt" that Iraq possessed weapons of mass destruction.  This assertion led the U.N.'s top weapons inspector, Hans Blix, to ask publicly how they could have 100 percent certainty that the WMDs exist, yet zero percent knowledge of where the weapons were located?
In the fall of 2002, Judith Miller's stenographic reportage for the New York Times gave plausibility to the bogus claim that the location of Iraq's WMD stockpile could be discovered using anonymous sources connected to the Bush administration (including the Iranian spy Ahmed Chalabi and the self-promoting flim-flam artist Ibn al Sheikh al-Libi who had the suitable nickname: "curve ball" ).  A self-perpetuating media loop was created whereby Dick Cheney on the Sunday talk shows cited the New York Times after Miller anonymously published bullshit from Cheney's own bogus sources.
The Big Lie that effortlessly leaves the lips of all the 2016 Republican presidential candidates is that the war was the result of an "intelligence failure."  But if George W. felt burned by bad intelligence that cost the country so dearly, why would he give CIA Director George "slam dunk" Tenet the Medal of Freedom?
The fact that Jeb Bush or Marco Rubio can say with a straight face that W. and Cheney and Rummy and Condi were innocent dupes of an "intelligence failure," and that the corporate media will blandly repeat these lies , points to a deeper failure in our political discourse.
Unfortunately, the Obama administration and the Democratic Congress that came to power in 2009 failed to give the country any in-depth investigation into all aspects of the Iraq War.  In the U.K., although it might not have amounted to much, at least Tony Blair and Foreign Minister Jack Snow were forced to squirm a little bit in front of a committee investigating their role in lying the British people into war; they had to testify before some independent body at least.  On this side of the pond nothing happened but P.R. and spin and amnesia that is setting us up for the next disaster.
In 2002, the arch-terrorist leader of Al Qaeda in Iraq, Abu Musab al-Zarqawi, was an unknown Jordanian jihadist wannabe who came on the scene too late to see any real action in Afghanistan.  Few militants in Iraq or anywhere else ever heard of Zarqawi until Secretary of State Colin Powell built him up into a big shot during his February 5, 2003 indictment of the Iraqi government at the U.N.
As the Italian terrorism expert, Loretta Napoleoni, reported in her 2005 book, Insurgent Iraq: Al Zarqawi and the New Generation, by mentioning Zarqawi by name as a "threat" in his most important address to the world Secretary Powell bestowed upon him a street credibility among jihadists he never had before.  President Bush's famous "Bring 'em on!" line was in response to those who claimed the U.S. military had become bogged down in Iraq and the war had turned the country into a magnet for jihadists to fight the Americans.
The 2016 Republican presidential candidates never tire of telling us how terrible Saddam Hussein was.  Yes, Saddam was a despot but at least his regime was secular and had arisen from the organic ethnic and sectarian politics of Iraq.  There was no sectarian war going on in Iraq until the U.S. invasion and occupation created the social, economic, and political conditions for it.
Lest we forget, in the 1980s, the U.S. allied itself with the Sunni Baathists in Iraq in their war against Iran.  And some of America's closest allies in the region, such as the theocracy in Saudi Arabia, Egypt under Mubarak, and Bahrain (where the U.S. Navy has the Fifth Fleet), all have abysmal human rights records.
There was no Al Qaeda in Iraq until the U.S. invaded and sparked an insurgency.  The rise of ISIL/ISIS was a direct consequence of the U.S. toppling the government and disfranchising the traditional Sunni technocratic class.  The Sunnis in Anbar Province and elsewhere in Iraq will never accept Shia rule in Baghdad .  And the Shia majority in Iraq and the Iranians are equally determined never to lose power.
This broiling civil and sectarian conflict has the potential to go on for decades and unleash a wider war. At this sad juncture, it looks like Iraq's disfranchised Sunnis (in a tactical alliance with ISIL/ISIS) will continue to carve out territory until they can shoot their way back into power.  (If that day ever comes.)  The most likely scenario in Iraq going forward is a multi-sided civil and sectarian war similar to those in Syria, Libya, and Yemen, which is unlikely to be extinguished before it unleashes an even bigger conflagration.
In 2016, given the ongoing U.S.-created catastrophe in Iraq, it's unbelievable that anyone named "Bush" could be seen as a viable presidential contender.  While people in Iraq suffer as a result of misguided and criminal U.S. policies, the American people, facing a $5 billion election in 2016, are hearing presidential candidates put forth the most pathetic apologetics, spin, and lies as they try to whitewash the whole thing.
For 70 years, historians have tried to figure out how World War II-era leaders, diplomats, business and foreign policy elites could allow that kind of carnage to be unleashed upon the world.  Today we might be closer to answering that question.
Follow Joseph A. Palermo on Twitter: www.twitter.com/JosephPalermo1
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
