<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:33:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill Cosby admitted to drugging women to have sex, rape accusers say they are ... - Fox News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEljfWXYx5eV5eTSev-TXG99g1zgA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896712105&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2015/07/07/bill-cosby-admitted-to-drugging-women-to-have-sex-rape-accusers-say-are/</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attacker Storms Factory Near Lyon, France, Beheading One - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFr54And1aifiIN0pt0OiQqgRnBvQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888740792&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/27/world/europe/french-factory-lyon-attack-isis.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:13:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: '19 killed' in Sousse hotel - BBC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFu9fAeGKKmvf2WXET9sKtCIArI6g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888824887&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33287978</Link>
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498 - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFFTYPT95IDiBi0_cMLC8p5VW8i_Q&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888991832&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/06/28/us-taiwan-fire-idUSKBN0P70TC20150628</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Bill Cosby admitted to drugging women to have sex, rape accusers say they are vindicated
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
Several women who accused Bill Cosby of drugging and raping them are saying newly unsealed testimony by the comedian in a 2005 case corroborates their claims.
Cosby admitted to acquiring quaaludes with the intent of giving them to women he wanted to have sex with, and giving the drug to several women, in testimony for a sexual-abuse case filed by former Temple University employee Andrea Constand.
In documents obtained by The Associated Press, Cosby said he obtained seven quaalude prescriptions in the 1970s. Constand's lawyer asked if he had kept the sedatives through the 1990s, after they were banned, but was frustrated by objections from Cosby's attorney.
"When you got the quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" Troiani asked.
"Yes," Cosby answered.
"Did you ever give any of these young women the quaaludes without their knowledge?" Troiani asked.
More on this...
Cosby jokes about allegations
Cosby's lawyer again objected, leading Troiani to petition the federal judge to force Cosby to cooperate.
Cosby's lawyers insisted that two of the accusers knew they were taking quaaludes from the comedian, according to the unsealed documents.
Click here to subscribe to FOX411s YouTube channel
Attorneys for some of the women now suing Cosby seized on the testimony as powerful evidence that what they have been saying all along is true: the comedian drugged and raped women.
Celebrity attorney Gloria Allred, who is representing several women, said she hopes to use the admission in court cases against the comedian.
"This confirms the allegations of numerous victims who have said that he has used drugs in order to sexually assault them," Allred told FOX411. "This admission is one that Mr. Cosby has attempted to hide from the public for many years and we are very gratified that it is now being made public." 
Meanwhile, a lawyer for one woman, who says Bill Cosby drugged and assaulted her when she was 19, says the unsealing of portions of his 2005 testimony is a "significant and positive step." Therese Serignese went public with the allegations last November. She says Cosby assaulted her after a show in Las Vegas around 1976.
Lisa Bloom, attorney for model Janice Dickinson, who says she was drugged and raped, said: "If today's report is true, Mr. Cosby admitted under oath 10 years ago sedating women for sexual purposes. Given that, how dare he publicly vilify Ms. Dickinson and accuse her of lying when she tells a very similar story?"
Three women in Massachusetts are suing Cosby for defamation. The women say his representatives branded them liars when the representatives denied accusations that Cosby had drugged and sexually assaulted them.
Lawyer Joe Cammarata represents one of the Massachusetts accusers. He says the use of drugs during sex has been a "recurring theme of the women's allegations." He says the documents unsealed appear to support their claims.
Cosby, 77, has been accused by more than two dozen women of sexual misconduct in episodes dating back more than four decades. Cosby has never been charged with a crime, and the statute of limitations on most of the accusations has expired.
The AP had gone to court to compel the release of the 2004 deposition. Cosby's lawyers had objected to the release of the material, arguing it would embarrass him. Ultimately, a judge unsealed just a small portion of the deposition.
"The stark contrast between Bill Cosby, the public moralist and Bill Cosby, the subject of serious allegations concerning improper (and perhaps criminal) conduct is a matter as to which the AP -- and by extension the public -- has a significant interest," U.S. District Judge Eduardo Robreno wrote.
Cosby, with his oft-espoused views on topics including childrearing, family life, education and crime "has voluntarily narrowed the zone of privacy that he is entitled to claim," the judge wrote.
Cosby, who starred as Dr. Cliff Huxtable on "The Cosby Show" from 1984 to 1992, settled Constand's lawsuit under confidential terms in 2006. His lawyers in the Philadelphia case did not immediately return telephone calls seeking comment on Monday. Constand consented to be identified but did not want to comment, her lawyer said.
"This evidence shows a pattern in which defendant 'mentored' naive young women and introduced drugs into the relationship, with and without the woman's knowledge, in order for him to achieve sexual satisfaction," Constand's lawyer, Dolores M. Troiani, argued in court papers.
Cosby later said he gave Constand three half-pills of Benadryl, although Troiani in the documents voices doubt that was the drug involved.
Cosby had fought the AP's efforts to unseal the testimony, with his lawyer arguing that the deposition could reveal details of Cosby's marriage, sex life and prescription drug use.
It would be terribly embarrassing for this material to come out," lawyer George M. Gowen III argued in June.
He also said the material would "prejudice him in eyes of the jury pool in Massachusetts," where Cosby is fighting defamation lawsuits brought by women who say his representatives smeared them by accusing them of lying.
Robreno asked last month why Cosby was fighting the release of his sworn testimony, given that the accusations in the Constand lawsuit were already public.
"Why would he be embarrassed by his own version of the facts?" the judge said.
Cosby resigned in December from the board of trustees at Temple University, where he was the popular face of the Philadelphia school in advertisements, fundraising campaigns and commencement speeches.
Lawyer Gayle Sproul, representing the AP, in court last month called the married Cosby "an icon" who "held himself out as someone who would guide the public in ways of morality."
Troiani, summarizing her evidence, painted a starkly different picture.
Cosby "has evidenced a predilection for sexual contact with women who are unconscious or drugged. His victims are young, 'star struck' and totally trusting of his public persona," Troiani argued.
Cosby's lawyers have not returned messages seeking comment.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:02:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras To Present New Proposals At Emergency ... - Huffington Post</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFFr6zd0T7zX7sX6GMTbsVM-FZ71Q&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778894022955&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/07/07/greece-debt-crisis_n_7742026.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras To Present New Proposals At Emergency Euro Zone Summit
Reuters | By                                                                      Paul Taylor and Costas Pitas
Posted:
reddit
BRUSSELS, July 7 (Reuters) - Greek Prime Minister Alexis  Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals  to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade  skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's  banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and  the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding,  Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom  are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorize  negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals  would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last  week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity  terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two  main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was  still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic  turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut  Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with  convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises,  spending cuts and pension and labor reforms that were on the  table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under  suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute  deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the  European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude  Greece from the euro zone."
He did not name names but may have been referring to German  Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of  his skepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and  last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically  acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and  other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which  the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece  nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more  than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrivial for a preparatory meeting of  finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew  debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule  out other forms of restructuring.
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate  bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian Finance Minister  Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time  left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for  Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint  media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. (1600  GMT) in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a  nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro  zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print  its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the  first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent  and fueling doubts about the long-term viability of an  incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the  integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with  each episode of political uncertainty within member countries,"  said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to  Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two  people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
Members of Communist Party affiliated trade union PAME march against austerity in Thessaloniki on July 7, 2015. (SAKIS MITROLIDIS/AFP/Getty Images)
CONCESSIONS UNCLEAR
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 percent 'No' vote in  Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented  support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced  his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the  soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting  without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it  was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are  closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek  government has an interest in coming up with serious and  credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke  to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as  well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S.  Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution  in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would  make to try to convince deeply skeptical European leaders to  lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and  fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse,  Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions  from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 percent discount on value added  tax on Greek islands and delay defense spending from cuts, which  rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have  called "red lines." It is also resisting raising VAT on  restaurants to 23 percent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase  out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to  get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their  aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU  of behaving like "terrorists," as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the  European Union is not something we want or indeed should want,"  the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested  the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding  while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it  over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the  Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a  solution before catastrophe," while the center-right Eleftheros  Typos said: "Tsipras' games finish at today's council: Time of  crisis: deal or Grexit."
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favor a hard line  at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that  Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the  austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would  implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for  Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral  they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was  largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was  prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain  limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two  days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.     (Additional reporting by Costas Pitas, Angeliki Koutantou and  George Georgiopoulos in Athens, Julia Fioretti and Alastair  Macdonald in Brussels, Paul Carrel in Berlin John O'Donnell in  Frankfurt and Mark John in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor;  editing by John Stonestreet and Giles Elgood)
Pensioners wait in front of the gate of the National Bank of Greece in Athens July 7, 2015. (ANGELOS TZORTZINIS/AFP/Getty Images)
Related on HuffPost:


A supporter of the No vote reacts after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag in front of the parliament after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, left, speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
A vendor sells Greek flags walks at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Three opinion polls carried out during Greece's bailout referendum, which could affect the country's future in the eurozone, indicate the "no" vote will win. Tsipras called Sunday's referendum last weekend, urging voters to reject creditor reform proposals. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Petr David Josek)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag as celebrates after the results of the referendum in Synatagma square in central Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras casts his vote at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, speaks to the media after voting at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Spyros Tsakiris)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag after the referendum's exit polls at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A woman waits to cross a street in front of an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A woman walks past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015. Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties.(AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A cleaner walks past display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A television journalist works in front of display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A display board at the Australian Stock Exchange flashes red indicating the losses of several names in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran talks deadline extended, again -- this time to July 10 - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEJOpib5EnQ1y2yeN2O7ACDWkboAg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896133592&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/07/07/politics/iran-nuclear-talks-deadline-extended/</Link>
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:02:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank Limits Aid to Greek Banks Amid Debt Crisis - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGDJggksB8zhQhc98QJfLgFtnGIMg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778890235863&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/29/business/greeces-financial-lifeline-is-now-up-to-european-central-bank.html</Link>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack on Sousse beach 'kills 27'
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
Tunisian TV ran footage from one hotel close to the attack
At least 27 people have been killed, including foreigners, in an attack on a beach near two tourist hotels in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse, according to the interior ministry.
Officials say one gunman has been shot dead and another is being pursued.
Sousse is a popular tourist destination.
Tunisia has been on high alert since March when militants killed 22 people, mainly foreign tourists, in an attack on a museum in the capital Tunis.
The interior ministry told the BBC "a terrorist attack" was ongoing.
Tunisia attacks: Live updates
A British man on holiday told the BBC that he heard the attack on a neighbouring hotel and saw a man with a pistol from his room, but did not know whether this was an attacker or a member of the security forces.
The holidaymaker said he and other guests had been told to take shelter in the hotel's staff quarters and have been told to wait for the all-clear.
One image circulating on social media appeared to show a man lying face down in the sand with what looks like blood around his head.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:15:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State Claims Responsibility for Kuwait Mosque Blast - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNE0Dlw0a0LxRLXk8yBEdWfnikFSqw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888791661&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/articles/deadly-blast-hits-kuwait-mosque-1435319403</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Islamic State Claims Responsibility for Kuwait Mosque Blast
Attack marks Sunni extremist groups first assault on the country
By
Maria Abi Habib
Updated June 26, 2015 8:07 a.m. ET
DUBAIIslamic State took responsibility for a deadly explosion on Friday at a Shiite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, a rare attack in the tiny Gulf nation.
The Sunni extremist group claimed the attack via a statement posted to a known Twitter account. It named the bomber as Abu Sleiman al Mouahed and said that he was wearing a suicide belt.
...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Draft | Today in Politics: GOP Finds Much to Add to Justices' Final Say on ... - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGTDff1kHQHsah1WqcXy1XQONsIYw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778885692391&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/06/26/today-in-politics-g-o-p-finds-much-to-add-to-justices-final-say-on-health-care-law/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:30:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Religious Groups Brace For Supreme Court's Same-Sex Marriage Ruling - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJ4u0paSlRzemLCjmLg1bP6jSbVA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778886195348&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/articles/religious-groups-brace-for-supreme-courts-same-sex-marriage-ruling-1435291179</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>tammy.audi@wsj.com
Updated June 26, 2015 6:54 a.m. ET
As the U.S. Supreme Court prepares to issue a potentially far-reaching ruling that effectively could legalize same-sex marriage nationwide, religious groups opposed to gay marriage are bracing for the potential impactdeveloping new legal strategies to carve out religious exemptions, and ramping up fundraising to pay for them.
People are scared the freedoms theyve always taken for granted are now at risk and theyre fearing discrimination by their government for simply trying to live according to their beliefs, said...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine Killed in Alaska Plane Crash - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG3AJyIv8Se3V0XRPRQ4Ehaxl9HUg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888403779&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/news/articles/SB11871130314313103897904581071500184640590</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nine Killed in Alaska Plane Crash
Eight passengers on a sightseeing excursion from a Holland America Line cruise and the pilot were killed
Associated Press
June 26, 2015 7:00 a.m. ET
ANCHORAGE, AlaskaNine people died when a sightseeing plane crashed in southeastern Alaska, but stormy weather prevented the immediate recovery of their bodies.
Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of the eight cruise ship passengers and pilot who were killed when the plane crashed in a remote and rugged area.
...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama set to eulogize pastor in Charleston shooting - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH7lQO4cSrLw8VXFElea3wtvPrvsw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888653336&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/06/26/politics/obama-charleston-eulogy-pastor/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CNN.com
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Obama set to eulogize pastor in Charleston shooting
By Kevin Liptak , CNN White House Producer
Updated 1326 GMT (2026 HKT) June 26, 2015
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
President Barack Obama attends the 2014 Nuclear Security Summit in March 2014 in the Hague, Netherlands. As his presidency winds down, here's a look at some key moments of his administration.
Hide Caption
1 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Michelle Obama brushes specks  from the coat of then-Sen. Obama inside the Old State Capitol in Springfield, Illinois, just before he announced his candidacy for president of the United States in February 2007. Their daughters Malia, left, and Sasha wait in the foreground.
Hide Caption
2 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama appears on "Meet the Press" with Tim Russert, right, in Des Moines, Iowa, in November 2007.
Hide Caption
3 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama shakes hands with supporters after addressing a rally in Concord, New Hampshire, in January 2008.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama gives a speech at the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia in March 2008.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama speaks at the 2008 Democratic National Convention in Denver, Colorado.
Hide Caption
6 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama stands on stage  in Chicago, Illinois, with his family after defeating Republican presidential candidate John McCain on November 4, 2008.
Hide Caption
7 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Left to right: Presidents George H. W. Bush, Obama, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton, and Jimmy Carter pose for photos in the Oval Office in January 2009.
Hide Caption
8 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama is sworn in by Chief Justice John Roberts as the 44th President of the United States on the West Front of the Capitol in Washington on January 20, 2009.
Hide Caption
9 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
As retired military officers stand behind him, Obama signs an executive order to close down the detention center at Guantanamo Bay in January 2009.
Hide Caption
10 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and Vice President Joe Biden look at solar panels as they tour the solar array at the Denver Museum of Nature and Science on February 17, 2009. That same day, Obama signed the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act.
Hide Caption
11 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
A soldier hugs Obama during his surprise visit to Camp Victory just outside Baghdad, Iraq, in April 2009.
Hide Caption
12 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama bends over so the son of a White House staff member can pat his head during a visit to the Oval Office in May 2009. The boy wanted to know if Obama's hair felt like his.
Hide Caption
13 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama kisses Sonia Sotomayor's cheek after announcing her as his nominee for justice on the Supreme Court in May 2009.
Hide Caption
14 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Palestinian security forces in Jenin, West Bank, listen to Obama speak from Cairo University in Egypt in June 2009. The Palestinian Authority hailed as a "good beginning" Obama's speech to the Muslim world in which he reiterated his support for a Palestinian state.
Hide Caption
15 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and first lady Michelle Obama meet with Pope Benedict XVI in Vatican City in July 2009.
Hide Caption
16 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama hosts the Apollo 11 astronauts, from left to right, Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin, Michael Collins and Neil Armstrong in the Oval Office on July 20, 2009, the 40th anniversary of the moon landing.
Hide Caption
17 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Police Sgt. James Crowley, second right, of Cambridge, Massachusetts, speaks with Harvard Professor Henry Louis Gates Jr., second left, alongside Obama and Biden as they share beers on the South Lawn of the White House in July 2009. In an effort to curb controversy, the so-called "Beer Summit," was held after Crowley arrested Gates at his own home which sparked tensions and racial furor.
Hide Caption
18 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama salutes during the transfer of Sgt. Dale R. Griffin at Dover Air Force Base in Dover, Delaware, in October 2009. Obama traveled to the base to meet the plane carrying the bodies of 18 U.S. personnel killed in Afghanistan on October 26, including Griffin.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama walks along the Great Wall of China in November 2009.
Hide Caption
20 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama delivers a speech after receiving the Nobel Peace Prize in Oslo, Norway, in December 2009.
Hide Caption
21 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Presidents Obama, Clinton, and Bush walk to the Rose Garden to speak about relief efforts for earthquake-stricken Haiti in January 2010.
Hide Caption
22 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
First daughters Sasha and Malia Obama play in the snow with their father in the Rose Garden during a snowstorm that hit Washington in February 2010.
Hide Caption
23 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama's signature on the Affordable Healthcare Act is seen at the White House in March 2010.
Hide Caption
24 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama throws out the opening pitch before a baseball game between the Philadelphia Phillies and the Washington Nationals on Opening Day at Nationals Park in Washington in April 2010.
Hide Caption
25 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and daughter, Sasha, swim at Alligator Point in Panama City Beach, Florida, in August 2010, in an effort to encourage people to come back to the Gulf Coast after the devastating oil spill.
Hide Caption
26 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama laughs as he makes a statement on his birth certificate in April 2011. Obama said he was amused over conspiracy theories about his birthplace, and said the media's obsession with the "sideshow" issue was a distraction in a "serious time."
Hide Caption
27 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama, Biden, Secretary of State Hillary Clinton and members of the national security team receive live updates in the Situation Room of the White House on the mission to capture or kill Osama bin Laden on May 1, 2011.
Hide Caption
28 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
U.S. Marines of Regiment Combat Team 1 watch from Camp Dwyer in Afghanistan as Obama announces the death of Osama bin Laden on May 2, 2011.
Hide Caption
29 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama enjoys a pint of Guinness in his ancestral home of Moneygall, Ireland, in May 2011.
Hide Caption
30 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama, left, and first lady Michelle Obama, right, meet with Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, at Buckingham Palace in London in May 2011.
Hide Caption
31 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and Missouri Gov. Jay Nixon walk together in May 2011 during a tour of the devastation of Joplin, Missouri, after it was hit by tornado with winds over 200 mph.
Hide Caption
32 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama delivers remarks to troops and military families at Fort Bragg, North Carolina, on December 14, 2011, marking the exit of U.S. soldiers from Iraq.
Hide Caption
33 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama pays for a dog toy as he shops with his dog Bo at a Petsmart in Alexandria, Virginia, in December 2011.
Hide Caption
34 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama sits on the famed Rosa Parks bus at the Henry Ford Museum in Dearborn, Michigan, in April 2012.
Hide Caption
35 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
British Prime Minister David Cameron, Obama, German Chancellor Angela Merkel, and others watch the overtime shootout of the Champions League final soccer match between Chelsea and Bayern Munich in the Laurel Cabin conference room at Camp David, Maryland, during a G8 Summit in May 2012.
Hide Caption
36 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama sits in his chair during a Cabinet meeting in the Cabinet Room in July 2012. This image was tweeted by his official Twitter account in August 2012 in response to Clint Eastwood's "empty chair" speech at the Republican National Convention. The tweet simply said, "This seat's taken."
Hide Caption
37 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama casts a shadow in this picture as he accepts the 2012 Democratic nomination for president during the final day of the Democratic National Convention in Charlotte, North Carolina, in September 2012.
Hide Caption
38 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Republican presidential candidate Mitt Romney and Obama participate in the first presidential debate of the 2012 election in Denver, Colorado, in October 2012.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama celebrates on stage in Chicago after defeating Romney on Election Day November 6, 2012.
Hide Caption
40 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama pauses during his speech at a memorial service in Newtown, Connecticut, for the victims and relatives of the Sandy Hook Elementary School massacre in December 2012.
Hide Caption
41 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Hundreds of thousands gather at the U.S. Capitol building as Obama is inaugurated for his second term on January 21, 2013.
Hide Caption
42 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Israeli President Shimon Peres, left, and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, right, stand with Obama during an arrival ceremony for Obama at Ben Gurion International Airport in Tel Aviv, Israel, in March 2013.
Hide Caption
43 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama adjusts an umbrella held by a Marine during a news conference with Turkish Prime Minister Recep Tayyip Erdogan in the Rose Garden of the White House in May 2013.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Jay Leno interviews Obama on "The Tonight Show" in August 2013.
Hide Caption
45 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
White House press secretary Jay Carney fields questions from reporters during a daily press briefing at the White House in September 2013 after Obama's push for Congressional approval for limited military strikes against the Syrian government.
Hide Caption
46 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Actor and comedian Zach Galifianakis interviews Obama during his appearance on "Between Two Ferns," a digital video series with a laser focus on reaching people aged 18 to 34. The President urged young people to sign up for the new health care plan in the video posted on the website Funny or Die.
Hide Caption
47 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama walks to the Oval Office on August 7, 2014, the same day he announced the beginning of air strikes on ISIS.
Hide Caption
48 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama speaks to the nation from the Cabinet Room of the White House about normalizing diplomatic relations with Cuba in December 2014.
Hide Caption
49 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Left to right: House Majority Leader Rep. Kevin McCarthy, House Minority Leader Rep. Nancy Pelosi, and Speaker of the House Rep. John Boehner listen as Obama speaks during a meeting in the Cabinet Room of the White House on January 13, 2015.
Hide Caption
50 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
President Barack Obama takes a selfie with podcast host Mark Maron after being a guest on his show "WTF with Marc Maron" in Los Angeles on June 22, 2015.
Hide Caption
51 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama responds to a heckler who interrupted his speech during a reception in honor of LGBT Pride Month in the East Room of the White House in Washington, D.C., June 24, 2015.
Hide Caption
52 of 52
Washington (CNN)
Friday's funeral service for Rev. Clementa Pinckney won't be the first time President Barack Obama delivers a high-profile eulogy; with a year-and-a-half remaining in office, it may not be the last.
But when the President stands in historic downtown Charleston to remember the slain pastor and eight others shot down in their church last week, his speech will move beyond just grief for the victims -- Obama will step directly into a national conversation about race in which he plays a central role.
The President, first lady Michelle Obama, Vice President Joe Biden, a bipartisan host of high-level members of Congress and Hillary Clinton were all headed to TD Arena on Friday for the memorial service more than a week after a 21-year-old man opened fire at a Bible study inside Charleston's Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church.
The shooter declared he was there to "kill black people," and an online manifesto attributed to him contained white supremacist screeds.
JUST WATCHED
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:23:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French government files legal complaint against UberPOP - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH3VUETN4XOuoW1B_-pKFtRdglhSg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778887823225&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/06/26/france-uber-idUSL8N0ZC0SD20150626</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>French government files legal complaint against UberPOP
PARIS, June 26
PARIS, June 26 French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said on Friday he had launched legal action targeting local managers of U.S.-based ride-sharing service Uber, denouncing the attitude of the company as "cynical" and "arrogant".
France already ordered a nationwide clampdown on its UberPOP mobile app-based service on Thursday, siding with taxi drivers who blockaded major transport hubs in protests against the service.
Faced with the threat of renewed disruption, even President Francois Hollande weighed in, calling from the sidelines of a late-night European Union summit in Brussels for the dissolution of UberPOP's activities in France.
"We are in a state of law and the law will rule," Cazeneuve told RTL radio.
A law from October 2014 placed a ban on putting clients in touch with unregistered drivers. However Uber contests the rule, saying it is unclear and counter to the freedom to do business. A constitutional ruling is expected around September.
On Thursday Cazeneuve ordered Paris police to issue a decree banning UberPOP and said cars defying the order would be seized. Uber France general manager Thibaud Simphal retorted by saying the measures "changed nothing" and that demand for its services in France would continue.
"The complaint I filed yesterday is wide enough to cover the statements of UberPOP managers," Cazeneuve told RTL, adding that inciting people to defy the ban was "a criminal offence".
An Uber spokesman on Thursday accused the French government of seeking to interfere in the course of justice.
UberPOP links drivers of private cars with potential passengers at cheaper rates than conventional cabs and has already come under political and legal scrutiny in France.   (Reporting by Dominique Vidalon; Editing by Mark John and Alison Williams)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>I-75 reopens after 6 killed in wreck outside Chattanooga - Twin Falls Times-News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGhJWpUm5aoS0h8ZzIa5Ava5bMMlA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888426097&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://magicvalley.com/news/national/i--reopens-after-killed-in-wreck-outside-chattanooga/article_9f73b8d7-9155-5b2f-a0c0-25276b822046.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>I-75 reopens after 6 killed in wreck outside Chattanooga
Saved
2015-06-26T05:40:46Z I-75 reopens after 6 killed in wreck outside ChattanoogaThe Associated Press The Associated Press
1 hour ago
(0) Comments
CHATTANOOGA, Tenn. (AP)  Police in southeastern Tennessee say Interstate 75 has reopened about 12 hours after six people were killed in a nine-vehicle wreck.
Chattanooga Police Department spokesman Kyle Miller says the accident happened around 7:10 p.m. Thursday on I-75 northbound near the suburb of Ooltewah.
He said investigators are still working to determine the cause of the crash.
Police believe more than 15 people were involved; the exact number is still being determined because multiple groups were taken to local hospitals.
The identities of the victims were not immediately released.
Miller said on Friday morning that no further updates were immediately available.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:24:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Missing Clinton Emails Likely to Raise New Questions - ABC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHEmfgLtug3QZc8r7W5QI256WUBMQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778886739320&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/wireStory/missing-clinton-emails-raise-questions-32043015</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Missing Clinton Emails Likely to Raise New Questions
WASHINGTON  Jun 26, 2015, 3:23 AM ET
By BRADLEY KLAPPER and MATTHEW LEE Associated Press
The State Department cannot find in its records all or part of 15 work-related emails from Hillary Rodham Clinton's private server that were released this week by a House panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi, Libya, officials said Thursday.
The emails all predate the Sept. 11 assault on the U.S. diplomatic facility and include scant words written by Clinton herself, the officials said. They consist of more in a series of would-be intelligence reports passed to her by longtime political confidant Sidney Blumenthal, the officials said.
Nevertheless, the fact that the State Department says it can't find them among emails she provided surely will raise new questions about Clinton's use of a personal email account and server while secretary of state and whether she has provided the agency all of her work-related correspondence, as she claims.
Rep. Trey Gowdy, chairman of the Select Committee on Benghazi, released a statement Thursday saying, "This confirms doubts about the completeness of Clinton's self-selected public record and raises serious questions about her decision to erase her personal server  especially before it could be analyzed by an independent, neutral third-party arbiter."
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Page
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heritage or hate: The history of the Confederate Flag - Hindustan Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFYjLRAdR05lyfHOK2Sy5tK3q_2kA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778889459940&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/heritage-or-hate-the-history-of-the-confederate-flag/article1-1363799.aspx</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>World powers, Iran struggling to meet nuclear deadline 01:18
Story highlights
The State Department announced that Iran nuclear talks have extended their deadline to Friday
Secretary of State John Kerry will remain in Vienna, where the latest round of negotiations are taking place.
Washington (CNN)
Negotiators working to broker a deal to rein in Iran's nuclear program on Tuesday extended the talks until the end of the week.
State Department spokeswoman Mari Harf said Tuesday morning in a statement that U.S. officials have "made substantial progress in every area" and will continue negotiating with their Iranian counterparts through Friday. This is the second time negotiators have extended the deadline, which was originally set for June 30.
Secretary of State John Kerry will remain in Vienna, where the latest round of negotiations are taking place.
"This work is highly technical and high stakes for all of the countries involved. We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time -- that is why we are continuing to negotiate," said Harf, who is the State Department's Senior Advisor for Strategic Communications.
RELATED: Netanyahu warns of 'worse and worse' deal with Iran
Officials on both the U.S. and Iranian sides have expressed in recent days that they are negotiating in earnest and making progress, and have downplayed concerns over reaching a specific deadline.
If the Obama administration does not submit a nuclear deal to Congress before Thursday, the amount of time Congress will have to review a deal will double, to 60 days from 30 days. That could set up a long and drawn-out fight to sway public opinion in favor or against the deal, with many Republicans already labeling the deal negotiators are crafting as one that would give Iran a path to a nuclear weapon.
Obama administration officials have insisted though that they will not waver on certain key points that could make or break a deal, most crucial of which is putting in place a rigorous inspections and verification mechanism that would allow international monitors to inspect any and all suspicious facilities throughout Iran.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:03:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK Commemorates 10th Anniversary of 7/7 Bombings in London - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHTp9y8MNEgFFcsjFDuzQ5ZUT7dSw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896821652&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/articles/u-k-commemorates-10th-anniversary-of-7-7-bombings-in-london-1436274166</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>U.K. Commemorates 10th Anniversary of 7/7 Bombings in London
Authorities say the country needs to strengthen its counterterrorism and surveillance capabilities
By
@jgginlondon
July 7, 2015 9:03 a.m. ET
LONDONAs Britain commemorates the 10th anniversary of the nations most deadly domestic terror attack, U.K. authorities say that the country needs to strengthen its counterterrorism and surveillance capabilities to keep pace with a rapidly changing extremist threat.
On Tuesday, British Prime Minister David Cameron joined survivors and families of those who died when four homegrown Islamic suicide bombers attacked Londons public transport during the morning rush hour on July 7, 2005. The bombings killed 52 people and...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Washington ice cave collapse: The dangers of frozen spelunking - Christian Science Monitor</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH55HJSwQUmt1VCfrEmKiFFk46AAg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896697786&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/USA-Update/2015/0707/Washington-ice-cave-collapse-The-dangers-of-frozen-spelunking</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Photos of the Day Photos of the day 07/06
In the past year, several warning signs have been posted to alert hikers to the danger, Tracy O'Toole, a Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest spokeswoman, told the Daily Herald of Everett.
According to the Washington Trail Association, there is always a certain level of danger in ice caves, even when no official warning has been issued.
Regardless of weather, temperature, or snow pack, ice caves in Washington pose a very real threat to anyone venturing in or near them, the WTAs website warns. It is never safe to enter an ice cave, but the caves at Big Four pose a particular danger if you venture beyond the viewing platform at the end of the trail.
Still, the Big Four Ice Caves remain a popular destination for hikers. Several others were present during Mondays collapse, including 18-year-old Chloe Jakubowski, who told the Seattle Times she drove with three friends about 15 miles to a pay phone to call emergency services.
Recommended: Climate change: Is your opinion informed by science? Take our quiz!
"Everybody there, we grabbed everybody out and helped as best we could," she said.
Another Big Four collapse occurred the day before, which a hiker caught on film. Several tourists had been inside the cave when it collapsed, but no injuries were reported.
This report contains material from the Associated Press.
Related Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Confederate Flag Opponents Face Harder Fight in South Carolina House - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNE0W8vW7J9hWs-nY6FURO98WDFvFA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778895711352&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/08/us/confederate-batttle-flag-debate-charleston-shooting.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grizzly bear shatters barrier at Minnesota Zoo - Fox News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHHW3WFvRt8Hf4MXz_7j3tYJDpwYQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896613750&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/07/07/grizzly-bear-shatters-barrier-at-minnesota-zoo/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Grizzly bear shatters barrier at Minnesota Zoo
Published July 07, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
APPLE VALLEY, Minn.  A grizzly bear exhibit at the Minnesota Zoo is temporarily closed after one of the bears picked up a basketball-sized rock and shattered a barrier.
Startled visitors stood on the other side as the bear repeatedly slammed the rock into a pane of glass Monday morning.
Zoo animal collections manager Tony Fisher tells the Minneapolis Star Tribune (http://strib.mn/1JQshzo ) the five-layer pane stayed in place "like a windshield." No one was hurt.
The grizzlies were called back inside. The area will be closed until a temporary fix can be made ahead of a permanent pane being installed.
Fisher isn't sure which of the three bears is responsible for busting one of pane's five layers. But he suspects it was Kenai, a nearly full-grown male who is "usually the clown out there."
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:41:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bush dines with popular Republican counselor: Romney - USA TODAY</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGwe5QSy-pnaqmfdR2KXYq_mr_YtA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896400234&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://onpolitics.usatoday.com/2015/07/07/bush-dines-with-popular-republican-counselor-romney/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>EMAIL
Jeb Bush and Mitt Romney in 2012. (Charles Dharapak, AP)
It seems like Mitt Romney has become the Republican Partys most popular member, at least among the presidential candidates.
Jeb Bush had lunch Monday with Romney, following a holiday weekend in which the 2012 GOP presidential nominee hosted Chris Christie and Marco Rubio at his home in New Hampshire.
The Romney lunch took place at the Bush family compound in Kennebunkport, Maine, and included former president George H.W. Bush and former first lady Barbara Bush.
Jeb Bush and wife, Columba, were grateful for the opportunity to host Governor and Mrs. Romney for lunch, said a statement from the Bush presidential campaign.
Some are casting all these meetings as a Romney primary, although the 2012 nominee  who passed on another race in 2016  has said he doesnt plan to endorse anybody this time around.
Im going to be as loyal to them as they were to me, Romney told reporters last weekend in New Hampshire.
Though many of the candidates frequently call on Romney for counsel, he declined to offer his advice  at least publicly  on how they should conduct their campaigns.
These guys will make their own mistakes, he quipped to reporters. Hopefully they wont follow mine.'
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:45:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Canada posts near-record $C3.34 billion trade deficit in May - Reuters Canada</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGPiQKVBw2Y8esqm6P8HbDxNIJfyA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778896981852&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://ca.reuters.com/article/businessNews/idCAKCN0PH19Z20150707</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Canada posts near-record $C3.34 billion trade deficit in May
Tue Jul 7, 2015 8:38am EDT

[ - ] Text [ + ]
July 7 (Reuters) - Canada posted a larger-than-expected trade deficit of C$3.34 billion ($2.63 billion) in May from a revised C$2.99 billion deficit in April, Statistics Canada said on Tuesday.
The deficit in May was Canada's second-biggest on record and the eighth monthly deficit in a row as exports declined 0.6 percent and imports rose 0.2 percent.
(Reporting by Simon Doyle; Editing by Leah Schnurr)
 Thomson Reuters 2015 All rights reserved.

Thomson Reuters Corporate:  Copyright | Disclaimer | Privacy Policy | Careers

International Editions : Africa | Arabic | Argentina | Brazil | Canada | China | France | Germany | India | Italy | Japan | LatinAmerica | Mexico | Russia | Spain | UnitedKingdom | UnitedStates

Thomson Reuters is the world's largest international multimedia news agency, providing investing news, world news, business news, technology news, headline news, small business news, news alerts, personal finance, stock market, and mutual funds information available on Reuters.com, video, mobile, and interactive television platforms. Thomson Reuters journalists are subject to an Editorial Handbook which requires fair presentation and disclosure of relevant interests.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:48:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taliban Attacks in Kabul Target Intel Compound, NATO Convoy - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHugP562ZDiPrxkOkt-z6ar3FPghA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778897013066&amp;ei=OtSbVfD-D9TCaKTolfAF&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2015/07/07/world/asia/ap-as-afghanistan.html</Link>
        <Description/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <MainBody/>
=======
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack: No 10 flags to be flown at half-mast
28 June 2015
From the section UK
The beach area where the attack happened reopened on Sunday
Downing Street's flags will be flown at half-mast in memory of the British victims of the Tunisian beach attack.
Officials fear the UK death toll from Friday's gun attack is likely to be in the mid to high 20s, out of a total of 38 victims.
Relatives of others still missing are anxiously awaiting any news of their loved ones.
Daniel Welch, who has not heard from his grandfather John since the attack, said "we can only expect the worst".
Simon Boon is another Briton desperately seeking information.
He says he saw his sister Allison Heathcote on news channels being stretchered off the beach on a sunbed, but had very little information from the Foreign Office, and had to rely on news websites and phoning hospitals in Sousse to find out what happened.
She had received two gunshot wounds, had undergone surgery and was now critical, he said.
"My brother-in-law - we still have no information. Originally the Foreign Office said he was with his wife but no hospitals have any records," he said.
"Nearly 48 hours on, we're none the wiser."
The Foreign Office flag was lowered to half-mast in memory of the victims of Friday's gun attack
A total of 38 people were killed in the attack at a beach resort in Sousse on Friday, and an unspecified number have been injured.
Other countries affected by the shooting carried out by 23-year-old Seifeddine Rezgui, who had links with Islamic State, include Belgium, Germany and Ukraine. Three people from Ireland were also killed.
The Foreign Office has updated its travel advice to warn that further terrorist attacks in Tunisia are possible, and urged people to be vigilant.
'Won't have had phones'
Speaking after she chaired a meeting of the government's emergency Cobra committee, Home Secretary Theresa May said Foreign Office staff were working round the clock in Tunisia and a 24-hour crisis centre was up and running in the UK.
She added that she had seen no evidence to indicate the beach was targeted because of the high number of British holidaymakers.
Armed police are now patrolling the beach where the gun attack took place
The home secretary suggested officials were having difficulty identifying the British victims as many were not carrying identification.
Ms May said many would not have had passports with them on the beach and some victims were being moved between hospitals in the country.
"What's important is that the information is absolutely 100% correct when it is given to a family," she told  BBC One's Andrew Marr Show.
"If you can imagine, because of the circumstances of the attack, people won't have had documents with them, they won't necessarily have had phones."
No British victims have been officially identified but the names of some have been confirmed by friends and family :
Carly Lovett, 24, a beauty blogger and photographer from Gainsborough in Lincolnshire who was first to be named
Sue Davey and her partner Scott Chalkley, both in their 40s, whose deaths were confirmed by their respective sons
Adrian Evans, his father, 78-year-old Patrick Evans and nephew Joel Richards, 19, from Wednesbury.
Bruce Wilkinson, 72, from Goole in Yorkshire
Lisa Burbidge, in her 60s, from Whickham, Gateshead
Claire Windass, 54, from Hull, was on the beach with her husband, who survived.
Carly Lovett, Adrian Evans and Joel Richards, left to right
Sue Davey and Scott Chalkley
Mr Welch, from Swindon in Wiltshire, says he is at a "bit of a loss" about his grandfather John Welch, 74, and his partner Eileen Swannack, 70.
He said the hardest thing was "not knowing".
John Welch and his partner Eileen Swannack
The family of Denis and Elaine Thwaites, from Blackpool, Lancashire, are appealing for information about their whereabouts.
The retired couple, aged 70 and 69, arrived in Sousse on Wednesday and had been staying at the Marhaba.
Their son-in-law Danny Clifford said news the family had received telling them Mr and Mrs Thwaites were in hospital was proved to be misinformation. "We are absolutely frantic," he added.
Denis and Elaine Thwaites
The beach area at Sousse where the attack took place has now reopened.
Rezgui, a Tunisian student who was not previously known to the authorities, began his attack on tourists at noon on Friday. He had been posing as a swimmer but carrying a rifle under a parasol.
Rezgui shot at people on the beach near the Imperial Marhaba and Bellevue hotels. He then entered one of the hotel lobbies, where explosives were also detonated.
He then walked through the streets of Sousse where he was reportedly chased by local Tunisians, firing shots at them.
It has also been reported that local builders threw rubble down at him from rooftops as he passed by in the street. The attack eventually ended when he was shot dead by police.
His parents, sister and close friends have been detained by the Tunisian authorities.
Were you in Sousse in Tunisia when the attacks happened? Do you have friends or family affected? Please share your stories.
You can share your experiences by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk . If you are happy to speak to a BBC journalist, please leave a contact number.
Or WhatsApp us on+44 7525 900971.
Or you can comment here:
Required field
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
    </Article>
</site>
