<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attacker Storms Factory Near Lyon, France, Beheading One - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFr54And1aifiIN0pt0OiQqgRnBvQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888740792&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/27/world/europe/french-factory-lyon-attack-isis.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:13:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: '19 killed' in Sousse hotel - BBC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFu9fAeGKKmvf2WXET9sKtCIArI6g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888824887&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-33287978</Link>
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498 - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFFTYPT95IDiBi0_cMLC8p5VW8i_Q&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888991832&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/06/28/us-taiwan-fire-idUSKBN0P70TC20150628</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498
TAIPEI | By J.R. Wu and Pichi Chuang
TAIPEI The number of party revelers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a colored powder thrown on those attending the party.
Six foreigners and seven visitors from Hong Kong, mainland China and Macau were among those injured after about 1,000 people dancing at Saturday's event were sprayed with the powder, as a special feature of a festival also held in previous years.
The figure released late Sunday by local authorities was lower than an earlier estimate of 519 injured due to patients being transferred between hospitals and being double-counted, a government official said.
The blaze, which broke out at around 8.30 p.m. at the Formosa Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the colored powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder explode," he said.
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed and its safety can be assured.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters. All of the 498 injured were still being treated in 43 hospitals across the island, according to the latest figures provided by the New Taipei City government.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, who wore wet swimsuits and lay on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
A video posted online by Apple Daily showed dancers in front of the stage engulfed in clouds of colored powder a moment before a fireball erupted, followed by pockets of flame, triggering panic and screams.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man  said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims suffered burns on limbs and torsos, with some passing out from the pain while others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and pictures showed.
"Her whole life is ruined," sobbed the father of Chu Li, an 18-year-old girl with burns on 80 percent of her body, during a visit by President Ma Ying-jeou to victims in a Taipei hospital.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on its website on Sunday.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in recent weeks.
(Additional reporting by Faith Hung; Editing by Clarence Fernandez and Digby Lidstone)
A person helps an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wang Wei
1 of 4
right
People carry an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Chen Bo
2 of 4
right
Injured victims from an accidental explosion during a music concert lie on the ground at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wang Wei
3 of 4
right
People carry an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wu Chia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:02:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Central Bank Limits Aid to Greek Banks Amid Debt Crisis - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGDJggksB8zhQhc98QJfLgFtnGIMg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778890235863&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/29/business/greeces-financial-lifeline-is-now-up-to-european-central-bank.html</Link>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack on Sousse beach 'kills 27'
26 June 2015
From the section Africa
Tunisian TV ran footage from one hotel close to the attack
At least 27 people have been killed, including foreigners, in an attack on a beach near two tourist hotels in the Tunisian resort town of Sousse, according to the interior ministry.
Officials say one gunman has been shot dead and another is being pursued.
Sousse is a popular tourist destination.
Tunisia has been on high alert since March when militants killed 22 people, mainly foreign tourists, in an attack on a museum in the capital Tunis.
The interior ministry told the BBC "a terrorist attack" was ongoing.
Tunisia attacks: Live updates
A British man on holiday told the BBC that he heard the attack on a neighbouring hotel and saw a man with a pistol from his room, but did not know whether this was an attacker or a member of the security forces.
The holidaymaker said he and other guests had been told to take shelter in the hotel's staff quarters and have been told to wait for the all-clear.
One image circulating on social media appeared to show a man lying face down in the sand with what looks like blood around his head.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:15:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State Claims Responsibility for Kuwait Mosque Blast - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNE0Dlw0a0LxRLXk8yBEdWfnikFSqw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888791661&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/articles/deadly-blast-hits-kuwait-mosque-1435319403</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Islamic State Claims Responsibility for Kuwait Mosque Blast
Attack marks Sunni extremist groups first assault on the country
By
Maria Abi Habib
Updated June 26, 2015 8:07 a.m. ET
DUBAIIslamic State took responsibility for a deadly explosion on Friday at a Shiite Muslim mosque in Kuwait City, a rare attack in the tiny Gulf nation.
The Sunni extremist group claimed the attack via a statement posted to a known Twitter account. It named the bomber as Abu Sleiman al Mouahed and said that he was wearing a suicide belt.
...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Draft | Today in Politics: GOP Finds Much to Add to Justices' Final Say on ... - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGTDff1kHQHsah1WqcXy1XQONsIYw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778885692391&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/06/26/today-in-politics-g-o-p-finds-much-to-add-to-justices-final-say-on-health-care-law/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:30:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Religious Groups Brace For Supreme Court's Same-Sex Marriage Ruling - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJ4u0paSlRzemLCjmLg1bP6jSbVA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778886195348&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/articles/religious-groups-brace-for-supreme-courts-same-sex-marriage-ruling-1435291179</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>tammy.audi@wsj.com
Updated June 26, 2015 6:54 a.m. ET
As the U.S. Supreme Court prepares to issue a potentially far-reaching ruling that effectively could legalize same-sex marriage nationwide, religious groups opposed to gay marriage are bracing for the potential impactdeveloping new legal strategies to carve out religious exemptions, and ramping up fundraising to pay for them.
People are scared the freedoms theyve always taken for granted are now at risk and theyre fearing discrimination by their government for simply trying to live according to their beliefs, said...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine Killed in Alaska Plane Crash - Wall Street Journal</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG3AJyIv8Se3V0XRPRQ4Ehaxl9HUg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888403779&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.wsj.com/news/articles/SB11871130314313103897904581071500184640590</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nine Killed in Alaska Plane Crash
Eight passengers on a sightseeing excursion from a Holland America Line cruise and the pilot were killed
Associated Press
June 26, 2015 7:00 a.m. ET
ANCHORAGE, AlaskaNine people died when a sightseeing plane crashed in southeastern Alaska, but stormy weather prevented the immediate recovery of their bodies.
Alaska emergency crews will attempt Friday to recover the remains of the eight cruise ship passengers and pilot who were killed when the plane crashed in a remote and rugged area.
...
To Read the Full Story, Subscribe or Sign In
Popular on WSJ
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama set to eulogize pastor in Charleston shooting - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH7lQO4cSrLw8VXFElea3wtvPrvsw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888653336&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/06/26/politics/obama-charleston-eulogy-pastor/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CNN.com
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Obama set to eulogize pastor in Charleston shooting
By Kevin Liptak , CNN White House Producer
Updated 1326 GMT (2026 HKT) June 26, 2015
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
President Barack Obama attends the 2014 Nuclear Security Summit in March 2014 in the Hague, Netherlands. As his presidency winds down, here's a look at some key moments of his administration.
Hide Caption
1 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Michelle Obama brushes specks  from the coat of then-Sen. Obama inside the Old State Capitol in Springfield, Illinois, just before he announced his candidacy for president of the United States in February 2007. Their daughters Malia, left, and Sasha wait in the foreground.
Hide Caption
2 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama appears on "Meet the Press" with Tim Russert, right, in Des Moines, Iowa, in November 2007.
Hide Caption
3 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama shakes hands with supporters after addressing a rally in Concord, New Hampshire, in January 2008.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama gives a speech at the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia in March 2008.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama speaks at the 2008 Democratic National Convention in Denver, Colorado.
Hide Caption
6 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama stands on stage  in Chicago, Illinois, with his family after defeating Republican presidential candidate John McCain on November 4, 2008.
Hide Caption
7 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Left to right: Presidents George H. W. Bush, Obama, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton, and Jimmy Carter pose for photos in the Oval Office in January 2009.
Hide Caption
8 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama is sworn in by Chief Justice John Roberts as the 44th President of the United States on the West Front of the Capitol in Washington on January 20, 2009.
Hide Caption
9 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
As retired military officers stand behind him, Obama signs an executive order to close down the detention center at Guantanamo Bay in January 2009.
Hide Caption
10 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and Vice President Joe Biden look at solar panels as they tour the solar array at the Denver Museum of Nature and Science on February 17, 2009. That same day, Obama signed the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act.
Hide Caption
11 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
A soldier hugs Obama during his surprise visit to Camp Victory just outside Baghdad, Iraq, in April 2009.
Hide Caption
12 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama bends over so the son of a White House staff member can pat his head during a visit to the Oval Office in May 2009. The boy wanted to know if Obama's hair felt like his.
Hide Caption
13 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama kisses Sonia Sotomayor's cheek after announcing her as his nominee for justice on the Supreme Court in May 2009.
Hide Caption
14 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Palestinian security forces in Jenin, West Bank, listen to Obama speak from Cairo University in Egypt in June 2009. The Palestinian Authority hailed as a "good beginning" Obama's speech to the Muslim world in which he reiterated his support for a Palestinian state.
Hide Caption
15 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and first lady Michelle Obama meet with Pope Benedict XVI in Vatican City in July 2009.
Hide Caption
16 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama hosts the Apollo 11 astronauts, from left to right, Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin, Michael Collins and Neil Armstrong in the Oval Office on July 20, 2009, the 40th anniversary of the moon landing.
Hide Caption
17 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Police Sgt. James Crowley, second right, of Cambridge, Massachusetts, speaks with Harvard Professor Henry Louis Gates Jr., second left, alongside Obama and Biden as they share beers on the South Lawn of the White House in July 2009. In an effort to curb controversy, the so-called "Beer Summit," was held after Crowley arrested Gates at his own home which sparked tensions and racial furor.
Hide Caption
18 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama salutes during the transfer of Sgt. Dale R. Griffin at Dover Air Force Base in Dover, Delaware, in October 2009. Obama traveled to the base to meet the plane carrying the bodies of 18 U.S. personnel killed in Afghanistan on October 26, including Griffin.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama walks along the Great Wall of China in November 2009.
Hide Caption
20 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama delivers a speech after receiving the Nobel Peace Prize in Oslo, Norway, in December 2009.
Hide Caption
21 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Presidents Obama, Clinton, and Bush walk to the Rose Garden to speak about relief efforts for earthquake-stricken Haiti in January 2010.
Hide Caption
22 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
First daughters Sasha and Malia Obama play in the snow with their father in the Rose Garden during a snowstorm that hit Washington in February 2010.
Hide Caption
23 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama's signature on the Affordable Healthcare Act is seen at the White House in March 2010.
Hide Caption
24 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama throws out the opening pitch before a baseball game between the Philadelphia Phillies and the Washington Nationals on Opening Day at Nationals Park in Washington in April 2010.
Hide Caption
25 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and daughter, Sasha, swim at Alligator Point in Panama City Beach, Florida, in August 2010, in an effort to encourage people to come back to the Gulf Coast after the devastating oil spill.
Hide Caption
26 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama laughs as he makes a statement on his birth certificate in April 2011. Obama said he was amused over conspiracy theories about his birthplace, and said the media's obsession with the "sideshow" issue was a distraction in a "serious time."
Hide Caption
27 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama, Biden, Secretary of State Hillary Clinton and members of the national security team receive live updates in the Situation Room of the White House on the mission to capture or kill Osama bin Laden on May 1, 2011.
Hide Caption
28 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
U.S. Marines of Regiment Combat Team 1 watch from Camp Dwyer in Afghanistan as Obama announces the death of Osama bin Laden on May 2, 2011.
Hide Caption
29 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama enjoys a pint of Guinness in his ancestral home of Moneygall, Ireland, in May 2011.
Hide Caption
30 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama, left, and first lady Michelle Obama, right, meet with Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, at Buckingham Palace in London in May 2011.
Hide Caption
31 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama and Missouri Gov. Jay Nixon walk together in May 2011 during a tour of the devastation of Joplin, Missouri, after it was hit by tornado with winds over 200 mph.
Hide Caption
32 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama delivers remarks to troops and military families at Fort Bragg, North Carolina, on December 14, 2011, marking the exit of U.S. soldiers from Iraq.
Hide Caption
33 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama pays for a dog toy as he shops with his dog Bo at a Petsmart in Alexandria, Virginia, in December 2011.
Hide Caption
34 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama sits on the famed Rosa Parks bus at the Henry Ford Museum in Dearborn, Michigan, in April 2012.
Hide Caption
35 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
British Prime Minister David Cameron, Obama, German Chancellor Angela Merkel, and others watch the overtime shootout of the Champions League final soccer match between Chelsea and Bayern Munich in the Laurel Cabin conference room at Camp David, Maryland, during a G8 Summit in May 2012.
Hide Caption
36 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama sits in his chair during a Cabinet meeting in the Cabinet Room in July 2012. This image was tweeted by his official Twitter account in August 2012 in response to Clint Eastwood's "empty chair" speech at the Republican National Convention. The tweet simply said, "This seat's taken."
Hide Caption
37 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama casts a shadow in this picture as he accepts the 2012 Democratic nomination for president during the final day of the Democratic National Convention in Charlotte, North Carolina, in September 2012.
Hide Caption
38 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Republican presidential candidate Mitt Romney and Obama participate in the first presidential debate of the 2012 election in Denver, Colorado, in October 2012.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama celebrates on stage in Chicago after defeating Romney on Election Day November 6, 2012.
Hide Caption
40 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama pauses during his speech at a memorial service in Newtown, Connecticut, for the victims and relatives of the Sandy Hook Elementary School massacre in December 2012.
Hide Caption
41 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Hundreds of thousands gather at the U.S. Capitol building as Obama is inaugurated for his second term on January 21, 2013.
Hide Caption
42 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Israeli President Shimon Peres, left, and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, right, stand with Obama during an arrival ceremony for Obama at Ben Gurion International Airport in Tel Aviv, Israel, in March 2013.
Hide Caption
43 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama adjusts an umbrella held by a Marine during a news conference with Turkish Prime Minister Recep Tayyip Erdogan in the Rose Garden of the White House in May 2013.
Hide Caption
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Jay Leno interviews Obama on "The Tonight Show" in August 2013.
Hide Caption
45 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
White House press secretary Jay Carney fields questions from reporters during a daily press briefing at the White House in September 2013 after Obama's push for Congressional approval for limited military strikes against the Syrian government.
Hide Caption
46 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Actor and comedian Zach Galifianakis interviews Obama during his appearance on "Between Two Ferns," a digital video series with a laser focus on reaching people aged 18 to 34. The President urged young people to sign up for the new health care plan in the video posted on the website Funny or Die.
Hide Caption
47 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama walks to the Oval Office on August 7, 2014, the same day he announced the beginning of air strikes on ISIS.
Hide Caption
48 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama speaks to the nation from the Cabinet Room of the White House about normalizing diplomatic relations with Cuba in December 2014.
Hide Caption
49 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Left to right: House Majority Leader Rep. Kevin McCarthy, House Minority Leader Rep. Nancy Pelosi, and Speaker of the House Rep. John Boehner listen as Obama speaks during a meeting in the Cabinet Room of the White House on January 13, 2015.
Hide Caption
50 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
President Barack Obama takes a selfie with podcast host Mark Maron after being a guest on his show "WTF with Marc Maron" in Los Angeles on June 22, 2015.
Hide Caption
51 of 52
Barack Obama's presidency 52 photos
Obama responds to a heckler who interrupted his speech during a reception in honor of LGBT Pride Month in the East Room of the White House in Washington, D.C., June 24, 2015.
Hide Caption
52 of 52
Washington (CNN)
Friday's funeral service for Rev. Clementa Pinckney won't be the first time President Barack Obama delivers a high-profile eulogy; with a year-and-a-half remaining in office, it may not be the last.
But when the President stands in historic downtown Charleston to remember the slain pastor and eight others shot down in their church last week, his speech will move beyond just grief for the victims -- Obama will step directly into a national conversation about race in which he plays a central role.
The President, first lady Michelle Obama, Vice President Joe Biden, a bipartisan host of high-level members of Congress and Hillary Clinton were all headed to TD Arena on Friday for the memorial service more than a week after a 21-year-old man opened fire at a Bible study inside Charleston's Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church.
The shooter declared he was there to "kill black people," and an online manifesto attributed to him contained white supremacist screeds.
JUST WATCHED
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:23:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French government files legal complaint against UberPOP - Reuters</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH3VUETN4XOuoW1B_-pKFtRdglhSg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778887823225&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2015/06/26/france-uber-idUSL8N0ZC0SD20150626</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>French government files legal complaint against UberPOP
PARIS, June 26
PARIS, June 26 French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said on Friday he had launched legal action targeting local managers of U.S.-based ride-sharing service Uber, denouncing the attitude of the company as "cynical" and "arrogant".
France already ordered a nationwide clampdown on its UberPOP mobile app-based service on Thursday, siding with taxi drivers who blockaded major transport hubs in protests against the service.
Faced with the threat of renewed disruption, even President Francois Hollande weighed in, calling from the sidelines of a late-night European Union summit in Brussels for the dissolution of UberPOP's activities in France.
"We are in a state of law and the law will rule," Cazeneuve told RTL radio.
A law from October 2014 placed a ban on putting clients in touch with unregistered drivers. However Uber contests the rule, saying it is unclear and counter to the freedom to do business. A constitutional ruling is expected around September.
On Thursday Cazeneuve ordered Paris police to issue a decree banning UberPOP and said cars defying the order would be seized. Uber France general manager Thibaud Simphal retorted by saying the measures "changed nothing" and that demand for its services in France would continue.
"The complaint I filed yesterday is wide enough to cover the statements of UberPOP managers," Cazeneuve told RTL, adding that inciting people to defy the ban was "a criminal offence".
An Uber spokesman on Thursday accused the French government of seeking to interfere in the course of justice.
UberPOP links drivers of private cars with potential passengers at cheaper rates than conventional cabs and has already come under political and legal scrutiny in France.   (Reporting by Dominique Vidalon; Editing by Mark John and Alison Williams)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>I-75 reopens after 6 killed in wreck outside Chattanooga - Twin Falls Times-News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGhJWpUm5aoS0h8ZzIa5Ava5bMMlA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888426097&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://magicvalley.com/news/national/i--reopens-after-killed-in-wreck-outside-chattanooga/article_9f73b8d7-9155-5b2f-a0c0-25276b822046.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>I-75 reopens after 6 killed in wreck outside Chattanooga
Saved
2015-06-26T05:40:46Z I-75 reopens after 6 killed in wreck outside ChattanoogaThe Associated Press The Associated Press
1 hour ago
(0) Comments
CHATTANOOGA, Tenn. (AP)  Police in southeastern Tennessee say Interstate 75 has reopened about 12 hours after six people were killed in a nine-vehicle wreck.
Chattanooga Police Department spokesman Kyle Miller says the accident happened around 7:10 p.m. Thursday on I-75 northbound near the suburb of Ooltewah.
He said investigators are still working to determine the cause of the crash.
Police believe more than 15 people were involved; the exact number is still being determined because multiple groups were taken to local hospitals.
The identities of the victims were not immediately released.
Miller said on Friday morning that no further updates were immediately available.
Copyright 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:24:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Missing Clinton Emails Likely to Raise New Questions - ABC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHEmfgLtug3QZc8r7W5QI256WUBMQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778886739320&amp;ei=UEmNVcjfAt7baar8rJAO&amp;url=http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/wireStory/missing-clinton-emails-raise-questions-32043015</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Missing Clinton Emails Likely to Raise New Questions
WASHINGTON  Jun 26, 2015, 3:23 AM ET
By BRADLEY KLAPPER and MATTHEW LEE Associated Press
The State Department cannot find in its records all or part of 15 work-related emails from Hillary Rodham Clinton's private server that were released this week by a House panel investigating the 2012 attack in Benghazi, Libya, officials said Thursday.
The emails all predate the Sept. 11 assault on the U.S. diplomatic facility and include scant words written by Clinton herself, the officials said. They consist of more in a series of would-be intelligence reports passed to her by longtime political confidant Sidney Blumenthal, the officials said.
Nevertheless, the fact that the State Department says it can't find them among emails she provided surely will raise new questions about Clinton's use of a personal email account and server while secretary of state and whether she has provided the agency all of her work-related correspondence, as she claims.
Rep. Trey Gowdy, chairman of the Select Committee on Benghazi, released a statement Thursday saying, "This confirms doubts about the completeness of Clinton's self-selected public record and raises serious questions about her decision to erase her personal server  especially before it could be analyzed by an independent, neutral third-party arbiter."
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Page
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heritage or hate: The history of the Confederate Flag - Hindustan Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFYjLRAdR05lyfHOK2Sy5tK3q_2kA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778889459940&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/heritage-or-hate-the-history-of-the-confederate-flag/article1-1363799.aspx</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>|
Updated: Jun 28, 2015 19:27 IST
A Confederate flag is held up by a man at a rally outside the State House to get the Confederate flag removed from the grounds in Columbia, South Carolina (Reuters Photo)
The recent shootings at Charleston which saw nine African-Americans gunned down at a church have brought racism and lax gun control legislation to the forefront of political debate in the US once again.
As more and more people express outrage in the aftermath of Dylann Roof's attack, one symbol has come to define the racism that is believed to have motivated the shooter: The Confederate flag.
But why does a relic from the US Civil War of 1861-65 still provoke such strong feelings among all classes, political or otherwise?
Its a rather strange quirk of history that the Confederate flag  which rouses such passionate debate, both in condemnation and in support of it  was never officially sanctioned.
Instead, the so-called "Southern Cross" that Roof was seen posing with , and that an activist was arrested for taking down in Columbia on Saturday, was the battle flag of the southern states of the US during the Civil War.
The original flag for the Confederate was meant to, in the words of its designer William T Thompson, symbolise the Heaven-ordained supremacy of the white man over the inferior or coloured race.
Civil war shook the United States with the South rebelling against Abraham Lincoln's decision to abolish slavery. In its aftermath, with the slave-owning landlords of the southern states shattered and brought to heel under Washington, the flag one sees today became embraced as a way of expressing regional pride. And therein lies the crux of the matter.
Jon Stewart explains the hypocrisy surrounding the defense of the Confederate battle-flag
Some have argued, and continue to do so, that the flag which Gen Robert E Lee most notably fought under is an important expression of the independent culture of the southern portion of the US, hence its presence over official public buildings and certain monuments.
Others, however, claim this representation is merely whitewashing history; as President Barack Obama himself said while delivering the eulogy for the victims of Charleston on Saturday, the flag was a reminder of systematic oppression and racial subjugation.
If u recognize the Confederate flag as part of your heritage, you're no different than Nazis! Hate is Hate. #FreeBree pic.twitter.com/wqtws5JhJm
 Benny (@BRios82) June 27, 2015
It is precisely for this reason that the Confederate flag continues to garner sharp criticism, and remains a contentious symbol for a country that has been confronted by the ugly spectre of racism in the recent past.
Slavery, or rather the Union's distaste for it, was after all a significant reason why the southern states wished to secede in the first place. But how exactly did the flag re-emerge as a potent political symbol?
It began, perhaps counter-intuitively, with the rise of the Civil Rights movement in the 20th century. As African-Americans began to articulate their political desires and push for an end to discrimination, those who opposed them sought a potent symbol to mobilise against them.
Arguably, the first use of the Southern Cross in this manner was in 1948, when Strom Thurmond ran for president under the newly founded States Right Democratic Party, also known as the Dixiecrats.
And while desegregation progressed, the battle flag cropped up with more and more frequency; a sign perhaps, that this reminder of the divisive and unhappy past of the US had acquired a new political presence.
After 45 min down, the Confederate flag was back up in S. Carolina. Who's going to be the next person to #takeitdown ? http://t.co/eXBDHmeboA
 Michael Moore (@MMFlint) June 27, 2015
This, then, is the legacy of the battle flag of the southern states; a sharp reminder of the racism that has been an indelible part of America's socio-political conscience since its formation, and the reason why it has been under fire in the wake of Charleston and other racial attacks.
With the President calling for the flag to be taken down permanently from public places, and widespread condemnation of it, it looks like the Southern Cross' days might be finally numbered.
Tags
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:17:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Manhunt for David Sweat Continues - ABC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHqvkFRjbP3_JVZUdwMxJTcc4R3xA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778887494852&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/manhunt-david-sweat-continues-32081334</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Video Transcript
Transcript for Manhunt for David Sweat Continues
Now, though, as promised that massive manhunt for escaped prisoner David sweat, it's all playing out near his accomplice Richard Matt. He's been on the run for more than three weeks now and ABC's Phillip Mena is in Malone, new York, where officials are making some bold predictions. Reporter: Danger, good morning. We spoke with the sheriff late last night, he believes there's going to be a major break in this manhunt very soon. He's not getting regular meals, regular sleep, I think he's getting desperate. Reporter: One of the men leading the hunt the local, state and federal officers pouring into the rural area believe they have sweat inside of a tight perimeter. A good or solid lead from a resident that someone has been near a cabin. Reporter: Fellow escapee Richard sweat was spotted and taken down. Calling police after discovering items missing Friday. Two pairs of boots. Reporter: He also saw a bottle of gin spill. Matt appeared to be acting intoxicating at the time he was shot. Reported in bad health with that unconer the with S.W.A.T. Team. U.s. Border patrol agent fired his weapon. Reporter: Police believe sweat was still traveling with Matt up until his death Friday and it's a matter of when, not if, the fugitive is captured or killed. Sweat has been out of prison now for three weeks, he's going to make a mistake. Reporter: And Paula, it's pouring out here, it's expected to stay this way all day. That will slow down the search, but it's going to be even harder on sweat who has no protection from the rain. Police sound pretty confident they're going to get their guy.
This transcript has been automatically generated and may not be 100% accurate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:07:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nuke Talks to Miss Target; Iran Foreign Minister Heads Home - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHLawTactSh5IRhrviqLuQb062mvQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778887910240&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2015/06/28/world/middleeast/ap-iran-nuclear-talks-.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:02:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch live: SpaceX launch Sunday morning - Los Angeles Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG7EM8VCSf1gyRWPYZ4aeza3NU1lw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778887325257&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-spacex-launch-20150628-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Broadcast live streaming video on Ustream
Early Sunday morning, entrepreneur Elon Musks SpaceX will make its third attempt to land a rocket on an ocean barge  a feat that if successful would be historic.
The landing would happen minutes after the companys Falcon 9 rocket blasts off carrying cargo to the International Space Station.  The rocket is programmed to turn itself around after it separates from the capsule and a second-stage engine, which will continue to orbit.
The Hawthorne-based company is trying to land its 13-story unmanned rocket in the hope that it could be used again. Such reusable rockets have long been a goal in the industry because they could sharply reduce the cost of space travel.
This will be the seventh time SpaceX has carried cargo to the International Space Station under a contract with NASA.
The launch from Florida's Cape Canaveral is scheduled for 7:21 a.m. PDT. Coverage of the event by NASAs television station begins at 6 a.m.
Follow me on Twitter @MelodyPetersen
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:13:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man, 64, shot near San Francisco Pride Parade, several detained - New York Daily News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEscURUuBKdr2REpGnZCRUaCMR9KA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778889238035&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/man-shot-san-francisco-pride-parade-detained-article-1.2274005</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Share this URL
Jeff Chiu/AP
Police say a bystander was shot at a gay pride event in San Francisco's Civic Center when an argument between several young men turned violent.
CNN
People scatter after a shooting at a gay pride event in San Francisco.
Sean-Franc Strang/AP
Police arrived at the scene after shots were fired at a gay pride event in San Francisco, Saturday.
Previous Next
Enlarge
A man was shot in the arm Saturday near the San Francisco Pride Parade after an argument broke out and shots were fired.
The shooting was unrelated to Pride events, police said, and stemmed from an argument between two groups of young men. The argument escalated and one of the men pulled out a gun and fired four shots.
The 64-year-old man who was shot was nearby watching the parade. He was taken to San Francisco General Hospital for treatment and was reported to be in stable condition.
Another man near the scene of the shooting was able to film the moment the shots rang out with his cellphone. In the video, people are seen screaming and running for cover.
Police arrived at the scene around 6 p.m. and were able to detain several suspects.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>​Same-sex marriage: A matter of dignity - CBS News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHvBl2yL3GWtzIeA1p437T4jCpICA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778885692391&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.cbsnews.com/news/same-sex-marriage-a-matter-of-dignity/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>"The thing about the same-sex marriage issue is, it wasn't started by the big gay groups -- they hated this issue," said Andy Humm, a long-time gay activist and journalist in New York.
"The big gay groups thought it was a big loser, and they were right in the beginning."
What changed so quickly? Because, he said, same-sex marriage in a few states happened, "and the sky didn't fall. The law changed, and what changed for people in their lives?  Well, they just saw happiness for gay couples."
Gloria and Linda Bailey-Davies were married on May 17, 2004, the first day same-sex marriage licenses were issued in Massachusetts, the first state to legalize gay marriage.
Since then, how much the landscape has changed is remarkable, and how fast -- over the last two years especially, the number of states has accelerated, reaching 37  -- before the Supreme Court guaranteed the right to same-sex marriage nationwide.
In 1996, fewer than 3 in 10 Americans (27 percent) thought same-sex marriage should be legal. Now, nearly 6 in 10 (57 percent) do .
Among those who do not: 55 percent of Republicans.
"I don't think most of us who have ever read the scripture would believe that there is a division over what marriage means," said former Arkansas Governor Mike Huckabee. "It's still one man, one woman, life partners, and the courts can no more suspend the law of marriage any more than it can suspend the law of gravity."
Like Huckabee, every Republican presidential candidate has lined up against the Supreme Court ruling .
Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton's response? "Amen, thank you!"
Chief Justice John Roberts argued in his dissent that the issue should have been left to states -- voted on, not decreed by the court. "Just who do we think we are?" he wrote.
"We have to go, obviously, by what the courts say, but I certainly can disagree with them, and I do," said Alabama Governor Robert Bentley. He's willing to comply with the ruling, but there is resistance..
When Michael Robinson and his partner, Earl Benjamin, tried to get a marriage license in New Orleans after the court ruled on Friday, they were told they would have to wait. Louisiana and Mississippi claimed "legal technicalities."
"It's disappointing that Louisiana will not be following the movement that is happening around the country today," said Robinson.
And in Texas, Reverend Dave Welch of the Houston Area Pastor Council vowed disobedience. "A law that violates the law of God is no law at all," he said. "There is no question: it is by the thousands and tens of thousands and the hundreds of thousands that will not bend the knee and we will not kiss the ring. We will not bow to the god of political correctness that seems to be dominating much of our court system today."
Andy Humm said in response, "This is your homophobia. This is your fear. This is your hatred of gay people, and you gotta get over it."
Immediately after the Supreme Court decision, 85-year-old Jack Evans and 82-year-old George Harris, partners for more than 50 years, were the first gays to tie the knot legally in Dallas. An estimated 390,000 same-sex couples had already beaten them to it in the United States, raising this question: A generation from now, will gay marriage be a non-issue?
For more info:
 2015 CBS Interactive Inc. All Rights Reserved.
Shares
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait government says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi national - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHE7lnXWBXOc0aGU_mBgkMk2mCZrw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888791661&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/06/28/middleeast/kuwait-mosque-suicide-bombing/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Driver's landlord, bearer of 'deviant ideology' arrested
Kuwait government says bomber's driver was illegal immigrant.
Worst attack in Kuwait in years
(CNN)
Kuwait's Interior Ministry said Sunday that it had identified the suicide bomber who blew himself up at a mosque as a Saudi citizen, according to the official Kuwait News Agency.
The Ministry named the attacker as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen Al-Gabbaa.
The terrorist group ISIS, which claimed responsibility for the attack, had identified the bomber as Abu Sulieman al Muwahid -- probably the man's nom de guerre.
The bomb ripped through the Al-Sadiq mosque during Friday prayers -- a time when, more than other, mosques are packed with worshipers.
It was the worst terrorist attack Kuwait had seen in years, and one of three that took place on three different continents Friday.
Kuwaiti emergency personnel pull stretchers past security forces outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
Kuwaiti police said they had arrested the man who drove the bomber to the mosque, the country's state-run Kuwait News Agency reported early Sunday. They identified him as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, whom they said was as an "illegal resident" born in 1989.
In addition, police said they had arrested the driver's landlord, whom who they said was the "bearer of fundamentalist and deviant ideology."
A message of unity
Beyond the immediate investigation looms the issue of preventing such attacks in the future and ensuring that ISIS, which is wreaking havoc in neighboring Iraq and also has claimed attacks in Saudi Arabia, cannot do the same in Kuwait.
Kuwaiti newspapers Saturday carried messages of unity in this emirate, where Shias are one-third of the population.
JUST WATCHED
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:35:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia attack: No 10 flags to be flown at half-mast - BBC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEQtS9oluSmsw10BxXepkyrFIiDBA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778888824887&amp;ei=7ACQVYjuEoqpaJfek9AK&amp;url=http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-33304310</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tunisia attack: No 10 flags to be flown at half-mast
28 June 2015
From the section UK
The beach area where the attack happened reopened on Sunday
Downing Street's flags will be flown at half-mast in memory of the British victims of the Tunisian beach attack.
Officials fear the UK death toll from Friday's gun attack is likely to be in the mid to high 20s, out of a total of 38 victims.
Relatives of others still missing are anxiously awaiting any news of their loved ones.
Daniel Welch, who has not heard from his grandfather John since the attack, said "we can only expect the worst".
Simon Boon is another Briton desperately seeking information.
He says he saw his sister Allison Heathcote on news channels being stretchered off the beach on a sunbed, but had very little information from the Foreign Office, and had to rely on news websites and phoning hospitals in Sousse to find out what happened.
She had received two gunshot wounds, had undergone surgery and was now critical, he said.
"My brother-in-law - we still have no information. Originally the Foreign Office said he was with his wife but no hospitals have any records," he said.
"Nearly 48 hours on, we're none the wiser."
The Foreign Office flag was lowered to half-mast in memory of the victims of Friday's gun attack
A total of 38 people were killed in the attack at a beach resort in Sousse on Friday, and an unspecified number have been injured.
Other countries affected by the shooting carried out by 23-year-old Seifeddine Rezgui, who had links with Islamic State, include Belgium, Germany and Ukraine. Three people from Ireland were also killed.
The Foreign Office has updated its travel advice to warn that further terrorist attacks in Tunisia are possible, and urged people to be vigilant.
'Won't have had phones'
Speaking after she chaired a meeting of the government's emergency Cobra committee, Home Secretary Theresa May said Foreign Office staff were working round the clock in Tunisia and a 24-hour crisis centre was up and running in the UK.
She added that she had seen no evidence to indicate the beach was targeted because of the high number of British holidaymakers.
Armed police are now patrolling the beach where the gun attack took place
The home secretary suggested officials were having difficulty identifying the British victims as many were not carrying identification.
Ms May said many would not have had passports with them on the beach and some victims were being moved between hospitals in the country.
"What's important is that the information is absolutely 100% correct when it is given to a family," she told  BBC One's Andrew Marr Show.
"If you can imagine, because of the circumstances of the attack, people won't have had documents with them, they won't necessarily have had phones."
No British victims have been officially identified but the names of some have been confirmed by friends and family :
Carly Lovett, 24, a beauty blogger and photographer from Gainsborough in Lincolnshire who was first to be named
Sue Davey and her partner Scott Chalkley, both in their 40s, whose deaths were confirmed by their respective sons
Adrian Evans, his father, 78-year-old Patrick Evans and nephew Joel Richards, 19, from Wednesbury.
Bruce Wilkinson, 72, from Goole in Yorkshire
Lisa Burbidge, in her 60s, from Whickham, Gateshead
Claire Windass, 54, from Hull, was on the beach with her husband, who survived.
Carly Lovett, Adrian Evans and Joel Richards, left to right
Sue Davey and Scott Chalkley
Mr Welch, from Swindon in Wiltshire, says he is at a "bit of a loss" about his grandfather John Welch, 74, and his partner Eileen Swannack, 70.
He said the hardest thing was "not knowing".
John Welch and his partner Eileen Swannack
The family of Denis and Elaine Thwaites, from Blackpool, Lancashire, are appealing for information about their whereabouts.
The retired couple, aged 70 and 69, arrived in Sousse on Wednesday and had been staying at the Marhaba.
Their son-in-law Danny Clifford said news the family had received telling them Mr and Mrs Thwaites were in hospital was proved to be misinformation. "We are absolutely frantic," he added.
Denis and Elaine Thwaites
The beach area at Sousse where the attack took place has now reopened.
Rezgui, a Tunisian student who was not previously known to the authorities, began his attack on tourists at noon on Friday. He had been posing as a swimmer but carrying a rifle under a parasol.
Rezgui shot at people on the beach near the Imperial Marhaba and Bellevue hotels. He then entered one of the hotel lobbies, where explosives were also detonated.
He then walked through the streets of Sousse where he was reportedly chased by local Tunisians, firing shots at them.
It has also been reported that local builders threw rubble down at him from rooftops as he passed by in the street. The attack eventually ended when he was shot dead by police.
His parents, sister and close friends have been detained by the Tunisian authorities.
Were you in Sousse in Tunisia when the attacks happened? Do you have friends or family affected? Please share your stories.
You can share your experiences by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk . If you are happy to speak to a BBC journalist, please leave a contact number.
Or WhatsApp us on+44 7525 900971.
Or you can comment here:
Required field
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
