<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:12:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Accuses Ex-House Speaker J. Dennis Hastert of Paying to Hide 'Misconduct' - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGDyPHdcBJmFymgfnXn22g-17czmg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858675452&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/29/us/ex-house-speaker-j-dennis-hastert-indicted-on-federal-charges.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:58:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia cries foul: Fifa arrests 'a conspiracy' says Moscow - BBC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFtImdnoUEbKdlri-rocgiXsKjivg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858684601&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-32925637</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Russia cries foul: Fifa arrests 'a conspiracy' says Moscow
By Sarah Rainsford BBC News, Moscow
28 May 2015
From the section Europe
Vladimir Putin said Sepp Blatter was being pressurised to drop Russia as World Cup hosts
As the rest of the world debates the exposure of corruption at the heart of Fifa, all the talk swirling in Russia is of a conspiracy.
President Vladimir Putin argues that the criminal inquiry is aimed at ousting long-time Fifa president Sepp Blatter from his post.
He sees it as punishment for continuing to support Russia as host for the 2018 World Cup.
There have been increasing calls to strip Moscow of that privilege, in protest at military action in Ukraine.
"We know the pressure that was exerted on him [Blatter] with the aim of banning the 2018 World Cup in Russia," Mr Putin said on Thursday, offering Fifa's embattled leader his firm backing.
He then accused the United States of mounting a campaign to "persecute" Sepp Blatter for resisting.
"I have no doubt about it at all. It is a clear attempt to prevent the re-election of Mr Blatter," Mr Putin said, speaking about the criminal investigation.
The Luzhniki Stadium in Moscow is being rebuilt in time to host the 2018 World Cup final
Russia has proposed hosting matches in 13 cities, including Yekaterinburg
The comments fit a general trend here for vilifying the US, and demonstrate a conviction that consideration of Russia dominates global decision-making.
But Vladimir Putin's tirade also hints at genuine concern over the tournament's future.
This week, two prominent US senators urged Fifa against re-electing Mr Blatter as its head, because he continued to back Russia's right to stage the World Cup.
Acting as host was a privilege and a boost for Vladimir Putin "at a time when his actions should be condemned," John McCain and Robert Menendez argued.
Those actions include last year's annexation of Crimea and ongoing Russian support for rebel fighters in eastern Ukraine.
Moscow denies sending troops and weapons across the border, despite mounting evidence to the contrary.
A previous appeal asked Fifa to ban Russia from hosting the international event, but Mr Blatter has vowed repeatedly that politics would not "get in the way" of football.
Russia won the rights to host the 2018 tournament at a ceremony in December 2010
'Let them prove it'
No Russians have been arrested in the US-led corruption inquiry, but Swiss prosecutors have also revealed that they are conducting a parallel probe into allegations of fraud during the World Cup bidding process for Russia 2018 and Qatar 2022.
The results of a previous internal inquiry were never made public.
"Our bidding campaign was held honestly. Russia is not mixed up in corruption, everything is fair for our part," Russia's Sports Minister Vitaly Mutko assured reporters in Zurich, even as prosecutors sifted through documents seized from Fifa.
He insisted that the World Cup here is not in doubt and that the Russian organising committee had pledged to co-operate fully with the inquiry.
The decision to award the tournament to Russia is a matter of pride for many and preparations are well under way. But Muscovites are nervous.
"Of course I think it's politically motivated. I hope they can settle this," one woman told the BBC.
"A lot of money has already been spent."
That is a key concern: Russia has already cut its budget and scaled back plans, as its economy suffers the twin blows of a depressed oil price and sanctions over Ukraine.
"My understanding is that this is just another form of pressure on Russia," another man commented on the Swiss investigation.
"But the decision has been made, so it has to happen now. If there was money involved, let them prove it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:47:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>It's down to two spellers at the national bee - USA TODAY</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG_RmmRSHAsOotZbfzXYODl3ciKMw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778857819331&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2015/05/28/spelling-bee-final/28062069/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FacebookEmail Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Pinterest
It's down to two spellers at the national bee
NATIONAL HARBOR, Md.  Vanya Shivashankar will try to make history Thursday at the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee by becoming the first champion with a sibling who has previously won the competition.
Post to Facebook
It's down to two spellers at the national bee NATIONAL HARBOR, Md.  Vanya Shivashankar will try to make history Thursday at the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee by becoming the first champion with a sibling who has previously won the competition. Check out this story on USATODAY.com: http://usat.ly/1HPtsks
CancelSend
A link has been sent to your friend's email address.
Posted!
A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
7
To find out more about Facebook commenting please read the Conversation Guidelines and FAQs
It's down to two spellers at the national bee
Ledyard King , USATODAY 9:50 p.m. EDT May 28, 2015
Spellers talk about the experience of being on stage at the Scripps National Spelling Bee. Jenny Leonard, USA TODAY
Ten spellers advance to the championship finals of the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee at National Harbor, Md., on May 28, 2015.
(Photo: Jeff Franko, USA TODAY)
171 CONNECT 135 TWEET 3 LINKEDIN 7 COMMENTEMAILMORE
NATIONAL HARBOR, Md.  Vanya Shivashankar is trying to make history at Thursday night's finals of the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee.
No sibling of a previous champion has ever won the competition. Vanya, whose sister Kavya won the 2009 bee, hopes to change that.
Vanya, 13, of Olathe, Kansas., is making her fifth (and final) appearance at the bee, She was one of 10 finalists who started spelling at 8 p.m. on ESPN. By 9:30 p.m. the field had narrowed to two: Vanya and Gokul Venkatachalam, an eighth-grader at Parkway West Middle School in Chesterfield, Mo.
Dev Jaiswal of Mississippi didn't fare as well, stumbling over "iridocyclitis" in Round 9. The word refers to inflammation of the iris and the ciliary body
"I've blown my own mind. I'll be happy wherever I place tonight,'' Dev, an eighth-grader at Winston Academy in Louisville, Miss., said before the finals started.  "It's just a great honor to be here.''
By the numbers: Fun stats about the Scripps Spelling Bee contestants
For awhile, it looked as if the finals would include a second speller with a sibling who had won a national championship. But JairamJagadeeshHathwar, whose brother Sriram was co-champion in 2014, misspelled "riegel," a low transverse rock ridge on the floor of a glaciated valley.
"I was very excited and happy that I even made it to the semi-finals," the sixth-grader from Painted Post, N.Y., said after bowing out. "I least I made it past one round. I'll study harder and hopefully next time I'll do better."
More than 11 million spellers participated in regional bees to yield the 283 who began this year's national bee on Tuesday.
The spellers ranged in age from from 9 to 15.
All the spellers took a written spelling and vocabulary test on Tuesday. Competitors encountered a panoply of challenging words during Wednesday's two oral rounds, including "longiloquence," "zamzumim," and "Gesamtkunstwerk."
The field was winnowed to 49 for the start of Thursday's semifinals, based in part on Tuesday's written test. Twenty-one semifinalists correctly spelled their way through Thursday's two oral rounds, but only 10 made it to the finals based on Tuesday's test and another written test taken after Wednesday's oral rounds.
In addition to an engraved trophy, this year's champion will receive $35,000, a $2,500 U.S. savings bond, a complete reference library and other prizes.
Special food, coaching among spellers' bee strategies
Last year's competition ended with two spellers sharing the championship  only the fourth time that has happened. AnsunSujoe, 13, a seventh-grader from Fort Worth, Texas, won with "feuilleton" (part of a European newspaper), and SriramHathwar, 14, an eighth-grader from Painted Post, N.Y., won with "stichomythia" (a type of dialogue between two actors in a play).
Some spellers used special strategies to enhance their chances, such as adjusting their diets and working with a personal spelling coach.
But experience continues to be a determining factor. Six of the 10 finalists have participated in previous national bees, including five of the six who will enter the finals with the highest total scores.
Past champions say winning is about more than trying to memorize the dictionary.
ArvindMahankali of New York won the bee in 2013 on his fourth try, after misspelling words with German origins the previous two years.
Aren't they cute? 5 wacky National Spelling Bee bios
"I decided no matter what, I wouldn't be eliminated on a German word," he told the TODAY Show the day after winning. "So first I studied the German language spelling patterns and then I created a list of German words with help from my father and I had my mother quiz on me on the list."
The word he nailed to win the championship? "Knaidel," a word with German origins that refers to a type of dumpling.
Contributing: Deborah Barfield Berry, USA TODAY
Co-champions Vanya Shivashankar and  Gokul Venkatachalam hold their trophy  from the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee.
(Photo: Jeff Franko, USA TODAY)
Siddharth Krishnakumar misspells minhag in round 9.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Dev Jaiswal salutes the crowd after being eliminated in round 9.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Dev Jaiswal correctly spells bacchius in round 7.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Dev Jaiswal gets makeup during a break in the championship finals.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Tejas Muthusamyv misspells tartarean in round 8.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Siddharth Krishnakumar correctly spells Albumblatt in round 7.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Snehaa Ganesh Kumar in round 7 of the championship finals.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Snehaa Ganesh Kumar correctly spells bouillabaisse in round 7.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Siyona Mishra misspells "hacek" in round 7.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Sylvie Lamontagne misspells cerastes in round 7.
(Photo: Jack Gruber, USA TODAY)
Ten spellers are advancing to the finals of the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee on May 28 at National Harbor, Md.
(Photo: Jeff Franko, USA TODAY)
Katherine  S. Wang misses her word at the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Sylvie Lamontagne, left, and Snehaa Ganesh Kumar celebrate during the semifinals.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Marcus Behling concentrates during Round 6 competition.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Cole Shafer-Ray, left, and William Yaeger speak during the semifinals.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Manu Nair waits during Round 6.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Srinath Mahankali spells a word correctly.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Jenna-May Ingal reacts after misspelling a word.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Cy Orentlicher yawns during the Round 6 semifinals.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Ankita Vadiala celebrates after correctly spelling her Round 5 word.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
Cooper Komatsu, left and Marcus Behling speak during a break in the Round 5 semifinals at the 2015 Scripps National Spelling Bee.
(Photo: Evan Eile, USA TODAY)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:48:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>James Holmes told psychiatrist he has 'regrets' over theater shootings - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNELpJlAYaFLQREMGKqx7rt7FxJFVw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778856734894&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/05/28/us/james-holmes-trial-psychiatrist/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CNN Leadership
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
James Holmes told psychiatrist he has 'regrets' over theater shootings
By Steve Almasy and Jane Caffrey, CNN
Updated 0247 GMT (0947 HKT) May 29, 2015
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Colorado shooting victims  Jonathan T. Blunk, 26, served for five years in the U.S. Navy. He died shielding his girlfriend from the gunfire inside the theater.
Hide Caption
1 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Alexander J. Boik, 18, was remembered by friends and loved ones as a "great person" whose "craziness touched hundreds," according to a Facebook page created in his memory.
Hide Caption
2 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Air Force Staff Sgt. Jesse E. Childress, an Air Force reservist, was a cybersystems operator on active duty. He was 29.
Hide Caption
3 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Gordon W. Cowden, 51, took his two teenage children to the theater. His children escaped unharmed.
Hide Caption
4 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Jessica Ghawi, 24, was an aspiring sports reporter. She grew up in Texas before moving to Denver to try break into the television market there.
Hide Caption
5 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Petty Officer 3rd Class John Thomas Larimer, 27, served in the Navy like his father and grandfather. He had been in the service for about a year.
Hide Caption
6 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Matthew R. McQuinn, 27, died trying to provide cover for his girlfriend, Samantha Yowler, during the shooting, according to a family attorney. Yowler survived.
Hide Caption
7 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Micayla C. Medek, 23, known to her friends as Cayla, was "very spiritual and close to God," cousin Anita Busch told CNN.
Hide Caption
8 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Veronica Moser Sullivan, 6, was the youngest victim of the Aurora theater shooting. She had just learned how to swim.
Hide Caption
9 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Alex M. Sullivan, 27, went to the movie to celebrate his birthday with his wife, two days before their first wedding anniversary.
Hide Caption
10 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Alexander C. Teves, 24, recently graduated from the University of Denver with a master's degree in counseling psychology. He died protecting his girlfriend.
Hide Caption
11 of 12
Colorado shooting victims 12 photos
Rebecca Ann Wingo, 32, joined the Air Force after high school, became fluent in Mandarin and served as a translator, according to CNN affiliate WFAA.
Hide Caption
12 of 12
Story highlights
Doctor says he thinks James Holmes knew he was doing something wrong when he killed 12 people
Defense asks for mistrial but judge dismisses request
Holmes and William Reid talked for 22 hours in 2014, two years after the killings
(CNN)
In an initial meeting with a psychiatrist two years after killing 12 people at a Colorado movie theater, James Holmes told the doctor  he sometimes had tears and regrets over the shooting.
The interview between Holmes and Dr. William Howard Reid, recorded on video in late July 2014, was played to the jury in Holmes' murder trial on Wednesday.
It is part of 22 hours of sessions the two had after the Mental Health Institute of Pueblo selected Reid to question Holmes and evaluate his psychiatric state.
During that first discussion the doctor asked about Holmes' family. Holmes said he and his parents had an emotional meeting when they came to visit him.
Holmes said he was told his mother broke down when she was leaving but he didn't cry.
"Do you ever get tears in your eye?" Reid asks in the video.
"Um, yeah, sometimes," Holmes replies.
"What brings tears to your eyes sometimes?" Reid asks.
"Just regrets," Holmes says.
"Can you tell me a little more?" the doctor asks.
"Usually it's before I go to sleep," Holmes says.
"Regrets about?"
"Uh, about the shooting," Holmes says.
Reid says they'll talk about the night of the shooting at another time and asks Holmes more questions about his personal life.
Reid tells the jury he had nine sessions with Holmes that each lasted 1 hours to 3 hours. The interviews do not indicate Holmes' mental state around the time of the shooting, he said.
Reid was one of two psychiatrists to examine Holmes after he pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity. He was chosen by the hospital where Holmes was taken after his plea, not by the prosecution or defense.
Doctor: Holmes was legally sane on July 20
Earlier, when Reid was being questioned by District Attorney George Brauchler, he said Holmes was mentally ill, but on July 20, 2012, he was legally sane when he took the lives of a dozen people and wounded scores more.
"My opinion is that he did not -- is that, whatever he suffered from -- it did not prevent him from forming the intent and knowing what he was doing and the consequences of what he was doing," Reid said.
It was a head-turning moment because Brauchler hadn't asked the psychiatrist specifically about his opinion of Holmes' sanity but was questioning him about Colorado standards for forming an opinion on a defendant's mental state.
Defense attorney Daniel King asked to approach the bench and requested a mistrial, because he believed the wrong standard was being applied. He also asked for Reid's comment to be stricken from the record.
Judge Carlos Samour denied his request but after lunch reviewed the law with the jury.
Brauchler began the second part of his questioning by asking the doctor whether Holmes could recognize his actions were wrong on the day prior and on the night of the shootings. This time Reid answered succinctly.
Asked if Holmes met the criteria for mental illness, Reid said, "Yes."
Asked if Holmes had the capacity on that night to know right from wrong, Reid said, "Yes."
Asked if Holmes, had the capacity to act after deliberating, Reid said, "Yes, it is."
Then Brauchler, who has to prove to the jury that Holmes was legally sane during the two days in question, asked if Holmes met the definition of legal sanity. Reid again answered simply, "Yes."
Because the doctor's testimony and showing the video is expected to take several days, it will be next week before the defense can cross-examine him.
Holmes, 27, a former doctoral student in neuroscience, is standing trial on charges of capital murder and other offenses. He is accused of killing 12 people and injuring 70 more. He faces 165 counts. Holmes has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity. Prosecutors have said they will seek the death penalty.
Holmes admits to the shootings but has said he was suffering "a psychotic episode" at the time.
More from US
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pataki Keeps His Own Counsel on Matters of Family and Citizenship - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6e-U0n-CotlqVoiZkeIqgDBb4oA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778854325343&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/29/nyregion/pataki-keeps-his-own-counsel-on-matters-of-family-and-citizenship.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jeb Bush argues experience matters in Michigan - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHpRccn0P_Hf93hZCOYEGNcb5TdFQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778857521626&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/05/28/politics/jeb-bush-anthrax-michigan-experience/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CNN.com
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Jeb Bush argues experience matters in Michigan
Updated 0256 GMT (0956 HKT) May 29, 2015
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Former Florida governor Jeb Bush shakes hands with attendees after speaking at the 42nd annual Conservative Political Action Conference  February 27, 2015 in National Harbor, Maryland.
Hide Caption
1 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush takes a selfie with a guest at a luncheon hosted by the Chicago Council on Global Affairs on February 18, 2015, in Chicago. Bush delivered his first major foreign policy speech at the event.
Hide Caption
2 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush hands out items for Holiday Food Baskets to those in need outside the Little Havana offices of CAMACOL, the Latin American Chamber of Commerce on December 17, 2014, in Miami.
Hide Caption
3 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush waves to the audience at the Tampa Bay Times Forum in Tampa, Florida, on August 30, 2012, on the final day of the Republican National Convention.
Hide Caption
4 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush (left) and wife Columba Bush attend the 2012 Lincoln Center Institute Gala at Frederick P. Rose Hall, Jazz at Lincoln Center on March 7, 2012, in New York City.
Hide Caption
5 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
President Barack Obama (left) speaks about Bush (center) while visiting Miami Central Senior High School on March 4, 2011 in Miami, Florida. The visit focused on education.
Hide Caption
6 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush (left) speaks with Brazilian President in charge Jose Alancar during a meeting at Planalto Palace in Brasilia,  April 17, 2007. Bush was in Brazil to speak about sugar and ethanol business.
Hide Caption
7 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Then-Texas Governor Rick Perry (center) testifies as Bush (right) and then-Arizona Governor Janet Napolitano (left) listen during a hearing before the House Committee on Homeland Security on Capitol Hill October 19, 2005.
Hide Caption
8 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush gives a thumbs up signal from his car as he leaves a local polling station after casting his vote in Coral Gables, Florida, November 5, 2002.
Hide Caption
9 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush walks out of the West Wing after meeting with his brother, then-President George W. Bush, at the White House January 9, 2002. Governor Bush participated in the signing ceremony of the Everglades Protection Agreement.
Hide Caption
10 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Then-Mexican President Vincente Fox (left) and Bush hold a press conference September 7, 2001, in Miami. Fox visited Florida to attend the Americas Conference and deliver a speech to speak about issues such as immigration.
Hide Caption
11 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Then-President George W. Bush (right) is greeted by Jeb Bush on March 21, 2001, at Orlando International Airport in Orlando, Florida. President Bush was in Orlando to attend the American College of Cardiology Annual Convention.
Hide Caption
12 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush speaks during a press conference at the Carandolet Government Palace in Quito, January 18, 2006. Bush and a businessmen delegation were in a two-day visit to talk about a free trade agreement.
Hide Caption
13 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Bush speaks to reporters after meeting with the Florida State Cabinet at the Florida State Capitol Building November 16, 2000, in Tallahassee, Florida.
Hide Caption
14 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Then-President George W. Bush (left) and Jeb Bush (right), raise their arms onstage following a rally at the Florida State Fairgrounds, October 25, 2000, in Brandon, Florida.
Hide Caption
15 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Jeb Bush (left) and then-President George W. Bush stand with their arms around each other's shoulders at a rally in Miami, Florida, September 22, 2000.
Hide Caption
16 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Then-President George W. Bush (right) and Jeb Bush go through the line for strawberries during a stop at the Stawberry Festival March 12, 2000 in Plant City, Florida.
Hide Caption
17 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
The Bush family, (left to right) former U.S. President George W., former Florida Governor Jeb, former President George H.W. and his wife Barbara, watch play during the Foursomes matches September 25, 1999 at The Country Club in Brookline, Massachusetts the site of the 33rd Ryder Cup Matches.
Hide Caption
18 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Former President George H.W. Bush (second left), his wife Barbara Bush (left), their son Jeb Bush (center), then-first lady Hillary Clinton (second right), and former then-President Bill Clinton (right) look up to see the U.S. Army Golden Knights parachute team November 6, 1997 at the conclusion of the dedication ceremony of the George Bush Library in College Station, Texas.
Hide Caption
19 of 20
Jeb Bush's life 20 photos
Portrait of the Bush family in front of their Kennebunkport, Maine house August 24, 1986. Pictured, back row: Margaret holding daughter Marshall, Marvin Bush, Bill LeBlond. Pictured, front row: Neil Bush holding son Pierce, Sharon, George W. Bush holding daughter Barbara, Laura Bush holding daughter Jenna, Barbara Bush, George Bush, Sam LeBlond, Doro Bush Lebond, George P. (Jeb's son), Jeb Bush holding son Jebby, Columba Bush and Noelle Bush.
Hide Caption
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:34:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gigi Jordan Receives 18-Year Sentence for Killing Her Son - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNF2iYy1OVll4agSKIA7JsYny2hXbw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858212875&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/29/nyregion/gigi-jordan-receives-18-year-sentence-for-killing-her-son.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gay marriage canvassing success detailed, dashed as study's findings are ... - Los Angeles Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEp0l1j5bQpg2XdVhCEKfhMR2x5dA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778858233698&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.latimes.com/science/la-sci-sn-gay-canvassing-study-retracted-20150528-story.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Gay marriage canvassing success detailed, dashed as study's findings are doubted
Same-sex marriage
John Boal / European Pressphoto Agency
Katherine Struck of Frederick, Md., and Aman Ardalan of Annapolis, Md., shout support for gay marriage in front of the U.S.Supreme Court in April.
Katherine Struck of Frederick, Md., and Aman Ardalan of Annapolis, Md., shout support for gay marriage in front of the U.S.Supreme Court in April.
(John Boal / European Pressphoto Agency)
The journal Science retracts a study on the effect of gay marriage canvassers
Coauthor of discredited study on success of gay marriage canvassing plans to address criticism Friday
Laura Gardiner knew she was making a difference with her work.
As national mentoring coordinator at the Los Angeles LGBT Center's Leadership Lab, she and her colleagues had toiled to train 1,000 volunteers who had fanned out across Los Angeles and beyond, lobbying voters in precincts that had cast ballots against gay rights.
The idea was to push back against prejudice, house by house  and over the years, the group's internal evaluations indicated, the Leadership Lab had gotten quite good at changing voter minds.
When an independent study published in the prestigious journal Science confirmed the group's success, Gardiner had been thrilled.
Then, last week, a report was issued raising significant doubts about the study's validity.
It felt like being cheated on in a relationship, she said Thursday after the journal issued a formal retraction. Breakup songs have been cathartic this week.
8
The study had excited readers well beyond Gardiner's circle for its surprising conclusion that a single doorstep chat could prompt a skeptic to embrace marriage equality. It even reported a spillover effect that extended to household members who didn't talk to canvassers.
Although the findings contradicted a body of research that said firmly held opinions weren't easily swayed by lobbying and political advertising, they seemed to confirm an idea people were happy to embrace  that honest conversation and open minds could bring people together.
The study made headlines across the country and was featured on the public radio program This American Life. Its primary author, UCLA graduate student Michael LaCour, scored a job offer from Princeton University.
As LaCour prepared to decamp for New Jersey, he handed off the study to a team at Stanford and UC Berkeley.
That's how things began to unravel.
@Love Bullwhips Cracking, so that means you can't trust the MAJORITY of Americans, right? Unfortunate.
food for thought...
20
The new researchers were the first to suspect that something wasn't quite right with LaCour's data. They produced a report that persuaded LaCour's coauthor, Columbia University political scientist Donald Green, to request a retraction last week.
The editors of Science agreed, citing three reasons for retracting the study. They said LaCour lied about the way he recruited participants for his study and did not pay volunteers to complete online surveys, as he had claimed. They also said he lied about receiving research funding from the Williams Institute, the Ford Foundation and the Evelyn and Walter Haas Jr. Fund. LaCour's attorney has acknowledged both of these deceptions.
Perhaps most significantly, the editors said, LaCour has not produced the original survey data from which someone else could independently confirm the validity of the reported findings.
LaCour still maintains that his study is sound. He said he has been preparing a definitive response to his critics, which he plans to provide Friday.
I appreciate your patience, as I gather evidence and relevant information, he said Thursday in an email to The Times.
The whole tale began at the LGBT Center, said Leadership Lab director David Fleischer. He came up with the idea of the canvassing effort after voters approved Proposition 8, the 2008 ballot measure that repealed same-sex marriage in California.
We wanted to understand the problems and what it would take to remedy them, he said.
Canvassers started knocking on doors in the Los Angeles area in 2009, focusing on precincts that had voted in favor of the gay marriage ban by a margin of at least 2 to 1. By 2013, with more than 12,000 one-on-one conversations under their belts, group members were pretty sure they were changing voter minds.
Fleischer was eager to find out whether an independent analysis would prove they were right  and he knew just the person to call.
I had admired Don's work for years, he said, praising Green's careful studies that apply the rigorous methods used in medical research trials to the squishier realm of political science.
Green was intrigued, but he warned Fleischer that research would probably show the LGBT Center was having a smaller impact than it thought.
I said OK  I just want to know, Fleischer recalled.
Green made the introduction to LaCour. The men met in April 2013, Fleischer said, and soon started working together.
To assess whether the talks were changing minds, LaCour was charged with designing an online survey to gauge residents' opinions on marriage equality. Then canvassers knocked on their doors. In 20-minute conversations, they discussed the benefits of marriage and explained that gays and lesbians wanted to experience them too.
The study also included a placebo group of residents who were lobbied about recycling and a control group that wasn't lobbied about anything.
LaCour was supposed to administer follow-up surveys after the visits were complete.
The study results purported to show that after speaking with canvassers, people were more inclined to support same-sex marriage, an increase from 39% to 47%. One year later, support for gay marriage was 14 percentage points higher among people who were lobbied by a gay person and 3 percentage points higher among those who were canvassed by a straight person, the study said.
With LaCour wrapping things up at UCLA, the LGBT Center brought on David Broockman, a professor of political economy at Stanford, and Joshua Kalla, a political science graduate student at UC Berkeley, to carry on the research.
But as they made plans to track a forthcoming canvassing project the Leadership Lab is undertaking in Miami, they started noticing problems with the work. For instance, as they began their own pilot survey, they noticed that their response rate was notably lower than LaCour's.
When they sought additional advice from the survey firm that LaCour had reportedly employed, they quickly realized something was amiss.
The survey firm claimed they had no familiarity with the project and that they had never had an employee with the name of the staffer we were asking for, the researchers wrote. The firm also denied having the capabilities to perform many aspects of the recruitment procedures described.
Alarmed, Broockman and Kalla turned a skeptical eye toward LaCour's data and began investigating further with the help of Yale political scientist Peter Aronow. They soon realized that some of the paper's key data were identical to that of a different national survey conducted in 2012: the Cooperative Campaign Analysis Project. That discovery raised suspicions that the data might have been lifted from CCAP, the researchers wrote.
The researchers compiled their findings in a 26-page report and sent it to Green. When confronted with the findings, Green immediately sent a letter to Science requesting that the paper be retracted.
I am deeply embarrassed by this turn of events and apologize to the editors, reviewers, and readers of Science, Green wrote.
Fleischer and his staff learned of the investigations last week, he said. By Thursday, he had started informing volunteers too, who were busily preparing to head off for the Miami project.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:02:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama administration lays out controversial plans to protect sage grouse - Fox News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHwDhfz9q-Wx3RLhRMFW3DKCPoE2g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778855817209&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2015/05/28/rules-aim-to-protect-imperiled-bird-habitat-in-10-states/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Obama administration lays out controversial plans to protect sage grouse
Published May 28, 2015
Facebook 0 Twitter 0 Email Print
July 25, 2005: In this file photo, a sage grouse stands in a meadow at the Smith Creek Ranch, east of Fallon, Nev. (AP)
The Obama administration disclosed plans Thursday to preserve the habitat of the imperiled greater sage grouse in 10 Western states that would include placing limits on oil and natural gas drilling.
The proposal would be the federal government's biggest land-planning effort to date for conservation of a single species. The regulations would require oil and gas wells to be clustered in groups of a half-dozen or more to avoid scattering them across habitat of the greater sage grouse.
Drilling near breeding areas would be prohibited during mating season, and power lines would be moved away from prime habitat to avoid serving as perches for raptors that eat sage grouse.
The new measures would apply to federal lands in California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, North Dakota, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah and Wyoming.
The U.S. Bureau of Land Management expects to adopt the new measures by late summer.
The Interior Department said the move would make it less likely that the bird would end up listed as endangered.
Announcing the plans, Interior Secretary Sally Jewell acknowledged that some would argue the plans don't go far enough to protect the bird.
"But I would say these plans are grounded in sound science  the best available science," Jewell said at a news conference on a ranch near Cheyenne.
Sage grouse are chicken-sized birds that inhabit grass and sagebrush ecosystems in 11 states from California to the Dakotas. The rules would not apply to a relatively small area of habitat in Washington state. The bird's numbers have declined sharply in recent decades, and some environmentalists warn they are at risk of extinction.
The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service faces a court-ordered deadline of Sept. 30 to decide whether the greater sage grouse needs protection as a threatened or endangered species. Many Western lawmakers and representatives of the oil-and-gas and agriculture industries say a threatened or endangered listing would devastate the region's economy.
Congress voted late last year to withhold funding to implement any listing until September 2016. Other measures pending before U.S. lawmakers aim to postpone any federal listing for five years or more as states develop their own plans for conserving habitat.
Kathleen Sgamma,vice president of government and public affairs at Western Energy Alliance, a group representing oil and gas companies with operations in Western states, told The Wall Street Journal that while they support conservation of the sage grouse, they believe that efforts at state level are the best way to proceed.
Western Energy Alliance will protest all land use plan amendments that fail to conform with state plans, and will continue to support actions by Congress to delay these land use plans and a final listing decision, Sgamma told the Journal.
Republicans in Congress criticized the plans as federal overreach.
"This is just flat out wrong," Rep. Rob Bishop of Utah, chairman of the House Natural Resources Committee, said in a statement. "If the Administration really cares about the bird they will adopt the state plans as they originally said they would. The state plans work. This proposal is only about controlling land, not saving the bird."
"This announcement is not cooperation; it is not collaboration, and it is not a solution. It is just wrong," Bishop said.
But Jewell argued that Wyoming shows that sage grouse and energy development can co-exist. It is a top oil, natural gas and coal producer with a sage grouse conservation strategy being copied by other states and the federal government.
"There is no future for our economy if we don't take care of the sage grouse," said Wyoming Gov. Matt Mead, a Republican who took part in the announcement. "That's a fact. Some like it, some don't."
Several environmental groups welcomed the plans.
"The sage grouse's listing under the Endangered Species Act is an outcome from which no one stands to gain, least of all public lands sportsmen," said Land Tawney, executive director of Backcountry Hunters and Anglers.
In what some environmentalists view as an accommodation to industry, the rules would not seek to block development across sage grouse habitat. The government still intends to honor valid and existing rights to develop resources on that land, the Interior Department said.
Restrictions would vary between states. Wyoming, with as many as 500,000 greater sage grouse, is home to more of the birds than any other state by far.
The Associated Press contributed to this report.
Advertisement
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:16:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New clues, questions in Natalee Holloway case - CNN</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHLIsE3Pp9OcFzOCRTwywkfKOSqZQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778857302175&amp;ei=PcpnVei2Gon9atOrg8AI&amp;url=http://www.cnn.com/2015/05/28/world/natalee-holloway-new-tip/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CNN Leadership
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ad_bnr_atf_01" class="ad-ad_bnr_atf_01"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
New clues, questions in Natalee Holloway case
Updated 0215 GMT (0915 HKT) May 29, 2015
JUST WATCHED
Story highlights
Jurrin de Jong says he believes he saw Natalee Holloway shortly before she died
De Jong says he saw a man put a woman's body in foundation of construction site in Aruba
Aruban officials dismiss de Jong; hotel chain says construction wasn't underway at that time
Watch special coverage of Natalee Holloway's disappearance at 8 p.m. ET this week on "Anderson Cooper 360."
(CNN)
Ten years after Natalee Holloway went missing, a Dutch citizen says he knows where to find her. Prosecutors, however, aren't buying it.
Jurrin de Jong told CNN's Martin Savidge that the teen's body is buried in a crawl space at a Marriott vacation property in Aruba, and he believes he saw her in her final moments.
De Jong says he was near Marriott's Aruba Surf Club, then under construction, on the night of May 30, 2005, when he saw a young man chase a young woman through the construction site.
At first, he thought the two were being playful, but he says a short time later the man reappeared, carrying the woman in his arms. He says her body appeared limp.
"... He pulled (the woman) by the ankles inside the crawl space, stayed inside for a minute and then came out and closed the gap," de Jong said.
Even though de Jong suspected he had witnessed something serious, he says didn't go to the police because he was involved in "illegal activities" at the time.
Keeping his own crimes quiet -- for years
When news of Holloway's disappearance came out, de Jong put the pieces together, but for three years he says he stayed quiet, afraid he'd be indicted for his own crimes. He also says he was afraid of talking to police and facing retaliation from the people he worked for in his illegal activities, which he declined to specify.
De Jong says he had a change of heart after seeing a 2008 Dutch broadcast of an undercover interview with Joran van der Sloot, who was brought in for questioning in Holloway's disappearance but never charged. In that interview, van der Sloot said that Holloway died while the two were together and her body was dumped in the ocean.
De Jong says he got angry because he knew it was a lie and says he felt bad because he has a daughter close to Holloway's age. Van der Sloot later said he was lying in that interview.
De Jong then called Holloway's father, Dave Holloway, who has never given up hope of finding his daughter. Holloway had faced many false leads and hoaxes before and wrote de Jong off.
Holloway's father opens up about new lead
'Running out of possibilities'
"I was running out of possibilities," de Jong said. "I tried to convince the head prosecutor, the parents, then I tried to convince the other head prosecutor, but he didn't listen."
That's when de Jong attempted what he called "Mission Impossible."
JUST WATCHED
Possible new lead in Natalee Holloway case 08:54
PLAY VIDEO
The site where de Jong says Holloway is buried now rests under the high-rise Marriott Aruba Surf Club resort, in an area called the Spyglass Tower.  De Jong bought an electric drill with a diamond tip and went to Aruba to investigate the site. He says he carefully planned a scheme to drill a hole through the hotel floor, but his efforts to take a look in the tower's foundations ultimately failed.
Next, de Jong turned to local newspapers. But before long, the new lead hit a snag -- on the night Holloway disappeared, officials say construction of the Spyglass Tower hadn't started.
Aruba's chief prosecutor, Eric Olthof, says he spent weeks investigating de Jong's assertions, including a 2010 sworn statement to police.
When asked about what construction was underway on May 30, 2005, Olthof says Marriott officials said there was no construction at the spot de Jong pointed out.
"It's evident now the story of Mr. de Jong can't be true, so that's a closed book," Oltholf told CNN.
Enter Google Earth ...
On the other hand, some signs complicate Marriott's official time line of the construction of Spyglass Tower. A satellite image from Google Earth taken in June 2005, just a few weeks after Natalee Holloway disappeared, shows what appears to be the blurry outlines of structures that could resemble a construction site.
Holloway's father says he remembers the site from the day after his daughter's disappearance. "I can tell you for a fact. I was there on June 1, and there was definitely construction in that area," he says.
Holloway says he has information that construction began in February, but he was not clear on how he knows. Natalee Holloway was last seen on May 30, 2005.
CNN's Savidge received this statement from Jeff Flaherty of global corporate relations at Marriott International Inc.: "Mr. de Jong has contacted Marriott in the past and each time we have suggested to Mr. de Jong that he present his account of the matter to the authorities.  As we have done all along, we cooperate fully with the authorities whenever they are conducting an official investigation."
For his part, de Jong says he believes authorities are dragging their feet.
"It's the inconvenient truth. It would damage the image of Aruba as one happy island," he says.
Oltholf won't say that de Jong is lying, but says his statement can't be true.
"It's the statement of the management of the Marriott that at that time, at that place, there was no construction. When there's no construction, Natalee Holloway can't be buried in the crawl space under the foundation," he said.
And, he added, that Marriott has provided proof.
"I think they're not wrong because they can prove it with some photographs and some other material. And I think they are right with what they are saying.  And Mr. de Jong can't prove it," said Olthof.
A high school graduation trip
Holloway was on a high school graduation trip when she vanished. The 18-year-old from Alabama was last seen leaving a bar with three young men, two brothers and van der Sloot, then 17. Van der Sloot has never been charged in Holloway's disappearance. He says he was with Holloway that night, but left her on the beach, alone.
In 2012, he pleaded guilty to the 2010 murder of Stephany Flores in Peru. Flores was killed five years to the day Holloway disappeared. Van der Sloot is serving a 28-year prison sentence. He is expected to be extradited to the United States after his release.
What does he think about de Jong's claim that he saw him that night, in 2005?   Through his attorney, van der Sloot did not call de Jong a liar, but told CNN's Savidge he was a drug dealer and is only out for money.
De Jong denies he ever asked for money, and laughs off the accusation, saying van der Sloot's angry because he's scared.
"I think he's desperate. I mean the only reason why he does that is that he's afraid that people go to believe me, " he said.
In the United States, he's been indicted on federal charges of extortion and wire fraud. American authorities accuse him of extorting money from Holloway's mother by offering bogus information about her daughter's disappearance.
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  Natalee Holloway disappeared while on a high school graduation trip to Aruba. She was last seen alive on May 30, 2005.
Hide Caption
1 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  An Alabama judge declared Holloway legally dead in 2012.
Hide Caption
2 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  A friend of Natalee Holloway signs a "wall of hope" erected in the weeks after the Alabama teen went missing. Media from all around the world covered Holloway's disappearance.
Hide Caption
3 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  A diver from Florida State University and volunteers with Texas EquuSearch search the waters near the California Lighthouse in Aruba in July 2005.
Hide Caption
4 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  Brothers Satish and Deepak Kalpoe leave jail after being freed in the Holloway case on July 4, 2005. The brothers, along with Joran van der Sloot, were seen with Holloway on the night she went missing. The three were arrested and released in 2005 in connection with the case, then arrested a second time in 2007 after Aruba's then-chief prosecutor Hans Mos said he had received new evidence in the case. Van der Sloot, then attending college in the Netherlands, was brought back to Aruba. But judges ruled the new evidence was not enough to keep them in custody.
Hide Caption
5 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  Joran van der Sloot, center, arrives at the hospital for DNA tests in July 2005, Today, van der Sloot is in prison in Peru after being convicted of murdering Stephany Flores in 2010.
Hide Caption
6 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  Van der Sloot confessed to the murder of Stephany Flores. He is expected to be extradited to the U.S. after he serves his 28-year murder sentence. In the United States, he's been indicted on federal charges of extortion and wire fraud.
Hide Caption
7 of 8
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway 8 photos
10 years after the disappearance of Natalee Holloway  Beth Holloway, mother of Natalee, met with van der Sloot in prison in 2010. The case remains unsolved.
Hide Caption
8 of 8
CNN's Martin Savidge and Tristan Smith interviewed Jurrin de Jong in Amsterdam, Netherlands. They've also been in Aruba to examine his allegations further.
&lt;div id="ad_rect_atf_01" class="ad-ad_rect_atf_01"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
More from World
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
