<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Google">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:17:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chris Christie Ally Expected to Plead Guilty in George Washington Bridge Lane ... - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEajQBl0jSgRd25FZ8yAhWoBsJlRQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778823477090&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/02/nyregion/christie-ally-expected-to-plead-guilty-in-george-washington-bridge-lane-closing-case.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:53:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scant Details From Gray Death as Baltimore Protests Continue - ABC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGuXBnEdpXEKTexnnaSRogI1dZwag&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778817075204&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/scant-details-gray-death-baltimore-protests-continue-30722120</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Scant Details From Gray Death as Baltimore Protests Continue
BALTIMORE  May 1, 2015, 8:42 AM ET
By CURT ANDERSON and DAVID DISHNEAU Associated Press
Authorities' refusal to provide more than a few sketchy details about the Freddie Gray investigation is fueling suspicion and mistrust as a weekend of protest rallies looms.
The secrecy may be legally appropriate, but many in Baltimore were finding it hard to be patient Thursday when police took no questions at a news conference about the criminal investigation findings they turned over to the state's attorney's office.
Nearly two weeks after Gray's death, the public still doesn't know much more than it did on Day One. The central question  what caused his fatal spinal cord injury while he was in police custody earlier this month  remains a mystery.
"The transparency is just not there," the Rev. Cortly "C.D." Witherspoon said after Police Commissioner Anthony Batts refused to answer any questions Thursday.
Batts said a 10 p.m. curfew for all residents and a state of emergency declared by Maryland Gov. Larry Hogan would remain in effect through Sunday. The curfew went into effect for the third night Thursday with no major incidents.
"We have two very large marches that are going to take place on the weekend," Batts told a news conference Thursday evening. "We have a lot more that are popping up by the minute."
Protesters were planning large demonstrations in Baltimore and around the country Friday, which is May Day , a date traditionally used to champion labor issues but which has expanded over the years to include such causes as women's and immigrant rights. This year, many planned to add civil rights and the slogan "black and brown lives matter."
Friday also was the day protesters initially expected police to release information about their investigation. Batts said the report was delivered a day ahead of time to State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby, and that from now on, any questions should go to her.
Mosby released no information; instead she issued a statement asking "for the public to remain patient and peaceful and to trust the process of the justice system."
A coalition of news media organizations, including The Associated Press, sent a letter Thursday evening to the Baltimore Police Department seeking the immediate release of the report as information that would serve the public interest.
With rumors flying about how Gray's spine was "80 percent severed," as his family's lawyer Billy Murphy put it, police did release a new piece of information Thursday, but it served mostly to raise more questions about how truthful the six suspended officers have been with investigators.
Deputy Commissioner Kevin Davis said investigators discovered a security camera recording showing that the police van carrying Gray had made a previously undisclosed, second stop, after the 25-year-old black man was put in leg irons and before the van driver made a third stop and called for help to check on his condition. The van then made a fourth stop, to pick up another passenger, before Gray arrived at the police station with the fatal spinal-cord injury that left him unresponsive.
Grocery store owner Jung Hyun Hwang told The Associated Press that officers made a copy last week of the video from his store. He said the only other copy was stolen, along with his video equipment, by looters Monday night. He said he didn't see the recording.
Police have said Gray was obviously injured and asking for medical help when he was hoisted into the van on April 12 and unresponsive on arrival at the station. He died in a hospital after a week in a coma.
Page
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:59:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chicago bid selected for Obama presidential library: reports - MarketWatch</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHb47Cnaxf1TS1VqTtxppfQxsDlmg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778824129336&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.marketwatch.com/story/chicago-bid-selected-for-obama-presidential-library-reports-2015-05-01</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>TimRostan
Managing editor
The Obama presidential library was Chicagos to lose, and, by many accounts, it nearly did just that. In the end, however, it appears the first ladys hometown and the presidents adoptive political base, and the university that once employed them both, carried the day.
The University of Chicago bid to host the institution has been selected, according to various national and local media reports, over local rival the University of Illinois at Chicago as well as Columbia University in New York, President Obamas undergraduate alma mater (his law degree is from Harvard), and the University of Hawaii, in the state where he spent much of his youth. Columbia was widely viewed in recent months as the U. of C.s chief rival, and as the likeliest to edge it out.
See: Obama foundation trims field for presidential library to four prospects
The University of Chicago had put forth two sites, both requiring the requisition of Chicago Park District land  a delicate matter that necessitated the direct intervention of Rahm Emanuel, the Chicago mayor who previously served as Obamas chief of staff  and it remains unclear, according to the Chicago Tribune, on which of those sites the library is to be constructed.
Dont miss: Changing of guard at Willis Tower highlights turbulent period for Chicago real estate
Emanuel is set to formally announce Chicagos selection in the coming weeks, the New York Times reported. The Chicago Tribune reported that Martin Nesbitt, the personal friend of the Obamas who heads the Barack Obama Foundation, declined to comment Thursday evening on a decisions having been made.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:52:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PNG earthquake: Magnitude-6.8 earthquake strikes off Papua New Guinea ... - ABC Online</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEX93mxAs7j8VRWWFTXS0BWn5SnWQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778824679903&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.abc.net.au/news/2015-05-01/papua-new-guinea-hit-by-earthquake-and-aftershock/6439008</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PNG earthquake: Magnitude-6.8 earthquake strikes off Papua New Guinea, USGS says
Updated May 01, 2015 21:50:30
Map: Papua New Guinea
A magnitude-6.8 earthquake has struck off Papua New Guinea, 106 kilometres south-southwest of the town of Kokopo, the US Geological Survey says.
The earthquake struck at 6:06pm (AEST), 693 kilometres north-east of the capital Port Moresby, in the New Britain region at a depth of 57 kilometres.
It was followed by a magnitude-7.1 aftershock, the USGS said.
The USGS had initially reported the earthquake's magnitude at 6.7 with a depth of 53 kilometres, but later revised its strength.
There were no tsunami warnings, the Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre said.
Papua New Guinea was struck by another magnitude-6.7 quake yesterday but there were no reports of serious damage.
"This is the second earthquake that has occurred in that region over the last two days," co-director of the Joint Australian Tsunami Warning Centre Daniel Jaksa said.
"The previous one was about 10 kilometres to the southeast of this particular epicentre. It's a very uninhabited region off the island of New Britain."
New Britain, the largest island of the Bismarck Archipelago, is east of mainland New Guinea and has a population of about 500,000 people.
The island lies on the 4,000-kilometre long Pacific Australia plate, which forms part of the "Ring of Fire," a hotspot for seismic activity due to friction between tectonic plates.
Mr Jaksa said earthquakes of similar magnitudes that occur within 24 hours were not common, and cautioned there was a possibility the tremors could be foreshocks ahead of a bigger seismic event.
"The probabilities of another earthquake in that region actually increases with an event like this, but it's ... one of the most active earthquake zones in the world," he said.
"Unfortunately this is completely unpredictable. Certainly the potential is there for a larger event to occur but a lot of the time, it doesn't."
Reuters/AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:55:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesla Ventures Into Solar Power Storage for Home and Business - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGkdwiLSIAVBEoaZyw3Yl2uqlw2Tw&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778822703937&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/01/business/energy-environment/with-new-factory-tesla-ventures-into-solar-power-storage-for-home-and-business.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:58:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First Draft | Today in Politics: Time and Distance Might Lessen Familiar Argument ... - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNH3CK-Ejl2xsY6EaVl6d2iLFUUUMg&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778824974635&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/05/01/today-in-politics-time-and-distance-might-lessen-familiar-argument-against-clinton/</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:43:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NFL Draft Day: Jameis Winston Goes to Tampa Bay Buccaneers as No. 1 NFL ... - ABC News</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHkVYT8k6wgPVNE-1PDVLaN77oywA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778824731182&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://abcnews.go.com/Sports/nfl-draft-day-jameis-winston-prepares-chapter/story?id%3D30710801</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jameis Winston Rape Accuser Speaks Out in Film
Before the draft, Winston had told ESPN , "Anyone that wants to take that chance on me ... they're going to be lucky."
The NFL Players Association told ABC News today that Winston could make roughly $24 million for his first four years. On April 17, Nike announced that it had signed Winston.
"The ultimate goal is to win the Super Bowl ," said ESPN football analyst Todd McShay. "And he looks like he's capable of winning a Super Bowl."
But Winston had said he'd be at home in Alabama during the draft, surrounded by his family. He posted on Instagram today, thanking his supporters.
La familia be4 it all started I just want to thank everyone who help raise me and get the opportunity to become a professional athlete
La familia be4 it all started I just want to thank everyone who help raise me and get the opportunity to become a professional athlete
A photo posted by Jameis Winston (@jaboowins5) on Apr 30, 2015 at 10:05am PDT
Still, though, the 21-year-old All-American athlete, known for his arm strength and agility on the gridiron, continues to be hounded by critics and skeptics because of some headline-grabbing controversies off the field.
At Florida State in 2012, Winston was accused of rape. He maintained that the sex was consensual. No charges were filed in the case, with Florida State Attorney Willie Meggs citing insufficient evidence. Winston was also cleared in a university code of conduct hearing. A day before Nike made the announcement, his accuser filed a civil suit against both him and the university. She also spoke out in a documentary titled "The Hunting Ground."
Winston was also sidelined for making lewd comments and received a civil citation in 2014 for allegedly stealing $32 worth of seafood from a Florida grocery store. He said that was a mistake.
"All my mistakes make me a better person," he told ESPN.
Today, his agent, Greg Genske, told ABC News in a statement that with the NFL draft today, Winston "enthusiastically begins a new chapter of his life and is grateful for the support of his family and friends, coaches, teammates, teachers and legions of fans."
Join the Discussion
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:03:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chelsea Clinton in Nairobi, Kenya, Says Holding Baby Reminds of Own Child - NBCNews.com</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFpPv8sZL566FMGpNXAE3s6dOZ9fQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778824449253&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/chelsea-clinton-nairobi-kenya-says-holding-baby-reminds-own-child-n351756</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:42:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boko Haram and the Childrens Crusade - Daily Beast</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNHxXHEsplVB3KhAqoNSbhmwxof7_A&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778823851137&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2015/05/01/boko-haram-and-the-children-s-crusade.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>05.01.155:15 AM ET
Boko Haram and the Childrens Crusade
Generations of young Nigerians in the northeast of their country are being shaped by the terrors of the war.
LAGOS  I was asked to kill my parents on the day I was captured, said 16-year-old Babagana, a former Boko Haram child slave. "I had no courage, so they killed them in front of me.
That is how Boko Haram operates, he told me when I saw him in March in Borno State. They first take out your parents so you have no one else to fall back to.
This may be the most tragic fact about the fight raging in northeast Nigeria: It is a war waged by children against children. Minors make up nearly a quarter of Boko Harams soldiers. Some recruits are as young as 10 and are inducted by raids on villages. They are brutalized and forced to commit atrocities on fellow kidnap victims and even on their own families. Militants kill children who attempt to escape from captivity.
Recently village militias have been enlisting young kids to fight against Boko Haram, as well. And the plague is spreading.
This week, the Nigerian army rescued almost 300 girls and women taken captive by Boko Haram, and even though they were not the Chibok schoolgirls who were kidnapped more than a year ago now, there was a great sense of pride and relief that the Nigerian Army was able to do this.
But many stories have not had such happy endings.
Last month the Chadian Army announced that it had rescued 43 children held by Boko Haram in Damask, Borno State. All had been soldiers in the Boko Haram ranks, but they were not from Nigeria.
The news of the rescue had at first given hope to local people. In March, militants abducted over 400 women and children from the same town in Borno, and I spoke with Bukkar Hassan, who had two sisters among the 400 kidnapped. He was set to travel to Damask, thinking the girls could be among the rescued kids only to be told that the lucky children were all of Chadian origin. Hassan began to weep.
For kids living in a state of constant fear, violence becomes a way of life and the psychological trauma is incalculable.
There are dramatic rates of acute malnutrition among the displaced children in Nigeria: 35 percent in some areas.
Fearing abduction, streams of children, often with parents in tow, leave their homes every night and walk for hours from surrounding villages to reach the relative safety of major towns, only to trek their way home again by daybreak.
Were seeing a high level of suffering, says Musa Kubo, a senior government official in Nigerias northeastern Borno State. Thousands of people in the northeast, mostly children, are just struggling to survive.
Since the insurgency began in 2009, thousands of children have been abducted to work as child soldiers and porters, or to serve as wives of rebels and bear their children, like those hundreds of girls taken from Chibok school just a year ago. The numbers have soared, with nearly a thousand children abducted in the past 18 months alone.
The Nigerian military, with help from troops from Chad, Cameroon and Niger, has claimed major gains against the Islamists in recent weeks, recapturing many towns held by the insurgents, and the newly elected Nigerian President Muhammadu Buhari is a military man committed to eradicating the insurgency .
But the impact of the fighting and violence has caused the humanitarian situation in the area to deteriorate rapidly over the past year. And the contrast between the embattled northeast and the prosperous southern regions of the country grows more extreme all the time.
The bustling commercial capital of Lagos, located in the south, exemplifies Nigerias transformation from a country plagued by economic decay to prosperity. With an average GDP growth of more than 6 percent over the past 10 years, Nigeria can come across as a compelling story of hope for other African nations.
But the 6-year-old uprising by Boko Haram militants, aiming to create a hardline Islamic state, has killed more than 13,000 people since 2009 and forced some 1.5 million othershalf of them childrento flee to squalid and overcrowded camps to escape wanton attacks and killings. The number of internally displaced persons has almost tripled since 2012. Attacks on soft civilian targets continue, carried out by child soldiers much younger than their victims.
The violence has, among other things, cut millions of households off from access to their farms, causing a surge in food insecurity. We estimate that only about 20 percent of agricultural land in Borno State (the hardest-hit area) was harvested last season, U.N. Assistant Secretary General Robert Piper told AFP in an interview, pointing out that that leaves a massive deficit.
There are dramatic rates of acute malnutrition among the displaced children in Nigeria. In some areas, including Maiduguri, the capital of Borno State, malnutrition rates as high as 35 percent have been recorded among children.
Fear of militant attacks badly hit the planting season for 2014, threatening to aggravate the already severe food shortages in the coming months. In the same vein, health facilities barely function as stocks run out and health workers flee to escape Boko Haram attacks.
During one peak of conflict in the region, a high number of deaths of children were caused by bacterial infection. Children suffer from lack of clean water and can quickly contract with bacterial diseases that threaten their lives. In Borno State anoutbreak of cholerawas declared last September. In under a month, there have been 4,500 cases and 70 deaths from the disease in Maiduguri, where the number of cases continues to rise.
But even as the humanitarian needs increase, the security situation is making it far more difficult for aid workers to get in.
Hoping to address some of these challenges,UNICEF has launched a new social media campaign#BringBackOurChildhoodto highlight the plight of the over 800,000 young people who are missing out on their childhoods as a result of the conflict.
To tell the stories of the children who have fled the violence, UNICEF and leading Snapchat artists will share images based on drawings from children in Nigeria, Chad, Niger and Cameroon, UNICEF said in a media release. The artwork reflects what children miss from home and the emotional wounds and suffering they have endured, including seeing their parents and siblings killed, tortured or abducted.
The violence wracking Africas most populous country is meanwhile sending shockwaves through the entire region.
Militants have been increasingly carrying out cross-border attacks into Cameroon, Niger, and Chad, which are also struggling to host around 200,000 Nigerian refugees.
In addition, around 100,000 Cameroonians have been displaced further inland to get away from the volatile border areas.
Despite the gravity of the humanitarian situation, less than 20 percent of the $93 million requested by the U.N. for Nigeria in 2014 was received.
This year, the organization is asking donors to cough up $100 million for its 2015 operations in the country, a figure that represents only a tenth of the countrys humanitarian need, which is estimated at $1 billion.
The government will have to foot most of that bill, said Piper, who coordinates the U.N.s humanitarian work in Africas Sahel region. Nigeria [Africas largest oil producer] is generally perceived as relatively prosperous, and it is hard to raise funds for.
Unfortunately, the success story that Nigeria represents in the minds of the worlds economic policy makers presents a jarring contrast with the tragedy of conflict in the northeast that shows few signs of abating despite improved military efforts against Boko Haram.
As the country and its international allies continue to search for ways of reaching thousands of displaced persons in the troubled region, it remains to be seen how much can be done to protect children from grave violence and conscription.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:49:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>US Said to Give Warren Weinstein's Family Ransom Advice - New York Times</title>
        <Link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNF3CYhWxzwIJMJIxuKiTI0Y3iKnBA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52778823451715&amp;ei=EXtDVZjRDKnaa-iDgagG&amp;url=http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/01/world/asia/us-said-to-give-warren-weinsteins-family-ransom-advice.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
