<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:36:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece To Consider Bank Closures And Capital Controls On Monday</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a4a3b7/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Cgreece0Edebt0Ecrisis0Ecapital0Econtrols0In0I76813440Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS/FRANKFURT, June 28 (Reuters) - Greece said it may impose capital controls and keep its banks shut on Monday after creditors refused to extend the country's bailout and savers queued to withdraw cash, taking Athens' standoff with the European Union and the International Monetary Fund to a dangerous new level.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece To Consider Bank Closures And Capital Controls On Monday
Reuters
Updated:
11 minutes ago
ATHENS, GREECE - JUNE 27:  Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a parliamentary session in Athens, Greece June 28, 2015 . Greece's fraught bailout talks with its creditors took a dramatic turn early Saturday, with the radical left government announcing a referendum in just over a week on the latest proposed deal . (Photo by Milos Bicanski/Getty Images) | Milos Bicanski via Getty Images
reddit
ATHENS/FRANKFURT, June 28 (Reuters) - Greece said it may impose capital controls and keep its banks shut on Monday after creditors refused to extend the country's bailout and savers queued to withdraw cash, taking Athens' standoff with the European Union and the International Monetary Fund to a dangerous new level.
Greece's banks, kept afloat by emergency central bank funding, are on the front line as Athens moves towards defaulting on a 1.6 billion euros payment due to the IMF on Tuesday.
The European Central Bank said it would not raise the level of emergency funding, adding to the pressure on Greece's banks which have been surviving for the past few weeks on frequent incremental increases to the funding lifeline
Amid political drama in Greece, where a clear majority wants to remain inside the euro, the next few days present a major challenge to the integrity of a 16-year-old currency bloc.
"This is a matter that we'll have to work overnight on with the appropriate authorities both here in Greece and in Frankfurt," Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis said of bank closures and capital controls. He was speaking to BBC radio.
The finance ministry later issued a statement saying capital controls were not the government's preference and were not consistent with monetary union.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis leaves the prime minister's office in Athens on June 28, 2015. (ARIS MESSINIS/AFP/Getty Images)
Greece's left-wing Syriza government had been negotiating a deal to release funding in time for its IMF payment. Then suddenly, in the early hours of Saturday, Prime Minster Alexis Tspiras asked for extra time to enable Greeks to vote in a referendum on the terms of the deal.
Creditors flatly turned down this request, leaving little option for Greece but to default, piling further pressure on the banking system.
Long lines formed outside many ATMs on Sunday, including some of 40 to 50 people outside some in central Athens. The German foreign ministry issued a travel warning advising tourists heading to Greece to take plenty of cash to avoid possible problems with local banks.
The Bank of Greece said it was making "huge efforts" to ensure the machines remained stocked.
The ECB said in a statement on Sunday it was keeping its emergency liquidity at current levels but was monitoring the situation and stood ready "to reconsider its decision."
There is growing opposition in some European countries to extending the ECB's funding line.
In economic powerhouse Germany, other southern states that have suffered austerity in return for EU cash and poor eastern countries with living standards much lower than Greece's, many voters and politicians have run out of patience.
If Greece were to leave the euro zone, the ECB's funding line, which is a form of overdraft with euro zone's central bank system, would fall to the bloc's other members to pay.
The head of Germany's Bundesbank has attacked the use of the ECB's funding line and speaking on German television on Saturday, Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble put a question mark over the solvency of Greek banks - a key condition to qualify to receive such finance.
"The ECB has always said that as long as Greek banks are solvent, then emergency loans, the ELA, can be granted," he said.
"And now there is naturally a new situation that because of the developments the liquidity and solvency of Greek banks, or some Greek banks, could be in doubt."
German Chancellor Angela Merkel has invited leaders of all the major German parties to a meeting in Berlin on Monday to discuss the crisis.
Tourists walks past a graffiti made by street artist N_Grams that read ''NO'' in German but also ''YES, IN'' in Greek language in Athens, on Sunday, June 28, 2015. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
DEAL STILL POSSIBLE
The 18 other countries sharing the euro countries have blamed Greece for breaking off negotiations and pledged to do whatever it takes to stabilize the common currency area.
But some officials said there was still time to return to the negotiating table.
French Prime Minister Manuel Valls on Sunday urged the Greeks to continue talks, warning that the country's membership of the euro was at stake.
"A deal is still possible, I invite the Greek government to come back to the negotiation table," Valls told Europe 1, Le Monde and iTELE in a joint interview. "I cannot resign myself to Greece leaving the euro zone ... We must find a solution."
International Monetary Fund boss Christine Lagarde told the BBC that there was still time for the Greek government to change course.
She also said that if the July 5 vote produced "a resounding yes" to remain in the euro and fix the Greek economy then the creditors would be willing to make an effort.
Pro-European Greek opposition parties have united in condemning the decision to call the referendum. There was rising speculation that Tsipras' left-wing government may have to resign if voters back the bailout in the referendum.
The offer from creditors requires Greece to cut pensions and raise taxes in ways that Tsipras has long argued would deepen one of the worst economic crises of modern times in a country where a quarter of the workforce is already unemployed.
European Council President Donald Tusk said on Sunday he was in contact with all the governments of the euro zone to ensure Greece remained in the single currency.   (Editing by Alastair Macdonald and Janet McBride)
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:58:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran, World Powers Plan To Keep Nuclear Talks Going Beyond June 30 Deadline, Official Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a42544/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0Eextended0In0I76812180Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>By Parisa Hafezi and John Irish</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran, World Powers Plan To Keep Nuclear Talks Going Beyond June 30 Deadline, Official Says
Reuters
Updated:
13 minutes ago
A view of the Palais Coburg Hotel, the venue of the nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria on June 28, 2015. Talks between Iran and major powers on finalising a historic nuclear deal will go beyond the June 30 deadline, a spokesman for the Iranian delegation in talks in Vienna said Sunday. AFP PHOTO / CHRISTIAN BRUNA        (Photo credit should read CHRISTIAN BRUNA/AFP/Getty Images) | CHRISTIAN BRUNA via Getty Images
reddit
By Parisa Hafezi and John Irish
VIENNA, June 28 (Reuters) - The six world powers seeking to negotiate an historic agreement with Iran to curb its nuclear program plan to carry on negotiating beyond a Tuesday deadline, a senior U.S. official said on Sunday.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif was to leave Vienna and return to Tehran for consultations with the country's leadership on the state of negotiations, Iran said.
Officials from both sides said big differences still remained.
European Union foreign policy chief Frederica Mogherini said earlier on Sunday it was not impossible to get an accord by the self-imposed deadline but that a few extra days may be needed.
Foreign ministers from the negotiating countries were gathering in Vienna on Sunday to assess where the talks stood.  They expected them to spill over into July.
"Zarif will return to Tehran tonight and will come back to Vienna tomorrow," Iran's Tasnim news agency said, citing an unnamed Iranian official.
An Iranian official told Reuters that Zarif would "consult with the leadership" over the talks in Vienna.
The U.S. official, who spoke to reporters on condition of anonymity, said Washington was not troubled by Zarif's decision to return to Tehran overnight, saying it was always expected that ministers would come and go from Vienna as the talks heated up.
The negotiations aim to limit Tehran's nuclear program in exchange for a lifting of U.S., European Union and United Nations sanctions on Tehran.
The United States, Israel and some Western nations fear that Iran has been trying to develop a nuclear weapons capability, but Tehran says its program is for peaceful purposes only.
The main differences are on the pace and timing of sanctions relief for Iran and on the nature of monitoring mechanisms to ensure Tehran does not cheat on any agreement.
U.S. and European negotiators also want to ensure there is a mechanism for restoring sanctions if Tehran fails to meet its commitments under any future accord.
In November, the seven nations involved in the talks set a late March deadline for a framework agreement, which they ultimately reached on April 2, and a June 30 deadline for a comprehensive deal.
Highlighting how much work remains, British Foreign Minister Philip Hammond said on arrival in Vienna that major challenges remained, including on the parameters already agreed in April.
"There are a number of different areas where we still have major differences of interpretation in detailing what was agreed in Lausanne)," Hammond told reporters.
"There is going to have to be some give or take if we are to get this done in the next few days," he said. "No deal is better than a bad deal."
In addition to Britain, Iran and the United States, the talks include China, France, Germany and Russia.
Speaking after a cabinet meeting in Jerusalem, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said too many concessions were being made to Tehran.
"We see before our very eyes a stark retreat from the red lines that the world powers set themselves only recently, and publicly," said Netanyahu, whose country is generally believed to have the Middle East's only nuclear arsenal.
"There is no reason to hasten into signing this bad deal, which is getting worse by the day."
(Additional reporting by Louis Charbonneau, Arshad Mohammed and Shadia Nasralla and Dan Williams in Jerusalem; Editing by Angus MacSwan)
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French Attack Suspect Admits To Killing His Boss: Report</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a42546/sc/8/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Cfrench0Ebeheading0Eterror0Eattack0In0I7680A9180Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS, June 28 (Reuters) - The suspected Islamist militant held over an attack against a French chemical plant has admitted killing his boss, a source close to the investigation said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>French Attack Suspect Admits To Killing His Boss: Report
Reuters
Updated:
12 minutes ago
This picture shows a general view of US-owned Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier on June 27, 2015 a day after a suspected Islamist attack on the factory.  French police interrogated a suspected Islamist as they tried to piece together an attack in which the man put his boss's severed head on display in the second jihadist attack to hit France in six months. Prime Minister Manuel Valls, who rushed home from an official trip to South America, warned that France faced more attacks and  | PHILIPPE DESMAZES via Getty Images
reddit
(Adds detals, background, Valls comment)
PARIS, June 28 (Reuters) - The suspected Islamist militant  held over an attack against a French chemical plant has admitted  killing his boss, a source close to the investigation said on  Sunday.
Yassin Salhi, 35, told detectives he had killed Herve  Cornara in a parking area before arriving at the plant in Saint  Quentin-Fallavier, 30 km (20 miles) south of Lyon, where he  attempted to cause an explosion on Friday, the source told  Reuters.
Police found the 54-year-old victim's decapitated body and  head, framed by Islamic inscriptions, at the plant owned by U.S.  group Air Products. There were no other casualties.
Examination of one of Salhi's mobile phones revealed that he  took a "selfie" with the severed head before his arrest and sent  the image via a messaging application to a Canadian phone  number. Canadian police are now investigating.
According to French media reports, Salhi told police he had  clashed with his boss as well as his own wife before the  killing. One of their work colleagues, quoted on the website of  television station i-Tele, also said the two men had argued days  earlier after Salhi dropped a pallet of fragile equipment.
The suspect, whose wife and sister are also being  questioned, is known to have associated with hardline Islamists  over more than a decade and had previously been flagged by  French security services as a potential risk.
Earlier on Sunday, French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said  the government was increasing resources in law enforcement and  domestic intelligence to combat Islamic extremism.
"We cannot lose this war, because it is essentially a war of  civilisation," Valls said in an interview broadcast on Europe 1  radio and i-Tele. "It is our society, our civilisation and our  values that we must defend."     (Reporting by Gregory Blachier, Writing by Laurence Frost,;  Editing by Angus MacSwan)
Also on HuffPost:


Demonstrators hold a banner reading "For democracy, for equality, for freedoms. Let us fight all fascism!" during a demonstration in solidarity with the victims of terrorist attacks at the Old-Port of Marseille, southern France, Jan. 10, 2015.
A sign on the Arc de Triomphe reads "Paris is Charlie" in solidarity with the victims of the shooting at the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo in Paris, France, Jan. 10, 2015.
Thousands of people attend  a demonstration in solidarity with the victims of terrorist attacks at the Old-Port of Marseille, Jan. 10, 2015.
People gather to pay to pay tribute to victims of the attack on the French satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo, at JFK Plaza in Philadelphia, Jan. 9, 2015.
Tunisians hold up old copies of Charlie Hebdo on Bourguiba Avenue in Tunis during a gathering in solidarity with those killed in the attack on Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 9, 2015.
People holding a banner reading "I am Charlie", take part to silent walk for victims of the shooting at the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 10, 2015, in Nice, southeastern France.
Demonstrators hold a banner reading "Charlie is great, barbarism will not erase talent" during a demonstration in solidarity with the victims of terrorist attacks at the Old-Port of Marseille, southern France, Jan. 10, 2015.
People hold "Je Suis Charlie" signs at a rally in solidarity with victims of the terrorist attacks in Paris, Jan. 10, 2015.
Nice soccer team and Lorient soccer team observe a minute of silence for the victims of the shooting at the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 10, 2015, in Nice stadium, southeastern France.
A tarp reading 'Je suis Charlie' is seen in the front of the Palais de Tokyo on January 10, 2015 in Paris, France.
Lille's supporters hold scarves as they observe a minute of silence in tribute to the victims of three days of terror before the French L1 football match at Pierre Mauroy stadium in Villeneuve-d'Ascq, northern France, on Jan. 10, 2015.
Nepalese journalists participate in a candlelight vigil in solidarity with victims of the attack on French satirical paper Charlie Hebdo, in Kathmandu, Nepal, Friday, Jan. 9, 2015.
Members of Paraguay's French community hold sheets of paper reading in French; "I am Charlie" during a tribute to victims of the terrorist attack against the French satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo, in Asuncion, Paraguay, Jan. 10, 2015.
People make a cross with pencils during a protest in solidarity with those killed in the attack on Charlie Hebdo, in Niteroi, Brazil, Jan. 8, 2015.
Egyptians hold candles in downtown Cairo in solidarity with the victims of the attack on Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 9, 2015.
School students pray by a sand sculpture made by Narayan Sahu as tribute to victims of the attack on French satirical paper Charlie Hebdo, at Juhu beach in Mumbai, India, Jan. 9, 2015.
People makes a cross with pencils, while others hold signs that read in French "Rio is Charlie," during a protest in solidarity with those killed in the attack on Charlie Hebdo, in Niteroi, Brazil, Jan. 8, 2015.
Muslims hold placards reading 'Islam is against terrorism' offer roses in the Sablons neighborhood of Le Mans, western France, on January 10, 2015.
A group of activists and journalists stage a protest against the attack on Charlie Hebdo in front of French Embassy in Morocco on Jan. 10, 2015 in Rabat, Morocco.
Guingamp's supporter hold signs reading 'Je suis Charlie' to pay tribute to the victims of the Charlie Hebdo attack during the French L1 football match in Guingamp, western France, on Jan. 10, 2015.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:57:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis Asks Forgiveness For Catholic Church's Persecution Of Waldensians</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a41a9f/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Cpope0Efrancis0Ewaldensians0In0I76449160Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis asked forgiveness on Monday for the Roman Catholic Church's "non-Christian and inhumane" treatment in the past of the Waldensians, a tiny Protestant movement the Vatican tried to exterminate in the 15th century.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis Asks Forgiveness For Catholic Church's Persecution Of Waldensians
Reuters | By                                                                      PHILIP PULLELLA
Updated:
3 hours ago
Pope Francis shakes hands with Eugenio Bernardini, the Moderator of the Waldensian Church, during the first ever visit of a pope to the Waldensian evangelical church, in Turin, northern Italy, Monday, June 22, 2015. Pope Francis asked forgiveness Monday for the Catholic Church's persecution of members of this small evangelical church in Italy whose leader was excommunicated and followers branded as heretics during the Middle Ages.  (L' Osservatore Romano/Pool Photo via AP) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
Pope Francis asked forgiveness on Monday for the Roman Catholic Church's "non-Christian and inhumane" treatment in the past of the Waldensians, a tiny Protestant movement the Vatican tried to exterminate in the 15th century.
Francis made his plea during the first ever visit by a pope to a Waldensian temple on the second day of a trip to Italy's northern Piedmont region, the centre of the Waldensian Church, which has only about 30,000 followers worldwide.
While the movement is miniscule compared to the 1.2 billion member Roman Catholic Church, the gesture is part of Francis' drive to promote Christian unity and it has taken on added significance ahead of the 500th anniversary of the Protestant Reformation in 2017.
"On behalf of the Catholic Church, I ask forgiveness for the un-Christian and even inhumane positions and actions taken against you historically," he said. "In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, forgive us!"
The Waldensians, who now live mostly in Italy and Latin America, were founded by Peter Waldo in France in the late 12th century. He gave up his wealth and preached poverty but as the movement grew it came into increasing theological conflict with the papacy.
The movement, an early precursor of the Protestant Reformation in the 16th century, was branded as heretical and in 1487 Pope Innocent VIII ordered its extermination.
Some 1,700 Waldensians were killed in 1655 by Catholic forces commanded by the Duke of Savoy.
Today the Waldensians are part of the World Communion of Reformed Churches and the World Council of Churches. They have
only two sacraments -- baptism and the Lord's Supper -- as opposed to seven in the Roman Catholic Church, a member of the Italian branch said.
During a visit to Jerusalem in 2000, Francis' predecessor Pope John Paul II asked forgiveness from Jews for their persecution by Catholics over the centuries.
In 2017, Christians will mark the 500th anniversary of the launching of the Protestant Reformation by Martin Luther, who nailed his 95 Theses to a church door in Germany to denounce corruption in the Catholic Church.
Various Christian churches have still not agreed on how they will jointly mark the divorce that split western Christianity and led to many bloody religious wars.
The head of the Protestant Church in Germany, Bishop Heinrich Bedford-Strohm, has said he would be in favour of inviting the pope to a "joint Christian festival" to mark the anniversary.
Francis, an Argentinian whose father and grandfather were born in the Turin area, wrapped up his two-day visit to the region with a private lunch with his Italian relatives.
Also on The Huffington Post
Close


A mere two weeks after he was announced as pontiff, Francis washed and kissed the feet of 12 prisoners incarcerated in Rome as part of the traditional Holy Thursday rite. The unorthodox component of the ceremony was the inclusion of two women, one of whom was a Muslim. This show of acceptance and compassion was just a hint at what was to come, as the pope has continued to make statements about the importance of interfaith understanding as well as the importance of a greater role for women in the church. Francis sent personal Eid al-Fitr holiday greetings to Muslims around the world, rather than relying on his office to do so in a show of care and good will that hasn't happened since Pope John Paul II sent a similar personal message in 1991.
Soon after he became pope, Francis tweeted, "The pope must serve all people, especially the poor, the weak, the vulnerable," and he's made sure to personally do so by comforting and greeting the sick after his weekly general audiences in St. Peter's Square. He moved many hearts, as pictures of him tenderly embracing and kissing some severely disfigured men showed his human concern for all people, especially the marginalized.
Pope Francis refused to live in the luxurious papal apartments located in the Apostolic Palace and prefers to live in more modest accommodations to show his personal commitment to humility and encourage other leaders to follow suit. He's also gained notice for his unusual choice of a car -- a humble Ford Focus with a starting sticker price of only about $16,000. He can rarely be seen in the ostentatious vestments that he could certainly wear as pope and  prefers his usual garments of a simple white hat and robe. He's always done so -- when he still lived in Argentina, he gave up his chauffeur and took the bus to work.
Arriving at World Youth Day, Pope Francis had rock-star appeal, as thousands of young people swarmed his car after it took a wrong turn. Though the mob of excited youth alarmed his security staff with the frenzy of their excitement, "the pope was happy, with his hand out the window waving," said a Vatican spokesman. World Youth Day was a great success, and this pope seems particularly in tune with the younger generation.
Pope Francis has given a 17-year-old boy with Down Syndrome the ride of his life  sort of.  Francis invited Alberto di Tullio up onto his open-top Mercedes at the end of his general audience Wednesday, letting him spin around on the pontiff's white chair while tens of thousands of people looked on.  Read more
Four homeless people, one of them bringing his dog, helped Pope Francis celebrate his 77th birthday at the Vatican Tuesday.  Read more here
Meet Nathan de Brito, the little boy who broke past barriers to run into Pope Francis' arms on Friday in order to tell him something that moved the pontiff to tears.  They embraced on the Popemobile as de Brito confided to Pope Francis, "Your Holiness, I want to be a priest of Christ, a representative of Christ."  Read more here
In this photo provided by the Vatican paper L'Osservatore Romano, Pope Francis, left, and Pope emeritus Benedict XVI pray together in Castel Gandolfo Saturday, March 23, 2013. Pope Francis has traveled to Castel Gandolfo to have lunch with his predecessor Benedict XVI in a historic and potentially problematic melding of the papacies that has never before confronted the Catholic Church. The Vatican said the two popes embraced on the helipad. In the chapel where they prayed together, Benedict offered Francis the traditional kneeler used by the pope. Francis refused to take it alone, saying "We're brothers," and the two prayed together on the same one. (AP Photo/Osservatore Romano, HO)
This adorable little boy was on top of the world when he made friends with Pope Francis by wandering up onto the stage during the Pontiff's address to a crowd of families.  Read more
Pope Francis' compassionate nature was poignantly captured in this image of him tenderly comforting a sick man by kissing him on the head.  Read more
Pope Francis is winning Twitter. The tweeting Pope upped the ante yesterday by posing for an incredible selfie at the Vatican on Wednesday.   Read more
Pope Francis boards a plane at Rome's Fiumicino international airport, Monday, July 22, 2013. It's wheels up on Pope Francis' first trip abroad as pontiff. A special Alitalia flight carrying Francis, his entourage and journalists who will cover him on his week-long visit to Brazil took off 10 minutes behind schedule Monday from Rome's Leonardo da Vinci airport. Keeping to his example that the Catholic church must be humble, Francis carried his own black hand luggage. He even kept holding it with his left hand while he used his left to shake hands with some of the VIPs who turned out to wish him well and while he climbed the stairs to the jet's entrance. Among the dignitaries was Italian Premier Enrico Letta. (AP Photo/Riccardo De Luca)
In this Sunday, March 31, 2013 file photo, Pope Francis hugs 8-year-old Dominic Gondreau, who has cerebral palsy, after celebrating his first Easter Mass in St. Peter's Square at the Vatican. Gondreau is the son of Dr. Paul Gondreau, a faculty member at Providence College in Providence, R.I.   Read more here
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:28:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>P5+1 and Iran Have Settled Framework for Sanctions Relief Timing, Says Iranian Sources</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a39bda/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Ctrita0Eparsi0Cp510Eand0Eiran0Ehave0Esettled0Ib0I7680A80A0A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Contrary to public posturing on the timing and pace of sanctions relief, a framework for handling this critical matter of the nuclear deal has been resolved, according to Iranian sources. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Contrary to public posturing on the timing and pace of sanctions relief, a framework for handling this critical matter of the nuclear deal has been resolved, according to Iranian sources.
Iranian officials have on numerous occasions insisted that sanctions relief must come immediately upon the signing of an agreement. This has been at direct odds with the position of the U.S. government and its allies, who insist that relief only can come after Iran has taken numerous steps limiting its nuclear activities.
As often times is the case in diplomacy, the solution was found in a combination of a play with words and practical measures.
This is exactly what the diplomats did to reconcile the Iranian insistence on front loaded sanctions relief and the Western position of relief being provided only after the International Atomic Energy Agency has verified Iranian steps to curtail its nuclear program.
According to Iranian sources, the agreement is divided into three phases. The initial phase -- called "adoption of agreement" -- takes places as the two sides agree on a final deal. This phase will kick in in the next few days -- if a deal is reached.
The next phase -- the operationalization of the agreement -- will begin once the domestic political processes of various parties have conclusively approved the agreement. This phase has been added primarily as a result of the US Congress passing the Corker bill, in which the American legislature gave itself the right to review and vote on the nuclear deal.
The timing of the second phase is directly related to the duration of the Congressional review process. If the two sides come to an agreement prior to July 10, the review process is set at 30 calendar days , in addition to 22 calendar days for Congress to pass a resolution to accept or reject the deal and for the President to use his veto, if need be. If the two sides fail to reach a deal by July 10, the Congressional review process increases to 60 calendar days.
While other states in the negotiations may also initiate some form of internal review and approval process, none of them are expected to take as long as the Congressional review. As such, the U.S. congress has significantly delayed the implementation of a presumptive deal.
Once the deal has survived the Congressional review -- whether through a resolution of affirmation or the failure to pass a resolution of rejection -- the Iranians will begin implementing the first steps of their commitments. This is phase III. The initiation of the implementation of their end of the deal must then be verified by the IAEA, after which the US and its allies will begin relieving sanctions. It is at this point that the deal will be "signed," enabling the Iranian demand for sanctions relief to occur upon signing of the deal to be upheld.
The exact timing of this schedule depends on the date the deal is adopted, the duration of the Congressional review and the time it takes for Iran to implement the first steps of the agreement. But at best it will begin a few months after the adoption of the deal. This is reflected by President Hassan Rouhani's statement earlier in June that he expected relief from sanctions within a "couple of months" after an agreement is reached .
While agreement on these principles of the process is a very important step forward, some question marks remain. What kind of a binding commitment will the U.S. and its allies make to reciprocate Iranian implementation of the deal, as the first steps taken will be Iranian? At what point will the UN Security Council adopt a resolution that affirms the deal?
While these are important details that must be settled, it is more important that the framework for the process has been agreed upon.
Follow Trita Parsi on Twitter: www.twitter.com/tparsi
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan Probes Water Park Fire As Tally Of Injured Skyrockets</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a42547/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Ctaiwan0Ewater0Epark0Efire0In0I7680A8120Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Taiwan Probes Water Park Fire As Tally Of Injured Skyrockets
Reuters
Updated:
1 hour ago
Two men walk at the explosion site of the water park in Pali district, in New Taipei City, on June 28, 2015. More than 500 people were injured, almost 200 of them seriously, when a ball of fire ripped through a crowd at a water park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei, authorities said. AFP PHOTO / Sam Yeh        (Photo credit should read SAM YEH/AFP/Getty Images) | SAM YEH via Getty Images
reddit
By J.R. Wu and Pichi Chuang
TAIPEI, June 28 (Reuters) - The number of party revelers  injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park rose to 519 on Sunday,  as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a  sudden explosion of a colored powder thrown on those attending  the party.
Six foreigners and seven visitors from Hong Kong, mainland  China and Macau were among those injured after about 1,000  people dancing at Saturday's event were sprayed with the powder,  as a special feature of a festival also held in previous years.
The blaze, which broke out around 8.30 p.m. at the Formosa  Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is  suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the colored  powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder  explode," he added, however.
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the  investigation is completed and its safety can be assured.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured,"  Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters. Of the 519 injured,  419 are still being treated in 41 hospitals across the island.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers  treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30,  who wore wet swimsuits and lay on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
A video posted online by Apple Daily showed dancers in front of the stage engulfed in clouds of colored powder a moment  before a fireball erupted, followed by pockets of flame,  triggering panic and screams.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man   said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims suffered burns  on limbs and torsos, with some passing out from the pain while  others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and  pictures showed.
"Her whole life is ruined," sobbed the father of Chu Li, an  18-year-old girl with burns on 80 percent of her body, during a  visit by President Ma Ying-jeou to victims in a Taipei hospital.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the  rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts,  along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on  its website on Sunday.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees  Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in recent weeks.     (Additional reporting by Faith Hung; Editing by Clarence  Fernandez)
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:25:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Are we living Islam's darkest hour?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a331a5/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cfaisal0Eabbas0Care0Ewe0Eliving0Eislams0Edark0Ib0I7680A4780Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>How much terrorism can the world take in 24 hours? Friday 26 June, 2015 will certainly go down in history as a day that pushed the limit.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
How much terrorism can the world take in 24 hours? Friday 26 June, 2015 will certainly go down in history as a day that pushed the limit.
Just in case the daily dose of evil committed by the likes of ISIS or Iranian-backed militias in Syria and Iraq wasn't enough, we witnessed three additional horrific attacks done in the name of Islam yesterday.
In Kuwait , a deadly bomb took the lives of 27 innocent people and injured 200 others in an ISIS attack on a Shiite mosque.
In the Tunisian resort town of Sousse, at least 38 innocent people were killed and dozens wounded when at least one ISIS gunman opened fire at a beachside resort. Meanwhile, a headless body and Islamist flags were found at the scene of an attack on a gas factory near France's second largest city, Lyon.
Here is what will happen next: leaders of affected countries will visit the wounded and vow retaliation, world leaders and concerned parties will condemn, the press will talk about it for a few days.
Then, the story will die and terrorism will be forgotten - until it strikes again.
'Quiet condoners'
The madness needs to stop. But this will not happen as long as there are Muslims who, while not actively participating in these crimes, still think the likes of ISIS have grounds for what they are doing,
People might say the above argument echoes the rather unpopular (but accurate nevertheless) views of British PM David Cameron who recently accused many British Muslims of quietly condoning the ISIS ideology.
Now, while it remains a puzzle how anyone can agree - privately or publicly - with this group's evil creed; one has to wonder if these "quiet condoners" realize that it is Muslims - and nobody else - who are ultimately being hurt the most?
Putting aside the innocent Christian, Jewish and/or Muslim lives that these terrorist acts take, let us not forget that after almost each one of these attacks, hate crimes against Muslims increase and Muslim communities end up finding it harder to be accepted, to find jobs and to integrate.
Some might ask: what about Muslim grievances regarding occupied lands, unjust causes and unfair treatment, which these terrorist groups claim to be fighting for?
In response to that question, one can only ask how many of these grievances, while legitimate, have been solved by terrorism? If anything, the likes of ISIS and al-Qaeda has made these causes worse and much more complicated to resolve.
As simple as this truth is, many people refuse to see it and this is probably the reason why I remain extremely pessimistic about our region. Perhaps one positive thought remains. It is said that the night is darkest just before the dawn - I don't think our night can get any darker!
*This blog was originally published on Al Arabiya News .
Follow Faisal J. Abbas on Twitter: www.twitter.com/FaisalJAbbas
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:57:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rift With Greece Sets Europe Into Uncharted Territory</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a1ffba/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Cgreece0Eparliament0Ereferendum0In0I76791980Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS, June 28 (Reuters) - Europe's grand project to bind its nations into an unbreakable union by means of a common currency lurched into uncharted waters after EU governments refused funding to save Greece from defaulting on its debts.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rift With Greece Sets Europe Into Uncharted Territory
Reuters | By                                                                      Alastair Macdonald
Updated:
2 hours ago
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras delivers a speech during a parliamentary session in Athens on June 28, 2015. Greece will hold a referendum on July 5 on the outcome of negotiations with its international creditors taking place in Brussels today. AFP PHOTO / ANGELOS TZORTZINIS (Photo credit should read ANGELOS TZORTZINIS/AFP/Getty Images) | ANGELOS TZORTZINIS via Getty Images
reddit
BRUSSELS, June 28 (Reuters) - Europe's grand project to bind its nations into an unbreakable union by means of a common currency lurched into uncharted waters after EU governments refused funding to save Greece from defaulting on its debts.
While finance ministers of the other 18 euro zone states chorused their insistence that Greece would remain inside the bloc, exasperation with the leftist government's decision to reject creditors' final offer and instead call a referendum was manifest and some officials spoke privately of expelling Athens.
"They were playing poker," said Austrian Finance Minister Hans Joerg Schelling after the Eurogroup that runs the currency met on Saturday without their Greek counterpart to discuss how to limit the fallout. "But in poker, you can always lose."
After five months of negotiations with a Greek government elected to end the pain of austerity measures, EU leaders left a summit in Brussels on Friday believing a deal was close to roll over bailout funding and let Athens meet a repayment to the IMF on Tuesday and further obligations over the coming months.
But Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras provoked consternation by returning home to call a referendum for next Sunday on the offer and urging voters, weary of years of debt crises, to reject it.
Not for the first time, EU officials said Greek negotiators across the table were themselves taken by surprise by news from Athens. "They heard about the referendum on Twitter," one said.
"Tsipras messed up," a euro zone official said. "We did everything possible. They chose to blow up when we were so close to settling this in a way that would allow them to sell it."
Amid political drama in Greece, where a clear majority wants to remain inside the bloc, the next few days present a major challenge to the integrity of a 16-year-old currency bloc, which many blame for massive unemployment in countries outside Germany and its neighbors in the richer north and west of Europe.
RISK MANAGEMENT
"We must do everything we can to fight any conceivable threat of contagion," German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble said after a meeting at which the group effectively called for capital controls to ring-fence Greek banks hemorrhaging cash.
While acknowledging that only Greece - or possibly banks themselves - can instigate such a shutdown, the ministers said the European Central Bank, whose management meets on Sunday, should use its powers to stabilize markets.
"You have to count on Greece getting into acute problems in the coming days because of this decision," said Schaeuble, some of whose conservative allies have made no secret of preferring to see Greece forced out of the euro zone. "That is difficult as we do not know how it will live up to its commitments."
He and others, however, stressed their faith in stability mechanisms put in place after skepticism among investors pushed the euro zone to breaking point following a run of national bankruptcy scares in the wake of the global crash of 2008.
And, echoing his French Socialist counterpart, Michel Sapin, Schaeuble insisted after the fifth such deadlocked ministerial meeting in just over a week: "Greece remains a member of the euro zone and Greece remains part of Europe."
But there is a divergence, certainly in tone, between Berlin and Paris. Sapin insisted the Eurogroup at least discuss the Greek request for an extension on Saturday but Schaeuble and most others had lost patience, sources close to the talks said.
Afterwards, Sapin said he was still ready to negotiate, a view repeated on Sunday in Paris by Prime Minister Manuel Valls.
But few EU leaders now trust this Greek government, whose calls for debt relief and criticisms of the bailout's deadening effect on growth have been echoed by some leading economists.
When representatives of the three creditor institutions - euro zone governments, the ECB and IMF - met after Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis had left, participants quoted one senior official as joking that at least they could refer again to the lenders as the "Troika," a term Varoufakis had insisted be dropped because Greeks associated it with external diktats.
Dutch Finance Minister Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the Eurogroup chairman, repeatedly referred to the possibility that the Greek parliament might reject Tsipras's call for a referendum. But lawmakers dashed any prospect of a quick shift in Greek politics before markets open on Monday by voting for it to go ahead.
Still, Dijsselbloem insisted: "The process has not ended. It will never end probably. We will continue to work with Greece. Many things could happen, many scenarios are conceivable."
As Greeks lined up to take cash from ATMs, it remained to be seen how financial mechanisms would work. If Greece fails, as it has said it will, to repay 1.6 billion euros to the IMF on Tuesday, that default can have knock-on effects.
Greece could stay in the euro zone but also issue a local currency to pay bills -- a form of "Grexit" recommended on Sunday by influential German economist Hans-Werner Sinn of Ifo.
The ECB must also decide whether to keep supplying liquidity to Greek banks, once the government whose debt makes up a large chunk of their assets is no longer meeting its obligations and once the bailout program formally expires on Tuesday.
POLITICAL FALLOUT
The central bank, under its president Mario Draghi, has been reluctant to take such a highly politicized decision. At the same time, political leaders have been reluctant to override the decisions of finance ministers lest that appear to be a signal that the rules of the common currency are open to manipulation.
Donald Tusk, a former Polish prime minister who chairs meetings of the 28 EU leaders, made clear at two summits in the past week that heads of government must nonetheless take their responsibilities in a crisis that affects the Union as a whole.
Early on Sunday, he was in contact with leaders again: "Greece is and should remain euro area member," Tusk tweeted.
The Greek government's demands have alienated its euro zone partners - from Germany and its northern allies, to southern states and Ireland whose governments face critics of their own bailout terms to easterners much less prosperous than Greece.
But with Britain already planning a referendum on leaving the EU, a breach in formal institutions worries those who fear economic drift. Complaints it lacks democratic accountability threaten the EU's survival in its present form.
One official close to Saturday's Eurogroup discussions said the issue of Greece leaving the euro, or the EU, was not raised - there is no obvious legal way to force it out of either. But, the official said, a "Grexit" could not be entirely ruled out.
Leaving Brussels on what he called a "sad day for Europe," the outspoken Varoufakis warned that the rift with Athens would damage the euro zone's credibility as a "democratic union" -  "And I'm very much afraid that that damage will be permanent."
(Additional reporting by Jan Strupczewski, Robert-Jan Bartunek and Andreas Rinke; Editing by Janet McBride and Anna Willard)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:53:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan Water Park Fire Leaves Over 200 Wounded</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a1c78c/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Ctaiwan0Ewater0Epark0Efire0In0I76795420Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) — A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan Water Park Fire Leaves Over 200 Wounded
Posted:
reddit
TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP)  A fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party Saturday night at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200 people, authorities said.
An accidental explosion of an unknown powder set off the fire near the stage in front of about 1,000 spectators, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
Rescue workers tend to injured people at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City on June 27, 2015. (AFP/Getty Images)
Wang said 83 people had serious injuries and 131 others have light injuries.
Taiwan's Central News Agency reported the fire at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City near the island's capital was quickly brought under control.
People carry an injured man at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park after an explosion in the Pali district of New Taipei City on June 27, 2015. (AFP/Getty Images)
Video showed rescue workers and bystanders carrying burned and injured people on their backs, in inflatable boats and on stretchers to get medical treatment.
CNA reported witnesses as saying the fire spread quickly after the colored powder was blown into the air.
It wasn't clear if the colored powder was part of a performance. The cause of the fire is being investigated.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:39:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Victims of Illusions: The Non-Solution of the Greferendum</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a1bcf1/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Ccas0Emudde0Cvictims0Eof0Eillusions0Ethe0E0Ib0I76791380Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The seemingly never-ending Greek drama has become a story of amateurism versus dogmatism with incompetence and cowardice on both sides. The Greek government has squandered all its goodwill within half a year through a combination of arrogance, belligerence, naivety and utter incompetence. It set out to restore the "dignity" of the Greek people by "liberating" them from the alleged stranglehold of the Troika, while in the process "transforming" Europe into a more equal and just continent. It has achieved neither. The current Greek government is confronted with almost exactly the same deal as its so maligned predecessor. Moreover, outside of (West) European gauche caviar, desperate for a new "anti-imperialist hero" after Hugo Chavez's death, support for Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and his Coalition for a Radical Left (Syriza) has evaporated its amid erratic behavior and endless accusations of "blackmail" and "betrayal." Even worse, they have strengthened the belief among its opponents that (all) Euro-skepticism is necessarily incompetent and moralistic.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
The seemingly never-ending Greek drama has become a story of amateurism versus dogmatism with incompetence and cowardice on both sides. The Greek government has squandered all its goodwill within half a year through a combination of arrogance, belligerence, naivety and utter incompetence. It set out to restore the "dignity" of the Greek people by "liberating" them from the alleged stranglehold of the Troika, while in the process "transforming" Europe into a more equal and just continent. It has achieved neither. The current Greek government is confronted with almost exactly the same deal as its so maligned predecessor. Moreover, outside of (West) European gauche caviar, desperate for a new "anti-imperialist hero" after Hugo Chavez's death, support for Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras and his Coalition for a Radical Left (Syriza) has evaporated its amid erratic behavior and endless accusations of "blackmail" and "betrayal." Even worse, they have strengthened the belief among its opponents that (all) Euro-skepticism is necessarily incompetent and moralistic.
The so often repeated claim that the Troika is "disingenuous" is not just evidence of the typical moralistic discourse of populism, in which the other side is "the enemy" that is "corrupt," but, even more importantly, shows the Greek government's utter misperception of its opponent(s). Whether they truly believe their accusations or not is not that relevant, although it does go to the question whether they are simply incompetent or (also) disingenuous. In essence, the Greek government is accusing the Troika of being -- well -- the Troika! It blames them for not supporting the Syriza program. The Troika largely does the same, of course, but uses overall a more technocratic, rather than moralistic, discourse.
The essence of this drama is that both camps are informed by fundamentally different visions and try to come to an impossible compromise on the basis of a warped view of each other. The Greek government thinks the Troika is essentially committed to a strong Europe than to the politics of austerity, and the Troika still thinks that Greece is a typical European state, which in their view means a Northern European state. Hence, Tsipras keeps presenting "fairer" options, while Merkel keeps calling for "rational reforms." While both can be criticized for incompetence and immorality, the costs are clearly much higher for Tsipras' Greeks than for Merkel's Germans.
Whatever the logic and morality of the austerity politics, and both can be seriously questioned, the Troika has been absolutely clear that this is the foundation of its Eurozone politics. It might be rigid, but it is straightforward and, therefore, honest. In sharp contrast, the Greek government, both Syriza and coalition partner Independent Greeks (ANEL), has been far from clear in its position. It has invented a third option, Eurozone without austerity, which from the outset has been rejected by the Troika. More fundamentally, however, Syriza proclaims to be a radical left party, which supports an economic model somewhere in between socialism and social democracy. It wants to realize this within the European Union and the Eurozone, which are both fundamentally neoliberal projects, in which substantial state involvement in the economy is considered wrong.
The current standoff was inevitable as soon as the Greek population voted Syriza into power. In essence, therefore, both ANEL/Syriza and their supporters are responsible for the situation that they find themselves in now. They can blame the Troika for being, and staying true to being, the Troika, but that doesn't change the reality. Tsipras' call for a referendum took much of the rest of the European Union, and perhaps many in Greece, by surprise. Pundits will undoubtedly see it as further proof of the highly rational (choice) strategy of 'game theorist' and Finance Minister Varoufakis, trying to put extra pressure on the Troika.  However, their archenemy Papandreou did the same in 2011 and failed (too).
In classic populist language Tsipras called for a "democratic response" to the creditors that try to "humiliate" Greece. Varoufakis tweeted that the referendum will "boost" democracy in "euro-related matters." Responding to reactions that he had been elected to make these decisions, as this is how representative democracies work, he said that the government doesn't have a mandate to make this important decision because only 41 percent of the people voted for ANEL and Syriza. This is a bizarre argument, which, in extremism, would mean that the government should resign, as it doesn't represent the majority of the Greek people. Moreover, it hasn't stopped Syriza in the last months from claiming to speak in the name of "the people," i.e. not just for a majority but for all (pure) Greek people. Incidentally, the righteous claim of boosting democracy was already undermined by ANEL leader Panos Kammenos, who said that the Greferendum would be withdrawn if the creditors would accept their counteroffer.
Rather than boosting democracy the more likely reason for the referendum is to prevent a break up of the government and of Syriza. As a literal coalition of more and less radical left groups Syriza is only really united in the opposition to the bailout conditions. The 'party' is fundamentally divided on continued membership of the Eurozone and even the European Union. However, if democracy is really so important to Varoufakis and the others, they should put the interests of the country and its population above those of the coalition government and the political party.
Tsipras has called a referendum on the very narrow issue of the specific terms offered by the creditors for the latest aid package. This is a ridiculous proposal on several accounts. First, the referendum will have to be organized within one week by a state with limited capacity under the best of circumstances, let alone in the height of an economic and political crisis. Second, the terms offered by the creditors are not even public yet (let alone translated into Greek). How can people vote on them if they haven't seen them? Third, the referendum is framed purely as a vote on the terms of the creditors, as if there is an option to get the financial aid under different terms. And, even if this were to be the case, and all behavior and statements of the Troika members makes this highly doubtful, what will happen then, i.e. in the best case scenario: Another referendum on the amended terms?
There is a good case to be made for a Greek referendum, but it is not this one. The Greeks should get a straightforward choice between the only two realistic options: staying in the Eurozone under the stated conditions or leaving the Eurozone (and allegedly have their "dignity" and "democracy" back). This is the fundamental choice that should have informed Greek politics for the past years. Greeks could have had that vote in the January elections, but Syriza prevented it by offering a faux third option: stay in the Eurozone without the Eurozone conditions. Now that everyone knows there are only two options, Syriza should finally give the people a vote on them, be it in new elections or in a (well-prepared) referendum.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:06:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Bank Run Empties Over A Third Of ATMs Of Cash</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a15271/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Cgreece0Ebank0Erun0In0I76788580Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>By George Georgiopoulos and Lefteris Papadimas</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece Bank Run Empties Over A Third Of ATMs Of Cash
Reuters
Updated:
06/27/2015  3:59 pm EDT
People queue at a national Bank of Greece ATM in central Athens on June 27, 2015. (ARIS MESSINIS/AFP/Getty Images) | ARIS MESSINIS via Getty Images
reddit
By George Georgiopoulos and Lefteris Papadimas
ATHENS, June 27 (Reuters) - More than a third of automated teller machines across Greece ran out of cash on Saturday before they were replenished as Greeks pulled out money on fears their country was set to crash out of the euro, three banking sources said.
Anxious Greeks lined up outside ATMs after Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras made a surprise call for a referendum on austerity terms demanded by lenders, throwing talks with lenders in disarray and putting Greece on the verge of a default.
About 35 percent of the ATM network - some 2,000 out of the 5,500 ATMs across Greece - ran out of euro banknotes at one point during the day and were being replenished, the bankers said. Banks were working in coordination with the central bank to keep the network fed with cash, they said.
Replenishing ATMs usually takes one to two hours per ATM, leading to the long lines, one banking source said.
Around 600 million euros was withdrawn from the banking system on Saturday, one senior banker at one of Greece's four big lenders told Reuters. A second banker estimated the outflow at more than 500 million euros.
Though that was below the level of over 1 billion euros seen on some days over the past two weeks, the figure was almost exclusively from ATM withdrawals, where the average daily limit of cash that can be taken out is 600 to 700 euros, bankers said.
"Demand for cash is definitely higher than what you see on a normal Saturday," one of the bankers said.
"This does not mean that there are lines everywhere but we are trying to keep ATMs fed with banknotes."
Minutes after Tsipras's address to the nation, small lines could be seen at some ATMs in Athens. In addition to lines at various ATMs across the country on Saturday, a line of about 40 people could be seen at an ATM inside the Greek parliament.
Greece's government has insisted that banks will reopen as normal on Monday and denied the country will have to impose capital controls to prevent the banks collapsing.
The banks depend on emergency liquidity from the European Central Bank to stay open, and senior government officials held talks with the ECB chief Mario Draghi on Saturday to ensure continued support to banks amid the crisis.  (Writing by Deepa Babington; editing by Ralph Boulton)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Senators Visit Cuba Hoping Congress Will Ease Restrictions</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a15272/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Csenators0Evisit0Ecuba0In0I76788640Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Senators Visit Cuba Hoping Congress Will Ease Restrictions
Reuters
reddit
By Daniel Trotta
HAVANA, June 27 (Reuters) - Three visiting U.S. senators  said on Saturday they hoped Congress would support President  Barack Obama's opening toward Cuba, including lifting a ban on  U.S. citizens traveling to the Communist-run island.
Democratic Senators Patrick Leahy of Vermont and Ben Cardin  of Maryland joined Republican Dean Heller of Nevada on a trip to  Cuba where they met First Vice-President Miguel Diaz-Canel,  Foreign Minister Bruno Rodriguez and ordinary Cubans.
A number of Cuba initiatives are pending in the Senate,  including a bill to remove the travel ban on Americans and a  more ambitions bill to rescind the decades-old U.S. economic  embargo.
Obama, a Democrat, has called on Congress to act but the  legislation is opposed by the Republican leadership in control  of the Senate and the House of Representatives.
Earlier this month, the House rejected a measure that would  have relaxed travel restrictions. But the senators said there  were better prospects for progress on Cuba legislation in their  chamber.
"We think that can be achieved this year and we can make  additional progress next year," Cardin told a news conference.  "We're optimistic this path that President Obama and President  (Raul) Castro started will be continued."
Heller, one of a few Republican senators to side with Obama  on Cuba, encouraged members of Congress to visit Cuba and engage  with ordinary Cubans. "I think the Senate can move the House,  but the Senate's going to have to act first," Heller told  Reuters after the news conference.
Currently, some Americans may travel to Cuba with official  permission but general tourism is banned.
Breaking decades of Cold War-era hostility, Obama and Castro   announced plans last December to restore diplomatic ties that  Washington severed in 1961, and to work toward normalizing  overall relations. An announcement on reopening embassies in  both capitals is expected soon.     (Reporting by Daniel Trotta; Editing by Frances Kerry)
Also on HuffPost:
Obama's Handshakes Around The World
of


In this image from TV, US President Barack Obama shakes hands with Cuban President Raul Castro at the FNB Stadium in Soweto, South Africa, in the rain for a memorial service for former South African President Nelson Mandela, Tuesday Dec. 10, 2013. (AP Photo/SABC Pool)
President Barack Obama meets with Argentina's President Cristina Fernandez at the G20 Summit in Cannes, France, Friday, Nov. 4, 2011. (AP Photo/Charles Dharapak)
Afghanistan President Hamid Karzai (L) and U.S. President Barack Obama shake hands after a joint news conference in the East Room of the White House on January 11, 2013 in Washington, D.C. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)
U.S. President Barack Obama (L) and Australian Prime Minister Julia Gillard shake hands during a bilateral meeting at Parliament House in Canberra on November 16, 2011. (JIM WATSON/AFP/Getty Images)
U.S. President Barack Obama (L) shakes hands with Brazilian President Dilma Vana Rousseff (R) during a joint press conference at Palacio do Planalto in Brasilia on March 19, 2011. (JIM WATSON/AFP/Getty Images)  CORRECTION: The title of this slide initially referred to Dilma Rousseff as the prime minister of Brazil. In fact, she is the president of Brazil.
U.S. President Barack Obama (L) and Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen (R) reach out to shake hands on arrival at the Peace Palace for the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and US summit in Phnom Penh on November 19, 2012 following the 21st ASEAN Leaders Summit.  (ROMEO GACAD/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with Canadas Prime Minister Stephen Harper in bilateral meeting during the G20 Summit, Tuesday, June 19, 2012, in Los Cabos, Mexico. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)
U.S. President Barack Obama greets Chilean President Sebastian Pinera before a dinner at the Washington Convention Center during  the Nuclear Security Summit in Washington, DC, on April 12, 2010. (JEWEL SAMAD/AFP/Getty Images)
U.S. President Barack Obama shakes hands with then-Chinese Vice President Xi Jinping during meetings in the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, DC, February 14, 2012. (SAUL LOEB/AFP/Getty Images)
Colombia President Juan Manuel Santos (R) and U.S. President Barack Obama shake hands during a joint press conference in the framework of the VI Summit of the Americas at Casa de Huespedes in Cartagena, Colombia, on April 15, 2012. (SAUL LOEB/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama and Costa Rica's President Laura Chinchilla shake hands at the end of their joint press conference in San Jose, Costa Rica, Friday, May 3, 2013. (AP Photo/Moises Castillo)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with French President Francois Hollande on arrival for the G8 Summit Friday, May 18, 2012 at Camp David, Md. (AP Photo/Charles Dharapak)
U.S. President Barack Obama (R) shakes hands with German Chancellor Angela Merkel looks after a joint press conference following their meeting in the East Room of the White House in Washington, D.C., on June 7, 2011. (JEWEL SAMAD/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with Italian President Giorgio Napolitano during their meeting in the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, Friday, Feb. 15, 2013. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe in the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, Friday, Feb. 22, 2013. (AP Photo/Charles Dharapak)
President Barack Obama and South Korea President Park Geun-Hye shake hands at the conclusion of their joint news conference in the East Room of the White House in Washington, Tuesday, May 7, 2013. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
President Barack Obama, left, and Mexico President Enrique Pena Nieto, right, shake hands following a news conference at the Palacio Nacional in Mexico City, Thursday, May 2, 2013. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
U.S. President Barack Obama (R) shakes hands with President Benigno Aquino of the Philippines in the Oval Office at the White House on June 8, 2012 in Washington, D.C. (Photo by Kevin Dietsch-Pool/Getty Images)
Polish Prime Minister Donald Tusk (R) shake hands with U.S. President Barack Obama (L) during their meeting in Warsaw on May 28, 2011. (JANEK SKARZYNSKI/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with Sheik Hamad bin Khalifa Al Thani of Qatar during their meeting in the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, Tuesday, April 23, 2013. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
U.S. President Barack Obama (R) greets Romania's President Traian Basescu before a dinner at the US Ambassador's residence in Prague on April 8, 2010. (JEWEL SAMAD/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with Russias President Vladimir Putin in a bilateral meeting during the G20 Summit, Monday, June 18, 2012, in Los Cabos, Mexico. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)
U.S. President Barack Obama shakes hands with King Abdullah bin Abdulaziz Al Saud of Saudi Arabia during meetings in the Oval Office at the White House in Washington, DC, June 29, 2010. (SAUL LOEB/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with with Singapore Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong during their meeting in the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, Tuesday, April, 2, 2013. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
U.S. President Barack Obama shakes hands with Sweden's Prime Minister Fredrik Reinfeldt (L) during meetings in the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, DC, November 2, 2009. (SAUL LOEB/AFP/Getty Images)
U.S. President Barack Obama, left, and Thai Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra shake hands following the conclusion of their joint news conference at Thai Government House in Bangkok, Thailand, Sunday, Nov. 18, 2012. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
FILE - In this March 22, 2013, file photo, President Barack Obama, left, and Jordan's King Abdullah II, right, shake hands following their joint new conference at the King's Palace in Amman, Jordan. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais, File)
U.S. President Barack Obama (R) shakes hands with Turkish Prime Minister Recep Tayyip Erdogan after their bilateral meeting in Seoul on March 25, 2012 on the eve of the 2012 Seoul Nuclear Security Summit. (JEWEL SAMAD/AFP/Getty Images)
President Barack Obama shakes hands with Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron on arrival for the G8 Summit Friday, May 18, 2012 at Camp David, Md. (AP Photo/Charles Dharapak)
Venezuelan President Hugo Chavez (R) gives a book, 'The Open Veins of Latin America' of Uruguayan writer Eduardo Galeano to US President Barack Obama (L) during a multilateral meeting to begin during the Summit of the Americas at the Hyatt Regency in Port of Spain, Trinidad April 18, 2009. (JIM WATSON/AFP/Getty Images)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:35:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Andong Song Becomes First Chinese Player Ever Taken In NHL Draft</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a1bcf3/sc/13/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Candong0Esong0Enhl0Edraft0Echinese0In0I7678570A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Andong Song Becomes First Chinese Player Ever Taken In NHL Draft
| By                                                                      By TIM REYNOLDS
Updated:
06/27/2015  4:17 pm EDT
SUNRISE, FL - JUNE 27:  AnDong Song poses after being selected 172nd overall by the New York Islanders during the 2015 NHL Draft at BB&amp;T Center on June 27, 2015 in Sunrise, Florida.  (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images) | Mike Ehrmann via Getty Images
reddit
SUNRISE, Fla.  For the first time, a Chinese player has been selected in the NHL draft.
Andong Song was chosen by the New York Islanders with the No. 172 pick in the draft Saturday. The defenseman, who goes by the name "Misha," started playing hockey on a smaller-than-normal rink in Beijing when his mother was trying to find him a sport. Once his talent was spotted, his family moved to Canada and he quickly excelled when he began playing as a 10-year-old.
AnDong Song poses after being selected 172nd overall by the New York Islanders during the 2015 NHL Draft.  (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images)
Now his pro rights belong to the Islanders, his selection broadcast live in China.
"Feels like I'm a star already," said Andong, who was followed by a Chinese television crew Saturday. "But, long way to go."
The fact he's made it this far is something in itself.
When his family moved to Ontario and coaches there heard that a Chinese boy was trying out, there was plenty of skepticism. He proved himself at each level, and was an assistant captain this past season on the varsity at Lawrenceville School in New Jersey.
The 18-year-old Andong, who plays on one of China's national teams, plans to attend Philips Andover Academy in Massachusetts this coming school year as a postgraduate student.
After that, he expects to play college hockey.
"I'm really honored to be the first Chinese player to be drafted," Andong said. "It's been great so far."
He hasn't yet met Islanders owner and governor Charles B. Wang, who was born in Shanghai and moved to the U.S. with his family as a boy. Andong said he and his agent were aware of interest from the Islanders for some time, but didn't absolutely know for certain that he was getting picked until his name was called.
"Being the first Chinese player, it's a lot of pressure from people back home, but good pressure," Andong said. "I hope that will motivate me to become a better player and hopefully I'll make them proud."
One of his earliest memories is watching the U.S. play against Russia at the Salt Lake City Olympics in 2002. China is trying to land the 2022 Winter Games, which is one of many reasons why the game seems to be growing there rapidly.
"When I started playing there weren't a lot of people playing there and not much support for the game," said Andong, whose brother still plays in Beijing. "But last year when I went back, it'd been like eight years since I've seen Chinese hockey, it's just been tremendous how far they've grown. I'm sure they'll keep trying to catch up to North America and Europe and Russia, but there's still a little gap."
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:32:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French Terror Suspect Took Selfie With Beheaded Victim, Officials Say</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a0f18c/sc/3/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Cfrance0Eselfie0Ebeheading0In0I7678560A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>FONTAINES-SUR-SAONE, France (AP) -- Officials say the top suspect in the beheading of a French businessman took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image to at least one recipient.</Description>
        <MainBody>French Terror Suspect Took Selfie With Beheaded Victim, Officials Say
Posted:
Updated:
06/27/2015  1:59 pm EDT
People gather in Bourgoin, southeast of Lyon, France, to pay their respects to the victim of the attack which took place earlier in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, Friday, June 26, 2015. A man with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car Friday into an American gas factory in southeastern France, triggering an explosion that caused injuries, officials said. The severed head of a local businessman was left hanging at the factory's entrance, along with banners with Arabic inscriptions, the | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
FONTAINES-SUR-SAONE, France (AP) -- Officials say the top suspect in the beheading of a French businessman took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image to at least one recipient.
Two French officials said authorities were working to confirm the identity of the recipient, but were not able to immediately confirm media reports that it was sent to an unspecified person in Syria.
On Friday, key suspect Yassine Salhi allegedly crashed a truck into an U.S.-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employer's severed head on a factory gate in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier - in what authorities are calling a terror attack.
He was arrested and remained in police custody on Saturday.
Authorities noted the similarity to tactics used by the Islamic State group, though no group has claimed responsibility for the attack.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:18:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Leaders Reject Greece Bailout Extension Throwing Eurozone Into Crisis</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a0f192/sc/25/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Cgreece0Ebailout0Eextension0Erejected0In0I76784880Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky.</Description>
        <MainBody>European Leaders Reject Greece Bailout Extension Throwing Eurozone Into Crisis
| By                                                                      RAF CASERT and ELENA BECATOROS
Posted:
Updated:
06/27/2015  9:59 pm EDT
Greeks queue in front of the National Bank to use ATM to withdraw cash as Parliament holds an emergency session for the government's proposed referendum June 27, 2015 in Athens, Greece. (Milos Bicanski/Getty Images) | Milos Bicanski via Getty Images
reddit
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky.
Tsipras' surprise call stunned Greece's international debt negotiators, and the country took a big step closer to falling out of the euro currency union after fellow eurozone member states refused to extend its bailout program past its expiry date on Tuesday, leaving Greece on the brink of financial chaos.
In the streets of Greece, worried people queued outside banks for cash from dawn to dusk after Tsipras' announcement in the early hours of Saturday, after billions of euros had already been emptied in the preceding weeks.
Greece has a 1.6 billion euro ($1.8 billion) debt due to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday and its bailout program expires the same day, after which it is unclear how the country might survive financially.
The referendum is set for next Sunday with the question on whether to accept proposed reforms needed to get bailout loans from other eurozone countries and the IMF. The government is advocating a rejection of the proposals.
The radical left-wing leader accused the creditors of using blackmail and ultimatums against his proud but struggling people. European officials and all Greek opposition parties except the extremist far-right Golden Dawn party called his move for a vote a foolish and rash gambit that effectively ended negotiations to keep Greece financially afloat.
The sudden move comes after five months of stalemated negotiations, with Tsipras accusing creditors of trying to strong-arm his country into taking harsh austerity measures he says would hammer an economy already on its knees after months of creditor-demanded spending cuts and tax hikes.
"They didn't ask us to agree, they asked us to surrender our political dignity," Tsipras said during a tumultuous and nearly 13-hour parliamentary session that cumulated in a vote just before 3 a.m. Sunday. Out of parliament's 300 lawmakers, 178 voted in favor and 120 against, with two people absent.
He insisted the Greek side had "exhausted every limit" of concessions so there could be an agreement, adding that "perhaps some saw that as a weakness."
The referendum move further crumbled already strained relations between Greece and its European partners.
Tsipras said the Greek people would vote against a deal next Sunday.
"This no will also be a big yes, a big yes to the decision of the Greek government to reject an ultimatum that insults the Greek people."
Tsipras dismissed harsh criticism from other European countries on his decision.
"The referendum will take place as scheduled, next Sunday, whether our partners want it or not," he said.
Eurozone finance ministers earlier rejected Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis' request for a one-month extension to the bailout program, with Varoufakis then leaving the meeting.
"It's a sad day for Europe, but we will overcome it," he said.
The other 18 finance ministers then huddled without him to assess how to minimize the damage from the Greek crisis on their currency.
"Our institutions are and will be prepared to take any action if needed," said top eurozone official Jeroen Dijsselbloem of fears that financial turbulence might extend to the rest of the currency bloc. Fellow ministers spoke candidly about the risks of a Greek exit from the euro in a way that would have been inconceivable only weeks ago.
The ministers stressed Greece remained in the eurozone for now, and Dijsselbloem said "the eurogroup stands ready to reconvene to take appropriate decisions where needed, in the interest of Greece as euro area member."
Without a bailout program extension or more loans from creditors, Greece is likely to be in arrears on a debt payment due the same day. Its banks face the risk of collapse.
"The Greek authorities have asked for a month extension. But in that month there can be no disbursements," Dijsselbloem said. "How does the Greek government think that it will survive and deal with its problems in that period? I do not know."
France's finance minister, Michel Sapin, stressed a deal was still possible and that he was ready to act as a go-between among Greece and the creditors after relations neared a breaking point.
Dijsselbloem refused to slam the door full shut. "The door is open. It was not the institutions that walked away from the last talks last night."
Now much will depend on whether the European Central Bank will accept to continue to prop up Greek banks even after the country's bailout program expires. It would be under huge pressure to stop using eurozone taxpayer money to keep alive the banks if there is no prospect for a deal.
The eurozone finance ministers suggested Greece should take steps to stabilize its financial system  code for putting limits on cash withdrawals and money transfers.
If Greece's banks collapse, the government would have to support them itself. Penniless, it would have to revert to printing a new currency, effectively drawing the country out of the euro union.
The ECB's governing council will meet "in due course" to assess the situation, most likely this Sunday, officials said.
While Greece's government is recommending a "no" vote on the referendum, Varoufakis noted "the high possibility that the Greek people will vote against the advice of the Greek government."
What would happen in that case  whether Greece would have to leave the euro or try to renegotiate with creditors  is unclear.
An exit from the euro would put Greece through a new era of economic pain. With the new currency less valuable than the euro, the government would have to write off a chunk of its foreign loans  mainly owed to eurozone countries  and many companies and households would go bankrupt. Experts predict a long and deep recession in a country that has already been through five years economic depression.
The uncertainties of all this would roil European and global markets, though experts are divided on the extent. Some say Europe is better equipped to handle a Greek euro exit, but others say it is unclear what might happen. The euro dropped in value slightly on international markets after the referendum was called.
___
Casert reported from Brussels. Demetris Nellas, Thanassis Stavrakis and Paris Ayiomamitis in Athens, Greece, and Derek Gatopoulos and Lorne Cook in Brussels contributed.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:05:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>These Are The World's 5 Most Wanted ISIS Jihadists</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a0bbf7/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Cisis0Emost0Ewanted0Ejihadist0In0I76734660Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Unlike Osama bin Laden, who often appeared in videos to lecture and incite attacks against the West, ISIS’ leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi has kept a low profile, and was reportedly </Description>
        <MainBody>These Are The World's 5 Most Wanted ISIS Jihadists
Vocativ | By                                                                      Jamie Tarabay
reddit
Unlike Osama bin Laden, who often appeared in videos to lecture and incite attacks against the West, ISIS leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi has kept a low profile, and was reportedly seen on camera only once since the militant group declared its caliphate a year ago in June. This makes the $10 million bounty on his whereabouts all the more elusive .
--&gt; More on ISIS from Vocativ : "Angel of Death," an axe-wielding university lecturer in Iraq had become a cult hero in the war against ISIS
The U.S. State Department in May put up major rewards to the tune of $20 million for the capture of ISIS top brass . Secretary of State John Kerry authorized a reward of $7 million for information on Abd al-Rahman Mustafa al-Qaduli, $5 million each for leads on Abu Mohammed al-Adnani and Tarkhan Tayumurazovich Batirashvili and $3 million for Tariq Bin-al-Tahar Bin al Falih al-Awni al-Harzi.
The biggest reward of $10 million is reserved for the person with information on al-Baghdadi, who has been on the State Departments most-wanted list since 2011, years before ISIS became a household name.
Since its inception, the State Departments Rewards for Justice program has forked over $125 million to over 80 people who have provided intel that helped put the wanted behind bars, according to its website. The programs biggest reward to date is $25 million for leads to bin Laden, but no one ever collected on that money.
The 43-year-old al-Baghdadi, also goes by the name Abu Dua. Overseing all ISIS operations, he is currently based in Syria.
According to the U.S. government, Baghdadi has taken personal credit for a series of deadly attacks in Iraq since 2011, including the June 2013 Abu Ghraib prison break and the March 2013 suicide bombing on the Ministry of Justice in which at least 20 people were killed.
Abd al-Rahman Mustafa al-Qaduli is a senior ISIS official who rejoined the group in Syria after his release from Iraqi prison in early 2012. Al-Qaduli joined al-Qaida in 2004 under the command of now deceased al-Qaida in Iraq (AQI) leader Abu Musab al-Zarqawi and served as al-Zarqawis deputy and the AQI amir (leader) of Mosul in northern Iraq.
Abu Mohammed al-Adnani, born Taha Sobhi Falaha in Syria, is the official spokesman for and a senior leader of ISIS. Al-Adnani is the main conduit for the dissemination of official messages, including ISIS declaration that it had established an Islamic caliphate.
Over the past several years, Syria-based Georgian national Tarkhan Tayumurazovich Batirashvili, also known as Omar the Chechen, has held a number of top military positions within ISIS.
As of mid-2014, Batirashvili has been a senior ISIS commander and Shura Council member based in al-Raqqah, Syria. He was identified as the ISIS military commander in a public video distributed by the group in late June 2014. Batirashvili oversaw an ISIS prison facility in al-Tabqa, close to al-Raqqah, where the group possibly held foreign hostages. As of mid-2014, Batirashvili also coordinated closely with the groups financial section and had a base of operations for the terrorist organization in the Minbij, Syria area.
As of mid-2014, Tariq Bin-al-Tahar Bin al Falih al-Awni al-Harzi has been an ISIS official operating in Syria. He works to raise funds, recruit, equip and facilitate the travel of fighters for the terrorist organization. He also commands the groups suicide bombers. He works to provide material support to ISIS by procuring and shipping weapons with his brother from Libya and Syria, including raising funds from Gulf-based donors.
Visit Vocativ.com for complete coverage of ISIS:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:57:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia Pledges Tough Security Measures After Sousse Hotel Attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a0bbf8/sc/3/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Ctunisia0Esecurity0Ehotel0Eattack0In0I76783440Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS, Tunisia (AP) — Thousands of tourists fled from Tunisia on Saturday after the country's worst terrorist attack killed 38 people — including 15 Britons — as the government struggles to prevent future jihadi attacks against the all-important tourism sector.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia Pledges Tough Security Measures After Sousse Hotel Attack
| By                                                                      BOUAZZA BEN BOUAZZA and PAUL SCHEMM
Posted:
Updated:
06/27/2015  3:59 pm EDT
Tunisian security forces man a checkpoint at the entrance of the resort area where is located the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Port el Kantaoui, on the outskirts of Sousse south of the capital Tunis, on June 27, 2015. (FETHI BELAID/AFP/Getty Images) | FETHI BELAID via Getty Images
reddit
TUNIS, Tunisia (AP)  Thousands of tourists fled from Tunisia on Saturday after the country's worst terrorist attack killed 38 people  including 15 Britons  as the government struggles to prevent future jihadi attacks against the all-important tourism sector.
New measures to increase the numbers of troops on the streets and crack down on organizations with radical links, however, won't bring the tourists back in the short-term, further threatening the fragile economy.
When a 24-year-old Master's student at Kairouan University strolled on to the Sousse beach and pulled out a Kalashnikov assault rifle and grenades hidden inside his beach umbrella, he was sounding the death knell for Tunisia's 2015 tourist season.
Tunisian authorities identified the attacker as Seifeddine Rezgui, saying he killed 38 people, 15 of them British, as well as German, Irish, Belgian and Portuguese victims, and sent thousands of tourists fleeing to airports. The wounded included 24 Britons, seven Tunisians, three Belgians, and a German, Russian and Ukrainian.
"It's the first time I've ever been on holiday and feared for my life," said British tourist Matthew Preece, adding it was his third time visiting Tunisia and likely his last. "So obviously you can't come back somewhere it's not safe."
Tourists and employees are returning home with tales of horror cowering in rooms or offices as the killer stalked through the hotel wearing shorts.
European countries and tour operators sent planes to evacuate their citizens. By midday Saturday, nine flights had whisked away 1,400 people, according to Mohammed Walid Ben Ghachem, manager of the Enfidha-Hammamet Airport near Sousse.
At the Imperial Marhaba Hotel itself, the guests had left, according to manager Mohammed Becheur.
"We may have zero clients today, but we will keep our staff," he said, lamenting the 75-percent occupancy rate the day before. "This summer will be hard, but we are very confident for the long term."
On the beach, there were still a few tourists from neighboring hotels. Some laid flowers at the site of the attack while police patrolling on horseback moved down the beach and security boats patrolled the waters.
Armed men on the beach may well become a more common sight in Tunisia, as Prime Minister Habib Essid announced a raft of new security measures that many have questioned why they weren't implemented after the last horrific attack against tourists in March at the National Bardo Museum that killed 22.
"It's clear that the government's security policy requires a massive revision, in the sense that most of the tourist sites weren't well-protected," Tunisian security analyst Alaya Allani said. "If the measures announced are well implemented, we could reduce but not eradicate terrorism."
Essid called up the army reserves and said there would now be armed men in the hotels and at tourists sites and he also promised to crack down on unregulated mosques that preached extremist ideas and close down organizations with shadowy funding and extremist links.
North Africa analyst Geoff Porter noted that in the short term, these measures will only drive the extremists underground and create a militarized feel to the country that might well discourage tourism.
"Tunisia's in a difficult position, you can harden a tourist site and make it more difficult to attack but the same measures would deter tourists," he said. "Tourists don't want to come and lie on a beach with guys with AK-47s."
And Tunisia needs these tourists, especially in the coastal resort areas like Sousse where it is the dominant industry. Tourist made up nearly 15 percent of gross domestic product in 2014 and it has been struggling to recover after the shocks of the Arab Spring revolution.
The attack was claimed by the radical Islamic State group, which thousands of Tunisians, disaffected with the lack of opportunity in the wake of the 2011 overthrow of secular President Zine El Abidine Ben Ali, have joined.
The attack came the same day that a suicide bomber killed 27 people in a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and a man in France ran his truck into a warehouse and hung his employer's severed head on the gate.
The attack in Kuwait was also claimed by the Islamic State and on Saturday thousands of people took part in a mass funeral procession. Police said they are interrogating a number of suspects with possible links to the bombing, which was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group.
Extremists have increasingly attacked soldiers and politicians in Tunisia over the past few years, but it was only with the March museum attack that it began targeting the tourism life blood of the country that will only deepen its economic crisis.
The presence of a few people still on the beaches a day after the attack does give some glimmers of hope, especially if world memory is short and people return attracted by the low prices and white sands of the beach.
"We want to see our holiday out," said Peter Phillips of Wales as he stood on the beach not far from where the attack happened.
It all may hinge, however, on whether the government can put an end to these attacks, which senior security official Rafik Chelli called an "isolated incident" that is difficult to guard against and could happen anywhere.
"If this attack doesn't do it, any subsequent attack will," Porter said. "It is hard to envision Tunisian tourism recovering from this attack and impossible to envision it recovering from a third one."
___
Paul Schemm reported from Rabat. Associated Press reporters Elaine Ganley and Benjamin Wiacek in Sousse, Tunisia, and Shawn Pogatchnik in Dublin contributed to this report.
___
This story has been corrected to show the surname of the British tourist is Preece, not Price. A previous version of this story was corrected to show that the gunman killed 38 people, not 39.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:10:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dalai Lama's 80th Birthday Wish Is That We All Live #WithCompassion</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a0c714/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Cdalai0Elama0E80Ath0Ebirthday0In0I76747320Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Dalai Lama is turning 80 years old on July 6, but he doesn’t want any gifts. Instead, your social media presence is the present.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
The Dalai Lama is turning 80 years old on July 6, but he doesnt want any gifts. Instead, your social media presence is the present.
In honor of his milestone birthday, His Holiness is asking people to share photos, videos and quotes depicting people simply treating one another kindly, along with the hashtag #withcompassion on social accounts.
He has done so much to spread peace and compassion to the world  this is our opportunity to truly say thank you and to show him the incredible impact his work has on the global community, Ven. Lama Tenzin Dhonden, founder and chair of Friends of the Dalai Lama nonprofit , said in an email statement.
The Dalai Lamas network of friends -- including Common, Arianna Huffington, Larry King, Russell Simmons and Randy Jackson -- are helping get the word out in the video above. Watch the clip and help celebrate the big day by sharing a post about what it means to live #withcompassion.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:08:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Behind Khamenei's Recent Red Lines for a Nuclear Deal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a0f19f/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cshahir0Eshahidsaless0Cbehind0Ekhameneis0Erecent0Er0Ib0I76782340Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In his fiery remarks on June 23rd, Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei delineated major red lines in nuclear negotiations. According to his</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
In his fiery remarks on June 23rd, Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei delineated major red lines in nuclear negotiations. According to his official twitter account , the seven items listed as red lines cover four basic areas: sanctions relief, sunset provisions for uranium enrichment, R&amp;D and access for International Atomic Energy Agency's (IAEA) inspectors.
The red lines undoubtedly contrast with the framework agreement that was reached in Lausanne, according to the fact sheet published in April by the U.S. State Department. However, immediately following the U.S. State Department's publication of its fact sheet in April, Iran publicly disagreed with its contents. This was apparent when Ayatollah Khamenei declared that the fact sheet showed "devilish" American intentions.
Now, Khamenei's delineation of red lines has left many observers and politicians scratching their head, wondering why the Ayatollah would adopt such an aggressive posture as the Iran nuclear talks enter the last lap of this marathon. According to many experts, these red lines could most likely break the deal altogether.
There may be multiple explanations for these remarks.
Domestic public appearance
Perhaps the most popular explanation among experts and politicians, including the US Secretary of State, John Kerry, is that the statements were designed for domestic consumption. "We are not going to be guided by or conditioned by or affected or deterred by some tweet that is for public consumption or domestic political consumption," Kerry reacted to the comments.
In other words, based on this argument, Ayatollah Khamenei issued the red lines to maintain stature among conservatives, as the leader that continues to spearhead resistance against the "global arrogance" led by the United States. However, this explanation is flawed.
If a deal is soon reached and Khamenei's red lines are crossed, his stature would severely suffer, likely resulting in dire consequences that might ultimately ensue. Those that dispute the notion of simple posturing for domestic consumption are his conservative supporters, primarily the security-military apparatus. What would they think of Vali-e Faqih (Guardian jurist), the symbol of revolutionary Islam, if a deal is struck and the red lines set by him are crossed? How can the Ayatollah explain that for the conservatives? Does he lack enough authority on the negotiating team or did his public opposition to apparently-negotiated terms amount to hollow rhetoric?
Effort to scuttle a deal
Another explanation is that as we near the precipice of negotiations, i.e., the actualization of a nuclear deal, Ayatollah Khamenei may be worried about the consequences of compromise on the nuclear issue so he set these strict red lines to torpedo the possibility of any deal.
A resolution to the nuclear crisis may lead to normalization of relations between Iran and the U.S. It is true that Iran seeks better relations with America to reduce threats to its survival, but the leadership harbors strong reservations about normal relations.
Ayatollah Khamenei has repeatedly asserted his opinion that because the Iranian establishment rejects foreign domination, the U.S. ultimately seeks regime change in its own effort to establish a puppet government. Drawing on experience from the 1953 coup, Ayatollah Khamenei contends that normal relations would prepare the grounds for infiltration by Americans' intelligence and spies who seek links to opposition inside Iran, undermining the nezam (state).
Additionally, normal relations will most likely lead to cultural exchanges which could erode religious beliefs in Iranian society and ultimately undermine the influence of the Islamic system.
Actualization of a nuclear deal could also be problematic from another angle. Iran's leader has repeatedly said , "I'm not optimistic about the talks and they will not get anywhere, but I'm not opposed to them." Therefore, the successful conclusion of nuclear talks would call into question the political vision and judgment of the Supreme Leader.
Saiid Ghasemi, a former commander of the IRGC and one of the leaders of the hard-line vigilante group, Ansar-e Hezbollah once remarked , "If the [nuclear] talks conclude we must say goodbye to the [the system] of Veyat-e faqih (guardianship of the jurist)," which is the foundation of Iran's Islamic system.
Despite all of the arguments which support scuttling a deal, Iran's ravaged economy threatens the very survival of the state. A poor economy could cause not only domestic unrest, but it also threatens its foothold and influence in Iraq, Syria and Lebanon as a means to confront the US, Israel, and Arab threats. Iran desperately needs sanctions relief and access to its estimated $100 billion in blocked assets.
In fact, Ayatollah Khamenei's dramatic shift in approach toward the US, abandoning the years-long policy of banning talks with them, was motivated by understanding the dangers of continuing such policies, and the perpetuation and intensification of sanctions that would result. Therefore, the theory that the Ayatollah made his most recent remarks to abort the talks defies logic.
Overconfidence
The last explanation is that Iranians are greatly overconfident and perceive that conditions are in their favor and that they can exploit the opportunity to impose their demands on the other side. Sobh-e Sadegh, the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) publication, once explained the logic behind this stance as follows:
"The Iranian side ... has been able to create a necessary crack in the body of sanctions. The eagerness of economic centers to conduct business with Iran reveals that the crack is irreparable and it is highly unlikely, if not impossible to return to the past situation."
This sense of overconfidence also emanates from the widely popular perception among high echelon Iranians, including Iran's leader and former president and current chairman of the Expediency Discernment Council, Ali Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani , that Americans need a nuclear deal more than Iranians. The Iranians believe that they must take advantage of this opportunity and adopt a maximalist position to ensure that world powers reduce concessions to the bare minimum, if not altogether.
The world may learn whether this is a miscalculation within days.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 18:33:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands Of Kuwaiti Sunnis, Shiites Come Together For Mass Funeral After ISIS Mosque Attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a06fa0/sc/3/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C270Ckuwait0Efuneral0Eisis0Eattack0In0I76780A280Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KUWAIT CITY (AP) -- Thousands of people in Kuwait took part in a mass funeral procession Saturday for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing that targeted a Shiite mosque a day earlier.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thousands Of Kuwaiti Sunnis, Shiites Come Together For Mass Funeral After ISIS Mosque Attack
Posted:
reddit
KUWAIT CITY (AP) -- Thousands of people in Kuwait took part in a mass funeral procession Saturday for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing that targeted a Shiite mosque a day earlier.
Police in Kuwait said they are interrogating a number of suspects with possible links to the suicide bombing, which was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group.
Mourners carry the body of one of the victims of the ISIS attack during a mass funeral at Jaafari cemetery in Kuwait City on June 27, 2015. (YASSER AL-ZAYYAT/AFP/Getty Images)
An Interior Ministry statement Saturday said police arrested the owner of the car that was used by the bomber to drive to the Imam Sadiq Mosque in Kuwait City, where he detonated his device inside among the worshippers. Police did not say how many suspects are being interrogated.
The bombing, which also wounded more than 200 male worshippers who were taking part in midday Friday prayers, was the first terrorist attack in Kuwait in more than two decades.
The government helped plan Saturday's mass funeral for those killed. Thousands of Sunnis and Shiites from across the country took part in the procession and prayer at Kuwait's Grand Mosque. Many carried the Kuwaiti flag; others a simple black flag to signify mourning. Some in the crowd chanted, "Sunnis and Shiites are brothers!"
Kuwaiti men react at the site of a suicide bombing at Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City. (YASSER AL-ZAYYAT/AFP/Getty Images)
Sunni groups in Kuwait and leaders from across the Middle East have strongly condemned the attack, which Gulf officials say is aimed at provoking a backlash from Shiites and sparking sectarian war. More than a third of Kuwait's 1.2 million citizens are believed to be Shiite. The majority of Kuwaitis are Sunni Muslims.
Kuwait's Deputy Prime Minister and Interior Minister Sheikh Mohammed Al-Hamad Al-Sabah was quoted in the official Kuwait News Agency describing the bombing as "grotesque" and vowing to "cut the evil hand" that tampers with the country's security.
The news agency also carried a statement from Iraq's top Shiite cleric, Grand Ayatollah Ali al-Sistani, extending his condolences to the families of the victims.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
