<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:04:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Helen Hunt Says Women In Hollywood Are 'F*cked'</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/helen-hunt-women-in-hollywood_n_7184620.html</Link>
        <Description>Even an Oscar winner like Helen Hunt feels the immense challenges of being a woman in Hollywood, she told HuffPost Live on Thursday. </Description>
        <MainBody>

The Skinnygirl mogul and "Real Housewives" star chatted with HuffPost Live's Caitlyn Becker on April 29, 2015.
The Terminator himself cozies up with HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri and "Maggie" director Henry Hobson on April 22, 2015.
The iconic comedian joined HuffPost Live on April 20, 2015, along with filmmaker Paul Weitz, director of the comedy "Grandma."
Peggy Olson herself dropped by to chat about all things "Mad Men" on April 2, 2015.
Chris Messina chatted with HuffPost Live about "The Mindy Project" and more On April 1, 2015.
The rapper dropped by to discuss "Furious 7" on March 27, 2015.
New mom Kelly Rowland dropped by to chat with HuffPost Live's Marc Lamont Hill on March 20, 2015.
The baddest man on the planet got seriously enthusiastic with host Marc Lamont Hill during a conversation about his documentary "Champs" on March 12, 2015.
Lily James and Richard Madden dropped by to discuss their fairytale film on March 9, 2015.
The iconic fashion designer brought a splash of style to her interview with Caroline Modarressy-Tehrani on Feb. 24, 2015.
Arianna Huffington interviewed Christine Lagarde, managing director of the International Monetary Fund, on Feb. 23, 2015.
The star of NBC's "The Slap" wishes HuffPost a very enthusiastic happy birthday after his interview on Feb. 19, 2015.
The star of "Shameless" opened up to HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri on Feb. 12, 2015.
The stunning supermodel lit up the HuffPost Live studio on Feb. 10, 2015, to dish on her role in the new hit series "Empire."
The stars of "Kingsman: The Secret Service" looked perfectly debonair on the HuffPost Live set on Feb. 10, 2015.
The Dude abides, and he also drops by HuffPost Live. Jeff Bridges chats with host Ricky Camilleri on Feb. 2, 2015.
The stars of "The Boy Next Door" bring a flawless glow to the HuffPost Live studio on Jan. 21, 2015.
Things got "CrazySexyCool" in the HuffPost Live studio when Chilli and T-Boz of TLC dropped by on Jan. 19, 2015.
The boxing champ knuckles up with HuffPost sports columnist Jordan Schultz on Jan. 16, 2015.
Talk about star power! Julianne Moore cozies up to her "Still Alice" co-star Kristen Stewart on Jan. 13, 2015.
The former president chats with Arianna Huffington backstage at HuffPost Live on Jan. 13, 2015.
The actor chats with HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri on Jan. 7, 2015, about "Birdman," "Batman" and his iconic career.
The hilarious Jane Lynch put a smile on host Alyona Minkovski's face when she stopped by to chat about the final season of "Glee" on Jan. 7, 2015.
Felicity Jones stopped by on Jan. 6, 2015, to chat about her role in the buzzy Stephen Hawking biopic "The Theory Of Everything."
The Academy Award-winner chatted with HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri on Jan. 5, 2015, about her film "Two Days, One Night."
Things got a little "Wild" when Laura Dern and author Cheryl Strayed stopped by HuffPost Live on Dec. 2, 2014, to discuss the film adaptation of Strayed's memoir.
Kristin Chenoweth brought some beautiful music to HuffPost Live when she chatted with Ricky Camilleri on Nov. 20, 2014.
Russell Brand snuggles up to HuffPost Live's Josh Zepps on Nov. 19, 2014.
The television icon behind "All In The Family," "The Jeffersons" and more spoke with HuffPost Live's Roy Sekoff about his new memoir "Even This I Get To Experience" on Nov. 19, 2014.
HuffPost Live hit the road on Nov. 11, 2014, when Roy Sekoff joined Jon Stewart at his "Daily Show" studio to discuss Stewart's directorial debut, "Rosewater."
Spiritual leader Deepak Chopra chatted with HuffPost Live's Caroline Modarressy-Tehrani on Nov. 11, 2014.
The one and only J.Lo stopped by the studio for a frank conversation about her memoir "True Love" with Arianna Huffington on Nov. 4, 2014.
The laughs never stopped when the hands-down hilarious Lisa Kudrow joined HuffPost Live to gab about the new season of "The Comeback" on Nov. 4, 2014.
"Nightcrawler" star Jake Gyllenhaal and director Dan Gilroy gave HuffPost Live the scoop of their top-notch film on Nov. 3, 2014.
The HuffPost Live studio lit up with star power when Angela Bassett and Dionne Warwick stopped to chat in between their interviews on Oct. 27, 2014.
Retro beauty Dita Von Teese lit up the HuffPost Live studio when she stopped by on Oct. 17, 2014, to chat about her new line of lingerie.
Transgender activist and "Orange Is The New Black" star Laverne Cox stopped by the HuffPost Live studio on Oct. 16, 2014. Joining Cox and host Marc Lamont Hill was Shane Henise and L'lerrt Ailith, stars of "The T Word," which documents the lives of seven young trans people.
The hilarious Michael Cera took a spot on the HuffPost Live couch Oct. 14, 2014, to chat about his work on the Broadway stage in "This Is Our Youth."
It doesn't get much funnier than this! Keegan-Michael Key and Jordan Peele crashed the set during HuffPost Live's interview with the cast of "The League," including Mark Duplass, Katie Aselton, Sstephen Rannazzisi, Jon Lajoie and Jason Mantzoukas.
The HuffPost Live studio enjoyed some side-splitting laughs when Chelsea Handler dropped by on Oct. 10, 2014.
Kim Cattrall hit the HuffPost Live studio Sept. 24, 2014, looking every bit as fabulous as Samantha Jones.
The master of horror himself joined HuffPost Live's Josh Zepps for a wide-ranging conversation on Sept. 24, 2014.
Bill Hader dropped by the HuffPost Live studio on Sept. 16, 2014, to chat about his dramatic turn in the new film "The Skeleton Twins."
We didn't have any cake, but HuffPost Live still rang in Nick Jonas' 22nd birthday with a celebratory steak on Sept. 16, 2014.
The hilarious Mindy Kaling put a smile on our faces and shared the scoop of season three of "The Mindy Project" on Sept. 12, 2014.
HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri chatted with the one and only Connie Britton about "Nashville," "Friday Night Lights" and her film "This Is Where I Leave You" on Sept. 9, 2014
The "Cornflake Girl" herself Tori Amos visited the HuffPost live studio on Aug. 14, 2014.
Matthew Weiner, the brain behind "Mad Men," spoke with HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri about his new film "Are You Here" on Aug. 13, 2014.
Kiss frontman Gene Simmons brought a dose of rock 'n' roll to HuffPost Live on Aug. 11, 2014.
"Today" host Hoda Kotb blows out a candle from afar as she celebrates her 50th birthday with HuffPost Live's Caroline Modarressy-Tehrani and comedian Lisa Lampanelli on Aug. 7, 2014.
"Vampire Diaries" vixen Nina Dobrev stopped by HuffPost Live on Aug. 4, 2014.
The always hilarious Joel McHale joins HuffPost Live on July 29, 2014, to talk "Community," "The Soup" and more.
Maggie Gyllenhaal grabs a seat on the HuffPost Live couch to chat about her miniseries "The Honorable Woman."
"Modern Family" star Eric Stonestreet chats with host Caitlyn Becker on July 23, 2014.
"True Blood" star Anna Paquin dishes on the vampire drama's final season with HuffPost Live's Alyona Minkovski on July 15, 2014.
Hollywood icon Rob Reiner and HuffPost Live's Roy Sekoff share a sandwich from Katz's Deli -- home of the famed "When Harry Met Sally..." fake orgasm scene -- on July 9, 2014.
Aaron Paul dropped by HuffPost Live on June 13 to discuss his new film "Hellion" and answer a few "Breaking Bad" questions.
NBA star Jeremy Lin discusses his off-the-court work with the Jeremy Lin Foundation on June 10, 2014.
Astrophysicist Neil deGrasse Tyson has some fun with HuffPost Live's Josh Zepps during a chat about "Cosmos" on June 9, 2014.
The head of the Kardashian clan brightens up the HuffPost Live studio on June 5, 2014.
"Cougar Town" star Busy Philipps pops in yellow on the HuffPost Live set on May 29, 2014.
Teen pop sensation Austin Mahone dropped by the studio on May 27, 2014 to chat about his album "The Secret."
Tyler The Creator, Earl Sweatshirt and the boys of Odd Future spit a few rhymes on the HuffPost Live set on May 14, 2014.
Film legend Robert Duvall makes a big statement to HuffPost Live President Roy Sekoff on May 14, 2014.
The star-studded cast of HBO's "The Normal Heart" -- including Marc Ruffalo, Julia Roberts, director Ryan Murphy, Jim Parsons, Matt Bomer and Taylor Kitsch -- joined HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri to discuss their film on May 12, 2014.
Acclaimed director Spike Lee poses with Marc Lamont Hill on May 12, 2014.
Supermodel Chrissy Teigen kicks up her heels with HuffPost Live's Marc Lamont Hill on May 8, 2014.
Hip-hop legend Nas discussed the 20th anniversary of his debut album "Illmatic" on April 15, 2014.
Kevin Costner joins HuffPost Live to discuss his film "Draft Day" on April 10, 2014.
Kathy Griffin shares a laugh with HuffPost Live's Caitlyn Becker on April 9, 2014.
The stylish Kelly Osbourne shows off a colorful springtime look on April 9, 2014.
Supermodel and actress Brooklyn Decker shocks host Marc Lamont Hill during a conversation about her series "Friends With Better Lives" on April 8, 2014.
Host Marc Lamont Hill is all smiles with "The Cosby Show" matriarch Phylicia Rashad, who discussed her film "Frankie &amp; Alice" on April 3, 2014.
Nick Cannon shows off a stylish pair of shoes on the HuffPost Live set on April 2, 2014.
President Jimmy Carter joins HuffPost Live on March 25, 2014, to discuss his book "A Call To Action: Women, Religion, Violence, and Power."
HuffPost Live's namesake hits the set! Arianna Huffington joins Caroline Modarressy-Tehrani ono March 25, 2014, to discuss her book "Thrive: The Third Metric to Redefining Success and Creating a Life of Well-Being, Wisdom, and Wonder."
Hulkamania ran wild on HuffPost Live when Hulk Hogan joined to discuss Wrestlemania 30 on March 24, 2014.
Emmy Rossum strikes a pose in the HuffPost Live studio on March 13, 2014.
Mary-Louise Parker chats with host Josh Zepps about why she's rallying behind Hope North, a charity which aims to educate and heal the young victims of Ugandas civil war, on March 12, 2014.
The Duggar Family piles into the HuffPost Live studio with host Nancy Redd on March 10, 2014.
Kristen Bell joins Ricky Camilleri to dish on the "Veronica Mars" movie on March 10, 2014.
Russell Simmons schools HuffPost Live's Caroline Modarressy-Tehrani on all things meditation on March 6, 2014.
The fabulous Naomi Campbell joins HuffPost Live on March 5, 2014, to chat about the second season of her reality series "The Face."
"The Walking Dead" star Norman Reedus snuggles up with host Caitlyn Becker on Feb. 27, 2014.
Jackie Collins joins HuffPost Live on Feb. 4, 2014, to talk about her 30th novel, love, life and more.
The stars of Comedy Central's "Workaholics"  Blake Anderson, Anders Holm, and Adam DeVine  stop by HuffPost Live on Feb. 4, 2014, to discuss season four of their hit show, the Superbowl and all things wizard.
"Brooklyn Nine-Nine" star Terry Crews shows off his legendary strength at HuffPost Live on Jan. 31, 2013.
Jerome "The Bus" Bettis and Barry Sanders catch up in the HuffPost Live green room on Jan. 31, 2014.
Larry King joins HuffPost Live host Marc Lamont Hill on Jan. 29, 2014.
Jerry Springer joins HuffPost Live's Alyona Minkovski on Jan. 28, 2014, to discuss his new show, "Tabloid."
As the youngest-ever gold medalist, ice skating champion Tara Lipinski knows well the pressure facing Olympic athletes as they head to Sochi. She joined HuffPost Live's Caroline Modarressy-Tehrani on Jan. 27, 2014, to preview the Winter Games.
HuffPost Live's Caitlyn Becker keeps up with Kardashian family matriarch Kris Jenner on Jan. 10, 2014.
Esperanza Spalding joins Marc Lamont Hill to co-host a HuffPost Live discussion about closing Guantanamo Bay on Jan. 8, 2014.
"Full House" star Candace Cameron Bure shares a laugh with HuffPost Live's Nancy Redd on Jan. 6, 2014.
"Dallas Buyers Club" star Jared Leto goofs off with HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri on Dec. 17, 2013.
Eva Longoria visits the HuffPost Live studio on Dec. 10, 2013.
Dick Cavett took over the HuffPost Live studio on Dec. 6, 2013, to interview Stephen Fry.
Bruce Dern joins HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri to discuss his critically-acclaimed role in "Nebraska" on Dec. 5, 2013.
Comedian Sarah Silverman gets a laugh out of HuffPost Live's Marc Lamont Hill on Nov. 22, 2013.
David Blaine works his magic on HuffPost Live's Ricky Camilleri on Nov. 18, 2013.
T-Boz and Chilli of TLC cross paths with Soleil Moon-Frye on the HuffPost Live set on Oct. 17, 2013.
Music legend Tony Bennett chats with HuffPost Live's Marc Lamont Hill on Oct. 8, 2013.
Sheryl Crow is giddy to chat with HuffPost Live's Josh Zepps on Sept. 11, 2013.
Dennis Rodman dished on his trips to North Korea with HuffPost Live's Marc Lamont Hill on Aug. 29, 2013.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:02:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>22 Movies That Will Relieve Your Summer Blockbuster Fatigue</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/summer-indie-movie-preview-2015_n_7180606.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>

Writen and directed by Joss Whedon   Starring Robert Downey Jr., Chris Hemsworth, Mark Ruffalo, Chris Evans, Scarlett Johansson, Jeremy Renner, Don Cheadle, Idris Elba and Samuel L. Jackson   What to expect: The first blockbuster out of the gate could bulldoze the entire summer lineup. The original "Avengers," released in 2012, raked in $1.5 billion worldwide and became the third highest-grossing movie of all time. Its follow-up looks much grimmer, but the ever-expanding cast -- which this time includes James Spader as Ultron, Elizabeth Olsen as Scarlet Witch, Aaron Taylor-Johnson as Quicksilver and Andy Serkis as Ulysses Klaue -- won't leave Marvel's merry brand of superheroes hunting for loose change. [Trailer]
Directed by Anne Fletcher  Written by David Feeney and John Quaintance   Starring Reese Witherspoon, Sofia Vergara, Robert Kazinsky and John Carroll Lynch   What to expect: The trailer didn't overwhelm us, but we'll buy tickets for anything that signals Reese Witherspoon's return to comedy. She plays a bumbling police officer who's called upon to protect the wife of a drug dealer (Sofia Vergara). [Trailer]
Directed by George Miller  Written by George Miller, Brendan McCarthy and Nico Lathouris   Starring Tom Hardy, Charlize Theron, Nicholas Hoult, Hugh Keays-Byrne, Riley Keough and Zo Kravitz   What to expect: C'mon, have you seen the trailer? It is a smoking hot post-apocalyptic thrill ride with enough adrenaline to fuel a small nation. Directed by the same guy who made the 1979 original starring Mel Gibson, "Mad Max" looks like the summer's most promising reboot. [Trailer]
Directed by Elizabeth Banks  Written by Kay Cannon   Starring Anna Kendrick, Skylar Astin, Rebel Wilson, Brittany Snow, Ester Dean, Anna Camp and Hailee Steinfeld   What to expect: The Barden Bellas are taking their act global, competing in a worldwide competition that no American group has ever won. If the trailers are reliable, prepare to hear "Before He Cheats," "Bootylicious," "Wrecking Ball" and Run the World (Girls)"  Don't miss it: "Pitch Perfect 3" is already warming up. [Trailer]
Directed by Gil Kenan  Written by David Lindsay-Abaire   Starring Sam Rockwell, Jared Harris, Rosemarie DeWitt, Saxon Sharbino and Kyle Catlett   What to expect: Jared Harris is no Zelda Rubinstein, but we're intrigued by this cast nonetheless -- not to mention screenwriter David Lindsay-Abaire, who won the Pulitzer for "Rabbit Hole." The trouble will come in offering a fresh take on the 1982 original, which helped to set the template for haunted-house thrillers. [Trailer]
Directed by Brad Bird  Written by Damon Lindelof and Brad Bird   Starring Britt Robertson, George Clooney, Hugh Laurie, Kathryn Hahn, Tim McGraw, Keegan-Michael Key and Judy Greer   What to expect: Inspired by the Disney theme parks' futuristic vision of the same name, "Tomorrowland" casts George Clooney as an inventor who teams up with a curious teenager (Britt Robertson) to explore a mysterious place that transcends space and time. Disney has been teasing this movie since 2011, and it wasn't until last month's trailer teased something about parallel realities and fixing the future (nice to see you again, "Interstellar") that we got legitimate clues regarding the strange world(s) this movie inhabits. [Trailer]
Directed by Brad Peyton  Written by Allan Loeb, Carlton Cuse, Carey Hayes, Chad Hayes, Jeremy Passmore and Andre Fabrizio   Starring Dwayne Johnson, Alexandra Daddario, Paul Giamatt, Kylie Minogue, Carla Gugino and Colton Haynes   What to expect: Can Dwayne Johnson topline an action blockbuster as lucratively as he has the "Fast &amp; Furious" sequels and brand-name fare like "Hercules" and "G.I. Joe: Retaliation"? He's pretty much selling this movie solo style, unless people are naturally inclined to see a $100 million disaster flick about a California earthquake. What's that you say? "The Day After Tomorrow" grossed $544 million? Oh, okay. [Trailer]
Written and directed by Cameron Crowe   Starring Bradley Cooper, Emma Stone, Rachel McAdams, Alec Baldwin, Bill Murray and John Krasinski   What to expect: Aloha, Cameron Crowe! The "Jerry Maguire" and "Almost Famous" director's Hawaii-set romantic dramedy has been in the offing since 2008, when Ben Stiller and Reese Witherspoon were cast and the movie was going to be called "Deep Tiki." Seven years later, "Aloha" probably won't provide the box office's sunniest receipts, but with a cast this great, don't discount it as a potential sleeper hit -- that is, if Amy Pascal's hacked condemnation doesn't bode poorly for its performance. [Trailer]
Written and directed by Doug Ellin   Starring Jeremy Piven, Kevin Connolly, Adrian Grenier, Kevin Dillon, Jerry Ferrara and a trillion other people   What to expect: You know the drill. The on-again, off-again big-screen update of the HBO comedy is finally here. The movie is expected to pick up six months after the events of 2011's series finale, with Ari footing the bill for Vince's costly directorial debut. The guys filmed footage at January's Golden Globes, so we'll see what all of that was about soon enough. [Trailer]
Written and directed by Paul Feig   Starring Melissa McCarthy, Rose Byrne, Jason Statham, Miranda Hart, Bobby Cannavale, Allison Janney, Jude Law and Curtis "50 Cent" Jackson   What to expect: The action comedy is Melissa McCarthy and Paul Feig's third movie together following "Bridesmaids" and "The Heat." Early reviews out of South by Southwest were largely glowing, praising the dynamic between McCarthy and the ever-funny Rose Byrne. [Trailer]
Written and directed by Leigh Whannell   Starring Dermot Mulroney, Stefanie Scott, Angus Sampson, Leigh Whannell and Lin Shaye   What to expect: This is the first "Insidious" entry not directed by James Wan. Also out of commission are Patrick Wilson and Rose Bryne, which makes sense because we're now in prequel territory. You will, however, see medium Elise Rainier (Lin Shaye) alive again after appearing as a ghost in "Insidious: Chapter 2." In this one, a teenage girl faces paranormal hauntings. [Trailer]
Directed by Colin Trevorrow  Written by Rick Jaffa, Amanda Silver, Colin Trevorrow and Derek Connolly   Starring Chris Pratt, Bryce Dallas Howard, Vincent D'Onofrio, Ty Simpkins, Omar Sy, Jake Johnson and B. D. Wong   What to expect: After 14 years of endless development rumors, a new "Jurassic Park" is finally upon us -- and it stars Mr. Movie Star 2015 himself, Chris Pratt. We'll see what "Safety Not Guaranteed" director Colin Trevorrow -- the latest in a long line of indie auteurs who've transitioned to big-budget spectacles -- can cook up in Steven Spielberg's prehistoric lab. [Trailer]
Directed by Alfonso Gomez-Rejon  Written by Jesse Andrews   Starring Thomas Mann, Olivia Cooke, Jon Bernthal, Nick Offerman, Molly Shannon and Connie Britton   What to expect: Praised at Sundance as this summer's "The Fault in Our Stars," the twee "Me and Early and the Dying Girl" notched one of the festival's most lucrative distribution deals and won the grand jury prize. Based on Jesse Andrews' 2012 young-adult novel, this may just be the movie to rescue you from the summer's high-octane lineup. [Trailer]
Directed by Pete Docter  Written by Pete Docter, Meg LeFauve and Josh Cooley   Starring Amy Poehler, Phyllis Smith, Bill Hader. Mindy Kaling. Diane Lane, Kyle MacLachlan and John Ratzenberger   What to expect: The season's most charming film, of course. Pixar's first new movie in two years will take us inside the mind of a teenage girl as she battles with the emotions that populate her head, each of whom is a distinct character (Joy, Sadness, Fear, Anger and Disgust). Get ready: "Inside Out" will probably one of summer's highest-grossing releases. [Trailer]
Directed by Seth MacFarlane  Written by Seth MacFarlane, Alec Sulkin and Wellesley Wild   Starring Mark Wahlberg, Seth MacFarlane, Amanda Seyfried, Liam Neeson, Morgan Freeman and Jessica Barth   What to expect: Seth MacFarlane was dreaming up a "Ted" sequel before his dreadful hosting stint at the 2013 Oscars could convince anyone to turn their backs. So here we are. [Trailer]
Directed by Alan Taylor  Written by Laeta Kalogridis and Patrick Lussier   Starring Arnold Schwarzenegger, Jason Clarke, Emilia Clarke, Jai Courtney, Matt Smith and J. K. Simmons   What to expect: Arnold is back, this time with a new John Connor (Jason Clarke), Sarah Connor (Emilia Clarke) and Kyle Reese (Jai Courtney). The war against the machines rages on in the franchise's time-travelling fifth installment, which has yet to explain why it thinks "Genisys" is a word. [Trailer]
Directed by Gregory Jacobs  Written by Reid Carolin and Channing Tatum   Starring Channing Tatum, Matt Bomer, Joe Manganiello, Adam Rodriguez, Gabriel Iglesias, Andie Macdowell, Amber Heard, Jada Pinkett Smith and Elizabeth Banks   What to expect: Alex Pettyfer, Matthew McConaughey and Steven Soderbergh have bid Xquisite adieu, but we have faith that "XXL" will indeed be a super-sized sequel. This one finds the boys traveling to a stripping convention in South Carolina. Along the way, raise a glass to Channing Tatum, Screenwriter. [Trailer]
Directed by Pierre Coffin and Kyle Balda  Written by Brian Lynch   Starring Pierre Coffin, Sandra Bullock, Jon Hamm, Michael Keaton, Allison Janney and Steve Coogan   What to expect: MONEY. Monumental foreign grosses left "Despicable Me 2" just shy of $1 billion. Expect the franchise's third outing -- technically a spin-off -- to be one of summer's most profitable titles, even without Steve Carell's Felonious Gru on hand. [Trailer]
Directed by Peyton Reed  Written by Adam McKay and Paul Rudd   Starring Paul Rudd, Evangeline Lilly, Corey Stoll, Bobby Cannavale, Michael Pea, Judy Greer and Michael Douglas   What to expect: "Ant-Man" is Marvel's second title of the summer, and all eyes will be looking to glean whether its box-office haul lives up to the studio's precedent. After the movie gestated for 13 years, director Edgar Wright dropped out due to reported battles with Marvel president Kevin Feige. But who are we kidding? This is Paul Rudd in a comic-book movie. It's safe to assume people will buy tickets. [Trailer]
Directed by Judd Apatow  Written by Amy Schumer   Starring Amy Schumer, Bill Hader, Tilda Swinton, LeBron James, Vanessa Bayer, Brie Larson and Colin Quinn   What to expect: Amy Schumer is making her big-screen debut in this comedy about a commitment-phobic magazine writer who may have to rethink her approach to dating after she meets a winning gent (Bill Hader). "Trainwreck" was a hit at its South by Southwest premiere, giving us summer's best hope for a traditional rom-com. Oh, and say hello to LeBron James, Movie Star. [Trailer]
UPDATE, April 20: Never mind, Warner Bros. has delayed this movie until Oct. 9 to avoid competing with the others on this list.   Directed by Joe Wright  Written by Jason Fuchs   Starring Levi Miller, Hugh Jackman, Garrett Hedlund, Rooney Mara, Amanda Seyfried and Cara Delevingne    What to expect: Joe Wright is known for sweeping period pieces like "Pride &amp; Prejudice" and "Atonement," and it doesn't appear that he's abandoned those sensibilities for this live-action "Peter Pan" update. It offers origin stories for the titular boy and Captain Hook, played in his younger days by Garrett Hedlund. [Trailer]
Directed by Jake Schreier  Written by Scott Neustadter and Michael H. Weber   Starring Nat Wolff, Cara Delevingne, Justice Smith and Austin Abrams   What to expect: We already christened "Me and Earl and the Dying Girl" the next "Fault in Our Stars," so let's call "Paper Towns" the next "Godfather" -- if Nat Wolff is to be believed. Teens (and adults alike) will line up once again at the John Green Tabernacle, this time with fewer tear-drenched reactions. [Trailer]
Directed by Chris Columbus  Written by Tim Herlihy and Timothy Dowling   Starring Adam Sandler, Kevin James, Michelle Monaghan, Peter Dinklage, Josh Gad and Jane Krakowski   What to expect: We're dubious of anything that asks Adam Sandler and Kevin James to share screentime, but the premise of "Pixels" -- in which Pac-Man and other arcade characters rampage Earth -- sounds too fun to pass up. Plus, it has Peter Dinklage with a mullet and a laser canon. [Trailer]
Directed by Antoine Fuqua  Written by Kurt Sutter and Richard Wenk   Starring Jake Gyllenhaal, Forest Whitaker, Rachel McAdams, Naomie Harris, Victor Ortiz and Curtis "50 Cent" Jackson   What to expect: After the triple threat of "Prisoners," "Enemy" and "Nightcrawler," we will follow Jake Gyllenhaal into the day after tomorrow (and every day after that). In "Southpaw," he plays a onetime, wildly jacked boxer attempting to stage a career comeback. [Trailer]
Directed by Christopher McQuarrie  Written by Drew Pearce and Will Staples   Starring Tom Cruise, Jeremy Renner, Simon Pegg, Rebecca Ferguson, Ving Rhames and Alec Baldwin   What to expect: If all you operating thetans out there can still stomach Tom Cruise movies, here's Ethan Hunt assembling his crew to take down an enigmatic group of assassins known as the Syndicate. [Trailer]
Written and directed by John Francis Daley and Jonathan Goldstein   Starring  Starring Ed Helms, Christina Applegate, Leslie Mann, Chris Hemsworth and Charlie Day   What to expect: Rusty Griswold is all grown up, but he's staying true to good ol' dad by road-tripping across the country to Walley World, which is about to close its doors forever. Whether the "National Lampoon's Vacation" franchise still has juice in it will soon be seen, but fear not: The elder Griswolds (Chevy Chase and Beverly D'Angelo) do make a cameo.
Directed by Josh Trank  Written by Simon Kinberg and Jeremy Slater   Starring Miles Teller, Kate Mara, Michael B. Jordan, Jamie Bell, Toby Kebbell, Reg E. Cathey and Tim Blake Nelson   What to expect: Milers Teller has teased a "more mature approach" to this particular "Fantastic Four" reboot, which offers origin stories for Reed Richards (Miles Teller), Johnny Storm (Michael B. Jordan), Ben Grimm (Jamie Bell) and Sue Storm (Kate Mara). [Trailer]
Directed by Jared Hess  Written by Chris Bowman, Jody Hill, Danny McBride, Hubbel Palmer and Emily Spivey   Starring Zach Galifianakis, Owen Wilson, Kristen Wiig, Jason Sudeikis, Mary Elizabeth Ellis and Leslie Jones   What to expect: From the guy who gave us "Napoleon Dynamite" and "Nacho Libre" comes a farcical take on the 1997 Loomis Fargo heist that became the largest cash robbery on U.S. soil to date. [Trailer]
Directed by Jonathan Demme  Written by Diablo Cody   Starring Meryl Streep, Mamie Gummer, Kevin Kline, Sebastian Stan, Rick Springfield and Audra McDonald   What to expect: We'll have to endure a lot of supersized visual effects before getting to this summer's real highlight: Meryl Streep singing Lady Gaga and Bruce Springsteen hits as the frontwoman of a cover band -- in a movie from Jonathan Demme ("The Silence of the Lambs") and Diablo Cody ("Juno"), no less. We would give up every summer movie for this one. Every. Single. One.
Directed by F. Gary Gray  Written by Jonathan Herman, Alan Wenkus, S. Leigh Savidge and Andrea Berloff   Starring Jason Mitchell, Corey Hawkins, O'Shea Jackson Jr., Aldis Hodge, Neil Brown Jr, Paul Giamatti and Keith Stanfield   What to expect: In a time when racist police brutality is at the fore of America's culture wars, a biopic about N.W.A. -- whose debut album, "Straight Outta Compton," rebelled against authoritative abuse -- is especially timely. The film will chronicle the seminal hip-hop group's rise and fall. [Trailer]
Directed by Guy Ritchie  Written by Lionel Wigram and Guy Ritchie   Starring Henry Cavill, Armie Hammer, Hugh Grant, Elizabeth Debicki and Alicia Vikander   What to expect: So many big-name directors (Steven Soderbergh!) and stars (Ryan Gosling! Leonardo DiCaprio!) were considered for this film at one point or another that we can't help but remain curious. Henry Cavill hasn't made a movie since "Man of Steel," but let's see if his comedic chops pay proper tribute to the 1960s spy classic. [Trailer]
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:58:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey's Police Clash With Hundreds Defying Protest Ban On May Day</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/turkey-may-day-protests_n_7188132.html</Link>
        <Description>ISTANBUL, May 1 (Reuters) - Turkish police fired tear gas and water cannon at hundreds of stone-throwing May Day protesters on Friday, after they defied a ban and tried to march on Istanbul's Taksim Square.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkey's Police Clash With Hundreds Defying Protest Ban On May Day
Reuters | By                                                                      Humeyra Pamuk and Nick Tattersall
Posted:
reddit
ISTANBUL, May 1 (Reuters) - Turkish police fired tear gas and water cannon at hundreds of stone-throwing May Day protesters on Friday, after they defied a ban and tried to march on Istanbul's Taksim Square.
Europe's biggest city was under a security lockdown as thousands of police manned barricades and closed streets to stop demonstrations at Taksim, a traditional rallying ground for leftists that saw weeks of unrest in 2013.
An elderly man lies on the ground near a row of riot police after Turkish police use a water cannon to disperse protestors during a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Riot police unleashed water cannon and chased protesters down sidestreets in the nearby Besiktas neighborhood, where they fired off canisters of tear gas, according to a Reuters reporter at the scene.
Several people were detained after demonstrators lobbed stones and bottles at police and set off fireworks. Citing security concerns, much of Istanbul's public transport had been shut down and police helicopters circled over the city.
Protesters run and protect themselves as riot police use a water cannon against them during a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2015. (OZAN KOSE/AFP/Getty Images)
Tens of thousands also gathered to march in the capital Ankara, where the mood was more festive, with dancing and singing.
Critics say President Tayyip Erdogan and the government have become more authoritarian in the buildup to June elections.
"People want to express their problems but the government doesn't want those problems to be heard ahead of elections," opposition politician Mahmut Tanal, holding a pocket-sized book of the Turkish constitution, told Reuters in Istanbul.
Demonstrators try to protect themselves from water, sprayed by a police water canon truck and tear gas, during clashes in Istanbul, Turkey, May 1, 2015. (AP Photo/Emrah Gurel)
The normally thronged Istiklal shopping avenue leading to Taksim was deserted, with shops shuttered and metal barricades blocking off sidestreets. Police helicopters circled overhead.
A usually bustling square lined with cafes and hotels, Taksim was filled with police buses, ambulances and satellite broadcast trucks. A pair of tourists emerged from a hotel to find the area sealed off and nervously made their way around police lines.
A woman reacts as Turkish police use water cannons and tear gas to disperse protesters during a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
The government had said Taksim would only be open to those who came peacefully and not for "illegal demonstrations."
"I wish May 1 to be celebrated in a festive mood without provocations," Erdogan said in a statement.
Opposition parties and unions called on the government to lift the ban.
A protester kicks a tear gas canister during clashes with riot police during a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2015. (OZAN KOSE/AFP/Getty Images)
Erdogan has previously dismissed protesters as "riff-raff" and terrorists, outraged by the unrest in 2013 that brought unwanted international attention and posed the biggest challenge to his AK Party since it came to power in 2002.
He is aiming for a massive victory for the party in June parliamentary polls, which would allow it to change the constitution and give him broad presidential powers.
Demonstrators challenge riot police officers during clashes in Istanbul, Turkey, Friday, May 1, 2015. (AP Photo/Lefteris Pitarakis)
The 2013 Taksim protests began as a peaceful demonstration against plans to redevelop Gezi Park, a leafy corner of the square. After a police crackdown the demonstration spiraled into weeks of nationwide protests against Erdogan's rule.
Turkish riot police officers charge demonstrators during clashes in Istanbul, Turkey, May 1, 2015. (AP Photo/Emrah Gurel)
(Additional reporting by Ece Toksabay and Jonny Hogg in Ankara and Asli Kandemir in Istanbul; Writing by David Dolan; Editing by Andrew Roche)
Earlier on HuffPost:
May Day Clashes In Istanbul
of


Turkish riot police use water cannon and tear gas to disperse protesters during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey.  (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
Protesters throw petrol bombs toward riot police during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
Turkish riot police use water cannons and tear gas to disperse protesters during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
A Turkish protestor wearing a gas mask and a hard hat takes cover during clashes with riot police who prevent demonstrators from reaching Taksim Square in Istanbul for a May Day rally on May 1, 2014.  (Photo credit should read OZAN KOSE/AFP/Getty Images)
A Turkish protester (L) runs for cover from a riot policeman during clashes that erupted as police tried to disperse a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Turkish riot police use water cannons and tear gas to disperse protesters during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
A protester takes aim at riot police with a flare gun during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
A protester takes aim at riot police with a flare gun during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
A protester takes aim at riot police with a slingshot during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
Protesters takes aim at riot police with a slingshot and a flare gun during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
A Turkish protester wearing a gas mask uses a slingshot during clashes with riot police who try to disperse a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A masked Turkish protester runs for cover as riot police fire tear gas to disperse a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: GURCAN OZTURK/AFP/Getty Images)
Turkish protesters take cover behind trash containers as riot police fire tear gas to disperse a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: GURCAN OZTURK/AFP/Getty Images)
A Turkish protester wearing a gas mask throws back a tear gas canister that was fired by riot police to disperse a May Day rally in Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A Turkish protester wearing a gas mask stands amid a fog of tear gas that was fired by riot police to disperse a May Day rally in Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A Turkish policeman tries to remove a banner made of flowers reading 'First of May' as police try to disperse a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Protesters wearing gas masks take cover during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
Turkish riot police use water cannons and tear gas to disperse protesters during a May Day demonstration on May 1, 2014 in Istanbul, Turkey. (Photo by Burak Kara/Getty Images)
Turkish protesters run for cover as riot police fire tear gas to disperse a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A police car is parked next to burning tyres during clashes between riot police and demonstrators that erupted after riot police dispersed a May Day rally near Taksim Square in Istanbul on May 1, 2014. (Photo credit: GURCAN OZTURK/AFP/Getty Images)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:56:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Meet Will Allen, The Urban Farmer Starting His Own Revolution</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/will-allen-urban-farmer-growing-power_n_7183926.html</Link>
        <Description>When you think of farming towns, Milwaukee-proper might not be the first to come to mind. The large Wisconsin city is perhaps better known for its famed breweries and picturesque location along Lake Michigan, but one resident there has been on a mission to make farming more accessible even within the city limits.</Description>
        <MainBody>Meet Will Allen, The Urban Farmer Starting His Own Revolution
Posted:
reddit
When you think of farming towns, Milwaukee-proper might not be the first to come to mind. The large Wisconsin city is perhaps better known for its famed breweries and picturesque location along Lake Michigan, but one resident there has been on a mission to make farming more accessible even within the city limits.
Will Allen is a former professional athlete who played basketball throughout college at the University of Miami and post-college in Belgium. Though he has also held jobs in corporate America, Allen has spent the last 21 years in a completely different profession: urban farmer.
As the founder of Growing Power , Allen oversees his urban farms and teaches people in urban Milwaukee how to grow not just food, but good food. The organization's sustainable farm features multiple greenhouses, indoor and outdoor gardens, crops and animals such as goats and chickens. Growing Power also hosts workshops and outreach programs, and distributes its produce, meats and products throughout the city, making a big impact the lives of many.
"We're only six blocks away from Milwaukee's largest public housing project," Allen says. "When people drive by the street and they see the greenhouses on the front, they have no idea that we feed about 10,000 people just from this farm alone."
In particular, Allen enjoys working with area youth. The work that he and the children do, he explains, isn't just about farming; it's about life.
"It's way more than just putting a plant in the ground," Allen says. "It's about learning some life skills in terms of how to take care of yourself, how to take care of your body, how to be able to work in this environment. It's about learning how to eat healthy, to be able to build things by doing something hands-on."
And for many of the children, these urban farms have become a haven of sorts from the chaos of their everyday lives. It's a place where they feel safe, and are encouraged to learn, grow and even find a sense of inner peace.
"Kids that come in here, they're wired and they're bouncing off the walls. But as soon as I put some soil in their hands, they just calm down," Allen says. "There's something very spiritual about touching the soil."
The nourishment of working with soil, which Growing Power grows itself through vermicomposting , is something that feeds Allen's soul as well. "When I touch the soil, I actually feel good. I feel something," he says. "If you have fertile soil, then your food is going to taste good, and that's one of the joys of life."
By far, being an urban farmer is the most challenging and rewarding job Allen says he's ever had.
"I was meant to do this," he says. "To be a farmer, you definitely have to have tremendous faith and trust that something good is going to come."
"Super Soul Sunday" airs Sundays at 11 a.m. ET on OWN. You can also stream the program live at that time on Oprah.com/supersoulsunday or Facebook.com/supersoulsunday .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:46:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Child Reportedly Found Loaded Gun Left In Boehner's Capitol Hill Bathroom: The Hill</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/child-reportedly-found-lo_n_7188162.html</Link>
        <Description>When a member of Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell’s security detail left his Glock and magazine stuffed in the toilet seat cover holder of a Capitol Visitor Center bathroom stall, a CVC worker found the gun, according to a source familiar with the Jan. 29 incident and two other disturbing instances when Capitol Police left loaded firearms in problematic places. </Description>
        <MainBody>Child Reportedly Found Loaded Gun Left In Boehner's Capitol Hill Bathroom: The Hill
The Hill | By                                                                      Hannah Hess
Posted:
Updated:
10 minutes ago
US House Speaker John Boehner holds a press conference with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu at the prime minister's office in Jerusalem on April 1, 2015. Netanyahu invited Boehner to speak before Congress in the run-up to Israel's elections. AFP PHOTO / POOL / DEBBIE HILL        (Photo credit should read DEBBIE HILL/AFP/Getty Images) | DEBBIE HILL via Getty Images
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:44:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inspiration To Many As A Boxer And Philantropist, Manny Pacquiao Disappoints As Politician</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/manny-pacquiao_n_7188156.html</Link>
        <Description>MANILA, Philippines (AP) — Manny Pacquiao has been an inspiration for millions of Filipinos not just as a boxer, but as a philanthropist. As a politician, not so much.</Description>
        <MainBody>Inspiration To Many As A Boxer And Philantropist, Manny Pacquiao Disappoints As Politician
| By                                                                      OLIVER TEVES
Updated:
10 minutes ago
Manny Pacquiao smiles during a news conference Wednesday, April 29, 2015, in Las Vegas. Pacquiao will face Floyd Mayweather Jr. in a welterweight boxing match in Las Vegas on May 2. (AP Photo/John Locher) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
MANILA, Philippines (AP)  Manny Pacquiao has been an inspiration for millions of Filipinos not just as a boxer, but as a philanthropist. As a politician, not so much.
The country's biggest individual taxpayer in 2013, Pacquiao has often shared his wealth with the poor in his home province of Sarangani, where he has been elected and re-elected to Congress on waves of adoration. Win or lose in his May 2 megafight with Floyd Mayweather, Pacquiao is a lock to keep his seat for a third and final term, unless he decides to run for another office such as senator.
But some are disappointed with Pacquiao's political record. After nearly six years in office, he has yet to get a single bill through committee. Last year, he was present in Congress for just four days.
While Pacquiao was absent mostly to train, public administration professor Prospero de Vera said he was denying his constituents representation.
Pacquiao "has a problem understanding what representation means," said de Vera, who has served as consultant to other legislators. "What is worrisome is that he doesn't seem to be bothered by it."
Pacquiao's financial help is often sought and given in Sarangani, one of the Philippines' poorer provinces, with a poverty rate of over 45 percent.
Rosario Mantua, a former councilor of Maasim township, said Pacquiao and his wife, Jinkee, the provincial vice governor, have donated fishing boats, water buffalos to plow fields with, home lots and funds for college scholarships.
The high school dropout's scholarships have helped hundreds of students who would never have gone to college without a financial sponsor, said Apolo Novicio, executive assistant to the Maasim mayor.
Pacquiao's doling out of benefits, even from his own pocket, strikes some critics as too similar to how Filipino politicians typically operate, especially since he has few other political accomplishments.
"When you speak of the patronage system, it seems that he has strongly embraced it," said political analyst Ramon Casiple, executive director of the Institute of Political and Electoral Reforms. He said Pacquiao keeps to the mold of the typical traditional politician, derisively called "trapo", the Filipino word for rag.
Casiple said that lacking any political strategy or world view, Pacquiao could fall prey to "people around him who are not only 'trapo' but also opportunists, who will take advantage of his name and his money."
Pacquiao has filed about a dozen bills as congressman but none has passed any of the committees they have been referred to, the first hurdle in the legislative mill. The bills include several pertaining to boxing and sports development and health, including one to build a provincial hospital.
Congressional records show that during his first term in 2010-2013, Pacquiao was "actually present" for 98 out of 168 session days, and only for four days last year. Congress is currently out of session, Pacquiao has been training for weeks and calls to his office rang unanswered.
Rep. Ben Evardone, a former provincial governor and member of the administration Liberal Party, defends Pacquiao's absences in Congress, saying "being in Congress, making noise" is not as important as delivering public services.
"What is important is you bring home the bacon, as they say," he said, referring to the number of school houses, irrigation canals and roads that people expect to be built in their district with their congressman's help. "The fact that he is bringing glory to our country, he is able to unify, he is putting our country on the map, overshadows everything, his shortcomings."
Pacquiao was praised for a 2010 speech supporting an anti-human trafficking law. But during a heated debate months later over the reproductive health bill that backs artificial contraception, he fumbled. He raised questions that had been asked and answered, and challenged provisions that had already been removed or amended in previous sessions when he was absent.
His missteps have not discouraged some from thinking he has what it takes to achieve higher office one day  perhaps even president. Political scientist Amado Mendoza views him as a "more authentic pro-poor" public servant than other prominent politicians.
"He would not be an eight-time champion if he wasn't wise," Mendoza said. "War is war, it just takes on different forms. Politics is war, boxing is war. It is easy to shift ... from one form of warfare to another form of warfare."
Roulette de Leon, a former city planning staff member and consultant on community development and management, said he supported Pacquiao's first and unsuccessful foray into politics in the 2007 congressional election in General Santos city, where Pacquiao began his boxing career.
He has since become frustrated over his performance in the House of Representatives and suggested that Pacquiao hold off any immediate plans to run for a national office like senator next year or president in 2022, when 36-year-old boxing hero reaches the age required for the presidency.
Pacquiao should "first understand the job of a congressman before he understands the work of a senator, before he studies the responsibilities of a president," de Leon said.
De Vera, the professor, said if Pacquiao intends to provide direct assistance to his constituents, he should run for a local government position such as mayor or governor because providing public service, though important, is not the main responsibility of a legislator.
Mayor Raul Martinez of Kiamba, who stood as wedding godfather for the Pacquiao couple, also thinks Pacquiao would be a good local executive. He has told the "fighting congressman" to make good on his commitment to develop Sarangani province and that the best way to do that is to serve as governor. But he suggests that should wait until he retires from boxing.
"'You have to be a governor, full time,'" Martinez said he told Pacquiao. "'You cannot serve two masters.' He just laughed."
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:41:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Death Of Awe In The Age Of Awesome</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/death-of-awe_n_7188088.html</Link>
        <Description>It was a seemingly innocuous YouTube clip that got me thinking. A fellow toddler-parent showed it to me, with the accompanying explanation that it had become a highly effective way of pacifying her daughter, like a sort-of video-tranquilizer.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Death Of Awe In The Age Of Awesome
Medium | By                                                                      Henry Wismayer
reddit
It was a seemingly innocuous YouTube clip that got me thinking. A fellow toddler-parent showed it to me, with the accompanying explanation that it had become a highly effective way of pacifying her daughter, like a sort-of video-tranquilizer.
Look, she said, and, presenting her phone to our pair of two-year-olds, bid me watch as their expressions began to glaze over. On the screen, a dozen or so Kinder-egg-style treats were arrayed in two neat lines. Then a womans manicured hands  belonging to a Brazilian ex-pornstar, my friend informed me, absently  reached in, and began to open egg after egg after egg.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:38:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Moms Unite For A Better Future For Families At Moms +SocialGood 2015 (LIVESTREAM)</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/moms-plus-socialgood-2015_n_7181794.html</Link>
        <Description>What kind of world do you want for your family in 2030? </Description>
        <MainBody>Moms Unite For A Better Future For Families At Moms +SocialGood 2015 (LIVESTREAM)
Posted:
reddit
What kind of world do you want for your family in 2030?
That's the question the United Nations Foundation and Johnson &amp; Johnson are posing at this year's Moms +SocialGood event, an annual one-day conference in New York City where celebrities, advocates, political leaders and mothers gather in person and via social media to discuss the problems -- and solutions -- for moms and families around the globe.
Held in the New York Times Center on May 1, the event opens with an address from actress Jennifer Garner and Save the Children CEO Carolyn Miles, and comprises panels on topics ranging from universal safe childbirth to plugged in parenting. Speakers will include U.S. Ambassador to the UN Samantha Power, photographer Anne Geddes and philanthropist Jackie Bezos, among others.
The event also kicks off the third annual Global Moms Relay , a charity blog series hosted on The Huffington Post and BabyCenter from May 1 to June 19. The series will feature the voices of more than 20 well-known contributors, kicking off today with a piece from Oscar-winning actress Patricia Arquette. Each time a blog from the series is shared on social media, Johnson &amp; Johnson will donate $1 (up to $300,000) to one of four nonprofits supporting mothers and children around the world.
Watch the livestream of Moms +SocialGood 2015 in the video above, and follow the Global Moms Relay here . Join the conversation on Twitter and Facebook with #GlobalMoms.
Editor's Note: Johnson &amp; Johnson is a sponsor of The Huffington Post's Global Motherhood section.
Being Born Around the World: Traditions, Customs and Superstitions!
of


In Russia, other women shouldnt touch a pregnant belly (unless they want to get pregnant themselves) because its believed to be contagious. I know how funny it may seem, but not long before I found out that I was pregnant, I had seen my pregnant friend and touched her belly, BabyCenter editor Irina Korabeinikova says.
In Malaysia, there are various taboos surrounding foods -- for example, eating durian during pregnancy. This spiky, strongly-scented green fruit has a sweet-bitter custardy inside. Some foreigners find its smell offensive, but I love it! BabyCenter editor Julia Shin says. This taboo is still so prevalent that once a vendor refused to sell one to my visibly pregnant friend as he said he could not live with himself if something happened to her baby!
In India, once a woman becomes pregnant, the focus of the entire family is on her and her baby. Everyone in the family makes sure the mom-to-be is eating well and is protected from any hazards, and they hold traditional baby showers called Godhbharais.
In Mexico, its believed if you experience a lot of nausea during pregnancy, your newborn will have a full head of hair.
In Mexico and other Latin American countries, many believe that if you don't eat the food you crave during pregnancy, your baby will have a birthmark shaped like that food.
In Russia, its a tradition for dads to give money to the nurse who passes him the newborn in the hospital. Its just a small and symbolic amount but it is considered to provide happiness and health of the baby, BabyCenter editor Irina Korabeinikova says.
Koreans believe that there is a "great grandmother" who gives the babies to their mothers. Shes called the Samshin Halmoni (Samshin Grandmother). Many Korean and Mongolian babies are born with blue bruise-like marks on their bottoms, and we believe its because the Samshin Halmoni slaps the babys bottom before the baby is born to let them know its time to go out, BabyCenter editor Julia Shin says.
In China, new moms receive a lot of care and attention, and the pampering is a family affair. By tradition, new moms aren't supposed to leave their home for a month. Many moms even spend time in postpartum centers, which are like spas for new moms. Meanwhile, grandparents and other relatives take care of the household duties so Mom can recuperate and care for her baby. She's given high protein soups and other special foods during this time.
In parts of India, for 45 days after a baby is born, the new mother is confined to home and cared for by relatives. She's not supposed to even step into the kitchen, because the gas in the stove is said to cause breast milk to dry up.
In Canada, working moms get a year-long leave after they have a baby and receive 55 percent of their salary during that year. This is a government benefit, and women are entitled to the same job or a comparable one when their leave is over. Many companies supplement this benefit with additional dollars during maternity leave.
In Brazil, parents like to dress their newborn babies in red outfits to leave the hospital in after birth. People say that it's a good luck charm and also that the red color keeps the evil eye away, BabyCenter editor Luciana Oliceira says.
In India and Malaysia, some parents have a Hindu mundan (head shaving) ceremony. After shaving the hair off, the babys head is washed with holy water (Gangajal) and a paste of turmeric and sandalwood is applied. The paste is meant to help in cooling the head down and healing any nicks and cuts. In a mundan ceremony, shaving the hair means ridding the baby of any of her past life's negativity.
In China they say: Shi shang zhi you mama hao.  Which means: "The best thing in the world is your mom."
In Sweden they say: Sma barn, sma problem, stora barn, stora problem.  Which means: Small children, small problems; big children, big problems.
In India they say: Ishwar sarvavyapi ho, isliye ishwar ne har parivar mein ek Maa di hai.  Which means: God couldn't be everywhere, so he gave each family a mother.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HUFFPOLLSTER: Polls Still Show Rising Support For Same Sex Marriage</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/support-for-gay-marriage-_n_7188084.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>HUFFPOLLSTER: Polls Still Show Rising Support For Same Sex Marriage
Posted:
Updated:
11 minutes ago
WASHINGTON, DC - APRIL 28:  Protesters hold pro-gay rights flags outside the US Supreme Court on April 28, 2015 in Washington, DC. The Supreme Court meets to hear arguments whether same-sex couples have a constitutional right to wed in the United States, with a final decision expected in June.  | Olivier Douliery via Getty Images
reddit
Pollsters measure and contemplate the rapid rise in support for same sex marriage. Democrats continue to dominate among Millennials. And there's a "reality gap" in perceptions of the ACA. This is HuffPollster for Friday, May 1, 2015.
SUPPORT FOR SAME-SEX MARRIAGE REMAINS HIGH - Quinnipiac University Poll: "American voters support same-sex marriage 58 - 34 percent, with strong support from every party, gender and age group except Republicans, who are opposed 59 - 33 percent, and voters over 55 years old, who support same-sex marriage by a narrow 48 - 43 percent....By a smaller 58 - 35 percent margin, voters say businesses should not be allowed to refuse service to gays and lesbians, even if it violates a business owner's religious beliefs. Again, there is strong agreement among all groups except Republicans, who say 56 - 37 percent a business owner should be allowed to deny service based on religious belief." [ Quinnipiac ]
Americans choose religious freedom over gay rights, but.. - Emily Swanson: "Most Americans think the government should protect religious liberties over gay rights when the two come into conflict, a new Associated Press-GfK poll finds, though fewer think most businesses should be allowed to turn away gay couples because of religious beliefs.....Americans are more likely to say that religious liberties are more important for the government to protect than the rights of gays and lesbians, by a 56 percent to 40 percent margin, the poll found. Just a quarter of Americans call gay rights a very or extremely important issue to them personally, while half call religious liberties a very or extremely important issue. But fewer Americans  just 40 percent  think most business owners should be allowed to refuse service to gays and lesbians on religious grounds. That finding goes to the heart of the significant political fallout over Indiana's Religious Freedom Restoration Act, which critics charged was intended to allow businesses discriminate against gays and lesbian." [ AP ]
Religious Americans support same-sex marriage - Robert Jones: "Although public opinion has shifted dramatically, especially among religious Americans, many leaders of the conservative Christian political movement continue to act as if public opinion were frozen in the 1970s. But in fact, more religiously affiliated Americans now support same-sex marriage than oppose it....84 percent of Buddhists, 77 percent of Jews, approximately six in ten white mainline Protestants (62 percent), white Catholics (61 percent) and Hispanic Catholics (60 percent), and 56 percent of Eastern Orthodox Christians now support allowing gay and lesbian couples to marry legally. Conceding the loss of some religious groups in their ranks, many conservative religious leaders nonetheless continue to assert that religious Americans overall continue to oppose same-sex marriage. Even among religiously affiliated Americans, however, supporters today actually slightly outnumber opponents. Among all religiously affiliated Americans, 47 percent favor allowing gay and lesbian couples to marry, compared to 45 percent who oppose. (The surveys huge sample-size makes even this narrow margin statistically significant.)" [ The Atlantic ]
Majority of Republicans would attend a gay wedding - Jeff Mason: "A majority of U.S. Republicans would attend the same-sex wedding of a loved one, a Reuters/Ipsos poll showed on Wednesday, highlighting the political risks for Republican presidential candidates who stake out positions against gay marriage....The poll showed 56 percent of Republicans would attend the gay wedding of a loved one if invited. That compares with 80 percent of Democrats and 70 percent of independents, who said they would go.Overall, 68 percent of Americans would attend, the poll showed, while 19 percent would not and 13 percent were unsure." [ Reuters ]
There's 'no going back' - Mark Mellman (D): "Years ago, I argued that opinions on gay rights generally, and same-sex marriage in particular, were changing faster than those on almost any subject in the history of polling. That revolution continues...Why the sudden and dramatic change? A combination of factors seems to be at work. What I euphemistically call 'the inexorable forces of generational replacement' contributed significantly. Younger people have long been more supportive of same-sex marriage than their elders....Increased contact propelled support among young and old. As more people have come out in recent years, more of their friends and relatives have become aware of the fact that people they know and love are part of the LGBT community....Politics also had an impact. As Ive regularly demonstrated, voters often follow their political leaders on issues. An ABC/Washington Post poll found support for gay marriage increasing 18 points among African-Americans just after President Obama announced his support....Whatever the cause of the change, the effect has been nothing short of seismic." [ The Hill ]
How many Americans are in same-sex marriages or partnerships? - Gary J. Gates and Frank Newport: "Approximately 0.3% of adults in the U.S. are married to a same-sex spouse, and another 0.5% identify as being in a same-sex domestic partnership. In examining the total population of 243 million U.S. adults, these survey estimates suggest nearly 2 million adults are part of a same-sex couple, of whom 780,000 are married. The Census Bureau, however, has cautioned that the ACS estimates of married same-sex couples may not be reliable as they have determined that a large portion of recorded married same-sex couples may actually be married heterosexual couples who miscoded the sex of one of the spouses." [ Gallup ]
NEW RESEARCH ON GENERATIONS &amp; PARTISANSHIP - Pew Research: "Over the past decade, there has been a pronounced age gap in American politics. Younger Americans have been the Democratic Partys strongest supporters in both vote preferences and partisanship, while older Americans have been the most reliably Republican...Using the more than 25,000 interviews conducted over the course of 2014 that allowed for a deep dive into party identification released April 7, we are able to see variations within generations as well as between them....Millennials generally are more likely than other generations to lean Democratic. The Silent Generation is more likely to lean Republican. The partisan preferences of the two generations in between  Generation X and the Baby Boomers  are closer to the average partisan leanings of the public." [ Pew ]
Differences among Millennials - More Pew: "[T]he differences within generations are as notable as the differences among them....Millennials of all ages favor the Democratic Party by large margins, though the [Democrats'] advantage in leaned identification is greater among the oldest Millennials. Among Millennials born between 1981 and 1986 (28 to 33 in 2014), the Democratic Party leads by 18 points (51% Dem/lean Dem, 33% Rep/lean Rep). Among the youngest adult Millennials (18 to 23 in 2014) the Democratic Partys advantage is a still sizeable, though slightly narrower, 14 points (51% Dem/lean Dem, 37% Rep/lean Rep)." [ Pew ]
Harvard IOP: Hillary dominates among Millennials - "A new national poll of Americas 18- to 29- year-olds by Harvards Institute of Politics (IOP)...finds no front-runner among prospective Republican candidates in a still-emerging presidential primary race  with no candidate capturing more than ten percent. Hillary Clinton is in command of a hypothetical Democratic presidential primary with 47%... Overall  a solid majority of 18- to 29- year-olds prefer a Democrat (55%) winning the 2016 campaign for president over a Republican (40%)... Among potential Republican primary voters (definite, probable or 50-50; n=486), not one of 16 prospective Republican presidential candidates garnered more than ten percent of the vote." [ Harvard release ]
MORE OF THIS WEEK'S NATIONAL POLLS
-Gallup: Fewer Americans now identify as middle class - "Currently, 51% of Americans say they are middle class or upper-middle class, while 48% say they are lower class or working class. In multiple surveys conducted from 2000 through 2008, an average of more than 60% of Americans identified as middle or upper-middle class." [ Gallup ]
-HuffPost/YouGov: GOP now seen as more extreme - HuffPollster: "In a shift of opinion since the 2014 midterms, Americans now consider the Republican Party more extreme than the Democratic Party, a new HuffPost/YouGov poll finds. In the days just after the GOP retook the Senate last November, Americans were evenly split as to which party they thought was more extreme. They now say by an 8-point margin that Republicans are further from the mainstream. Half of Americans now say the GOP is too extreme, up 7 points since November....Forty-eight percent of independents now say the GOP is too extreme, up 9 points from last year. The percentage of Republicans calling their own party too extreme also rose by 6 points." [ HuffPost ]
-Pew: Americans split on views of union membership -"Over the past three decades, the share of wage and salary workers in the United States who belong to labor unions has fallen by about half. The public expresses mixed views of the impact of the long-term decline in union membership on the country: 45% say this has been mostly a bad thing, while 43% see it as mostly a good thing." [ Pew ]
HuffPost/YouGov: Republicans say their party was justified in opposing Lynch - HuffPollster: "Senate Republicans who opposed Loretta Lynch's nomination as attorney general lost the battle to keep her from being confirmed, but many Americans, including the vast majority of their party, think they were justified in disputing her nomination for political reasonsIn a new HuffPost/YouGov poll, 41 percent say senators are justified in voting against a nominee if they disagree with that nominee's political opinions. More than 70 percent in the GOP agree that senators should have the discretion to oppose cabinet nominees. Three-quarters of Republicans say it was appropriate for GOP senators to oppose [Lynch's] nomination because she supported President Barack Obama's executive actions on immigration. Just 19 percent of Democrats agree. [ HuffPost ]
-Pew: A mobile majority - "At the start of 2015, 39 of the top 50 digital news websites have more traffic to their sites and associated applications coming from mobile devices than from desktop computers, according to Pew Research Centers analysis of comScore data."[ Pew ]
BERNIE SANDERS' BIG CHALLENGE - Harry Enten: "Lets be real right out of the gate: Sen. Bernie Sanders of Vermont is almost certainly not going to be the Democratic nominee for president in 2016....Polls show Sanders doesnt match up well against Clinton. He trails her by nearly 57 percentage points nationally, 54 percentage points in Iowa and 40 percentage points in New Hampshire. More than that, there seems to be very little desire on the left for a challenger to Clinton. She regularly earns 60 percent support among self-described 'liberal' and 'very liberal voters, according to national polls. And Sanderss colleagues in the Senate with the most liberal voting records  those who would be key to starting a mutiny against Clinton  have already endorsed her."[ 538 ]
Not enough liberals among Democrats - Nate Cohn: "[T]here is another, strangely simple reason Mrs. Clinton will have an easy road to the nomination: The left wing of the Democratic Party just isnt big enough to support a challenge to the left of a mainstream liberal Democrat like Mrs. Clinton...The majority of Democrats and Democratic primary voters are self-described moderates or even conservatives, according to an Upshot analysis of Pew survey data from 2014 and exit polls from the 2008 Democratic primary." [ NYT ]
THE OBAMACARE PERFORMANCE 'REALITY GAP' - Jonathan Cohn and HuffPollster: "In a new [YouGov] survey, more than half of self-identified Republicans said they didnt think the Affordable Care Act is increasing the number of people with health insurance, with a fifth of respondents saying it has actually reduced the number of people with coverage. For the record, the evidence suggests these people are flat-out wrong....Among Democrats, 77 percent said the number of people with insurance had risen, while just 9 percent said it had decreased. But among Republicans, just 43 percent thought the number of people with insurance had increased, while 21 percent said it had decreased Every major study -- including official estimates by the federal government and analyses by independent researchers -- has shown that the number of people with health insurance has risen substantially since the Affordable Care Act took full effect...Its likely that perceptions of the Affordable Care Act are affecting the way some people assess its performance, rather than the other way around." [ HuffPost ]
HUFFPOLLSTER VIA EMAIL! - You can receive this weekly update every Friday morning via email! Just click here , enter your email address, and click "sign up." That's all there is to it (and you can unsubscribe anytime).
THIS WEEK'S 'OUTLIERS' - Links to the best of news at the intersection of polling, politics and political data:
-Jeb Bush isn't winning the invisible primary. [ 538 ]
-President Obama continues to be the more trusted economic actor in Washington. [ Gallup ]
-Americans are slowly and steadily warming up to Obamacare. [ YouGov ]
-Ed Kilgore sees some gold in early polls; Jonathan Bernstein responds. [ Washington Monthly , Bloomberg ]
-Bill McInturff (R) sees no real growth in "hard" independents. [ POS ]
-DeepRootX (R) shares an interactive visualization of 2012 Republican primary ads. [ National Journal ]
-Karlyn Bowman summarizes recent polling on income inequality. [ AEI ]
-Alex Tribou and Keith Collins chart America's fast social evolution. [ Bloomberg via @joshuatopolsky ]
-The Census Bureau explains why the American Community Survey (ACS) asks so many questions about our lives. [ MarketingResearch.org ]
-The Roper Center for Public Opinion Research wins the "Data Seal of Approval." [ Roper ]
-American Viewpoint, the firm of Republican pollster Linda Divall, celebrates its 30th year anniversary. [ AmView ]
-What the probability of precipitation really means. [ WashPost ]
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Walking For An Extra 2 Minutes Per Hour Can Help You Live Longer</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/short-walks-health-benefi_n_7160544.html</Link>
        <Description>Next time you get up and walk to the bathroom, you can feel good about doing something positive for your health. </Description>
        <MainBody>How To Move More This Weekend
of


This old-timey favorite is fun for kids and adults alike, and can burn 100 calories in just 30 minutes.   Flickr photo by Machine is Organic
You don't have to be Michael Phelps to get a water workout. Even some leisurely splashing around can shave off 200 calories, and it's a great way to stay cool in the heat, too!  Flickr photo by Joe Shlabotnik
Instead of just lounging on the sand working on your tan, get up and move around if you're at the beach this weekend. Bonus: Digging in the sand can be a surprisingly good workout for abs and obliques.   Flickr photo by Michael Bentley
You're not chained to that park bench! If you're already enjoying the outdoors, why not throw around a Frisbee or a football, pass a volleyball or kick a soccer ball? It doesn't have to be strenuous -- you don't even have to be any good! -- but it will get you up and moving.  Flickr photo by Elvert Barnes
If you've got a date night planned this weekend, skip dinner and a movie in favor of something that gets you off your rears. It doesn't have to be a trip to the gym or a jog -- it can be anything active you like doing together.  Flickr photo by Tobyotter
Many local parks, rivers and lakes have row boats, canoes or kayaks available for rent. No matter your vessel of choice, it's a fun, seasonal way to burn some serious calories.  Flickr photo by Josh Hawley
During the busy week, you sometimes might just let your pet out in the backyard to dig up his own trouble. This weekend, spend a little extra time moving with him. Play fetch, give him that much-needed belly rub or take him on an extra-long walk.  Flickr photo by footloosiety
If you've made plans to meet a friend for coffee, take your catch up session to-go instead and gab on a walk. Even strolling at a snail's pace will burn 85 calories in 30 minutes!
Let the music move you when you're out on Saturday night. A little boogying can burn 150 calories in just 30 minutes.
If dancing's not your thing, you can still do better than sitting. Belly up to the bar instead of ordering drinks at a table or booth, or grab dinner at a high table with bar stools.   Leaning against a high stool is a step up from sitting, but can be more comfy than standing all night, Health magazine reported.
Put down the drink for some foosball or pool if you're at a bar this weekend that offers it. Thirty minutes of pool can shave off 85 calories, not to mention you may save yourself a few if your hands aren't wrapped tightly around that pint glass.  Flickr photo by Nicola since 1972
Head for the hills! Depending on where you live, a hike can be a weekend expedition or a quick afternoon adventure. It's a change of scenery and a great way to spend some time outdoors. If you're feeling sporty enough to tackle some hills, you can burn almost 250 calories in just 30 minutes.  Flickr photo by mikebaird
If you typically find yourself hailing a taxi on the weekends, try hoofing it instead. If your destination is too far to make it on foot, try public transportation -- and leave the seat for someone else.  Flickr photo by TMAB2003
If you have plans to barbecue this weekend, break out the lawn games to get you out of your seat. Try croquet or badminton, which can burn more than 150 calories in 30 minutes.  Flickr photo by Jessa B.C.
Those people who do their exercise walking around the mall are onto something. Whether or not you plan to buy anything, browsing around your favorite shopping center gets you moving -- especially if you decide to wiggle in and out of a few things in the dressing room.  Flickr photo by jimmyharris
Spend some time strolling through the halls and galleries of your favorite museum. You'll give your brain a workout while you're at it!
Pick your favorite nearby joint and walk to pick up your meal.
Sure, it might take a little longer than sitting through the drive-thru, but you get the pleasure of working those muscles a little bit.
Instead of sitting at a restaurant waiting to be served, why not whip something up at home? You'll be on your feet slicing, chopping, mixing and more, not to mention cleaning up after yourself.  Flickr photo by mamaloco
A number of fall veggies are ready for planting now. Spending an hour digging, crouching, weeding and planting in your garden can burn more than 300 calories.  Flickr photo by auntjojo
You don't have be imitate the Tour de France! Even the most casual rides can burn 200 calories an hour. Don't own a bike? Many cities now have bike share programs that allow you to take a short spin for a small fee, and some parks have bikes available for rent, too.  Flickr photo by machernucha
Go old-school, and grab a group of friends to head to the nearest laser tag arena. You'll run, jump, squat, crawl -- all in the name of fun and (healthy) competition.  Flickr photo by shawnzrossi
With the increase in popularity of bouldering, you no longer need a load of gear (and experience!) to reap the fitness benefits of rock climbing. Try it out at a local gym -- you'll burn calories and seriously work those arm muscles.  Flickr photo by toolmantim
It's not just for dads in bowling shirts! Grab a pair of nerdy-chic shoes and aim straight. You may even wiggle a little arm workout out of it!  Flickr photo by junklab
Dreaming of a couch-potato weekend? Turn that screen time into something more productive by challenging a roommate, spouse or kid to a Wii Fit boxing or tennis match.  Flickr photo by SashaW
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:30:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A $349 Apple Watch Only Costs $83.70 To Make: IHS</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/apple-watch-cost_n_7188064.html</Link>
        <Description>(Reuters) - Apple Inc's Watch has the lowest ratio of hardware costs to retail price across any Apple phone, according to a preliminary estimate by research firm IHS after a teardown study.</Description>
        <MainBody>A $349 Apple Watch Only Costs $83.70 To Make: IHS
Reuters
reddit
(Reuters) - Apple Inc's Watch has the lowest ratio of hardware costs to retail price across any Apple phone, according to a preliminary estimate by research firm IHS after a teardown study.
The hardware cost of an Apple Watch Sport model was about 24 percent of the suggested retail price compared with 29-38 percent for the iPhone maker's other products, IHS said on Thursday. (http://bit.ly/1zuOZMq)
The Apple Watch Sport 38 mm costs $349 and the teardown shows a bill of materials of $81.20 with the cost of production rising to $83.70 when $2.50 in manufacturing expense is added, IHS said.
(This version of the story corrects the first paragraph to say Apple phone, not Apple product, after IHS amends report)
(Reporting by Supantha Mukherjee in Bengaluru; Editing by Kirti Pandey)
Also on The Huffington Post
Close


If you're lucky enough to be an owner of either the BMW i3 or i8 then you're in for a treat. BMW has confirmed that the i Remote app for iPhone will come with its own Apple Watch app. Offering the same key remote functions as the iPhone app you'll be able to check charging, unlock the doors, hoot the horn, flash the lights and more.
That's right, Instagram is on Apple Watch. This skimmed down version of the full app lets you browse through images, like posts and share them with friends.
More an extension than a dedicated interactive app, the Barclays Apple Watch is a simple and secure way of seeing your balance across all your accounts. It'll also re-route all notifications that you go either via the iPhone app or via SMS through the watch as Watch notifications.
Using GPS your iPhone will let your Apple Watch know when you've arrived at a W Hotel. If you have a room booked it'll even pop up with an option to turn your Apple Watch into your door key. All you have to do is press 'Unlock Your Door' and you're good to go.
Keeping at the cutting edge is Uber. You can request a cab, see when it's ready and get home all through the Uber app on Apple Watch. You'll never have to take the iPhone out of your pocket.
Using GPS, the Apple Watch knows when you're arriving at the airport. As soon as you arrive it'll bring up your boarding information and even let you pass through security using the boarding card on your Watch.
Push down on the Digital Crown and it'll bring up your favourite contacts. From there you can make calls, send images and even send them your heartbeat.
Contact over the Apple Watch couldn't be simpler. You'll be able to draw shapes, send emojis and even send your heartbeat.
Using the Apple Watch's built-in speaker you can make, and answer phone calls without ever having to pick up your iPhone.
That's right, your favourite music mixing app is now compatible with Apple Watch. Naturally being able to do an entire set on your iPhone is no longer hip enough, so they've moved it from the hip to the wrist. You'll look like you're doing literally nothing but then again, isn't that kind of the point?
1Password, the app that replaces your brain is now on Apple Watch. Using a simple four-digit passcode it'll give you access to your key passwords, so if you suddenly forget your Facebook login or Amazon details your Watch will be on hand to help out.
Is there an app more useful than Citymapper? As we discovered only the other week, there probably isn't. Well now you won't even have to take your phone out for it to babysit you from A to B.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:26:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>These Are My Confessions: What Diary-Keeping Means In An Age Of Oversharing</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/01/diary-online_n_7109776.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>These Are My Confessions: What Diary-Keeping Means In An Age Of Oversharing
Posted:
reddit
Heidi Julavits felt trapped. While vacationing in Germany with a friend, she reluctantly set out on a drive up a narrow, icy road. The further they travelled, the steeper and riskier the climb became. Terrified by her inability to change course -- the road had shrunken to the narrow width of the car -- she panicked. The potentials of the day had suddenly been reduced to a binary fate: theyd make it to their destination, or they wouldnt. As soon as she was able to turn around, thanks to a widening near a tunnel, she did. In her new book, The Folded Clock: A Diary , she likens this incident to the experience of novel writing, an act she finds suffocating. She writes:
I imagine a fictional scenario and so quickly the march of consequence takes over. Things happen and so other things must happen. I spend so much time working in the guts of this machine I feel less like a writer and more like the engineer of a high-performance vehicle. I am stuck perfecting the mechanics of happenings and coincidence. This is how plots take shake and achieve viability. [...] I would like to learn other means.
So, rather than penning another novel (Julavits has written two of them), she began recording her daily actions and thoughts, allowing them space to roam around, to latch onto earlier memories and musings. In short: she wrote a diary.
Shes among a slew of writers abandoning the strictures of fiction for more personal, meandering narratives. Be it a novel-from-life (Sheila Hetis How Should a Person Be? ), a collection of confessional essays (Leslie Jamisons The Empathy Exams ), or an autobiographical series (Karl Ove Knausgrd's My Struggle ), the books that are shaking up conventions, and arguably reflecting contemporary life most accurately, are those that infuse so-called more literary philosophical observations with the banality of the day-to-day.
But can these works -- most of them written with some knowledge that they will eventually be published -- be classified as diaries? And what, if anything, distinguishes them from the confessional writing happening en masse on Twitter?
That Julavits chooses a diary as the subtitle for her work is telling of the increasingly murky boundary between personal life-logging and art produced for public consumption. So what, exactly, does diary-keeping mean in a time when over-sharing has become not only acceptable but expected? When live-tweeting our woes, and reading the daily concerns of others in real time, are as much a part of our sensory intake as listening to music or watching a show?
Today I Ate Fish: The Diarys Dull History
The reasons for keeping a diary are many: its therapeutic and can act as a reliable line of communication between us and our former selves -- a way of chronicling our lives sans filter, as Joan Didion sagely observes in  On Keeping a Notebook . If the diary-keeper is to log her thoughts honestly, though, theres bound to be some mundane, self-indulgent rambling involved. This is true even of the most historically lauded diaries.
Take that of Samuel Pepys , a servant living in London in 1660, whose entries are valued for the details they contain surrounding the reign of the Cromwells and the Restoration of the British monarchy. Though the period is likely to appeal to history buffs, the entries themselves are painfully dull. Mostly, he logs his meals. In one entry he writes, They brought us also some caveare, which I attempted to order, but all to no purpose, for they had neither given it salt enough, nor are the seedes of the roe broke, but are all in berryes.
He goes on to describe the badness of [his] hat.
Though this diary was likely a pleasure for Pepys to keep and reflect on - he was at it for over ten years - its a slog of a read for anyone not interested in the heyday of the British Commonwealth. Theres an awing gap between the personal and the social value of a diary. The social value, according to Kylie Cardell, author of De@r World: Contemporary Uses of the Diary , is as a document written in media res. Its a way of experiencing firsthand an event or period we cant quite envision when we look at it from the birds eye view of history books.
Think of the diaries we uphold as excellent: Anne Franks, of course, but also Helen Kellers and Sei Shonagons -- those whose firsthand observations fall far outside our personal realm of experience. To read their accounts of war or illness is to insert ourselves into the throes of travail. To take in what these diarists did or thought about each day is to connect with them on a more human level, and to understand history in a way that exists beyond the clean, chronological timelines we use to make sense of an event's importance.
Julavits cites one such diary as a source of inspiration for her book. Marie Illarionova Vassiltchikovs Berlin Diaries 1940-1945 , penned by a woman who lived in Germany during the bombing of Berlin, and was loosely involved in the July 20 Plot. Because she knew of some details surrounding an attempt to assassinate Hitler, she felt it necessary to exclude factual details from her writings, instead tethering her story to her own wavering emotions. Due to the authors fear-induced restrictions, the diary had to be guarded carefully, and literally without a plot.
When asked whether she believed such thorough yet private observations like these still exist today, Julavits paused before answering: You know I dont know.
Diarist and fish eater Samuel Pepys
Today I Went Viral: The Diarys Role Online
Like any good diary, Julavitss book begins with a warning about the personal nature of its contents: This book is an accounting of two years of my life. I have altered identifying characteristics to protect peoples privacy. This forward is no cumbersome lock and key -- The Folded Clock can be found on shelves of readers who are strangers to the author -- but it does highlight the notion that in spite of the proliferation of public, confessional writing, we still think of diaries as a separate, quieter and more intimate form of self-expression.
Ostensibly, what makes a diary a diary, and not, say, a note, or a letter, is its function as a vault for our unfiltered, secret musings. But, as Susan Sontag notes in Reborn: Journals and Notebooks , One of the main (social) functions of a diary is to be read [...] by other people, the people (like parents + lovers) about whom one has been cruelly honest only in the journal.
Kylie Cardell echoed this sentiment in De@r World: The perceived privacy of the diary is less about its status as withheld - as unpublished, kept under a pillow [] than its relation to uncensored and unmediated self-narration.
On some level, when we vent, we want to be heard -- if only by our future selves. Why else would we choose such a permanent format for sorting out our thoughts? This may explain journalings evolution from guarded confessions to blunt, public blogging. Julavits agrees. When she began compiling entries for The Folded Clock, she had no intention of publishing them in a sleek, bound book, but did hope to share them with her children one day.
In spite of our apparent willingness to share, the first online diaries still featured metaphorical locks. LiveJournal, Xanga and other early online journals allow users to password-protect individual entries, or entire pages. But, in the last four years alone, theres been a six percent increase in public LiveJournal accounts, and a similar decrease in customized accounts - for which users can manage the privacy of individual entries. In the past fifteen years, the blog's relative number of private account holders has decreased by 21 percent. The company describes itself in its Twitter bio as blurring the lines between blogging and social networking... since 99, apparently capitalizing on the shift weve undergone from squirreling away our secrets to announcing them proudly.
Its clear that sharing our quotidian wants and happenings has become a rampant pastime, regardless of whether theyre password protected or trumpeted on Twitter. As Jenna Wortham observed in a New York Times article about the surfacing scores of dull Vine videos , A cynic might dismiss all this obsessive self-documentation as evidence of generational narcissism. But theres something liberating -- even artistic -- about the raw immediacy of confession. Cardells observation that a diary is valuable as a document written in media res applies not only to historical musings, but to present ones, too.
Today I Made Art: The Diary As An Alternative To Novels
Of course, the diarys value as a tool that can zero in on a single moment in the tidal wave of history -- or a strong voice among the social media deluge -- becomes less intriguing when said moments are painfully shallow and therefore banal. Theres nothing intimate about a log of a diarists food intake or outfit choices. But Julavitss diary -- and those of other successful confessional writers -- uses the dailiness of these observations as a jumping-off point to examine her life sans-plot.
When she began accruing the entries that would become The Folded Clock, Julavits gave herself a single rule: Every piece would begin with the phrase, Today, I..., thereby circumventing a story arc that would thread the book together in the neat, chronological manner so much fiction is characterized by. It seems to suggest that what would follow would be really, really circumscribed by the facts of those two words, Julavits said. In fact, it became this permission to go anywhere in time -- it was like opening up a portal.
The result is what Julian Barnes -- who Julavits quotes at length in her book -- would call episodicism. In an essay of art criticism , he writes, Episodicists see and feel little connection between the different parts of their life, [and] have a more fragmentary sense of life. He pits the mode of living against narrativism - that is, seeking a plot or cohesive story that ties everything together neatly. Narrativists, Barnes writes, tend to find episodicists selfish and irresponsible.
In other words, those of us who prefer to see our lives, and the lives of others, as stories full of repetition, connection and meaning, might look down on more confessional, in-the-moment mediums, such as diaries. Cardell backs this claim in the introduction to her book: Scandalous, sordid, unmediated, associated with 'unprofessional' writers or adolescent girls, the diary is a genre desired as much for its promise of rawness and unself-conciousness as it has also been derided for excessive interiority [and] solipsism.
But in going public the diary has become much more than a therapeutic act of self-reflection, and those steeped in the form defend it as a viable means of connecting with others and creating art, not just a trove of crush-related tirades. Julavits says when she began writing Clock, she had this residual hesitation regarding the use of a diary as a place where a woman talks about her love life. She even omitted her husband from the book entirely until she realized the choice was dishonest.
Similarly, personal essayist Leslie Jamison writes of the fist story she published : The female narrator Id be depicting in my story -- a woman consumed by self-pity, drowning her sorrows in drink, engaged in reckless sexual self-destruction, obsessed with the man whod left her -- didnt seem like a particularly appealing or empowered sort of woman to think about or be. And yet, she was me.
To write about the ordinariness of pain may seem like a story not worth telling, but increasingly -- and with the unfortunately needed help of literary male writers such as Karl Ove Knausgrd jumping on the bandwagon -- its become an accepted art form.
Its a shift we should be thankful for. Sure, changing the privacy settings on our once-discreet musings could be seen as narcissistic -- a strategic move in a quest for validation. And keeping a public inventory of our daily happenings might be a yawn for readers. But its something else, too. When such observations are compiled into a work of art, they become an honest reflection on how we absorb and produce information.
When asked why she wanted to write a plotless story -- a diary -- Julavits said it felt true to how we live. I do feel like we move through space and information differently now, she said. We do it every day. Youre linking. Theres a link. Everything has a link. Theres a link buried in whatever youve read. Things suddenly go off in these unexpected zig-zags through virtual spaces, which are kind of story spaces that you create for yourself as you navigate. Theres no plot to that. There is a type of linkage, but its a different type of linkage. Thats what I was trying to capture, or come to terms with.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
