<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:47:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japanese Volcano Mount Shindake Erupts On Kuchinoerabu Island</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/mount-shindake-volcano-_n_7465596.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (AP) — A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, and authorities ordered residents to evacuate the island.</Description>
        <MainBody>Japanese Volcano Mount Shindake Erupts On Kuchinoerabu Island
Posted:
reddit
TOKYO (AP)  A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, and authorities ordered residents to evacuate the island.
Mount Shindake erupted about 10 a.m. (0100 GMT) in spectacular fashion, spewing towering black-gray clouds into the sky.
No injuries had been reported, although the Japan Meteorological Agency reported that pyroclastic flows from the volcano had reached the shore to the northwest.
The government was surveying the island by helicopter to assess damage.
The national broadcaster NHK cited local officials as saying that 80 residents had taken refuge in a shelter on the island.
About 140 people live on Kuchinoerabu island in the Ryukyu archipelago, 50 miles (80 kilometers) southwest of the main southern island of Kyushu. Tourism and fishing are the main activities on the heavily forested, mountainous island, which is a national park.
The Japan Meterological Agency raised the volcano alert level to five, the highest on its scale. Shindake also erupted in August last year for the first time since 1980.
Kuchinoerabu island can be reached only by a once-a-day ferry from Yakushima island, 12 kilometers (about 7 miles) to the east, which has an airport and a population of more than 13,000 people.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:49:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'What Happened To The Yazidis Is Nothing But Genocide,' Kurdish Rep Says</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/yazidis-genocide-isis_n_7463034.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON -- When the Obama administration began military action against the Islamic State back in August 2014, </Description>
        <MainBody>'What Happened To The Yazidis Is Nothing But Genocide,' Kurdish Rep Says
Posted:
reddit
WASHINGTON -- When the Obama administration began military action against the Islamic State back in August 2014, one of its stated goals was to defend Iraq's Yazidi religious minority from mass killings by the militant group. Almost a year later, hundreds of thousands of Yazidis have fled their historic homes in northwestern Iraq to escape what many argue is a genocide perpetrated by the Islamic State.
After successfully conquering the Yazidi areas of Iraq in August, the Islamic State, also known as ISIS, summarily executed hundreds of Yazidi men over the age of 14 and took hundreds of women as hostages. The United Nations suggested in March that the group's extremist behavior showed that it intended to carry out a religiously motivated genocide to wipe out the Yazidis.
The Huffington Post spoke with Bayan Sami Abdul Rahman, the Kurdistan region's representative in the U.S., about the actions of ISIS and the current status of the Yazidis.
"What happened to the Yazidis is nothing but genocide," Rahman said. "Anybody who denies that, I think, is just using political maneuvering, which is shameful and despicable in my book."
Rahman is a representative, not a formal ambassador, since the Kurdistan region is a part of Iraq and not an independent state. She took up her post in January, after serving as the region's representative to the U.K.
Though the Yazidis are usually distinguished by their religious identity -- their faith being a distinctive mix of ancient Assyrian, Zoroastrian, Christian and Islamic beliefs -- they are considered ethnically Kurdish. That binds them to the Muslim Kurds in Iraq, Turkey and Syria, who have been involved in defending the minority group against the Islamic State onslaught. As a result of the mass killings by ISIS, more than 400,000 Yazidis are now living as internally displaced persons in Iraq's northeastern Kurdistan region.
The U.N. report argued that the Islamic State's actions constituted a genocide because of their focus on the Yazidis' religious identity. ISIS killed male Yazidis even if they had agreed to convert -- in contrast to its treatment of other religious minorities, whom the group has instead forced to convert or to pay special taxes. Weeks after their massacres, the extremists again highlighted the Yazidis' identity in a chilling piece of propaganda saying that Islamic law required captured women who were non-believers to be treated as concubines and slaves.
"There are women and girls who are being held as sex slaves or sold in the open markets," Rahman said. "It's actually just so horrific to think that today in the 21st century, this still goes on -- that there are people who do the selling and that there are people who do the buying."
Accounts have since emerged of the women's treatment at sex slavery markets, their suffering in the homes of their new "owners" and their efforts to escape their plight -- from reaching out to relatives via hidden mobile phones to slashing their own wrists.
The regional government of Kurdistan, which Rahman represents, is working to recover those enslaved Yazidis. It revealed last month that it has paid Iraqi residents of Islamic State-controlled areas to "buy" Yazidi women and liberate them.
Rahman maintains that what the Yazidis went through should be considered a genocide. Her government has pushed for the U.N. and the U.S. Congress to pass resolutions declaring as much, even though she explained why it would be politically difficult to make that kind of statement.
"Genocide internationally has legal obligations on everybody," she said. "All of us, internationally, by law, are obliged to prevent genocide."
Rahman underscored the importance of this recognition by referring to a prominent Yazidi political leader, the Iraqi parliamentarian Vian Dakhil, who said in Washington earlier this year that the Yazidis' suffering should be classified as a genocide.
"[Dakhil] said that in Yazidi oral history -- it's an oral tradition -- there have been 73 episodes of genocide. But there's no written record, there's nothing to say that this happened, other than what the Yazidis pass on to their children."
"This time, the world witnessed it," Rahman continued, "and for the Yazidis, it's important that not only they and their children recognize this as genocide but also the international community does so."
This is the first installment in The Huffington Post's new "Ambassadors Unplugged" series, which will interview prominent diplomats on important global issues.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:13:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery Saiga Antelope Die-Off Stumps Scientists</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/antelope-die-off_n_7463206.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Endangered, adorable </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Endangered, adorable Saiga antelope are dying off at a terrifying rate in Kazakhstan -- and nobody knows why.
More than a third of the world's population of saigas has died off in the past month. The cause has stumped scientists and sparked conspiracy theories.
A month ago, Kazakhstan was home to 250,000 saigas. The population was considered a conservation success story. Now, the United Nations has confirmed that 120,000 saigas are dead , and the number may continue to rise.
Biologist EJ Milner-Gulland told The Guardian that the evidence points to a highly contagious disease. The U.N. statement said the bacteria Pasteurella and Clostridia are contributing to the die-off. But both bacteria are opportunistic, meaning they only kill animals with weakened immune systems.
Nobody's sure why so many saigas have succumbed. Kazakh environmentalists blame toxic Russian rocket fuel that may have rained down on the plains after rockets exploded during their launch from a Kazakh site, The Guardian reported.
Saigas are compellingly strange-looking creatures with a distinctive long nose. Male saigas use their capacious nostrils to produce a "nasal roar" during mating season.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:11:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The IRS Data Theft and Putin's Red Notice</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/harlan-green/the-irs-data-theft-and-pu_b_7464490.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>It has to be more than a coincidence that the </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
It has to be more than a coincidence that the recent cyber theft of IRS tax data has been traced to Russian criminals.  IRS investigators believe the identity thieves who stole the personal tax information of more than 100,000 taxpayers from an IRS website are part of a sophisticated criminal operation based in Russia, two officials told the Associated Press.
"The information was stolen as part of an elaborate scheme to claim fraudulent tax refunds, IRS Commissioner John Koskinen told reporters. Koskinen declined to say where the crime originated," said the AP report.
In fact, the connection between fraudulent tax refunds and actual officials of the Russian government has been well-documented by former Russian Hedge Fund Manager Bill Browder in his new book, Red Notice, which provides evidence of how Russian government officials were able to steal back $230,000,000 in taxes paid by his hedge fund, Hermitage Capital, which managed $4.5 billion in assets at the time.
This happened in Russia.  Russian officials have stolen from their own government.  It was Russia's FSB Secret Police, successor to their KGB, that stole actual tax receipts, according to Browder.  They had raided his Russian offices, and confiscated the corporate seals and legal documents of corporations he managed that had paid $230 million in taxes the year before President Putin kicked him out of Russia in 1995.
When Russian officials found they couldn't confiscate his assets--he had been able to sell all his Russian assets--they literally changed the ownership of his corporations and re-filed fraudulent tax returns.  The refiled returns then reported sufficient losses that they could claim a refund for all of the $280 million in taxes his companies had paid to the Russian government.
This was so blatant a financial fraud that we can be sure our IRS must be aware of Russian government complicity.  How?  Because Browder was able to document the fraud, which resulted in a new U.S. law, the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act ,  which named the actual perpetrators of the tax theft --some 35 Russian government officials at last count--from ever entering the U.S. and freezing their assets.
Yet it seems even the IRS can be fooled.
"In 2012, the IRS sent a total of 655 tax refunds to a single address in Lithuania, and 343 refunds went to a lone address in Shanghai, according to a report by the agency's inspector general. The IRS has since added safeguards to prevent similar schemes, but the criminals are innovating as well, said the AP report.
The amount of rampant criminal fraud in Russia cannot have happened without Putin's knowledge or assent.  We know this because the very same perpetrators of the Browder-Hermitage Capital tax fraud were awarded medals by Putin for their 'heroism' in the scheme, believe it or not.
The Russian government then charged Bill Browder with the theft, which resulted in a call for his arrest by Interpol, and the resulting Red Notice--a notice the Russian government put out to Interpol for his arrest.  They have put out a Red Notice 3 times to date, and 3 times Interpol has rejected their request because of the overwhelming evidence that the Russian government was behind the theft.
This shows the lengths corrupt officials have gone to cover up their thefts.  That's why we should have no illusion about the IRS tax return thefts.  It's a new cold war, of sorts.  Putin's Russia will want to continue stealing tax refunds from US taxpayers as they have done in Russia.
We also know this because Sergei Magnitsky , Bill Browder's Russian attorney, was imprisoned and beaten to death by the same perpetrators for his refusal to recant the evidence of theft that defrauded the Russian people.
Harlan Green  2015
Follow Harlan Green on Twitter: www.twitter.com/HarlanGreen
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:46:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sweden Is About To Give New Fathers A Third Month Of Paid Paternity Leave</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/sweden-paternity-leave_n_7463530.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Sweden is a great place to be a dad, and the country is about to make things even better for soon-to-be fathers.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Countries With No Maternity Leave
of


New parents in the U.S. are entitled to a measly 12 weeks of job-protected time off under the 1993 Family Medical Leave Act, though with no cash benefits. And the 12-week rule only covers those who work for companies with 50 employees or more. Unfortunately for expectant parents, a full 96 per cent of businesses in the United States have fewer than 50 workers on the payroll.  Some states do offer paid leave, along with more enlightened companies, including Google, which gives new parents 22 weeks plus $500 in cash to cover baby-related expenses.  Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer increased paid leave for moms from eight weeks to 16; the company also gives dads eight weeks off.
In this tiny nation, nestled within South Africa, life expectancy is just 52 years, three-quarters of the country's two million people are subsistence farmers, and 42 per cent of women are unemployed.
Also located in southern Africa, Swaziland is an impoverished nation where 60 per cent of the population lives on less than $1.25 a day.  It also has one of the highest rate of HIV infection among adults aged 15 to 49: 26 per cent. Among pregnant women between the ages of 30 and 24, that spikes to a heart-wrenching 54 per cent.  Not surprisingly, the country is in the bottom 10 when it comes to life expectancy, which is just 47 years.
This island just north of Australia remains one of the least explored places in the world. The majority of Papua New Guinea's seven million inhabitants still live in traditional societies and speak 820 indigenous languages. Most women are illiterate and have an average of 3.3 children (compared to 1.89 in the U.S.).
The West African nation of Liberia was colonized by black Americans in the 1820s, mostly by freed slaves, who ruled for 130 years.  In 1980, they were overthrown in a military coup that led to bloody civil wars that killed 250,000 people and brought Charles Taylor to power. Taylor was himself overthrown after yet another horrific conflict.  In 2005, a Harvard-trained economist named Ellen Johnson Sirleaf came to power in Liberia's first fair election. Africa's first female president won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2011. So there's hope that Liberia will be surpassing the U.S. on maternity leave sometime soon.
Maternity Leaves From Around The World
Length Of Maternity Leave: 52 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid:  55 per cent at 17 weeks for maternity leave, and the additional 35 weeks can be taken by either parent. Wages also depend on province.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 3 Months Percentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 67
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Paid, 38 Weeks UnpaidPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 14 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 12 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: No national program but cash benefits may be provided at the state level.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 15 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 82 per cent for the first 30 days and 75 per cent for the remaining period.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 105 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 70
Length Of Maternity Leave: 105 Days Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 112 Days Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 16 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 119 Days Percentage Of Wages Paid: 50
Length Of Maternity Leave: 18 Weeks Percentage Of Wages Paid: Each parent can take up to 12 months of leave, of which 18 weeks are paid.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 126 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 85
Length Of Maternity Leave: 120 to 150 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: Parental benefits paid at 100 per cent for the shorter duration of leave and 80 per cent for the longer option
Length Of Maternity Leave: 140 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 20 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 140 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 5 MonthsPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 135 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid:90
Length Of Maternity Leave: 24 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 70
Length Of Maternity Leave: 26 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80
Length Of Maternity Leave: 28 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 60
Length Of Maternity Leave: 28 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 55
Length Of Maternity Leave: 9 MonthsPercentage Of Wages Paid: Not found.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 36 to 46 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: Parental benefits paid at 100 per cent for the shorter duration of leave and 80 per cent for the longer option.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 365 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80 per cent prior to birth and for 150 days after and 50 per cent for the rest of the leave period. Albanian Prime Minister Sali Berisha shown here.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 1 YearPercentage Of Wages Paid: 82 per cent for the first 30 days and 75 per cent for the remaining period.
Length Of Maternity Leave: 1 YearPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 52 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
Length Of Maternity Leave: 52 WeeksPercentage Of Wages Paid: 100
52 Weeks 90 (p)
Length Of Maternity Leave: 420 DaysPercentage Of Wages Paid: 80
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:46:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Putting Silk Road Founder Ross Ulbricht Behind Bars Accomplish Anything?</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/stefanie-jones/ross-ulbricht-silk-road-sentence_b_7464438.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Friday Silk Road founder Ross Ulbricht will be sentenced. He faces the possibility of between 20 years to life behind bars because drugs were bought and sold on his website. The prosecution is painting him as a major drug dealer and blaming him for the deaths of six people who overdosed (without acknowledging that our current drug policies lead to 35,000 accidental overdose deaths per year).
On the eve of his sentencing, it's worth considering: what will we actually accomplish by putting this man away?
The fact is, the existence of Silk Road proved something we all know to be true: millions of people around the world want to use and buy drugs. As many have argued, including my former colleague Meghan Ralston and Phil Smith on Alternet , Silk Road's online marketplace actually reduced the harms of drugs in several key ways.
Silk Road reduced the potential violence associated with buying drugs. By taking away the need for face-to-face interaction, Silk Road reduced the violence commonly associated with drug purchases. It also took power away from cartels.
It allowed for better knowledge about content and purity. One of the greatest dangers of drug use is that it's very difficult to know if you're getting what you intend to get, especially with today's rapidly diversifying synthetic market. Using a review system similar to what you'd see on Yelp or other sites, a seller who was not representing his or her product accurately would not have customers long, and a user could be sure about his or her purchase.
It encouraged harm reduction among users. Silk Road had a whole section of its site devoted to safer drug use practices. It's relevant and important that this kind of content reach people at the very place where they are making purchases.
Ulbricht's defense recognized this and included these arguments in their memo to Katherine Forrest, the judge handing down the sentencing. If nothing else, a shorter sentence might help acknowledge the reality that no matter what your opinion about drug sales, Silk Road served as harm reduction for these marketplaces.
Friday, the path of Ulbricht's life will be determined. But his sentencing will have little to no impact on those millions of people who will still buy and use drugs. Other online drug marketplaces will arise and the violent, wasteful drug war will carry on unchecked.
Unless we end 40 years of failure, and consider the lessons from Silk Road, and think about a new approach to drug use and sales.
Stefanie Jones is the nightlife community engagement manager for the Drug Policy Alliance.
CORRECTION: A previous version of this post incorrectly stated that Ross Ulbricht may be facing 30 years to life in prison.
This piece first appeared on the Drug Policy Alliance Blog .
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:29:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FINALLY: Science Figured Out Where The Holes In Swiss Cheese Have All Gone</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/swiss-cheese-holes-gone-science_n_7462942.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>New research is poking holes in old thinking about Swiss cheese. Namely: Where do cheese holes come from, and where have they all gone?</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
New research is poking holes in old thinking about Swiss cheese. Namely: Where do cheese holes come from, and where have they all gone?
Those questions have plagued Swiss cheese producers who, in the last 15 years, have seen the signature holes in their product decrease for no apparent reason. Thanks to Agroscope, a government-funded Swiss agriculture institute, we now know it all comes down to hay.
In a report released Thursday, Agroscope and the Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Science and Technology revealed microscopic hay particles are believed to be responsible for the creation of holes in cheeses such as Emmental and Appenzell.
Cleanliness has increased in cheese-making facilities in the last 15 years, virtually eliminating the possibility for outside particles to enter the milk before it's converted into cheese and stored. That, in turn, has prevented Swiss cheese from developing its characteristic holes.
Agroscope spokesman Regis Nyffeler told The Telegraph the primary difference in cheese manufacturing methods has been "the disappearance of the traditional bucket" used during milking. Before, small amounts of hay would have entered the bucket; now, sealed milking machines send the milk straight to a filter.
Agroscope arrived at their newest hay-pothesis after taking multiple CT scans of cheese as it developed over a 130-day period, reports the Swiss Broadcasting Corporation . The research overturns a prior theory , held since at least 1917 , that concluded the holes were created by bacteria that produced carbon dioxide bubbles.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:19:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why, more than ever, UN Peacekeeping needs global support</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/herve-ladsous/why-more-than-ever-un-pea_b_7464110.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
By Herv  Ladsous, Under-Secretary-General for the United Nations Department of  Peacekeeping Operations
Eighteen  months ago, Bentiu, like most towns in South Sudan, was bustling with the  restlessness of markets, people trading and children going to school. UNMISS, the UN Mission in South Sudan , was  busy supporting development and growth in the world's youngest nation.
Today,  a visitor to the UN Mission's base outside Bentiu in Unity State, would see a  sea of blue and white tarpaulin tents and hastily-erected stalls. The base has  become temporary home to some 63,000 civilians seeking protection from the  cataclysm of violence that has gripped the new state of South Sudan since the  outbreak of the political crisis in December 2013. The town of Bentiu itself remains  deserted, its main dirt road lined with the grim evidence of an ongoing war in  the absence of a final peace agreement between Government and Opposition  forces.
The  story is repeated across the country. Today, more than 130,000 are being  protected by UN peacekeepers in seven bases, with civilians continuing to arrive  at UN protection sites as they flee unimaginable suffering and grave human  rights violations.
As  we mark the International Day of UN Peacekeepers , the reality is that our peacekeepers  are often the only hope for a better life for the civilians they are mandated  to serve. In other places where peacekeeping missions are deployed today, there  is little peace to keep. In some of the harshest conditions on Earth, UN  personnel must negotiate complex threats each day amidst political instability,  with large, often terrified populations to protect. They work to provide  security in these places, while pursuing a political solution to ongoing  conflict.
This  is the case in Mali, where peacekeepers strive to bring stability while bearing  the brunt of violent attacks from armed groups. Since the establishment of the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali in July  2013, 36 peacekeepers have been killed and more than 170 others have been  wounded in hostile incidents alone. It is also the case in the Central African  Republic , where we are seeing encouraging signs following the 2013 breakdown in  law and order and widespread ethnically motivated violence. Here, 10,000 UN  troops, police and civilians are on the ground, supporting efforts to bring the  country back on to the path of peace, good governance and stability. Earlier in  May, the country adopted a peace pact that reflects the people of the Central  African Republic's aspirations to put the conflict behind them once and for  all. Our peacekeepers battle inhospitable terrain and an almost complete lack  of infrastructure every day to react quickly to flare-ups of violence which, if  left unchecked, could threaten this fragile peace.
Over the course of nearly seven decades,  UN peacekeeping has proven itself to be a legitimate, reliable and effective means  of protecting civilians and facilitating the transition from conflict to peace.  In countries like Liberia, Timor-Leste and Bosnia Herzegovina, peacekeeping has  played a critical role in helping stabilise countries as they seek to rebuild.  Today, more than 125,000 military, police and civilian staff carry on this work  in 16 peacekeeping operations world-wide, our largest deployment in history,  serving as a testament to the international community's faith in peacekeeping  as a tool for bringing peace and security.
But,  for UN peacekeeping to continue responding effectively and robustly to the  conflicts of today and tomorrow, it needs a strengthened international  partnership and the willingness of all to share the burden and risk. In  environments where peacekeepers are directly targeted, where widespread  violence is ongoing, or where thousands of civilians need protection from  unthinkable acts of violence, peacekeeping operations must remain fit for  purpose. Our missions require well-trained and skilled troops from a broad  array of countries. When crises erupt, they must be ready to deploy more  quickly to where they are most needed. And to confront the unique challenges of  this century, peacekeepers require the tools and capabilities of this century.  In the Democratic Republic of the Congo , unarmed unmanned aerial vehicles are  being used to improve situational awareness, serve as a deterrent to armed  groups and improve mandate delivery and the safety and security of our  personnel. In Mali, an innovative Information Fusion Cell is improving the  information-gathering efforts of the peacekeeping mission as it confronts determined  non-state actors and armed groups. As we honour the 126 peacekeepers that died  in 2014 , these tools help our Blue Helmets to better protect themselves and  vulnerable populations.
A  renewed engagement of all Member States of the United Nations is critical. This  process has already begun and will receive a major boost in the margins of this  year's General Assembly when the Secretary-General and several world leaders  will co-host a Summit on UN peacekeeping. For its part, UN peacekeeping is  determined to be more innovative, more flexible and more cost-effective. With  an annual budget of just under $8.5 billion -- less than one half of one percent of global  military spending -- we are working to increase our value for money and using  new approaches to implement our mandates more effectively and efficiently.
Peacekeeping  missions deliver because they represent a convergence of interests that is the  fundamental concept behind the United Nations. At a moment in history where new  crises and conflicts emerge constantly, the stakes for peacekeeping are higher,  and the consequences of failure are dire. The people of Bentiu, like the  populations protected by missions around the world, today deserve a UN  peacekeeping institution that is an effective tool of international peace and  security. More than ever, today, UN peacekeeping needs global support.
Find out more at www.un.org/peacekeeping

Follow Herv Ladsous on Twitter: www.twitter.com/UNPeacekeeping
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:15:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>10 Children's Books That Paved The Way For A New Queer Protagonist</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/lgbtq-childrens-books_n_7462250.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
In Kendrick Daye and Myles E. Johnsons Large Fears, Jeremiah Nebula may not be a bullfrog. But he is the queer, black protagonist of a childrens picture book -- a genre traditionally dominated by heterosexual, cisgender, white characters. Although the politics of representation is an issue for all literary forms, parent sensitivity has made materials for young readers particularly resistant to plots that question gender, sexuality or the institution of the family.
Daye and Johnson were frustrated with those age-old patterns, so they decided to create new ones. Their recent Kickstarter campaign casts the project as both subtle and radical. Jeremiah, they say coyly, is just a boy who loves pink. But they also stress how his queer, black identity makes him a character that defies gender roles, race politics, sexuality, and his fears.
Jeremiahs story builds on over 30 years of childrens books that portray LGBTQ characters, translating complex issues of gender and sexuality to an accessible, picture-heavy format. These books, though, reveal far more than cutesy anecdotes. They are instructional, cathartic, and ethical, explaining different family models, connecting children with LGBTQ identities or parents to fictional counterparts, and teaching values of acceptance at impressionable ages.
Jenny Lives with Eric and Martin by Susanne Bsche (1981)
This black-and-white Danish photobook was arguably the first to feature gay characters. Two men raise their daughter, Jenny, whose biological mother lives nearby and visits from time to time. Most events are normal childrens books fare like laundry-folding and surprise birthday parties. But the characters also deal with a homophobic comment from a stranger in the street.
Heather Has Two Mommies by Lesla Newman and Diana Souza (1989)
Like Bsches story, this one follows a child with same-sex parents. New plot points include artificial insemination and an inclusive discussion at Heathers playgroup about different family structures. In real-life playgroups, the response to this book was far less benign: the story rocked the U.S., and the resulting controversy led to extensive parodies including a "Simpsons" version: Bart Has Two Mommies.
Ashas Mums by Rosamund Elwin, Michele Paulse and Dawn Lee (1990)
Asha needs to get a permission slip signed by her mother, but she is perplexed when she must decide which of her two moms to ask. While Heather was lucky enough to have an accepting playgroup, Asha confronts a far less hospitable school -- and world. Its a tale for anyone whose family does not fit into educational bureaucracy, and Ashas African-Canadian identity marks a decisive step away from lily-white characters.
Daddys Roommate by Michael Willhoite (1991)
You might recognize the name from the 2008 presidential campaign when it came out that Sarah Palin, back in her 1995 councilwoman days, had said the book should not be permitted in public libraries. Why? Theres a gay relationship between the the father and his new roommate-actually-boyfriend, Frank. Plus it all starts off with a divorce and arrives at a pretty clear message: Being gay is just one more kind of love.
King &amp; King by Linda De Haan and Stern Nijland (2002)
Originally published in Dutch, this book offered both a new take on the royal marriage story, with a gay child rather than just gay parents. I've never cared much for princesses, says the princely protagonist, as he finds a series of potential wives paraded in front of him by his wedding-hungry mother. Then, he spots one of the princesses brothers. They are soon crowned King and King, and the story ends with a subversive same-sex kiss -- which launched a series of conservative campaigns to ban the book.
One Dad, Two Dads, Brown Dad, Blue Dads by Johnny Valentine and Melody Sarecky (2004)
Instead of focusing on a single storyline, the book features two kids comparing different paternal figures. Blue, it turns out, is a not-so-subtle euphemism for gay, and the children slowly come to the realization that all skin-colors and sexual identities are equally valid. (Bonus points for the enchanting Seussical rhyming scheme.)
And Tango Makes Three by Justin Richardson, Peter Parnell and Henry Cole (2005)
A tale of two male penguins who are chick-less until a zookeeper helps them adopt Tango from a heterosexual couple. Animals are always one of the easier ways to discuss unconventional storylines, but that didnt stop Singapore from banning the book along with two others last year. In fact, its ranked third on ALAs list of  Most challenged books of the 21st century , which is hard to explain considering how heartwarming these polar birds are. Did we mention its based on real gay penguins at the Central Park Zoo ?
10,000 Dresses by Marcus Ewert and Rex Ray (2008)
Bailey is a boy by day who, at night, dreams of cross-dressing. His night-time escapades are rebuked by his family, until he finds a seamstress in playmate Laurel. Baileys story is an early forerunner to Jeremiahs, for it broke from the gay-character plot to examine what it meant to be a gender-queer child.
My New Mommy by Lilly Mossiano and Sage Mossiano (2012)
Who says transgender identity cant be explained to young children? Four-year-old Violet has a transitioning father who carefully walks her -- and us -- through the process. Like Daye and Johnson, Mossiano was frustrated with the lack of childrens materials, so she took matters into her own hands. She challenged herself to make the content accessible to a young audience, but the real challenge is the one she posed to traditional portrayals of gender in children's books.
Call Me Tree by Maya Christina Gonzalez (2014)
The third in a trilogy that opted for gender neutral pronouns, providing what the writer called a much needed break from the constant boy-girl assumptions and requirements. Gonzalez took another decisive step away from the gay parent trend and gave us an unambiguously ambiguous gender-queer character. Her engagement with the Chicano identity also departed from the classic whiteness of LGBTQ childrens characters.
Morris Micklewhite and the Tangerine Dress by Christine Baldacchino and Isabelle Malenfant (2014)
Like Bailey, Morris has a penchant for gender-queer behavior. He loves to wear the titles orange garment but his fashion choices leave him open to relentless teasing from his classmates. Tensions escalate, and Morris becomes physically ill from the psychological pain. Though his imagination helps him triumph in the end, the books real triumph is that it gives a harsh and realistic account of queer bullying.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:07:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Here's More Proof That We Shouldn't Stereotype Dogs By Breed</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/pit-bull-bans-ireland_n_7450400.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>If you're hoping that restricting dogs by breed will lead to fewer dog bites, well, you're barking up the wrong tree, according to the author </Description>
        <MainBody>

Robbybad:Vicious pitbull has my baby cornered.  No wait, she's using her as a recliner never mind.
Stacy Bove-Fulgenzi:Sweet, Gentle and Loving
Terrence Greene:
johnalcock:
Whitney Pflanzer:Starla and Sienna were both found as strays in Indianapolis. After being adopted from the city shelter, they now spend their days as happy girls and love everyone they meet.
Jill Tyler McDaniels:My foster dogs!
Katie Griffith:Capone loves his turtle :)
Adam Mangel:She was mistreated from her previous owners, but patience and a flood of love have brought her back to trust.
Justin Moreno:Our 5 Year old Pitty Marley with her little sister Penny the french bulldog
Krista Hickman:Giving my godson love in the morning!
craigkaos:Piggy Roo, the Pit Bull, and Lucy, the Australian Cattle Dog, have helped raise over 50 Pit Bull foster puppies through Richmond-based Ring Dog Rescue over the past three years.
Megan Lovejoy:This adorable girl is up for adoption through Love-A-Bull, a non profit rescue in Austin, TX. She was rescued from a sad life, which can negatively effect some dogs, but what about this girl? Nope! She is delighted to be friends with EVERYONE. All she wants is non stop tummy rubs, and her favorite little pink stuffed owl toy.
Chris Loveless:Joker and Daphne - Daphne (grey and white) has just met Joker after being brought home from the SPCA. She spent two years as a neglected, starved, and abused dog.
Nomsnotbombs:Mona is a rescue pit mix who hasn't let  her early life experiences deter her from loving life...or every single person she meets. Her appetite for snuggles is insatiable, and she fancies herself to be a 55 pound lapdog.
Megan Lovejoy:Betty the pit bull, Bushi the pit mix, and Polly the teacup pit bull (really chihuahua/peke mix) having a ferocious naptime.
Megan Lovejoy:Betty the wonder-bull!
Candi Diamond:Grandma's cuddle muffin and protector follows her everywhere!
Melissa Sue HutJo:
Angie Laurusaitis:Daisy adored my mother who had Alzheimers. Daisy knew mom was special and kept very close to her
Jamie Delgado:My niece and her Cane Corso/American Bulldog 9 month old "puppy"
AVSmartz:A boy &amp; his dog.  Dog's remind us to stay young and release our inner child. Not a day goes by that Einstein doesn't take me outside to play. Something I would not do every day if not for his friendship.
amy5167:We rescued Emmitt from the county pound on his euthanasia day.  He is a great dog...
Robert Andrade:Petunia and Moby adopted siblings napping
PitBullMomma:Dixie, at the time a 1 year old American Pit Bull Terrier, is best friends with her human sister, Hadley.
Heather DeWitt:
Ashley Endres:Petunia always gets tuckered out at sleepovers with my godchildren.
Brandi Hyatt:His christmas present one year. He kept handing it to my barely one year old daughter Seraphina to "throw" lol
HarkShark:Our Pit Bull Pearl loves to curl up on the pillow on the couch.
Danielle Bauman:Um, excuse me but that looks like a hot dog you're holding. May I pleeeeeeaaase?
Jennifer Flees:
Brandy Lehto:Suvi and Ramsey live peacefully with their chihuahua brother.
Brian Martin:Pierre and KrazyKat snuggling up for a nap.
rappublicist:Pit Bulls can be super heroes
PitBullMomma:Dixie, a 2 year old American Pit Bull Terrier, is best friends with her human sister, Hadley.
Brandy Lehto:Suvi lives at home with her sister Ramsey (a doberman) and her brother Pablo (a chihuahua). They work day and night to advocate for misunderstood breeds!
ILLJWILL11:
Sam Goodwin 1:Eliza is 2 years old &amp; was rescued by her previous owners from an owner that had her locked in a closet where she only had drywall to eat. She adopted me when they had to move &amp; their new landlord was scared of pit bulls.
Rich Wyckoff:Allie and Brody are both rescues. Allie is teaching her little brother the ins and outs of what faces you need to make to sucker their owners into giving them treats. It's working.
westophervan:All smiles.
Riah Day:My little brother and I taking a nap with freckles (Fatty)
Fayclis: 3 Girls and a Boy
Laura Bobrowsky:Bubba keeping watch on his baby girl
Jill Tyler McDaniels:
woolysock:Mini is a rescue dog. We call her our pit-belle ;-)
Chloe
ILLJWILL11:The nicest, BIGGEST, (100 lb) lap dog I've ever had or seen!
peebo:Child and cop friendly!
Adam Mangel:This is my boy. Had him since he was a little sausage.  He's 10 years old in April and he's never attacked anyone.
Jill Tyler McDaniels:
mmmchelsea:
Chrysta Cherrie:Our buddy, rescued by the Michigan Humane Society, is happily tuckered out after an afternoon playing in the yard.
Our handsome pit at the dog park! His favorite game is chased, only he's the one that likes to be chased. :)
Stevie Manning:Hank loves people and pets of all shapes and sizes!
Justin Moreno:Marley, the 5 year old Pitt bull hanging out with her favorite people in the entire world
the1Murdoc:
Heather DeWitt:
Rick Minyard:I have one each of the top two breeds on the list.  And am all the better for it.
terriecro:Ella just loves to snuggle on the couch
doutsiderd:"Rocky" is a beautiful 18 month old pure pitbull, with 2 different eye colors! She positively thinks that she is human, uses the TOILET!,sleeps under the covers with my son and his girlfriend, has her own seat in the car, and as you can see, loves to dress cool! She is adorable, loveable, great listener, talks to you intelligently, and is such an added family member! She is also gentle and kind with my 8 year old grandson, and loves to open his bedroom door with her paws when she is closed out from him! We love her!!!
Hannah Hilgeford:This is a photo of one of my three pitbulls adopted from a shelter!  She had less than a week before she would be put down due to her breed when Adore-A-Bull Rescue stepped in and saved her.  She is now an irreplaceable part of my family.  And as you can see here she has the most gentle touch and loving intentions while sitting with my Grandmother.
KChance:She will attack you with her tongue.
Kate6917:Bella my 8yr old Pitbull with my 1yr old being used as a couch by my 1yr old 3lb Chihuahua, Fiona
Sharon Brown84:Rub my belly!! Star is a Stafforshire Terrier/Pit Bull
Cindy Parks Ross:
Kristina Gale:Our pups Louie and Nina, having a playdate with Mitzi
HuffPost Blogger Rayya Elias:
michellejacobson:
BeMoreDog:Zoey, a 2 year old rescued pitty/coon hound mix, would much rather cuddle then hurt a fly!
terriecro:Spencer's life was devoted to bringing joy to everyone and loved to give kisses!
Kimberly McClain:We found Hank wandering in the desert while we were camping. Skinny and lethargic but sweet as can be, he loves everyone and everything (kitties included). Now spends his days sleeping, eating, and playing with our two other dogs!
Here's Louie, our Pit/Newfoundland mix. He was acting very guilty this afternoon so I immediately went on a hunt to figure out what he'd done.
Laura Filtness:Brooklyn and Boss are both rescue dogs. Brooklyn was rescued in TN and has helped many people see just how fun loving the breed can be. Boss was rescued by Animal Rescue Corps as part of Operation Forgotten Angels and now has high hopes of becoming a therapy dog.
Della Earley:
HuffPost Blogger Rayya Elias:
rappublicist:Found on street with truck chain padlocked to neck. Look at him now!
Kathy Mc:This adorable girl was abandoned on the streets of NYC more than 3 years ago, and spent a year in foster care before she came to us. She loves sunshine and snuggling, even on a hammock!
CrazyDogLady4:
CourtneyColeman:Swami doing what pit bulls do best: being a couch potato.
bednarluck:
Si Sa:
Michelle Oosterloo:My bull terrier mix Poker. We got him through a rescue 3 years ago and he is the best dog I have ever known. He shares his home with 3 kids, a Boston Terrier and 4 cats. In this pic, my then 5 year old daughter had the flu. He stayed with her all night. Didn't even get up for his dinner.
Sabrina Reichstein Carey:Everyone wants to be on dad's lap so they piled on :)
SamanthaBlake14:My nine year old Ozzy posing like a pin up girl.
Ashley Pie:
Wtebb001:Dexter is a rescue from VA Beach ACAC. He loves his people and playi8ng outdoors.
Cm123803:Raoul Duke giving kisses to his Aunt Greta.
Candi Diamond:The very best dogs on the planet!
Melissa LeBender:Party Animal
Rebecca Mis:Amelia, an American Staffordshire Terrier, enjoying time with her squeaky ball.
Jamie Delgado:Paulie is a sweet 8 month old pitbull found in an abandoned car behind a restaurant.  He has exhuberant energy and will chase balls all day long and learn tricks for yummy treats.  He is available for adoption at the Grass Valley Animal Control shelter in CA.
Noir Dfault:Pancho is a rescue pup that has changed my life and lives of everyone he meets.  He is a true example of the breed and the love of my life.
Michael Brozovic:My boy Petey.
Michael Brozovic:Just loungin' around.
Jamie Delgado:Paulie is a sweet 8 month old pitbull found in an abandoned car behind a restaurant.  He has exhuberant energy and will chase balls all day long and learn tricks for yummy treats.  He is available for adoption at the Grass Valley Animal Control shelter in CA.
Jamie Delgado:Popeye was found as a stray being attacked by 2 other dogs, he just hid under a car.  He is loves to chew on balls like they are gum and is learning how to sit still for doggie "cookies" He is available for adoption right now at the Grass Valley Animal Control shelter in CA.
mipadre:
Eh653198:We adore all of our dogs!!!!!
Athena Scheidet:Peewee and Bella Mia enjoying a swell cuddle
s s s s:Rory &amp; Cy, pit bull mixes, live in harmony with little sister Cookie and 2 cats!
Diana DeGarmo:One of our failed foster, pit mixes. The Face of Boe, Bowie for short, is the biggest baby of a dog you'll ever meet. He was found on Christmas eve, tied to a fence by two policemen in NYC. I simultaneously want to shake his former owners for abandoning him and hug them because I'm so glad he's mine. Mostly shake though because Bowie was definitely not treated well previously. He's living the good life now.
Sabrina Reichstein Carey:Boxie the pibble loves her kitty and doggy friends :)
Heather Farquhar:Smudge at his book club
sampista:A ball and some grass--pure bliss.
Ashley Thibault:Best dog in the world.  My Dot, she's 10.  Pictured with her brothers Redgie and Bagpuss.
Robin Weissbohn Barnes:
Wtebb001:Dexter and our other rescue Winter
Robs Raven:Daddy's Girl
Meagan Jane:My Pit mix and my new boxer pup
Souhaila El-Souki:Sweet Alice's favorite spot to cuddle up and relax-my bed
Souhaila El-Souki:My sweet Alice showing grandma love
Souhaila El-Souki:My sweet Alice in her favorite comfy chair with my mom
jlgclassof2000:Gemma at Guardian Pit Bull Rescue's Kissing Booth
gow81:My girls and their dogs, Ace our cocker spaniel and Kitty our pitbull.
Laura Filtness:rooklyn and Boss are both rescue dogs. Brooklyn was rescued in TN and has helped many people see just how fun loving the breed can be. Boss was rescued by Animal Rescue Corps as part of Operation Forgotten Angels and now has high hopes of becoming a therapy dog.
Gurpreet Sandhu:Stella
Eva Lagudi-Devereux:Our beautiful Rescue! We are constantly trying to overturn the stereotype of aggressive dangerous pit bulls. She may cuddle you to death.... but I think thats it!
Azsa Hanson:
gow81:Always looking out for her.
Fred Aguirre:Sam and Mali garden keepers
Rachel Harrison Massa:Shea spent the first year of his life passed around from shelter to foster home, and we still can't understand why no one wanted him.  Aside from being the sweetest most loving dog, he is the absolute best friend to our 3 year old son.  His only problem is - he thinks he is a lap dog!
Sarah Miller Ross:Bauzy Boo Bear - the sweetest, most gentle baby boy ever :)
Pj Kendrick:Juneau is a ten month old rescued pit bull mix. She also happens to me the best friend a girl could ever hope for.
Sarah Miller Ross:They love to snuggle, even when they don't quite fit ;)
Vicki Gramm:Taking a break from all the fun.
Kim Wangnoo:My grandson Jaylen and his BFF, Rylee.  Sweetest dog in the world.  I was leery when my daughter got a Pit but Rylee changed my heart 100%
DunkNorris:MooMoo is a beautiful rescued pit bull. She loves to enjoy the warm summer sun on her face.
Lizz Rockford:MOMMMYYYYY are you still fueling up the car I can't see you
Lindsay Henson:Roxy our rescue posing with her hat on July 4th.
Ashley Duesler:Bailey (brown) 8 years old &amp; Lola, 10 months old are the best of friends and snuggle buddies with my two boys!
Jill Spinello:
Shannon Westphal Kubenez:Mr. Jack!
Rebecca Cohen Clayter:Two rescued pit bulls = two VERY spoiled babies!  Beau was only 5 months old and roaming the streets of Philadelphia when we adopted him.  Halo is a pure breed American Staffordshire Terrier whose family never registered her microchip!  She's our "foster failure"!
Heather Feamster:
nvtribefan:
Claudiagsb:The most amazing companions our family can have!Pita, Lilo and Rocky , rescued from a high kill shelter in FL, they now enjoying their days sunbathing or on the sofa!
David Von Eschen:Madison as a puppy
Eileen Finn:Our girl, Sunshine, has the cutest, goofiest grin ever.
Jake McGee:Teddy in Shades
ChristopherCharles:Baby was kept on a chain in a backyard for three years, She recently got her Canine Good Citizen certificate and is now training to be a therapy dog!
bcarmic:Patty the Pet Bull  bobcarmichael.com
Cage LaCapitan:Stewie does not like to get out of bed. He'd rather snuggle than get up.
casaroonc:The best dog that has ever been part of our family. My boys could do anything to him when they were younger &amp; he would tolerate it &amp; give back love. He also understood over 100 words, he was very smart.  He was truly a forever dog. He is greatly missed.
RonJRoy:First day home and so excited!
Kristine Genovese:Blue is a 5 yr old rescued Pit/Rhodesian Ridgeback X who loves dressing up in costumes and playing with his 6 yr old human brother and border collie sister. He is the most mellow dog we've ever had, and at 80 lbs is a big lap dog/cuddle bunny!
Mags226:Benny the Pit Bull has four brothers who are all cats. They are best friends and take turns adoring each other.
Stacy Lusk:Juniper visiting the beach for the first time. We rescued her from a local shelter in July of this year.
CJ Osburn:Acey lounging with his Dad
Si Sa:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:56:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Guide to Slovenia's Best Craft Breweries</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/inga-batur/a-guide-to-slovenias-best-craft-breweries_b_7447918.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Despite its size of 20.273 square kilometers, Slovenia is home to roughly around 28 breweries, making it a perfect destination for any beer connoisseur. The two major brands are Union and Lasko, recently bought by Heineken. Avoid getting sucked into the local debate on which of these two is better and rather give these small microbreweries a chance. These are the true stars of Slovenia's beer renaissance.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Despite its size of 20.273 square kilometers, Slovenia is home to roughly around 28 breweries, making it a perfect destination for any beer connoisseur. The two major brands are Union and Lasko, recently bought by Heineken. Avoid getting sucked into the local debate on which of these two is better and rather give these small microbreweries a chance. These are the true stars of Slovenia's beer renaissance.
Bevog Brewery
It's technically produced in Austria, just a few kilometers away from the Slovenian border, but it's owned by a Slovenian. The microbrewery is dedicated to making beers of top fermentation, better known as ales. The owner Vasja Golar claims: "Despite the English roots of ales, we here at Bevog are very creative and do not stick to the established norms. We design our beers in our own way, the way we know is right."
With all the awards they have recently received for both beer and the design of their labels they are apparently doing it right. You can give all their beers a chance at the brewery or get some to take home.
Try: Pale ale Tak -- very tasty and aromatic. It's just a bit bitter at the end, and then it mellows down, beginning for another sip.
Reservoir Dogs
This is one of the youngest microbreweries in Slovenia, located in Nova Gorica. In their case the saying: curiosity trumpets experience, definitely holds true, because despite being young they are certainly making their mark. They've named their beer after the four horsemen of the apocalypse -- a force of nature to be reckoned with, just like their Grim Reaper, IPA and Warriors Pale Ale. As the horsemen, they deliver a blow.
Try: Grim Reaper starts off with an aroma of tropical fruit and then the sweet bitterness takes over.
Mali Grad
A married couple Anja and Urban Florjancic have established their own microbrewery in Kamnik, a few kilometers away from Ljubljana. While husband is in charge of the recipes, they try to further improve them together. In their case being small is not necessarily a disadvantage because they've managed to turn it into a lead, as they pay special attention to the ingredients they use and don't rush the whole process. The results are very delicious bottles of beer.
Try: India Pale Lager (special edition), with a lovely taste full of citruses and it finishes with a bitter bang.
Human Fish
They claim to be the leading family-owned microbrewery in Slovenia. Their glass of IPA was actually my first sample of Slovenian craft beer. You could say I have them to thank for getting hooked and I know for a fact I am not the only one. Their microbrewery is based in Vrhnika, just a few kilometers out of the capital. It is worth mentioning since they offer tours of their place and you can check for yourself to see how the job is being done. They have a wide variety of different beers and are constantly experimenting and trying something new. So, the visit will definitely be inspirational.
Try: Their IPA, which they named "SIPA" (meaning "squid" in Slovenian), hazy orange color of the beer, delicious aroma and a bitter jolt.
Carniola
Rok Rutar is the owner of the Carniola Brewery and he pays special attention to the ingredients he uses. And if you want a uniquely Slovenian experience give his drinks a go, since he primarily uses Slovenian hops. What will also immediately capture your imagination are the pretty cool labels.
Try: ESB, light and refreshing, making it just ideal for the summer.
Pelicon
Voters of Ratebeer website voted them the best beer and brewery in Slovenia in 2014. Matej Pelicon and Anita Lozar opened their microbrewery in the heart of the Vipava valley in Ajdovscina. They launched their first pale ale beer Pally in the November 2013.
Try: They are most famous for their India pale ale beer called the 3rd Pill. But just to make sure how good they are and check if the awards are well deserved you can try the others as well, because their list is getting longer.
This post originally appeared on coolkidzcooltrips.com.
Follow Inga Batur on Twitter: www.twitter.com/Coolkidzcooltri
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:56:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Warren Pushes Obama To Keep Slavery Ban In Trade Deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/elizabeth-warren-trade-slavery_n_7463252.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>BOSTON -- Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.) on Thursday decried efforts by the Obama administration to undermine an anti-slavery measure that the Senate approved last week as part of a major trade bill.</Description>
        <MainBody>Warren Pushes Obama To Keep Slavery Ban In Trade Deal
Posted:
Updated:
4 hours ago
WASHINGTON, D.C. - Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.) delivers remarks during the Good Jobs Green Jobs National Conference at the Washington Hilton April 13, 2015 in Washington, D.C. Sponsored by a varied coalition including lightweight metals producer Alcoa, the United Steelworks union, the Sierra Club and various other labor, industry and telecommunications leaders, the conference promotes the use of efficient and renewable energy and cooperation in updating the country's energy infrastructure. | Chip Somodevilla via Getty Images
reddit
BOSTON -- Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.) on Thursday decried efforts by the Obama administration to undermine an anti-slavery measure that the Senate approved last week as part of a major trade bill.
The provision, authored by Sen. Robert Menendez (D-N.J.), would bar the U.S. from expediting trade deals with governments that the State Department deems to be among the very worst offenders on human trafficking. The Senate passed the Menendez language late Friday night, despite strident objections from President Barack Obama's administration. Both Obama officials and House Ways and Means Committee Chairman Paul Ryan (R-Wis.) are now working to defang the anti-slavery effort.
The problem for Obama is Malaysia, one of 11 other nations included in the controversial trade talks for the Trans-Pacific Partnership. Malaysia occupies a strategically important position in global shipping routes, but its government has a long history of supporting some of the most abusive forms of human trafficking, earning it a spot on the State Department's official list of the worst abettors of modern slavery .
When asked by The Huffington Post Thursday whether the U.S. should ink trade deals with such countries, Warren responded emphatically in the negative.
"I'll give you a really short answer on that," Warren said. "No."
"This is an opportunity for the United States to use our leverage to get countries like Malaysia to clean up their acts," she added. "We're talking about really horrible violations of human rights. And Malaysia needs to make significant changes if it wants to be part of a trade agreement with other countries."
Earning a State Department designation as a Tier 3 human trafficking violator is no easy task. Malaysia's companions on the list include Iran and North Korea. Other notorious offenders, like Qatar , where hundreds of migrant workers have been killed in recent years, are considered better at fighting human trafficking than Malaysia.
The Guardian reported this week on the discovery of mass graves for trafficking victims in Malaysia. One-third of workers in the nation's burgeoning electronics industry are victims of forced labor, according to the nonprofit group Verite , which works with the State Department on human rights issues. The government is not merely looking the other way -- the State Department has said Malaysia needs to beef up efforts to investigate and prosecute government officials who profit from such exploitation.
Although Warren has long opposed Obama's trade agenda, tensions between the two Democratic leaders erupted into a public feud last month, when Obama attacked Warren's arguments as "dishonest," "bunk" and an effort to spread "misinformation."
Warren responded by calling on Obama to release a draft of the TPP legislation, so that the public could make up its own mind about the trade pact. When Obama opted to keep the deal classified, Warren's office issued a report detailing lax enforcement of labor and human rights standards in trade deals on Obama's watch.
Most of Warren's critique has focused on regulatory issues and a host of academic experts have supported her arguments. Leaked TPP documents have revealed that the pact will include an enforcement mechanism known as Investor State Dispute Settlement, which allows corporations to challenge a country's domestic laws and regulations before an international tribunal. Adverse rulings could require governments to change their laws or pay financial penalties.
But much of the debate over TPP has shifted to human rights issues, due to the unexpected Senate survival of the Menendez ban on slavery. Warren's comments Thursday marked the first time she publicly spoke out on the Malaysian human trafficking issue. Although Obama has touted the TPP as "the most progressive trade bill in history," complete with robust labor and environmental standards, the administration now finds itself seeking to neutralize a human trafficking crackdown to maintain its trade coalition.
The Office of the U.S. Trade Representative has said that excluding Malaysia from the TPP would take away diplomacy tools that could help fight slavery in the South Pacific nation. But substitute legislation sought by the Obama administration would not actually require the Malaysian government to improve its human trafficking record in order to enjoy trade benefits from the TPP.
Malaysia occupies a strategically important position in the Strait of Malacca, through which a tremendous amount of global commerce currently passes. China, in particular, relies heavily on the oil shipments that pass through the strait. Malaysia has been eager in recent years to contain China's influence in the strait and the neighboring South China Sea.
Zach Carter reported from Washington and Shahien Nasiripour reported from Boston.
Also on HuffPost:


Elizabeth Warren announced a bill creating a Financial Product Safety Commission with House and Senate Democrats in March 2009. The body was designed to have oversight over mortgages and other financial instruments to protect consumers against predatory practices. She said if the agency had existed before the subprime collapse then "there would have been millions of families who got tangled in predatory mortgages who never would have gotten them." HuffPost's Ryan Grim reported:  Without all these toxic assets on banks' balance sheets, the institutions wouldn't be on the brink of collapse and the recession would be more manageable. "Consumer financial products were the front end of the destabilization of the American economic system."  Sen. Charles Schumer's cosponsorship of the bill is notable because of his proximity to Wall Street. The bill's merit, the New York Democrat said, is that it regulates the actual financial product rather than the company producing it.
Tim Geithner expressed opposition to her nomination for the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, reported HuffPost's Shahien Nasiripour. Geithner thought Warren's views on the big banks and Wall St. were too tough. Warren's oversight of the Treasury department as a watchdog for TARP apparently irked Geithner, agressively questioning him during Congressional hearings:  While her grilling of Geithner in September, over what members of Congress have called the "backdoor bailout" of Wall Street through AIG, inspired the "squirm" video, just last month Warren pressed Geithner on the administration's lackluster foreclosure-prevention plan, Making Home Affordable. Criticizing him for Treasury's failure to keep families in their homes, she questioned Treasury's commitment to homeowners.
Elizabeth Warren reiterated her desire for a strong Consumer Financial Protection Agency to HuffPost's Shahien Nasiripour:  "My first choice is a strong consumer agency," the Harvard Law professor and federal bailout watchdog said in an interview with the Huffington Post. "My second choice is no agency at all and plenty of blood and teeth left on the floor."
In September of 2010, HuffPost's Ryan Grim reported that Elizabeth Warren was being considered as a candidate for interim director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. Days later the announcement was official.  The move allowed Warren to set up the groundwork for the agency immediately without risking a GOP filibuster of her nomination, a response that seemed certain giving the public opposition expressed by some Republican senators.  When it came time to put forth an appointment for a longterm CFPB chief, Warren was overlooked, partially because she was seen as unfeasible, but also, HuffPost's Shahien Nasiripour reported, because she was a divisive figure within the Obama administration:  Ultimately, Warren wanted the job, allies said. And near-united opposition from Senate Republicans -- 44 of them signed a letter saying they'd oppose any nominee -- should have made it easier for Obama to nominate her, since the Republicans publicly said they wouldn't support anyone for the role.  Instead, the Republicans made it easy for the White House to deflect questions about the administration's lack of support for Warren.  Asked how she squared the administration's public statements with its private ones, Warren declined.  "I really have to say, I'm just not there. I'm not in the intricacies of the political part of this, and I can't comment," Warren said Monday. "The truth is I don't know anything about it."
In October 2010, shortly after being tasked with building the groundwork for the CFPB, Warren stopped by HuffPost to chat with Ryan Grim and Shahien Nasiripour  "This is the first real agency we've built in the 21st century -- well, there's Homeland Security, but one for the people. And it means we ought to think differently," said Warren. "The government can talk to people and people can talk to the government differently than when the Consumer Product Safety Commission was built, or when the FDA was built. And if we do this right, that should change the whole dynamic of who this agency really is."  HuffPost's Ryan Grim reported:  By gathering information, contracts and documents from homeowners and consumers, and allowing watchdog groups and individual concerned citizens access to those documents, the agency can exponentially expand the manpower it has to review the operations of banks and lenders. The goal would be to become aware of a particularly fraudulent practice before it is rampant and insulates itself in the financial services industry.  For full video of the interview, click here.
In May, Warren was called to testify before a House subcommittee and defend the merits of the CFPB. Some of the questions submitted by Republican representatives appeared confused and at times aggressive, leaving Warren to correct them on some basic facts about the actual purpose of the bureau.  HuffPost's Mike McCauliff relays one particularly contentious moment:  The subcommittee chairman, Rep. Patrick McHenry (R-N.C.), began the proceedings by suggesting Warren had lied to the committee in a previous hearing that had questioned the CFPB's role in offering advice to state attorneys general negotiating a settlement with abusive mortgage servicers.  At the time, Warren said she was proud her agency had been able to help, at the request of the treasury secretary. But McHenry brought up the memo again, suggesting it showed that she hid a larger role in the negotiations from Congress.  "This is our job, and we're trying to do our job, to be helpful to other agencies, and to help those agencies to hold those who break the law accountable," Warren said, repeating that she was proud of the work.
Elizabeth Warren announced on September 14, 2011 that she was running for the United States Senate seat currently held by Scott Brown (R-Mass.)  "After listening to people all across our state who know that we can do better, folks who are frustrated like I am that Washington just doesn't get it, I'm running for the Senate so I can fight every day for Massachusetts families," Warren wrote on The Huffington Post.
One month into her campaign to secure the U.S. Senate seat currently held by Scott Brown in Massachusetts, Elizabeth Warren raised $3.15 million, largely from small donations. According to a campaign email, 96 percent of donations were under $100.   "These are pretty amazing numbers for our first official finance report, raised in a very short period of time," she said in an email to supporters.  Warren's campaign has also attracted large liberal donors, including colleagues from Harvard and well-known liberal donors like George Soros, Barbra Streisand, and DreamWorks CEO Jeffrey Katzenberg.  Warren raised an impressive $5.7 million in the fourth quarter of 2011. In early January, the candidate's money bomb pulled in more than $100,000 in just one weekend.
Elizabeth Warren and Sen. Scott Brown (R-Mass.) signed a pledge to curb third-party attack ads. If either campaign breaks the agreement, they would donate half the cost of the outside ad to a charity of their opponent's choice.   "This may not work," Warren said in an email to supporters. "But there's enough at stake to make it worthwhile to try to take back this election."
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:51:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Asian Refugee Crisis: Trafficked Migrants Held Off Thailand In Vast 'Camp Boats'</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/asian-refugee-crisis-traf_n_7463976.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of Bangladeshi and ethnic Rohingya migrants are being held in huge cargo ships by human traffickers in the Andaman Sea, according to testimony collected from survivors. </Description>
        <MainBody>Asian Refugee Crisis: Trafficked Migrants Held Off Thailand In Vast 'Camp Boats'
The Guardian
Click here to view Conversations
Conversations
Please check the checkbox to indicate your consent
Options
Get top stories and blog posts emailed to me each day..
Facebook
Copyright 2015 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. "The Huffington Post" is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved.
Part of HPMG News
Use this form to alert a HuffPost editor about a factual or typographical error in this story.
Notify message
* What kind of error is this?
* What is the correction? 0 count
Describe the error here (1,000 character limit)
* Type the words below so we know you are not a cyborg
Sign me up for The Morning Email
Thanks for your report!
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:47:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. To 'Fine Tune' Iraq Strategy In Light Of Ramadi Debacle</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/us-iraq-strategy_n_7463934.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (AP) — Pentagon leaders are trying to "fine tune" U.S. strategy for ousting the Islamic State group from Iraq, focusing on faster and better training and arming of Sunni tribes whose combat role is central to reversing the extremists' advances, senior U.S. officials said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. To 'Fine Tune' Iraq Strategy In Light Of Ramadi Debacle
| By                                                                      ROBERT BURNS and LOLITA C. BALDOR
Posted:
Updated:
5 hours ago
ARLINGTON, VA - MAY 07:  Secretary of Defense Ash Carter speaks to the media during a briefing at the Pentagon May 7, 2015 in Arlington, Virginia. Secretary Carter talked about various issues including the situation in the Middle East and the Department of Defense budget request.  (Photo by Mark Wilson/Getty Images) | Mark Wilson via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON (AP)  Pentagon leaders are trying to "fine tune" U.S. strategy for ousting the Islamic State group from Iraq, focusing on faster and better training and arming of Sunni tribes whose combat role is central to reversing the extremists' advances, senior U.S. officials said Thursday.
Defense Secretary Ash Carter, speaking to reporters while traveling to Asia, said he told senior military officers at the Pentagon this week to come up with ideas to improve training and equipping, particularly of the Sunni tribes who complain that the Shiite-dominated government in Baghdad is dragging its heels on helping them.
"I can't describe to you what the possibilities are because folks are looking at them right now," Carter said.
The scramble for answers comes after Islamic State forces, though outnumbered, captured the Anbar province capital of Ramadi as Iraqi forces fled on May 16. Although the White House says those Iraqi forces were not U.S.-trained, the defeat prompted Carter to make the startlingly frank public assessment last weekend that the Iraqis lacked "the will to fight."
President Barack Obama on Tuesday said it was time for the U.S. to consider whether it was delivering military aid to Iraq efficiently.
A Pentagon spokesman, Col. Steve Warren, said later that the focus is on fine-tuning the strategy, not rewriting it.
The U.S. military strategy in Iraq is built on airstrikes to degrade the Islamic State forces while rebuilding Iraqi security forces to eventually regain the vast swaths of territory in the north and west that were lost over the past 18 months. The current focus is on retaking Ramadi and other parts of predominantly Sunni Anbar province.
The Obama administration insists it will assist the Sunnis only through the Shiite-dominated central government in Baghdad because it wants to foster a multi-sectarian government, rather than directly arm and organize the ethnic tribes for combat. It was unclear whether Carter might recommend scrapping the indirect approach or adjust it in some way in the days ahead, but the tenor of his remarks and comments by other officials suggested that dramatic changes were unlikely.
Gen. Ray Odierno, the Army chief of staff who was a top commander in Iraq during the 2003-11 war, said there may be merit in enlarging the U.S. military role by embedding U.S. advisers with Iraqi forces in the field. But he made clear that this also has drawbacks, and that it would be a judgment call if recommended by the Pentagon.
Odierno, who served in command three times in Iraq, said the failure of Iraqi security forces to hold their ground was "incredibly disappointing to me personally." But he also said he sees no wisdom in sending substantial U.S. ground combat forces to do the fighting.
"I'm adamant about that," he said. Expending American lives to defeat the extremists without fixing Iraq's internal political divisions would be a waste and an unsustainable solution.
"It always comes back to the government of Iraq," Odierno said, referring to its inability to unify its Sunni, Shiite and Kurdish populations in a way that would give the country's security forces confidence and motivation to fight.
Washington already has pledged to accelerate the shipment of certain weapons to Baghdad, including AT-4 weapons that could be used to stop armored vehicles that Islamic State fighters have used effectively as suicide bombs. The U.S. also has said it will try to speed up the delivery of airstrikes requested by the Iraqi government.
Speaking to reporters on Thursday, Carter focused on arming and equipping Sunni tribes.
"One particular way that's extremely important is to involve the Sunni tribes in the fight  that means training and equipping them," Carter said. "Those are the kinds of things the team back home is looking at."
But a senior defense official said Carter still wants to work through the Iraqi government, an approach that has been ineffective so far. The official was not authorized to describe the defense secretary's thinking publicly and spoke on condition of anonymity.
Carter said the events in Ramadi "highlighted the central importance of having a capable ground partner" in Iraq.
Part of Iraq's plan to bolster its effectiveness against IS fighters includes training, equipping and paying Sunni tribesmen to join in the fight. It is reminiscent of the Sunni Sahwa, or Awakening movement, which confronted al-Qaida in Iraq starting in 2006, although that program was begun by U.S. forces working directly with the tribes. Al-Qaida in Iraq is the Islamic State's predecessor.
In January, the Iraqi government held an inauguration ceremony for a few hundred Sunni fighters in Anbar province with the hope that it would plant the seed for an expanded national guard in which Sunnis would take on responsibility for security in Iraq's Sunni areas. Those are predominantly under Islamic State control today.
But the force has failed to progress at the rate the Iraqi government had hoped.
___
Baldor reported from Singapore. Associated Press writer Vivian Salama in Baghdad contributed to this report.
Also on HuffPost:
Most Iconic Photos Of Obama's First Term
of


May 1, 2011:  President Barack Obama and Vice President Joe Biden, along with members of the national security team, receive an update on the mission against Osama bin Laden in the Situation Room of the White House, May 1, 2011. Seated, from left, are: Brigadier General Marshall B. "Brad" Webb, Assistant Commanding General, Joint Special Operations Command; Deputy National Security Advisor Denis McDonough; Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton; and Secretary of Defense Robert Gates. Standing, from left, are: Admiral Mike Mullen, Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff; National Security Advisor Tom Donilon; Chief of Staff Bill Daley; Tony Blinken, National Security Advisor to the Vice President; Audrey Tomason Director for Counterterrorism; John Brennan, Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism; and Director of National Intelligence James Clapper. Please note: a classified document seen in this photograph has been obscured. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
May 8, 2009:  President Barack Obama bends over so the son of a White House staff member can pat his head during a family visit to the Oval Office May 8, 2009. The youngster wanted to see if the President's haircut felt like his own. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Dec. 3, 2009:  President Barack Obama fist-bumps custodian Lawrence Lipscomb in the Eisenhower Executive Office Building following the opening session of the White House Forum on Jobs and Economic Growth, Dec. 3, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
July 4, 2012:  President Barack Obama holds a baby while greeting guests during an Independence Day celebration on the South Lawn of the White House, July 4, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
July 26, 2012:  President Barack Obama holds a Cabinet meeting in the Cabinet Room of the White House, July 26, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
July 9, 2012:  President Barack Obama runs around his desk in the Oval Office with Sarah Froman, daughter of Nancy Goodman and Mike Froman, Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics, July 9, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 13, 2012:  President Barack Obama and First Lady Michelle Obama wave goodbye to President Shimon Peres of Israel on the North Portico of the White House following the Presidential Medal of Freedom ceremony and dinner in his honor, June 13, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
April 23, 2012:  President Barack Obama tours the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum in Washington, D.C., with Elie Wiesel, Nobel Peace Prize laureate and Holocaust survivor, and Sara Bloomfield, museum director, April 23, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 11, 2012:  President Barack Obama talks with Betty White in the Oval Office, June 11, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
April 24, 2012:  President Barack Obama stops to view the moon and Venus before boarding Marine One in Boulder, Colo., April 24, 2012. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Feb. 21, 2012:  President Obama joins in singing "Sweet Home Chicago" during the "In Performance at the White House: Red, White and Blues" concert in the East Room of the White House, Feb. 21, 2012. Participants include, from left: Troy "Trombone Shorty" Andrews, Jeff Beck, Derek Trucks, B.B. King, and Gary Clark, Jr. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
March 20, 2011:  "The Obama family was scheduled to tour the Christ the Redeemer statue in Rio before dinner one night. But when heavy fog rolled in, they canceled the visit. After dinner, the fog had dissipated somewhat so they decided to make the drive up the mountain. It was quite clear when they arrived and then the fog started to roll back in. I managed to capture this silhouette as they viewed the statute one last time just before departure."  (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 11, 2011:  "The top photograph shows the President having a water gun fight with his daughter Sasha on her birthday weekend at Camp David. Unbeknownst to me, David Lienemann captured a similar photo of the Vice President on the very same day." (Official White House Photos by Pete Souza and David Lienemann)
Dec. 11, 2011:  President Barack Obama, First Lady Michelle Obama, and their daughters, Malia, left, and Sasha, right, sit for a family portrait in the Oval Office, Dec. 11, 2011. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Oct. 14, 2011:  President Barack Obama tours the Martin Luther King, Jr. National Memorial in Washington, D.C., Oct. 14, 2011. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Oct. 11, 2011:  "This photograph by Chuck Kennedy has to catch your eye. It shows Guinness Book of World Records holder John Cassidy performing a balloon act for First Lady Michelle Obama in the Diplomatic Reception Room following a Let's Move event."  (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)
June 21, 2011:  First Lady Michelle Obama meets with former President Nelson Mandela of South Africa at Mandela's home in Houghton, South Africa, June 21, 2011. (Official White House Photo by Samantha Appleton)
May 29, 2011:  President Barack Obama greets Hugh Hills, 85, in front of his home in Joplin, Mo., May 29, 2011. Hills hid in a closet during the tornado, which destroyed the second floor and half the first floor of his house. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 9, 2011:  President Barack Obama greets children at a day care facility adjacent to daughter Sasha's school in Bethesda, Md., following her 4th grade closing ceremony, June 9, 2011. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Jan. 10, 2011:  President Barack Obama and First Lady Michelle Obama walk towards the White House after observing a moment of silence for the victims of the Arizona shooting, on the South Lawn, Jan. 10, 2011. White House staff joined the President and First Lady for the moment of silence.(Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)
March 7, 2011:  President Barack Obama, Prime Minister Julia Gillard of Australia, and members of the Australian and American delegations look up at the presidential seal in the Oval Office ceiling following their bilateral meeting, March 7, 2011. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
May 31, 2010:  "The skies opened up on Memorial Day outside of Chicago. When the lightning began, the Secret Service told the President that it was too dangerous to proceed. He took the stage by himself and informed the audience that his speech was canceled and that for everyone's safety, they should return to their busses. Later, he boarded a few of the busses to thank them for attending and apologized for not being able to speak." (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
July 20, 2010:  President Barack Obama and British Prime Minister David Cameron walk across the South Lawn of the White House, July 20, 2010. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
May 28, 2010:  President Barack Obama and Lafourche Parish President Charlotte Randolf, left, inspect a tar ball as they look at the effect the BP oil spill is having on Fourchon Beach in Port Fourchon, La., May 28, 2010. (Official White House Photo by Chuck Kennedy)
March 21, 2010:  President Barack Obama, Vice President Joe Biden, and senior staff, react in the Roosevelt Room of the White House, as the House passes the health care reform bill, March 21, 2010. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
March 31, 2010:  President Barack Obama practices his pitching form with personal aide Reggie Love and Jake Levine in the Rose Garden of the White House, March 31, 2010. The President threw out the ceremonial first pitch on opening day of the baseball season prior to the game between the Washington Nationals and the Philadelphia Phillies.
Feb. 1, 2009:   "During a Super Bowl watching party in the White House theatre, the President and First Lady join their guests in watching one of the TV commercials in 3D." (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
March 15, 2009:  "The Obama family was introduced to a prospective family dog at a secret greet on a Sunday. After spending about an hour with him, the family decided he was the one. Here, the dog ran alongside the President in an East Wing hallway. The dog returned to his trainer while the Obama's embarked on their first international trip. I had to keep these photos secret until a few weeks later, when the dog was brought 'home' to the White House and introduced to the world as Bo." (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
Jan. 20, 2009:  "President-elect Barack Obama was about to walk out to take the oath of office. Backstage at the U.S. Capitol, he took one last look at his appearance in the mirror." (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
Dec. 19, 2009:  "Snowball in hand, the President chases Chief of Staff Rahm Emanuel on the White House colonnade. To escape, Rahm ran through the Rose Garden, which unfortunately for him, was knee-deep in snow." (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
Dec. 10, 2009:  President Barack Obama looks at the Nobel Peace Prize medal for the first time at the Norwegian Nobel Institute in Oslo, Norway, Dec. 10, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Jan. 16, 2010:  "President Obama had called on the two former Presidents to help with the situation in Haiti. During their public remarks in the Rose Garden, President Clinton had said about President Bush, 'I've already figured out how I can get him to do some things that he didn't sign on for.' Later, back in the Oval, President Bush is jokingly asking President Clinton what were those things he had in mind." (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
Oct. 8, 2009:  President Barack Obama watches as members of the National Naval Medical Center's Marine Wounded Warrior basketball team play on the White House basketball court, Oct. 8, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Oct. 8, 2009:  President Barack Obama takes a shot during a game with Cabinet secretaries and members of Congress on the White House basketball court, Oct. 8, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Aug. 16, 2009:  President Barack Obama looks at the Grand Canyon in Arizona on Aug. 16, 2009. (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
April 21, 2009:  President Barack Obama and Sen. Ted Kennedy walk down the South Lawn sidewalk at the White House April 21, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
July 10, 2009:  President Barack Obama and First Lady Michelle Obama meet with Pope Benedict XVI at the Vatican on July 10, 2009. (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
July 13, 2009:   President Barack Obama feigns a punch while talking about health care reform with Nancy-Ann DeParle, Peter Orszag, Phil Schiliro and Larry Summers in the Outer Oval Office, July 13, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 26, 2009:  President Barack Obama jokingly reacts to news that staffer Nora Becker will be leaving to pursue a joint MD and PhD in healthcare economics, during the White House staff picnic on the South Lawn, June 26, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 2, 2009:  President Barack Obama and former First Lady Nancy Reagan walk side-by-side through Center Hall in the White House, June 2, 2009. To the left of Mrs. Reagan hangs her official White House portrait as First Lady. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 4, 2009:  Secretary of State Hillary Clinton recounts a story to President Barack Obama, Senior Advisors David Axelrod and Valerie Jarrett, outside the Sultan Hassan Mosque in Cairo, Egypt, June 4, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
June 4, 2009:  President Barack Obama tours the Egypt's Great Sphinx of Giza (left) and the Pyramid of Khafre, June 4, 2009. (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
Feb. 18, 2009:  President Barack Obama takes aim with a photographer's camera backstage prior to remarks about providing mortgage payment relief for responsible homeowners at Dobson High School, Mesa, Ariz., Feb. 18, 2009. (Official White House Photo by Pete Souza)
Jan. 21, 2009:  President Barack Obama walks into the Oval Office for his first full day in office, Jan. 21, 2009. His Personal Aide Reggie Love stands nearby. (Official White House photo by Pete Souza)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:38:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS Settles Into Ramadi, But Quiet Is Unlikely To Last</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/28/isis-ramaid_n_7463826.html?utm_hp_ref=world&amp;ir=WorldPost</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD, May 28 (Reuters) - The blind man with just one hand arrived at the main mosque in the center of the Iraqi city of Ramadi at dusk on Wednesday, flanked by Islamic State fighters.</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS Settles Into Ramadi, But Quiet Is Unlikely To Last
Reuters
Updated:
5 hours ago
Carcass of vehicles are seen in Amriyat al-Fallujah, in Iraq's Anbar province, where Iraqi Sunni men presented as former jihadists fighting alongside the Islamic State (IS) group who defected to join Iraq government forces, are deployed, on May 26, 2015. Iraqi forces took up positions on the southern outskirts of Ramadi, officials said, taking two neighbourhoods and moving into Anbar university. Army and police forces as well as allied paramilitaries clashed with IS fighters to take full control | HAIDAR HAMDANI via Getty Images
reddit
BAGHDAD, May 28 (Reuters) - The blind man with just one hand arrived at the main mosque in the center of the Iraqi city of Ramadi at dusk on Wednesday, flanked by Islamic State fighters.
When the evening prayer was over, the man, whose head was shrouded in black, delivered a speech to the faithful, hailing the Islamic State's capture of the capital of Anbar Province -- its greatest victory over Iraqi forces in almost a year.
Ali Attiya al-Jubouri, widely known as "the blind judge," is one of Islamic State's most senior figures and his presence in the mosque signaled the group's dominance over the city, which it seized on May 17 from hapless government forces.
"By the blessing of God, we now have an open road between Ramadi and Raqqa," he said, referring to the ultra hardline group's de-facto capital in neighboring Syria.
"You are free to travel there and work in trade, and we will help you by all means," he said, according to a resident of the city who was in the audience.
The Sunni Muslim group has declared a caliphate, or Islamic state, across wide areas of Syria and Iraq, defying hostile government forces and U.S.-led airstrikes in both countries.
Despite a fearsome reputation for inflicting savage violence on foes, Islamic State militants have gone out of their way to try to win over residents of Ramadi, providing basic services and governance, said locals speaking to Reuters by telephone.
Most residents have fled, but those who stayed are savoring what they describe as a semblance of order and tranquility in a city that had been a warzone for more than a year.
"We are having a pleasant dream now of living in peace without hearing gunfire or bombs and walking freely through open streets," said teacher Abdul Wahab Ahmed, 45, who compared the new order to "passing a glass of chilled water to the thirsty."
However, the lull is unlikely to last, with government security forces and Shi'ite paramilitaries already preparing to launch a counter-offensive to retake the city.
"The dream won't last long, and soon we'll wake up to the bitter reality of being stuck in the crossfire between government forces and (IS) fighters," he said.
Iraqi fighters from the Shiite Muslim Al-Abbas popular mobilisation unit battle Islamic State jihadists in an area surrounding the village of Dujail in the Salaheddin province, north of Baghdad, on May 26, 2015. (MOHAMMED SAWAF/AFP/Getty Images)
MASS GRAVES
Residents said no sooner had the militants claimed victory earlier this month than they set about removing blast walls and barricades from the streets with cranes, just as they did in Mosul, the northern Iraqi city they captured last June.
"It's good to see some normality restored to life in Ramadi," said Abu Abdul Rahman. "We were living in a military barracks when government forces were in control. Now we can taste a minimum level of freedom."
Islamic State reopened the municipality, and militants accompanied employees from the department of health to collect the bodies of unknown number of policemen and soldiers lying in the streets where they had died.
They were buried in mass graves on the city's outskirts, while burned-out vehicles were towed away to a scrap yard in a rural area north of Ramadi.
Under the militants' supervision, teams of plumbers repaired broken drinking water pipes, and free food and vegetables were handed out from refrigerated trucks.
Two tankers escorted by Islamic State fighters dispensed fuel to the owners of electricity generators in each neighborhood and instructed them to keep their prices in check.
The unemployed were urged to take work at the municipality for a monthly wage of 350,000 Iraqi dinars ($270), and repeated calls were made for female doctors to treat women patients at Ramadi hospital.
Following the surprise visit by the blind judge, fighters withdrew from the city streets, handing control to the Islamic morality police, or Hisba, multiple sources inside Ramadi said.
"Some of the fighters said goodbye and apologized if they had done anything wrong, it was not purpose," said one resident.
"They told us they will go to bolster defenses on Ramadi's outskirts."
As elsewhere under their sway, Islamic State has wasted no time in imposing their unyielding interpretation of Islamic Sharia law. They also appointed their own preachers to run the city's mosques, empowering them to resolve civilian disputes.
Male shopowners who stock womenswear were ordered to bring a wife, sister or mother to attend to female customers, limiting contact between the sexes. Orders were given for shop windows displaying women's clothing to be covered and manikins removed.
One cigarette seller recalled how he was approached by a militant who said: "Brother, we don't like you to sell something harmful to the health of Muslims: stop selling cigarettes and we are prepared to help you find another, decent occupation."
The cigarette seller, who refused to be identified, was skeptical: "I know this trick very well: to begin with Daesh ask you very politely, but when they grow stronger they won't even talk to you, they will just wave a knife at your neck."
Daesh is the unflattering Arabic acronym for Islamic State.
Video posted online earlier this year appeared to show militants elsewhere whipping men who had been found smoking.
Iraqi Sunni men presented as former jihadists fighting alongside the Islamic State (IS) group who defected to join Iraq government forces take position in Amriyat al-Fallujah, in Iraq's Anbar province, on May 26, 2015. (HAIDAR HAMDANI/AFP/Getty Images)
PLANTING BOMBS
Islamic State fighters have warned residents not to venture outside the city because they say they have laid a web of bombs to hinder any incursion by government forces.
Residents who went to find relatives displaced by fighting east of the city saw men embedding dozens of explosive devices in the road, using small mobile generators to power electrical cutters to slice open the asphalt.
Asked why they were also planting mines on either side of the road, a local militant leader said: "We learned a lesson from Tikrit, where our brothers only planted bombs on key roads. Government forces and rejectionist militia.... used dirt tracks to enter the city."
In a setback to the militants, Iraqi troops and Shi'ite paramilitaries drove Islamic State out of Tikrit -- the hometown of former dictator Saddam Hussein -- in late March.
"We will not allow the same scenario to be repeated in Ramadi," the militant leader was quoted as saying.
However, Iraqi security expert Hisham al-Hashimi, who tracks the radical insurgents, said he did not expect Islamic State to keep Ramadi for long as well-armed, opposing forces muster for an assault on the city.
Despite the impending attack, residents said they had chosen to stay because they did not want to leave their homes or be treated in the way that others fleeing Ramadi had complained of.
Most of those displaced from the region had sought refuge in Baghdad, but they were not allowed into the city without a sponsor. Those who managed to get through said they were harassed by security forces and Shi'ite militias who suspected them of being infiltrators.
"We are sure that the control of the (IS) fighters is temporary, and sooner or later the government will be back," said Ramadi resident Abu Omar al-Obeidi.
"Our main concern is that the security forces will accuse us of supporting Daesh because we stayed in the city."
Retired civil servant Said Kamil, 68, who owns a food shop in central Ramadi said he had resigned himself to his fate: "For me, dying in dignity is better than living in humiliation."
Iraqis fleeing violence drive on May 26, 2015 in al-Nibaie area, north-west of Baghdad. (AHMAD AL-RUBAYE/AFP/Getty Images)
(Reporting by Baghdad Bureau; Writing by Isabel Coles; Editing by Crispian Balmer)
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
