<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:18:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'I Got A Divorce For My 30th Birthday'</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/what-its-like-to-divorce-at-30-_n_7446678.html</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
"This Is Divorce At..." is a HuffPost Divorce series delving into divorce at every stage of life. Want to share your experience of divorcing at a certain age? Email us at divorce@huffingtonpost.com or tweet @HuffPost Divorce .
At 27, Rebecca Neville agreed to marry her boyfriend after eight years of dating. Just a few short years later, she was 30 -- and divorced.
Splitting up at 30 was devastating, but today, Neville says she's stronger than ever.
"I put up with the heartache and eventually, the pain got smaller each day," she told The Huffington Post. "I learned to trust myself and take advantage of this second chance."
Below, Neville tells us more about her life after divorce.
I didnt think Id be divorced at any age. It certainly wasnt the way I wanted to celebrate the big 3-0. But thats what I got for my birthday: a divorce.
I was in between youth and middle age: settling into life with another person and settling into my job. I was just beginning to feel like an adult but could still justify late nights out and the occasional Pop-Tart for dinner. Sure, marriage was challenging but I felt we had just hit our stride, comfortably falling into our roles. And then, everything changed. Overnight, my ex wanted a divorce.
At the time, it was painful. Sundays were the worst. During the week, I could distract myself at work. My friends were there to offer support and whisk me out of the house. But Sundays were family days. Those were the days wed go to breakfast or run errands to the hardware or grocery store or do absolutely nothing but be together. Overnight, Sundays were lonely and boring.
Sure, I expected the loneliness, but boredom? How could I be bored? I had so many new responsibilities at home now that I was separated: I had to cut the lawn, do all the cleaning myself and pay all the bills on my measly salary. The worry alone should have occupied me. But somehow, it didnt. Life after divorce was downright boring.
I came to realize my boredom was the result of no longer thinking and feeling for two. I had spent so many years aiding my husband: helping him write college papers, dealing with his family drama, making his life comfortable. Free of those responsibilities, I had leisurely time to think about me. I had been helping to fulfill my husbands dreams for so long I had forgotten that I had dreams, too.
(Photo courtesy of Rebecca Neville)
It had been years since I had asked myself, "What do I want to do today?" So I began asking myself this question and doors opened where I had previously seen only walls. The boredom I felt was a catalyst for new adventures. I began traveling, enrolled in a masters program and met new friends through activities I enjoyed. I became myself again. Or, more precisely, I became the person I hid to sustain a relationship destined to fail the minute we stopped pretending to be what the other wanted.
Becoming suddenly single at 30 couldnt have happened at a better time. My thirties ushered in a freedom of expression and a confidence I hadnt expected. Paired with the freedom in my personal life, I felt invincible. Of course there were the occasional setbacks -- the surprise moments when youre reminded of the sad times and you mourn just a little more. You can't escape those moments but you have to remind yourself: No matter how much it hurts, it gets better; being in a relationship that isn't healthy never feels better. The death of my relationship brought about my rebirth. I can truly say divorce at 30 was both awful and fantastic.
Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on Facebook and Twitter . Sign up for our newsletter here .
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:15:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Floodwaters Deepen After Storms Dump Another Foot Of Rain In Houston Area</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/texas-floods-houston-flooding_n_7447078.html</Link>
        <Description>HOUSTON (AP) -- Floodwaters deepened across much of Texas on Tuesday as storms dumped almost another foot of rain on the Houston area, stranding hundreds of motorists and inundating the famously congested highways that serve the nation's fourth-largest city.</Description>
        <MainBody>Floodwaters Deepen After Storms Dump Another Foot Of Rain In Houston Area
Posted:
reddit
AARON M. SPRECHER via Getty Images
HOUSTON (AP) -- Floodwaters deepened across much of Texas on Tuesday as storms dumped almost another foot of rain on the Houston area, stranding hundreds of motorists and inundating the famously congested highways that serve the nation's fourth-largest city.
Meanwhile, the search went on for at least 13 people who were still missing, including a group that disappeared after a vacation home was swept down the river and slammed into a bridge.
Several more fatalities were reported - four in Houston and one more in Central Texas. That brought to 14 the number of people killed by the holiday weekend storms in Texas and Oklahoma.
The water rose sharply overnight as about 11 more inches of rain fell, much of it in a six-hour period. By Tuesday evening, most rivers had receded back within their banks.
The floodwaters affected virtually every part of the city and paralyzed some areas. Firefighters carried out more than 500 water rescues, most involving stranded motorists. At least 2,500 vehicles were abandoned by drivers seeking higher ground, officials said.
"Given the magnitude and how quickly it happened, in such a short period of time, I've never seen this before," said Rick Flanagan, Houston's emergency management coordinator.
The drenching weather threatened to linger. National Weather Service forecasts called for a 20 to 40 percent chance of thunderstorms through the rest of the week in Houston.
The flooding closed several highways, and the ones that stayed open became a gridlocked mess.
Interstate 45 near downtown was backed up for miles on Tuesday morning, and a handful of motorists traveled the wrong way on the highway to retreat from high water.
The small cars weaved between massive 18-wheelers as other drivers stared at them in disbelief. With no end to the backup in sight, some drivers got off the freeway, only to be held up again by water covering nearby access roads.
In the Heights neighborhood about 5 miles from downtown, groups of people roamed the streets after escaping their stalled cars, and police cruisers blocked some dangerous roads.
Some motorists were stuck on I-45 all night, sleeping in their cars until the backup was cleared about 8 a.m.
NBA fans at the Toyota Center, where the Rockets hosted a Western Conference finals game against Golden State on Monday, were asked with about two minutes left in the game not to leave the arena because of the severe weather.
The game ended before 11 p.m., but about 400 people remained in their seats at 1:30 a.m., choosing to stay in the building rather than brave the flooded roads that awaited them outside.
A spokeswoman for the flood district of Harris County, which includes Houston, said up to 700 homes sustained some level of damage.
Officials in Hays County, about 180 miles west of Houston, said 30 people who had been reported as missing were accounted for by mid-afternoon Tuesday.
Crews were also searching for victims and assessing damage just across the Texas-Mexico border in Ciudad Acuna, where a tornado killed 13 people Monday.
Some of the worst flooding in Texas was in Wimberley, a popular tourist town along the Blanco in the corridor between Austin and San Antonio. That's where the vacation home was swept away.
The "search component" of the mission ended Monday night, meaning no more survivors were expected to be found, said Trey Hatt, a spokesman for the Hays County Emergency Operations Center.
Eight of those missing from the destroyed house were friends and family who had gathered for the holiday, said Kristi Wyatt, a spokeswoman for the City of San Marcos. She said three more were members of another family in a separate situation. An unrelated person was also missing, Wyatt said.
Young children were believed to be among the missing.
The Blanco crested above 40 feet - more than triple its flood stage of 13 feet. The river swamped Interstate 35 and closed parts of the busy north-south highway. Rescuers used pontoon boats and a helicopter to pull people out.
Hundreds of trees along the Blanco were uprooted or snapped, and they collected in piles of debris up to 20 feet high.
The deaths in Texas included a man whose body was pulled from the Blanco; a 14-year-old who was found with his dog in a storm drain; a high school senior who died Saturday after her car was caught in high water; and a man whose mobile home was destroyed by a reported tornado.
The Oklahoma Department of Emergency Management also reported four fatalities between Saturday and Monday after severe flooding and reports of tornadoes.
In Ciudad Acuna, Mayor Evaristo Perez Rivera said 300 people were treated at local hospitals after the twister, and up to 200 homes had been completely destroyed in the city of 125,000 across from Del Rio, Texas.
Thirteen people were confirmed dead - 10 adults and three infants, including one that was ripped from its mother's arms by the storm.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:10:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Skyping With The Enemy: I Went Undercover As A Jihadi Girlfriend</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/skyping-with-enemy_n_7447056.html</Link>
        <Description>When a French journalist posed online as a young woman interested in Isis, she was soon contacted by a fighter in Syria. He proposed marriage – but could she maintain a double life? </Description>
        <MainBody>Skyping With The Enemy: I Went Undercover As A Jihadi Girlfriend
The Guardian
reddit
ASSOCIATED PRESS
When a French journalist posed online as a young woman interested in Isis, she was soon contacted by a fighter in Syria. He proposed marriage  but could she maintain a double life?
Click here to view Conversations
Conversations
Please check the checkbox to indicate your consent
Options
Get top stories and blog posts emailed to me each day..
Facebook
Copyright 2015 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. "The Huffington Post" is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved.
Part of HPMG News
Use this form to alert a HuffPost editor about a factual or typographical error in this story.
Notify message
* What kind of error is this?
* What is the correction? 0 count
Describe the error here (1,000 character limit)
* Type the words below so we know you are not a cyborg
Sign me up for The Morning Email
Thanks for your report!
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:09:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Galapagos' Highest Volcano Erupts For First Time In More Than 30 Years</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/galapagos-volcano-eruption_n_7446882.html</Link>
        <Description>The highest volcano in the Galapagos Islands erupted early Monday for the first time in nearly 33 years, the archipelago's national park service reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
The highest volcano in the Galapagos Islands erupted early Monday for the first time in nearly 33 years, the archipelago's national park service reported.
Isabela Island's Wolf Volcano sent smoke more than six miles high and glowed orange with lava as it overflowed at 1:30 a.m., CNN reported.
The 5,800-foot volcano poses no threat to people, as it is 70 miles from the nearest human population in Puerto Villamil, the Galapagos National Park Service said in a press release translated by the Galapagos Conservancy.
The park service said there is no threat to the many unique species on the islands, where naturalist Charles Darwin first conceived of evolution in the 19th century.
"The worlds only population of pink land iguanas lives on the northwestern side of the volcano, sharing the habitat with yellow land iguanas and giant tortoises," the park service said. "This population is not expected to be affected at this time . The situation will be monitored in the area once the eruptive activity has subsided and is safe for Park rangers."
The most pressing threats to the Galapagos Islands' ecosystem are not natural phenomena like volcanoes, experts say.
"There are far more human-induced threats to the species of the Galapagos ," Hugo Arnal, the World Wildlife Fund's director for Ecuador, told ABC News. Those concerns, the network reported, include "invasive species, overfishing, pollution, overpopulation and unsustainable tourism."
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:09:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Georgia Lawmakers And Corporate Lobbyists Mingle In Secret Meetings Hosted By ALEC</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/georgia-lobbyists-alec_n_7447054.html</Link>
        <Description>The Georgia Legislature has a message for voters: don't ask us about our meetings with corporate lobbyists behind closed doors.</Description>
        <MainBody>Georgia Lawmakers And Corporate Lobbyists Mingle In Secret Meetings Hosted By ALEC
WXIA-Savannah
Updated:
44 minutes ago
reddit
The Georgia Legislature has a message for voters: don't ask us about our meetings with corporate lobbyists behind closed doors.
The 11Alive Investigators tracked lawmakers to a resort hotel in Savannah last week, where we observed state legislators and lobbyists mingling in the hotel bar the night before they gathered in private rooms to decide what new laws would best serve the corporations.
The meetings were part of the Spring Task Force Summit of the American Legislative Exchange Council, or ALEC.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:58:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Viral Wedding Photo Of A Marine Praying With His Soon-To-Be Wife Will Move You</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/marines-wedding-photo-with-bride-goes-viral_n_7446506.html</Link>
        <Description>A photo of U.S. Marine Corps Cpl. Caleb Earwood and his bride Maggie </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
A photo of U.S. Marine Corps Cpl. Caleb Earwood and his bride Maggie sharing an emotional moment before their wedding in Asheville, North Carolina this Memorial Day weekend has gone viral. One look at the powerful shot and it's easy to see why:
Photographer Dwayne Schmidt captured the moment and shared it on his business's Facebook on Saturday, calling it "one of the best things I have ever [gotten] to see, much less photograph." At the time of publication, the post had amassed more than 47,000 likes and counting.
The photo shows the couple holding hands and closing their eyes as to not catch a glimpse of each other before the ceremony. The groom is saying a prayer aloud, while his bride-to-be stands around the corner.
"It broke me down to know that we felt the same way about God," the bride told ABC News . "It just made me happy."
The soon-to-be-newlyweds weren't the only ones who were overcome with intense emotions.
"The whole room was full of emotion," Schmidt said. "I tried not to cry and focus on what I was doing."
Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Weddings on Facebook , Twitter and Pinterest . Sign up for our newsletter here .
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:53:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Girl Charged In Slender Man Killing Called A Model Inmate</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/anissa-weier-slender-man-killing_n_7446964.html</Link>
        <Description>WAUKESHA, Wis. (AP) — Defense experts say one of two Wisconsin girls charged as adults with trying to kill a friend to please a fictional horror character has a very low risk of future criminal behavior and a high likelihood of success in treatment.</Description>
        <MainBody>Girl Charged In Slender Man Killing Called A Model Inmate
Posted:
Updated:
1 hour ago
One of the two 12-year-old defendants is led into the courtroom in Waukesha, Wis. on Thursday, Dec. 18, 2014 during the trial for the stabbing of a third girl in May 2014. The two girls told detectives the attack was an attempt to please Slenderman, a fictional character they found on a horror website. (AP Photo/Milwaukee Journal-Sentinel, Michael Sears, Pool) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
stumble
WAUKESHA, Wis. (AP)  Defense experts say one of two Wisconsin girls charged as adults with trying to kill a friend to please a fictional horror character has a very low risk of future criminal behavior and a high likelihood of success in treatment.
The Milwaukee Journal Sentinel reports (http://bit.ly/1RlXXQD ) the testimony came Tuesday at the start of a two-day hearing in which the 13-year-old's attorneys are trying to show she should be transferred to juvenile court for plotting with a 12-year-old to kill Payton Leutner. The 12-year-old Leutner survived 19 stab wounds last May at a Waukesha park.
The girls charged allegedly wanted to please Slender Man, a character they believed could kill them or their families.
Psychologist Anthony Jurek testified the 13-year-old struggled with her parents' divorce and peer acceptance.
___
Information from: Milwaukee Journal Sentinel, http://www.jsonline.com
Also on HuffPost:
10 Major Crimes That Shocked the Nation (SLIDESHOW)
of


On January 15, 1947, the remains of  Elizabeth Short, were found in a vacant lot in Los Angeles. What made this discovery the stuff of tabloid sensation, however, was the Glasgow smile left on the aspiring actress' face--made with 3-inch slashes on each side. This, coupled with Short's dark hair, fair complexion and reputation for sporting a dahlia in her hair, dubbed her "The Black Dahlia" in headlines. What followed was a media circus filled with rumors and speculation about the promiscuous 22-year-old's checkered past. What haunts theorists to this day, apart from the victim's uniquely nightmarish visage, is that the case remains unsolved after some 200 suspects were interviewed and ultimately released--making it one of Hollywood's most lurid legends.
"Lizzie Borden took an axe And gave her mother forty whacks. And when she saw what she had done, She gave her father forty-one."  So goes the lurid nursery rhyme to one of the most mystifying crimes of the century. The nature of the deaths of Andrew J. Borden and his wife, Abby, are trumped only by the identity of the alleged perpetrator: their daughter, Lizzie.  Inexplicably found "not guilty" in contrast to the era's zeitgeist of swift justice, Lizzie's legacy--guilty or not--has become immortalized as one of the most perplexing cases of parricide in history.
In a case of mother-gone-mad that startled a nation, Andrea Yates, to her few friends and neighbors, was known as a mere recluse suffering from postpartum depression leading up to the birth of her fifth child. That all changed on June 20, 2001, when she snapped, drowning five of her children in their home's bathtub.  She was convicted in 2002 of capital murder, carrying a sentence of life in prison with possible parole. As of July 2006, however, a Texas jury found her not guilty by reason of insanity.
Known as the "Long Island Lolita," Fisher became involved with Joey Buttafuoco in May of 1991. Shortly after the two began a sexual relationship (she, 16, while he, 35, was married with two children), his presence and influence in her life became all she cared for. In what he's since denied to this day, Buttafuoco would go on to help an obsessive Fisher plan the murder of his wife, culminating in Fisher putting a bullet in Mary Jo Buttafuoco's head, but failing to kill her. In the highly publicized trial that ensued, Fisher accepted a plea deal for 15 years in prison in exchange for a testimony against Joey, who faced and served out charges of statutory rape.
With a face that graced the covers of nearly every news and gossip rag during the winter of '96, it's hard to suggest the death of child beauty pageant queen JonBent Ramsey had little effect outside the city of Boulder, Colorado.  Found dead from a blow to the head and strangulation in the family's basement, coupled with a ransom note left on the staircase asking for $118,000 (conveniently or coincidentally, nearly the same amount Mr. Ramsey received as a bonus that year), as well as no obvious signs of forced entry into the house, the evidence was overwhelmingly stacked against parents John and Patsy, who managed to maintain their innocence throughout the investigation. The case reopened in 2010, but critics cite poor handling of the crime scene as obstructing what remains a mystery regarding the events of that Christmas day.
Tattooed with "Born to Raise Hell" on his arm, Richard Speck made good on his mantra through a history of violence, theft, alcoholism, and spousal abuse, but made his infamy known to all when, on July 13, 1966, he walked into a dormitory armed with a knife. After leaving 8 student nurses dead in his wake, only one, Cora Amurao, was spared--hiding under a bed until 6 a.m. Speck was found guilty of murder and died of a heart attack in prison. As one of the most press-worthy crimes of the decade, the grim events were used most recently as the backdrop for an episode of Mad Men.
Perhaps the most terrifying figure in American crime to have never actually killed anyone himself, Charles Manson founded a "family" of wayward individuals who hailed him as a prophet. So strong was his manipulation, he ordered, on the night of Aug. 8, 1969, four of his followers to kill everyone at the residence of 10050 Cielo Drive--including Roman Polanski's wife, Sharon Tate, and her unborn child. Tate was stabbed 16 times, and her blood was used to write "pig" on the house's front door. The next night, Manson accompanied six of his family to the residence of supermarket executive Leno LaBianca and his wife, only to help bind them before ordering their deaths. In 1971, Manson and three of his fellow defendants were found guilty of murder in the first-degree and several other crimes. At the time, it was the longest murder trial in American history, spanning nine and a half months, as well as the most expensive, estimating $1 million. Manson was denied parole for the 12th time in April 2012.
Used as the basis for an Agatha Christie novel (Murder on the Orient Express) and dubbed "the biggest story since the Resurrection" by famed journalist H.L. Mencken, the kidnapping and murder of aviator Charles Lindbergh's infant son continues to fascinate theorists today. Charles Jr. was discovered missing from his second-floor bedroom on March 1, 1932, along with a note demanding a then-unimaginable $50,000, igniting a media frenzy like no other. The tabloid pandemonium prompted many tips and leads, but none as concrete as a package containing the boy's pajamas and another message demanding the ransom.  After some misdirection from the presumed kidnapper, Lindbergh's child was soon after discovered in the woods along a road near the family residence. Notwithstanding the evidence stockpiled against the easily vilified illegal German immigrant Bruno Hauptmann (who was sentenced), speculation prevails as to the true identity of the caper responsible in this tragic tale of one of America's greatest heroes.
Still fresh in the minds of many and not to easily be forgotten, the trial of Casey Anthony turned Orlando, Florida into anything but the "happiest place on earth."  Following a series of lies, misdirection and manipulation by then-22 year old Casey, Caylee's skeletal remains were found five months into the investigation, setting the stage for what could only be described as the most incessantly publicized and shocking trial in recent memory. The media had a field day that went on for months: Highlighting the young, pretty, party girl image used against her in court as the prosecution tore apart an aimless defense--or so it seemed. After resorting to throwing her family under the bus, incriminating people entirely made-up ("Zanny the Nanny"), and fabricating elaborate stories for the police, Casey was found not guilty of murder due to evidence deemed mostly circumstantial and not meeting the burden of "beyond reasonable doubt," inciting much debate regarding whether true justice was served.
Known and heralded as the "trial of the century," former football star and actor O.J. Simpson found himself in the middle of the nation's biggest, most-televised trial following the deaths of his ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson and her friend Ron Goldman, but not before fleeing an all-points bulletin in his Ford Bronco with 20 units in tow, interrupting game 5 of the NBA Finals. By enlisting a dream team including Johnnie Cochran, Robert Shapiro, and Robert Kardashian, the defense claimed Simpson was merely a victim of police fraud with regard to contaminated DNA evidence, while famously quipping "If it [the glove] doesn't fit, you must acquit." On October 3, 1995, an estimated 100 million people from around the world tuned in to watch the jury hand down a verdict of not guilty, consequently resulting in an estimated loss of $480 million in productivity and inciting an ongoing discussion of race in the judicial system that continues to this day.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:47:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>California Assembly Passes Bill Banning Crisis Pregnancy Centers From Misleading Patients</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/california-abortion-cpc-bill-_n_7446390.html</Link>
        <Description>The California Assembly passed legislation Tuesday that </Description>
        <MainBody>Abortion Protests Around The Nation
of


FILE - In this July 12, 2013 file photo, anti-abortion rights supporter Katherine Aguilar holds a crucifix and prays while opponents and supporters of abortion rights gather in the State Capitol rotunda in Austin, Texas. Nearly three-quarters of Texas' 18 abortion facilities would be forced to close by the end of Aug. 2014 if one of the nation's toughest new anti-abortion laws is allowed to take effect, attorneys for clinics challenging the law told a federal judge Monday, Aug. 4, 2014. (AP Photo/Tamir Kalifa, File)
Demonstrators rally against Colorado Senate Bill 175, in a protest led by Archbishop of Denver Samuel J. Aquila, on the steps of the state capitol in Denver, Tuesday April 15, 2014. The bill up for debate Tuesday is described as a guarantee that state or local policies won't interfere with reproductive decisions such as abortion and contraception. Democratic sponsors say the measure is needed to protect women's rights. (AP Photo/Brennan Linsley)
Georgia Sen. Donzella James, D-Atlanta, left, and Sen. Valencia Seay, D-Riverdale, right, hold up coat hangers with pictures of the Statue of Liberty attached while protesting against an abortion bill sponsored by Sen. Judson Hill, RMarietta, rear, on the Senate floor, Monday, March 3, 2014, in Atlanta. The Georgia Senate has voted to approve a bill restricting abortion coverage in plans available through the state health insurance exchange.State senators voted 35-18 to advance the bill, which now heads to the House for consideration. The federal health care law allows states to draft legislation prohibiting abortion coverage in qualified health plans offered through an exchange. Supporters of the Georgia effort say 24 states have done so. Democrats opposed the bill, calling it a continuation of a "war on women" and saying it infringes on a woman's right to choose. (AP Photo/David Goldman)
FILE - This Feb. 20, 2013 file photo shows a protester outside the Red River Valley Women's Clinic, the state's sole abortion provider, in Fargo, N.D. The clinic has entered into settlement talks on a lawsuit it filed last year against a new law that requires doctors who perform abortions to obtain hospital-admitting privileges. (AP Photo/Dave Kolpack, File)
Ellie Schilling, center, a lawyer representing Louisiana abortion clinics, speaks at a protest outside the Department of Health and Hospitals building on Tuesday, Feb. 4, 2013, in Baton Rouge, La. Abortion rights supporters say DHH issued rules that would have shut down all of the state's abortion clinics. The department rescinded the rules this week. (AP Photo/Melinda Deslatte)
Abortion opponents gather in San Francisco's Civic Center for the "Walk for Life" rally and march, Saturday, Jan. 25, 2014, in San Francisco.  Thousands of abortion opponents marched through downtown San Francisco for the 10th annual "Walk for Life West Coast." The protesters rallied at Civic Center Plaza in front of City Hall before marching down Market Street to Justin Herman Plaza.  (AP Photo/Beck Diefenbach)
Abortion opponents from across Kansas rally outside the Statehouse, Wednesday, Jan. 22, 2014, in Topeka, Kan. Hundreds marked the anniversary of the U.S. Supreme Court decision legalizing abortion nationwide. (AP Photo/John Hanna)
Anti-abortion demonstrators rally at the annual March for Life on the National Mall in Washington, Wednesday, Jan. 22, 2014. Thousands of anti-abortion demonstrators are gathering in Washington for an annual march to protest the Supreme Court's landmark 1973 decision that declared a constitutional right to abortion. (AP Photo/Charles Dharapak)
Pro-choice demonstrators rally outside the Supreme Court in Washington, Wednesday, Jan. 22, 2014. Thousands of abortion opponents are facing wind chills in the single digits to rally and march on Capitol Hill to protest legalized abortion, with a signal of support from Pope Francis. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)
FILE - In this March 25, 2013, file photo Kris Kitko, left, leads chants of protest at an abortion-rights rally at the state Capitol in Bismarck, N.D. Abortion-rights advocates filed a lawsuit in federal court June 25, 2013, in Bismarck, N.D., challenging two new North Dakota laws that impose the nation's toughest abortion restrictions. (AP Photo/James MacPherson, File)
BOSTON - JUNE 28: Congregants from Immaculate Conception Parish in Everett, Mass. recited the rosary outside Planned Parenthood in Boston, Mass. on June 28 2014. (Photo by Wendy Maeda/The Boston Globe via Getty Images)
FILE - This Nov. 21, 2013 file photo shows abortion support signs outside of the Jackson Women's Health Organization clinic in Jackson, Miss. A federal appeals court panel ruled Tuesday, July 29, 2014 that a Mississippi law that would close the state's only abortion clinic is unconstitutional. (AP Photo/Rogelio V. Solis, File)
Demonstrators gather outside the Alabama Statehouse in Montgomery, Ala., Tuesday, April 2, 2013. About 100 Pro-Choice demonstrators gathered to voice their opinions to lawmakers who were gathering inside the Statehouse for the second half of the regular legislative session. (AP Photo/Dave Martin)
Abortion-rights supporters Dina van der Zalm, right, and Allyson Junker stand on the steps of the Missouri Capitol Wednesday, Sept. 10, 2014, in Jefferson City, Mo. Missouri lawmakers are expected to consider whether to override a veto by Gov. Jay Nixon of legislation requiring a 72-hour waiting period for abortions, one of the longest mandatory delays in the nation, during a special legislative session that begins Wednesday. (AP Photo/Jeff Roberson)
Opponents to expanded abortion rights in New York state hold signs at the Capitol on Wednesday, June 12, 2013, in Albany, N.Y. Part of Gov. Andrew Cuomo's 10-point women's rights legislation aims to codify the federal Roe v. Wade decision on abortion rights into state law. (AP Photo/Mike Groll)
Ruth Bromer, 63 of Raleigh, North Carolina (foreground) and Jennifer Hesse, 34, of Cary (center) shout slogans on the BiCentennial Plaza  across from the Legislative Building as the North Carolina Senate gave its approval to a series of abortion restrictions Wednesday, July 3, 2013 in Raleigh, North Carolina. The bill, when originally introduced prohibited the recognition of foreign law, such as Islamic Sharia law, in family courts, was changed Tuesday with little public notice and the new bill titled the Family, Faith and Freedom Protection Act, added anti-abortion legislation. Senators voted 29-12 to approve House Bill 695. (Chuck Liddy/Raleigh News &amp; Observer/MCT via Getty Images)
The Senate gallery is already at capacity before session starts Wednesday July 3, 2013, in Raleigh, North Carolina. House bill 695, when originally introduced prohibited the recognition of foreign law, such as Islamic Sharia law, in family courts, was changed Tuesday with little public notice and the new bill titled the Family, Faith and Freedom Protection Act, added anti-abortion legislation. Senators voted 29-12 to approve House Bill 695. (Chuck Liddy/Raleigh News &amp; Observer/MCT via Getty Images)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:39:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Newport Folk Festival Celebrates 50 Years Since Bob Dylan Went Electric</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/newport-folk-festival-cel_0_n_7446892.html</Link>
        <Description>NEWPORT, R.I. (AP) — This year's Newport Folk Festival plans to pay tribute to the moment when Bob Dylan made rock history by going electric 50 years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Newport Folk Festival Celebrates 50 Years Since Bob Dylan Went Electric
Posted:
Updated:
1 hour ago
This is an undated photo of singer-songwriter Bob Dylan performing with his electric guitar at an unknown location.  (AP Photo) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
NEWPORT, R.I. (AP)  This year's Newport Folk Festival plans to pay tribute to the moment when Bob Dylan made rock history by going electric 50 years ago.
The festival, noted for introducing performers who later became big stars, will have a secret lineup of musicians billed as '65 Revisited.
Festival producer Jay Sweet said on Tuesday that nearly a dozen contemporary musicians are included in an "all-star lineup," but the audience won't know who they are until they take the stage to close the festival with a "massive" set celebrating Dylan's 1965 performance.
Dylan first appeared at Newport as a guest of Joan Baez in 1963. His three-song electric set two years later  including "Like a Rolling Stone" and "Maggie's Farm"  is widely viewed as one of the most pivotal moments in rock 'n' roll history. It marked Dylan's break with the folk movement and spurred others to go electric as well.
The Fender Stratocaster guitar Dylan played in the performance sold at auction in 2013 for nearly $1 million, the highest price paid for a guitar at auction.
Dylan is not playing at this year's festival, although Sweet said he's invited to play every year. If there's any year Dylan wouldn't come, it's Sweet's guess it would probably be this one.
"Having him back would be the least Newport way to celebrate it," he said.
Dylan last played Newport in 2002.
"Trying to recreate that moment is a fool's errand," Sweet said. "We're about the future, not about reliving the past."
But Sweet said without that moment, when Dylan struck out a new path for music, the Newport Folk Festival probably would not be celebrating its 56th anniversary this year.
"Every once in a while, you have to acknowledge, that allowed us to be here," he said.
The festival runs July 24-26. Tickets are sold out for the last two days, but a few are available for the first day. Other headliners include Roger Waters and The Decemberists.
Earlier on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:34:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beloved Documentary Photographer Mary Ellen Mark Dies At 75</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/mary-ellen-mark-dead_n_7446878.html</Link>
        <Description>NEW YORK (AP) — Documentary photographer Mary Ellen Mark, called "a snake charmer of the soul" for her gift of capturing searing images of human vulnerability, has died at age 75.</Description>
        <MainBody>Beloved Documentary Photographer Mary Ellen Mark Dies At 75
| By                                                                      VERENA DOBNIK
Updated:
1 hour ago
RUSSELL, KS - JULY 20:  US Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole(L) talks with a Russell, Kansas resident, 23 July as documentary photographer Mary Ellen Mark(R), who is shooting a campaign commercial for the Dole campaign, takes their picture. Dole is spending the day in his howetown shooting a campaign film and still pictures.   (ELECTRONIC IMAGE)  (Photo credit should read J. DAVID AKE/AFP/Getty Images) | DAVID AKE via Getty Images
reddit
NEW YORK (AP)  Documentary photographer Mary Ellen Mark, called "a snake charmer of the soul" for her gift of capturing searing images of human vulnerability, has died at age 75.
She died Monday at a New York hospital after a long battle with a blood illness caused by bone marrow failure, her close friend Kelly Cutrone said.
Mark's subjects ranged from runaway children and heroin addicts to celebrities and world leaders. She also pointed her lens at members of the Ku Klux Klan, a women's security ward in a mental institution and various celebrities.
Over the decades, "what resulted was, in fact, a lamentation: one of the most delicately shaded studies of vulnerability ever set on film," wrote the late Time magazine art critic Robert Hughes.
A collection of Mark photographs in a book titled "Streetwise" documents the life of Tiny Blackwell, a Seattle prostitute and drug addict Mark met in the 1980s when Tiny was 13. A new book on Blackwell photographed over decades is yet to be published, titled "Tiny: Streetwise Revisited."
The photographer chose Seattle "because it is known as 'America's most livable city,'" she wrote in the preface to her book on the subject. "By choosing America's ideal city we were making the point: 'If street kids exist in a city like Seattle then they can be found everywhere in America, and we are therefore facing a major social problem of runaways in this country.'"
Mark's work appeared in prominent publications including Life, the New York Times Magazine, The New Yorker, Rolling Stone and Vanity Fair. She also published 18 books.
Her latest project, for CNN, was New Orleans on the 10th anniversary of Hurricane Katrina.
Mark was born and raised in Elkins Park, Pennsylvania, just outside Philadelphia. In 1962, she graduated from the University of Pennsylvania with a bachelor of fine arts in art history and painting, followed by a master's in photojournalism.
Her work drew attention in the 1960s, when she photographed heroin addicts in London, steeping herself in the humanity of overlooked subjects.
"She was a snake charmer of the soul," said Cutrone, an author and publicist who considered Mark "like my divine mother and mentor." ''She had the ability and intuition to see inside people, to evoke their soul."
Mark, in her SoHo neighborhood, knew people in the street and in shops, Cutrone said.
"She talked to everybody," she said. "She was really connected."
Mark, a photographer's photographer, never really switched to digital cameras.
"I'm staying with film, and with silver prints, and no Photoshop," she told The Philadelphia Inquirer in 2008. "That's the way I learned photography: You make your picture in the camera. Now, so much is made in the computer. ... I'm not anti-digital, I just think, for me, film works better."
Mark is survived by her husband, filmmaker Martin Bell, who directed the documentary "Streetwise" based on her images.
A New York memorial is planned for Sept. 10.
Earlier on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:19:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hitler Ice Cream Cones Causing A Furor</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/hitler-ice-cream-_n_7446800.html</Link>
        <Description>We did not see this coming: A brand of ice cream cones named after Adolf Hitler.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hitler Ice Cream Cones Causing A Furor
BarstoolSports.com
We did not see this coming: A brand of ice cream cones named after Adolf Hitler.
The Hitler cones are currently sold in India, where education about the Holocaust is minimal, sources say.


The members of a UFO cult called the Raelians have declared June 23 as "World Swastika Rehabilitation Day" and are holding demonstrations to show that the swastika was long considered a positive symbol before the Nazis coopted it in 1920.
Organizers for Swastika Rehabilitation Day say that when Westerners interpret it as meaning something ugly just because the Nazis used it, our society denies millions of people the right to live their religion freely.
Swastika Rehabilitation Day is celebrated in cities all over the world including Tel Aviv, Israel.
Andrew Cochrane....Meet George, the pet fish who looks like Hitler. The five-year-old common goldfish has recently developed an uncanny resemblance to the evil German dictator.
A picture dated 1939 shows German nazi Chancellor and dictator Adolf Hitler with his German Shepherd dog.   Research by Cardiff University professor  Dr. Jan Bondeson allegedly indicates that Hitler's SS forces tried read, write and speak. The goal was to turn the pooches into the ultimate guard dogs by training them to be able to communicate with their SS handlers.
Philippe Loret, a French plumber, revealed the family's dark secret recently -- that he and his six siblings were the grandchildren of Der Fuhrer. Loret said his father told the family about their ancestry 40 years ago.   The connection to Hitler made Loret depressed, although he went public in April 2012 with the story.   "In order not to get depressed, I worked non-stop, never took a holiday, and had no hobbies," Loret said in the Telegraph. "For twenty years I didn't even go to the cinema."
There are a lot of far-out stories about Roswell, N.M. -- the site of a supposed alien spaceship crash in 1947.  Perhaps the most bizarre conspiracy theory about Roswell concerns Soviet leader Josef Stalin and infamous Nazi scientist Josef Mengele. The duo supposedly teamed up to dispatch children surgically altered to look like aliens to Roswell, according to author Annie Jacobsen's book "Area 51."
Heath Campbell, left, with his wife, Deborah, and son Adolf Hitler Campbell, 3, pose in Easton, Pa. On Thursday, Aug. 5, 2010, a state appeals court determined the Campbells should not regain custody of their children, after the New Jersey Division of Youth Family Services removed the Campbells three children, Adolph Hitler Campbell, 3, and younger sisters JoyceLynne Aryan Nation Campbell and Honszlynn Jeannie Campbell, from their home in Holland Township, N.J., on Jan. 9, 2009, for unspecified reasons.
Cyclists pass by the bungalow on one of the real estates formerly owned by Joseph Goebbels, the Reich Minister of Propaganda in Nazi Germany on the island of Schwanenwerder at lake Greater Lake Wannsee in Berlin, Germany, Wednesday, June 22, 2011. The lakeside property in the German capital once owned by Nazi propaganda minister Joseph Goebbels was up for sale at auction.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:16:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As Duggar Dad Ran On A Political Platform Saying Rape And Incest Merited Capital Punishment, He Was Covering Up His Son's Actions</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/duggars-politics-incest_n_7444264.html</Link>
        <Description>In 2002, Jim Bob Duggar argued that rape and incest merited the death penalty. But that same year, one of his own sons reportedly committed incest, and Duggar allegedly covered it up. </Description>
        <MainBody>Previous Story
Next Story
As Duggar Dad Ran On A Political Platform Saying Rape And Incest Merited Capital Punishment, He Was Covering Up His Son's Actions
Updated:
1 hour ago
reddit
In 2002, Jim Bob Duggar argued that rape and incest merited the death penalty. But that same year, one of his own sons reportedly committed incest, and Duggar allegedly covered it up.
While running for U.S. Senate in Arkansas, the patriarch of the Duggar clan -- the family that is the central focus of the TLC reality TV show "19 Kids And Counting" -- said that rape and incest should be punishable by death. Yet during his run, he reportedly knew that one of his sons, Josh, had molested one of his daughters.
Gawker Media dug up a cached version of Duggar's political platform from the 2002 Republican primaries .
When asked if he believed abortion should be legal if a woman had been raped, Duggar said, "If a woman is raped, the rapist should be executed instead of the innocent unborn baby. ... Rape and incest represent heinous crimes and as such should be treated as capital crimes."
Duggar lost the primary election in May 2002 to the incumbent, Sen. Tim Hutchinson.
While Duggar was running on a platform that included this position about rape, the first allegations that Josh had molested a child surfaced. According to In Touch Weekly, which broke the story, a female minor told Duggar in March 2002 that Josh, who was 14 at the time, had been sexually touching her as she slept. Josh admitted as much to his parents in July 2002.
A police report suggests that the first victim who came forward lived in the same home as Josh. In March 2003, more minors accused Josh of touching their breasts and genitals. The police report suggests that four of the five total victims were Josh's sisters.
Duggar did not alert authorities. He reportedly did not punish his son at all, except to send him to live and work with a family friend for a while.
When Josh returned, his father allegedly took him to speak with Arkansas State Trooper Jim Hutchens, who gave the boy a "very stern talk." According to In Touch, Hutchens is now serving 56 years in jail for child pornography.
The authorities first heard about the allegations in 2006, when an anonymous woman contacted "The Oprah Winfrey Show" with details of the accusations. The police launched an investigation, and In Touch reports five victims confirmed that Josh had touched their breasts and genitals.
Reportedly, the police did not press charges because the statute of limitations had expired.
The Duggar family could not be reached for comment. TLC did not respond to a request for comment.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:09:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>WTF! Merriam-Webster Adds A Bunch Of Internet Slang To Dictionary</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/internet-slang-dictionary_n_7446288.html</Link>
        <Description>Emoji (noun):         </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Emoji (noun):    
Merriam-Webster just added "emoji," "meme," "WTF" and "clickbait" to the dictionary among 1,700 new words, meaning that the Internet has succeeded in ruining the English language.
JK LOL 
In a blog post, Merriam-Webster noted that some of the new words are "kind of goofy" and some come from the "not-so-natural world," including "net neutrality," "dark money," "click fraud," "photobomb" and "NSFW." We'll take just a little credit: The entry for "jegging" includes a citation from a HuffPost article , and another citation for "clickbait" refers to "those seductive Huffington Post-esque headlines."
The dictionary site reports that its editors identify new words by spending an hour or two each day reading newly published material , online and otherwise, and checking for new and common word usage.
You can read more about new words you've probably never heard, like "eggcorn," by clicking here , or check out some of the best additions below, as compiled by Time magazine :
WTF (abbrev.)
Definition: what the f, used especially to express or describe outraged surprise, recklessness, confusion or bemusement.
eggcorn (n.)
Definition: a word or phrase that sounds like and is mistakenly used in a seemingly logical or plausible way for another word or phrase either on its own or as part of a set expression.
colossal squid (n.)
Definition: an extremely large squid occurring in deep waters of the Southern Ocean that is the largest known living invertebrate.
sharing economy (n.)
Definition: economic activity that involves individuals buying or selling usually temporary access to goods or services, especially as arranged through an online company or organization.
vocal fry (n.)
Definition: a vocal effect produced by very slow vibration of the vocal cords and characterized by a creaking sound and low pitch.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:06:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Carly Fiorina Calls The Chinese Unimaginative Idea Thieves</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/carly-fiorina-china-innovate_n_7446512.html</Link>
        <Description>GOP presidential contender Carly Fiorina tells a reporter in a video that surfaced Tuesday that Americans shouldn't fear competition with China because its</Description>
        <MainBody>

Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas), his wife Heidi and their two daughters wave on stage after he announced his campaign for president, Monday, March 23, 2015 at Liberty University, in Lynchburg, Va. Cruz, who announced his candidacy on Twitter in the early morning hours, was the first major candidate to officially enter 2016 race for president.
Sen. Rand Paul (R-Ky.) announces the start of his presidential campaign, Tuesday, April 7, 2015, at the Galt House Hotel in Louisville, Ky. Paul launched his 2016 presidential campaign Tuesday with a combative message against both Washington and his fellow Republicans, declaring that "we have come to take our country back."
Democratic presidential candidate and former U.S. Sectetary of State Hillary Clinton speaks to employees of Whitney Brothers, an educational furniture manufacturer, at a round table discussion on April 20, 2015 in Keene, New Hampshire. This marked Clinton's first major political event in New Hampshire after announcing her campaign for president a little over a week before.  (Photo by Andrew Burton/Getty Images)
Sen. Marco Rubio (R-Fla.) smiles as he speaks to supporters as he announces that he is running for the Republican presidential nomination, during a rally at the Freedom Tower, Monday, April 13, 2015, in Miami. (AP Photo/Wilfredo Lee)
Sen. Bernie Sanders (I-Vt.) speaks to the media about his agenda in running for president, Thursday, April 30, 2015, on Capitol Hill in Washington. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
Ben Carson announces his candidacy for president during an official announcement in Detroit on Monday, May 4, 2015. Carson, 63, a retired neurosurgeon, begins the Republican primary as an underdog in a campaign expected to feature several seasoned politicians.
Former Hewlett-Packard CEO Carly Fiorina speaks at the Iowa Faith &amp; Freedom 15th Annual Spring Kick Off, in Waukee, Iowa, Saturday, April 25, 2015.
Former Arkansas Gov. Mike Huckabee salutes supporters in Hope, Ark., after announcing Tuesday, May 5, 2015, that he is seeking the Republican nomination in the race for president.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:03:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mother Of Daughter Killed By Army Father Will Get $2 Million</title>
        <Link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/05/26/tarshia-williams-talia-death-settlement_n_7446740.html</Link>
        <Description>HONOLULU (AP) -- The U.S. government will pay an Atlanta woman $2 million for the Hawaii beating death of her 5-year-old daughter at the hands of a former soldier.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mother Of Daughter Killed By Army Father Will Get $2 Million
Posted:
Updated:
1 hour ago
FILE - In this April 24, 2014 file photo, Tarshia Williams displays a pendant with her daughter, Talia's face on it outside of a federal courthouse in Honolulu. The U.S. government will pay Williams from Atlanta, $2 million for the Hawaii beating death of her 5-year-old daughter at the hands of a former soldier. The settlement amount was announced Tuesday, May 26, 2015, at a brief hearing in federal court in Honolulu. (AP Photo/Sam Eifling, File) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
HONOLULU (AP) -- The U.S. government will pay an Atlanta woman $2 million for the Hawaii beating death of her 5-year-old daughter at the hands of a former soldier.
The settlement amount was announced Tuesday at a brief hearing in federal court in Honolulu.
Tarshia Williams filed the lawsuit against the government over the 2005 death of her daughter, Talia. The lawsuit, filed in Honolulu in 2008, claimed the military didn't report to the proper authorities that Talia's father and stepmother "abused and tortured" her throughout the seven months she lived in Army housing in Hawaii.
"I will never have complete closure because my daughter is gone," she said by phone after the hearing. "And all the abuse she went through, I will never get over that. My healing will never be complete."
In what was the first death penalty case to go to trial in the history of Hawaii's statehood, Naeem Williams was convicted of murder in his daughter's death and sentenced to life in prison without possibility for parole.
Talia's stepmother, Delilah Williams, testified against her husband as part of a deal with prosecutors for a 20-year sentence. She provided disturbing details of abuse that included withholding food for days at a time, keeping her out of school to hide from others the physical signs of beatings and whipping the child while she was duct-taped to a bed.
Talia died July 16, 2005, after prosecutors say her father dealt a blow so hard it left knuckle imprints on her chest.
The settlement brings some relief because it ends years of litigation and prevents Tarshia Williams from having to return to Hawaii for a nonjury trial that was scheduled for June, she said.
"I just been through it last year," she said of testifying at the murder trial and sitting through graphic accounts of what Talia suffered. "I don't have to go through all the things that happened to her all over again. It will always be in my mind. It will never go away."
At Naeem Williams' trial, she testified that the last time she saw Talia was when the child left South Carolina to live with her father in Hawaii. She said the last time she spoke to Talia was by telephone on July 2, 2005.
The settlement has been approved by the Justice Department and will be paid in about six to eight weeks, Assistant U.S. Attorney Thomas Helper said in court. He declined to comment after the hearing.
Tarshia Williams and her Honolulu attorneys want to work on federal legislation that that would require the military to directly report child abuse to state child protective services, said one of her attorneys, Mark Davis.
"We hope that what may come out of this case are some fundamental, systemic changes," Davis said. "There were so many opportunities that were missed to try to remove this child from this toxic environment."
A judge's 2010 ruling noted some of those missed opportunities, including one on June 29, 2005. "The military police responded to the Williams' home, but despite finding Talia, `naked and mute, in a room standing near feces on the floor' and thinking `something did not look right,' no reports were ever made to CPS," said the order by U.S. District Judge Alan Kay in allowing the lawsuit to move forward.
"She would be about 15 now," Tarshia Williams said. "She would be in high school."
--
Follow Jennifer Sinco Kelleher at http://www.twitter.com/JenHapa .
 2015 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Learn more about our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
