<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:01:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beach Hotel In Tunisia's Sousse Attacked By Gunmen, At Least 7 Killed</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4799660f/sc/10/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Ctunisia0Esousse0Ehotel0Eattack0In0I7670A3420Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS, June 26 (Reuters) - At least seven people have been killed in an attack on a tourist hotel in the Tunisian beach resort of Sousse, an interior ministry spokesman said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Beach Hotel In Tunisia's Sousse Attacked, At Least 27 Killed
Posted:
An official at Tunisia's Interior Ministry said on Friday that at least 27 people were killed in an attack on hotels in the beach town of Sousse, Reuters reports. The official added that foreigners were among those killed.
This is breaking news. Check back later for updates.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:47:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosion At Mosque In Kuwait City Kills Several</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47996616/sc/38/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Ckuwait0Ebomb0In0I7669840A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Explosion At Mosque In Kuwait City Kills Several
| By                                                                      By HUSSAIN AL-QATARI
Updated:
24 minutes ago
A Kuwaiti man reacts at the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City. AFP PHOTO / YASSER AL-ZAYYAT        (Photo credit should read YASSER AL-ZAYYAT/AFP/Getty Images) | Getty
reddit
DUBAI, June 26 (Reuters) - Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for a suicide attack on a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait that killed or wounded several people, according a statement posted on social media.
The statement identified the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said the target was a "temple of the rejectionists" - a term used by the Islamist militant group to refer to Shi'ite Muslims - and said dozens were killed or wounded.  (Reporting by Omar Fahmy, writing by Sami Aboudi; editing by John Stonestreet)
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:24:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jon Stewart Has A Blast With GOP Response To Pope's Climate Change Encyclical</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798da45/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cjon0Estewart0Epope0Eclimate0Echange0In0I76693620Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Many of the Republican presidential candidates who normally aren't shy about bringing religion into politics had a sudden change of heart when Pope Francis released his </Description>
        <MainBody>Climate Change: Ten Beautiful Places Under Threat
of


The impacts of climate warming in Alaska are already occurring, experts have warned.   Over the past 50 years, temperatures across Alaska increased by an average of 3.4F.   Winter warming was even greater, rising by an average of 6.3F jeopardising its famous glaciers and frozen tundra.
The most fragile of Italian cities has been sinking for centuries. Long famous for being the city that is partially under water, sea level rise associated with global warming would have an enormous impact on Venice and the surrounding region.   The Italian government has begun constructing steel gates at the entrances to the Venetian lagoon, designed to block tidal surges from flooding the city. However, these barriers may not be enough to cope with global warming.
The West Antarctic Peninsula is one of the fastest warming areas on Earth, with only some areas of the Arctic Circle experiencing faster rising temperatures.   Over the past 50 years, temperatures in parts of the continent have jumped between 5 and 6 degrees F a rate five times faster than the global average.  A 2008 report commissioned by WWF warned that if global temperatures rise 3.6 degrees Fahrenheit (2 degrees Celsius) above pre-industrial averages, sea ice in the Southern Ocean could shrink by 10 to 15 percent.
The rapid decline of the world's coral reefs appears to be accelerating, threatening to destroy huge swathes of marine life unless dramatic action is swiftly taken, leading ocean scientists have warned.   About half of the world's coral reefs have already been destroyed over the past 30 years, as climate change warms the sea and rising carbon emissions make it more acidic.
The world's highest mountain range contains the planet's largest non-polar ice mass, with over 46,000 glaciers.   The mammoth glaciers cross eight countries and are the source of drinking water, irrigation and hydroelectric power for roughly 1.5 billion people. And just like in Antarctica, the ice is melting.
An expected 2C rise in the worlds average temperatures in the next decades will impact island economies such as the Maldives with extreme weather patterns and rising sea levels.
Over the last century, global warming has caused all Alpine glaciers to recede. Scientists predict that most of the glaciers in the Alps could be gone by 2050.   Global warming will also bring about changes in rain and snowfall patterns and an increase in the frequency of extreme meteorological events, such as floods and avalanches, experts have warned.
The Arctic is ground zero for climate change, warming at a rate of almost twice the global average.    The sea ice that is a critical component of Arctic marine ecosystems is projected to disappear in the summer within a generation.
Called the "epicenter of the current global extinction," by Conservation International, this smattering of more than 4,000 South Pacific islands is at risk from both local human activity and global climate change.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:11:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Massive V404 Cygni Black Hole Wakes Up And Swallows A Star</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e42b/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cblack0Ehole0Ewakes0Eup0In0I76686840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A black hole has woken up... </Description>
        <MainBody>Best Space Images Of 2014
of


This Hubble Space Telescope photo shows NGC 2174, the "Monkey Head Nebula," located 6,400 light-years from Earth.
A powerful X-class solar flare, one of three X-class flares unleashed by the sun on June 10 and 11, as seen by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory. X-class flares are the most powerful kind.
Hubble image of the barred spiral galaxy M83, the "Southern Pinwheel," which lies 15 million light-years away in the constellation Hydra. This mosaic image was released in January.
Astronaut Koichi Wakata tweeted this view of a crescent moon rising and the cusp of Earth's atmosphere on Feb. 1, 2014.
Galaxy NGC 4258, located about 23 million light-years away from Earth, as seen by NASA's Chandra X-ray Observatory.
This photo of a "rainbow aurora" was taken by ISS astronaut Alexander Gerst.
This close-up image of part of Saturn's rings was taken by the Cassini spacecraft on June 30. It shows, from left to right, the outer portion of Saturn's C ring and the inner portion of the B ring.
ISS astronaut Reid Wiseman tweeted this image of a sunrise on Oct. 29. Wiseman wrote, "Not every day is easy. Yesterday was a tough one. #sunrise"
This image taken by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory shows a profile view of coronal loops. Coronal loops are found around sunspots and in active regions.
This image shows the sunlit side of Saturn's rings. It was taken in red light by the Cassini spacecraft's narrow-angle camera on Aug. 23.
Several celestial objects photographed in the same field of view by Spanish-American astrophotographer Rogelio Bernal Andreo, including supernova remnant Simeas 147, the "Flaming Star" nebula, nebula IC 410, and galactic clusters M36 and M38.
Astrophotographer Rick Stevenson released this photo of SH2-199, also known as the "Soul Nebula," in December. This emission nebula is located about 6,500 light-years from Earth.
This Hubble image shows a portion of the Large Magellanic Cloud, a small nearby galaxy that orbits our galaxy, the Milky Way.
A new day dawns on Saturn. The image was taken with the Cassini spacecraft's wide-angle camera on Aug. 23.
The photo is a composite image of the spiral galaxies NGC 2207 and IC 2163, located 130 million light years away in the constellation Canis Major. The image contains data from the Chandra X-ray Observatory in pink, optical light data from the Hubble Space Telescope in red, green, and blue, and infrared data from the Spitzer Space Telescope in red.
In January and February 1979, NASA's Voyager 1 spacecraft zoomed toward Jupiter, capturing hundreds of images during its approach, including this close-up of swirling clouds around Jupiter's Great Red Spot. This image was assembled from three black and white negatives and newly released.
An extreme ultra-violet wavelength image of a solar flare captured on Sept. 10.
This Hubble Space Telescope composite image shows a supernova explosion designated SN 2014J in the galaxy M82, at a distance of approximately 11.5 million light-years from Earth. It was taken on Jan. 31, as the supernova approached its peak brightness.
An image of the Tarantula Nebula (or NGC 2070), located about 160,000 lights years away, released in January.
This composite image shows one of the clusters, NGC 2024, which is found in the center of the so-called Flame Nebula about 1,400 light years from Earth. In this image, X-rays from Chandra are seen as purple, while infrared data from NASA's Spitzer Space Telescope are colored red, green and blue.
Saturn's moon Tethys captured by the Cassini spacecraft's narrow-angle camera on July 14.
The Philae lander took this portrait of the Rosetta spacecraft on Sept. 7, 2014, at a distance of about 30 miles from comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko.
The puzzling, fascinating surface of Jupiter's icy moon Europa looms large in this newly-reprocessed color view, made from images taken by NASA's Galileo spacecraft in the late 1990s.
A widefield view of the Flame (NGC2024) and Horsehead (IC434) Nebulae in Orion, captured in December by astrophotographer Roger Hutchinson. The pair are approximately 900 to 1,500 light years away.
Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, captured on Aug. 3, 2014 by Rosetta's OSIRIS narrow-angle camera.
The Orion Nebula, an immense stellar nursery some 1,500 light-years away. This stunning false-color view was constructed using infrared data from the Spitzer Space Telescope.
NASA astronaut Reid Wiseman captured this image from the International Space Station and tweeted it on Sept. 28, writing, "The Milky Way steals the show from Sahara sands that make the Earth glow orange."
European Space Agency astronaut Alexander Gerst tweeted this photograph taken from the International Space Station to social media on Aug. 29, 2014, writing, "words can't describe how it feels flying through an #aurora. I wouldn't even know where to begin."
This view, captured by the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and released in July, shows a nearby spiral galaxy known as NGC 1433. At about 32 million light-years from Earth, it is a type of very active galaxy known as a Seyfert galaxy--with a bright, luminous center comparable in brightness to that of our entire galaxy, the Milky Way.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:03:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Harry Potter And The Cursed Child' To Hit London Stage In 2016; Play Tells 'Untold' Story, J.K. Rowling Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e445/sc/15/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Charry0Epotter0Eand0Ethe0Ecursed0Echild0Eplay0In0I76692840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Harry Potter fans, hold onto your broomsticks. An “untold part” of the boy wizard’s story will soon be revealed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Previous Story
Next Story
'Harry Potter And The Cursed Child' To Hit London Stage In 2016; Play Tells 'Untold' Story, J.K. Rowling Says
reddit
Harry Potter fans, hold onto your broomsticks. An untold part of the boy wizards story will soon be revealed.
Author J.K. Rowling confirmed on Twitter Friday that a play, entitled  Harry Potter and the Cursed Child , will be opening in London next year.
It will tell a new story, Rowling wrote, later adding: I dont want to say too much more, because I dont want to spoil what I know will be real treat for fans.
Rowling stressed, however, that the play will not be a prequel.
I'm also very excited to confirm today that a new play called Harry Potter and the #CursedChild will be opening in London next year.
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
It will tell a new story, which is the result of a collaboration between writer Jack Thorne, director John Tiffany and myself. #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
I don't want to say too much more, because I don't want to spoil what I know will be a real treat for fans. #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
However, I can say that it is not a prequel! #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
To answer one inevitable (and reasonable!) question - why isn't #CursedChild a new novel? - I am confident that when audiences see the play
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
they will agree that it was the only proper medium for the story. #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
I've had countless offers to extend Harry's story over the years, but Jack, John and Sonia Friedman are a dream team! #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
It has been a huge pleasure to share with them (and soon, with you!) this untold part of Harry's story. #CursedChild
According to The Daily Mail, Harry Potter and the Cursed Child may detail the lives of Harrys parents, James and Lily , before they were killed by Lord Voldemort.
The play may also look at the complicated relationship between siblings Lily and Petunia, the news outlet wrote. Petunia, and her husband Vernon, were the muggles (non-magical people) who raised Harry after he was orphaned.
The play is slated to open in the summer of 2016 at the Palace Theatre on Londons West End, Entertainment Weekly writes. Tickets will reportedly go on sale in the fall.
Also on HuffPost:
'Harry Potter': Where Are They Now?
of


Since appearing as the movies' title character, Daniel has managed to shake off Harry and ensure he's known by his own name - which has been aided by the fact he'll happily get his kit off on-screen and on-stage.   After stints in the West End and on Broadway, Daniel recently starred in 'What If', and in 2015, fans will see him take on the role of Igor in 'Frankenstein'.
Since hanging up his wizard's hat, Rupert has made waves on the West End stage, and in 2013 he received rave reviews for his performance in 'Mojo'.  He also stowed some his 'Harry Potter' cash away and splashed it on an ice cream truck, fulfilling a childhood dream. Aww!
You'll find Ralph in 'Wrath of the Titans', 'Skyfall' and 'Great Expectations'. It has also been announced he's been cast in the upcoming, as-yet-unnamed, James Bond film.
Sadly, Jamie hasn't fared too well in recent years and in 2012 he was imprisoned after participating in the 2011 London riots.
Sadly, Joshua hasn't faired too well either, and has dropped off the radar as far as acting is concerned.
After being everyone's favourite bad guy in the films, Tom decided to try something a little different and recorded a number of singles, which he shared with fans via YouTube.   He's currently filming 'Clavius', where he stars as a character called Lucius. Tom's also really, really good at Twitter.
After getting surprisingly dishy, Matthew now spends his time reminding everyone that he's also hugely talented, making his West End debut in 2012 alongside Arthur Darvill and Laurence Fox in 'Our Boys'.   Matthew also took part in one of the best editions of Innuendo Bingo ever on Scott Mills' Radio 1 show.
Bonnie was one of the 'Harry Potter' frachise's younger stars, however, that hasn't stopped her from going on to carve a successful career.   While she hasn't quite achieved the worldwide success of the films' leading stars, Bonnie has been applauded for her work as a model and actress. She also writes and directs her own screen plays.
To be honest, Rob's had a rather quiet life since his character's exit left us weeping in the 'Goblet Of Fire' film.   After a lot of digging, Robert's main achievement seems to be another franchise entitled 'Twilight'. Nope, we've never heard of it either...
Julie is one of the many huge names who appeared in the 'Harry Potter' films so it's not like her career needed the boost.   Since the final film in 2011, Julie's been praised by critics her roles in a whole host of other movies, including voicing the witch in Disney's 'Brave'.
Michael is rumoured to be reprising his role in the upcoming wizrding flick 'Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them'.   He also plays Howard Mollison in the TV adaptation of JK's novel 'A Casual Vacancy'.
Already a legend, Dame Maggie Smith continues to win fans with her performance as the Dowager Countess in hit TV series 'Downton Abbey'.   She's also no stranger to the big screen, and starred in 'The Best Exotic Marigold Hotel' and is set to feature in the upcoming sequel.
Amongst other projects, John has completed three where he was cast alongside other 'Harry Potter' stars; 'Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy', 'The Gruffalo's Child' and 'Labyrinth'.
Since 'Harry Potter', method actor Alan has been part of several projects including 'CBGB', alongside his former co-star Rupert Grint.
After providing the voice of everybody's favourite House Elf, Toby's projects included 'The Hunger Games', 'Snow White and the Huntsman' and 'The Adventures of Tintin'.
Once filming wrapped, Robbie moved over to the Dark Side and joined Voldemort's gang. By which we mean, starred alongside Ralph Fiennes, in 'Great Expectations'.   Traitor.
Oh Kenneth, where do we start?   Ever since *that* version of 'Hamlet', Brannagh has been one of our favourite stars to swoon over.   Since leaving the Wizarding World, Kenneth has turned his attention to directing, as well as starring in flicks such as 'My Week With Marilyn' and 'Jack Ryan: Shadow Recruit'.
In between stints studying for a degree at Brown University in the US, Emma starred in a number of blockbusters including 'The Bling Ring' and 'The Perks Of Being A Wallflower'.   Shortly after graduating in 2013, it was announced that Emma has accepted a UN post and will serve as a Women's Goodwill Ambassador.
Gary's a very busy man and has totted up an extensive list of appearances since his Harry Potter days. These include: 'The Dark Knight' and 'The Dark Knight Rises' and 'Dawn of the Planet of the Apes'.  He also voiced Viktor Reznov and Daniel Clarke in the 'Call of Duty' games.
David also lent his voice to video games, specifically as the voice of Lord Darius Crowley in 'World of Warcraft: Cataclysm in 2010'.  Other projects include 'War Horse' and a role in 'Separate We Come, Separate We Go', a short film directed by Bonnie Wright, who played Ginny Weasley.
Do we really need to tell you what John Cleese has been up to? Seriously?
Mad-eye Moody is actually quite sharp, bagging himself parts in numerous projects including 2014's 'Edge of Tomorrow'.  He's also set to star in 'Suffragette', alongside Carey Mulligan and Helena Bonham-Carter.
Geraldine's fleeting appearances as Harry's mum gave the movies some of their most poignant moments.   Since then, she's appeared in 'My Week With Marilyn' and 'Grace Of Monaco'.
Natalia evidently knows how to smell out a hit as she's also starred in 'Game of Thrones' as Osha.
David's done barely anything since his time as Barty Crouch Jr.   No time as a famous Timelord, no treading the boards in Shakespeare plays and he definitely didn't star opposite Olivia Colman in an award-winning ITV drama series. Lazy moo.
A bit of a cult hit on YouTube, Warwick Davies has been feautured on several channels, most notably the YogsCast.   In the land of television he's made guest appearances on shows including 'An Idiot Abroad', 'Top Gear'. He also played Oberon the Ufgood in 'Dwarves Assemble'.  More recently he played Old Hamm in 'Jack the Giant Slayer' and can (sometimes) be found teaching charms lessons at the Warner Bros. Studios VIP nights.
Like Ralph Fiennes, Helen also appeared in 'Skyfall'. she also stars in the hit drama 'Peaky Blinders' as Aunt Polly.
What can we say? The inimitable Helena Bonham Carter played the role of Bellatrix to disturbing perfection and played similarly creepy parts in many other movies. To be honest, if Voldy had left her in charge, he probably would have triumphed.  Helena was the perfect Madame Thernardier in 'Les Miserables' and also gave a stellar performance as Elizabeth Taylor in a BBC television film.
Shirley Henderson appeared in just a couple of the movies as the ghoul skulking around the toilets.   Since then, she voiced the Gruffalo's child in the film of the same name and also starred in 'Soutchliffe', 'Filth' and 'Death In Paradise'.
Since 'Harry Potter' Staunton has voiced Queen Victoria in 'The Pirates! Band of Misfits' and played Knotgrass in 'Maleficent'.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:55:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>An HIV-Positive Man Asked Strangers To Touch Him. What Happened Next Brought Him To Tears</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e454/sc/19/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Chiv0Epositive0Eman0Etouch0Eme0Eexperiment0In0I76688180Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>

Only one quarter of the 1.1 million people with HIV have their condition under control, where "under control" means the virus has been suppressed, according to a report released this summer by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.   CORRECTION: The first sentence has been reworded to more accurately reflect the number of people with HIV.
Even though two men were, for a time, able to go off antiretrovirals because their HIV had been reduced to undetectable levels after receiving bone marrow transplants, the HIV eventually returned in the men, according to news reports.  In 2012, the news of the mens undetectable HIV levels made headlines. The men, who were both HIV positive and taking antiretroviral drugs, had received bone marrow transplants for Hodgkins lymphoma. They had received the transplants while they were also taking the antiretroviral medication.   However, in late 2013, preliminary results showed that the HIV had returned.   This slide has been updated to note more recent developments related to the procedure.
New HIV infection rates can be dramatically lowered by making antiretroviral drugs free, a study from Canadian researchers found.   The Canadian Press reported on the study, conducted by B.C. Centre for Excellence in HIV-AIDS researchers, which showed that British Columbia -- a province that offers free access to antiretroviral therapy  -- had the lowest rate of new HIV infections over a more-than-10-year period, compared with Ontairio and Quebec.
More than half of HIV-infected young people are unaware that they have the virus, according to a Centers for Disease Control and Prevention report.  "Given everything we know about HIV and how to prevent it in 30 years of fighting the disease, it's just unacceptable that young people are becoming infected at such high rates," Reuters reported CDC Director Dr. Thomas Frieden saying.   The report also showed that for young people, 72 percent of the new HIV infections were in men who have sex with men, while almost 50 percent were in young, African-American males, Reuters reported. These figures are based on 2010 data.
The number of people living with HIV has increased by 18 percent from 2001 to 2011, according to a report released this year from the United Nations Programme on AIDS. An estimated 34.2 million people around the world are living with HIV.   The report also showed that deaths from AIDS have dropped, from 2.3 million in 2005-2006 to 1.7 million in 2011, Reuters reported.
According to the same United Nations report, costs for the cheapest UN-recommended antiretroviral therapy drugs have also decreased over the past 10 years, Reuters reported. A year's worth of the drugs used to cost $10,000 in 2000 for one person; now, it costs $100 a year.
The Food and Drug Administration this year officially approved the drug Truvada -- which has been used since 2004 as a treatment for HIV -- to be sold as a preventive measure for people who don't have the infection, but are at high risk for it.  The FDA said that the pill should be considered for preventive use not only by gay or bisexual men who are at high risk for HIV, but also heterosexual men and women who may also face HIV risks, the Associated Press reported.   Heterosexual men and women make up more than one-fourth of new cases of HIV, and "that's not a portion of the epidemic we want to ignore," the CDC's Dr. Dawn Smith, who was the lead author of the new recommendations, told the Associated Press.   The FDA also approved a new drug this year, Stribild, to treat HIV, Reuters reported.
In findings published this year in the journal PLoS Pathogens, scientists from the University of California, Los Angeles found that it's possible to genetically engineer stem cells to attack living HIV-infected cells in mice.   While the study was only for "proof-of-principle," it "lays the groundwork for the potential use of this type of an approach in combating HIV infection in infected individuals, in hopes of eradicating the virus from the body," study researcher Dr. Scott G. Kitchen, an assistant professor of medicine at UCLA, said in a statement.
People should be screened for HIV even if they're not at high risk of contracting the infection, according to draft recommendations released just last month by the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force. The recommendations would mean that everyone between the ages of 15 and 65 should be screened for HIV, even if they're not at high risk for it, Reuters reported.   "The prior recommendations were for screening high-risk adults and adolescents," Dr. Douglas Owens, a member of the USPSTF task force and a Stanford University medical professor, told Reuters. "The current recommendation is for screening everyone, regardless of their risk."
All HIV patients should be treated immediately with antiretrovirals, according to new guidelines issued this year from a panel of the International Antiviral Society-USA, as reported by TIME. The recommendations are counter to previous guidelines, which said that antiretrovirals should only be used if the CD4 count -- a measure of immune cells in a person's body -- becomes less than 350 cells for every mm3 of blood.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attack, Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Decapitated, Several Wounded</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e458/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cfrance0Efactory0Eattack0In0I76694620Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France (AP) — An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Attack, Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Decapitated, Several Wounded
| By                                                                      LORI HINNANT and ANGELA CHARLTON
Posted:
reddit
SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France (AP)  An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack. He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - prosecutor : http://t.co/Y6f803Jkd7 pic.twitter.com/3Eq9Zuw8ze
 Reuters Top News (@Reuters) June 26, 2015
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
A photo taken on June 26, 2015 shows the Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates. (JEAN-PHILIPPE KSIAZEK/AFP/Getty Images)
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
Investigating police officers work outside the plant where an attack took place, Friday, June 26, 2015 in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France.  (AP Photo/Laurent Cipriani)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Dead</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47988697/sc/6/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cexplosion0Efrance0Efactory0In0I76694620Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (AP) — A French security official says an attack and explosion at a gas factory in southeastern France has left one person dead.</Description>
        <MainBody>Attack, Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Decapitated, Several Wounded
| By                                                                      LORI HINNANT and ANGELA CHARLTON
Posted:
reddit
SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France (AP)  An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack. He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - prosecutor : http://t.co/Y6f803Jkd7 pic.twitter.com/3Eq9Zuw8ze
 Reuters Top News (@Reuters) June 26, 2015
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
A photo taken on June 26, 2015 shows the Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates. (JEAN-PHILIPPE KSIAZEK/AFP/Getty Images)
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
Investigating police officers work outside the plant where an attack took place, Friday, June 26, 2015 in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France.  (AP Photo/Laurent Cipriani)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese-Filipino Community's Dilemma: The Philippines, China, and the South China Sea Disputes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47982745/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Crichard0Ejavad0Eheydarian0Cchinese0Efilipino0Ecommunit0Ib0I766930A40Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
At its very core, the Philippines is an idea, representing a pluralistic land with hospitable people, who have always welcomed persecuted people from around the world. It is an all-embracing society that has been open to peoples from around the world.
Nationalism and nationhood in post-colonial, cosmopolitan countries like the Philippines aren't about ethnicity, but, as eminent Sociologist Benedict Anderson suggest, they are instead anchored by an "imagined community" that is bound by shared dreams, sufferings, and experiences. Amid rising tensions in the South China Sea, pitting a powerful China against a beleaguered Philippines, the sizable and well-integrated Chinese community in the Philippines is feeling the heat.
Recently, one of the Philippines' most celebrated writers elicited highly negative reactions among certain circles, particularly the Filipino-Chinese community, by implicitly questioning their loyalty to the Philippines, specifically in an event of war with China. The last thing the Philippines needs at this point is divisive talk and internal divisions. The Filipino-Chinese community serves as a backbone of the country's economy, with many among them rising to positions of great prominence -- whether in business or politics or entertainment -- in the Southeast Asian nation.
Critical Junctures
In their best-selling book, Why Nations Fail , economists James A. Robinson and Daron Acemolu discuss the double-edged nature of what they call critical junctures: Seismic events, which shake up the foundations of the status quo. Sometimes, crises create the right kind of exogenous pressure to disrupt a dysfunctional equilibrium, forcing positive change and encouraging innovative adaptation by troubled societies.
In other cases, crises lead to further divisions and, ultimately, the collapse of an entire civilization. In Collaps e, Evolutionary Biologist Jared Diamond dramatically chronicles the extinction of certain civilizations due to their inability to adapt to changes in their environment.
Yes, we are in the 21st century, but the Darwinian nature of international politics has not dramatically changed in recent times, as exemplified by Russia's unabashed annexation of Crimea and China's sweeping territorial push across the Western Pacific. As much as we would want our world to be strictly governed by international law, power politics, however, continues to shape our globalized world (See John Mearsheimer's Tragedy of Great Power Politics ), with more powerful countries still pressing ahead with their interests even under immense international pressure.
Despite widespread international outcry, China has effectively concluded its construction activities on disputed features in the Spratly chain of islands, creating a sprawling network of civilian and military installations at the heart of one of the world's most important waterways. If and when China chooses to impose an Air Defense Identification Zone (ADIZ) in the area, it would be in a position to push its neighbors out of features under their control.
In some ways, the ongoing disputes with China in the South China Sea represent a critical juncture, testing the competence of Philippine state institutions and the patriotism of its citizenry. The festering territorial spats should serve as a wake up call, instilling into the fabric of Filipino society a robust sense of national unity like never before.
Chinese Threat in Perspective
To begin with, the prospect of a full-scale Chinese invasion of its neighboring countries is highly unlikely. Such paranoid language is more of an outcome of sensationalist commentaries by warmongering journalists and self-serving defense wonks than sober assessment of realities on the ground. Without a question, China is rapidly developing an anti-access/area-denial (A2/AD) capability , which down the road may give it the ability to dominate adjacent waters and push the United States out of East Asia.
But what China is seeking is a "zone of deference" rather than European-style colonization of its neighbors. China is developing the kind of military technology and economic hegemony, which will allow it to win strategic battles without waging full-scale war. As prominent Chinese scholar Yan Xuetong b luntly puts it : "The policy now is to allow these smaller [neighboring] countries to benefit economically from their relationships with China. For China, we need good relationships more urgently than we need economic development. We let them benefit economically, and in return we get good political relationships. We should 'purchase' the relationships."
This is one of the reasons behind China's massive investment in the infrastructure of neighboring countries, a phenomenon that will be buttressed by the establishment of the Asia Infrastructure Investment Bank (AIIB) and the Maritime Silk Road Initiative in Southeast Asia. China channels its ambitions through calibrated assertiveness -- just look at China's salami-slicing strategy in the South China Sea -- rather than mindless expansionism. Of course, there is a risk that things will get out of hand as China expands its presence in contested waters -- marking a gradual sleep walk into confrontation, similar to what happened prior to World War I.
As for China's People's Liberation Army (PLA), it is more interested in and preparing for winning limited wars -- small skirmishes with chilling strategic effect -- than waging an invasion of a neighboring country. China's military strategy is driven by the doctrine of "active defense". Not to mention, the PLA, which still relies on some Soviet-era technology, is yet to be fully-modernized, putting into question its ability to effectively project power beyond its immediate shores.
On National Unity
One of the things the Philippines should be proud about is how it has never, at least in modern times, experienced the kind of inter-ethnic strife -- particularly against minority Chinese communities -- that have afflicted other Southeast Asian countries in the 20th century. Compared to some of its counterparts in Southeast Asia, the Chinese community in the Philippines is highly integrated and doesn't suffer from systematic exclusion.
Over generations, the Filipino-Chinese community has evolved into an authentic, integral component of the Filipino society. Filipino-Chinese businessmen consistently rank among the wealthiest in the country, overseeing large conglomerates, which have been the drivers of growth in recent years. Obviously, given their expanding business interests in China, many Filipino-Chinese tycoons have tried to foster a semblance of stability in Philippine-China relations, often supporting diplomatic efforts to diffuse territorial tensions.
There is a reason why the Chinese diaspora in the Philippines has managed to so easily integrate: Being Filipino is not necessarily defined by ethnicity, but rather by shared values -- opposition to dictatorship, instinctive embrace of liberalism, and celebration of multiculturalism. The Philippines' own very founding fathers -- no less than Jose Rizal, who has a monument in his ancestral home in Qiongque Village, Luoshan Town in Jinjiang City -- were from (Filipino-Chinese) Mestizo stock. The Philippines' incumbent president, and his late mother who was also a president, has Chinese lineage.
In his deeply moving column for the Philippine Daily Inquirer, legal scholar Oscar Franklin Tan points out how the mindset of the Filipino-Chinese community, especially liberal-minded members like him, and the Beijing government are "worlds apart". He laments how he "cannot celebrate [Philippine] independence when I can be so casually told in public that I am less of a Filipino or a person solely because my grandparents were immigrants".
Given the gravity of challenges faced by the Philippines, it is the perfect moment for national unity, building on the vast talents of the Filipino people of all ethnicities. And it is also time for the Philippines to stand on its own, developing its own capabilities to deter aggression and revanchism.
Follow Richard Javad Heydarian on Twitter: www.twitter.com/Richeydarian
More:
China Philippines Benigno Aquino Southchinasea Russia Ukraine
This Blogger's Books and Other Items from...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State Attack In Northeast Syria Displaces 60,000, UN Reports</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4797f2a2/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cisis0Esyria0Erefugees0In0I76690A0A20Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Islamic State Attack In Northeast Syria Displaces 60,000, UN Reports
Reuters
reddit
(Adds details from U.N. report)
BEIRUT, June 26 (Reuters) - An Islamic State attack on the  northeastern Syrian city of Hasaka is reported to have displaced  60,000 people, the United Nations office in Syria said on  Friday, warning that up to 200,000 people may eventually try to  flee.
Islamic State launched an assault on government-held areas  of Hasaka on Thursday, capturing at least one district in the  southwest of the city, which lies close to the borders with  Turkey and Iraq.
Hasaka is divided into zones run separately by the  government of President Bashar al-Assad and a Kurdish  administration. Islamic State fighters also attacked the  Kurdish-held town of Kobani, or Ayn al-Arab, in its twin  offensive on Thursday.
The U.N. Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs  said an estimated 50,000 people had been displaced within Hasaka  city while 10,000 had left northwards towards Amuda town, close  to the Turkish border.
Its report on developments on Thursday cited the Syrian  government's Department of Social Affairs and local partners. It  said the estimated pre-war population in Hasaka was around  300,000 people.
"An estimated 200,000 people may try to flee the city in the  coming hours to northern areas of the governorate, most likely  towards Amuda and Qamishli," it said. Qamishli is a city around  80km (50 miles) north of Hasaka that sits on the Turkish border.
Islamic State said on Thursday it had seized al-Nashwa  district and neighboring areas in the southwest of Hasaka, a  city divided into zones of government and Kurdish control.
It said humanitarian partners in Qamishli and the Department  of Social affairs met on Thursday in preparation for an expected  influx of displaced people.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a UK-based  organization that tracks the war, said clashes in Kobani erupted  between Islamic State militants and the Kurdish YPG militia for  a second day on Friday.       (Reporting by Sylvia Westall; Editing by Dominic Evans)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:54:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paul McCartney Delivers Show-Stopping Charleston Tribute In Columbia, South Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47971cb7/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cpaul0Emccartney0Echarleston0Etribute0In0I7668660A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Performing in South Carolina on Thursday night, Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Famer </Description>
        <MainBody>Paul McCartney Photos and GIFs
of


Paul McCartney and Ringo Starr perform at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
Ringo Starr and Paul McCartney perform at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney, left, and Dave Grohl, accept the award for best rock song for Cut Me Some Slack" at the 56th annual Grammy Awards at Staples Center on Sunday, Jan. 26, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Matt Sayles/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney performs at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
British musician Paul McCartney drinks ahead of the Atlanta Hawks versus Brooklyn Nets NBA basketball game at the O2 Arena in London, Thursday, Jan. 16, 2014. (AP Photo/Kirsty Wigglesworth)
FILE - This Feb. 1964 file photo shows the Beatles' Paul McCartney on the set of the "Ed Sullivan Show," in New York. McCartney and Ringo Starr will attend the Recording Academy's Special Merit Awards ceremony, on Saturday, Jan. 25, 2014, where the Beatles will be honored with a lifetime achievement award, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/File)
FILE - In this Feb. 9, 1964 file photo, The Beatles, clockwise from top, Ringo Starr, John Lennon, George Harrison and Paul McCartney, perform on CBS' "Ed Sullivan Show" in New York. CBS is planning a two-hour special on Feb. 9, 2014, to mark the 50th anniversary of the Beatles groundbreaking first appearance on The Ed Sullivan Show. (AP Photo, file)
Paul McCartney and Ringo Starr perform at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney arrives with his band to give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15th. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
People gather to see Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15th. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney arrives with his band to give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Sir Paul McCartney and his new wife Nancy Shevell arrive at their north London home following their wedding at Westminster Registry Office. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney performing on stage. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney performs during the Super Bowl XXXIX Halftime Show at Alltell Stadium in Jacksonville, FL on February 6, 2005. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney performs during the Super Bowl XXXIX Halftime Show at Alltell Stadium in Jacksonville, FL on February 6, 2005. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney with his pregnant wife, Heather Mills McCartney, at the 3rd Annual Adopt-A-Minefield benefit in Los Angeles. The McCartneys hosted the event which raises money to clear minefields and provides aid to people injured by landmines.  (Photo credit: PA)
Sir Paul McCartney and his wife Heather Mills arriving for the Daily Mirror Pride of Britain Awards 2003 at the London Hilton Hotel on Park Lane.  * 28/05/03 The couple,  announced they were expecting their first child and were said to be "delighted" with the news.
British rock and roll legend Paul McCartney and his wife, Linda McCartney, mess around with 'Kiss Me Quick' hats at the seaside (Circa 1989).
Paul McCartney and wife Linda pause for a break during rehearsals at the Playhouse Theatre in London.
The Beatles perform on the "Ed Sullivan Show" in New York on February 9, 1964. From left, front, are Paul McCartney, George Harrison and John Lennon. Ringo Starr plays drums. (AP Photo)
Paul McCartney in The Beatles. (Photo credit: PA)
The Beatles released he album Abbey Road on this day in 1969.  EMI Group, the music company which numbers The Beatles and The Spice Girls among its artists, confirmed  that it had received an approach over a possible offer for the company.  (Photo credit: PA)
The Beatles, from left, Paul McCartney, Ringo Starr, John Lennon and George Harrison, are shown in this November 1963 photo. (AP Photo)
The Beatles in rehearsal at the Royal Command Performance. (Photo credit: PA)
The big-screen debut of Macca features Paul and his three bandmates (and his "grandfather") running around London, being chased by hordes of fans, as they attempt to film a performance for a television show. The movie was a parody on the Beatles staggering popularity.
The second comedy flick from the Fab Four follows the Beatles as they attempt to rescue Ringo from a cult who've chosen him as a sacrificial victim.
The last live performance by the Beatles (and arguably the greatest concert in music history), was recorded for the documentary, "Let It Be." Despite the band bickering and fighting on screen, the four still manage to pull off an entertaining, unannounced show on the top of the Apple records building in London, stopping traffic on the street below and prompting a shutdown by local police.
The film, named after the Beatles 1967 album, featured the Bee Gees' Barry, Robin and Maurice Gibb, along with Peter Frampton (Billy Shears), as the reformed Sgt. Pepper's band. The movie included covers of Beatles songs by other bands and celebrities (including this wacky version of "Maxwell's Silver Hammer" by comedian Steve Martin.)
The 1974 James Bond movie starring Roger Moore featured a theme song composed by Paul and Linda McCartney and performed by Macca's band Wings. The track is still one of the most popular themes in the 007 canon.
Similar to "A Hard Day's Night," this day-in-the-life musical starred Paul and Linda McCartney and Ringo Starr, as themselves. The plot revolves around Paul attempting to locate the masters to his new album, which have been stolen by an employee.
Wes Anderson's movies are no stranger to classic rock-heavy soundtracks. In his 2001 film, "The Royal Tenenbaums," Wes had the Mutato Muzika Orchestra cover the Beatles' "Hey Jude," (a song credited to Lennon-McCartney, but mainly written by Sir Paul, himself).
Though McCartney and the Beatles did not provide voice work to the characters (well, other than the songs), the film was eventually endorsed by the group, after having reservations due to the negative reception of their last project, the TV special "Magical Mystery Tour." Here, the song "All Together Now," written primarily by McCartney, plays to great effect as the crew begins turning the ship on.
Speaking of the "Magical Mystery Tour" movie, which debuted on BBC1 in 1967, it ended up being a critical disaster for the band. But, oh well, at least it gave us McCartney singing "A Fool on the Hill"...on a hill!
Though it got mixed reviews from critics, "Across the Universe" still attempts to pay tribute to the Beatles in a new and unique way. Julie Taymor's visually stunning musical is just one of the dozens of movies to reimagine the Beatles music. This scene features the McCartney-penned "I've Just Seen a Face," covered by actor Jim Sturgess
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:05:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The UN Charter at 70: Toward a Safer and Sustainable Future for We the Peoples</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4799269f/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cban0Ekimoon0Cthe0Eun0Echarter0Eat0E70A0Etowa0Ib0I76678460Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Long before I became Secretary-General, the United Nations occupied a special place in my life. I was six years old when the Korean War broke out. I have memories of my village in flames as my family sought refuge in nearby mountains. But another sight is even more lasting: the UN flag. We were saved from hunger by UN food relief operations; we received textbooks from UNESCO; and when we wondered whether the outside world cared about our suffering, the troops of many nations sacrificed their lives to restore security and peace. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Long before I became Secretary-General, the United Nations occupied a special place in my life.  I was six years old when the Korean War broke out.  I have memories of my village in flames as my family sought refuge in nearby mountains.  But another sight is even more lasting: the UN flag.  We were saved from hunger by UN food relief operations; we received textbooks from UNESCO; and when we wondered whether the outside world cared about our suffering, the troops of many nations sacrificed their lives to restore security and peace.
I know from my childhood, and now from decades of public service, the immense difference the United Nations can make.  As we mark the anniversary of the adoption of the Organization's founding Charter on June 26, 1945 in San Francisco, my hope is that the human family will come together with greater determination to work for a safer and more sustainable future for "we, the peoples," in whose name the Charter was drafted.
The United Nations at 70 can look back on a proud record of working with many partners to dismantle colonialism, triumph over apartheid, keep the peace in troubled places and articulate a body of treaties and law to safeguard human rights.  Every day, the United Nations feeds the hungry, shelters refugees and vaccinates children against polio and other deadly diseases.  Our relief workers brave remote and dangerous environments to deliver humanitarian assistance, and our mediators strive to find common ground between warring parties and peaceful solutions to grievances and disputes.  The United Nations was founded to prevent another world war, and it has succeeded in that core mission; despite grave setbacks, the past seven decades would surely have been even bloodier without the United Nations.
Yet we are keenly aware that today's landscape is scarred by conflict, exploitation and despair.  At least 59.5 million people have fled their homes - more refugees, displaced persons and asylum-seekers than at any time since the end of the Second World War.  Violence against women blights all societies. At a time of pressing human needs, huge   amounts of money continue to be squandered on nuclear weapons and other destabilizing military arsenals. The consequences of climate change are ever more apparent - and have only just begun. And although the world said "never again" after the Holocaust, and again after genocides in Rwanda and Srebrenica, we continue to witness atrocious crimes by violent extremists and others.
New powers have emerged since the representatives of 50 nations gathered to draft the Charter, and membership in the Organization has grown to 193.  Globalization, urbanization, migration, demographic shifts, technological advances and other seismic developments continue to remake our societies and transform international relations.  Yet the Charter's vision of a world of peace, and the values enshrined in the text - dignity, equal rights, tolerance and freedom - remain touchstones for people everywhere.
The 70th anniversary falls in a year of potentially momentous decisions on our common future.  Countries are shaping what we hope will be an inspiring new sustainable development agenda and moving towards a meaningful agreement on climate change.  Our goal is transformation: we are the first generation that can erase poverty from the earth - and the last that can act to avoid the worst impacts of a warming world.
As the distinctions between the national and the international continue to fall away, challenges faced by one become challenges faced by all, sometimes gradually but often suddenly. With our fates ever more entwined, our future must be one of ever deeper cooperation - nations united by a spirit of global citizenship that lives up to the promise of the Organization's name.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:49:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rebuilding U.S. policy post-Obama</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4796170a/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Craghida0Edergham0Crebuilding0Eus0Epolicy0Epost0Ib0I7668150A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Raghida Dergham</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Raghida Dergham
http://alhayat.com/Opinion/Raghida-Dergham/9649015/%D8%A5%D8%B9%D8%A7%D8%AF%D8%A9-%D8%A8%D9%86%D8%A7%D8%A1-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%B3%D9%8A%D8%A7%D8%B3%D8%A9-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%A3%D9%85%D9%8A%D8%B1%D9%83%D9%8A%D8%A9-%D8%A8%D8%B9%D8%AF-%D8%A3%D9%88%D8%A8%D8%A7%D9%85%D8%A7
As part of the brainstorming sessions in US intellectual and political circles, much is being said about how the United States could coexist with the Islamic Republic of Iran when it is radically empowered under a final nuclear deal and an upgraded bilateral relationship like the one being sought by the Obama administration. One of the clear consequences of Obama's insistence on a deal with Tehran is perpetuating unprecedented division in the United States: One faction focuses on appeasement of Iran considering that there is no alternative to a nuclear deal, even if it is full of loopholes, and that American-Iranian rapprochement will co-opt the mullahs of Iran, embolden moderates, rein in hardliners, and undermine Iran's regional expansion plans. The other faction sees that the nuclear agreement will not curb the nuclear ambitions of the Iranian theocracy, and that at best, it would delay an Iranian nuclear bomb by a decade. This faction also believes that lifting the sanctions on Iran would practically allow it to execute its nuclear plans, which would launch a nuclear arms race in the Gulf and invalidate the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT). This factions sees that the primary beneficiary of such an outcome would not be the moderate forces but the Revolutionary Guards, they key sponsor of Iran's regional expansion from Iraq, Syria, and Lebanon to Yemen, establishing militias that undermine the states in these countries--mirroring the Islamic State group (ISIS) whose doctrine is the destruction of nation states in the Arab region to establish its caliphate.
The first faction embraces the US pivot away from traditional allies, including in the Arab region, and closer to Iran. It sees this as a wise policy, based on its interpretation of 9/11 which blames Arab actors for the terrorist attacks.
The second faction stresses that it was Iran and its allies that killed the largest number of Americans, and not the Arab countries or even al-Qaeda and ISIS. For this reason, senior members of the second faction want to redesign US policy in the Middle East post-Obama, and they have ideas worth pausing at as part of the necessary brainstorming that the Arab region must take part in.
Under the title "The realignment of the Arab region in the international arena: Beyond politics, economics, and security threats", an Arab-regional-international workshop will be held in October to discuss the options available and come up with recommendations on how to overcome various challenges. The Beirut Institute, an Arab think-tank founded by the author of this article, will convene the Beirut Institute Summit in Abu Dhabi as an opportunity to come up with positive and practical ideas.
Some of the participants have already started submitting proposals, including figures closely involved in long-term US policymaking. The autumn scheduling is meant to coincide with the start of the US presidential election campaigns. The idea is that the Arab region must start thinking seriously about the future, instead of remaining fixated on what Barack Obama is doing.
By this autumn, the Arab region in all likelihood will have to start accepting the new reality of the American-Iranian relationship built by Barack Obama.  And regardless of who the next president will be, be it a Democrat or a Republican, US policy in the Middle East will be shaped by the ties with Iran and the putative nuclear deal and its implementation.
The American strategist who was involved in decision-making for decades believes rebuilding the US Middle East policy post-Obama is not difficult, and says this will depend on three things the new US president will have to do:
First, reestablishing the alliance with Egypt, not just verbally, but also by doubling US military aid to $3 billion a year and inviting President Sisi to the White House, to reaffirm the Camp David accords and restore defensive ties. This alone, he says, can reassure Egypt and stop it from seeking alternative partners including Russia. This, he argues, cannot be achieved as long as there are American restrictions on Egypt. Egypt is crucial in the war on ISIS, especially in Libya, and is a key partner in broader US-Arab relations, especially in the light of the firm strategic alliance among Egypt, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates.
Second, Libya needs an intervention similar to the NATO-led intervention in the past, in support of the legitimate government in Tobruk. Hesitation and complacency will allow ISIS and similar extremist groups in Libya to grow and threaten other North African nations. The positions of Saudi Arabia, the UAE, and Egypt must get real support from Washington, and there is no option but to defeat the Tripoli-based government and ISIS in Libya. This requires supporting Khalifa Haftar's forces, which are fighting both al-Qaeda and ISIS.
Third, always according to the US strategist, political and military decisions concerning Kurdistan should be made: Sending military aid directly to Erbil and not via Baghdad, and declaring that the United States does not mind for Kurdistan to export oil and even welcome Kurdish oil in US energy markets, as this would help Kurdistan fund its war with ISIS.
These are the views of veteran US policymaker, meant to prevent the deterioration of US influence in the Middle East. Some may agree with them, others may not, but they are strategic ideas and not just a diagnosis followed by surrender. And this is exactly what's needed: Pragmatic ideas to take US policy into a new approach following recent shifts in its policy.
Some may protest the idea of allowing the Kurds to secede from Iraq, which is implicit in the qualitative shift in US-Kurdish relations. In fact, the moderates are in Sulaymaniyah as they are in Amman, and a million Kurds have been displaced. There is a need for the Arab countries, led by Saudi Arabia, to reassess. Kurds in the Arab region as part of the Arab fabric just like Shiite Arabs are. It is time for a new and radically different relationship with both components, and it is crucial to correct the impression that only Sunni Arabs are Arabs as in the Saudi perception. Kurds and Shiites in the Arab countries are an essential part of the multiethnic, multiconfessional mosaic, and the Arab interest requires addressing this problem.
The Arab interest also requires practical ideas in light of the nuclear deal and the upgrading of the American-Iranian bilateral relationship. There is a dire need for a change in strategy from Yemen to Lebanon.
In Yemen, there is no alternative to choosing between an exit strategy, one that would secure the Saudi-Yemeni border, and escalating militarily to secure Aden, Hodeidah, and Taiz, with measures in Sanaa. The options boil down to securing the cities and gradually clawing back territory, or withdrawing from Yemen in an organized international framework supported by a Marshall plan to rescue Yemen economically and humanitarianly. The aerial bombardment campaigns will not achieve anything more, and it would be best to reduce air strikes and focus them as part of a new strategy.
In Syria, the Kurds do have a place in a new military strategy based on bringing the Kurdish forces together with moderate rebel forces. This, in turn, would require a shift in how Syria is dealt with. The Gulf countries need to think profoundly about the subject, especially in light of the possible lifting of the sanctions on Iran.
Economists speak of a golden age in Iran if the sanctions are lifted under a nuclear deal. They say Iran's oil exports could increase from 1 million barrels per day to 2 million barrels, worth $75 million a day or $2.2 billion a month. This would be enough cash for the Revolutionary Guard to finance its plans. The Revolutionary Guard already used Iraq's budget to finance its war in Syria in the past, when former Iraqi PM Nuri al-Maliki made the Iraqi treasury the equivalent to an ATM to finance the adventures of the Revolutionary Guard in Syria.
After the sanctions are lifted, Tehran will be able to pump money not only into its war in Syria, but also into Hezbollah in Lebanon, which in turn will radically alter the path and fate of Lebanon. Since Lebanon is in a state of complete vacuum, Hezbollah would be able to impose its demands there.
ISIS is being used as a pretext in Lebanon, since Hezbollah and ISIS are fighting in Syria. But if the Arab strategy wants to be wise, it must give Lebanon due attention before it is too late. Because while ISIS wants Damascus and Baghdad, and not Beirut, it could be lured into Lebanon. Losing Lebanon to Hezbollah or ISIS would be a major loss for Arab strategy and for the United States, whether under Obama or a new occupant of the White House.
The Obama administration does not want to pay attention to such "trivial" issues standing in its way towards a legacy represented by a deal with Iran. The administration is in a willful coma, it seems.
However, the United States is not bound by its administration. True, major US policies are developed in their broad outlines for the long term on a strategic basis, and various administrations implement them with some changes here or amendments there. However, policies are not detached from reality, and all this shapes decision-making. For this reason, it is possible to see institutions operating for years and decades to shape decision making.
Think-tanks and workshops are part of the dynamic of influencing strategic decision-making, which is what the Arab region needs.
The picture appears bleak in the context of the nuclear deal with Tehran. Ali Khamenei has dictated seven near-impossible conditions he dubbed "red lines". These could be part of the art of negotiations but they could lead to detonating the entire nuclear talks.
Logically, there is no room today for an agreement. Khamenei made it clear that Tehran insists on having the US and international sanctions lifted as soon as a deal is concluded, before Iran dismantles any nuclear capabilities. He said nuclear research would not be frozen and military sites would be off-limits. As for the issue of reimposing sanctions in the event Tehran fails to abide by its commitments, Russia and China will be there to guarantee any such bid would be vetoed.
But politically, it seems illogical that we have reached this point in the negotiations only for them to fail. Ultimately, it is more important to develop strategies in preparation for any outcome. Once again, an Arab collective brainstorming is crucial and urgent.
This article was translated from Arabic by Karim Traboulsi
Follow Raghida Dergham on Twitter: www.twitter.com/raghidadergham
More:
Click here to view Conversations
Conversations
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:32:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As Debt Deal Looms, Greeks Dream Big</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47952a08/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Cdebt0Edeal0Egreek0Edreams0In0I766620A0A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Greek leaders work around the clock to negotiate a new bailout deal with their creditors, ordinary Greeks remain anxious about what lies ahead. </Description>
        <MainBody>As Debt Deal Looms, Greeks Dream Big
Posted:
reddit
As Greek leaders work around the clock to negotiate a new bailout deal with their creditors, ordinary Greeks remain anxious about what lies ahead.
The Huffington Post spoke to two Greek citizens with very different political views and very different hopes and expectations about a forthcoming deal. While both are deeply concerned about the outcome of the deal, they have dreams for a brighter future for Greece that go far beyond the events of the coming weeks.
Parina Stiakaki, 66, is a translator living in Athens. Stiakaki used to translate Greek business and stock market materials into English, but in the past few years, all of her work has dried up. Her only source of income now is the residential properties that she owns. Because many of her renters can no longer pay their rent, and she refuses to throw them out, Stiakaki still operates at a loss. She estimates that she has to withdraw 5,000 euros a year from her life savings in order to pay her bills. Despite her negative income, Stiakaki says she's still paying income taxes, because the government now counts the value of her house and car as income.
Stiakaki has applied for her state pension, but she's not expecting to receive it anytime soon. If I get one at all, it wont be for another year and a half, she said. There is currently a backlog of 400,000 pension applications, according to Greek government estimates .
Still, Stiakaki considers herself lucky. She has two grown sons who support themselves and their families without her help. And she knows many people who have not been so fortunate.
I have friends who cannot pay their taxes anymore and are worried about having their houses repossessed, she said. People are skimping on food, even.
There used to be a 70-year-old man living down the road from Stiakaki. He was a civil engineer, she remembers. He shot and killed himself as the recession was beginning. Stiakaki believes that the man had debts he couldn't pay, and that the suicide was at least partly a response to his economic distress.
Stiakaki voted for Greece's Syriza party in January because she wanted relief from economic austerity.
Now she says that any deal that asks Greeks to endure even higher taxes and smaller government benefits must include debt relief as well -- or it is not worth taking at all. She would prefer a "Grexit," or Greek exit from the euro, to a deal that puts the country in such a position.
It is inevitable that after six months or a year, Greece will leave the euro, she said. This is a useless exercise. It will mean more pain and suffering and no problem will be fixed.
Polling shows that Stiakakis support for a Grexit puts her in the minority among Greeks -- and even among Syriza supporters. But Stiakaki, who has a bachelors degree in economics from the London School of Economics and who maintains a blog on Greek politics , believes that restoring Greeces control of its currency is the best of many bad options.
The choice is between a slow, lingering death, Stiakaki said, referring to additional budget tightening, and a jolt that will be hard and bring a change in the economic outlook.
In my personal opinion, it would be very tough for a few months and maybe a year, she explained. But after that, the economy would get growing. We would go back to the drachma and devalue our currency.
This isn't the prevailing view among economists, although some -- including the Nobel laureate Paul Krugman -- share the same outlook as Stiakaki, arguing that a cheaper currency could allow Greece to recover economically.
And Stiakaki is ready to vote against Syriza to make a Grexit happen.
If Syriza would run as the party it is today, then I would still vote for them, she said. If it splits, I would side with the party in favor of leaving the euro.
As HuffPost has reported , the scenario Stiakaki describes -- in which a deal freighted with concessions prompts Syrizas more radical factions to revolt against Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras -- is not unlikely.
Like Stiakaki, Yannis Koutsomitis, 50, a television and film producer living in Crete, saw his livelihood destroyed by the 2008 financial crisis and the prolonged recession since then. Koutsomitis had enjoyed success and recognition for his production of TV primetime dramas. In 2008, he won the Greek equivalent of an Emmy for producer of the year for his work on the popular Greek series " Matomena Homata ."
Koutsomitis award-winning work was also his last in the industry to date.
The TV sector has suffered a devastating crisis, Koutsomitis said. There is almost no primetime drama produced in Greece anymore.
Koutsomitis' partner is a lawyer, and when Koutsomitis stopped getting work after the economic downturn, the two of them were able to rely on her income for a while. In 2010, Koutsomitis started blogging about post-crisis Greek politics and economics, and he now earns some money as a political analyst for Germanys NTV and BBC Radio. Koutsomitis and his partner support a son from one of the partners previous relationships. Koutsomitis parents are financially independent, living off combined pension benefits of 1,500 euros a month.
Koutsomitis and Stiakaki are both educated professionals whose careers were disrupted by Greeces economic turmoil. But they've drawn very different conclusions from the crisis.
A centrist on the Greek political spectrum, Koutsomitis is angry with Syriza for spending five months negotiating with Greeces creditors only to run out the clock in the final weeks over differences on pensions and a value-added tax increase that were known to be the main sticking points all along.
Koutsomitis does not share Stiakaki's hostility toward the countrys European creditors. Actually, he's of the view that they saved the Greek economy after its banks teetered on the brink of collapse, and he doesn't wholly blame the country's persistent economic malaise on the budget tightening the creditors have imposed. In fact, Koutsomitis thinks that structural problems like clientelism and a culture of social immobility will prevent unemployment from falling below 15 percent even after private sector demand recovers.
As a result, Koutsomitis believes the reforms demanded by creditors provide an opportunity to make Greece more economically competitive. He said he'd like to see a deal that institutes very thorough reform of the pension system. He'd also like to see defense cuts and other government spending cuts in exchange for debt relief.
The Greek government, as led by Syriza, has put up greater resistance to the idea of pension cuts than to any of the creditors other demands. Tsipras has claimed that additional cuts to the already reduced benefits will "only cause a further worsening of the already dramatic social situation." Tsipras and others point to the pension systems role as an all-purpose, multigenerational safety net at a time of high unemployment.
But Koutsomitis argues that current proposals would shield the poorest pensioners by guaranteeing a minimum pension.
And despite some measures limiting early retirement, he says that the pension system is still overly generous toward people who do not need the help.
The problem is that there are many, many people on pensions of 1,000 euros or more in their 50s, he said -- the implication being that people of that age ought to be working or at least looking for work.
As for taxes, Koutsomitis said he does not mind raising rates on wealthy individuals. But he objects to Syrizas proposed corporate tax hike, which he said could cause struggling Greek companies to collapse or move overseas.
Still, unlike Stiakaki, Koutsomitis considers leaving the euro a nonstarter. To his mind, a deal that lacks any of the components he prefers would still be better than no deal and a Grexit.
Nonetheless, Koutsomitis shares Stiakakis dream of a Greece that one day has more control over its destiny.
He hopes that five years from now, the country will have recovered enough economically to begin having a conversation about what kind of society it wants to be.
Some people want socialism and some want free-market economy, he said. Currently, he argues, Greece has neither model, but instead has a very odd mixture of clientelism and a state-run economy.
It has to be an open debate in the society, he said.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:55:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Julian Assange: Mainstream Media Rife With Censorship</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47950868/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cseungyoon0Elee0Cjulian0Eassange0Emedia0Ecensorship0Ib0I76666540Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Seung-yoon Lee, CEO and co-founder of Byline, recently conducted a rare exclusive three-hour interview with Julian Assange in Embassy of Ecuador, London. The interview has been serialized into three parts.
In part two of the series, Assange reflects on media -- how it works, whether there is hope in new media models and citizen journalism and whether he prefers Rupert Murdoch or Eric Schmidt. Read the original interview here . Read part one here .
Seung-Yoon Lee (SY): You have worked with the mainstream media throughout the world in releasing documents. How did your experience of cooperating with mainstream media influence your perspective on them? In retrospect, if you could go back, would you still choose to work with them?
Julian Assange (JA): We have contracts with more than a hundred media organizations around the world, still. But it varies among mainstream press outlets. For example, the one in Pakistan can be great on issues outside of Pakistan. Issues inside Pakistan are different. It's the same for Russia Today, outside Russia and Ukraine, it can be great, but inside Russia is a different story and through this we need to understand the political and economic dynamics that mean the organization might be trustworthy on one matter and not trustworthy on another matter.
"In my experience the best journalists are those that predominantly work for one news institution but also have one foot in others, or one foot in academia."
If we look at the big players in the Western press, such as the international New York Times or the BBC, they are all highly compromised organizations in terms of geopolitics, and in terms of their relationships with their own countries. It would be nice to live in a world where people didn't have to deal with an organization that is not compromised in any manner whatsoever, but we don't live in that world. People have to use cars and they have put to petrol in their cars, and that petrol is made by Shell or BP.
In order to get things done it is necessary, unfortunately -- or perhaps even fortunately -- to make compromises. But as long as you understand that you're making a compromise, and as long as you understand the whole trade-off and exactly what that trade-off is and that you are balancing a number of different players with each other, you are not becoming dependent. And that's a good rule not just for media startups, but also for journalists themselves. In my experience the best journalists are those that predominantly work for one news institution but also have one foot in others, or one foot in academia. They have a sense that they have another outlet, and that tends to keep their "home" newspaper honest as well.
For example, look at the James Risen case. James Risen was a New York Times reporter who had information about NSA air surveillance back in 2003. The NYT sat on that for 18 months, intentionally, across the U.S. election. Risen informed the NYT that he was going to publish this book containing that information , and as a result the NYT then published his story.
SY: How much self-censorship and/or censorship goes on in the mainstream media?
JA: It's almost all censorship. The majority of censorship is selectivity, so it is the decision to do one story and not another, to interview one person and not another. That's the way that the bulk of censorship occurs, and those decisions are made as a result of personal or shared experience. And what happens if you don't tow the party line? People are compromised, and their employment opportunities or social opportunities...
It's obvious if you think about it. Let's take a society like the United Kingdom -- about 70 million people. A study was done on news stories in the U.K., where the majority are generated by newspapers and picked up by TV networks. There are around 70 news stories each day in the U.K., on different subjects. That's one news story per million people in the U.K., per day. But just consider your own family or your own business, and how many interesting rumors or stories you pick up in your own life. The idea that there is only one interesting story per million people is absurd.
Take a country like Iceland, with a population of 300,000. That would suggest that the Icelandic press should only publish one story every three days. So that whittling down from where things would be if the U.K. was proportionate to Iceland -- throwing out all those stories that would naturally be there -- that is done by selectivity, which is performed according to political and psychological biases, and the fears of the journalists and editors concerned.
Here's a hard example. In the U.K. they have something called the Defence Advisory Board [ The Defence, Press and Broadcasting Advisory Committee ]. It has monthly meetings with the editors of the newspapers, and they have agreements about what should and shouldn't be published.
"It would be nice to live in a world where people didn't have to deal with an organization that is not compromised in any manner whatsoever, but we don't live in that world."
SY: Our previous interviewee Noam Chomsky argued in "Manufacturing Consent" that the primary role of the mass media is to mobilize public support for the elite interests. I asked him if anything has changed since then to the media landscape. He said , "as far as we can see, the basic analysis we made is essentially unchanged," despite the mainstream perception that the Internet has given rise to citizen journalism and undermined the power of the traditional "manufacturers of consent". Obviously, WikiLeaks has done a lot on this front, but do you think Chomsky's view is relevant today?
JA: It's still true in so far as how Chomsky was talking about the relationship between successful large organizations and domestic populations. It is no longer true in all respects. National media or established media organizations principally based in one territory are now able to project their view of the world onto other territories. There are examples like Russia Today or CCTV. And many national newspapers that have a large following outside their own territory are gearing their content to maximize the power of national elites. They espouse positions that undermine the power of national elites in other countries. That's an important development for the mainstream press --internationalization of readership.
SY: You're talking about Al Jazeera, CCTV, Russia Today and so on?
JA: They are the big ones in terms of impact, but national newspapers which are geared toward domestic populations are nonetheless still often read internationally now. So while their content is not pushed on other populations through marketing, nonetheless people are able to read them through Internet recommendations. I've seen that phenomenon producing important results. For example, WikiLeaks has an international readership in English. The other way things have changed is -- and I don't mean social media per se here -- the increasing ability for individuals to communicate with each other outside their own regions. Information has been obtained and published through small publications, and it has then spread en masse through individual communication networks -- and happened rapidly, before censorship could be applied.
SY: Ferguson was reported through Twitter before being picked up by the press. . .
JA: You had RT going down there. The combination of social media and individuals talking about what was happening. It was through these individual networks and social networks, and then RT whipped it up and acted as an amplifier, to the point where the mainstream press felt they had to get onto the issue. They got on the issue predominantly to demonize it, and then eventually to co-opt certain elements. So basically like "bankers are bad, but the rest of the system is okay."
But it's also a time of great vibrancy for new publications, and for middle size startups like Vice, for instance. Vice has many problems -- Rupert Murdoch has bought a 5 percent stake, and 15 percent has gone off to one of the cable companies -- but nonetheless it is basically an organization that is more hungry for growth than it is for careful control of its content, and that's something that we're seeing in several hundred different publications around the world. Now, those publications will eventually be consolidated and integrated. Conde Nast has already done that with the previous generation, including Wired magazine, Reddit, the New Yorker online, etc. They have pulled them together and created an increasingly conservative organization. So these consolidations will happen. They will happen reasonably quickly because the Internet encourages economies of scale.
But each time we have a new technical platform -- for example, mobile phones or a change of web standards -- it tends to be the case that a new entrant who is not constrained by existing operations grows much faster. The problem is that some of the large organizations realize this as well. So if you look at Google, Google is actually an organization with very little innovation. It depicts itself as an innovative organization; it did improve the algorithmic efficiency of search engines. It was not, by any means the first search engine.
Nearly all the innovations that people think are Google's have come from acquisitions. YouTube was acquired , Android was acquired . Most of what people perceive to be Google innovations are actually Google acquisitions. So if you have the largest player gobbling up the new entrants then we aren't going to see that vibrancy as previously seen. Now, traditionally perhaps we would see antitrust or anti-monopoly laws used to prevent those kinds of acquisitions. However, there is no international antitrust law, because we are dealing with multinational companies that operate at scale across the whole Internet. There is no effective antitrust method to stop monopolization.
"What matters is whether it is done well. Very often it is not done well. But then, the standards in the mainstream press are appallingly low."
SY: What is your perspective on "citizen journalism"?
JA: The phrase is overplayed. But I think we should separate it into what I call "bystander journalism" and freelance journalism. Bystander journalism is when you happen to be in a place at a certain time and you take a photo of an event and report what you saw. But you usually don't do that. And the information just happens to be valuable. Especially photos and videos, which are harder to fake and therefore don't need any more external credibility. In the case of freelance journalism a person makes it their occupation, or part time occupation, to become an expert in some particular area, or an expert journalist in reporting about the world. And they can sell their work to newspapers.
I don't think this matters much. What matters is whether it is done well. Very often it is not done well. But then, the standards in the mainstream press are appallingly low.
SY: There was a comment I saw in your i nterview with John Pilger that you disclosed some materials to citizen journalists first but they didn't do anything. Why did you not rely on the so-called "citizen journalists"? Why did you rely on the traditional fourth estate like the Guardian and the New York Times instead of the new media players like bloggers and non-mainstream media outlets like new media and informal media?
JA: Back in 2007 when WikiLeaks was just starting, I knew from my previous experience that we could get leaks -- a lot of them. We could get a quality of information that could eclipse the research capacity of the mainstream press, and anyway the mainstream press had biases. And so we threw our material open to all these citizen journalists and commenters.
The result was that generally, citizen journalists were completely useless, with some exceptions. The market has improved, to be fair, but I realized that you have to look at the economy of why people do things. Most "citizen journalists" are surviving on surplus labor. They have something else that subsidizes them, whether employment or a pension, or whatnot. And then they engage in this other activity. So you have to question why they do it. A lot of the reason seems to be the desire to build a name for themselves, or to demonstrate their political position to their peers. The easiest way of doing that is to see what's on the front page of the New York Times and, using more words, essentially say "I agree" or "I disagree." And because it's so cost effective in relation to the desired outcome, that's what is done. If you look at popular blog sites like Tumblr or Wordpress, or microblogs like Twitter, you actually see that the overwhelming majority of it is commentary on the mainstream press, and repeating and forwarding those stories from the mainstream press which people feel back up their position. They can position themselves amongst their peers by taking a position.
We published a fantastic document on the War on Iraq, a classified document from the U.S. Army Ground Intelligence Center on the assault against Fallujah in 2004 . Fallujah even at that time was viewed to be the worst example of the U.S. occupation of Iraq. It was an example of the clearest violation of the laws of war, and so it was a hot topic and here was proof of what had happened that day, written up by the U.S. military themselves. It was a document which I did not need to analyze, and that WikiLeaks staff did not need to analyze to great depth. It was easy to read, and it was on a controversial topic that a lot of people said they were interested in. So we thought we could put it out there and inevitably a lot of people would write about it, because many, many people were talking about Fallujah and saying how bad it was. The result was nothing. No one did a thing. It wasn't until we contacted some professors who were friends of ours, and a friend in one of the news wires, that it got a proper write-up and analysis. That's because it takes time and effort. And if you can position yourself amongst your peers without taking any time and effort, and that's what your goal is, then why would you bother?
"In some sense, it's not Rupert Murdoch that controls the distribution of news, but Eric Schmidt and Mark Zuckerberg."
SY: What do you think the potential of crowdfunding to democratize the media landscape? Most recently, investigative journalists like John Pilger have used the method to finance their reporting. By freeing journalists and media organizations from the influence of media moguls and advertisers, do you think it can open the window for independent journalism?
JA: I hope so! But it hasn't been determined yet. In the case of WikiLeaks, we have mostly been crowdfunded throughout our whole history. However WikiLeaks has a worldwide base reporting on high-profile conflicts. It's hard -- if we didn't have that worldwide base and publish in such scale, then we wouldn't break even through crowdfunding. So we have to say that there are some examples of where it has been done successfully. It may just be a matter of adjusting the parameters to increase the ease with which it can be done.
SY: This form of media will necessarily get rid of the "middle man" like editors and curators and connect the readers and journalists directly, and this is what Byline is doing. The only criterion for whether a journalistic project will be able to take place is whether readers want it or not. What's your thought on such form of media that takes out the middlemen like curators and editors?
JA: The more sources of funding there are for journalism, the better, because journalism is constrained by its funders and their particular political views, their worldview and their business interests. So the more types of funding we can get, be they crowdfunding for individual journalists; or some novel form of stock investment scheme; whether they are mutual societies; whether they are subscription or advertising-based funding models; or public journalism funded from tax revenues spent at the discretion of the government; or whether there is constitutional garnishing of tax funds for independent bodies, spent in accordance with population surveys. We need all these things to gain different perspectives.
SY: The analysis of Emily Bell, director at the Tow Center for Digital Journalism at Columbia Journalism School, is that the fourth estate has been killed by a few unaccountable Silicon Valley companies:
"News spaces are no longer owned by newsmakers. The press is no longer in charge of the free press and has lost control of the main conduits through which stories reach audiences. The public sphere is now operated by a small number of private companies, based in Silicon Valley."
In some sense, it's not Rupert Murdoch that controls the distribution of news, but Eric Schmidt and Mark Zuckerberg. Simply put, do you prefer Eric Schmidt to Rupert Murdoch?
JA: I would prefer neither. Google collects extensive amounts of information on every single person who uses the Internet. It tracks nearly every single web page you go to. Even if you think you are not using Google, you are, because those websites [you do visit] use Google. It collects information from Android phones in extraordinary detail on people's movements and interests -- and of course, everything they search for, and their emails if they use Gmail, and what videos they watch on YouTube.
"Google has decided a very important social policy, which is that there was not to be proper reportage of war."
Google's real business is the integration business. It's not a search business, it's not an advertising businesses -- it's an integration business. They take hundreds of sources of information across the world, they purchase startups that gained users and they integrate all this information to build up bigger, richer profiles on people, building it into a larger repository of information, which they then use to train their artificial intelligence algorithms. YouTube has become the largest collection of human video footage, which is being used to train Google's artificial intelligence algorithm, which will go into its drones. It has bought many companies that navigate the world, using material collected by Google maps and Android phones, so it's a massive integrationist project.
SY: But there are some people that can ask why this is bad. I mean, doesn't it help search what we want to?
JA: Philosophically, this is the tyranny of efficiency -- that which is more efficient must be good. But that is not true. If suddenly you go from one person having no weapons, to another person having a stick, to one person having a rifle, to another person having a gun, it's not necessarily an improvement.
Put that aside. Look at Google's increasing monopoly power -- Google's geometrically increasing monopoly power. In terms of media, we've seen in the past 10 years a great flourishing as a result of disconnecting distribution from content production. That's what's really freed it up. The two things that really freed up the media landscape are the tremendous decrease in cost, and disconnecting distribution from content production. Google and Facebook and Twitter and AT&amp;T and Cable &amp; Wireless had been following that model over the last few years. In the last few years there has been vertical integration and increasing political control in content production and content distribution. For example, Facebook, and all these organizations, are increasingly mandating new sets of rules about what can be published and what cannot be published. And these rules are increasing in number with great rapidity. These form a new system of social laws, created by fiat, not produced by a parliament, not produced by democracy, and with no balancing power or judiciary. They are now applied to essentially everyone who uses the Internet.
Just two days ago, there was the issue with antiwar.com, a libertarian right-wing anti-war, anti-militarist website in the U.S.. They published many great essays in the past 10 years, including essays on the Abu Ghraib scandal. Google decided that they would not accept its advertising brokering services to appear on any webpage where there were photos of war, because they are gruesome. So Google has decided a very important social policy, which is that there was not to be proper reportage of war. By fiat.
Please stay tuned for the final part of the series, coming within the next two weeks. Byline thanks Alex Nunns (@alexnunns) for his assistance in editing this interview.
Close
Guantanamo Bay Revelations From WikiLeaks
of


As the New York Times reports, Mohammed Qahtani -- a Saudi believed to have been an intended participant in the Sept. 11 attacks -- was subject to coercive questioning and other abuses during his interrogation. The cables describe Qahtani as being leashed like a dog, sexually humiliated and forced to urinate on himself. His file says, "Although publicly released records allege detainee was subject to harsh interrogation techniques in the early stages of detention," his confessions "appear to be true and are corroborated in reporting from other sources."
As Le Monde is reporting, one "low-value" Iranian-Catholic detainee was kept in Guantanamo even after being deemed ready for release -- given his "cooperative nature" and in the interest of "possible financing relations" between Al Qaeda and traffickers. According to the cables, Abdul Majid Muhammed was deemed fit for release in 2002: "The detainee is not affiliated with Al Qaeda or the Taliban. He was involved in drug trafficking. It is unlikely that he represents a risk for the U.S. or its allies."
An Al Jazeera journalist was reportedly held at Guantanamo Bay for six years partially so he could be interrogated about the network Sami al-Hajj, a Sudanese national and Al Jazeera cameraman, was captured in Pakistan in late 2001. Though he was never convicted or even tried of any terrorist ties, al-Hajj was held until 2008 because interrogators wanted to find out more about "the al-Jazeera news network's training programme, telecommunications equipment, and newsgathering operations in Chechnya, Kosovo and Afghanistan, including the network's acquisition of a video of UBL [Osama bin Laden] and a subsequent interview with UBL," according to the cables.
Some detainees are described as ruthlessly violent in the documents. As the New York Times reports, one detainee said "he would like to tell his friends in Iraq to find the interrogator, slice him up, and make a shwarma (a type of sandwich) out of him, with the interrogator's head sticking out of the end of the shwarma." Another "threatened to kill a U.S. service member by chopping off his head and hands when he gets out," and informed a guard that "he will murder him and drink his blood for lunch. Detainee also stated he would fly planes into houses and prayed that President Bush would die."
As the Washington Post reports, the documents describe a major gathering of some of Al Qaeda's most senior operatives in early December 2001. They included Khalid Sheik Mohammed, the self-described mastermind of the Sept. 11 attacks; Abd al-Rahim al-Nashiri, the alleged planner of the USS Cole attack; and Abu Faraj al-Libbi, a key facilitator for bin Laden. After returning to Karachi, Mohammed "put together a training program for assassinations and kidnappings as well as pistol and computer training."
The leaked files indicate Khalid Sheikh Mohammed told Guantanamo Bay interrogators that Al Qaeda had hidden a nuclear bomb in Europe which will unleash a "nuclear hellstorm" if Osama bin Laden is captured or killed. The terror group also planned to make a 9/11 style attack on London's Heathrow airport by crashing a hijacked airliner into one of the terminals, the files showed.
The Washington Post reports Abd al-Rahim al-Nashiri, the alleged planner of the USS Cole attack, "received injections to promote impotence" to avoid being distracted by women, and "recommended the injections to others so more time could be spent on the jihad."
Gitmo detainees are reportedly assessed "high," "medium" or "low" in terms of their intelligence value, the threat they pose while in detention and the continued threat they might pose to the United States if released. As Reuters reports, most of the 172 remaining prisoners have been rated as a "high risk" of posing a threat to the United States and its allies if released without adequate rehabilitation and supervision.
Gitmo authorities named Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence agency a "terrorist organization" along with Hamas and other international militant networks, according to leaked documents. As the Associated Press reports, the ISI is part of a list that includes more than 60 international militant networks, as well as Iran's intelligence services, that  are "terrorist" entities or associations and say detainees linked to them "may have provided support to Al Qaeda and the Taliban, or engaged in hostilities against U.S. and coalition forces."
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:50:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escaped Giant Rhea Bird Can Disembowel A Human With One Strike</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4795086b/sc/32/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Crhea0Ebird0Eescape0In0I7666220A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police are warning residents to beware of a giant rhea bird that escaped into the countryside of Nottinghamshire, England, this week. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Police are warning residents to beware of a giant rhea bird that escaped into the countryside of Nottinghamshire, England, this week. The ostrich-sized bird reportedly fled a private collection in the area either Monday night or Tuesday morning.
"We are warning local people and particularly those with small children to be on their guard and not to approach the bird, which poses a very real threat to the public," police said .
Rheas, native to Brazil and Argentina , can reach heights of up to six feet, run 40 mph, and have sharp claws capable of disemboweling a human being with a single blow.
But bird expert David Lindo told the BBC that the rhea isn't as dangerous as people think, and is more likely to flee humans than to attack them.
"They're quite stealthy and they'll be running off, hiding into the bushes. ... They can melt into the countryside quite easily," Lindo said.
A fugitive rhea roamed the English countryside for two months in 2014. It was eventually shot and turned into gourmet sausages.
We can only hope this rhea will find its way home to its mate, reportedly pacing its enclosure in distress.
The mate of a rhea bird missing in Nottinghamshire is said to be pacing their field by herself http://t.co/a1hbLF2D2C pic.twitter.com/ySMwBOaZJM
 Sky News (@SkyNews) June 25, 2015
Also on The Huffington Post
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:35:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4794986e/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Cputin0Eobama0Ephone0Ecall0Eiran0In0I76671140Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS
Reuters
Updated:
06/25/2015  6:59 pm EDT
Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a session of the Civic Chamber at the Kremlin in Moscow on June 23, 2015. AFP PHOTO / POOL / SERGEI KARPUKHIN        (Photo credit should read SERGEI KARPUKHIN/AFP/Getty Images) | SERGEI KARPUKHIN via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.
"The leaders discussed the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria, and underscored the importance of continued P5+1 unity in ongoing negotiations to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon," the White House said.
Obama also told Putin that Russia needs to live to up to the terms of a ceasefire deal with Ukraine, "including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," the White House said.  (Reporting by Roberta Rampton)
Also on HuffPost:
Putin And The Night Wolves
of


In this Monday, Aug. 29, 2011 photo, then Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin, center left, and leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), right, ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia. (AP Photo/RIA Novosti, Alexei Druzhinin, POOL, file)
A picture taken on July 7, 2009, shows Vladimir Putin, then Russian Prime Minister, listening to the leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov (R), also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), during Putin's visit to the 'Night Wolves' biker club's  headquarters. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, as they ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia, Monday, Aug. 29, 2011. (AP Photo/Ivan Sekretarev, pool)
Vladimir Putin (C) poses for a photo with members of the 'Night Wolves' bikers' movement after watching a friendly football match between of Serbia's FC Crvena Zvezda Belgrade and Russia's FC Zenit St Petersburg junior teams at Marakana Stadium in Belgrade, on March 23, 2011. (ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/AFP/Getty Images)
Russian President Vladimir Putin (C) and Night Wolves Moscow Bikers club leader Alexander 'Khirurg' Zaldostanov (L) attend the opening of the Barmaley Fountain during a wider ceremony to remember the 40, 000 people who died on this day in 1942, when the city was bombed by Nazi Germany, on August 23, 2013 in Volgograd, Russia. (Sasha Mordovets/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (R) speaks with a biker as he takes part in the 16th annual motorbike festival held by 'The Night Wolves' youth organization in the southern Russian town of Novorossiysk, on August 29, 2011. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (L) hands over a medal to the leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, during Putin's meeting with members of the Military History Society in the Novo-Ogaryovo residence outside Moscow, on March 14, 2013. (MIKHAIL KLIMENTYEV/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin pays a surprise visit to the headquarters of the 'Night Wolves' biker club in Moscow on July 7, 2009. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, pose for a press attending a meeting of motorbikers at their camp at Gasfort lake near Sevastopol in Ukraine's Crimea Peninsula, Saturday, July 24, 2010.  (AP Photo/Alexander Zemlianichenko, Pool)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:35:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47949870/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Cputin0Eobama0Ephone0Ecall0Eiran0In0I7667110A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS
Reuters
Updated:
06/25/2015  6:59 pm EDT
Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a session of the Civic Chamber at the Kremlin in Moscow on June 23, 2015. AFP PHOTO / POOL / SERGEI KARPUKHIN        (Photo credit should read SERGEI KARPUKHIN/AFP/Getty Images) | SERGEI KARPUKHIN via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.
"The leaders discussed the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria, and underscored the importance of continued P5+1 unity in ongoing negotiations to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon," the White House said.
Obama also told Putin that Russia needs to live to up to the terms of a ceasefire deal with Ukraine, "including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," the White House said.  (Reporting by Roberta Rampton)
Also on HuffPost:
Putin And The Night Wolves
of


In this Monday, Aug. 29, 2011 photo, then Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin, center left, and leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), right, ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia. (AP Photo/RIA Novosti, Alexei Druzhinin, POOL, file)
A picture taken on July 7, 2009, shows Vladimir Putin, then Russian Prime Minister, listening to the leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov (R), also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), during Putin's visit to the 'Night Wolves' biker club's  headquarters. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, as they ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia, Monday, Aug. 29, 2011. (AP Photo/Ivan Sekretarev, pool)
Vladimir Putin (C) poses for a photo with members of the 'Night Wolves' bikers' movement after watching a friendly football match between of Serbia's FC Crvena Zvezda Belgrade and Russia's FC Zenit St Petersburg junior teams at Marakana Stadium in Belgrade, on March 23, 2011. (ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/AFP/Getty Images)
Russian President Vladimir Putin (C) and Night Wolves Moscow Bikers club leader Alexander 'Khirurg' Zaldostanov (L) attend the opening of the Barmaley Fountain during a wider ceremony to remember the 40, 000 people who died on this day in 1942, when the city was bombed by Nazi Germany, on August 23, 2013 in Volgograd, Russia. (Sasha Mordovets/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (R) speaks with a biker as he takes part in the 16th annual motorbike festival held by 'The Night Wolves' youth organization in the southern Russian town of Novorossiysk, on August 29, 2011. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (L) hands over a medal to the leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, during Putin's meeting with members of the Military History Society in the Novo-Ogaryovo residence outside Moscow, on March 14, 2013. (MIKHAIL KLIMENTYEV/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin pays a surprise visit to the headquarters of the 'Night Wolves' biker club in Moscow on July 7, 2009. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, pose for a press attending a meeting of motorbikers at their camp at Gasfort lake near Sevastopol in Ukraine's Crimea Peninsula, Saturday, July 24, 2010.  (AP Photo/Alexander Zemlianichenko, Pool)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
