<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Huffingtonpost">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:05:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant Boat Sinks Off Coast Of Greece</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e83579/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cmigrant0Eboat0Esinks0Egreece0In0I77431340Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS, Greece (AP) — Greek authorities have launched a search and rescue operation in the eastern Aegean after a sailboat carrying dozens of migrants sank between the small islands of Agathonisi and Farmakonisi, near the Turkish coast.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant Boat Sinks Off Coast Of Greece
Posted:
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:01:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beach Hotel In Tunisia's Sousse Attacked By Gunmen, At Least 7 Killed</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4799660f/sc/10/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Ctunisia0Esousse0Ehotel0Eattack0In0I7670A3420Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS, June 26 (Reuters) - At least seven people have been killed in an attack on a tourist hotel in the Tunisian beach resort of Sousse, an interior ministry spokesman said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Beach Hotel In Tunisia's Sousse Attacked, At Least 27 Killed
Posted:
An official at Tunisia's Interior Ministry said on Friday that at least 27 people were killed in an attack on hotels in the beach town of Sousse, Reuters reports. The official added that foreigners were among those killed.
This is breaking news. Check back later for updates.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:47:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosion At Mosque In Kuwait City Kills Several</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47996616/sc/38/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Ckuwait0Ebomb0In0I7669840A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Explosion At Mosque In Kuwait City Kills Several
| By                                                                      By HUSSAIN AL-QATARI
Updated:
24 minutes ago
A Kuwaiti man reacts at the site of a suicide bombing that targeted the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City. AFP PHOTO / YASSER AL-ZAYYAT        (Photo credit should read YASSER AL-ZAYYAT/AFP/Getty Images) | Getty
reddit
DUBAI, June 26 (Reuters) - Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for a suicide attack on a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait that killed or wounded several people, according a statement posted on social media.
The statement identified the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said the target was a "temple of the rejectionists" - a term used by the Islamist militant group to refer to Shi'ite Muslims - and said dozens were killed or wounded.  (Reporting by Omar Fahmy, writing by Sami Aboudi; editing by John Stonestreet)
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:24:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jon Stewart Has A Blast With GOP Response To Pope's Climate Change Encyclical</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798da45/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cjon0Estewart0Epope0Eclimate0Echange0In0I76693620Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Many of the Republican presidential candidates who normally aren't shy about bringing religion into politics had a sudden change of heart when Pope Francis released his </Description>
        <MainBody>Climate Change: Ten Beautiful Places Under Threat
of


The impacts of climate warming in Alaska are already occurring, experts have warned.   Over the past 50 years, temperatures across Alaska increased by an average of 3.4F.   Winter warming was even greater, rising by an average of 6.3F jeopardising its famous glaciers and frozen tundra.
The most fragile of Italian cities has been sinking for centuries. Long famous for being the city that is partially under water, sea level rise associated with global warming would have an enormous impact on Venice and the surrounding region.   The Italian government has begun constructing steel gates at the entrances to the Venetian lagoon, designed to block tidal surges from flooding the city. However, these barriers may not be enough to cope with global warming.
The West Antarctic Peninsula is one of the fastest warming areas on Earth, with only some areas of the Arctic Circle experiencing faster rising temperatures.   Over the past 50 years, temperatures in parts of the continent have jumped between 5 and 6 degrees F a rate five times faster than the global average.  A 2008 report commissioned by WWF warned that if global temperatures rise 3.6 degrees Fahrenheit (2 degrees Celsius) above pre-industrial averages, sea ice in the Southern Ocean could shrink by 10 to 15 percent.
The rapid decline of the world's coral reefs appears to be accelerating, threatening to destroy huge swathes of marine life unless dramatic action is swiftly taken, leading ocean scientists have warned.   About half of the world's coral reefs have already been destroyed over the past 30 years, as climate change warms the sea and rising carbon emissions make it more acidic.
The world's highest mountain range contains the planet's largest non-polar ice mass, with over 46,000 glaciers.   The mammoth glaciers cross eight countries and are the source of drinking water, irrigation and hydroelectric power for roughly 1.5 billion people. And just like in Antarctica, the ice is melting.
An expected 2C rise in the worlds average temperatures in the next decades will impact island economies such as the Maldives with extreme weather patterns and rising sea levels.
Over the last century, global warming has caused all Alpine glaciers to recede. Scientists predict that most of the glaciers in the Alps could be gone by 2050.   Global warming will also bring about changes in rain and snowfall patterns and an increase in the frequency of extreme meteorological events, such as floods and avalanches, experts have warned.
The Arctic is ground zero for climate change, warming at a rate of almost twice the global average.    The sea ice that is a critical component of Arctic marine ecosystems is projected to disappear in the summer within a generation.
Called the "epicenter of the current global extinction," by Conservation International, this smattering of more than 4,000 South Pacific islands is at risk from both local human activity and global climate change.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:36:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece To Consider Bank Closures And Capital Controls On Monday</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a4a3b7/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Cgreece0Edebt0Ecrisis0Ecapital0Econtrols0In0I76813440Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS/FRANKFURT, June 28 (Reuters) - Greece said it may impose capital controls and keep its banks shut on Monday after creditors refused to extend the country's bailout and savers queued to withdraw cash, taking Athens' standoff with the European Union and the International Monetary Fund to a dangerous new level.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece To Consider Bank Closures And Capital Controls On Monday
Reuters
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Updated:
10 minutes ago
A dinghy used by migrants lies on the shore on the island of Lesbos, early on June 18, 2015. (LOUISA GOULIAMAKI/AFP/Getty Images) | LOUISA GOULIAMAKI via Getty Images
reddit
ATHENS, Greece (AP)  Greek authorities have launched a search and rescue operation in the eastern Aegean after a sailboat carrying dozens of migrants sank between the small islands of Agathonisi and Farmakonisi, near the Turkish coast.
The Greek coast guard said six people were rescued by a Greek helicopter, and another 10 by the Turkish coast guard while between 17 and 21 people were missing after the boat sank Tuesday.
Those rescued by the Turkish crews said there had been between 33 and 37 people on board. It was not clear why the boat sank, or what the migrants' nationalities were.
Tens of thousands of migrants have made their way from the Turkish coast to Greek islands so far this year, hoping to make their way to more prosperous European Union countries.
Related on HuffPost:


Migrants crowd an inflatable dinghy as a rescue vessel of the Italian Coast Guard approaches them off the Libyan coast, April 22, 2015.
Migrants crowd an inflatable dinghy as a rescue vessel of the Italian Coast Guard approaches them, off the Libyan coast, April 22, 2015.
Rescued migrants disembark off the Italian Guardia Costiera vessel Fiorillo at the Sicilian harbour of Catania on April 24, 2015.
Migrants wait to disembark from the Italian Coast Guard ship Fiorillo, at the Catania harbor, Sicily, April 24, 2015.
Migrants wait to disembark from the Italian Coast Guard ship Fiorillo, at the Catania harbor, Sicily, April 24, 2015.
People lay candles at a vigil in Sliema, on the outskirts of Valletta, Malta, April 22, 2015.
Migrants crowd an inflatable dinghy as a rescue vessel of the Italian Coast Guard approaches them off the Libyan coast, April 22, 2015.
Fishermen look at the wreckage of a boat which was carrying dozens of immigrants in the eastern Aegean island of Rhodes, Greece.
People pause by the sea during a candle-lit vigil in Sliema, on the outskirts of Valletta, Malta, April 22, 2015.
Migrants from Nigeria relax by the sea after taking a swim on April 22, 2015 in Lampedusa, Italy.
Eric Joseph, 27, a migrant from Nigeria stands in a 'boat graveyard' by the port on April 22, 2015 in Lampedusa, Italy.
Amnesty International volunteers lie in a body bags on the beach on April 22, 2015 in Brighton, England.
A boy who was on board a boat carrying migrants which ran aground off the island of Rhodes, hugs a relative outside a Greek Coast Guard office at the southeastern island of Rhodes, April 22, 2015.
An asylum seekers holds a paper boat, with words written in Italian that read, 'Too many deaths, it is not good' during a demonstration in front of the Italian parliament in Rome, on April 23, 2015.
Maltese soldiers carry a coffin of a baby during the funeral of 24 migrants who died after a fishing boat carrying migrants capsized off the Libyan coast, on the helipad at Mater Dei Hospital in Malta, on April 23, 2015.
Asylum seekers living in Malta arrive at an interfaith funeral ceremony of 24 migrants on the helipad at Mater Dei Hospital in Malta on April 23, 2015.
Migrants wait to disembark from the Italian Navy vessel 'Chimera' in the harbor of Salerno, Italy, April 22, 2015.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:03:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spain Arrests Woman Suspected Of Recruiting Young Girls For ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e8357d/sc/3/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cspain0Eisis0Egirls0Erecruiter0In0I77430A920Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MADRID (AP) — Spanish police on Tuesday arrested a woman suspected of recruiting pre-teen girls and teenagers of both sexes to send to areas controlled by the Islamic State armed group in Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>Spain Arrests Woman Suspected Of Recruiting Young Girls For ISIS
| By                                                                      CIARAN GILES and ALAN CLENDENNING
Posted:
Updated:
13 minutes ago
A Syrian Kurdish woman sits by the window of a house in Suruc in Turkey's Sanliurfa province near the border with Syria on June 27, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images) | BULENT KILIC via Getty Images
reddit
MADRID (AP)  Spanish police on Tuesday arrested a woman suspected of recruiting pre-teen girls and teenagers of both sexes to send to areas controlled by the Islamic State armed group in Syria.
An Interior Ministry statement said the woman, a Spaniard, was arrested in the city of Arrecife on the Canary Island of Lanzarote.
The ministry said the woman maintained contact with Islamic State militants in Syria, including a facilitator who gave her orders for recruiting girls and arranging their travel to Syria.
Girls and teens who she helped get to Syria ended up being sexually exploited, did domestic work and work in hospitals and had roles policing women, the statement said. A few joined the Islamic State as combatants, the statement said.
Authorities did not specify how many people the woman was suspected of recruiting but said police have been investigating her since 2014 in a probe overseen by the National Court in Madrid.
Spain has arrested dozens of suspected jihadi militants and recruiters in recent years.
On Monday, police arrested two men in Madrid for alleged collaboration with Kurdish groups fighting in Syria and Iraq.
The two are suspected of having being trained to use arms and explosives and fight guerrilla warfare. The ministry said their actions affected Spain's national interests.
The ministry said it hoped to dissuade other militants from enlisting and possibly falling into the hands of the Islamic State group, which could use them for propaganda.
Earlier on HuffPost:


A man carries a girl as Syrians fleeing the war pass through broken down border fences to enter Turkish territory illegally, near the Turkish Akcakale border crossing in the southeastern Sanliurfa province, on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Syrian refugees ask for water in Akcakale at the Turkish border near the Syrian town of Tal Abyad, on June 13, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Syrian refugees ask for water in Akcakale at the Turkish border near the Syrian town of Tal Abyad, on June 13, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Thousands of Syrians run away from center Tal Abyad after they heard Kurdish fighters are coming at the Turkish Akcakale crossing gate in Sanliurfa province, on June 13, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A man believed to be  member of the Islamic State Islamist group  gestures to aske people to go back to the city centre of the Syrian town of Tal Abyad, as seen from Turkey at the Turkish crossing of Akcakale in the southeast Sanliurfa province, on June 13, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Syrians gather after leaving the city centre of the Syrian town of Tal Abyad, as seen from Turkey at the Turkish crossing of Akcakale in the southeast Sanliurfa province, on June 13, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Syrians fleeing fighting in the city centre of the Syrian town of Tal Abyad ask for water as they gather at a border crossing on the Syrian side of the border, as seen from Turkey at the Turkish crossing of Akcakale in the southeast Sanliurfa province, on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A Syrian woman cries after an airstrike hit the eastern part of the Syrian town of Tal Abyad at the Turkish crossing of Akcakale in the southeast Sanliurfa province, on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A man carries a girl as Syrians fleeing the war pass through broken down border fences to enter Turkish territory illegally, near the Turkish Akcakale border crossing in the southeastern Sanliurfa province, on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Syrians fleeing the war pass through broken down border fences to enter Turkish territory illegally, near the Turkish Akcakale border crossing in the southeastern Sanliurfa province, on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
Syrians fleeing the war pass through broken down border fences to enter Turkish territory illegally, near the Turkish Akcakale border crossing in the southeastern Sanliurfa province, on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
A picture taken from Akcakale, in Turkey shows black smoke billowing into sky after an airstrike during clashes in the eastern part of the Syrian town of Tal Abyad on June 14, 2015. (BULENT KILIC/AFP/Getty Images)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:59:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jewish Officials Protest Gas Chamber Art Installation In Poland</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e83580/sc/38/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cartur0Ezmijewski0Egame0Eof0Etag0In0I77430A840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WARSAW, Poland (AP) — Jewish officials are furious over a video installation at a Polish museum that shows naked men and women playing a game of tag in a gas chamber.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jewish Officials Protest Gas Chamber Art Installation In Poland
Posted:
Updated:
17 minutes ago
Lights illuminate the interior of the crematorium and gas chamber building at the Auschwitz I extermination camp on November 15, 2014 in Oswiecim, Poland. Ceremonies marking the 70th anniversary of the liberation of the camp by Soviet soldiers took place on January 27, 2015. Auschwitz was a network of concentration camps built and operated in occupied Poland by Nazi Germany during the Second World War. Auschwitz I and nearby Auschwitz II-Birkenau was the extermination camp where an estimated 1.1 | Christopher Furlong via Getty Images
reddit
WARSAW, Poland (AP)  Jewish officials are furious over a video installation at a Polish museum that shows naked men and women playing a game of tag in a gas chamber.
Efraim Zuroff, director of the Simon Wiesenthal Center in Jerusalem, called the exhibit at the Museum of Contemporary Art in Krakow "so offensive and so disgusting that we found it necessary to protest."
"Game of Tag," made in 1999 by Polish artist Artur Zmijewski, has for years been accused of violating the dignity of Holocaust victims.
In response to protests, the museum put it behind an enclosure with a warning.
But Zuroff and other Jewish officials say it isn't enough. He said it is "simply incomprehensible" that the video is being shown in Poland, where Nazi Germany killed millions of Jews and non-Jews.
Earlier on HuffPost:
20 Most Confusing Performance Art Pieces Of All Time
of


<<<<<<< HEAD
Let's hit the ground running, shall we? In 1972, Vito Acconci stunned audiences at New York's Sonnabend Gallery when he buried himself, so to speak, under a ramp in the art haven and proceeded to masturbate, using the sound of visitors walking above him to spark his "sexual fantasies." He also used a microphone to project his ongoing monologue -- basically, a series of very dirty thoughts -- to the entire room.  The performance was, as you might expect, pretty controversial. Despite the obvious sexual undertones, however, the piece had broader intentions. "The troubled personality Acconci acted out resembles the paranoid, dissociated characters in American films of the era: Gene Hackman in 'The Conversation,' Robert de Niro in 'Taxi Driver,'" The Guardian's Jonathan Jones wrote in 2002.
In 2011, New York-based performance artist Marni Kotak gave birth to a healthy baby boy during a live durational exhibition titled "The Birth of Baby X." To do so, she built a home birthing center at Microscope Gallery (see above), invited an audience (and a doula) to oversee the labor and created a collection of birth memorabilia including a 10-foot trophy awarded to Baby X for being born.  The performance didn't stop there, though. "She plans to re-conceptualize her role as a parent to baby Ajax into a work of performance art that will last for the rest of her life," The Washington Post explained.
In 2010, NYU professor and Iraq-born artist Wafaa Bilal surgically implanted a camera into the back of his head for an intense, year-long surveillance project. Inspired by his past experience as a refugee, "3rdi" sought to take a photo every 60-seconds and publish his images on the web, in effect, capturing all the things he "leaves behind" on a daily basis.  "I see myself as a mirror reflecting some of the social conditions that we ignore," he said to CNN. "This will expose the unspoken conditions we face... A project like this is meant to establish a dialogue about surveillance."
French artist Abraham Poincheval's 2014 performance stunt was simple: He slept in a dead bear for two weeks. Yup, equipped with a small amount of food and water (plus a light, cushion, reading material, kettle and toilet of some kind), he hibernated inside the remains of a hollowed-out bear stomach at the Muse de la Chasse et de la Nature while fans watched him on a live feed.  We're sure the small quarters were claustrophobia-inducing, but from the photos and footage, it sort of appears as though the man was just relaxing in a cramped shelter, which, from the inside, looked nothing like the insides of a bear. Did he push his "physical limits" in the process? Maybe, but what's compelling the audience to care?
In 2007, a courageous masochistic DC-based artist named Adrian Parsons circumcised himself on stage, in front of an audience, with a dull Swiss army knife. Then he proceeded to stuff the removed foreskin into a glory hole.  "I was trying to penetrate -- in, yes, a direct, literal way -- the gallery and the audience. I wanted to be organic shrapnel," he explained to HuffPost. "Shrapnel" is, in fact, the name of the performance.
Once upon a time a politically-minded performance artist named Rachel Mason decided to reenact Paul Rand's infamous 13-hour filibuster. But, in typical contemporary performance art fashion, she did so dressed as her bizarre alter ego, FutureClown. Horror ensued.  "I happened to hear about Rand Paul's 13-hour filibuster on the news and as a performer, it just struck a chord," she explained to HuffPost. "I perform a lot and think about what it is to simply perform for any duration. It just seemed like an epic durational performance piece... In a strange way I would say aesthetically it almost feels like a Gertrude Stein novel."
Clayton David Pettet, a 19-year-old from Central Saint Martins College of Arts and Design, found himself at the center of a media firestorm in 2013 when he announced his plan to have sex with an anonymous male partner... in front of a gallery audience. The project, called "Art School Stole My Virginity,' was inspired by his own experience as a 16-year-old student questioning the cultural significance of virginity. But what actually happened, was a little bit different than the show's tease.  The 120 audience members didn't end up watching Pettet engaged in his first "sexual" experience; instead, they were asked to "penetrate" the artist's mouth with a banana. "I think if people were expecting something else, it shows what they really wanted," the artist told Dazed Digital. "They didnt want an art piece, they wanted to see me have sex. If they came for the art, they wouldnt be as disappointed -- theyd know there were things to read between the lines for.
Ron Athey began his "Incorruptible Flesh" project back in 1996, but here's what his 2014 iteration looked like: The artist, naked and strapped to a metal examination table, transformed into a frightening corpse-like figure. The skin of his eyes pinned back, a baseball bat impaling him from behind, he invited viewers to "anoint" him with a white, foamy substance.  According to Grace Exhibition Space, Athey and his collaborators "studied the lives of saints, the relics and in particular, the display of the incorruptible bodies, most of which are wax sculptures with a corpse inside." He then adopted the incorruptible status as a representation of his HIV positive diagnosis, chock full of references to his childhood experiences with the Pentecostal church.
For some artists, creation is a labor of love. For others, it's literal labor, of the birthing variety. Swiss-born Milo Moire counts herself in the latter party, as evidenced by her 2014 performance piece, "Plop Egg Painting." In it, the female artist pushes paint eggs out of her vagina onto an empty canvas, taking Jackson Pollock's expressionist painting method to new and very nude heights.  "The 'PlopEgg Painting'...releases a loose chain of thoughts -- about the creation fear, the symbolic strength of the casual and the creative power of the femininity," a video description for the performance reads. "At the end of this almost meditative art birth performance the stained canvas is folded up, smoothed and unfolded to a symmetrically ref
In her 1964 performance "Meat Joy," Carolee Schneemann had eight underwear-clad men and women perform a partially choreographed routine, set to music, that involved writhing on the floor in a pile of paint, paper and lots of raw meat. Schneemann staged the strange happening in New York and London following the initial debut at the First Festival of Free Expression in Paris. It was described as an "erotic rite," simultaneously sensual and repellent.  "'Meat Joy' has such an intensive dynamic and carries all the themes of physicality, intensive improvisational contact and training with me," Schneeman recounted to HuffPost. "It carries itself through time and that's been very interesting to look at."
Feminist artist Casey Jenkins, a self-professed "craftivist," caught the attention of the pop performance art world in 2013 when she opted to knit from a ball of yarn wedged inside her vagina. "I'm spending 28 days knitting from wool that I've inserted in my vagina," the Melbourne-based artist stated in a video of the act. "Everyday I take a new skein of wool that's been wound so that it will unravel from the centre and I stick it up inside me... and then I pull out the thread and knit."  The work was called "Casting Off My Womb," and it incited a hilarious storm of Twitter outcry.
In 2013 Tilda Swinton napped at New York's Museum of Modern Art, showing up several times unannounced to sleep in a glass box somewhere in the famous art institute. Called "The Maybe," the work was a reprisal of an earlier Swinton napfest (circa 1995), and was, well, kind of boring.  MoMA's description of the work: An integral part of The Maybe's incarnation at MoMA in 2013 is that there is no published schedule for its appearance, no artist's statement released, no museum statement beyond this brief context, no public profile or image issued. Those who find it chance upon it for themselves, live and in real -- shared -- time: now we see it, now we don't.
From animal slaughters as religious sacrifices to faux crucifixions, Hermann Nitsch has long been known as a "cult provocateur" and the "Pope of Viennese Aktionism." Whether he was drinking blood or drunkenly processing, his pagan rituals often involved the audience as participants, rather than mere viewers.
In an homage to Gustav Courbet's "The Origin of the World" (that saucy, unabashed portrait of a woman's genitalia), Luxembourgian artist Deborah de Robertis transformed the two-dimensional masterpiece into a live performance art piece by sitting in front of the 1866 artwork and baring her own "origin of the world" for all patrons of Paris' Muse dOrsay to see.  The artist was arrested for her bold move (she did not plan ahead with the museum to see if, you know, they'd be cool with her showing her vulva to unsuspecting kids and adults), but she managed to make her intentions known.  If you ignore the context, you could construe this performance as an act of exhibitionism, but what I did was not an impulsive act, she explained to Luxemburger Wort. There is a gap in art history, the absent point of view of the object of the gaze... I am not showing my vagina, but I am revealing what we do not see in the painting, the eye of the vagina, the black hole, this concealed eye, this chasm, which, beyond the flesh, refers to infinity, to the origin of the origin.
In 2000, Chinese performance artist Zhu Yu recorded himself eating what appeared to be a dead fetus stolen from a medical school. It was presented at the bombastic "Fuck Off" exhibition organized by Ai Weiwei and Feng Boyi. When stills of the act (which did not actually involve a human fetus) hit a Channel 4 documentary in the UK, critics tore the artist apart for courting recognition with deliberately shocking art.  "No religion forbids cannibalism," Zhu Yu claims in the video above. "Nor can I find any law which prevents us from eating people. I took advantage of the space between morality and the law and based my work on it."
Aliza Shvarts, a 2008 art major at Yale, documented her nine-month process artificially inseminated herself on a regular basis while simultaneously taking abortifacient drugs to induce miscarriages. The resulting exhibition featured video recordings of the miscarriages and physical evidence of the experience, including blood.  "For the past year, I performed repeated self-induced miscarriages," Shvarts wrote in a column for Yale Daily News. "Using a needleless syringe, I would inject the sperm near my cervix within 30 minutes of its collection, so as to insure the possibility of fertilization. On the 28th day of my cycle, I would ingest an abortifacient, after which I would experience cramps and heavy bleeding... Because the miscarriages coincide with the expected date of menstruation (the 28th day of my cycle), it remains ambiguous whether the there (sic) was ever a fertilized ovum or not."  "The reality of the pregnancy, both for myself and for the audience, is a matter of reading," she added.  Yale University, rather predictably, took issue with the artist's project, calling it a "creative fiction." When Shvarts spoke out against that claim, reaffirming that the piece was in fact "university sanction," Yale said that statement was "part of the performance."
For a 2003 piece titled "I Miss You," Italian artist Franco B walked down a catwalk at London's Tate Modern museum covered in white body paint and bleeding from self-inflicted wounds on his wrists. "I dont make work that lives in somebodys living room," the artist said to Metro UK, "but lives in the memory because it speaks to them. Art is about creating language and memories. Language is like a virus that can invade you, and I love that."
Before there was Pussy Riot there was Voina (meaning "war" in Russian), a collective of radical street artists and performers who challenge Russia's authoritative regime through a series of public disruptions, based largely in Moscow and St. Petersburg. The acts can range from painting giant penises on bridges to violently overturning police cars to tossing cats at McDonalds employees, but their most infamous performance was a public orgy.  The orgy took place at the Timiryazev State Biological Museum in Moscow in February of 2008 as an action titled "Fuck for the heir Puppy Bear!" Aiming their outrage at presidential hopeful Dmitry Medvedev (whose last name comes from the word medved, or "bear"), the Voina members stripped naked and engaged in sexual intercourse on the floor of the museum as a means of "subversively affirming" the state's fertility and reproduction goals.
Who could forget Marina Abramovic's 2010 endurance spectacle "The Artist is Present," in which the Serbian artist spent 736 hours staring at Museum of Modern Art visitors across a table. It was a giant exhibition that prompted headlines like "Wait, Why Did That Woman Sit in the MoMA for 750 Hours?" and blogs like this.  "Its narcissistic, exhibitionistic work, and it has brought out the crowds own narcissism and exhibitionism, in a self-fulfilling feedback loop," New York Magazine's Jerry Saltz wrote. "But its also very compelling."
We began with Vito Acconci so why not end with Chris Burden, the artist who allowed a friend to shoot him with a .22 rifle from 15 feet away... all in the confines of a gallery in 1971.
=======
Demonstrators hold a banner reading "For democracy, for equality, for freedoms. Let us fight all fascism!" during a demonstration in solidarity with the victims of terrorist attacks at the Old-Port of Marseille, southern France, Jan. 10, 2015.
A sign on the Arc de Triomphe reads "Paris is Charlie" in solidarity with the victims of the shooting at the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo in Paris, France, Jan. 10, 2015.
Thousands of people attend  a demonstration in solidarity with the victims of terrorist attacks at the Old-Port of Marseille, Jan. 10, 2015.
People gather to pay to pay tribute to victims of the attack on the French satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo, at JFK Plaza in Philadelphia, Jan. 9, 2015.
Tunisians hold up old copies of Charlie Hebdo on Bourguiba Avenue in Tunis during a gathering in solidarity with those killed in the attack on Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 9, 2015.
People holding a banner reading "I am Charlie", take part to silent walk for victims of the shooting at the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 10, 2015, in Nice, southeastern France.
Demonstrators hold a banner reading "Charlie is great, barbarism will not erase talent" during a demonstration in solidarity with the victims of terrorist attacks at the Old-Port of Marseille, southern France, Jan. 10, 2015.
People hold "Je Suis Charlie" signs at a rally in solidarity with victims of the terrorist attacks in Paris, Jan. 10, 2015.
Nice soccer team and Lorient soccer team observe a minute of silence for the victims of the shooting at the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 10, 2015, in Nice stadium, southeastern France.
A tarp reading 'Je suis Charlie' is seen in the front of the Palais de Tokyo on January 10, 2015 in Paris, France.
Lille's supporters hold scarves as they observe a minute of silence in tribute to the victims of three days of terror before the French L1 football match at Pierre Mauroy stadium in Villeneuve-d'Ascq, northern France, on Jan. 10, 2015.
Nepalese journalists participate in a candlelight vigil in solidarity with victims of the attack on French satirical paper Charlie Hebdo, in Kathmandu, Nepal, Friday, Jan. 9, 2015.
Members of Paraguay's French community hold sheets of paper reading in French; "I am Charlie" during a tribute to victims of the terrorist attack against the French satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo, in Asuncion, Paraguay, Jan. 10, 2015.
People make a cross with pencils during a protest in solidarity with those killed in the attack on Charlie Hebdo, in Niteroi, Brazil, Jan. 8, 2015.
Egyptians hold candles in downtown Cairo in solidarity with the victims of the attack on Charlie Hebdo, Jan. 9, 2015.
School students pray by a sand sculpture made by Narayan Sahu as tribute to victims of the attack on French satirical paper Charlie Hebdo, at Juhu beach in Mumbai, India, Jan. 9, 2015.
People makes a cross with pencils, while others hold signs that read in French "Rio is Charlie," during a protest in solidarity with those killed in the attack on Charlie Hebdo, in Niteroi, Brazil, Jan. 8, 2015.
Muslims hold placards reading 'Islam is against terrorism' offer roses in the Sablons neighborhood of Le Mans, western France, on January 10, 2015.
A group of activists and journalists stage a protest against the attack on Charlie Hebdo in front of French Embassy in Morocco on Jan. 10, 2015 in Rabat, Morocco.
Guingamp's supporter hold signs reading 'Je suis Charlie' to pay tribute to the victims of the Charlie Hebdo attack during the French L1 football match in Guingamp, western France, on Jan. 10, 2015.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:30:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Artist Grimanesa Amoros Combines Architecture And Ecology For Spellbinding Public Work</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e27/sc/38/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cgirmanesa0Eamoros0In0I77370A880Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>

Why craft boring suspension bridges or arched overpasses when humanity is capable of building massive architectural feats like this to cross a river? The impressive, undulating design, destined to function as a pedestrian footbridge over the Dragon King Harbour River in China, is the product of NEXT Architects. The bridge design involves three individual, swirling lanes hovering over the picturesque landscape of Changsha.  The rendering won an international competition associated with a new public park in the area last year, and the project is currently under construction. The construction with the intersecting connections is based on the principal of the Mbius ring, states Michel Schreinemachers on the NEXT website. On the other hand it refers to a Chinese knot that comes from an ancient decorative Chinese folk art, John van de Water adds.
This image of an 80-story skyscraper, imagined by Dynamic Architecture's David Fisher back in 2008, is a far-fetched rendering fit for Dubai's future rich and famous. Why? Because it rotates.  The enormous, towering building would have floors that move ever so slightly, completing a 360 degree rotation every 90 minutes. Forget about fighting for an east-facing apartment, the suites in Dynamic Architecture's creation would have all four cardinal directions covered. And it get's better. The building would be equipped with several giant wind turbines that generate electricity for tenants, and penthouse residents would be able to park their car at their apartments thanks to nifty lifts.  While we're not sure this design will ever actually come to fruition (it was scheduled to be up and running in 2010), it's certainly a visual feast worth ogling.
In November of 2013, the Strelka Institute announced the winner of a two-stage international competition to design Zaryadye Park, Moscow's first new public park in over 50 years. The winner was Diller Scofidio + Renfro (in collaboration with Hargreaves Associates and Citymakers), who proposed this particularly stunning design based on a theory of "Wild Urbanism," or the concept of a "hybrid landscape where the natural and the built cohabit to create a new public space."  The park will feature four landscape typologies -- tundra, steppe, forest and wetland, integrating augmented micro-climates that will enable the park to function as a public space throughout Russias extreme winters. Essentially, the quasi-indoor environments will involve regulated temperatures, controlled wind and simulated daylight that encourage 24/7, year-round park pleasure. As Diller Scofidio +Renfro aptly put it, "Zaryadye Park will embody the past and the future simultaneously."
nvisible architecture is the calling card of science fiction design, and we're happy to report that architects of today are on the case. Of course, there's South Korea's in-the-works, LED-clad Infinity Tower. CNN reported in 2013 that "the invisibility illusion will be achieved with a high-tech LED facade system that uses a series of cameras that will send real-time images onto the building's reflective surface."   But there's also the shorter, less flashy structure (pictured above) designed by New York-based architecture firm stpmj. The parallelogram-shaped barn would be made of wood and sheeted with mirror film, at a cost of $5,000. The idea is to "blur the perceptual boundary" between object and setting, according to a statement sent by the architects to The Huffington Post earlier this year. We have to say we're impressed with architects' ability to push the boundaries of what invisible really means.
For his series "Dauphin Island," artist Dionisio Gonzalez designed dreamlike, futuristic forts made from iron and concrete, fusing the role of artist with that of architect, engineer and urban planner. The peculiar edifices -- the hybrid of a beach house, a bunker and a space ship -- were designed with the residents of Dauphin Island in mind. Located off the coast of Alabama in the Gulf of Mexico, the tiny landmass is known for experiencing perpetual and catastrophic hurricanes. When a storm hits the small island of around 1,200 people, it often washes away much of the coastline, leaving residents to rebuild their homes again and again.  Gonzalez created hypothetical blueprints for his forts, illustrating how his bulbous, concrete structures would better suit the fraught island's populous. You can learn more about the project on his website. Keep in mind, these structures are not yet slated for reality, but they certainly paint an interesting picture of what futuristic island homes could look like.
Dubai's Burj Khalifa is widely known as the world's tallest building, measuring in at a whopping 2,716.5 feet and 160 stories. The structure itself is mesmerizing, but what's even more intriguing is a think tank's bizarre proposal to cover the towering skyscraper in a giant fabric casing made of reflective material.  We learned about the project, dubbed EXO-BURJ, in 2014. The strange, sock-like covering would wrap around the entire building, from spire to ground level, in a "super-lightweight, reflective and semi-transparent fabric material," according to a description by the Dubai-based think tank, OP-EN. The temporary "sweater" would reflect the expansive urban scenes around it, turning the Burj Khalifa into a massive mirror in the vein of Christo and Jeanne-Claude.
What is there to do with an outdated, eyesore of a power plant in the future? Why not give the sprawling facilities a green makeover, one that would serve two functions: to beautify the structure and provide a new way of dealing with CO2 emissions.  Here's how it would work: The architecture firm AZPA (Alejandro Zaera-Polo Arquitectura) plans to turn the existing Wedel Vattenfall power plant in Germany into a new industrial complex, one that would be built up from the previous facilities and wrapped with a corrugated skin of creeper plants. This strategically-placed skin would not only soften the exterior aesthetic of the plant, but it would create a sheath of creepers to absorb CO2 emissions. AZPA describes the endeavor, imagined in 2013, as "an attempt to resolve the conflict between the natural ecology and the manmade environment."
Earlier this year, the Museum of Modern Art and MoMA PS1 selected The Livings circular tower of organic and reflective bricks -- called "Hy-Fi" -- as the winner of the Young Architects Programs (YAP) 15th edition. The temporary structure will be built using a new method of bio-design incorporating entirely organic material.  As Arch Daily reported back in February, the tower will involve "the unique stacking of two new materials: Ecovative-manufactured organic bricks, made from corn stalks and specially-developed living root structures; and reflective bricks, designed by 3M, that were used as growing trays for the organic bricks before being implemented into the structure."  Bonus: According to MoMA's site, Hy-Fi will is the first sizable structure to claim near-zero carbon emissions in its construction process and represents a 100% compostable design. Recurring to the latest developments in biotech, it reinvents the most basic component of architecture -- the brick -- as both a material of the future and a classic trigger for open-ended design possibilities."
Forget interior decorators, the future of indoor design will be run by 3D printers. We have architects Michael Hansmeyer and Benjamin Dillenburger to thank for introducing us to this concept. The two pulled off a three-dimensional printing feat to rival them all just last year. As part of the project "Digital Grotesque," the duo 3D printed an entire room, creating a 16-square-meter cube adorned with unbelievable ornamentation that looks like it belongs in a futuristic cathedral.  "We aim to create an architecture that defies classification and reductionism," states the group's website. "Digital Grotesque is between chaos and order, both natural and the artificial, neither foreign nor familiar. Any references to nature or existing styles are not integrated into the design process, but are evoked only as associations in the eye of the beholder."
It's hard not to love this New York design project from Family and PlayLab, which plans to bring a giant filtration system to the murky waters between Manhattan and Brooklyn. The project would take the shape of a 164-foot long floating pool set to take shape in 2016 -- if all funding efforts go as planned. If there are swimming pools in our future, let them look like this.  In a statement released at the end of 2013, pool masterminds Archie Lee Coates IV, Dong-Ping Wong and Jeff Franklin announced they are beginning construction on Float Lab, an experimental version of the planned 164-foot +POOL. They raised the funds for the smaller pool (35 feet by 35 feet, to be exact) through their last Kickstarter endeavor. With a launch date planned for this summer, the mini pool will put the team's filtration membranes to the test in real-river conditions.  "We dont think about using the river recreationally at all," Coates explained in a previous interview with Huff Post. "So as an architect you think, 'What if we could change that or propose an idea that could change that?' We decided to pitch [+Pool] to the world. We just had no idea the response we would get."
From the outside it resembles a giant, plushy purple jelly bean, and on the inside it looks more like a glowing, colored seashell. But this balloon-like form is actually the world's first inflatable concert hall, entitled "Ark Nova." Iconic British sculptor Anish Kapoor and Japanese architect Arata Isozaki teamed up to create the structure, meant to tour through areas of Japan affected by the 2011 earthquake and tsunami. It's a novel idea that could make for an innovative design strategy in many other fields.  "I am honored to have been asked to design Ark Nova for the Tohoku area," Kapoor states on the Ark Nova site. "The structure defines a space for community and for music in which color and form enclose. I hope that the devastation can be overcome by creativity. Music can give solace and bring community together and in so doing can help us to see we are not alone."
While wooden skyscrapers might not be as sensational as the previously mentioned rotating tower, the idea of building 34 wooden stories on on top of the other is pretty astonishing.  And it might become a reality if Scandinavian practice C.F. Mller and DinnellJohansson -- 2013's winners of the HSB Stockholm architectural competition -- follow through with their rendering for the world's tallest wooden skyscraper. The design (pictured above) is one of three ultra-modern residential high-rises planned for Stockholms city center in 2023, but the catch is, only one of these proposals will actually be built.
It's no secret that New York's Gowanus Canal is a breeding ground for toxic waste, polluted runoff, and raw sewage that's -- rather unfortunately -- been dumped directly into the area's bodies of water. But a little project known as "Sponge Park" is hoping to transform the Brooklyn locale into a cleaner, properly filtered sanctuary -- and provide a model for future urban design.  The Gowanus Canal Conservancy and the landscape architecture firm dlandstudio announced in the summer of 2013 that they plan to employ a system of landscape buffers and remediation wetlands to slow, absorb, and filter Gowanus' polluted sewer runoff before it reaches the canal. So, not only will the Sponge Park turn 11.4 acres of contaminated fields into a pleasant waterfront arena, it will provide a means of absorbing harmful pollutants that continue to ooze into the industrial battlefield.  "In a process called phytoremediation, specially selected plants metabolize pollutants and heavy metals present in the contaminated water," the American Society of Landscape Architects explains on its website. "Dirty water from the combined sewer system is captured in underground storage tanks and slowly released into the landscape."
In 2014, Chinese architecture firm MAD unveiled renderings of Chaoyang Park Plaza, a center of skyscrapers, office blocks and public spaces meant to mimic the appearance of mountains, hills and lakes depicted in Chinese landscape paintings. The complex is now under construction in Beijing, and will result in an expansive sky line seemingly ripped from the pages of a futuristic novel.  "By transforming features of Chinese classical landscape painting, such as lakes, springs, forests, creeks, valleys, and stones, into modern 'city landscapes,' the urban space creates a balance between high urban density and natural landscape," MAD writes on its website. "The forms of the buildings echo what is found in natural landscapes, and re-introduces nature to the urban realm."  Lucky for Beijing, the innovative skyline is already under construction.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:11:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Massive V404 Cygni Black Hole Wakes Up And Swallows A Star</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e42b/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cblack0Ehole0Ewakes0Eup0In0I76686840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A black hole has woken up... </Description>
        <MainBody>Best Space Images Of 2014
of


This Hubble Space Telescope photo shows NGC 2174, the "Monkey Head Nebula," located 6,400 light-years from Earth.
A powerful X-class solar flare, one of three X-class flares unleashed by the sun on June 10 and 11, as seen by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory. X-class flares are the most powerful kind.
Hubble image of the barred spiral galaxy M83, the "Southern Pinwheel," which lies 15 million light-years away in the constellation Hydra. This mosaic image was released in January.
Astronaut Koichi Wakata tweeted this view of a crescent moon rising and the cusp of Earth's atmosphere on Feb. 1, 2014.
Galaxy NGC 4258, located about 23 million light-years away from Earth, as seen by NASA's Chandra X-ray Observatory.
This photo of a "rainbow aurora" was taken by ISS astronaut Alexander Gerst.
This close-up image of part of Saturn's rings was taken by the Cassini spacecraft on June 30. It shows, from left to right, the outer portion of Saturn's C ring and the inner portion of the B ring.
ISS astronaut Reid Wiseman tweeted this image of a sunrise on Oct. 29. Wiseman wrote, "Not every day is easy. Yesterday was a tough one. #sunrise"
This image taken by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory shows a profile view of coronal loops. Coronal loops are found around sunspots and in active regions.
This image shows the sunlit side of Saturn's rings. It was taken in red light by the Cassini spacecraft's narrow-angle camera on Aug. 23.
Several celestial objects photographed in the same field of view by Spanish-American astrophotographer Rogelio Bernal Andreo, including supernova remnant Simeas 147, the "Flaming Star" nebula, nebula IC 410, and galactic clusters M36 and M38.
Astrophotographer Rick Stevenson released this photo of SH2-199, also known as the "Soul Nebula," in December. This emission nebula is located about 6,500 light-years from Earth.
This Hubble image shows a portion of the Large Magellanic Cloud, a small nearby galaxy that orbits our galaxy, the Milky Way.
A new day dawns on Saturn. The image was taken with the Cassini spacecraft's wide-angle camera on Aug. 23.
The photo is a composite image of the spiral galaxies NGC 2207 and IC 2163, located 130 million light years away in the constellation Canis Major. The image contains data from the Chandra X-ray Observatory in pink, optical light data from the Hubble Space Telescope in red, green, and blue, and infrared data from the Spitzer Space Telescope in red.
In January and February 1979, NASA's Voyager 1 spacecraft zoomed toward Jupiter, capturing hundreds of images during its approach, including this close-up of swirling clouds around Jupiter's Great Red Spot. This image was assembled from three black and white negatives and newly released.
An extreme ultra-violet wavelength image of a solar flare captured on Sept. 10.
This Hubble Space Telescope composite image shows a supernova explosion designated SN 2014J in the galaxy M82, at a distance of approximately 11.5 million light-years from Earth. It was taken on Jan. 31, as the supernova approached its peak brightness.
An image of the Tarantula Nebula (or NGC 2070), located about 160,000 lights years away, released in January.
This composite image shows one of the clusters, NGC 2024, which is found in the center of the so-called Flame Nebula about 1,400 light years from Earth. In this image, X-rays from Chandra are seen as purple, while infrared data from NASA's Spitzer Space Telescope are colored red, green and blue.
Saturn's moon Tethys captured by the Cassini spacecraft's narrow-angle camera on July 14.
The Philae lander took this portrait of the Rosetta spacecraft on Sept. 7, 2014, at a distance of about 30 miles from comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko.
The puzzling, fascinating surface of Jupiter's icy moon Europa looms large in this newly-reprocessed color view, made from images taken by NASA's Galileo spacecraft in the late 1990s.
A widefield view of the Flame (NGC2024) and Horsehead (IC434) Nebulae in Orion, captured in December by astrophotographer Roger Hutchinson. The pair are approximately 900 to 1,500 light years away.
Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, captured on Aug. 3, 2014 by Rosetta's OSIRIS narrow-angle camera.
The Orion Nebula, an immense stellar nursery some 1,500 light-years away. This stunning false-color view was constructed using infrared data from the Spitzer Space Telescope.
NASA astronaut Reid Wiseman captured this image from the International Space Station and tweeted it on Sept. 28, writing, "The Milky Way steals the show from Sahara sands that make the Earth glow orange."
European Space Agency astronaut Alexander Gerst tweeted this photograph taken from the International Space Station to social media on Aug. 29, 2014, writing, "words can't describe how it feels flying through an #aurora. I wouldn't even know where to begin."
This view, captured by the NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope and released in July, shows a nearby spiral galaxy known as NGC 1433. At about 32 million light-years from Earth, it is a type of very active galaxy known as a Seyfert galaxy--with a bright, luminous center comparable in brightness to that of our entire galaxy, the Milky Way.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:57:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis Asks Forgiveness For Catholic Church's Persecution Of Waldensians</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a41a9f/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C280Cpope0Efrancis0Ewaldensians0In0I76449160Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis asked forgiveness on Monday for the Roman Catholic Church's "non-Christian and inhumane" treatment in the past of the Waldensians, a tiny Protestant movement the Vatican tried to exterminate in the 15th century.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis Asks Forgiveness For Catholic Church's Persecution Of Waldensians
Reuters | By                                                                      PHILIP PULLELLA
Updated:
3 hours ago
Pope Francis shakes hands with Eugenio Bernardini, the Moderator of the Waldensian Church, during the first ever visit of a pope to the Waldensian evangelical church, in Turin, northern Italy, Monday, June 22, 2015. Pope Francis asked forgiveness Monday for the Catholic Church's persecution of members of this small evangelical church in Italy whose leader was excommunicated and followers branded as heretics during the Middle Ages.  (L' Osservatore Romano/Pool Photo via AP) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
reddit
Pope Francis asked forgiveness on Monday for the Roman Catholic Church's "non-Christian and inhumane" treatment in the past of the Waldensians, a tiny Protestant movement the Vatican tried to exterminate in the 15th century.
Francis made his plea during the first ever visit by a pope to a Waldensian temple on the second day of a trip to Italy's northern Piedmont region, the centre of the Waldensian Church, which has only about 30,000 followers worldwide.
While the movement is miniscule compared to the 1.2 billion member Roman Catholic Church, the gesture is part of Francis' drive to promote Christian unity and it has taken on added significance ahead of the 500th anniversary of the Protestant Reformation in 2017.
"On behalf of the Catholic Church, I ask forgiveness for the un-Christian and even inhumane positions and actions taken against you historically," he said. "In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, forgive us!"
The Waldensians, who now live mostly in Italy and Latin America, were founded by Peter Waldo in France in the late 12th century. He gave up his wealth and preached poverty but as the movement grew it came into increasing theological conflict with the papacy.
The movement, an early precursor of the Protestant Reformation in the 16th century, was branded as heretical and in 1487 Pope Innocent VIII ordered its extermination.
Some 1,700 Waldensians were killed in 1655 by Catholic forces commanded by the Duke of Savoy.
Today the Waldensians are part of the World Communion of Reformed Churches and the World Council of Churches. They have
only two sacraments -- baptism and the Lord's Supper -- as opposed to seven in the Roman Catholic Church, a member of the Italian branch said.
During a visit to Jerusalem in 2000, Francis' predecessor Pope John Paul II asked forgiveness from Jews for their persecution by Catholics over the centuries.
In 2017, Christians will mark the 500th anniversary of the launching of the Protestant Reformation by Martin Luther, who nailed his 95 Theses to a church door in Germany to denounce corruption in the Catholic Church.
Various Christian churches have still not agreed on how they will jointly mark the divorce that split western Christianity and led to many bloody religious wars.
The head of the Protestant Church in Germany, Bishop Heinrich Bedford-Strohm, has said he would be in favour of inviting the pope to a "joint Christian festival" to mark the anniversary.
Francis, an Argentinian whose father and grandfather were born in the Turin area, wrapped up his two-day visit to the region with a private lunch with his Italian relatives.
Also on The Huffington Post
Close


A mere two weeks after he was announced as pontiff, Francis washed and kissed the feet of 12 prisoners incarcerated in Rome as part of the traditional Holy Thursday rite. The unorthodox component of the ceremony was the inclusion of two women, one of whom was a Muslim. This show of acceptance and compassion was just a hint at what was to come, as the pope has continued to make statements about the importance of interfaith understanding as well as the importance of a greater role for women in the church. Francis sent personal Eid al-Fitr holiday greetings to Muslims around the world, rather than relying on his office to do so in a show of care and good will that hasn't happened since Pope John Paul II sent a similar personal message in 1991.
Soon after he became pope, Francis tweeted, "The pope must serve all people, especially the poor, the weak, the vulnerable," and he's made sure to personally do so by comforting and greeting the sick after his weekly general audiences in St. Peter's Square. He moved many hearts, as pictures of him tenderly embracing and kissing some severely disfigured men showed his human concern for all people, especially the marginalized.
Pope Francis refused to live in the luxurious papal apartments located in the Apostolic Palace and prefers to live in more modest accommodations to show his personal commitment to humility and encourage other leaders to follow suit. He's also gained notice for his unusual choice of a car -- a humble Ford Focus with a starting sticker price of only about $16,000. He can rarely be seen in the ostentatious vestments that he could certainly wear as pope and  prefers his usual garments of a simple white hat and robe. He's always done so -- when he still lived in Argentina, he gave up his chauffeur and took the bus to work.
Arriving at World Youth Day, Pope Francis had rock-star appeal, as thousands of young people swarmed his car after it took a wrong turn. Though the mob of excited youth alarmed his security staff with the frenzy of their excitement, "the pope was happy, with his hand out the window waving," said a Vatican spokesman. World Youth Day was a great success, and this pope seems particularly in tune with the younger generation.
Pope Francis has given a 17-year-old boy with Down Syndrome the ride of his life  sort of.  Francis invited Alberto di Tullio up onto his open-top Mercedes at the end of his general audience Wednesday, letting him spin around on the pontiff's white chair while tens of thousands of people looked on.  Read more
Four homeless people, one of them bringing his dog, helped Pope Francis celebrate his 77th birthday at the Vatican Tuesday.  Read more here
Meet Nathan de Brito, the little boy who broke past barriers to run into Pope Francis' arms on Friday in order to tell him something that moved the pontiff to tears.  They embraced on the Popemobile as de Brito confided to Pope Francis, "Your Holiness, I want to be a priest of Christ, a representative of Christ."  Read more here
In this photo provided by the Vatican paper L'Osservatore Romano, Pope Francis, left, and Pope emeritus Benedict XVI pray together in Castel Gandolfo Saturday, March 23, 2013. Pope Francis has traveled to Castel Gandolfo to have lunch with his predecessor Benedict XVI in a historic and potentially problematic melding of the papacies that has never before confronted the Catholic Church. The Vatican said the two popes embraced on the helipad. In the chapel where they prayed together, Benedict offered Francis the traditional kneeler used by the pope. Francis refused to take it alone, saying "We're brothers," and the two prayed together on the same one. (AP Photo/Osservatore Romano, HO)
This adorable little boy was on top of the world when he made friends with Pope Francis by wandering up onto the stage during the Pontiff's address to a crowd of families.  Read more
Pope Francis' compassionate nature was poignantly captured in this image of him tenderly comforting a sick man by kissing him on the head.  Read more
Pope Francis is winning Twitter. The tweeting Pope upped the ante yesterday by posing for an incredible selfie at the Vatican on Wednesday.   Read more
Pope Francis boards a plane at Rome's Fiumicino international airport, Monday, July 22, 2013. It's wheels up on Pope Francis' first trip abroad as pontiff. A special Alitalia flight carrying Francis, his entourage and journalists who will cover him on his week-long visit to Brazil took off 10 minutes behind schedule Monday from Rome's Leonardo da Vinci airport. Keeping to his example that the Catholic church must be humble, Francis carried his own black hand luggage. He even kept holding it with his left hand while he used his left to shake hands with some of the VIPs who turned out to wish him well and while he climbed the stairs to the jet's entrance. Among the dignitaries was Italian Premier Enrico Letta. (AP Photo/Riccardo De Luca)
In this Sunday, March 31, 2013 file photo, Pope Francis hugs 8-year-old Dominic Gondreau, who has cerebral palsy, after celebrating his first Easter Mass in St. Peter's Square at the Vatican. Gondreau is the son of Dr. Paul Gondreau, a faculty member at Providence College in Providence, R.I.   Read more here
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:26:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jimmy Carter Joins HuffPost Live</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e2d/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cwatch0Elive0Ejimmy0Ecarter0Ej0In0I7739870A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter joins us to recount his journey from Georgia farmer to 39th President of the United States, detailed in his new memoir </Description>
        <MainBody>Jimmy Carter Joins HuffPost Live
HuffPost Live
Updated:
18 minutes ago
Former President Jimmy Carter speaks during a forum at the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum in Boston, Thursday, Nov. 20, 2014. Among other topics, Carter discussed his new book, "A Call to Action:  Women, Religion, Violence, and Power." (AP Photo/Elise Amendola) | ASSOCIATED PRESS
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:03:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Harry Potter And The Cursed Child' To Hit London Stage In 2016; Play Tells 'Untold' Story, J.K. Rowling Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e445/sc/15/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Charry0Epotter0Eand0Ethe0Ecursed0Echild0Eplay0In0I76692840Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Harry Potter fans, hold onto your broomsticks. An “untold part” of the boy wizard’s story will soon be revealed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Previous Story
Next Story
'Harry Potter And The Cursed Child' To Hit London Stage In 2016; Play Tells 'Untold' Story, J.K. Rowling Says
reddit
Harry Potter fans, hold onto your broomsticks. An untold part of the boy wizards story will soon be revealed.
Author J.K. Rowling confirmed on Twitter Friday that a play, entitled  Harry Potter and the Cursed Child , will be opening in London next year.
It will tell a new story, Rowling wrote, later adding: I dont want to say too much more, because I dont want to spoil what I know will be real treat for fans.
Rowling stressed, however, that the play will not be a prequel.
I'm also very excited to confirm today that a new play called Harry Potter and the #CursedChild will be opening in London next year.
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
It will tell a new story, which is the result of a collaboration between writer Jack Thorne, director John Tiffany and myself. #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
I don't want to say too much more, because I don't want to spoil what I know will be a real treat for fans. #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
However, I can say that it is not a prequel! #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
To answer one inevitable (and reasonable!) question - why isn't #CursedChild a new novel? - I am confident that when audiences see the play
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
they will agree that it was the only proper medium for the story. #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
I've had countless offers to extend Harry's story over the years, but Jack, John and Sonia Friedman are a dream team! #CursedChild
 J.K. Rowling (@jk_rowling) June 26, 2015
It has been a huge pleasure to share with them (and soon, with you!) this untold part of Harry's story. #CursedChild
According to The Daily Mail, Harry Potter and the Cursed Child may detail the lives of Harrys parents, James and Lily , before they were killed by Lord Voldemort.
The play may also look at the complicated relationship between siblings Lily and Petunia, the news outlet wrote. Petunia, and her husband Vernon, were the muggles (non-magical people) who raised Harry after he was orphaned.
The play is slated to open in the summer of 2016 at the Palace Theatre on Londons West End, Entertainment Weekly writes. Tickets will reportedly go on sale in the fall.
Also on HuffPost:
'Harry Potter': Where Are They Now?
of


Since appearing as the movies' title character, Daniel has managed to shake off Harry and ensure he's known by his own name - which has been aided by the fact he'll happily get his kit off on-screen and on-stage.   After stints in the West End and on Broadway, Daniel recently starred in 'What If', and in 2015, fans will see him take on the role of Igor in 'Frankenstein'.
Since hanging up his wizard's hat, Rupert has made waves on the West End stage, and in 2013 he received rave reviews for his performance in 'Mojo'.  He also stowed some his 'Harry Potter' cash away and splashed it on an ice cream truck, fulfilling a childhood dream. Aww!
You'll find Ralph in 'Wrath of the Titans', 'Skyfall' and 'Great Expectations'. It has also been announced he's been cast in the upcoming, as-yet-unnamed, James Bond film.
Sadly, Jamie hasn't fared too well in recent years and in 2012 he was imprisoned after participating in the 2011 London riots.
Sadly, Joshua hasn't faired too well either, and has dropped off the radar as far as acting is concerned.
After being everyone's favourite bad guy in the films, Tom decided to try something a little different and recorded a number of singles, which he shared with fans via YouTube.   He's currently filming 'Clavius', where he stars as a character called Lucius. Tom's also really, really good at Twitter.
After getting surprisingly dishy, Matthew now spends his time reminding everyone that he's also hugely talented, making his West End debut in 2012 alongside Arthur Darvill and Laurence Fox in 'Our Boys'.   Matthew also took part in one of the best editions of Innuendo Bingo ever on Scott Mills' Radio 1 show.
Bonnie was one of the 'Harry Potter' frachise's younger stars, however, that hasn't stopped her from going on to carve a successful career.   While she hasn't quite achieved the worldwide success of the films' leading stars, Bonnie has been applauded for her work as a model and actress. She also writes and directs her own screen plays.
To be honest, Rob's had a rather quiet life since his character's exit left us weeping in the 'Goblet Of Fire' film.   After a lot of digging, Robert's main achievement seems to be another franchise entitled 'Twilight'. Nope, we've never heard of it either...
Julie is one of the many huge names who appeared in the 'Harry Potter' films so it's not like her career needed the boost.   Since the final film in 2011, Julie's been praised by critics her roles in a whole host of other movies, including voicing the witch in Disney's 'Brave'.
Michael is rumoured to be reprising his role in the upcoming wizrding flick 'Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them'.   He also plays Howard Mollison in the TV adaptation of JK's novel 'A Casual Vacancy'.
Already a legend, Dame Maggie Smith continues to win fans with her performance as the Dowager Countess in hit TV series 'Downton Abbey'.   She's also no stranger to the big screen, and starred in 'The Best Exotic Marigold Hotel' and is set to feature in the upcoming sequel.
Amongst other projects, John has completed three where he was cast alongside other 'Harry Potter' stars; 'Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy', 'The Gruffalo's Child' and 'Labyrinth'.
Since 'Harry Potter', method actor Alan has been part of several projects including 'CBGB', alongside his former co-star Rupert Grint.
After providing the voice of everybody's favourite House Elf, Toby's projects included 'The Hunger Games', 'Snow White and the Huntsman' and 'The Adventures of Tintin'.
Once filming wrapped, Robbie moved over to the Dark Side and joined Voldemort's gang. By which we mean, starred alongside Ralph Fiennes, in 'Great Expectations'.   Traitor.
Oh Kenneth, where do we start?   Ever since *that* version of 'Hamlet', Brannagh has been one of our favourite stars to swoon over.   Since leaving the Wizarding World, Kenneth has turned his attention to directing, as well as starring in flicks such as 'My Week With Marilyn' and 'Jack Ryan: Shadow Recruit'.
In between stints studying for a degree at Brown University in the US, Emma starred in a number of blockbusters including 'The Bling Ring' and 'The Perks Of Being A Wallflower'.   Shortly after graduating in 2013, it was announced that Emma has accepted a UN post and will serve as a Women's Goodwill Ambassador.
Gary's a very busy man and has totted up an extensive list of appearances since his Harry Potter days. These include: 'The Dark Knight' and 'The Dark Knight Rises' and 'Dawn of the Planet of the Apes'.  He also voiced Viktor Reznov and Daniel Clarke in the 'Call of Duty' games.
David also lent his voice to video games, specifically as the voice of Lord Darius Crowley in 'World of Warcraft: Cataclysm in 2010'.  Other projects include 'War Horse' and a role in 'Separate We Come, Separate We Go', a short film directed by Bonnie Wright, who played Ginny Weasley.
Do we really need to tell you what John Cleese has been up to? Seriously?
Mad-eye Moody is actually quite sharp, bagging himself parts in numerous projects including 2014's 'Edge of Tomorrow'.  He's also set to star in 'Suffragette', alongside Carey Mulligan and Helena Bonham-Carter.
Geraldine's fleeting appearances as Harry's mum gave the movies some of their most poignant moments.   Since then, she's appeared in 'My Week With Marilyn' and 'Grace Of Monaco'.
Natalia evidently knows how to smell out a hit as she's also starred in 'Game of Thrones' as Osha.
David's done barely anything since his time as Barty Crouch Jr.   No time as a famous Timelord, no treading the boards in Shakespeare plays and he definitely didn't star opposite Olivia Colman in an award-winning ITV drama series. Lazy moo.
A bit of a cult hit on YouTube, Warwick Davies has been feautured on several channels, most notably the YogsCast.   In the land of television he's made guest appearances on shows including 'An Idiot Abroad', 'Top Gear'. He also played Oberon the Ufgood in 'Dwarves Assemble'.  More recently he played Old Hamm in 'Jack the Giant Slayer' and can (sometimes) be found teaching charms lessons at the Warner Bros. Studios VIP nights.
Like Ralph Fiennes, Helen also appeared in 'Skyfall'. she also stars in the hit drama 'Peaky Blinders' as Aunt Polly.
What can we say? The inimitable Helena Bonham Carter played the role of Bellatrix to disturbing perfection and played similarly creepy parts in many other movies. To be honest, if Voldy had left her in charge, he probably would have triumphed.  Helena was the perfect Madame Thernardier in 'Les Miserables' and also gave a stellar performance as Elizabeth Taylor in a BBC television film.
Shirley Henderson appeared in just a couple of the movies as the ghoul skulking around the toilets.   Since then, she voiced the Gruffalo's child in the film of the same name and also starred in 'Soutchliffe', 'Filth' and 'Death In Paradise'.
Since 'Harry Potter' Staunton has voiced Queen Victoria in 'The Pirates! Band of Misfits' and played Knotgrass in 'Maleficent'.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:55:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>An HIV-Positive Man Asked Strangers To Touch Him. What Happened Next Brought Him To Tears</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e454/sc/19/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Chiv0Epositive0Eman0Etouch0Eme0Eexperiment0In0I76688180Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>

Only one quarter of the 1.1 million people with HIV have their condition under control, where "under control" means the virus has been suppressed, according to a report released this summer by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.   CORRECTION: The first sentence has been reworded to more accurately reflect the number of people with HIV.
Even though two men were, for a time, able to go off antiretrovirals because their HIV had been reduced to undetectable levels after receiving bone marrow transplants, the HIV eventually returned in the men, according to news reports.  In 2012, the news of the mens undetectable HIV levels made headlines. The men, who were both HIV positive and taking antiretroviral drugs, had received bone marrow transplants for Hodgkins lymphoma. They had received the transplants while they were also taking the antiretroviral medication.   However, in late 2013, preliminary results showed that the HIV had returned.   This slide has been updated to note more recent developments related to the procedure.
New HIV infection rates can be dramatically lowered by making antiretroviral drugs free, a study from Canadian researchers found.   The Canadian Press reported on the study, conducted by B.C. Centre for Excellence in HIV-AIDS researchers, which showed that British Columbia -- a province that offers free access to antiretroviral therapy  -- had the lowest rate of new HIV infections over a more-than-10-year period, compared with Ontairio and Quebec.
More than half of HIV-infected young people are unaware that they have the virus, according to a Centers for Disease Control and Prevention report.  "Given everything we know about HIV and how to prevent it in 30 years of fighting the disease, it's just unacceptable that young people are becoming infected at such high rates," Reuters reported CDC Director Dr. Thomas Frieden saying.   The report also showed that for young people, 72 percent of the new HIV infections were in men who have sex with men, while almost 50 percent were in young, African-American males, Reuters reported. These figures are based on 2010 data.
The number of people living with HIV has increased by 18 percent from 2001 to 2011, according to a report released this year from the United Nations Programme on AIDS. An estimated 34.2 million people around the world are living with HIV.   The report also showed that deaths from AIDS have dropped, from 2.3 million in 2005-2006 to 1.7 million in 2011, Reuters reported.
According to the same United Nations report, costs for the cheapest UN-recommended antiretroviral therapy drugs have also decreased over the past 10 years, Reuters reported. A year's worth of the drugs used to cost $10,000 in 2000 for one person; now, it costs $100 a year.
The Food and Drug Administration this year officially approved the drug Truvada -- which has been used since 2004 as a treatment for HIV -- to be sold as a preventive measure for people who don't have the infection, but are at high risk for it.  The FDA said that the pill should be considered for preventive use not only by gay or bisexual men who are at high risk for HIV, but also heterosexual men and women who may also face HIV risks, the Associated Press reported.   Heterosexual men and women make up more than one-fourth of new cases of HIV, and "that's not a portion of the epidemic we want to ignore," the CDC's Dr. Dawn Smith, who was the lead author of the new recommendations, told the Associated Press.   The FDA also approved a new drug this year, Stribild, to treat HIV, Reuters reported.
In findings published this year in the journal PLoS Pathogens, scientists from the University of California, Los Angeles found that it's possible to genetically engineer stem cells to attack living HIV-infected cells in mice.   While the study was only for "proof-of-principle," it "lays the groundwork for the potential use of this type of an approach in combating HIV infection in infected individuals, in hopes of eradicating the virus from the body," study researcher Dr. Scott G. Kitchen, an assistant professor of medicine at UCLA, said in a statement.
People should be screened for HIV even if they're not at high risk of contracting the infection, according to draft recommendations released just last month by the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force. The recommendations would mean that everyone between the ages of 15 and 65 should be screened for HIV, even if they're not at high risk for it, Reuters reported.   "The prior recommendations were for screening high-risk adults and adolescents," Dr. Douglas Owens, a member of the USPSTF task force and a Stanford University medical professor, told Reuters. "The current recommendation is for screening everyone, regardless of their risk."
All HIV patients should be treated immediately with antiretrovirals, according to new guidelines issued this year from a panel of the International Antiviral Society-USA, as reported by TIME. The recommendations are counter to previous guidelines, which said that antiretrovirals should only be used if the CD4 count -- a measure of immune cells in a person's body -- becomes less than 350 cells for every mm3 of blood.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attack, Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Decapitated, Several Wounded</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4798e458/sc/31/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cfrance0Efactory0Eattack0In0I76694620Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France (AP) — An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Attack, Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Decapitated, Several Wounded
| By                                                                      LORI HINNANT and ANGELA CHARLTON
Posted:
reddit
SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France (AP)  An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack. He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - prosecutor : http://t.co/Y6f803Jkd7 pic.twitter.com/3Eq9Zuw8ze
 Reuters Top News (@Reuters) June 26, 2015
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
A photo taken on June 26, 2015 shows the Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates. (JEAN-PHILIPPE KSIAZEK/AFP/Getty Images)
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
Investigating police officers work outside the plant where an attack took place, Friday, June 26, 2015 in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France.  (AP Photo/Laurent Cipriani)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:38:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Dead</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47988697/sc/6/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cexplosion0Efrance0Efactory0In0I76694620Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (AP) — A French security official says an attack and explosion at a gas factory in southeastern France has left one person dead.</Description>
        <MainBody>Attack, Explosion At Gas Factory In Southeastern France Leaves 1 Decapitated, Several Wounded
| By                                                                      LORI HINNANT and ANGELA CHARLTON
Posted:
reddit
SAINT-QUENTIN-FALLAVIER, France (AP)  An attacker with suspected ties to French Islamic radicals rammed a car into a gas factory Friday in southeastern France, and a severed head was staked on a post at the entrance, officials said. France immediately opened a terrorism investigation.
Two people were injured, authorities said.
President Francois Hollande, speaking in Brussels, said the attack began shortly before 10 a.m. when a car crashed through the gate of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon. The car then plowed into gas canisters, touching off an explosion, he said.
"No doubt about the intention  to cause an explosion," Hollande said, calling the attack "of a terrorist nature."
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said a man who had been flagged in 2006 for suspected ties to extremists was seized by an alert firefighter, one of multiple people in custody after the attack. He said authorities were trying to identify the victim whose severed head was posted at the factory's entrance.
"People who could have participated in this abject crime are in custody," he said.
Anti-terrorist police to investigate southeast France attack - prosecutor : http://t.co/Y6f803Jkd7 pic.twitter.com/3Eq9Zuw8ze
 Reuters Top News (@Reuters) June 26, 2015
Cazeneuve said the suspect had been known to intelligence services, who had him under surveillance from 2006-08. The man is from the Lyon region, he said.
A severed head was found staked on a gate at the factory's entrance, in what appeared to be an echo of the Islamic State group's practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see. An official said two flags  one white and one black, both with Arabic inscriptions  were found nearby.
The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to release details to the media, said the victim was not decapitated by the blast.
France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, and potential charges including plotting as part of "a terrorist group."
Hollande spoke after watching TV news reports about the attack with German Chancellor Angela Merkel as both leaders attended a European Union summit in Brussels.
The industrial site belongs to Air Products, an American chemical company based in Allentown, Pennsylvania. The company would not confirm whether any employees were injured or killed.
"Our priority at this stage is to take care of our employees, who have been evacuated from the site and all accounted for," the company said in a statement. "The site is secure. Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
A photo taken on June 26, 2015 shows the Air Products gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, central eastern France, after a suspected Islamist assault in which a decapitated head was pinned to the gates. (JEAN-PHILIPPE KSIAZEK/AFP/Getty Images)
Cazeneuve said the investigation had just begun and cautioned against jumping to conclusions.
France went on high alert after attacks in January against the satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, a kosher grocery store and a policewoman that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including three Islamic extremist attackers.
Since then, fears of copycat attacks have risen. One person was arrested after authorities said he was plotting to gun down churches in the Paris region. Cazeneuve said Friday that security has been heightened at religious sites around the country.
Investigating police officers work outside the plant where an attack took place, Friday, June 26, 2015 in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast of Lyon, France.  (AP Photo/Laurent Cipriani)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chinese-Filipino Community's Dilemma: The Philippines, China, and the South China Sea Disputes</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47982745/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Crichard0Ejavad0Eheydarian0Cchinese0Efilipino0Ecommunit0Ib0I766930A40Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
At its very core, the Philippines is an idea, representing a pluralistic land with hospitable people, who have always welcomed persecuted people from around the world. It is an all-embracing society that has been open to peoples from around the world.
Nationalism and nationhood in post-colonial, cosmopolitan countries like the Philippines aren't about ethnicity, but, as eminent Sociologist Benedict Anderson suggest, they are instead anchored by an "imagined community" that is bound by shared dreams, sufferings, and experiences. Amid rising tensions in the South China Sea, pitting a powerful China against a beleaguered Philippines, the sizable and well-integrated Chinese community in the Philippines is feeling the heat.
Recently, one of the Philippines' most celebrated writers elicited highly negative reactions among certain circles, particularly the Filipino-Chinese community, by implicitly questioning their loyalty to the Philippines, specifically in an event of war with China. The last thing the Philippines needs at this point is divisive talk and internal divisions. The Filipino-Chinese community serves as a backbone of the country's economy, with many among them rising to positions of great prominence -- whether in business or politics or entertainment -- in the Southeast Asian nation.
Critical Junctures
In their best-selling book, Why Nations Fail , economists James A. Robinson and Daron Acemolu discuss the double-edged nature of what they call critical junctures: Seismic events, which shake up the foundations of the status quo. Sometimes, crises create the right kind of exogenous pressure to disrupt a dysfunctional equilibrium, forcing positive change and encouraging innovative adaptation by troubled societies.
In other cases, crises lead to further divisions and, ultimately, the collapse of an entire civilization. In Collaps e, Evolutionary Biologist Jared Diamond dramatically chronicles the extinction of certain civilizations due to their inability to adapt to changes in their environment.
Yes, we are in the 21st century, but the Darwinian nature of international politics has not dramatically changed in recent times, as exemplified by Russia's unabashed annexation of Crimea and China's sweeping territorial push across the Western Pacific. As much as we would want our world to be strictly governed by international law, power politics, however, continues to shape our globalized world (See John Mearsheimer's Tragedy of Great Power Politics ), with more powerful countries still pressing ahead with their interests even under immense international pressure.
Despite widespread international outcry, China has effectively concluded its construction activities on disputed features in the Spratly chain of islands, creating a sprawling network of civilian and military installations at the heart of one of the world's most important waterways. If and when China chooses to impose an Air Defense Identification Zone (ADIZ) in the area, it would be in a position to push its neighbors out of features under their control.
In some ways, the ongoing disputes with China in the South China Sea represent a critical juncture, testing the competence of Philippine state institutions and the patriotism of its citizenry. The festering territorial spats should serve as a wake up call, instilling into the fabric of Filipino society a robust sense of national unity like never before.
Chinese Threat in Perspective
To begin with, the prospect of a full-scale Chinese invasion of its neighboring countries is highly unlikely. Such paranoid language is more of an outcome of sensationalist commentaries by warmongering journalists and self-serving defense wonks than sober assessment of realities on the ground. Without a question, China is rapidly developing an anti-access/area-denial (A2/AD) capability , which down the road may give it the ability to dominate adjacent waters and push the United States out of East Asia.
But what China is seeking is a "zone of deference" rather than European-style colonization of its neighbors. China is developing the kind of military technology and economic hegemony, which will allow it to win strategic battles without waging full-scale war. As prominent Chinese scholar Yan Xuetong b luntly puts it : "The policy now is to allow these smaller [neighboring] countries to benefit economically from their relationships with China. For China, we need good relationships more urgently than we need economic development. We let them benefit economically, and in return we get good political relationships. We should 'purchase' the relationships."
This is one of the reasons behind China's massive investment in the infrastructure of neighboring countries, a phenomenon that will be buttressed by the establishment of the Asia Infrastructure Investment Bank (AIIB) and the Maritime Silk Road Initiative in Southeast Asia. China channels its ambitions through calibrated assertiveness -- just look at China's salami-slicing strategy in the South China Sea -- rather than mindless expansionism. Of course, there is a risk that things will get out of hand as China expands its presence in contested waters -- marking a gradual sleep walk into confrontation, similar to what happened prior to World War I.
As for China's People's Liberation Army (PLA), it is more interested in and preparing for winning limited wars -- small skirmishes with chilling strategic effect -- than waging an invasion of a neighboring country. China's military strategy is driven by the doctrine of "active defense". Not to mention, the PLA, which still relies on some Soviet-era technology, is yet to be fully-modernized, putting into question its ability to effectively project power beyond its immediate shores.
On National Unity
One of the things the Philippines should be proud about is how it has never, at least in modern times, experienced the kind of inter-ethnic strife -- particularly against minority Chinese communities -- that have afflicted other Southeast Asian countries in the 20th century. Compared to some of its counterparts in Southeast Asia, the Chinese community in the Philippines is highly integrated and doesn't suffer from systematic exclusion.
Over generations, the Filipino-Chinese community has evolved into an authentic, integral component of the Filipino society. Filipino-Chinese businessmen consistently rank among the wealthiest in the country, overseeing large conglomerates, which have been the drivers of growth in recent years. Obviously, given their expanding business interests in China, many Filipino-Chinese tycoons have tried to foster a semblance of stability in Philippine-China relations, often supporting diplomatic efforts to diffuse territorial tensions.
There is a reason why the Chinese diaspora in the Philippines has managed to so easily integrate: Being Filipino is not necessarily defined by ethnicity, but rather by shared values -- opposition to dictatorship, instinctive embrace of liberalism, and celebration of multiculturalism. The Philippines' own very founding fathers -- no less than Jose Rizal, who has a monument in his ancestral home in Qiongque Village, Luoshan Town in Jinjiang City -- were from (Filipino-Chinese) Mestizo stock. The Philippines' incumbent president, and his late mother who was also a president, has Chinese lineage.
In his deeply moving column for the Philippine Daily Inquirer, legal scholar Oscar Franklin Tan points out how the mindset of the Filipino-Chinese community, especially liberal-minded members like him, and the Beijing government are "worlds apart". He laments how he "cannot celebrate [Philippine] independence when I can be so casually told in public that I am less of a Filipino or a person solely because my grandparents were immigrants".
Given the gravity of challenges faced by the Philippines, it is the perfect moment for national unity, building on the vast talents of the Filipino people of all ethnicities. And it is also time for the Philippines to stand on its own, developing its own capabilities to deter aggression and revanchism.
Follow Richard Javad Heydarian on Twitter: www.twitter.com/Richeydarian
More:
China Philippines Benigno Aquino Southchinasea Russia Ukraine
This Blogger's Books and Other Items from...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State Attack In Northeast Syria Displaces 60,000, UN Reports</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4797f2a2/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cisis0Esyria0Erefugees0In0I76690A0A20Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Islamic State Attack In Northeast Syria Displaces 60,000, UN Reports
Reuters
reddit
(Adds details from U.N. report)
BEIRUT, June 26 (Reuters) - An Islamic State attack on the  northeastern Syrian city of Hasaka is reported to have displaced  60,000 people, the United Nations office in Syria said on  Friday, warning that up to 200,000 people may eventually try to  flee.
Islamic State launched an assault on government-held areas  of Hasaka on Thursday, capturing at least one district in the  southwest of the city, which lies close to the borders with  Turkey and Iraq.
Hasaka is divided into zones run separately by the  government of President Bashar al-Assad and a Kurdish  administration. Islamic State fighters also attacked the  Kurdish-held town of Kobani, or Ayn al-Arab, in its twin  offensive on Thursday.
The U.N. Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs  said an estimated 50,000 people had been displaced within Hasaka  city while 10,000 had left northwards towards Amuda town, close  to the Turkish border.
Its report on developments on Thursday cited the Syrian  government's Department of Social Affairs and local partners. It  said the estimated pre-war population in Hasaka was around  300,000 people.
"An estimated 200,000 people may try to flee the city in the  coming hours to northern areas of the governorate, most likely  towards Amuda and Qamishli," it said. Qamishli is a city around  80km (50 miles) north of Hasaka that sits on the Turkish border.
Islamic State said on Thursday it had seized al-Nashwa  district and neighboring areas in the southwest of Hasaka, a  city divided into zones of government and Kurdish control.
It said humanitarian partners in Qamishli and the Department  of Social affairs met on Thursday in preparation for an expected  influx of displaced people.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a UK-based  organization that tracks the war, said clashes in Kobani erupted  between Islamic State militants and the Kurdish YPG militia for  a second day on Friday.       (Reporting by Sylvia Westall; Editing by Dominic Evans)
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:54:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paul McCartney Delivers Show-Stopping Charleston Tribute In Columbia, South Carolina</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47971cb7/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C260Cpaul0Emccartney0Echarleston0Etribute0In0I7668660A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Performing in South Carolina on Thursday night, Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Famer </Description>
        <MainBody>Paul McCartney Photos and GIFs
of


Paul McCartney and Ringo Starr perform at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
Ringo Starr and Paul McCartney perform at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney, left, and Dave Grohl, accept the award for best rock song for Cut Me Some Slack" at the 56th annual Grammy Awards at Staples Center on Sunday, Jan. 26, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Matt Sayles/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney performs at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
British musician Paul McCartney drinks ahead of the Atlanta Hawks versus Brooklyn Nets NBA basketball game at the O2 Arena in London, Thursday, Jan. 16, 2014. (AP Photo/Kirsty Wigglesworth)
FILE - This Feb. 1964 file photo shows the Beatles' Paul McCartney on the set of the "Ed Sullivan Show," in New York. McCartney and Ringo Starr will attend the Recording Academy's Special Merit Awards ceremony, on Saturday, Jan. 25, 2014, where the Beatles will be honored with a lifetime achievement award, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/File)
FILE - In this Feb. 9, 1964 file photo, The Beatles, clockwise from top, Ringo Starr, John Lennon, George Harrison and Paul McCartney, perform on CBS' "Ed Sullivan Show" in New York. CBS is planning a two-hour special on Feb. 9, 2014, to mark the 50th anniversary of the Beatles groundbreaking first appearance on The Ed Sullivan Show. (AP Photo, file)
Paul McCartney and Ringo Starr perform at The Night that Changed America: A Grammy Salute to the Beatles, on Monday, Jan. 27, 2014, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Zach Cordner/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney arrives with his band to give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15th. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
People gather to see Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15th. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney and his band give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Paul McCartney arrives with his band to give a surprise pop up concert in Times Square on Thursday, Oct. 10, 2013 in New York. McCartney will release his new album called "New" on October 15. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)
Sir Paul McCartney and his new wife Nancy Shevell arrive at their north London home following their wedding at Westminster Registry Office. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney performing on stage. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney performs during the Super Bowl XXXIX Halftime Show at Alltell Stadium in Jacksonville, FL on February 6, 2005. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney performs during the Super Bowl XXXIX Halftime Show at Alltell Stadium in Jacksonville, FL on February 6, 2005. (Photo credit: PA)
Paul McCartney with his pregnant wife, Heather Mills McCartney, at the 3rd Annual Adopt-A-Minefield benefit in Los Angeles. The McCartneys hosted the event which raises money to clear minefields and provides aid to people injured by landmines.  (Photo credit: PA)
Sir Paul McCartney and his wife Heather Mills arriving for the Daily Mirror Pride of Britain Awards 2003 at the London Hilton Hotel on Park Lane.  * 28/05/03 The couple,  announced they were expecting their first child and were said to be "delighted" with the news.
British rock and roll legend Paul McCartney and his wife, Linda McCartney, mess around with 'Kiss Me Quick' hats at the seaside (Circa 1989).
Paul McCartney and wife Linda pause for a break during rehearsals at the Playhouse Theatre in London.
The Beatles perform on the "Ed Sullivan Show" in New York on February 9, 1964. From left, front, are Paul McCartney, George Harrison and John Lennon. Ringo Starr plays drums. (AP Photo)
Paul McCartney in The Beatles. (Photo credit: PA)
The Beatles released he album Abbey Road on this day in 1969.  EMI Group, the music company which numbers The Beatles and The Spice Girls among its artists, confirmed  that it had received an approach over a possible offer for the company.  (Photo credit: PA)
The Beatles, from left, Paul McCartney, Ringo Starr, John Lennon and George Harrison, are shown in this November 1963 photo. (AP Photo)
The Beatles in rehearsal at the Royal Command Performance. (Photo credit: PA)
The big-screen debut of Macca features Paul and his three bandmates (and his "grandfather") running around London, being chased by hordes of fans, as they attempt to film a performance for a television show. The movie was a parody on the Beatles staggering popularity.
The second comedy flick from the Fab Four follows the Beatles as they attempt to rescue Ringo from a cult who've chosen him as a sacrificial victim.
The last live performance by the Beatles (and arguably the greatest concert in music history), was recorded for the documentary, "Let It Be." Despite the band bickering and fighting on screen, the four still manage to pull off an entertaining, unannounced show on the top of the Apple records building in London, stopping traffic on the street below and prompting a shutdown by local police.
The film, named after the Beatles 1967 album, featured the Bee Gees' Barry, Robin and Maurice Gibb, along with Peter Frampton (Billy Shears), as the reformed Sgt. Pepper's band. The movie included covers of Beatles songs by other bands and celebrities (including this wacky version of "Maxwell's Silver Hammer" by comedian Steve Martin.)
The 1974 James Bond movie starring Roger Moore featured a theme song composed by Paul and Linda McCartney and performed by Macca's band Wings. The track is still one of the most popular themes in the 007 canon.
Similar to "A Hard Day's Night," this day-in-the-life musical starred Paul and Linda McCartney and Ringo Starr, as themselves. The plot revolves around Paul attempting to locate the masters to his new album, which have been stolen by an employee.
Wes Anderson's movies are no stranger to classic rock-heavy soundtracks. In his 2001 film, "The Royal Tenenbaums," Wes had the Mutato Muzika Orchestra cover the Beatles' "Hey Jude," (a song credited to Lennon-McCartney, but mainly written by Sir Paul, himself).
Though McCartney and the Beatles did not provide voice work to the characters (well, other than the songs), the film was eventually endorsed by the group, after having reservations due to the negative reception of their last project, the TV special "Magical Mystery Tour." Here, the song "All Together Now," written primarily by McCartney, plays to great effect as the crew begins turning the ship on.
Speaking of the "Magical Mystery Tour" movie, which debuted on BBC1 in 1967, it ended up being a critical disaster for the band. But, oh well, at least it gave us McCartney singing "A Fool on the Hill"...on a hill!
Though it got mixed reviews from critics, "Across the Universe" still attempts to pay tribute to the Beatles in a new and unique way. Julie Taymor's visually stunning musical is just one of the dozens of movies to reimagine the Beatles music. This scene features the McCartney-penned "I've Just Seen a Face," covered by actor Jim Sturgess
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:05:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The UN Charter at 70: Toward a Safer and Sustainable Future for We the Peoples</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4799269f/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cban0Ekimoon0Cthe0Eun0Echarter0Eat0E70A0Etowa0Ib0I76678460Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Long before I became Secretary-General, the United Nations occupied a special place in my life. I was six years old when the Korean War broke out. I have memories of my village in flames as my family sought refuge in nearby mountains. But another sight is even more lasting: the UN flag. We were saved from hunger by UN food relief operations; we received textbooks from UNESCO; and when we wondered whether the outside world cared about our suffering, the troops of many nations sacrificed their lives to restore security and peace. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Long before I became Secretary-General, the United Nations occupied a special place in my life.  I was six years old when the Korean War broke out.  I have memories of my village in flames as my family sought refuge in nearby mountains.  But another sight is even more lasting: the UN flag.  We were saved from hunger by UN food relief operations; we received textbooks from UNESCO; and when we wondered whether the outside world cared about our suffering, the troops of many nations sacrificed their lives to restore security and peace.
I know from my childhood, and now from decades of public service, the immense difference the United Nations can make.  As we mark the anniversary of the adoption of the Organization's founding Charter on June 26, 1945 in San Francisco, my hope is that the human family will come together with greater determination to work for a safer and more sustainable future for "we, the peoples," in whose name the Charter was drafted.
The United Nations at 70 can look back on a proud record of working with many partners to dismantle colonialism, triumph over apartheid, keep the peace in troubled places and articulate a body of treaties and law to safeguard human rights.  Every day, the United Nations feeds the hungry, shelters refugees and vaccinates children against polio and other deadly diseases.  Our relief workers brave remote and dangerous environments to deliver humanitarian assistance, and our mediators strive to find common ground between warring parties and peaceful solutions to grievances and disputes.  The United Nations was founded to prevent another world war, and it has succeeded in that core mission; despite grave setbacks, the past seven decades would surely have been even bloodier without the United Nations.
Yet we are keenly aware that today's landscape is scarred by conflict, exploitation and despair.  At least 59.5 million people have fled their homes - more refugees, displaced persons and asylum-seekers than at any time since the end of the Second World War.  Violence against women blights all societies. At a time of pressing human needs, huge   amounts of money continue to be squandered on nuclear weapons and other destabilizing military arsenals. The consequences of climate change are ever more apparent - and have only just begun. And although the world said "never again" after the Holocaust, and again after genocides in Rwanda and Srebrenica, we continue to witness atrocious crimes by violent extremists and others.
New powers have emerged since the representatives of 50 nations gathered to draft the Charter, and membership in the Organization has grown to 193.  Globalization, urbanization, migration, demographic shifts, technological advances and other seismic developments continue to remake our societies and transform international relations.  Yet the Charter's vision of a world of peace, and the values enshrined in the text - dignity, equal rights, tolerance and freedom - remain touchstones for people everywhere.
The 70th anniversary falls in a year of potentially momentous decisions on our common future.  Countries are shaping what we hope will be an inspiring new sustainable development agenda and moving towards a meaningful agreement on climate change.  Our goal is transformation: we are the first generation that can erase poverty from the earth - and the last that can act to avoid the worst impacts of a warming world.
As the distinctions between the national and the international continue to fall away, challenges faced by one become challenges faced by all, sometimes gradually but often suddenly. With our fates ever more entwined, our future must be one of ever deeper cooperation - nations united by a spirit of global citizenship that lives up to the promise of the Organization's name.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:49:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rebuilding U.S. policy post-Obama</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4796170a/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Craghida0Edergham0Crebuilding0Eus0Epolicy0Epost0Ib0I7668150A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Raghida Dergham</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Raghida Dergham
http://alhayat.com/Opinion/Raghida-Dergham/9649015/%D8%A5%D8%B9%D8%A7%D8%AF%D8%A9-%D8%A8%D9%86%D8%A7%D8%A1-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%B3%D9%8A%D8%A7%D8%B3%D8%A9-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%A3%D9%85%D9%8A%D8%B1%D9%83%D9%8A%D8%A9-%D8%A8%D8%B9%D8%AF-%D8%A3%D9%88%D8%A8%D8%A7%D9%85%D8%A7
As part of the brainstorming sessions in US intellectual and political circles, much is being said about how the United States could coexist with the Islamic Republic of Iran when it is radically empowered under a final nuclear deal and an upgraded bilateral relationship like the one being sought by the Obama administration. One of the clear consequences of Obama's insistence on a deal with Tehran is perpetuating unprecedented division in the United States: One faction focuses on appeasement of Iran considering that there is no alternative to a nuclear deal, even if it is full of loopholes, and that American-Iranian rapprochement will co-opt the mullahs of Iran, embolden moderates, rein in hardliners, and undermine Iran's regional expansion plans. The other faction sees that the nuclear agreement will not curb the nuclear ambitions of the Iranian theocracy, and that at best, it would delay an Iranian nuclear bomb by a decade. This faction also believes that lifting the sanctions on Iran would practically allow it to execute its nuclear plans, which would launch a nuclear arms race in the Gulf and invalidate the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT). This factions sees that the primary beneficiary of such an outcome would not be the moderate forces but the Revolutionary Guards, they key sponsor of Iran's regional expansion from Iraq, Syria, and Lebanon to Yemen, establishing militias that undermine the states in these countries--mirroring the Islamic State group (ISIS) whose doctrine is the destruction of nation states in the Arab region to establish its caliphate.
The first faction embraces the US pivot away from traditional allies, including in the Arab region, and closer to Iran. It sees this as a wise policy, based on its interpretation of 9/11 which blames Arab actors for the terrorist attacks.
The second faction stresses that it was Iran and its allies that killed the largest number of Americans, and not the Arab countries or even al-Qaeda and ISIS. For this reason, senior members of the second faction want to redesign US policy in the Middle East post-Obama, and they have ideas worth pausing at as part of the necessary brainstorming that the Arab region must take part in.
Under the title "The realignment of the Arab region in the international arena: Beyond politics, economics, and security threats", an Arab-regional-international workshop will be held in October to discuss the options available and come up with recommendations on how to overcome various challenges. The Beirut Institute, an Arab think-tank founded by the author of this article, will convene the Beirut Institute Summit in Abu Dhabi as an opportunity to come up with positive and practical ideas.
Some of the participants have already started submitting proposals, including figures closely involved in long-term US policymaking. The autumn scheduling is meant to coincide with the start of the US presidential election campaigns. The idea is that the Arab region must start thinking seriously about the future, instead of remaining fixated on what Barack Obama is doing.
By this autumn, the Arab region in all likelihood will have to start accepting the new reality of the American-Iranian relationship built by Barack Obama.  And regardless of who the next president will be, be it a Democrat or a Republican, US policy in the Middle East will be shaped by the ties with Iran and the putative nuclear deal and its implementation.
The American strategist who was involved in decision-making for decades believes rebuilding the US Middle East policy post-Obama is not difficult, and says this will depend on three things the new US president will have to do:
First, reestablishing the alliance with Egypt, not just verbally, but also by doubling US military aid to $3 billion a year and inviting President Sisi to the White House, to reaffirm the Camp David accords and restore defensive ties. This alone, he says, can reassure Egypt and stop it from seeking alternative partners including Russia. This, he argues, cannot be achieved as long as there are American restrictions on Egypt. Egypt is crucial in the war on ISIS, especially in Libya, and is a key partner in broader US-Arab relations, especially in the light of the firm strategic alliance among Egypt, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates.
Second, Libya needs an intervention similar to the NATO-led intervention in the past, in support of the legitimate government in Tobruk. Hesitation and complacency will allow ISIS and similar extremist groups in Libya to grow and threaten other North African nations. The positions of Saudi Arabia, the UAE, and Egypt must get real support from Washington, and there is no option but to defeat the Tripoli-based government and ISIS in Libya. This requires supporting Khalifa Haftar's forces, which are fighting both al-Qaeda and ISIS.
Third, always according to the US strategist, political and military decisions concerning Kurdistan should be made: Sending military aid directly to Erbil and not via Baghdad, and declaring that the United States does not mind for Kurdistan to export oil and even welcome Kurdish oil in US energy markets, as this would help Kurdistan fund its war with ISIS.
These are the views of veteran US policymaker, meant to prevent the deterioration of US influence in the Middle East. Some may agree with them, others may not, but they are strategic ideas and not just a diagnosis followed by surrender. And this is exactly what's needed: Pragmatic ideas to take US policy into a new approach following recent shifts in its policy.
Some may protest the idea of allowing the Kurds to secede from Iraq, which is implicit in the qualitative shift in US-Kurdish relations. In fact, the moderates are in Sulaymaniyah as they are in Amman, and a million Kurds have been displaced. There is a need for the Arab countries, led by Saudi Arabia, to reassess. Kurds in the Arab region as part of the Arab fabric just like Shiite Arabs are. It is time for a new and radically different relationship with both components, and it is crucial to correct the impression that only Sunni Arabs are Arabs as in the Saudi perception. Kurds and Shiites in the Arab countries are an essential part of the multiethnic, multiconfessional mosaic, and the Arab interest requires addressing this problem.
The Arab interest also requires practical ideas in light of the nuclear deal and the upgrading of the American-Iranian bilateral relationship. There is a dire need for a change in strategy from Yemen to Lebanon.
In Yemen, there is no alternative to choosing between an exit strategy, one that would secure the Saudi-Yemeni border, and escalating militarily to secure Aden, Hodeidah, and Taiz, with measures in Sanaa. The options boil down to securing the cities and gradually clawing back territory, or withdrawing from Yemen in an organized international framework supported by a Marshall plan to rescue Yemen economically and humanitarianly. The aerial bombardment campaigns will not achieve anything more, and it would be best to reduce air strikes and focus them as part of a new strategy.
In Syria, the Kurds do have a place in a new military strategy based on bringing the Kurdish forces together with moderate rebel forces. This, in turn, would require a shift in how Syria is dealt with. The Gulf countries need to think profoundly about the subject, especially in light of the possible lifting of the sanctions on Iran.
Economists speak of a golden age in Iran if the sanctions are lifted under a nuclear deal. They say Iran's oil exports could increase from 1 million barrels per day to 2 million barrels, worth $75 million a day or $2.2 billion a month. This would be enough cash for the Revolutionary Guard to finance its plans. The Revolutionary Guard already used Iraq's budget to finance its war in Syria in the past, when former Iraqi PM Nuri al-Maliki made the Iraqi treasury the equivalent to an ATM to finance the adventures of the Revolutionary Guard in Syria.
After the sanctions are lifted, Tehran will be able to pump money not only into its war in Syria, but also into Hezbollah in Lebanon, which in turn will radically alter the path and fate of Lebanon. Since Lebanon is in a state of complete vacuum, Hezbollah would be able to impose its demands there.
ISIS is being used as a pretext in Lebanon, since Hezbollah and ISIS are fighting in Syria. But if the Arab strategy wants to be wise, it must give Lebanon due attention before it is too late. Because while ISIS wants Damascus and Baghdad, and not Beirut, it could be lured into Lebanon. Losing Lebanon to Hezbollah or ISIS would be a major loss for Arab strategy and for the United States, whether under Obama or a new occupant of the White House.
The Obama administration does not want to pay attention to such "trivial" issues standing in its way towards a legacy represented by a deal with Iran. The administration is in a willful coma, it seems.
However, the United States is not bound by its administration. True, major US policies are developed in their broad outlines for the long term on a strategic basis, and various administrations implement them with some changes here or amendments there. However, policies are not detached from reality, and all this shapes decision-making. For this reason, it is possible to see institutions operating for years and decades to shape decision making.
Think-tanks and workshops are part of the dynamic of influencing strategic decision-making, which is what the Arab region needs.
The picture appears bleak in the context of the nuclear deal with Tehran. Ali Khamenei has dictated seven near-impossible conditions he dubbed "red lines". These could be part of the art of negotiations but they could lead to detonating the entire nuclear talks.
Logically, there is no room today for an agreement. Khamenei made it clear that Tehran insists on having the US and international sanctions lifted as soon as a deal is concluded, before Iran dismantles any nuclear capabilities. He said nuclear research would not be frozen and military sites would be off-limits. As for the issue of reimposing sanctions in the event Tehran fails to abide by its commitments, Russia and China will be there to guarantee any such bid would be vetoed.
But politically, it seems illogical that we have reached this point in the negotiations only for them to fail. Ultimately, it is more important to develop strategies in preparation for any outcome. Once again, an Arab collective brainstorming is crucial and urgent.
This article was translated from Arabic by Karim Traboulsi
Follow Raghida Dergham on Twitter: www.twitter.com/raghidadergham
More:
Click here to view Conversations
Conversations
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 02:32:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As Debt Deal Looms, Greeks Dream Big</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47952a08/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Cdebt0Edeal0Egreek0Edreams0In0I766620A0A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Greek leaders work around the clock to negotiate a new bailout deal with their creditors, ordinary Greeks remain anxious about what lies ahead. </Description>
        <MainBody>As Debt Deal Looms, Greeks Dream Big
Posted:
reddit
As Greek leaders work around the clock to negotiate a new bailout deal with their creditors, ordinary Greeks remain anxious about what lies ahead.
The Huffington Post spoke to two Greek citizens with very different political views and very different hopes and expectations about a forthcoming deal. While both are deeply concerned about the outcome of the deal, they have dreams for a brighter future for Greece that go far beyond the events of the coming weeks.
Parina Stiakaki, 66, is a translator living in Athens. Stiakaki used to translate Greek business and stock market materials into English, but in the past few years, all of her work has dried up. Her only source of income now is the residential properties that she owns. Because many of her renters can no longer pay their rent, and she refuses to throw them out, Stiakaki still operates at a loss. She estimates that she has to withdraw 5,000 euros a year from her life savings in order to pay her bills. Despite her negative income, Stiakaki says she's still paying income taxes, because the government now counts the value of her house and car as income.
Stiakaki has applied for her state pension, but she's not expecting to receive it anytime soon. If I get one at all, it wont be for another year and a half, she said. There is currently a backlog of 400,000 pension applications, according to Greek government estimates .
Still, Stiakaki considers herself lucky. She has two grown sons who support themselves and their families without her help. And she knows many people who have not been so fortunate.
I have friends who cannot pay their taxes anymore and are worried about having their houses repossessed, she said. People are skimping on food, even.
There used to be a 70-year-old man living down the road from Stiakaki. He was a civil engineer, she remembers. He shot and killed himself as the recession was beginning. Stiakaki believes that the man had debts he couldn't pay, and that the suicide was at least partly a response to his economic distress.
Stiakaki voted for Greece's Syriza party in January because she wanted relief from economic austerity.
Now she says that any deal that asks Greeks to endure even higher taxes and smaller government benefits must include debt relief as well -- or it is not worth taking at all. She would prefer a "Grexit," or Greek exit from the euro, to a deal that puts the country in such a position.
It is inevitable that after six months or a year, Greece will leave the euro, she said. This is a useless exercise. It will mean more pain and suffering and no problem will be fixed.
Polling shows that Stiakakis support for a Grexit puts her in the minority among Greeks -- and even among Syriza supporters. But Stiakaki, who has a bachelors degree in economics from the London School of Economics and who maintains a blog on Greek politics , believes that restoring Greeces control of its currency is the best of many bad options.
The choice is between a slow, lingering death, Stiakaki said, referring to additional budget tightening, and a jolt that will be hard and bring a change in the economic outlook.
In my personal opinion, it would be very tough for a few months and maybe a year, she explained. But after that, the economy would get growing. We would go back to the drachma and devalue our currency.
This isn't the prevailing view among economists, although some -- including the Nobel laureate Paul Krugman -- share the same outlook as Stiakaki, arguing that a cheaper currency could allow Greece to recover economically.
And Stiakaki is ready to vote against Syriza to make a Grexit happen.
If Syriza would run as the party it is today, then I would still vote for them, she said. If it splits, I would side with the party in favor of leaving the euro.
As HuffPost has reported , the scenario Stiakaki describes -- in which a deal freighted with concessions prompts Syrizas more radical factions to revolt against Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras -- is not unlikely.
Like Stiakaki, Yannis Koutsomitis, 50, a television and film producer living in Crete, saw his livelihood destroyed by the 2008 financial crisis and the prolonged recession since then. Koutsomitis had enjoyed success and recognition for his production of TV primetime dramas. In 2008, he won the Greek equivalent of an Emmy for producer of the year for his work on the popular Greek series " Matomena Homata ."
Koutsomitis award-winning work was also his last in the industry to date.
The TV sector has suffered a devastating crisis, Koutsomitis said. There is almost no primetime drama produced in Greece anymore.
Koutsomitis' partner is a lawyer, and when Koutsomitis stopped getting work after the economic downturn, the two of them were able to rely on her income for a while. In 2010, Koutsomitis started blogging about post-crisis Greek politics and economics, and he now earns some money as a political analyst for Germanys NTV and BBC Radio. Koutsomitis and his partner support a son from one of the partners previous relationships. Koutsomitis parents are financially independent, living off combined pension benefits of 1,500 euros a month.
Koutsomitis and Stiakaki are both educated professionals whose careers were disrupted by Greeces economic turmoil. But they've drawn very different conclusions from the crisis.
A centrist on the Greek political spectrum, Koutsomitis is angry with Syriza for spending five months negotiating with Greeces creditors only to run out the clock in the final weeks over differences on pensions and a value-added tax increase that were known to be the main sticking points all along.
Koutsomitis does not share Stiakaki's hostility toward the countrys European creditors. Actually, he's of the view that they saved the Greek economy after its banks teetered on the brink of collapse, and he doesn't wholly blame the country's persistent economic malaise on the budget tightening the creditors have imposed. In fact, Koutsomitis thinks that structural problems like clientelism and a culture of social immobility will prevent unemployment from falling below 15 percent even after private sector demand recovers.
As a result, Koutsomitis believes the reforms demanded by creditors provide an opportunity to make Greece more economically competitive. He said he'd like to see a deal that institutes very thorough reform of the pension system. He'd also like to see defense cuts and other government spending cuts in exchange for debt relief.
The Greek government, as led by Syriza, has put up greater resistance to the idea of pension cuts than to any of the creditors other demands. Tsipras has claimed that additional cuts to the already reduced benefits will "only cause a further worsening of the already dramatic social situation." Tsipras and others point to the pension systems role as an all-purpose, multigenerational safety net at a time of high unemployment.
But Koutsomitis argues that current proposals would shield the poorest pensioners by guaranteeing a minimum pension.
And despite some measures limiting early retirement, he says that the pension system is still overly generous toward people who do not need the help.
The problem is that there are many, many people on pensions of 1,000 euros or more in their 50s, he said -- the implication being that people of that age ought to be working or at least looking for work.
As for taxes, Koutsomitis said he does not mind raising rates on wealthy individuals. But he objects to Syrizas proposed corporate tax hike, which he said could cause struggling Greek companies to collapse or move overseas.
Still, unlike Stiakaki, Koutsomitis considers leaving the euro a nonstarter. To his mind, a deal that lacks any of the components he prefers would still be better than no deal and a Grexit.
Nonetheless, Koutsomitis shares Stiakakis dream of a Greece that one day has more control over its destiny.
He hopes that five years from now, the country will have recovered enough economically to begin having a conversation about what kind of society it wants to be.
Some people want socialism and some want free-market economy, he said. Currently, he argues, Greece has neither model, but instead has a very odd mixture of clientelism and a state-run economy.
It has to be an open debate in the society, he said.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:55:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Julian Assange: Mainstream Media Rife With Censorship</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47950868/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cseungyoon0Elee0Cjulian0Eassange0Emedia0Ecensorship0Ib0I76666540Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Seung-yoon Lee, CEO and co-founder of Byline, recently conducted a rare exclusive three-hour interview with Julian Assange in Embassy of Ecuador, London. The interview has been serialized into three parts.
In part two of the series, Assange reflects on media -- how it works, whether there is hope in new media models and citizen journalism and whether he prefers Rupert Murdoch or Eric Schmidt. Read the original interview here . Read part one here .
Seung-Yoon Lee (SY): You have worked with the mainstream media throughout the world in releasing documents. How did your experience of cooperating with mainstream media influence your perspective on them? In retrospect, if you could go back, would you still choose to work with them?
Julian Assange (JA): We have contracts with more than a hundred media organizations around the world, still. But it varies among mainstream press outlets. For example, the one in Pakistan can be great on issues outside of Pakistan. Issues inside Pakistan are different. It's the same for Russia Today, outside Russia and Ukraine, it can be great, but inside Russia is a different story and through this we need to understand the political and economic dynamics that mean the organization might be trustworthy on one matter and not trustworthy on another matter.
"In my experience the best journalists are those that predominantly work for one news institution but also have one foot in others, or one foot in academia."
If we look at the big players in the Western press, such as the international New York Times or the BBC, they are all highly compromised organizations in terms of geopolitics, and in terms of their relationships with their own countries. It would be nice to live in a world where people didn't have to deal with an organization that is not compromised in any manner whatsoever, but we don't live in that world. People have to use cars and they have put to petrol in their cars, and that petrol is made by Shell or BP.
In order to get things done it is necessary, unfortunately -- or perhaps even fortunately -- to make compromises. But as long as you understand that you're making a compromise, and as long as you understand the whole trade-off and exactly what that trade-off is and that you are balancing a number of different players with each other, you are not becoming dependent. And that's a good rule not just for media startups, but also for journalists themselves. In my experience the best journalists are those that predominantly work for one news institution but also have one foot in others, or one foot in academia. They have a sense that they have another outlet, and that tends to keep their "home" newspaper honest as well.
For example, look at the James Risen case. James Risen was a New York Times reporter who had information about NSA air surveillance back in 2003. The NYT sat on that for 18 months, intentionally, across the U.S. election. Risen informed the NYT that he was going to publish this book containing that information , and as a result the NYT then published his story.
SY: How much self-censorship and/or censorship goes on in the mainstream media?
JA: It's almost all censorship. The majority of censorship is selectivity, so it is the decision to do one story and not another, to interview one person and not another. That's the way that the bulk of censorship occurs, and those decisions are made as a result of personal or shared experience. And what happens if you don't tow the party line? People are compromised, and their employment opportunities or social opportunities...
It's obvious if you think about it. Let's take a society like the United Kingdom -- about 70 million people. A study was done on news stories in the U.K., where the majority are generated by newspapers and picked up by TV networks. There are around 70 news stories each day in the U.K., on different subjects. That's one news story per million people in the U.K., per day. But just consider your own family or your own business, and how many interesting rumors or stories you pick up in your own life. The idea that there is only one interesting story per million people is absurd.
Take a country like Iceland, with a population of 300,000. That would suggest that the Icelandic press should only publish one story every three days. So that whittling down from where things would be if the U.K. was proportionate to Iceland -- throwing out all those stories that would naturally be there -- that is done by selectivity, which is performed according to political and psychological biases, and the fears of the journalists and editors concerned.
Here's a hard example. In the U.K. they have something called the Defence Advisory Board [ The Defence, Press and Broadcasting Advisory Committee ]. It has monthly meetings with the editors of the newspapers, and they have agreements about what should and shouldn't be published.
"It would be nice to live in a world where people didn't have to deal with an organization that is not compromised in any manner whatsoever, but we don't live in that world."
SY: Our previous interviewee Noam Chomsky argued in "Manufacturing Consent" that the primary role of the mass media is to mobilize public support for the elite interests. I asked him if anything has changed since then to the media landscape. He said , "as far as we can see, the basic analysis we made is essentially unchanged," despite the mainstream perception that the Internet has given rise to citizen journalism and undermined the power of the traditional "manufacturers of consent". Obviously, WikiLeaks has done a lot on this front, but do you think Chomsky's view is relevant today?
JA: It's still true in so far as how Chomsky was talking about the relationship between successful large organizations and domestic populations. It is no longer true in all respects. National media or established media organizations principally based in one territory are now able to project their view of the world onto other territories. There are examples like Russia Today or CCTV. And many national newspapers that have a large following outside their own territory are gearing their content to maximize the power of national elites. They espouse positions that undermine the power of national elites in other countries. That's an important development for the mainstream press --internationalization of readership.
SY: You're talking about Al Jazeera, CCTV, Russia Today and so on?
JA: They are the big ones in terms of impact, but national newspapers which are geared toward domestic populations are nonetheless still often read internationally now. So while their content is not pushed on other populations through marketing, nonetheless people are able to read them through Internet recommendations. I've seen that phenomenon producing important results. For example, WikiLeaks has an international readership in English. The other way things have changed is -- and I don't mean social media per se here -- the increasing ability for individuals to communicate with each other outside their own regions. Information has been obtained and published through small publications, and it has then spread en masse through individual communication networks -- and happened rapidly, before censorship could be applied.
SY: Ferguson was reported through Twitter before being picked up by the press. . .
JA: You had RT going down there. The combination of social media and individuals talking about what was happening. It was through these individual networks and social networks, and then RT whipped it up and acted as an amplifier, to the point where the mainstream press felt they had to get onto the issue. They got on the issue predominantly to demonize it, and then eventually to co-opt certain elements. So basically like "bankers are bad, but the rest of the system is okay."
But it's also a time of great vibrancy for new publications, and for middle size startups like Vice, for instance. Vice has many problems -- Rupert Murdoch has bought a 5 percent stake, and 15 percent has gone off to one of the cable companies -- but nonetheless it is basically an organization that is more hungry for growth than it is for careful control of its content, and that's something that we're seeing in several hundred different publications around the world. Now, those publications will eventually be consolidated and integrated. Conde Nast has already done that with the previous generation, including Wired magazine, Reddit, the New Yorker online, etc. They have pulled them together and created an increasingly conservative organization. So these consolidations will happen. They will happen reasonably quickly because the Internet encourages economies of scale.
But each time we have a new technical platform -- for example, mobile phones or a change of web standards -- it tends to be the case that a new entrant who is not constrained by existing operations grows much faster. The problem is that some of the large organizations realize this as well. So if you look at Google, Google is actually an organization with very little innovation. It depicts itself as an innovative organization; it did improve the algorithmic efficiency of search engines. It was not, by any means the first search engine.
Nearly all the innovations that people think are Google's have come from acquisitions. YouTube was acquired , Android was acquired . Most of what people perceive to be Google innovations are actually Google acquisitions. So if you have the largest player gobbling up the new entrants then we aren't going to see that vibrancy as previously seen. Now, traditionally perhaps we would see antitrust or anti-monopoly laws used to prevent those kinds of acquisitions. However, there is no international antitrust law, because we are dealing with multinational companies that operate at scale across the whole Internet. There is no effective antitrust method to stop monopolization.
"What matters is whether it is done well. Very often it is not done well. But then, the standards in the mainstream press are appallingly low."
SY: What is your perspective on "citizen journalism"?
JA: The phrase is overplayed. But I think we should separate it into what I call "bystander journalism" and freelance journalism. Bystander journalism is when you happen to be in a place at a certain time and you take a photo of an event and report what you saw. But you usually don't do that. And the information just happens to be valuable. Especially photos and videos, which are harder to fake and therefore don't need any more external credibility. In the case of freelance journalism a person makes it their occupation, or part time occupation, to become an expert in some particular area, or an expert journalist in reporting about the world. And they can sell their work to newspapers.
I don't think this matters much. What matters is whether it is done well. Very often it is not done well. But then, the standards in the mainstream press are appallingly low.
SY: There was a comment I saw in your i nterview with John Pilger that you disclosed some materials to citizen journalists first but they didn't do anything. Why did you not rely on the so-called "citizen journalists"? Why did you rely on the traditional fourth estate like the Guardian and the New York Times instead of the new media players like bloggers and non-mainstream media outlets like new media and informal media?
JA: Back in 2007 when WikiLeaks was just starting, I knew from my previous experience that we could get leaks -- a lot of them. We could get a quality of information that could eclipse the research capacity of the mainstream press, and anyway the mainstream press had biases. And so we threw our material open to all these citizen journalists and commenters.
The result was that generally, citizen journalists were completely useless, with some exceptions. The market has improved, to be fair, but I realized that you have to look at the economy of why people do things. Most "citizen journalists" are surviving on surplus labor. They have something else that subsidizes them, whether employment or a pension, or whatnot. And then they engage in this other activity. So you have to question why they do it. A lot of the reason seems to be the desire to build a name for themselves, or to demonstrate their political position to their peers. The easiest way of doing that is to see what's on the front page of the New York Times and, using more words, essentially say "I agree" or "I disagree." And because it's so cost effective in relation to the desired outcome, that's what is done. If you look at popular blog sites like Tumblr or Wordpress, or microblogs like Twitter, you actually see that the overwhelming majority of it is commentary on the mainstream press, and repeating and forwarding those stories from the mainstream press which people feel back up their position. They can position themselves amongst their peers by taking a position.
We published a fantastic document on the War on Iraq, a classified document from the U.S. Army Ground Intelligence Center on the assault against Fallujah in 2004 . Fallujah even at that time was viewed to be the worst example of the U.S. occupation of Iraq. It was an example of the clearest violation of the laws of war, and so it was a hot topic and here was proof of what had happened that day, written up by the U.S. military themselves. It was a document which I did not need to analyze, and that WikiLeaks staff did not need to analyze to great depth. It was easy to read, and it was on a controversial topic that a lot of people said they were interested in. So we thought we could put it out there and inevitably a lot of people would write about it, because many, many people were talking about Fallujah and saying how bad it was. The result was nothing. No one did a thing. It wasn't until we contacted some professors who were friends of ours, and a friend in one of the news wires, that it got a proper write-up and analysis. That's because it takes time and effort. And if you can position yourself amongst your peers without taking any time and effort, and that's what your goal is, then why would you bother?
"In some sense, it's not Rupert Murdoch that controls the distribution of news, but Eric Schmidt and Mark Zuckerberg."
SY: What do you think the potential of crowdfunding to democratize the media landscape? Most recently, investigative journalists like John Pilger have used the method to finance their reporting. By freeing journalists and media organizations from the influence of media moguls and advertisers, do you think it can open the window for independent journalism?
JA: I hope so! But it hasn't been determined yet. In the case of WikiLeaks, we have mostly been crowdfunded throughout our whole history. However WikiLeaks has a worldwide base reporting on high-profile conflicts. It's hard -- if we didn't have that worldwide base and publish in such scale, then we wouldn't break even through crowdfunding. So we have to say that there are some examples of where it has been done successfully. It may just be a matter of adjusting the parameters to increase the ease with which it can be done.
SY: This form of media will necessarily get rid of the "middle man" like editors and curators and connect the readers and journalists directly, and this is what Byline is doing. The only criterion for whether a journalistic project will be able to take place is whether readers want it or not. What's your thought on such form of media that takes out the middlemen like curators and editors?
JA: The more sources of funding there are for journalism, the better, because journalism is constrained by its funders and their particular political views, their worldview and their business interests. So the more types of funding we can get, be they crowdfunding for individual journalists; or some novel form of stock investment scheme; whether they are mutual societies; whether they are subscription or advertising-based funding models; or public journalism funded from tax revenues spent at the discretion of the government; or whether there is constitutional garnishing of tax funds for independent bodies, spent in accordance with population surveys. We need all these things to gain different perspectives.
SY: The analysis of Emily Bell, director at the Tow Center for Digital Journalism at Columbia Journalism School, is that the fourth estate has been killed by a few unaccountable Silicon Valley companies:
"News spaces are no longer owned by newsmakers. The press is no longer in charge of the free press and has lost control of the main conduits through which stories reach audiences. The public sphere is now operated by a small number of private companies, based in Silicon Valley."
In some sense, it's not Rupert Murdoch that controls the distribution of news, but Eric Schmidt and Mark Zuckerberg. Simply put, do you prefer Eric Schmidt to Rupert Murdoch?
JA: I would prefer neither. Google collects extensive amounts of information on every single person who uses the Internet. It tracks nearly every single web page you go to. Even if you think you are not using Google, you are, because those websites [you do visit] use Google. It collects information from Android phones in extraordinary detail on people's movements and interests -- and of course, everything they search for, and their emails if they use Gmail, and what videos they watch on YouTube.
"Google has decided a very important social policy, which is that there was not to be proper reportage of war."
Google's real business is the integration business. It's not a search business, it's not an advertising businesses -- it's an integration business. They take hundreds of sources of information across the world, they purchase startups that gained users and they integrate all this information to build up bigger, richer profiles on people, building it into a larger repository of information, which they then use to train their artificial intelligence algorithms. YouTube has become the largest collection of human video footage, which is being used to train Google's artificial intelligence algorithm, which will go into its drones. It has bought many companies that navigate the world, using material collected by Google maps and Android phones, so it's a massive integrationist project.
SY: But there are some people that can ask why this is bad. I mean, doesn't it help search what we want to?
JA: Philosophically, this is the tyranny of efficiency -- that which is more efficient must be good. But that is not true. If suddenly you go from one person having no weapons, to another person having a stick, to one person having a rifle, to another person having a gun, it's not necessarily an improvement.
Put that aside. Look at Google's increasing monopoly power -- Google's geometrically increasing monopoly power. In terms of media, we've seen in the past 10 years a great flourishing as a result of disconnecting distribution from content production. That's what's really freed it up. The two things that really freed up the media landscape are the tremendous decrease in cost, and disconnecting distribution from content production. Google and Facebook and Twitter and AT&amp;T and Cable &amp; Wireless had been following that model over the last few years. In the last few years there has been vertical integration and increasing political control in content production and content distribution. For example, Facebook, and all these organizations, are increasingly mandating new sets of rules about what can be published and what cannot be published. And these rules are increasing in number with great rapidity. These form a new system of social laws, created by fiat, not produced by a parliament, not produced by democracy, and with no balancing power or judiciary. They are now applied to essentially everyone who uses the Internet.
Just two days ago, there was the issue with antiwar.com, a libertarian right-wing anti-war, anti-militarist website in the U.S.. They published many great essays in the past 10 years, including essays on the Abu Ghraib scandal. Google decided that they would not accept its advertising brokering services to appear on any webpage where there were photos of war, because they are gruesome. So Google has decided a very important social policy, which is that there was not to be proper reportage of war. By fiat.
Please stay tuned for the final part of the series, coming within the next two weeks. Byline thanks Alex Nunns (@alexnunns) for his assistance in editing this interview.
Close
Guantanamo Bay Revelations From WikiLeaks
of


As the New York Times reports, Mohammed Qahtani -- a Saudi believed to have been an intended participant in the Sept. 11 attacks -- was subject to coercive questioning and other abuses during his interrogation. The cables describe Qahtani as being leashed like a dog, sexually humiliated and forced to urinate on himself. His file says, "Although publicly released records allege detainee was subject to harsh interrogation techniques in the early stages of detention," his confessions "appear to be true and are corroborated in reporting from other sources."
As Le Monde is reporting, one "low-value" Iranian-Catholic detainee was kept in Guantanamo even after being deemed ready for release -- given his "cooperative nature" and in the interest of "possible financing relations" between Al Qaeda and traffickers. According to the cables, Abdul Majid Muhammed was deemed fit for release in 2002: "The detainee is not affiliated with Al Qaeda or the Taliban. He was involved in drug trafficking. It is unlikely that he represents a risk for the U.S. or its allies."
An Al Jazeera journalist was reportedly held at Guantanamo Bay for six years partially so he could be interrogated about the network Sami al-Hajj, a Sudanese national and Al Jazeera cameraman, was captured in Pakistan in late 2001. Though he was never convicted or even tried of any terrorist ties, al-Hajj was held until 2008 because interrogators wanted to find out more about "the al-Jazeera news network's training programme, telecommunications equipment, and newsgathering operations in Chechnya, Kosovo and Afghanistan, including the network's acquisition of a video of UBL [Osama bin Laden] and a subsequent interview with UBL," according to the cables.
Some detainees are described as ruthlessly violent in the documents. As the New York Times reports, one detainee said "he would like to tell his friends in Iraq to find the interrogator, slice him up, and make a shwarma (a type of sandwich) out of him, with the interrogator's head sticking out of the end of the shwarma." Another "threatened to kill a U.S. service member by chopping off his head and hands when he gets out," and informed a guard that "he will murder him and drink his blood for lunch. Detainee also stated he would fly planes into houses and prayed that President Bush would die."
As the Washington Post reports, the documents describe a major gathering of some of Al Qaeda's most senior operatives in early December 2001. They included Khalid Sheik Mohammed, the self-described mastermind of the Sept. 11 attacks; Abd al-Rahim al-Nashiri, the alleged planner of the USS Cole attack; and Abu Faraj al-Libbi, a key facilitator for bin Laden. After returning to Karachi, Mohammed "put together a training program for assassinations and kidnappings as well as pistol and computer training."
The leaked files indicate Khalid Sheikh Mohammed told Guantanamo Bay interrogators that Al Qaeda had hidden a nuclear bomb in Europe which will unleash a "nuclear hellstorm" if Osama bin Laden is captured or killed. The terror group also planned to make a 9/11 style attack on London's Heathrow airport by crashing a hijacked airliner into one of the terminals, the files showed.
The Washington Post reports Abd al-Rahim al-Nashiri, the alleged planner of the USS Cole attack, "received injections to promote impotence" to avoid being distracted by women, and "recommended the injections to others so more time could be spent on the jihad."
Gitmo detainees are reportedly assessed "high," "medium" or "low" in terms of their intelligence value, the threat they pose while in detention and the continued threat they might pose to the United States if released. As Reuters reports, most of the 172 remaining prisoners have been rated as a "high risk" of posing a threat to the United States and its allies if released without adequate rehabilitation and supervision.
Gitmo authorities named Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence agency a "terrorist organization" along with Hamas and other international militant networks, according to leaked documents. As the Associated Press reports, the ISI is part of a list that includes more than 60 international militant networks, as well as Iran's intelligence services, that  are "terrorist" entities or associations and say detainees linked to them "may have provided support to Al Qaeda and the Taliban, or engaged in hostilities against U.S. and coalition forces."
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:50:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Escaped Giant Rhea Bird Can Disembowel A Human With One Strike</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4795086b/sc/32/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Crhea0Ebird0Eescape0In0I7666220A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police are warning residents to beware of a giant rhea bird that escaped into the countryside of Nottinghamshire, England, this week. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Police are warning residents to beware of a giant rhea bird that escaped into the countryside of Nottinghamshire, England, this week. The ostrich-sized bird reportedly fled a private collection in the area either Monday night or Tuesday morning.
"We are warning local people and particularly those with small children to be on their guard and not to approach the bird, which poses a very real threat to the public," police said .
Rheas, native to Brazil and Argentina , can reach heights of up to six feet, run 40 mph, and have sharp claws capable of disemboweling a human being with a single blow.
But bird expert David Lindo told the BBC that the rhea isn't as dangerous as people think, and is more likely to flee humans than to attack them.
"They're quite stealthy and they'll be running off, hiding into the bushes. ... They can melt into the countryside quite easily," Lindo said.
A fugitive rhea roamed the English countryside for two months in 2014. It was eventually shot and turned into gourmet sausages.
We can only hope this rhea will find its way home to its mate, reportedly pacing its enclosure in distress.
The mate of a rhea bird missing in Nottinghamshire is said to be pacing their field by herself http://t.co/a1hbLF2D2C pic.twitter.com/ySMwBOaZJM
 Sky News (@SkyNews) June 25, 2015
Also on The Huffington Post
Close
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:35:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/4794986e/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Cputin0Eobama0Ephone0Ecall0Eiran0In0I76671140Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS
Reuters
Updated:
06/25/2015  6:59 pm EDT
Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a session of the Civic Chamber at the Kremlin in Moscow on June 23, 2015. AFP PHOTO / POOL / SERGEI KARPUKHIN        (Photo credit should read SERGEI KARPUKHIN/AFP/Getty Images) | SERGEI KARPUKHIN via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.
"The leaders discussed the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria, and underscored the importance of continued P5+1 unity in ongoing negotiations to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon," the White House said.
Obama also told Putin that Russia needs to live to up to the terms of a ceasefire deal with Ukraine, "including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," the White House said.  (Reporting by Roberta Rampton)
Also on HuffPost:
Putin And The Night Wolves
of


In this Monday, Aug. 29, 2011 photo, then Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin, center left, and leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), right, ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia. (AP Photo/RIA Novosti, Alexei Druzhinin, POOL, file)
A picture taken on July 7, 2009, shows Vladimir Putin, then Russian Prime Minister, listening to the leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov (R), also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), during Putin's visit to the 'Night Wolves' biker club's  headquarters. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, as they ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia, Monday, Aug. 29, 2011. (AP Photo/Ivan Sekretarev, pool)
Vladimir Putin (C) poses for a photo with members of the 'Night Wolves' bikers' movement after watching a friendly football match between of Serbia's FC Crvena Zvezda Belgrade and Russia's FC Zenit St Petersburg junior teams at Marakana Stadium in Belgrade, on March 23, 2011. (ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/AFP/Getty Images)
Russian President Vladimir Putin (C) and Night Wolves Moscow Bikers club leader Alexander 'Khirurg' Zaldostanov (L) attend the opening of the Barmaley Fountain during a wider ceremony to remember the 40, 000 people who died on this day in 1942, when the city was bombed by Nazi Germany, on August 23, 2013 in Volgograd, Russia. (Sasha Mordovets/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (R) speaks with a biker as he takes part in the 16th annual motorbike festival held by 'The Night Wolves' youth organization in the southern Russian town of Novorossiysk, on August 29, 2011. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (L) hands over a medal to the leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, during Putin's meeting with members of the Military History Society in the Novo-Ogaryovo residence outside Moscow, on March 14, 2013. (MIKHAIL KLIMENTYEV/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin pays a surprise visit to the headquarters of the 'Night Wolves' biker club in Moscow on July 7, 2009. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, pose for a press attending a meeting of motorbikers at their camp at Gasfort lake near Sevastopol in Ukraine's Crimea Peninsula, Saturday, July 24, 2010.  (AP Photo/Alexander Zemlianichenko, Pool)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:35:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47949870/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A60C250Cputin0Eobama0Ephone0Ecall0Eiran0In0I7667110A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin Calls Obama To Talk Iran, Ukraine And ISIS
Reuters
Updated:
06/25/2015  6:59 pm EDT
Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a session of the Civic Chamber at the Kremlin in Moscow on June 23, 2015. AFP PHOTO / POOL / SERGEI KARPUKHIN        (Photo credit should read SERGEI KARPUKHIN/AFP/Getty Images) | SERGEI KARPUKHIN via Getty Images
reddit
WASHINGTON, June 25 (Reuters) - Russian President Vladimir Putin phoned U.S. President Barack Obama on Thursday, their first call since February, to discuss Iran nuclear talks, "the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria" and the need to counter Islamic State militants, the White House said in a statement.
"The leaders discussed the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria, and underscored the importance of continued P5+1 unity in ongoing negotiations to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon," the White House said.
Obama also told Putin that Russia needs to live to up to the terms of a ceasefire deal with Ukraine, "including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," the White House said.  (Reporting by Roberta Rampton)
Also on HuffPost:
Putin And The Night Wolves
of


In this Monday, Aug. 29, 2011 photo, then Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin, center left, and leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), right, ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia. (AP Photo/RIA Novosti, Alexei Druzhinin, POOL, file)
A picture taken on July 7, 2009, shows Vladimir Putin, then Russian Prime Minister, listening to the leader of Nochniye Volki (the Night Wolves) biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov (R), also known as Khirurg (the Surgeon), during Putin's visit to the 'Night Wolves' biker club's  headquarters. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, as they ride bikes at a motor bikers' festival in the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk, Russia, Monday, Aug. 29, 2011. (AP Photo/Ivan Sekretarev, pool)
Vladimir Putin (C) poses for a photo with members of the 'Night Wolves' bikers' movement after watching a friendly football match between of Serbia's FC Crvena Zvezda Belgrade and Russia's FC Zenit St Petersburg junior teams at Marakana Stadium in Belgrade, on March 23, 2011. (ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/AFP/Getty Images)
Russian President Vladimir Putin (C) and Night Wolves Moscow Bikers club leader Alexander 'Khirurg' Zaldostanov (L) attend the opening of the Barmaley Fountain during a wider ceremony to remember the 40, 000 people who died on this day in 1942, when the city was bombed by Nazi Germany, on August 23, 2013 in Volgograd, Russia. (Sasha Mordovets/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (R) speaks with a biker as he takes part in the 16th annual motorbike festival held by 'The Night Wolves' youth organization in the southern Russian town of Novorossiysk, on August 29, 2011. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin (L) hands over a medal to the leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, during Putin's meeting with members of the Military History Society in the Novo-Ogaryovo residence outside Moscow, on March 14, 2013. (MIKHAIL KLIMENTYEV/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin pays a surprise visit to the headquarters of the 'Night Wolves' biker club in Moscow on July 7, 2009. (ALEXEY DRUZHININ/AFP/Getty Images)
Vladimir Putin, center, and leader of the Night Wolves biker group, Alexander Zaldostanov, right, pose for a press attending a meeting of motorbikers at their camp at Gasfort lake near Sevastopol in Ukraine's Crimea Peninsula, Saturday, July 24, 2010.  (AP Photo/Alexander Zemlianichenko, Pool)
 Share
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:28:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>P5+1 and Iran Have Settled Framework for Sanctions Relief Timing, Says Iranian Sources</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47a39bda/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Ctrita0Eparsi0Cp510Eand0Eiran0Ehave0Esettled0Ib0I7680A80A0A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Contrary to public posturing on the timing and pace of sanctions relief, a framework for handling this critical matter of the nuclear deal has been resolved, according to Iranian sources. </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Contrary to public posturing on the timing and pace of sanctions relief, a framework for handling this critical matter of the nuclear deal has been resolved, according to Iranian sources.
Iranian officials have on numerous occasions insisted that sanctions relief must come immediately upon the signing of an agreement. This has been at direct odds with the position of the U.S. government and its allies, who insist that relief only can come after Iran has taken numerous steps limiting its nuclear activities.
As often times is the case in diplomacy, the solution was found in a combination of a play with words and practical measures.
This is exactly what the diplomats did to reconcile the Iranian insistence on front loaded sanctions relief and the Western position of relief being provided only after the International Atomic Energy Agency has verified Iranian steps to curtail its nuclear program.
According to Iranian sources, the agreement is divided into three phases. The initial phase -- called "adoption of agreement" -- takes places as the two sides agree on a final deal. This phase will kick in in the next few days -- if a deal is reached.
The next phase -- the operationalization of the agreement -- will begin once the domestic political processes of various parties have conclusively approved the agreement. This phase has been added primarily as a result of the US Congress passing the Corker bill, in which the American legislature gave itself the right to review and vote on the nuclear deal.
The timing of the second phase is directly related to the duration of the Congressional review process. If the two sides come to an agreement prior to July 10, the review process is set at 30 calendar days , in addition to 22 calendar days for Congress to pass a resolution to accept or reject the deal and for the President to use his veto, if need be. If the two sides fail to reach a deal by July 10, the Congressional review process increases to 60 calendar days.
While other states in the negotiations may also initiate some form of internal review and approval process, none of them are expected to take as long as the Congressional review. As such, the U.S. congress has significantly delayed the implementation of a presumptive deal.
Once the deal has survived the Congressional review -- whether through a resolution of affirmation or the failure to pass a resolution of rejection -- the Iranians will begin implementing the first steps of their commitments. This is phase III. The initiation of the implementation of their end of the deal must then be verified by the IAEA, after which the US and its allies will begin relieving sanctions. It is at this point that the deal will be "signed," enabling the Iranian demand for sanctions relief to occur upon signing of the deal to be upheld.
The exact timing of this schedule depends on the date the deal is adopted, the duration of the Congressional review and the time it takes for Iran to implement the first steps of the agreement. But at best it will begin a few months after the adoption of the deal. This is reflected by President Hassan Rouhani's statement earlier in June that he expected relief from sanctions within a "couple of months" after an agreement is reached .
While agreement on these principles of the process is a very important step forward, some question marks remain. What kind of a binding commitment will the U.S. and its allies make to reciprocate Iranian implementation of the deal, as the first steps taken will be Iranian? At what point will the UN Security Council adopt a resolution that affirms the deal?
While these are important details that must be settled, it is more important that the framework for the process has been agreed upon.
Follow Trita Parsi on Twitter: www.twitter.com/tparsi
More:
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:25:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What Your Favorite Political Leaders Would Look Like As Hipsters</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e2f/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Camit0Eshimoni0In0I77144240Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
Hillary Clinton
Being a world leader, we can only assume, takes up a lot of time. So we totally understand that political figures past and present, from Abe Lincoln to Che Guevara to Hillary Clinton, haven't quite had room in their schedules to keep up with the latest trends and adjust their signature looks accordingly.
But what if, in some alternate universe, your favorite politicians took a hiatus from their legislative duties to update their haircuts, wardrobes and tattoo games? Artist Amit Shimoni imagines such a world in his illustrated series " Hipstory ." And though they may not be accomplishing quite as much in the way of political activism or diplomacy, we have to admit they look damn good.
Barack Obama
Barack Obama sports a dreadlocked topknot while Hillary Clinton opts for a candy-colored ombr cut. George Washington flaunts an eagle chest tattoo peeking out from atop his low-cut tee, and Ronald Reagan sports a flashy diamond stud.
" The history of the last century is heavily defined by its prominent figures ," Shimoni explained in an earlier email to HuffPost, "the main leaders who shaped the course of history. I often find myself imagining a world where some of these leaders are less interested in influencing lives, and more focused on their own persona."
George Washington
Shimoni's vibrant portraits access a realm where past iconic figures become obsessed with contemporary anxieties, like looking super cool. Placed against striking, saturated backdrops, the square illustrations resemble Instagram uploads that never were. Shimoni's project doesn't intend to criticize the current youth generation and its interest in cultivating a desirable persona, but rather to shed light on the different ways we've visualized ourselves throughout history.
"It is my hope that this series will encourage us to reflect: upon our leaders, our society, and ourselves," the artist adds. "And failing that, HIPSTORY will at least make us smile." See Shimoni's delightfully preposterous images below and let us know if you wish Hillary would opt for a similar look IRL.
Ronald Reagan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:21:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deadly Boko Haram Bombing Hits Nigeria University Town Zaria</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e32/sc/40/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cboko0Eharam0Enigeria0Ebombing0Ezaria0In0I77428520Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) — A bomb blast in Nigeria's northern university town of Zaria killed 25 people Tuesday including a 2-year-old toddler, the Kaduna state governor reported, the latest in a string of deadly bombing and shooting attacks by the Boko Haram Islamic extremist group.</Description>
        <MainBody>Deadly Boko Haram Bombing Hits Nigeria University Town Zaria
| By                                                                      MICHELLE FAUL
Updated:
15 minutes ago
Women and children flee from home burnt by Boko Haram Islamists at Zabarmari, a fishing and farming village near Maiduguri, northeast Nigeria, on July 3, 2015. (STRINGER/AFP/Getty Images) | STRINGER via Getty Images
reddit
LAGOS, Nigeria (AP)  A bomb blast in Nigeria's northern university town of Zaria killed 25 people Tuesday including a 2-year-old toddler, the Kaduna state governor reported, the latest in a string of deadly bombing and shooting attacks by the Boko Haram Islamic extremist group.
Gov. Nasir el-Rufai urged citizens to avoid crowded public places including mosques and churches as the militants widen and accelerate the pace of attacks that have killed some 300 people in a week. Boko Haram may be responding to an Islamic State group order to commit more mayhem during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan.
The blast targeted government headquarters in the historic Muslim town as civil servants assembled to welcome a new chairman, El-Rufai said in an email to The Associated Press.
"Terrorists detonated explosives that killed and injured several persons ... (with) 25 fatalities including a 2-year-old," el-Rufai said.
Thirty-two wounded victims are being treated at the university teaching hospital, he said.
Boko Haram wants to install an Islamic state across the West African nation of about 170 million people divided between a predominantly Muslim north and Christian south. The extremists say democracy has brought nothing but woes to Nigerians plagued by endemic corruption that keeps Africa's biggest oil producer and richest economy mired in poverty.
Nigeria's police force Monday night announced increased security around mosques and churches after Boko Haram assaults on Sunday killed more than 60 people in a mosque and posh Muslim restaurant in central Jos city and at an evangelical Christian church in northeastern Potiskum town.
The attacks come just five weeks into the administration of President Muhammadu Buhari, a Muslim and former military dictator who has vowed to crush the 6-year-old insurgency that has killed more than 13,000 people and driven 1.5 million from their homes.
Related on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:21:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Childhood Memories Disappear</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e33/sc/38/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cchildhood0Ememories0Edisappear0In0I77428260Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>My first memory is of the day my brother was born: November 14, 1991. I can remember my father driving my grandparents and me over to the hospital in Highland Park, Illinois, that night to see my newborn brother. I can remember being taken to my mother’s hospital room, and going to gaze upon my only sibling in his bedside cot. But mostly, I remember what was on the television. It was the final two minutes of a Thomas the Tank Engine episode. I can even remember the precise story: “Percy Takes the Plunge,” which feels appropriate, given that I too was about to recklessly throw myself into the adventure of being a big brother.</Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
My first memory is of the day my brother was born: November 14, 1991. I can remember my father driving my grandparents and me over to the hospital in Highland Park, Illinois, that night to see my newborn brother. I can remember being taken to my mothers hospital room, and going to gaze upon my only sibling in his bedside cot. But mostly, I remember what was on the television. It was the final two minutes of a Thomas the Tank Engine episode. I can even remember the precise story: Percy Takes the Plunge, which feels appropriate, given that I too was about to recklessly throw myself into the adventure of being a big brother.
In sentimental moments, Im tempted to say my brothers birth is my first memory because it was the first thing in my life worth remembering. There could be a sliver of truth to that: Research into the formation and retention of our earliest memories suggests that peoples memories often begin with significant personal events, and the birth of a sibling is a textbook example. But it was also good timing. Most peoples first memories date to when they were about 3.5 years old, and that was my age, almost to the day, when my brother was born.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:12:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Here's What The Future Of Energy Might Look Like. And It's Pretty Amazing (VIDEO)</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e35/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cfuture0Eof0Eenergy0Evideo0In0I7410A4680Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Here's What The Future Of Energy Might Look Like. And It's Pretty Amazing (VIDEO)
Posted:
reddit
You're already familiar with solar power, wind power, and even water power. But when it comes to the future of energy, those renewable power sources soon could be old news. Scientists and engineers are now building mashup versions of the renewable sources we're using today with the goal of generating power with even greater efficiency and sustainability.
"The next category is sort of putting together elements that already exist but havent been put together," John Rogers, senior energy analyst for the Union of Concerned Scientists , told The Huffington Post in a telephone interview. "What comes to mind is solar and wind... or putting solar panels in places they haven't been put before."
That's not all. Work is continuing on fusion energy, and scientists are also exploring ways to harness energy from space. Check out the video above, and/or read the transcript below for four promising sources of energy that may power our future. Don't forget to leave your thoughts in the comments below. C'mon, talk nerdy to me!
CLICK HERE FOR FULL TRANSCRIPT
Fossil fuels like coal or oil are great at providing power, but they also give us pollution , climate change , and even wars . Thats why scientists are seeking alternative and renewable sources of energy to power our future homes and cars. What will the future bring when it comes to energy? Heres what scientists have determined either to be working or to have significant promise.
Hey everyone. Jacqueline Howard here. Renewable sources of energy have been in use for quite some time now. We have water, wind, and solar. But these sources account for only 13 percent of Americas electricity generation . Looking ahead, scientists not only hope to combine these sources into hybrid versions of themselves, but there are also some untapped renewable sources of energy that show promise. Here are just a few examples of what you could see in the future that may seem totally sci-fi but are actually very real.
1. We may beam down energy from space.
Now this sounds like something from an episode of The Jetsons. But Japan is mulling over plans to build a space-based solar power farm --essentially a giant satellite that would include several so-called solar collectors (kind of like solar panels) to capture solar energy that otherwise would bypass the Earth. The energy would be transmitted to us here on Earth in the form of either laser beams or microwaves. Of course, this concept is still in the early stages of development.
2. We may have solar panels in bizarre places.
Here on Earth, weve captured the suns power using solar panels on rooftops, carports, and even in windows. But now, we may see these solar panels all over the place. In Korea, for instance, engineers have lined up solar panels that cover a bike path , providing a tunnel to travel through. On the other hand, in the Netherlands, engineers have put energy-generating solar panels in the surface of a bike path . And in California, solar panels are placed over water reservoirs , not only to generate energy but also to block sunlight that may cause the water to evaporate. Thats important, given the states ongoing drought.
3. We may see a wind-solar hybrid on steroids.
Plans are afoot to build a massive 2,235-foot-tall tower in the Arizona desert that would produce clean energy. It would be the worlds second-tallest structure . Heres how it would work. A series of pumps would send water to the top of the tower . The water would be injected out into a tunnel opening thats part of the tower, creating a mist. There, the mist would mix with dry, desert air that had been heated by the sun. That dry air would absorb the water particles and become heavy, causing it to fall through the tunnel, creating wind that spins turbines at the base, which then power generators to produce electricity.
4. We may be fussing over fusion.
Yes, fusion energy. It may not be renewable energy, but it still may be a power source for our future. Its produced when hydrogen reaches a temperature in excess of 100 million degrees Celsius. At that point, the hydrogen is contained in a high-powered magnetic confinement system , where positively charged hydrogen atoms, stripped of their electrons, fuse to form helium. This fusion produces energy.
An international research team is setting out to design and possibly operate the worlds first electricity-producing fusion power plant . It could produce energy around year 2027 at the earliest, but scientists are trying to think of a faster way to develop fusion energy as a viable source.
After all, fusion is what powers our sun. At extreme temperatures in our star, atoms react the same way to produce energy. That means, for all of human existence, most of our energy has come from nuclear fusion.
And think about the sources of energy we started using during the Industrial Revolution, some 225 years ago -- Im talking about the oil, natural gas, and coal that powered buildings, machine tools, and transportation. Those fossil fuels are made of dead plant and animal matter thats been compressed in the Earth for millions of years. Animals feed off of plants. Plants produce the material they need to grow through photosynthesis. The sun causes photosynthesis. See the connection here?
Nearly all sources of energy are linked back to the sun. But do you think the sun will remain our biggest source of energy? Or will we move on to space solar or even man-made fusion? What will the future hold? Let me know your thoughts.
Archi-future: 11 Green Buildings That Will Blow Your Mind
of


Commissioned by Avrosti Holding, the Zira Island Masterplan is a zero-energy resort situated within the Caspian Sea near Azerbaijan's Seven Peaks. Designed to be a model for sustainable development, the resort utilizes wind, water and solar energy systems -- including naturally powered desalination and water treatment plants.    Source:  BIG
P.S.62 Richmond will be the first net-zero energy school in New York City and in the Northeast United States. When completed, the cutting-edge building will harvest as much energy from renewable on-site sources as it uses on an annual basis.   Using a photovoltaic array, SOM's design will offer an energy-use reduction of 50% over a SCA standard public school.  Sustainable and low-energy features incorporated in the design include an ultra-tight high-performance building envelope, daylit offset corridors, energy efficient lighting fixtures, low-energy kitchen equipment, a greenhouse and vegetable garden, a geo-exchange system, energy recovery ventilators and demand-control ventilation, and a solar thermal system for hot water  Source: NYCSCA  SOM
Conceived by architectural upstart BIG for Stockholm's Swedish Transport Administration, the Grontmij Spacescape's hyper-futuristic structures transform Stockholm's E18 and E4 highways in to a "pie chart park." The 30 percent of the sphere that faces the sun is covered in photovoltaic film, which produces enough energy to keep the sphere afloat -- in addition to supplying 235 houses with electricity.  Source:  BIG
The KAFD Conference Center employs several profoundly innovative sustainability strategies, including an enclosure which locates areas of glazing where they are least susceptible to the harsh desert sun, a ventilation system incorporating a "solar chimney" that uses solar heat to move air through the main atrium spaces, and a roof which contains indigenous desert grasses to minimize irrigation requirements.  Source:  SOM
Another design from BIG, the Shenzhen Energy Mansion is a massive skyscraper that leverages natural climate conditions to regulate internal temperatures. The facade's folds shade the building from the sun, avoiding the overheating problems caused by traditional facades.  The result is an energy-lean structure with minimal reliance on air-conditioning.  Source:  BIG
This residential building from ARO meets the rigorous German Passive House standard, which uses approximately 75% less energy than conventional American construction. Through airtight construction, mechanically circulation ventilation, and solar optimization, a Passive House maintains a consistent internal temperature, requiring only minimal heating and cooling.    Windows and skylights open the interior to views and are optimized to receive southern light. The roof and walls are sheathed with corrugated aluminum. The silver color, muted reflectivity and fine texture of this cladding contribute to a sense of vibrancy that counters the gray winter months.    Source:   ARO
The 2.3-million square-foot Pearl River Tower redefines what is possible in sustainable design by incorporating the latest green technology and engineering advancements. The 309-meter tower's sculpted body directs wind to a pair of openings at its mechanical floors, where traveling winds push turbines which generate energy for the building.   Completion Year: 2012  Source:   SOM / Crystal CG
Occupying an entire city block between the Marina Center and the Civic District, the scheme will create a 150,000 square meter eco-quarter in downtown Singapore that continues the Singaporean ideal of the 'city in a garden' with its lush planting and sky gardens.   Source:  Foster + Partners
We love BIG's conceptual transformation of Copenhagen's aging Amagerforbraending waste factory in to a combination renewable energy plant and ski resort.  BIG's choice to build a sustainable, multifunctional structure around  a decaying factory is a powerful symbolic gesture that brings renewal (and fun!) to the otherwise flat, un-ski-friendly terrain of Copenhagen.    Source: Glessner +  BIG
Developed by Form-ula in an effort to create a Zero-Environmental Footprint for the 300 North LA -- the Predator BLDG aims to minimize the distance between the occupant and the outside world.   The building addresses the lack of day-lighting and natural-ventilation to eliminate the large mechanical dependencies usually employed to keep the space properly lit and cooled, a trend that can be found in many buildings from that era.  The building also features a system for harvesting water for occupant use and building functions -- inducing the condensation of moisture and by filtering grey/black water via Living Machine.  Source: Form-ula
A kinetic curtain wall system, Heliotrace can literally trace the path of the sun over the course of a day and over the course of a year. in conjunction with other system components, this will significantly increase daylighting while reducing solar heat gain effects for building occupants. The kinetic, solar-responsive curtain wall system can reduce solar gains on buildings by up to 81%  Source: Permasteelisa + ABI +  SOM
Located between two river deltas in Taiwan, the Hualien Beach Resort used to be the site of an industrial factory region. Low-angle, high-glare morning and evening sun is blocked by the striped design while favorable north-south light is let in to the unit. Green roofs further mitigate heat gain, creating a low energy masterplan.  Source: Glessner +  BIG
This gallery and studio art building extends Yale University's extraordinary arts district one block west of Paul Rudolph's Art and Architecture Building and Louis Kahn's Art Gallery and Mellon Center for British Art. During its first year, the new structure will house the Yale School of Architecture while its own building is renovated and added to by the firm Gwathmey Siegel. Following completion of renovations to the Art and Architecture Building, the new structure will become the permanent home for Yale's world renowned Sculpture Department.  Source:   Kieran + Timberlake
The Atwater Project pays careful attention to site strategy, water runoff and material selection. The residence halls are naturally ventilated, incorporating through-floor suite plans, transom windows and ceiling fans in all rooms. Ventilation is supplemented by attic fans, which exhaust through rooftop "chimneys." The dining hall incorporates a planted roof, providing excellent insulation, protection of the roofing membrane, and, most significantly, reduction of impervious surfaces on campus. The green roof allows the college landscape to extend literally through and across the dining hall structure.  Source:   Kieran +Timberlake
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran, World Powers To Continue Nuclear Talks Past Tuesday Deadline</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e82e36/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0Edeadline0In0I7742710A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Iran, World Powers To Continue Nuclear Talks Past Tuesday Deadline
Reuters
Updated:
18 minutes ago
High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, Federica Mogherini (L) and US Secretary of State John Kerry (R) meet at the table at the Palais Coburg Hotel, where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held, in Vienna, Austria on July 7, 2015. (JOE KLAMAR/AFP/Getty Images) | JOE KLAMAR via Getty Images
reddit
(Adds quotes, details)
VIENNA, July 7 (Reuters) - Iran and major powers will  continue negotiations on an historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's  deadline for a long-term agreement, European Union foreign  policy chief Federica Mogherini said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days.  This does not mean we are extending our deadline," Mogherini  told reporters.
The deal under discussion between Iran, Britain, China,  France, Germany, Russia and the United States is aimed at  curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or  more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed  Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
"We might see some ministers leaving in the next hours and  then ready to come back," Mogherini said.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which  means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to  finalize the agreement," she said, adding that there remained  several difficult issues to resolve.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final  agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.     (Reporting by John Irish, Louis Charbonneau, Arshad Mohammed  and Parisa Hafezi)
Related on HuffPost:


Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, who is also Iran's top nuclear negotiator, waves to his well wishers upon arrival at the Mehrabad airport in Tehran, Iran, from Lausanne, Switzerland, Friday, April 3, 2015.  (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, who is also Iran's top nuclear negotiator, waves to his well wishers upon arrival at the Mehrabad airport in Tehran, Iran, from Lausanne, Switzerland, Friday, April 3, 2015. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
Iranians flash the victory sign as they hold their country's flag while waiting for arrival of Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif from Lausanne, Switzerland, at the Mehrabad airport in Tehran, Iran, Friday, April 3, 2015.  (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, who is also Iran's top nuclear negotiator, waves to his well wishers upon arrival at the Mehrabad airport in Tehran, Iran, from Lausanne, Switzerland, Friday, April 3, 2015.  (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, who is also Iran's top nuclear negotiator, waves to his well wishers upon arrival at the Mehrabad airport in Tehran, Iran, from Lausanne, Switzerland, Friday, April 3, 2015.  (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
Iranians celebrate on a street in northern Tehran, Iran, Thursday, April 2, 2015, after Iran's nuclear agreement with world powers in Lausanne, Switzerland.  (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
Iranians flash the victory sign while waiting for arrival of Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif from Lausanne, Switzerland, at the Mehrabad airport in Tehran, Iran, Friday, April 3, 2015.(AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:55:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Zea, The Ohio Girl Who Stood Up To A Homophobic Preacher, Raises Money For LGBT Youth</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e71ac3/sc/14/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Czea0Erainbow0Eflag0Egirl0In0I77419860Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Zea Bowling, the Ohio girl who became an Internet sensation last week when she calmly and quietly </Description>
        <MainBody>reddit
Zea Bowling, the Ohio girl who became an Internet sensation last week when she calmly and quietly waved a rainbow flag as a homophobic preacher screamed at her , is using her newfound fame to make a difference.
An image of Zea (pronounced "Zay-uh") was turned into a T-shirt by a local artist , and in a video released on Monday, the 7-year-old said she would donate half the funds from sales of the shirt to the Kaleidoscope Youth Center , an LGBTQ youth community center in Columbus.
"I want to donate money from my T-shirts to help kids have fun and be safe ," Zea said in a video released on Monday.
Following the Supreme Court's landmark ruling legalizing same-sex marriage in all 50 states , Zea attended a local arts and music festival with her family. As happened across the country, the event became an impromptu celebration of the decision, and Zea was waving a rainbow flag when the preacher approached and began yelling at her through a microphone.
Instead of backing down, Zea waved her flag in an image that quickly went viral across social media:
A photo posted by Ryan Bowling (@bowling.ryan) on
Jun 27, 2015 at 10:09am PDT
Ryan Bowling, Zea's dad, told The Huffington Post via email that she isn't really conscious of her sudden fame.
"Thankfully, Zea is not on social media, and she doesn't watch the news, so that has helped to shield her from much of the buzz," Bowling said. "That having been said, at play-dates, the first thing her friends have said to her has been 'Zea, I saw you on TV last night!'"
As for Zea's distinctive name, Bowling said they were looking for something unique and pretty.
"We didn't want her to ever be mistaken for anybody but herself," he said.
There's little chance of that happening now.
Also on HuffPost:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras To Present New Proposals At Emergency Euro Zone Summit</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e723c2/sc/25/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Cgreece0Edebt0Ecrisis0In0I77420A260Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras To Present New Proposals At Emergency Euro Zone Summit
Reuters | By                                                                      Paul Taylor and Costas Pitas
Posted:
reddit
BRUSSELS, July 7 (Reuters) - Greek Prime Minister Alexis  Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals  to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade  skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's  banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and  the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding,  Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom  are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorize  negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals  would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last  week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity  terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two  main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was  still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic  turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut  Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with  convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises,  spending cuts and pension and labor reforms that were on the  table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under  suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute  deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the  European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude  Greece from the euro zone."
He did not name names but may have been referring to German  Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of  his skepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and  last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically  acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and  other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which  the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece  nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more  than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrivial for a preparatory meeting of  finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew  debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule  out other forms of restructuring.
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate  bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian Finance Minister  Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time  left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for  Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint  media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. (1600  GMT) in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a  nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro  zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print  its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the  first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent  and fueling doubts about the long-term viability of an  incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the  integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with  each episode of political uncertainty within member countries,"  said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to  Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two  people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
Members of Communist Party affiliated trade union PAME march against austerity in Thessaloniki on July 7, 2015. (SAKIS MITROLIDIS/AFP/Getty Images)
CONCESSIONS UNCLEAR
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 percent 'No' vote in  Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented  support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced  his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the  soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting  without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it  was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are  closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek  government has an interest in coming up with serious and  credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke  to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as  well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S.  Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution  in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would  make to try to convince deeply skeptical European leaders to  lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and  fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse,  Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions  from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 percent discount on value added  tax on Greek islands and delay defense spending from cuts, which  rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have  called "red lines." It is also resisting raising VAT on  restaurants to 23 percent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase  out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to  get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their  aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU  of behaving like "terrorists," as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the  European Union is not something we want or indeed should want,"  the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested  the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding  while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it  over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the  Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a  solution before catastrophe," while the center-right Eleftheros  Typos said: "Tsipras' games finish at today's council: Time of  crisis: deal or Grexit."
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favor a hard line  at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that  Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the  austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would  implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for  Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral  they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was  largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was  prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain  limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two  days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.     (Additional reporting by Costas Pitas, Angeliki Koutantou and  George Georgiopoulos in Athens, Julia Fioretti and Alastair  Macdonald in Brussels, Paul Carrel in Berlin John O'Donnell in  Frankfurt and Mark John in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor;  editing by John Stonestreet and Giles Elgood)
Pensioners wait in front of the gate of the National Bank of Greece in Athens July 7, 2015. (ANGELOS TZORTZINIS/AFP/Getty Images)
Related on HuffPost:


A supporter of the No vote reacts after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag in front of the parliament after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote chant slogans after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
A supporter of the No vote shouts slogans after the results of the referendum in the northern Greek port city of Thessaloniki, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Giannis Papanikos)
Supporters of the No vote celebrate after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks overwhelmingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans in a critical referendum Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, left, speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras speaks with the Greek President Prokopis Pavlopoulos after the results of the referendum at the Presidential Palace in Athens, early Monday, July 6, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)
A vendor sells Greek flags walks at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Three opinion polls carried out during Greece's bailout referendum, which could affect the country's future in the eurozone, indicate the "no" vote will win. Tsipras called Sunday's referendum last weekend, urging voters to reject creditor reform proposals. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote wave Greek flags after the results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Petr David Josek)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag as celebrates after the results of the referendum in Synatagma square in central Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Voters in Greece resoundingly rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in return for rescue loans Sunday, backing Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, who insisted the vote would give him a stronger hand to reach a better deal. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras casts his vote at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Petros Karadjias)
Greece's Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, center, speaks to the media after voting at a polling station in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greeks began voting early Sunday in a closely-watched, closely-contested referendum, which the government pits as a choice over whether to defy the country's creditors and push for better repayment terms or essentially accept their terms, but which the opposition and many of the creditors paint as a choice between staying in the euro or leaving it. (AP Photo/Spyros Tsakiris)
A supporter of the No vote waves a Greek flag after the referendum's exit polls at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as officials counted the results of a referendum Sunday on whether to accept creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans, with three opinion polls showing a tight race with a narrow victory likely for the "no" side. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
Supporters of the No vote react after the first results of the referendum at Syntagma square in Athens, Sunday, July 5, 2015. Greece faced an uncharted future as its interior ministry predicted Sunday that more than 60 percent of voters in a hastily called referendum had rejected creditors' demands for more austerity in exchange for rescue loans. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)
A woman waits to cross a street in front of an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A woman walks past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015. Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties. (AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
People walk past an electronic stock indicator of a securities firm in Tokyo, Monday, July 6, 2015.  Greece's foray into the unknown with its rejection of terms set by its international creditors is jolting markets as investors react to looming uncertainties.(AP Photo/Shizuo Kambayashi)
A cleaner walks past display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A television journalist works in front of display boards at the Australian Stock Exchange in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
A display board at the Australian Stock Exchange flashes red indicating the losses of several names in Sydney, Monday, July 6, 2015. Asian markets are falling as investors reacted to Greece's sound rejection of terms set by its international creditors, deepening uncertainties over its status as a member of the 19-nation eurozone. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:22:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran Nuclear Talks Deadline Nears, Testing Diplomatic Process And U.S. Resolve</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e6df58/sc/7/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0In0I77419540Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (AP) — Iran nuclear talks busted through their second deadline in a week Tuesday, raising new questions about the ability of world powers to cut off all Iranian pathways to a bomb through diplomacy. The talks, already in their 12th day, were prolonged until possibly Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran Nuclear Talks Deadline Nears, Testing Diplomatic Process And U.S. Resolve
| By                                                                      BRADLEY KLAPPER
reddit
ASSOCIATED PRESS
VIENNA (AP)  Iran nuclear talks busted through their second deadline in a week Tuesday, raising new questions about the ability of world powers to cut off all Iranian pathways to a bomb through diplomacy. The talks, already in their 12th day, were prolonged until possibly Friday.
"We knew it would have been difficult, challenging, and sometimes hard," said Federica Mogherini, the European Union's foreign policy chief. She said the negotiations would continue despite hitting some "tense" moments, and the State Department declared the current interim nuclear arrangement with Iran extended through July 10.
As the latest target date arrived for a deal setting a decade of restrictions on Iran's nuclear program, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry, Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and other top diplomats huddled in Vienna in search of a breakthrough.
All had spoken of deep differences remaining, and there was no public indication they had resolved disputes ranging from inspection rules on suspicious Iranian sites to limits on Tehran's research and development of advanced nuclear technology. Still, no one was speaking yet on Tuesday of a long-term extension.
"The last, difficult, political issues, we have to solve," Mogherini said.
And as he left the talks for an economic summit at home, Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov said fewer than 10 major differences needed to be ironed out, including access to Iranian sites for international monitors. He said questions related to the easing of sanctions on Iran had been decided, Russian news agency RIA Novosti reported. Lavrov said he could return to the talks later in the week.
Diplomats had extended their discussions by a week when they missed their goal of a pact by June 30, after passing previous deadlines in July 2014 and last November. For Kerry and his team, pressure is increasing from skeptical U.S. allies and members of Congress. If the accord isn't sent over to American lawmakers by Thursday, their month-long review period would be doubled to 60 days, hampering the ability of the Obama administration to offer speedy economic benefits to Iran for nuclear concessions.
In Tehran Tuesday, Iran's Atomic Energy Organization declared it had reached a "general understanding" in parallel talks with the U.N. nuclear agency on "joint cooperation." The Iranians have made similar claims previously, and it was unclear if any process was established for the International Atomic Energy Agency's long-stymied investigation of past nuclear weapons work by the Islamic Republic  a demand of Washington and its partners in negotiations in Austria's capital.
There, in a baroque, 19th-century palace, Kerry gathered early Tuesday with the foreign ministers of Britain, China, France, Germany and Russia. The larger group was to meet with Zarif at some point later in the day. Russia's Lavrov and China's Wang Yi had to leave for a gathering of emerging economies in the Russian city of Ufa starting Wednesday, and the EU's Mogherini said different ministers were likely to depart and return.
"We are taking these negotiations day to day to see if we can conclude a comprehensive agreement," State Department spokeswoman Marie Harf said in a statement, adding that Kerry would remain in Vienna.
"We've made substantial progress in every area, but this work is highly technical and high stakes for all of the countries involved," Harf said. "We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time. That is why we are continuing to negotiate."
The U.S. is in a tough spot. President Barack Obama has expended significant political capital on finalizing an agreement that has prompted suspicion from Iran's regional rival, Saudi Arabia, outright hostility from America's closest Mideast ally, Israel, and deep ambivalence even among Obama's Democratic allies in Congress. They're concerned that the accord would leave Iran's nuclear infrastructure largely intact and compel the West to provide the leading U.S.-designated state sponsor of terrorism with potentially hundreds of billions of dollars' worth of economic relief from international sanctions.
To ease their concerns, Obama and Kerry have vowed to hold out for a "good deal" that verifiably keeps Iran at least a year away from a nuclear weapons capability for at least a decade. Current intelligence estimates put the Iranians only two to three months away from amassing enough material for a nuclear warhead, if they pursued such a course. As part of the guarantee, the administration has repeatedly threatened to abandon negotiations if they prove fruitless or appear as an Iranian stall for time.
On-and-off talks with Tehran have been going on for more than a decade, though this incarnation has come closest to any resolution. The latest effort began in secret a couple of years ago and gained speed after the election of moderate-leaning Iranian President Hassan Rouhani in 2013. By November that year, Iran and the six world powers clinched an interim nuclear agreement and began the process for a comprehensive accord.
Over the weekend, a cautious Kerry told reporters that talks on the final package "could go either way."
Republicans hostile to compromise with Iran have been urging the U.S. to pull back from the talks. Their refrain has been that Obama and Kerry want a deal more than the Iranians do, and have let red lines erode on Iranian enrichment capacity, inspections and providing limited sanctions relief. The president and his top advisers vehemently reject such claims.
Iran has its own red lines, defiantly outlined in recent weeks by Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, the nation's supreme leader. They include a quick easing of sanctions, and rejection of any inspections of military sites or interviews with Iranian nuclear scientists.
___
Associated Press writer George Jahn contributed.
Earlier on HuffPost:


"I am convinced that if this framework leads to a final, comprehensive deal, it will make our country, our allies, and our world safer. This has been a long time coming," Obama said in remarks delivered at the White House Rose Garden. (AP Photo/J. David Ake)
There is no nuclear deal or framework with Iran; there is only a list of dangerous U.S. concessions that will put Iran on the path to nuclear weapons," Cotton said in a statement. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)
"I am cautiously optimistic about this framework. We must always remain vigilant about preventing Iran from getting a nuclear weapon but there is no question that a diplomatic solution is vastly preferable to the alternatives. Now is the time for thoughtful consideration, not rash action that could undermine the prospects for success," Reid said in a statement. (AP Photo/John Locher)
"The president says negotiators have cleared the basic threshold needed to continue talks, but the parameters for a final deal represent an alarming departure from the White Houses initial goals. My longtime concerns about the parameters of this potential agreement remain, but my immediate concern is the administration signaling it will provide near-term sanctions relief," Boehner said in a statement. (AP Photo/Karim Kadim)
"This framework to roll back Irans nuclear program is founded not on trust, but on vigilance and enforcement.  Critically, this framework significantly restricts Irans enrichment capability and enables us to intensify our vigilance where it is needed most and that is inside Irans facilities.  The aggressive inspections and restrictions outlined in the preliminary framework offers a strong, long-term plan to stop Iran from building a bomb," Pelosi said in a statement. (AP Photo/Andrew Harnik)
"To the detriment of international security--specifically regarding the security of the United States, Israel and other allies, as well as preventing a nuclear arms race in the Middle East--the Obama administration has always approached the goal of these negotiations as reaching the best deal that is acceptable to Iran, rather than what should be our national goal: ending Iran's nuclear program," McConnell said in a statement. (AP Photo/Molly Riley)
"The understanding that the major world powers have reached with Iran is an important step toward a comprehensive agreement that would prevent Iran from getting a nuclear weapon and strengthen the security of the United States, Israel, and the region," she said in the statement. "Getting the rest of the way to a final deal by June won't be easy, but it is absolutely crucial. I know well that the devil is always in the details in this kind of negotiation," Clinton said in a statement. (Photo by Win McNamee/Getty Images)
"The reported details of the Iran deal include significant concessions to a nation whose leaders call for death to America and the destruction of Israel. Iran remains a major destabilizing force in the region, working against American interests," Bush said in a statement. (AP Photo/Brennan Linsley)
"Finding a negotiated solution, something that works, something that doesn't involve trusting, something that involves verifying that Iran is not moving toward developing a nuclear weapon, that is our best promise in the region. And so far, when everyone says they don't like this deal -- not everyone certainly, [but] the people who do say it -- the real question is, 'And what's the alternative here? What have you got as the next best move?'" Warren said during an appearance on "The HuffPost Show." (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
"Under no circumstance should a U.S. President lift sanctions and grant nuclear capability to a nation that proudly chants Death to America.' It is unfortunate that throughout these negotiations the President continually reserved his harshest language not for the Iranian regime, but for the United States Congress and the Prime Minister of Israel," Cruz said in a statement. (AP Photo/Nati Harnik)
"While much more work remains to be done this framework is an important step forward. It is imperative that Iran not get a nuclear weapon. It also is imperative that we do everything we can to reach a diplomatic solution and avoid never-ending war in the Middle East. I look forward to examining the details of this agreement and making sure that it is effective and strong," Sanders said in a statement. (AP Photo/Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
"We cannot, and should not, divorce our nuclear diplomacy with Iran from the larger strategic challenge that Iran poses. I am concerned about the impact that todays agreement may have on the growing tensions and conflicts in the Middle Eastfor as Dr. Henry Kissinger has observed, the Administrations approach to nuclear diplomacy with Iran has moved from preventing proliferation to managing it," McCain said in a statement. (AP Photo/Ross D. Franklin)
This is a very serious issue that deserves careful consideration, and I expect to have a classified briefing in the near future. I strongly believe Congress should have the right to disapprove any agreement and I support the Corker bill which would allow that to occur, Schumer said in an emailed statement to Politico. (AP Photo/Andrew Harnik)
A nuclear-armed Iran would lead to a less safe and less secure world, which is why the stakes are so high in the pursuit of a strong agreement that is fully enforceable, verifiable and is in our national security interests. It is important that we wait to see the specific details of todays announcement, and as the P5-plus-one works toward any final deal, we must remain clear-eyed regarding Irans continued resistance to concessions, long history of covert nuclear weapons-related activities, support of terrorism, and its current role in destabilizing the region. If a final agreement is reached, the American people, through their elected representatives, must have the opportunity to weigh in to ensure the deal truly can eliminate the threat of Irans nuclear program and hold the regime accountable," Corker said in a statement. (AP Photo/J. Scott Applewhite)
The United States  executive branch and Congress  are unified in our goal to ensure that Iran is blocked from ever having a nuclear weapon. The best outcome is a strong diplomatic one. This framework and the ultimate agreement cannot be based on trust; there is no trust when it comes to Iran. The final agreement must be verifiable and transparent, making it clear that any violations would result in an immediate restoration of the strongest possible sanctions. Congress has a role to play in this process and I look forward to reviewing all the details of this long-sought agreement that Secretary of State John Kerry and our allies have negotiated, Cardin said in a statement. (AP Photo/Cliff Owen, File)
"I am very concerned by the extent of the sanctions relief that this announcement appears to offer Iran. Almost all congressionally-mandated sanctions related to Iran's nuclear program are also related to Tehran's advancing ballistic missile program, intensifying support for international terrorism, and other unconventional weapons programs. And I remain concerned regarding the ability to effectively re-impose sanctions once they have been weakened," Royce said in a statement. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster, File)
"Today's announcement is the culmination of months of negotiation and compromise. We now need to take a close look at the details to determine if the compromises made are worth the dismantling of years of pressure built on Iran. As I've said and again, no deal is better than a bad deal, and we need to ensure that this agreement forecloses any pathway to a bomb," Engel said in a statement. (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)
This attempt to spin diplomatic failure as a success is just the latest example of this administrations farcical approach to Iran. Under this Presidents watch, Iran has expanded its influence in the Middle East, sowing instability throughout the region. Irans support for terrorism has continued unabated without a serious response from the United States. The regimes repression of the Iranian people and its detentions of American citizens continue. And now Tehran is gaining international acceptance of its nuclear ambitions and will receive significant sanctions relief without making serious concessions," Rubio said in a statement. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)
I welcome todays announcement that a framework understanding has been reached between Iran, the United States and our partners in the P5+1, and look forward to reviewing the details of the framework over the coming days. A comprehensive diplomatic agreement remains the best way to prevent Iran from developing a nuclear weapon, and this agreement demonstrates the political will exists to complete a final deal by the July deadline," Murphy said in a statement. (AP Photo/Sergei Chuzavkov)
"If I ultimately choose to run, and if Im honored to be elected by the people of this country, I will pull back on that on January 20, 2017, because the last thing  not just for the region but for this world  we need is a nuclear-armed Iran. It leaves not only problems for Israel, because they want to annihilate Israel, it leaves the problems in the sense that the Saudis, the Jordanians and others are gonna want to have access to their own nuclear weapons" Walker told Wisconsin radio host Charlie Sykes. (AP Photo/Charlie Neibergall)
"I'm encouraged to hear that negotiators have agreed to a frameworka major step toward achieving a final deal. Our shared goal in the United States is clear: to prevent a nuclear-armed Iran. The stakes couldn't be higher and I commend Secretary Kerry and our entire negotiating team for their commitment to finding a diplomatic solution that guarantees our security and that of our allies," Durbin said in a statement. (AP Photo/Andrew Harnik)
"The Obama Administration's efforts to get a deal at any cost, will have a greater cost than the world can bear. Iranian leaders will now find a nuclear weapon dangerously within reach. Even during these recent negotiations, Iranians have continued to chant "death to America". When people show you who they are, it's important to believe them the first time. If this deal moves forward the consequences for the US and our allies in the region will be dire," McCaul said in a statement.  (AP Photo/Lauren Victoria Burke)
"Americans want to prevent Iran from getting a nuclear weapon, and they would prefer to do it through diplomacy rather than military action. This breakthrough agreement is an important step toward that goal. I believe that Congress now should give our negotiators time and space to work out the details of a strong, verifiable comprehensive agreement," Franken said in a statement. (AP Photo/Jim Mone)
"Based upon the statements made and press reports, there appears to be major confusion and uncertainty over exactly what the deal entails. There also appears to be major differences of opinion over what impact the deal will have on the Iranian's drive to develop a nuclear weapon. While I will reserve judgment until the details are known, it is notable how far from the White House's initial negotiating principals we appear to be. Given the magnitude of this potential agreement and based on the obvious conflicts in interpretation, it is increasingly imperative Congress review any deal before it is finalized and before congressional sanctions are lifted," Graham said in a statement. (AP Photo/Manuel Balce Ceneta)
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:59:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Si Robertson, 'Duck Dynasty' Star, Says Atheists Don't Exist</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e53c93/sc/15/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Csi0Erobertson0Eatheists0In0I77410A0A60Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>There's no such thing as an atheist, according to one of the stars of the reality TV show "</Description>
        <MainBody>

"I'm probably 20 percent atheist and 80 percent agnostic," Pitt said in 2009. "I don't think anyone really knows. You'll either find out or not when you get there, until then there's no point thinking about it." His prettier half, Jolie, said in 2000: "There doesn't need to be a God for me. There's something in people that's spiritual, that's godlike. I don't feel like doing things just because people say things, but I also don't really know if it's better to just not believe in anything, either."
"I'm an atheist, but I'm very relaxed about it," the "Harry Potter" star said in 2009. "I don't preach my atheism, but I have a huge amount of respect for people like Richard Dawkins who do. Anything he does on television, I will watch."
In a 2002 interview on "Inside the Actor's Studio," Moore was asked as part of the series' questionnaire, "If heaven exists, what would you like God to say at the pearly gates?" She replied: "Well, I guess you were wrong. I do exist!"  (36:45)
In an interview in 2012, Bardem was quick to say "I've always said I don't believe in God, I believe in Al Pacino."
In a 2007 interview, Foster replied to the question of whether she's religious or not by saying "I'm an atheist. But I absolutely love religions and the rituals. Even though I don't believe in God. We celebrate pretty much every religion in our family with the kids. They love it, and when they say, 'Are we Jewish?' or 'Are we Catholic?' I say, 'Well, I'm not, but you can choose when you're 18. But isn't this fun that we do seders and the Advent calendar?'"
In 2012, when asked "Did we invent God?" Freeman replied "Yes." He then elaborated: "Has anybody ever seen hard evidence? What we get is theories from our earlier prophets. Now, people who think that God invented us think that the Earth can't be more than 6,000 years old. So I guess it's a question of belief. My belief system doesn't support a creator as such, as we can call God, who created us in His/Her/Its image."
"If only I wasn't an atheist, I could get away with anything," Knightley said in 2012. "You'd just ask for forgiveness and then you'd be forgiven."
"I'm an atheist," Thompson said in 2008. "I suppose you can call me a sort of libertarian anarchist. I regard religion with fear and suspicion. It's not enough to say that I don't believe in God. I actually regard the system as distressing: I am offended by some of the things said in the Bible and the Koran, and I refute them."
In 2010, Joel was a guest on Howard Stern's radio show and when asked if he believes in God, he replied: "No. I'm an atheist."
In the 2010 book "The Futurist," Cameron calls himself a "converted agnostic" and says "I've sworn off agnosticism, which I now call cowardly atheism. I've come to the position that in the complete absence of any supporting data whatsoever for the persistence of the individual in some spiritual form, it is necessary to operate under the provisional conclusion that there is no afterlife and then be ready to amend that if I find out otherwise."
In 2010, Garofalo compared the Bible to a Bill O'Reilly autobiography and a childrens book authored by former President Bush, saying: "That's just three works of fiction targeted to a child-like audience."
During her Emmy Award acceptance speech in 2007, Griffin said: "A lot of people come up here and they thank Jesus for this award. I want you to know that no one had less to do with this award than Jesus. He didn't help me a bit. If it was up to him, Cesar Millan would be up here with that damn dog. So all I can say is suck it Jesus, this reward is my God now."
In 2012, Hefner penned an editorial that said "when religion rather than reason dictates legislation, do not expect logic with your law," and: "This is a religious nation, but it is also a secular one. For decades the American people have found a way to balance religious beliefs with secular freedoms. We have enjoyed freedom of religion as well as freedom from religion. These need not be incompatible. No one should have to subjugate their religious freedom, and no one should have their personal freedoms infringed. This is America and we must protect the rights of all Americans."  Earlier this year, the prestigious Hugh Hefner award for those who protect the First Amendment went to a 16-year-old atheist who fought to have a prayer banner at her high school removed.
In this Sept. 9, 2010 photo, a billboard erected by atheists in Oklahoma City reads " Don't believe in God? Join the club". Nick Singer, the coordinator of a local atheists' group called "Coalition of Reason," recently received $5,250 from its national counterpart to erect the billboard along Interstate 44 near the Oklahoma State Fair.  Oklahoma ranks eighth in the nation for percentage of residents who self-identify as Christians (85 percent), according to an analysis of the 2008 U.S. Religious Landscape Survey conducted by the Pew Research Center's Forum on Religion and Public Life. (Sue Ogrocki, AP)
Atheist billboard on Capital Blvd. in Raleigh, North Carolina, can be seen March 29, 2011. (Chris Seward, Raleigh News &amp; Observer / MCT)
A billboard sponsored by an atheist group is displayed near the entrance to the Lincoln Tunnel in North Bergen, N.J., Wednesday, Dec. 1, 2010. Now, the Catholic League has countered by putting up its own billboard near one of the tunnel's New York City entrances.  (Seth Wenig, AP)
An atheistic billboard in Chicago. (Eric Ingrum, Flickr)
A billboard sponsored by a Catholic group is displayed near an exit of the Lincoln Tunnel in New York, Wednesday, Dec. 1, 2010. Similarly, a billboard sponsored by an atheist group is displayed near the tunnel's New Jersey entrance. (Seth Wenig, AP)
From RNS' Diana Fishlock: A billboard erected in one of the Harrisburg, Pa.'s most racially diverse neighborhoods featured an African slave with the biblical quote, "Slaves, obey your masters." It lasted less than a day before someone tore it down.
An atheist group was blocked from erecting a billboard in a heavily Jewish neighborhood in Brooklyn, New York.
Ghanaian cardinal Peter Kodwo Appiah Turkson attends a mass at the St Peter's basilica on March 12, 2013 at the Vatican. Cardinals moved into the Vatican today as the suspense mounted ahead of a secret papal election with no clear frontrunner to steer the Catholic world through troubled waters after Benedict XVI's historic resignation.The 115 cardinal electors who pick the next leader of 1.2 billion Catholics in a conclave in the Sistine Chapel will live inside the Vatican walls completely cut off from the outside world until they have made their choice.
In this photo taken on Thursday, July 18, 2013, Hauwa Jubril, a muslim girl sit outside a shop in Obalende, Lagos, Nigeria. Nigerias secular and Islamic laws clashed when a senator notorious for marrying a 14-year-old filibustered a vote to amend the constitution by insisting that a girl child comes of age when she marries, not at 18. Enraged activists are demanding the senate revisit the vote, asking how a known pedophile could get away with subverting the countrys constitution.
This photo taken on January 5, 2013 shows a man lighting a candle during a Christmas Eve service at the Khor Virab church outside Yerevan. Millions of Armenians will celebrate Christmas on January 6.
Pilgrims from Fiji attend the morning Mass of Pope Benedict XVI at Randwick Racecourse in Sydney on July 20, 2008.    Far fewer people than the predicted crowd of 500,000 turned out for a final World Youth Day mass led by Pope Benedict XVI on Sunday, leaving one venue almost empty of worshippers, AFP photographers said.
The president of Macedonia'parliament Trajko Veljanoski kisses the hand of Pope Francis during a private audience on May 24, 2013 at the Vatican.
Visitors light up candles inside a room 'The space for Recollection and Prayer' to commemorate victims of the communist repression in Romania, in Sighetu Marmatiei on July 13, 2013. Former dissidents and political prisoners gathered in Romania on July 14, 2013 at a museum commemorating those who suffered abuses under communism, set up 20 years ago at the site of a prison where scores died.
Shiite Muslim worshippers light candles outside Imam Mohammed al-Mahdi shrine during the annual festival of Shabaniyah, which marks the anniversary of the birth of the ninth-century Shiite leader known as the Hidden Imam, in Karbala, 50 miles (80 kilometers) south of Baghdad, Iraq, Monday, June 24, 2013. (AP Photo/ Hadi Mizban)
Njemps tribemen dance in front of a statue of Buddha at the Gallmann nature conservancy near Kinamba, Laikipia, Northern Kenya on March 4, 2012. High Priest Shinso Ito and a group of Shinnyo-en priests arrived in Kenya to perform a Buddhist fire and water ceremony for the first time ever in Africa.The ceremony was attended by over 300 spiritual leaders and was streamed live on the internet to millions of viewers and devotees globally. The ceremony involved Kenyan tribal elders and members of the Njemps, Pokot Samburu, Kikuyu and Turkana communites. AFP PHOTO/Carl de Souza (Photo credit should read CARL DE SOUZA/AFP/Getty Images)
A faithful holds an image of the 'The Lord of Miracles', worshipped by the majority of the Catholic Peruvians, during his main procession on October 18, 2012 in Lima.
Catholics touch an icon of the Virgin Mary and Jesus Christ as it is taken along with the World Youth Day (WYD) Cross that in 1984 Pope John Paul II entrusted the youth of the world, across Rocinha shantytown in Rio de Janeiro on July 18, 2013. The Pope is due in Rio for the July 22-28 Catholic WYD, an event expected to attract two million people from around the globe.
Roman Catholics listen to Bishop Noel Treanor during mass at St Peter's Roman Catholic Cathedral in West Belfast, Northern Ireland, Sunday, March, 21, 2010. Pope Benedict XVI has apologised to victims of child sex abuse by Catholic priests in Ireland. Extracts from the Popes letter were read at all masses across Ireland Sunday, in the pastoral letter to Irish Catholics, he acknowledged the sense of betrayal in the Church felt by victims and their families.
A Falun Gong Practitioner poses on the 14th anniversary of the beginning of the persecution of Falun Gong in China on July 21, 2013 in Sydney, Australia. In July of 1999, the communist Chinese government outlawed the spiritual practise of Falun Gong, declaring it illegal and forbidding citizens to practise. Followers believe thousands of practitioners have been killed, imprisoned or put in labour camps in China since 1999.
Pope Benedict XVI (R) poses with Iceland president Olafur Ragnar Grinsson during a private audience at the Vatican  on March 4, 2011.
The Russian Orthodox cathedral of St. Nicholas is seen on a clear day in Vienna on April 1, 2013.
Dozens of people queue in front of the Nieuwe Kerk in Amsterdam on May 1, 2013. A day after the crowning of king Willem-Alexander the church has opened it's doors for those who want to see the church in the same setting as during the ceremony on April 30.
Eight new priests prepare for their ordination at the Freisinger Dom cathedral on June 29, 2013 in Freising, Germany. Freising Cathedral, also called Saint Mary and Corbinian Cathedral, is a romanesque basilica in Freising, Bavaria. The Freising Cathedral is also known for being the place where Pope Benedict XVI was ordained a priest. Bavaria, Germany's southern-most state, is heavily Catholic.
Nuns walk on a popular shopping street in Seoul on July 6, 2013. Freedom of religion is constitutionally guaranteed in South Korea, which is predominantly Buddhist and Christian.
A picture taken on July 12, 2013 shows a nun walking by the Sacre-Coeur basilica in the Montmartre neighborhood of Paris.
Tourists enjoy a sunny day on March 25, 2010 at the traditional Eastern market in the Old Town Square in Prague.
Crown Prince Naruhito of Japan (R) and Galician regional president Alberto Nunez Feijoo (L) attend a concert at Cathedral on June 15, 2013 in Santiago de Compostela, Spain.
This photo taken on on June 27, 2013 shows a muslim Uighur walking through dusty streets in Turpan, Xinjiang Province.  China's constitution proclaims the country's dozens of minority groups as integral and equal parts of the national tapestry -- but analysts say the mishandling of such distinctions is a driver of unrest in remote Xinjiang. Beijing's propaganda portrays the vast western region more than four times the size of Japan as a harmonious land of colourful, mostly Muslim Uighur natives and hard-working migrants prospering under Communist Party rule.
"The impossibility of conceiving that this grand and wondrous universe, with our conscious selves, arose through chance, seems to me the chief argument for  the existence of God."  Clarification: The full quote, from one of Darwin's letters, carries a different sentiment.  A young admirer asked Darwin about his religious views (the original inquiry is lost), and the great naturalist answered: "It is impossible to answer your question briefly; and I am not sure that I could do so, even if I wrote at some length. But I may say that the impossibility of conceiving that this grand and wondrous universe, with our conscious selves, arose through chance, seems to me the chief argument for the existence of God; but whether this is an argument of real value, I have never been able to decide."
"So you're made of detritus [from exploded stars]. Get over it. Or better yet, celebrate it. After all, what nobler thought can one cherish than that the universe lives within us all?"   --American astrophysicist and science commentator
"What I have done is to show that it is possible for the way the universe began to be determined by the laws of science. In that case, it would not be necessary to appeal to God to decide how the universe began. This doesn't prove that there is no God, only that God is not necessary."  --English physicist and cosmologist
"Science is not only compatible with spirituality; it is a profound source of spirituality. When we recognize our place in an immensity of light-years and in the passage of ages, when we grasp the intricacy, beauty, and subtlety of life, then that soaring feeling, that sense of elation and humility combined, is surely spiritual...The notion that science and spirituality are somehow mutually exclusive does a disservice to both."   --American astrophysicist
"Science is...a powerful way, indeed - to study the natural world. Science is not particularly effective...in making commentary about the supernatural world. Both worlds, for me, are quite real and quite important. They are investigated in different ways. They coexist. They illuminate each other."  --American physician-geneticist and director of the National Human Genome Research Institute
"Emotionally, I am an atheist. I don't have the evidence to prove that God doesn't exist, but I so strongly suspect he doesn't that I don't want to waste my time"   --American biochemist and science fiction writer
Clarification: While the New York Times noted that "Einstein consistently characterized the idea of a personal God who answers prayers as naive, and life after death as wishful thinking," he also "described himself as an 'agnostic' and 'not an atheist.'" One ambiguous quote, from Einstein's response to a letter from a sixth-grade student named Phyllis Wright, reads "Everyone who is seriously involved in the pursuit of science becomes convinced that a spirit is manifest in the laws of the universe - a spirit vastly superior to that of man, and one in the face of which we with our modest powers must feel humble. In this way the pursuit of science leads to a religious feeling of a special sort, which is indeed quite different from the religiosity of someone more naive."  --German physicist, created theory of general relativity.
"It was not by accident that the greatest thinkers of all ages were deeply religious souls."  --German physicist, noted for work on quantum theory
"I am very astonished that the scientific picture of the real world around me is very deficient. It gives a lot of factual information, puts all our experiences in a magnificently consistent order, but is ghastly silent about all and sundry that is really near to our heart, that really matters to us. It cannot tell us a word about red and blue, bitter and sweet, physical pain and physical delight; it knows nothing of beautiful and ugly, good or bad, god and eternity."  --Austrian physicist, awarded Nobel prize in 1933
"In my view, all that is necessary for faith is the belief that by doing our best we shall come nearer to success and that success in our aims (the improvement of the lot of mankind, present and future) is worth attaining...I maintain that faith in this world is perfectly possible without faith in another world."   --British biophysicist renowned for her work on X-ray diffraction.
"From religion comes a man's purpose; from science, his power to achieve it. Sometimes people ask if religion and science are not opposed to one another. They are: in the sense that the thumb and fingers of my hands are opposed to one another. It is an opposition by means of which anything can be grasped."  --British physicist, chemist, and mathematician. Awarded Nobel Prize in 1915
"God was invented to explain mystery. God is always invented to explain those things that you do not understand."  --American physicist, awarded Nobel Prize in 1965
"I find it as difficult to understand a scientist who does not acknowledge the presence of a superior rationality behind the existence of the universe as it is to comprehend a theologian who would deny the advances of science."   --German-American rocket scientist
"The more you understand the significance of evolution, the more you are pushed away from the agnostic position and towards atheism. Complex, statistically improbable things are by their nature more difficult to explain than simple, statistically probable things."   --British evolutionary biologist
"Science can have a purifying effect on religion, freeing it from beliefs of a pre-scientific age and helping us to a truer conception of God. At the same time, I am far from believing that science will ever give us the answers to all our questions."  --English physicist, awarded Nobel Prize in 1977
"A commonsense interpretation of the facts suggests that a superintellect has monkeyed with physics, as well as with chemistry and biology, and that there are no blind forces worth speaking about in nature. The numbers one calculates from the facts seem to me so overwhelming as to put this conclusion almost beyond question."  --English mathematician and astronomer.
"Science can destroy religion by ignoring it as well as by disproving its tenets. No one ever demonstrated, so far as I am aware, the nonexistence of Zeus or Thor - but they have few followers now"   --British science fiction author and inventor
"I am very much a scientist, and so I naturally have thought about religion also through the eyes of a scientist. When I do that, I see religion not denominationally, but in a more, let us say, deistic sense. I have been influence in my thinking by the writing of Einstein who has made remarks to the effect that when he contemplated the world he sensed an underlying Force much greater than any human force. I feel very much the same. There is a sense of awe, a sense of reverence, and a sense of great mystery."  --American theoretical physicist, awarded Nobel Prize in 1998
"Atheism is not a philosophy; it is not even a view of the world; it is simply a refusal to deny the obvious."  --American neuroscientist
"With pantheism...the deity is associated with the order of nature or the universe itself...when modern scientists such as Einstein and Stephen Hawking mention 'God' in their writing, this is what they seem to mean: that God is Nature."   --American physicist
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:37:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>3 Gored, 8 Injured During Running Of The Bulls Event At Pamplona's San Fermin Festival</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e60a8b/sc/28/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A70Crunning0Eof0Ethe0Ebulls0Epamplona0In0I7741340A0Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>3 Gored, 8 Injured During Running Of The Bulls Event At Pamplona's San Fermin Festival
| By                                                                      By ALVARO BARRIENTOS and CIARAN GILES
Posted:
reddit
ASSOCIATED PRESS
PAMPLONA, Spain (AP)  Two Americans and a Briton were gored and eight others injured Tuesday as thousands of daredevils dashed alongside fighting bulls through the streets of this northern Spanish city on the first bull run of the San Fermin festival, organizers said.
The San Fermin press office said a 38-year-old American identified only by his initials, M.W.O., was gored in the armpit and a 27-year-old Californian identified by the initials D.M.O. was also gored. A 30-year-old Briton with the initials A.B.O. was gored in the groin area. None of the three was said to be in serious condition.
Three other Americans were among the eight others injured, most with bruises sustained in falls and crowd crushes during the nationally-televised run that lasted just over two minutes.
In its first report after the run, the Spanish Red Cross only had details of one person being gored and six people injured.
The daily run sees people dashing with six bulls along a narrow, 930-yard (850-meter) course from a holding pen to the city's bull ring. The bulls are then killed by professional matadors in bullfights each afternoon. The nine-day fiesta in Pamplona, which features 24-hour street partying, was made famous in Ernest Hemingway's 1926 novel "The Sun Also Rises" and attracts thousands of foreign tourists.
Bull runs are a traditional part of summer festivals across Spain. Dozens of people are injured each year in the runs, most in falls.
Two men have died recently after being gored by bulls in Spanish festivals  one Saturday in the eastern town of Grao de Castellon and another June 24 in the southwestern town of Coria.
In all, 15 people have died from gorings in San Fermin since record-keeping began in 1924.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:17:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ladybaby, Japanese Pop Metal Band Featuring Ladybeard, Releases 'Nippon Manju' Video</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e48405/sc/15/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A60Cladybaby0Enippon0Emanju0In0I7740A5720Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>J-pop has just been turned upside down, thanks to </Description>
        <MainBody>

Travel blogger La Carmina tries her luck in a Nakano Broadway game center. (Photo by Said Karlsson, hair by Kukukachoo)
Inside, you can play with arcade games from the 1980s. (Photo by Said Karlsson)
This isn't the entrance to a Shinto temple, but to a shop filled with robots and figurines. (Photo by Said Karlsson)
Nakano has plenty of inexpensive little eateries, such as this ramen joint near North Exit. (Photo by Said Karlsson)
It's a neighborhood chock full of character, lit up by colorful signs. (Photo by Said Karlsson)
At night, there are plenty of eccentric bars to visit. (Photo by Said Karlsson)
Such as this dai-kaiju bar, dedicated to Japanese monsters and strange beasts. (Photo by Naomi Rubin)
Visitors can try on monstrous costumes, play with toys, and watch old Ultraman films. (Photo by Naomi Rubin)
Nakano station is a five-minute direct ride from Shinjuku, making it a convenient location for travelers to stay.
It's pricy to live in a Tokyo hotel, so I recommend renting a fully furnished apartment from a foreigner-friendly company like Live in Asia.
One of the best places in Tokyo to find pop culture underground goods.
Inside, you can find collectible items such as these retro figures.
Some stores sell racy comic books and toys.
On the innocent side, a bakery features Totoro-shaped pastries, based on characters from the Hayao Miyazaki film.
Omega Algea is a spooky tea room, filled with skeletons and chandeliers.
The back room is an art gallery for underground works. For more about Tokyo Goth culture, including shopping and nightlife guides, visit La Carmina blog.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:37:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Horrible Tour De France Crash Brings Down 20 Riders, Briefly Stops Race</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e3a0ef/sc/6/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A60Ctour0Ede0Efrance0Ecrash0In0I77396860Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Joaquim Rodriguez was among the few cyclists having a good day during Monday's Stage Three of the Tour de France. </Description>
        <MainBody>

Riders get up after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Scores of riders lie on the road after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Laurens ten Dam of the Netherlands is treated for injuries after crashing with several of other riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Riders get up after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Riders get up after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Riders collect themselves after a crash with 65km left to race in stage three of the 2015 Tour de France from Anvers to Huy on July 6, 2015 in Huy, Belgium.
William Bonnet of France holds his head after crashing with scores of other riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015. Bonnet abandoned the race following the crash.
Scores of riders lie on the road after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Scores of riders lie on the road after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Switzerland's Fabian Cancellara, wearing the overall leader's yellow jersey, gets back on his bicycle after crashing with several riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
William Bonnet of France holds his head after crashing with scores of other riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015. Bonnet abandoned the race following the crash.
William Bonnet of France is carried onto a stretcher after crashing with several other riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Riders get up after crashing during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Riders wait for a restart after the race was neutralized following a crash involving scores of riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
William Bonnet of France is carried onto a stretcher after crashing with several other riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015. Bonnet abandoned the race following the crash.
Laurens ten Dam of the Netherlands is treated for injuries after crashing with several of other riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015. Bonnet abandoned the race following the crash.
Switzerland's Fabian Cancellara, wearing the overall leader's yellow jersey, grimaces after catching up with the pack following a crash as riders wait for a restart after the race was neutralized following a crash involving scores of riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Australia's Michael Rogers talk to the race direction as riders wait for a restart after the race was neutralized following a crash involving scores of riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
Australia's Michael Rogers, down right corner,  talks to the race direction as Germany's Andre Greipel, wearing the best sprinter's green jersey, and other riders wait for a restart after the race was neutralized following a crash involving scores of riders during the third stage of the Tour de France cycling race over 159.5 kilometers (99.1 miles) with start in Antwerp and finish in Huy, Belgium, Monday, July 6, 2015.
 Share
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:15:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friends of Tibet in Lithuania Celebrate the Dalai Lama</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e39cb6/sc/11/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cvytis0Evidunas0Cfriends0Eof0Etibet0Ein0Elithuania0Ib0I7740A2580Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
<<<<<<< HEAD
Friends of Tibet in Lithuania celebrated the 80th Birthday of His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama on June 19 in Vilnius. This celebration became a part of the huge traditional cultural event called "Culture Night" which was held in Vilnius that night. The citizens of Vilnius and the guests of the city had a unique opportunity to attend different cultural places and various performances overnight; streets of Vilnius were therefore crowded till dawn.
It was a good opportunity to invite a lot of different people to celebrate the jubilee of His Holiness and to present Tibetan culture a few cultural events under the common name "The House of Tibet at the Culture Night" were organized by Tibet supporters. The visitors had an opportunity to paint mandalas, to taste traditional salt Tibetan tea and some snacks, to watch documentaries about Tibetan culture, Tibetan political situation, relations between Lithuania and Tibet and visits of His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama to Lithuania. The last film was screened before 4 AM and a lot of people watched the program. The event was arranged at Tibet Square which was established by friends of Tibet in the popular district of artists and art called Uzupis in 2010. His Holiness consecrated the Tibet Square and the "Mandala" sculptural composition in the center of the Square during his last visit to Lithuania in 2013.
When His Holiness celebrated the 80th birthday on June 22 (according to Tibetan lunar calendar) in Dharamsala, Tibet supporters with Tibet flags and banners reminded the Tibet issue to Vice Premier of the People's Republic of China, Zhang Gaoli, who visited Vilnius those days.
It's worthwhile to remind here about some coincidences in the history of Lithuania and Tibet and some facts concerned with relations between Lithuania and Tibet in recent decades. As Tibet by PRC in 1949, Lithuania was occupied by the Soviets in 1940. The same narration was used by occupants in both cases -- Lithuanians were "liberated," as well as Tibetans. After decades of struggle and suffers under occupation Lithuania declared independence on March 11, 1990. On April 3 -- after 24 days -- the Chairman of Lithuanian Parliament (Seimas) Prof. Vytautas Landsbergis received a telegram from His Holiness the 14th Dalai Lama. His Holiness congratulated Lithuania on the independence and expressed his strong support of the peaceful struggle which was chosen by Lithuanians on their way to freedom.
In October 1991, His Holiness visited Lithuania for the first time and addressed Lithuanian people at the Lithuanian Parliament (Seimas). It was a real and a very strong support for young Independence - very few countries recognized Lithuania at that time and the visit of world known person, the Nobel Prize winner was really important for the return of Lithuania to the world map. Since then we have strong Tibet support traditions in our country - there was the Group of Parliamentarian Relations with Tibet in the Lithuanian Parliament during all years of independence. And since 1994 we have had the informal Tibet Freedom Movement, which was initiated by the famous late Lithuanian writer -- the author of the trilogy about Tibet -- Jurga Ivanauskaite. After the first visit in 1991, His Holiness visited Lithuania two more times in 2001and 2013. And every time thousands of Lithuanian people came to listen to his public talks and just to enjoy meeting with him.
It was announced by media that His Holiness joked at Dharamsala that he will celebrate his 90th Birthday at this place again. We strongly believe that he will -- but not at the same place. We hope that we will be able to send our greetings to Lhasa.
Long live the Dalai Lama!
Free Tibet!
=======
The Dalai Lama is turning 80 years old on July 6, but he doesnt want any gifts. Instead, your social media presence is the present.
In honor of his milestone birthday, His Holiness is asking people to share photos, videos and quotes depicting people simply treating one another kindly, along with the hashtag #withcompassion on social accounts.
He has done so much to spread peace and compassion to the world  this is our opportunity to truly say thank you and to show him the incredible impact his work has on the global community, Ven. Lama Tenzin Dhonden, founder and chair of Friends of the Dalai Lama nonprofit , said in an email statement.
The Dalai Lamas network of friends -- including Common, Arianna Huffington, Larry King, Russell Simmons and Randy Jackson -- are helping get the word out in the video above. Watch the clip and help celebrate the big day by sharing a post about what it means to live #withcompassion.
More:
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:44:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Is Just The Beginning Of The Great Austerity Backlash</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e38517/sc/24/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0C20A150C0A70C0A60Causterity0Epolitics0In0I77397880Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON -- The global politics of austerity seeped into the press room of the White House on Monday, the day after the Greeks voted overwhelmingly to reject a harsh bailout deal with Europe.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece Is Just The Beginning Of The Great Austerity Backlash
Posted:
Updated:
07/06/2015  7:59 pm EDT
President Barack Obama warned this past winter that you cant keep squeezing countries that are in the midst of depression. | AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster
reddit
WASHINGTON -- The global politics of austerity seeped into the press room of the White House on Monday, the day after the Greeks voted overwhelmingly to reject a harsh bailout deal with Europe.
Reporters pressed Josh Earnest, President Barack Obamas spokesman, for details of what his boss thought of the vote and of the bailout deal, and whether he agreed with 2016 Democratic presidential candidate Bernie Sanders that the latter was outrageous. Earnest answered with streams of polite words that added up to ... nothing. Obama was staying out of the issue, as he apparently had promised German Chancellor Angela Merkel he would when they met at the G-7 summit recently.
Obama favors a package of relief and reform, was all Earnest would say.
Nevertheless, the exchange with reporters in Washington was another of the many signs that the debate over the power that should accrue to money -- and what those who wield it can fairly demand -- is spreading around the world.
Its a new echo on a global scale of the politics of a much earlier, but in some ways remarkably similar, era in the U.S. As the U.S. became a continental economy in the late 19th century, with vast new hordes of wealth built in railroads, coal, electricity and communications, a political backlash arose. The new money power was judged too big and uncontrollable: an engine not of prosperity, but of inequality and corruption. The backlash launched America's Progressive movement, which among other reforms pushed laws to rein in the power of big corporationsin the interests of ordinary people.
Now that the planets economies have essentially become one, and the worlds top dozen banks control $30 trillion in assets, the callous demands of a new and even larger money power is starting to spark a worldwide backlash.
Even the ever-cautious Obama has alluded to it. This past winter, he defended Greece , saying that you cant keep squeezing countries that are in the midst of depression to pay off debt and warning that "eventually the political system, the society cant sustain it.
Around the same time, he sent the U.S. Congress a budget proposal with many new spending plans, declaring that it was time to end the mindless austerity of his Republican foes. They responded by proposing their stingiest budget plan in years.
This fall, Obama will again be battling the Republican Party over cutting spending to reduce debt -- even as he declines to get involved in the more intense version of the same debate going on in Europe.
Europe, meanwhile, is likely to see the Greek anti-austerity sentiment spread -- in the first instance to Portugal and Spain, which have national elections this fall and winter, respectively. Governments in both countries are responding to heavy borrowing and debt with controversial austerity measures sure to be at issue with the voters. French and Italian national elections are much further away, but the leftist parties in each nation have been invigorated by the fight in Athens. Representatives of parties and movements in all four countries were on the scene in Greece this week, cheering on the Syriza party and trying to learn from its victories and mistakes.
The leftists face long odds despite growing evidence that what British economist John Maynard Keynes warned during the Great Depression (and what Obama said this winter) remains true: You cant squeeze a country into prosperity. Just the opposite, in fact.
This was something the founders of the International Monetary Fund understood. Their original aim was to provide guidance to national governments in economic distress but also to feed in more money where needed, not cut it back. Today the IMF has become something akin to a collection agency, insisting on harsh measures that guarantee the repayment of loans made to vulnerable countries by private global banks.
Something has to change, as the Greeks declared with their vote this weekend.
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:42:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putting the Dalai Lama's Lessons to the Test</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.huffingtonpost.com/c/35496/f/677102/s/47e38518/sc/23/l/0L0Shuffingtonpost0N0Cleon0Estuparich0Cputting0Ethe0Edalai0Elamas0El0Ib0I7740A0A380Bhtml0Dutm0Ihp0Iref0Fworld0Gir0FWorldPost/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>reddit
After spending two extremely intimate weeks with the Dalai Lama, making his award winning film ROAD TO PEACE, Leon Stuparich wanted to take the Dalai Lama's message of peace and put it to the test. The Dalai Lama says that "peace starts within, and peace can only happen through action." So Leon decided to leave his home comforts of city life, and set himself the challenge to walk 200 miles in the ancient tradition of pilgrims, without spending money, taking food or water, and seeing if he could rely on the kindness and generosity of strangers to survive this epic journey of discovery. As a non-Buddhist, what he has learned has changed his perspective on life forever.
Overwhelmingly, people say they love the Dalai Lama because of his integrity. But what does that mean? And how can we live in the same way? How can we concretely learn from his teachings?
When I shot a documentary on the Dalai Lama, the people I interviewed about his message constantly expressed how honest and truthful he is. How there is a lack of duality in his message. He is the same person behind the scenes as he is on stage. He is the same when he meets a prime minister or president as when he shakes hands with a stranger on the street.
My first morning back from my 2-week long pilgrimage for peace, I am buying morning coffees when I realize: I messed up.
I wanted seeing my kids to be the first thing I did when I returned. However, exhausted and still in a whirl, I quickly became engulfed in the stress of my busy work life.
As I walk to my regular coffee cart, I find myself walking slower than usual. I'm still digesting the pilgrimage, a journey that blended ancient and modern trails. We pioneered a new pilgrimage route along the Thames Path and The Ridgeway, at times we were wild camping, and at others we had no idea where we were go to sleep or what we going to eat. But with faith, a good map, and a large amount of fortitude, we survived the epic journey with little more than a few bad blisters on our feet. Now home, I'm walking another path that I've walked hundreds of times before -- to and from the coffee cart -- but after walking penniless for two weeks, these steps today are some of the most striking.
Maybe it's the contrast of walking this route before and after the pilgrimage, maybe it's the act of spending money again. I think it's more likely that last night I had my first good sleep in weeks and today I woke up with the striking clarity of how much I miss my family. I say to myself, "Today I will see my family no matter what."
As I stand in the queue for coffee, I realize that the explanation that "we're pilgrims on a penniless journey" is no longer required. That story we had to tell again and again for two weeks, in order to get food or shelter, is no longer my story. That story was who I was for a while.
Which is when a little bell rings in my head and I finally realize what I mean by "story" and where it fits in with the Dalai Lama's integrity that so many people talk about:
Your story is your ego.
The story of the penniless pilgrim is one we created by going on the 200 mile walk. It was necessary to survive -- without it we would have starved. People loved the story. They loved our journey and we were taken in with so much love and kindness -- our story defined us.
Maybe, the story we tell ourselves and other people is not simply our ego -- it's the story we write to define our lives. In this case, the story you write is how other people read you. If you make up a false story -- a story of something you are not genuinely doing or being, then people will instinctively see through it. If your story genuinely reflects your heart and who you truly are as a person -- if it's a story of love and kindness -- then you are seen to have integrity.
So, what makes up a whole person? Perhaps it is a combination of our inner values and the ego story we tell ourselves. Is this what defines us in life? Is this what determines whether we are a success or failure? Is this how we ensure we live our lives to the fullest and live in our own integrity?
If we can identify our own individual inner values (what makes us happy, who and how we love, etc.) and express that through the story we tell of ourselves, then maybe life can open up and be the miracle it has the potential to be.
Realizing this, at the coffee cart, I am struck by the fact that, though I seem to have just arrived home from my "big journey," in fact it is just the beginning of a new journey for me. This journey is one of embarking upon understanding my own "story" and becoming comfortable with it. I can feel a skip of joy as I write this because I know I've never had the confidence to hear my own story.
If this is my lesson from working with the Dalai Lama's principles for seven years and going on a 200 mile journey, then I am infinitely grateful. The power of writing your own story -- with the help of others -- is an incredible concept.
It's always been my hope that the work I do will inspire other people. Whilst walking alone on the Ridgeway, Britain's most ancient road, during the pilgrimage I realised we are all walking together as one human family. If one person is inspired, we are all a little more inspired. This is why the story we tell ourselves and the stories that people say about us are so important.
Do you believe what others say about you?
During the two weeks filming with the Dalai Lama, one of the most surprising things was his approach on self-confidence and determination. Not something I'd previously considered as part of creating peace. In an interview he gave me, he said, "Buddha taught: don't care what other people say. When one person says something critical then you should think: some people are praising me. When someone says a lot of praise, then you should think: I also have the critics. So it doesn't matter. As long as your own intention is honest, sincere. That's important. Paying too much attention to these things is silly."
Ignore the stories other people create for you. Receive them as a reflection of the story you're expressing, but don't let those external stories completely rewrite or change your own personal expression of your self. The power is within the story. The story is the conduit through which we connect to each other.
On the walk we naturally slowed down, and when we stopped to meet people, or they took up the pilgrimage and walked along with us for a while, the most powerful moments were always in hearing other people's stories. Listening. Now, in retrospect, it was as if we were listening to their hearts. If we are too busy to listen to the story, if we are too engrossed in our own stories to make the space needed in ourselves to receive the stories of others, it's the same as saying that we don't care or we don't have time for anyone but ourselves.
If your life is dominated by your story and there is a lack of actual expression -- integrity of your actions with your story -- then your story is unbalanced and people stop listening. If you just take action and don't express what you're doing -- or you're uncomfortable in expressing it -- then it's harder for people to read.
Do what you say. And say what you do.
Your story informs your actions in a symbiotic relationship, but if the story doesn't start from your own heart and an understanding of your own nurtured inner values, then you're going to fall over!
Of all the lessons I have learned from the Dalai Lama, this is the most powerful so far: to live in your own integrity. To live honestly, with self confidence. To explore your inner values and deepen those and then live life from these values.
It certainly isn't easy, but walking the pilgrimage and putting my own values into action -- largely by going penniless -- has taught me that only through taking action, and the intention behind the action, can we really learn and therefore hopefully create a lasting change within ourselves and the world in which we live.
Today I hope this insight will inspire others and create a little more peace and love in the world.
Follow Leon Stuparich on Twitter: www.twitter.com/roadtopeacefilm
More:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
