<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Independent">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:41:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Backlash against JPMorgan boss Jamie Dimon after branded his own investors as 'lazy'</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda4d1/sc/31/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Cbacklash0Eagainst0Ejpmorgan0Eboss0Ejamie0Edimon0Eafter0Ebranded0Ehis0Eown0Einvestors0Eas0Elazy0E10A2832970Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; Business &gt; Business News
Backlash against JPMorgan boss Jamie Dimon after branded his own investors as 'lazy'
Chief executive of giant Wall Street bank branded 'insulting' and 'out of touch' for his reaction to shareholders' executive pay revolt
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
The JPMorgan boss Jamie Dimon has been blasted as removed from reality and insulting after he branded his own investors lazy for voting against his multimillion-dollar pay deal.
At a conference in New York on Wednesday, the chief executive of the giant Wall Street bank said stockholders who had followed the recommendations of two influential professional advisory services and rejected Mr Dimons $20m (13m) pay package last week were irresponsible and not good investors.
Luke Hildyard, deputy director of the High Pay Centre think-tank in the UK, said the lazy shareholders were the ones who voted in favour of Mr Dimons pay deal. He must be totally removed from reality if he thinks closer scrutiny of lavish executive pay packages will result in higher levels of approval for top pay  rather than higher levels of condemnation he said. There will be many active and engaged shareholders who feel extremely insulted by Mr Dimons suggestions of lack of professionalism, said Sarah Wilson, chief executive of the Manifest proxy voting agency.
A spokesman for Pensions &amp; Investment Research Consultants (Pirc), which itself advised clients to vote against Mr Dimons pay, drew attention to the regulatory fines paid by the bank in recent years: Given JPMorgan has attracted around $40bn of fines since 2008, it is legitimate for shareholders to question whether they are getting value for money from the huge pay packages executives want them to approve.
Thirty-eight per cent of JP Morgan shareholders rejected Mr Dimons pay package at the banks annual meeting on 19 May. ISS, the largest of the shareholder advisory firms, had urged a no vote on the grounds that the board had not linked Mr Dimons remuneration to performance and that 40 per cent of his pay was in cash. Glass Lewis, another advisory firm, had also urged a no vote.
God knows how any of you can place your vote based on ISS or Glass Lewis, Mr Dimon told the conference. If you do that, you are just irresponsible, I am sorry. And you probably arent a very good investor either. I know some of you here do it because you are very lazy. ISS declined to comment on Mr Dimons remarks; Glass Lewis could not be reached.
Another concern for investment advisers is that Mr Dimon occupies the roles of both chief executive and chairman at JP Morgan. Ms Wilson, of Manifest, said the blending of the two roles was a red-line issue [for corporate governance] going back a quarter of a century at least. She also suggested Mr Dimons latest outburst suggests he is out of touch with shareholders. Does he understand what they do or is he just listening to what his advisers are paid to tell him? she asked.
Last week 36 per cent of shareholders also rejected the JP Morgan boards wishes and voted in favour of installing an independent chairman after Mr Dimon retires.
Advisory firms were eager to rebut Mr Dimons suggestion that asset managers simply vote in the way consultants tell them to on matters of pay and governance. Asset owners make the decisions; proxy advisers only make recommendations, said a Pirc spokesman.
However, Mr Dimon is not without high-profile supporters among the shareholders. In January 2014 Warren Buffet suggested Mr Dimon is not paid enough. If I owned JP Morgan Chase, he [Mr Dimon] would be running it and he would be making more money than the directors are paying him, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:38:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Discount retail is digging in as B&amp;M buys 12 B&amp;Q stores</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda4cf/sc/23/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Cdiscount0Eretail0Eis0Edigging0Ein0Eas0Ebm0Ebuys0E120Ebq0Estores0E10A2832950Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Discount retail is digging in as B&amp;M buys 12 B&amp;Q stores

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
The shape of the high street has shifted in one of the most symbolic signs yet of the rise and rise of discount retailing.
B&amp;M Bargains, the cut-price variety retailer chaired by the former Tesco boss Sir Terry Leahy, is understood to have snapped up 12 of the 14 sites that have so far been sold by the Kingfisher-owned B&amp;Q, Britains biggest DIY retailer.
B&amp;Q has previously revealed that it will shut 60 of its 360 stores over the next two years, while B&amp;M said it would open 60 new stores this year alone  up from the 40 first mooted.
Tony Shiret, a retail analyst at the investment bank BESI, said: The most significant news here is the disposal of 12 B&amp;Q units to B&amp;M (undisclosed but no leap of the imagination). Kingfisher management believes that B&amp;M is no real threat to B&amp;Q, with a limited overlapping range.
While true of the current majority of B&amp;M stores, the largest ones carry, in our view, a very credible range of DIY low-end furniture and to a lesser extent garden products.
The news came as B&amp;M, which sells everything from toys to gardening shears and tinned tuna, revealed its maiden full-year results since listing on the stock market. Pre-tax profits hit 61.7m in the year to March, against a 14.3m loss last time, on sales up 29.5 per cent at 1.65bn.
Its chief executive, Simon Arora, said: We originally planned on opening 40 stores this year, but property developers are back with confidence and more mature retailers are rightsizing their estate and exiting sites, so weve raised this to 60 stores.
Sources at B&amp;M added that many of the new stores would be purpose-built by developers for the company.
Like-for-like sales increased by 4.4 per cent and Mr Arora added that he plans further expansion into Europe, after buying the German group Jawoll earlier this year.
The cold weather has hit more recent sales, although Mr Arora said he was able to fill B&amp;Ms shelves with different items due to its wide range of products. He added: I asked my two girls last weekend if they wanted to get out the paddling pool, and they both looked at me like I was mad.
By contrast, Kingfisher revealed that like-for-like sales at B&amp;Q fell 1.1 per cent in the first quarter, although this was offset by continued strong growth at its Screwfix business, up 15.4 per cent, which targets the building trade. Outdoor seasonal and building product sales were hit hard, dropping 4 per cent.
The strong pound also hit Kingfishers French business. Sales at Castorama and Brico Dpt, which make up a third of total revenues, declined by 12.4 per cent and 10.4 per cent respectively.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:37:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reliance on imports harms UK growth</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda2bd/sc/24/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Creliance0Eon0Eimports0Eharms0Euk0Egrowth0E10A2832940Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Reliance on imports harms UK growth

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Hopes that the UK would shake off its early-year doldrums were temporarily dashed as official growth figures showed a widening trade gap and surprising weakness from the nations dominant services firms.
Economists had hoped that the Office for National Statistics would lift its initial 0.3 per cent estimate for GDP growth between January and March to 0.4 per cent, following healthier signs from manufacturers and builders.
But the economy sucked in imports during the first quarter, far outstripping exports and leaving net trade dragging 0.9 percentage points from the wider economy. The surge  driven by oil, machinery and cars  is likely to revive concerns that recovery is too reliant on domestic consumers.
The stronger pound also hit its highest level against a basket of currencies since August 2008 in March, dampening the competitiveness of UK exporters in the eurozone and other markets.
Chris Williamson, chief economist at financial data firm Markit, said the economy is being driven again by consumers, adding: The unbalanced pattern of growth is likely to result in a slower expansion of GDP in 2015 than expected.
However, there was slightly better news on business investment, which rose 1.7 per cent  the best since April-June last year.
The pace of household spending softened slightly to 0.5 per cent, but experts expect it to grow strongly this year thanks to the falling prices of food and petrol.
The Bank of England predicts overall growth for the quarter will eventually be revised up to 0.5 per cent.
people
News
health
News
filmReview: In the face of all-round devastation, even Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson appears a little puny
News
footballPaul Scholes on the best players, managers and goals of the season - and the biggest disappointments
News
ebookA unique anthology of reporting and analysis of a crucial period of history
Life and Style
voices
Life and Style
Autistic adults could take pure MDMA to 'reduce social anxiety'
2
Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:36:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tom Hayes Libor trial: Broker 'was offered $100,000 to fix benchmark interest rate'</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda2bc/sc/25/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Ctom0Ehayes0Elibor0Etrial0Ebroker0Ewas0Eoffered0E10A0A0A0A0A0Eto0Efix0Ebenchmark0Einterest0Erate0E10A2832930Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:33:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Group planning to sue Tesco bring in top commercial lawyer Philip Marshall</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda2bb/sc/28/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Cgroup0Eplanning0Eto0Esue0Etesco0Ebring0Ein0Etop0Ecommercial0Elawyer0Ephilip0Emarshall0E10A2832920Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Group planning to sue Tesco bring in top commercial lawyer Philip Marshall

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A highly respected commercial lawyer has been drafted in by a group set up to sue Tesco over last years accounting scandal in what could turn into a multi-billion pound lawsuit.
Philip Marshall QC represented Paddy McKillen in his epic battle with the Barclay brothers over ownership of the Claridges, Connaught and Berkeley hotels, grilled Bernie Ecclestone in the High Court for three days over the sale of the Formula One business to CVC and fought for the largest group of fraud actions ever to be brought in the High Court against Kazakhstans BTA Bank.
He will advise the various institutional investors who have been signed up by the Tesco Shareholder Claims (TSC) group and a formal claim is expected to be filed later this year.
The revelation is another blow to Tesco, which is under intense scrutiny and investigations by the Serious Fraud Office, the Groceries Code Adjudicator and the Financial Reporting Council.
Last month its chief executive Dave Lewis dumped the companys auditor of 32 years, PwC, for failing to spot the accounting scandal that saw the supermarkets commercial division notching up profits from supplier payments before those payments had been received.
An internal report by Freshfields and Deloitte found that 263m had been mis-stated over at least the last three years, although this figure was revised up to 326m last month as further discrepancies were found in the supermarkets Irish business.
The TSC, along with British law firm McGuireWoods and US attorneys Scott and Scott, which are filing a similar claim on behalf of US shareholders, claim the scandal wiped between 50p and 70p permanently from the value of the shares, meaning the total bill could be as high as 1.9bn.
David Scott, managing partner at Scott and Scott, said: Our investigation over the last few months has shown that Tesco committed serious violations when it overstated its profits. We intend to pursue Tesco in order to help our clients recoup their losses.
The addition of Marshall to the legal fight will give a major boost to the cause following his performances in several, high-profile cases. In 2013 he rattled Mr Ecclestone in court, accusing him of fabricating evidence in an albeit unsuccessful attempt by the German media company Constantin Medien to sue the F1 boss. Mr Marshall, of Serle Court Chambers, also represented Liverpool FC directors when the club was sold to Fenway Sports Group in 2010.
Tesco declined to comment when contacted.
The news comes as the supermarket lost its battle with residents of Londons Belsize Park, where bosses were hoping to build a new store. The plans faced heavy resistance from famous local residents including Tom Conti and Janet Suzman.
Businessman Andrew Thornton, who runs the local Budgens store, revealed the plans were pulled on Wednesday night.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:32:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Every little helps in the case of Tesco's shareholders</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda2b5/sc/23/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Ccomment0Cevery0Elittle0Ehelps0Ein0Ethe0Ecase0Eof0Etescos0Eshareholders0E10A2832910Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Every little helps in the case of Tesco's shareholders

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Outlook After misstating its profits by more than a quarter of a million pounds, Tesco will have been well aware that a lawsuit could appear at the check out. Lawyers swim towards situations like this faster than sharks scenting blood in the water.
The shareholders affected by the share price slump in the wake of the fateful profit announcement have at least managed to get their hands on some good ones.
The problem is that even if they are successful their compensation will ultimately be paid by other shareholders. Peter is suing Paul.
Given the way the stock has rebounded, those who bought in after the announcement when the shares were on special offer arent showing any signs of concern. The share price barely moved in response to the legal news, which tells you a lot. But even if such actions appear a little self-defeating, you can hardly blame the Peters for trying. After all, as the slogan goes, every little helps.
The pity is that those responsible for situations like that at Tesco rarely seem to suffer much.
people
News
health
News
filmReview: In the face of all-round devastation, even Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson appears a little puny
News
footballPaul Scholes on the best players, managers and goals of the season - and the biggest disappointments
News
ebookA unique anthology of reporting and analysis of a crucial period of history
Life and Style
voices
Life and Style
Autistic adults could take pure MDMA to 'reduce social anxiety'
2
Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:31:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Official figures undermine Government's promises</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda2aa/sc/24/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Ccomment0Cofficial0Efigures0Eundermine0Egovernments0Epromises0E10A283290A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Official figures undermine Government's promises

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Outlook It seems to have become standard practice to question the Office for National Statistics data whenever it springs a surprise on the economy.
Which is what happened on Thursday when it kept faith with its initial  and disappointing  estimate of growth in the first quarter at 0.3 per cent rather than increasing it to 0.4 per cent.
As ever, the reasons for this were mixed, and some forecasters  including the Bank of England  still feel theres scope for an upward revision. However, even if that happens, the numbers will still represent a disappointment. Were it not for relatively robust domestic demand, they would be much worse.
Exports fell by 0.3 per cent while imports surged by 2.3 per cent. The upshot being that net trade cut 0.9 percentage points off GDP, the biggest negative from this source for nearly two years.
The Conservatives rode to an election victory on the back of their claims of economic competence. These figures call that into question.
Two of the big economic goals of the last Government were to eliminate the deficit by the end of the Parliament, and to rebalance Britains economy.
We all know what happened to the first one. Stubbornly high Government borrowing has forced the forthcoming emergency budget.
While part of the reason for the UKs poor export performance is down to the problems faced by some of our major trading partners, policy failure must bear part of the blame here too. There is precious little sign that the economy is being re-balanced in the ONSs numbers and those claims to economic competence might need to be reassessed.
people
News
health
News
filmReview: In the face of all-round devastation, even Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson appears a little puny
News
footballPaul Scholes on the best players, managers and goals of the season - and the biggest disappointments
News
ebookA unique anthology of reporting and analysis of a crucial period of history
Life and Style
voices
Life and Style
Autistic adults could take pure MDMA to 'reduce social anxiety'
2
Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:30:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Spread betting is a success story for these most volatile of times</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bda2a1/sc/31/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Ccomment0Cspread0Ebetting0Eis0Ea0Esuccess0Estory0Efor0Ethese0Emost0Evolatile0Eof0Etimes0E10A2832880Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Spread betting is a success story for these most volatile of times

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Outlook These are the salad days for the spread betting industry, one of those rare sub-sectors of business in which Britain is a world leader. It thrives on volatility because it is volatility that excites the punters and theres plenty of that about right now.
The worlds major currencies are bouncing around as speculators bet on interest rates moving up. Closer to home, there is the uncertainty created by the UKs EU referendum together with the impact on the eurozone of the continuing agonies of the Greek economy.
Then there are the host of simmering geo-political crises that regularly worry the worlds markets when they flare up.
No wonder CMC Markets is preparing a flotation. Its the perfect time for it, as Peter Cruddas baby proved by toasting a 61 per cent rise in profits.
On the same day market leader IG issued a rather terse trading statement, saying its earnings will be as expected. Move along, nothing to see here.
Perhaps there are good reasons for IG wanting to steer clear of the spotlight for a while. Unlike CMC, with a business more weighted towards stock market indices, it suffered a big blow from the shock decision of the Swiss Central Bank to abandon the Swiss francs euro peg in January.
The Swissie immediately lurched upwards by 30 per cent and the scale of the move shattered punters stop loss policies, designed to limit their downside. Many were left with debts they were unable to pay. Amidst apparently savvy speculators were the sort of people you really wouldnt expect to find punting on European currency markets. People on relatively modest incomes such as primary school teachers, even concert pianists.
Some months down the line, and with the industry apparently none the worse for wear, it would be all too easy to sweep the event under the carpet as a one-off. The problem is that such one-offs do rather have a habit of occurring in financial markets.
The industrys leaders need to learn lessons from what went on. Its easy enough to point the finger at punters and say they should have known what they were getting themselves into. It is true, after all.
All the same, it isnt in the industrys interest to have people who cant meet their margin calls on its books. Regulators have plenty of fish to fry at the moment, but if the industry doesnt see the danger, theyll be knocking at its door before too long.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:25:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Market Report:</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd6f0c/sc/21/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Csharewatch0Cmarket0Ereport0E10A2832870Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:24:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thirst for luxury: who would pay £250 for a bottle of spirits?</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd6f0b/sc/26/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Canalysis0Eand0Efeatures0Cthirst0Efor0Eluxury0Ewho0Ewould0Epay0E250A0Efor0Ea0Ebottle0Eof0Espirits0E10A2832860Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Britain may be known for having a boozy culture, but investors are hoping we have a taste for luxury as well as alcohol. Illva Saronno, the Italian drinks company that makes the liqueurs Tia Maria and Disaronno, this week revealed it will make an audacious new push into the UK with a special blend costing 250 a bottle.
The UK spirits industry is big. In total last year, it made a profit of 721.3m on sales of 4.1bn generated from 122 companies, according to IBISWorld. The research body also forecasts that revenue will increase at a compound annual rate of 1.8 per cent over the five years to 2020.
But what is it that convinces Illva Saronnos chief executive, Augusto Reina, that now is the time to expand further in Britain? What is it about luxury drinks, many endorsed with a celebrity name, that attracts the public? And which other companies are cashing in?
Illva Saronno expansion
The luxury drinks brand is launching its new product, Disaronno Riserva, across the world and it will hit British shores in the second half of the year. It is produced by mixing Disaronno with Scotch whisky in oak barrels that previously contained marsala wine reserves.
Negotiations are now under way to sell the product in high-end retailers. It will also be stocked in some UK duty- free shops.
This is something new and very different that has taken time and dedication said Mr Reina. The UK market right now is one of the most important for us and London has a key role to play for our UK sales.
The company has just hired a new, four-strong dedicated UK-based team, including Ian Taylor who joins as a director from rival Pernod Ricard. Previous luxury initiatives by the company include forming an alliance with the fashion house Versace to create a designer look for its bottles. Mr Reina said the company wants to increase its UK presence aggressively.
Disaronno and Tia Maria revenues reached 350m (250m) last year, of which 10 per cent came from Britain.
Whats the appeal of luxury liquor?
Christian Davis, editor of the trade magazine Drinks International, said he does not envisage any slowdown in the high-end drinks market.
This is what is dubbed premiumisation and it is a very important revenue channel for key drinks companies. Some of the firms are recruiting people from the perfume and haute couture industries to help market their brands as a luxury product.
Mr Davis added that the drinks tend to be bought by rich people passing through airports, or stocked in the coolest London and New York bars. The middle classes of countries such as India and China are also keen buyers.
Sara Grady, food and drink analyst at Datamonitor Consumer believes companies making unusual and limited products can expect a strong customer base.
Consumers become more aware of the qualities associated with a luxury beverage, such as exclusivity, production expertise, and product provenance, she said. This starts to become the norm and to be expected in mainstream alcohol launches. We can therefore expect these super-luxury arrivals to focus even more on exclusivity and production routes.
So confident are some of the brands, especially those linked to celebrities, that James Ebel, a partner at the property agent Harper Dennis Hobbs, has been approached by companies from the US seeking shops and concession space on some of the UKs most elite shopping streets.
He said there is some concern among landlords about whether all the brands will have longevity, but that they are willing to offer pop-up space and short-term leases.Any business willing to commit to the sometimes troubled British high street is probably convinced that the returns will outweigh the risks in any investment.
What else is on the shelf?
The luxury drinks market has been hit by a drop in sales in China as consumers stop buying pricey bottles of upmarket alcohol such as cognac amid the Chinese Governments crackdown on lavish gift-giving. Recent results from companies such as Pernod Ricard and Diageo show they have both been affected.
Nevertheless, Pernod said in March that sales of Martell cognac performed well during the Chinese New Year holiday, and last year Diageo confirmed its commitment to luxury celebrity products by launching Haig Club  a new Scotch whisky  in partnership with David Beckham and the showbusiness svengali Simon Fuller.
One company that has seen the benefit of stocking celebrity lines is the three-year-old 31Dover.com.
The e-tailer prides itself on securing the latest must-have releases, such as George Clooneys Casamigos Tequila and Hipster Chablis (which comes in a glow-in-the-dark bottle).
Last year the companys turnover hit 1m. Director Jay Swanborough said: We are seeing more and more brands approach us with new, higher-end formats and approaches to distilling and blending. People are buying larger formats across the board, spending more. A bigger bottle of anything tends to feel special, and to some extent can be seen as a bit of a luxury or extravagance.
With Illva Saronno prepared to invest so much time and money on a new luxury product, it certainly seems confident that the thirst for expensive alcohol will not be sated for some time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:23:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The uncomfortable permanence of these temporary measures</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd6f07/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Ccomment0Cthe0Euncomfortable0Epermanence0Eof0Ethese0Etemporary0Emeasures0E10A2832850Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; Business &gt; Business Comment
The uncomfortable permanence of these temporary measures
Das Capital: In may be that low interest rates and QE cannot be reversed easily, if at all
Satyajit Das
Satyajit Das
Satyajit Das writes the Das Capital Column in the Independent. He has worked in financial markets for over 35 years, as a banker, a corporate treasurer and now as a consultant to banks, fund managers, governments, companies and regulators around the world. He is also the author of Traders Guns and Money and Extreme Money as well as a number of reference books on derivatives and risk-management, which double as 'door stops'. He became a banker because he wasn't good enough to be a professional cricketer, but would give up finance if anyone offered him a job as a cricket commentator or allowed him to pursue his other passion- wildlife (he is the co-author with Jade Novakovic of In Search of The Pangolin: The Accidental Eco-Tourist). He lives in Sydney, Australia.
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Central banks have convinced themselves that low interest rates and quantitative easing (QE) policies are temporary. It is reminiscent of Ashly Lorenzanas definition of addiction in her journal Sex, Drugs &amp; Being an Escort: When you can give up something any time, as long as its next Tuesday. It isnt necessarily so that these policies can be reversed easily, if at all.
Withdrawing fiscal stimulus would lead to sharp slowdowns in economic activity. Reduction in government services and higher taxes accelerate contraction in disposable incomes, especially in an environment of stagnant wages and uncertain employment. In turn, this leads to a sharp contraction in consumption. Slower growth, exacerbated by high fiscal multipliers, makes it difficult to correct budget deficits and control government debt levels.
As this debt grows, financing difficulties trigger a financial crisis or force reliance on the central bank monetising its debt.
Low interest rates and QE are also hard to change. Normalisation of rates and cuts in central bank purchases of government bonds risk reduced availability of funding and financial disruption.
Low rates allow over-extended companies and nations to maintain or increase borrowings rather than reducing debt levels. Levels of debt encouraged by low rates become rapidly unsustainable at higher rates.
Central banks also cannot sell government bonds and other securities held on their balance sheet. The size of these holdings means disposals would lead to higher rates, resulting in large losses for the central bank as well as other banks and investors. The reduction in liquidity would exacerbate this by sharply tightening the supply of credit, destabilising a fragile financial system.
If sustained, a 1 per cent rise in rates would increase the debt servicing costs of the US government by around $170bn (110bn). A rise of 1 per cent in G7 rates would increase the interest expense of the G7 countries by around $1.4trn.
Higher interest rates would also affect indebted consumers and corporations. In the US, a 1 per cent rise in interest rates, according to a McKinsey Global Institute study, would increase household debt payments from $822bn to $876bn, a rise of 7 per cent. In the UK, a 1 per cent rate change would increase household debt payments from 96bn to 113bn, a rise of 19 per cent.
The central question is for what period and to what extent current policies can be continued. The stock of private sector domestic savings limits the amount of government debt, ignoring foreign borrowing and debt monetisation by the central bank. If a nation has accumulated large foreign investments, then income and capital from these can finance the government for a time. Ultimately, reliance shifts to the ability of the central bank to monetise debt and finance the government but there may be limits to this.
The balance sheet expansion required by QE programmes exposes a central bank to the risk of losses on its holdings of securities from defaults or (more realistically) higher yields  ironically, if the economy recovers and rates rise. In theory, there is no limit to the size of the losses a central bank can incur. But there may be practical constraints.
The US Federal Reserve has $54bn in capital supporting assets of around $4trn. The European Central Bank has 10bn in capital supporting assets of 3trn. The Bank of England has 3.3bn in capital supporting assets of 397bn. In effect, a small change in asset values would significantly impair their capital bases.
Seigniorage revenues constitute another possible limit to debt. Seigniorage is the difference between the value of money and the cost of producing it  the difference between interest earned on securities acquired in exchange for money created by central banks, and the cost of producing and distributing that money. A central bank is considered solvent so long as the discounted value of seigniorage income is greater than its other liabilities in the long run.
The ultimate constraint remains preservation of the status of the currency as a medium of exchange or accepted store of value. Central banks would not risk a currency becoming unacceptable for normal commercial transactions, as with Zimbabwe and other similar cases.
While central banks have not reached the limits of their capacity to act, they retain scope for action. But existing policy does not address the real issues and may not be capable of restoring economic health. Addicted to monetary morphine, central banks believe there is no alternative.
Satyajit Das is a former banker and author of Extreme Money and Traders, Guns &amp; Money
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:20:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CMC founder £14m richer as he heads for the market</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd6ef7/sc/24/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Ccmc0Efounder0E14m0Ericher0Eas0Ehe0Eheads0Efor0Ethe0Emarket0E10A2832840Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>CMC founder 14m richer as he heads for the market

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
CMC Markets founder, Peter Cruddas, has added another 14m to his fortune after the spread-betting business announced a huge increase in its profits and confirmed plans for a 1bn flotation.
The company is talks with investment banks over the long-awaited move and is expected to appoint advisers in the next fortnight for the initial public offering.
CMC laid the groundwork for the expected launch with a 61 per cent rise in pre-tax profits to 51.9m for the year to 31 March.
As a result it upped its dividend from 12m to 16m, meaning a payout of 14.4m for Mr Cruddas, who holds a 90 per cent stake in CMC. The balance is owned by the US bank Goldman Sachs.
The Hackney-born entrepreneur founded the company with 10,000 in 1989. It now has around 75,000 regular traders a year. Client numbers rose 11 per cent and revenues were up 18 per cent to 143.7m over the year.
Mr Cruddas, who last tried to list on the stock market in 2007, before the financial crisis struck, said: The bottom line is that it just feels like we need to be a public company now.
The flotation is likely to generate hundreds of millions of pounds in cash  a lot of which will go to Mr Cruddass charitable foundation, he added.
He resumed day-to-day control two years ago after a period in the background. The company has invested heavily in its technology, generating a surge in mobile trading.CMC largely shrugged off the bombshell lobbed into currency markets by the Swiss National Bank in January, when it suddenly scrapped its 1.20 peg for the Swiss franc and sent the value of the Swissie soaring. The company took a 4m hit, in contrast to the much bigger 30m blow to its larger competitor, IG Group.
Mr Cruddas added: Our strong risk management meant that we saw only a minimal impact from the Swiss National Bank decision, and our strong balance sheet and capital ratio are increasingly attracting clients from a number of our competitors, as they fly to safety.
IG reported that its trading was solid in the three months to May, leaving it well on track to hit its full-year hopes.
The company has extended its stockbroking service into the Netherlands and is set to open a new office in Dubai in the weeks ahead after securing regulatory approvals.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:56:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>British schoolgirls 'will never leave Syria', senior female Isis commander claims as teenagers reportedly make contact with their families</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46b6ad6c/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cbritish0Eschoolgirls0Ewill0Enever0Eleave0Esyria0Esenior0Efemale0Eisis0Ecommander0Eclaims0Eas0Eteenagers0Ereportedly0Emake0Econtact0Ewith0Etheir0Efamilies0E10A280A50A90Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>British schoolgirls 'will never leave Syria', senior female Isis commander claims as teenagers reportedly make contact with their families
Um Asmah says she met the teenagers at the Syrian border
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A female senior commander who defected from Isis has warned the three British schoolgirls who travelled to Syria in February will never be able to return to the UK.
The woman, who called herself Um Asmah, is one of the most high-ranking commanders to speak out after leaving the group and was interviewed by Sky News just days after fleeing Isis.
The 22-year-old told the network she met the teenagers from the border as part of her role introducing new recruits to life in the groups self-declared caliphate.
Shamima Begum, Kadiza Sultana and Amira Abase are now under-going a four month training programme in its stronghold of Raqqa to prepare for special missions.
Um Asmah shook her head when asked if the girls would ever return home and said: I think they will die in Syria or Iraq.
Kazida Sultana, Amira Abase and Shamima Begum Her comments came amid reports the three girls had contacted their families more than three months after disappearing. One of the girls said they were healthy and well, but had no intention if travelling back to the UK, according to ITV News . The remaining two are believed to have made contact with their families in east London via the internet.
Isis seizes Ramadi
She said the girls are not particularly well-known among Isis members because there are already a lot of girls from Britain, Germany and France living there. They were happy to be in Syria, she added, but were unprepared for what would be expected of them there. She said one of the girls was reprimanded for showing her face to a driver.
Veiled women walk past a billboard that carries a verse from Koran urging women to wear a hijab in the northern province of Raqqa (REUTERS/Stringer) She claimed all three were groomed by Isis who she says has developed a structured system to target vulnerable young people, especially from overseas. "Isis is not stupid, they have educated people who know how to deal with (the) psychology of others, how to deal with the human being," she explained.
"They have ways to attract people - especially foreigners. Otherwise young British people wouldn't come and say they will change the flag on Buckingham Palace."
Um Asmah said she now spends every second living in fear that militants will track her down. "I am a traitor and an unbeliever now. I am scared every day, every minute and of everyone I meet."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to live to be really old</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46ba52ab/sc/15/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Chow0Eto0Elive0Eto0Ebe0Ereally0Eold0E10A2823260Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>How to live to be really old
From the supercentenarians themselves
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
It's highly questionable whether you'd want to live well into your hundreds, but if longevity is your thing, how best to achieve a good run?
The best piece of advice: BE A WOMAN.
The ten oldest people ever to have lived where all female, and the list of 100 verified oldest people contains only a handful of men.
Location-wise, the United States is the place to be for being super old, with a staggering 51 of the Top 100 hailing from the US, while Japan also sees its fair share of supercentenarians.
Beyond that, we only have the testimonies of the hyper-elderly to rely on, which fortunately are plentiful given that reporters nearly always ask them what their secret is.
Jeanne Calment, oldest human ever to have lived, born 1875, died 1997 aged 122 years and 164 days in France
Said to have enjoyed 'an occasional glass of Port wine and a diet rich in olive oil'
Fun fact: She met Van Gogh and described him as "dirty, badly dressed and disagreeable".
Sarah Knauss, second oldest human to have lived, born 1880, died 1999 aged 119 years and 97 days in the US
Didn't divulge a secret, but her passions were said to be watching golf on television, doing needlepoint, and nibbling on milk chocolate turtles, cashews, and potato chips.
Misao Okawa, born 1898, died 2015 aged 117 years and 27 days in Japan
"Eating delicious things is a key to my longevity."
These included ramen noodles and beef stew, as well as hashed beef and rice mackerel sushi.
When asked how she felt about her 117 years on Earth, she quite wonderfully replied: "It seemed rather short."
Mara Capovilla, born 1889, died 2006 aged 116 years and 347 days in Ecuador
She was said to enjoy painting, embroidery, dancing and walking. In her youth she would also drink fresh milk from the donkeys at her aunt's farm, which relatives credited with helping herachieve such a good age.
She is said never to have smoked, ate regular small meals, and only drank in moderation.
Gertrude Weaver, born 1898, died 2015 aged 116 years and 276 days in the US
She focused less on diet and more on outlook.
"Trusting in the Lord, hard work and loving everybody"
"Kindness. Treat people right and be nice to other people the way you want them to be nice to you."
Tane Ikai, born 1879, died 1995 aged 116 years and 175 days
Scant details. Apparently enjoyed making pottery and sewing.
Elizabeth Bolden, born 1890, died 2006 aged 116 years and 118 days
She shied away from media attention, and when she turned 113 in 2003, a reporter who asked her why she had lived so long was met with the reply "I don't know."
The reporter speculated that Bolden just wasn't in the mood to talk that day, given that when one of her daughters kept trying to cover her with a blanket, she said "If you weren't my child, I'd put you over my knee and whoop the [expletive] out of you."
Besse Berry Cooper, born 1896, died 2012 aged 116 years and 100 days
She credited "minding her own business" and avoiding junk food.
----
Nowadays, the oldest person in the world keeps dying.
Though curiously no recent 'champions' have come close to the ages of those that died in the 90s, improvements in health care have meant that a much larger number of people now reach their hundreds, making the reign of each oldest person often last only days.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>America is officially the most competitive country in the world</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46b7cc66/sc/24/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Camerica0Eis0Eofficially0Ethe0Emost0Ecompetitive0Ecountry0Ein0Ethe0Eworld0E10A280A9560Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>America is officially the most competitive country in the world

Victoria Richards
Victoria Richards
Victoria Richards is a freelance journalist currently working for The Independent online. She has previously worked for The Times and Sunday Times online and BBC News UK
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
In what may come as no shock to anyone, America has topped the rankings on a list of the most competitive countries in the world.
The International Institute for Management Development (IMD)  an international business school in Lausanne  has released its annual list of world competitiveness according to the key factors of innovation, drive, effectiveness of each country's infrastructure and strong business efficiency.
Hong Kong moved up, hot on the heels of the USA, to second place, with Singapore in third, overtaking Switzerland, which dropped down into fourth place.
Canada came in fifth, followed by Luxembourg, and Norway, Denmark, Sweden and Germany were all in the top ten.
Results for Asia, however, were more mixed - with Malaysia, Japan, Thailand and Indonesia all moving down in the rankings.
The same drops were seen in Eastern Europe and in Latin America, with Estonia and Latvia moving down, as did Chile, Peru and Argentina.
World Competitiveness Center Director Arturo Bris warned that increasing productivity remained a "fundamental challenge for all countries".
"Simply put, business efficiency requires greater productivity and the competitiveness of countries is greatly linked to the ability of enterprises to remain profitable over time," he said.
And he said that long-term business profitability and productivity are notoriously difficult to achieve.
One country to be added to the competitiveness ranking for the first time, however, was Mongolia - which had 11.6 per cent GDP growth in 2013.
Hunters, Altantsogts province, Mongolia: Only 400 members of the Kazakh tribe still hunt with golden eagles on the Mongolian steppes. The birds are given to the tribe members at puberty. This image cost Nelson the skin off his hand when it froze to his bulky plate camera in the sub-zero conditions (Jimmy Nelson)
Growth, in this case, is driven by mining and natural resources, domestic consumption growth, levels of employment, an education system that promotes talent, and a favorable fiscal environment.
The IMD World Competitiveness Yearbook measures how well countries manage all their resources and competencies to facilitate long-term value creation.
The overall ranking reflects more than 300 criteria, two-thirds of which are based on statistical indicators, and one-third on an exclusive survey of 6,234 international executives.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Michel Platini will consider pulling England and other Uefa members out of the World Cup if Sepp Blatter wins Fifa president election</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46b8f562/sc/13/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Csport0Cfootball0Clive0Cmichel0Eplatini0Ewill0Econsider0Epulling0Eengland0Eand0Eother0Euefa0Emembers0Eout0Eof0Ethe0Eworld0Ecup0Eif0Esepp0Eblatter0Ewins0Efifa0Epresident0Eelection0E10A2819230Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Michel Platini will consider pulling England and other Uefa members out of the World Cup if Sepp Blatter wins Fifa president election
Fifa is currently in a crisis after 14 current and former members were arrested on corruption charges
Jack de Menezes
Jack de Menezes
Jack de Menezes is a digital sport reporter for The Independent, specialising in football, rugby union and motor racing.
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Michel Platini has said that Uefa will reconsider its relationship with Fifa if Sepp Blatter retains the presidency - in a move which could see England being pulled from the next World Cup.
Mr Platini was speaking at a news conference to confirm that footballs European governing body has given its support to Blatters presidency rival, Prince Ali bin al-Hussein, ahead of the disgraced organisation's leadership vote on Friday.
The Uefa chief also revealed that he had asked Mr Blatter to resign as a friend, but that the under-fire Fifa head had refused to quit.
So many scandals have shaken Fifa, Mr Platini told the press conference. Fifa does not deserve to be treated like this.
"I have had enough - enough is enough, too much is too much. I am the first to be disgusted.
"I told Mr Blatter 'we started together and now I am asking you to step down as we cannot continue this way'.
"He told me 'it's too late, I can't today all of sudden leave when Congress starts this afternoon'."
It means that Mr Platini could consider pulling out the 54 Uefa members  which includes England  from the World Cup should Mr Blatter win tomorrows vote.
When pushed further on the prospect of England and the other 53 members that fall under Uefa's confederation, Mr Platini said: "There may be proposals. I honestly don't wish that."
The Fifa bigwigs facing charges

The 59-year-old Frenchman also said that Mr Blatter "was affected when I spoke to him, because I spoke to him like a friend".
Mr Platini added: "If Mr Blatter wins, Uefa will meet in Berlin to discuss the future of our relations with Fifa. A very, very big majority of Uefa associations will vote for Prince Ali - a minimum of 45 or 46 [out of 53], and I try to convince more.
Platini has told Blatter face-to-face that he must quit Fifa Mr Platini also stressed that should Mr Blatter win a fifth term as Fifa's president, it will demonstrate a worrying state of affairs where Mr Blatter still holds a majority stranglehold over the globe's football officials.
"If he has decided to stay on, it means he is still strong," he said.
"But there's a renewal of democracy in the African zone to vote freely. As I said to Europe, vote freely - but vote for Prince Ali."
Read more:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Playboy model April Summers speaks out about becoming a victim of a voyeuristic sex crime</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bcf149/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Ccrime0Cplayboy0Emodel0Eapril0Esummers0Espeaks0Eout0Eabout0Ebecoming0Ea0Evictim0Eof0Ea0Evoyeuristic0Esex0Ecrime0E10A2830A990Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; UK &gt; Crime
Playboy model April Summers speaks out about becoming a victim of a voyeuristic sex crime
Summers was tricked into posing for a fake photo shoot, and was filmed taking part in a sex act
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A model has bravely spoken out about being secretly filmed taking part in a sex act in an attempt to protect young models from the same fate.
April Summers met voyeur Naushad Faruk at a party in 2011 where he was filming for a PR company. Farul then built up Summers trust by putting her in contact with valuable members of the modelling industry.
Waiving her lifelong right to anonymity as a victim of a sex crime, Summers has described how Faruk became obsessive, and invited her to take part in what would later transpire to be a fake shoot for the now-closed Loaded mens magazine.
Faruk manipulated Summers into stripping for the bogus spread, and secretly filmed her with a camera hidden in his watch as she took part in a sex act.
When Summers called her contact at the magazine to check they were happy with the results, she realised Faruk had duped her.
Faruk then threatened Summers by sending a clip of the explicit video to her on Facebook alongside the message: 'TBC [To be continued].
What happens next to up to you.
Read more: A law introduced to protect women is already being used to prosecute one
Summers contacted the police, and officers discovered the footage on Faruks computer.
She told the Mail Online that the shoot caused her to lose trust in others and she became so "terrified" of leaving the house that she had to take medication to cope.
Writing on Facebook, Miss Summers told her followers: I just want to take the time to say first thank you to all my fans who have supported me and for your kind messages regarding the story about me in the News today.
It is a sensitive subject and was difficult for me to finally speak out. I am glad I have finally spoken out and can help and warn other young models starting out in this industry.
It is a sensitive subject but I am happy to be able.to speak out and warn other models if the creeps in my industry pic.twitter.com/hH8pUaes6I
 April Summers (@april_summerz) May 28, 2015
Faruk was convicted of three counts of voyeurism and two of perverting the course of justice, and handed a 42 month jail sentence, and issued with a 12-year restraining order against Miss Summers and another woman.
Investigating officer, Detective Constable Rob Jones, told the Ham and High : This case shows that if someone threatens to release 'revenge porn' into the public domain they will be dealt with robustly, not only by the police but also by the courts as is demonstrated by this sentence.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:31:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smoking parents plunging nearly half a million children into poverty, says new research</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd682b/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Clife0Estyle0Chealth0Eand0Efamilies0Chealth0Enews0Csmoking0Eparents0Eplunging0Enearly0Ehalf0Ea0Emillion0Echildren0Einto0Epoverty0Esays0Enew0Eresearch0E10A2824320Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Life &gt; Health &amp; Families &gt; Health News
Smoking parents plunging nearly half a million children into poverty, says new research
The new findings come as the UKs latest tobacco control measures face a High Court challenge from the worlds tobacco giants
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Parents who smoke are plunging nearly half a million children into poverty, according to new research.
Around half of the 2.3 million children living in relative poverty in the UK have a parent who smokes, the analysis by the University of Nottingham found.
However, a further 400,000 would be classified as being in poverty if their parents weekly expenditure on tobacco was subtracted from family income.
In households where both parents are smokers, average weekly spend on smoking would be 50, the study, published in the journal BMC Public Health, estimates.
Dr Tessa Langley, at Nottinghams UK Centre for Tobacco and Alcohol Studies, said that smoking cut income available to feed, clothe and care for children.
This study demonstrates that if our government, and our health services, prioritised treating smoking dependence, it could have a major effect on child poverty as well as health she said.
A separate study, from the University of Edinburgh, reveals that the 2007 ban on smoking in public places led to fall in the number of children in England admitted to hospital with respiratory infections.
The biggest falls were seen in the number of chest infections, which fell by 14 per cent almost immediately. The researchers estimate that between 2007 and 2012, the measures have been responsible for preventing 11,000 admissions a year.
UK smoking ban applies in prisons, court rules
The new findings come as the UKs latest tobacco control measures  the introduction of plain packaging, scheduled for roll-out by 2017  face a High Court challenge from the worlds tobacco giants.
This week Japan Tobacco International (JTI), the worlds third biggest tobacco company, joined Philip Morris International and British American Tobacco in filing a lawsuit against the Government.
JTIs suit claims that the move, which would see all tobacco products sold in standardised packs, runs counter to the UKs World Trade Organisation obligations.
people
News
health
News
filmReview: In the face of all-round devastation, even Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson appears a little puny
News
footballPaul Scholes on the best players, managers and goals of the season - and the biggest disappointments
News
voices
Life and Style
Autistic adults could take pure MDMA to 'reduce social anxiety'
2
Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:31:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Most processed 'fruit' snacks contain more sugar than bag of Haribo sweets, say campaigners</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd6829/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Clife0Estyle0Chealth0Eand0Efamilies0Chealth0Enews0Cmost0Eprocessed0Efruit0Esnacks0Econtain0Emore0Esugar0Ethan0Ebag0Eof0Eharibo0Esweets0Esay0Ecampaigners0E10A2826870Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Life &gt; Health &amp; Families &gt; Health News
Most processed 'fruit' snacks contain more sugar than bag of Haribo sweets, say campaigners
Researchers from Action on Sugar said that 80 out of 94 products surveyed contain more than 47g sugar per 100g
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
The vast majority of processed fruit snacks contain higher concentrations of sugar than a bag of Haribo, health campaigners have claimed.
Researchers from Action on Sugar said that 80 out of 94 products surveyed contain more than 47g sugar per 100g, with some containing up to four teaspoons of sugar.
They said that highlighting the fact these products contained fruit, despite having high levels of added sugar, was misleading parents into believing that they were buying a healthy option.
Processed fruit snacks sold by Tesco, ASDA, Aldi and Sainsburys were all found to have high concentrations of sugar.
Tescos Yogurt Coated Strawberry Fruit Bites for example, contain 17.5g, or 4.4 teaspoons of sugar, in each 25g bag  the equivalent of 70g/100g. A bag of Haribo Starmix contains 47g of sugar per 100g.
Action on Sugar is lobbying the Government and the food industry to improve diets and protect the nations health by cutting the amount of sugar in food. Tesco recently became the first supermarket to commit to what the group called a major sugar reduction programme, pledging to remove added sugar from drinks in their Kids range.
'Personalised' cancer vaccine moves a step closer
Graham McGregor, professor of cardiovascular medicine at Queen Mary University and chairman of Action on Sugar, that the food industry, by taking something as natural as fruit and running it by adding sugar was the cause of a pandemic of obesity and type 2 diabetes.
The new Conservative government has a tremendous opportunity to take control of public health and reduce the huge burden on the NHS, he said.
A Tesco spokesperson said: We have a wide range of low-sugar, healthy snack options available at Tesco. Our products are clearly labelled with calorie, salt, sugar and fat content so our customers are equipped with the right information to make a choice about what to buy.
people
News
health
News
filmReview: In the face of all-round devastation, even Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson appears a little puny
News
footballPaul Scholes on the best players, managers and goals of the season - and the biggest disappointments
News
voices
Life and Style
Autistic adults could take pure MDMA to 'reduce social anxiety'
2
Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:31:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Labour leadership candidate Andy Burnham says the party got it 'wrong on business' under Ed Miliband</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/46bd6827/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Clabour0Eleadership0Ecandidate0Eandy0Eburnham0Esays0Ethe0Eparty0Egot0Eit0Ewrong0Eon0Ebusiness0Eunder0Eed0Emiliband0E10A28280A50Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; UK &gt; UK Politics
Labour leadership candidate Andy Burnham says the party got it 'wrong on business' under Ed Miliband
Mr Burnham will use a speech to business leaders to say Labour should 'value the entrepreneur as much as the nurse'
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Andy Burnham will pivot his campaign for the Labour leadership towards the right, admitting that the party got it wrong on business under Ed Miliband.
In a marked change of tone from his leadership campaign of 2010 when he claimed he was never relaxed about people getting extremely rich Mr Burnham will use a speech to business leaders to say Labour should value the entrepreneur as much as the nurse.
He is expected to add that, under Mr Miliband, the party didnt say enough about the role that business played in creating jobs and wealth.
I want this message to go out loud and clear, he will say. Labour must always champion wealth creation, and show we understand that, if we want high-skill, high-wage jobs, we have to support businesses that create them.
Some in the party suggest Mr Burnhams speech is an attempt to move him towards the centre and avoid accusations he is the unions candidate. A Labour MP, who is backing Mr Burnham, told the website Labour Uncut that he needed to broaden his appeal or risk being outflanked by Liz Kendall and Yvette Cooper.
Burnham urges Pope Francis to back same-sex marriage
Andy is being defined as the left-wing choice, he needs to balance out his support, they said.
In his speech Mr Burnham is also expected to say that Labour had not been clear enough in explaining how it would reduce the deficit.
people
News
health
News
ebookA unique anthology of reporting and analysis of a crucial period of history
Life and Style
filmReview: In the face of all-round devastation, even Dwayne 'The Rock' Johnson appears a little puny
News
footballPaul Scholes on the best players, managers and goals of the season - and the biggest disappointments
News
voices
Life and Style
Autistic adults could take pure MDMA to 'reduce social anxiety'
2
Go
The 161-page dossier that exposes Fifa's dark heart
How did a group of corrupt officials turn footballs governing body into what was, in essence, a criminal enterprise? Chris Green and David Connett reveal all
Exclusive interview with Tripoli PM Khalifa al-Ghweil
'If Europe thinks bombing boats will stop smuggling, it will not. We will defend ourselves'
Raymond Chandler's Los Angeles
How the author foretold the Californian water crisis
Art attack
Chinese artist who posted funny image of President Xi Jinping facing five years in prison
Cher is the new face of Marc Jacobs
Alexander Fury explains why designers are turning to august stars to front their lines
'I'm climbing Ben Nevis for my daughter'
Karen Attwood's young daughter Yasmin beat cancer. Now her family is about to take on a new challenge - scaling Ben Nevis to help other children
It's that time of year again... 10 best wedding gift ideas
Forget that fancy toaster, we've gone off-list to find memorable gifts that will last a lifetime
Paul Scholes column
With the Premier League over for another year, here are my end of season awards
Liverpool have seen too much tragedy to forget Heysel
Thirty years ago, 39 fans waiting to watch a European Cup final died as a result of a fatal cocktail of circumstances. Ian Herbert looks at how a club dealt with this tragedy
Khans audition for Mayweather may turn into a no-win situation
The Bolton fighter could be damned if he dazzles and damned if he doesnt against Algieri, the man last seen being decked six times by Pacquiao, says Frank Warren
Blundering Blair quits as Middle East peace envoy  only Israel will miss him
For Arabs  and for Britons who lost their loved ones in his shambolic war in Iraq  his appointment was an insult, says Robert Fisk
Fifa corruption arrests
All hail the Feds for riding to football's rescue, says Ian Herbert
The Kurdish enclave still resisting the tyranny of Assad and Isis
In Syrian Kurdish cantons along the Turkish border, the progressive aims of the 2011 uprising are being enacted despite the war. Patrick Cockburn returns to Amuda
How I survived Cambodia's Killing Fields
Acclaimed surgeon SreyRam Kuy celebrates her mother's determination to escape to the US
How Stephen Mangan got his range
Posh buffoon, hapless writer, pregnant dad - Mangan is certainly a versatile actor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
