<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Independent">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:48:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jimmy Savile: Publication into TV presenter's abuse over decades at BBC postponed</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45eb0cc7/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Ccrime0Cjimmy0Esavile0Epublication0Einto0Etv0Epresenters0Eabuse0Eover0Edecades0Eat0Ebbc0Epostponed0E10A2188130Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:33:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police seek men after couple pushed on to tracks in 'appalling' attack at London station</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45eb0bcc/sc/33/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Chome0Enews0Cpolice0Eseek0Emen0Eafter0Ecouple0Epushed0Eon0Eto0Etracks0Ein0Eappalling0Eattack0Eat0Elondon0Estation0E10A2187640Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Police seek men after couple pushed on to tracks in 'appalling' attack at London station
The incident occurred at Turkey Street Station in Enfield
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Police want to speak to two men after a young couple were assaulted and pushed on to the tracks at a London railway station.
The incident occurred at Turkey Street station in Enfield, north London on 2 April and photos of the men police wish to speak to have now been released.
A man in his twenties was with his girlfriend, who was boarding a train for central London, when two men got off the same train and assaulted the young man.
In an attempt to help her boyfriend, the woman, also in her twenties, got off the train but was then attacked as well.
When the train pulled out of the station the couple were pushed on to the tracks.
The attackers then took the womans phone and fled the scene. During the attack the womans wrist was broken and the man sustained a broken nose.
Detective Sergeant Karina Ghersinich said: This was an appalling attack of the kind which is thankfully extremely rare on the rail network.
It is absolutely vital we find those responsible. As part of our investigation we have spoken to people at the station and the surrounding area.
We have also analysed CCTV, and I think the men in the image we are issuing today can help with our enquiries. Please tell us who they are.
Anyone with information is asked to contact British Transport Police.
food + drinkThere are surprises in the list
Life and Style
ebooksA special investigation by Andy McSmith
Arts and Entertainment
newsIt is terrible at guessing how old celebrities are, too
Life and Style
What happens to your body when you give up sugar?
2
We are offering one lucky reader the chance to win a seven night self-catering holiday for two. What are you waiting for? Enter now.

Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:33:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK bank holiday weather: Rain, sunshine, gale force winds of 60mph and temperatures of 19C make for an unsettled weekend</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45eb0bcb/sc/26/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Chome0Enews0Cuk0Ebank0Eholiday0Eweather0Erain0Esunshine0Egale0Eforce0Ewinds0Eof0E60Amph0Eand0Etemperatures0Eof0E19c0Emake0Efor0Ean0Eunsettled0Eweekend0E10A2186890Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Remember to take your umbrella out on any bank holiday excursions this weekend as May Day celebrations are set to be hit by a mixed bag of rain, sunshine and gale force winds.
To add to the confusion, the UK's weather will once again be split by a north-south divide. Temperatures are expected to hit highs of 13C today and up to 19C in London on Sunday on Monday.
Meanwhile, some areas in Scotland will not get above 7C today and parts of northern England, such as Newcastle and Scarborough, will struggle to hit 9C.
However, the temperatures in the north are set to creep up to 13C on Sunday and between 15C and 16C on Monday.
A spokesperson for the Met Office said: Today is looking pretty good. There is a bit of cloud and some showers dotted in Scotland over Aberdeenshire and the Highlands but generally some good sunshine around, particularly in eastern parts.
Weather in Britain: Stunning images show off beauty of British landscape
The south-west will be a bit wet and Cornwall in particular will experience the tail end of showers but this will clear up later."
Forecasters predict Saturday morning will be a good, dry start apart from in Scotland, where the weather will be much cloudier. East Anglia and south-east England and Scotland wont see any rainfall until overnight on Saturday.
Saturday will average at about 10C across northern England, while Sunday and Monday in the north is looking at between 12C to 14C in Glasgow, and up to 15C on Monday," the spokesperson said.
On Sunday, there will be gale force winds of up to 60mph to the north-west coast of Scotland and wet weather in Scotland, northern England and Northern Ireland, while the rest of the country will be quite dry, apart from some thundery showers in the Midlands.
Sunday is ok for most parts and begins with warmer temperatures. Monday is not looking too bad either. In some areas it could be quite mild with most places seeing some dry weather with some risk of showers along the south coast towards Monday afternoon.
All in all, its very spring-like weather.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:29:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Old Do I Look: Microsoft’s super advanced age-guessing app is terrible at guessing how old celebrities are, too</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45eb0bc9/sc/15/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Clife0Estyle0Cgadgets0Eand0Etech0Cnews0Chow0Eold0Edo0Ei0Elook0Emicrosofts0Esuper0Eadvanced0Eageguessing0Eapp0Eis0Eterrible0Eat0Eguessing0Ehow0Eold0Ecelebrities0Eare0Etoo0E10A2186830Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Age might be just a number, but when that number is generated by a supposedly highly-intelligent algorithm it can cause more than a few hurt feelings. But the machine also thinks that the 18-year-old Lorde is actually 31, and that its 59-year-old father, Bill Gates, is 77.
Many have worried that the app, which can be found at how-old.net , has suggested that they look much older than they are. But so does everyone, it seems  apart from those lucky souls like Madonna, who is identified as less than half her actual age.
Madonna seems to have done best out of the app, which identified pictures of her as somewhere between 27 and 31. In actual fact, shes 56.
Kanye West, who Madonna described as the "black Madonna", does at least to have picked up whatever magic allows the singer to fool the computer. He's identified as 32, despite being 37.
Kanye's colleague, Jay Z, does much less well out of the app. But it only identifies him as one year older than his 45 years.
But whatever trick American celebrities have found doesn't seem to have worked for much less glamorous British celebrities.
The Greens' Natalie Bennett is 76, according to the app. But she's not: she's 49.
And the tool shows no affiliation in those that it says are much older than they are. It reckons Nigel Farage is 66  but it's actually been 51 years since he arrived on the planet.
(The lesson, perhaps, is to avoid the stresses and strains of becoming a British politician and instead aim for stardom. At least, if you want to fool the How Old Do I Look app.)
Microsoft has said that the app is still in development, and that it is continuing to learn as it is being used. But some have suggested that the apps ages might be almost random and all those insulted people and celebrities might be part of a huge, terrifying experiment by Microsoft.
Imagine if you hooked up a face detector to a random number generator and then it went viral.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:25:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Giant sinkhole swallows seven homes in Ukraine leaving villagers terrified</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea342e/sc/11/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Ceurope0Cgiant0Esinkhole0Eswallows0Eseven0Ehomes0Ein0Eukraine0Eleaving0Evillagers0Eterrified0E10A218440A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Giant sinkhole swallows seven homes in Ukraine leaving villagers terrified
The sinkhole was understood to have been caused by the collapse of an abandoned salt mine.
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A gigantic sinkhole in western Ukraine has left villagers terrified after it reportedly swallowed seven houses.
The sinkhole, measuring 100m wide and 60m deep, suddenly opened up in the village of Solotvino in the Zakarpatska Oblast region of western Ukraine.
Villagers say that it formed in just one day.

Sinkholes in the region are caused by 220-year-old salt mines abandoned and left to collect water underground.
The collected water dissolves underground rock formations and leaves huge caverns when it eventually drains away.
The empty cavern eventually collapses under the weight of tonnes of earth, causing vast sinkholes like this one.
Watch: Sinkhole in South Korea swallows two people whole
These cause what is known as a Karst landscape , a landscape formed from the dissolution of soluble rock.
Villagers have called on the Ukrainian government to either do something to stop the sinkhole from getting even bigger or else to relocate them to a safer location.
Ivan Prokop, 53, said, "the holes are getting closer to other houses all the time.
"At first, we thought it might just be one hole and it would stop, but it's clear the entire region will eventually sink."
Last year, six people died after their car fell into a huge sinkhole in the middle of the motorway, located near the Crimean capital Simferopol.
food + drinkThere are surprises in the list
Life and Style
ebooksA special investigation by Andy McSmith
Arts and Entertainment
newsIt is terrible at guessing how old celebrities are, too
Life and Style
What happens to your body when you give up sugar?
2
We are offering one lucky reader the chance to win a seven night self-catering holiday for two. What are you waiting for? Enter now.

Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:22:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This video of Britain's politicians lip-syncing to 'Let's Get It On' is just disturbing</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea342b/sc/6/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Cgeneralelection0Cthis0Evideo0Eof0Ebritains0Epoliticians0Elipsyncing0Eto0Elets0Eget0Eit0Eon0Eis0Ejust0Edisturbing0E10A2186860Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:17:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Investors take £1 billion out of UK markets ahead of general election</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea3428/sc/28/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Cinvestors0Etake0E10Ebillion0Eout0Eof0Euk0Emarkets0Eahead0Eof0Egeneral0Eelection0E10A2187130Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Investors take 1 billion out of UK markets ahead of general election
Most of the cash pumped into Europe where equity funds hit highest level in 18 months
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Investors have taken a record 1 billion out of funds linked to the UK stock exchange in March 2015 in what experts believe to be a sign of stress about the upcoming general election.
European funds benefitted from the UK scare, topping a previous record to hit 663 million in sales, according to monthly data releases by The Investment Association.
Tracker funds, which use a passive investment strategy to mirror the moves in the stock market, also did well, with net retail sales of 938 billion.
Business news in pictures
It seems the election is to blame for the outpouring of cash from UK funds. In the same period last year the same income funds 542 million in investment.
Private investors are staging a buyer's strike in the lead-up to the election, said Laith Khalaf, senior analyst at Hargreaves Lansdown.
This is pretty par for the course when it comes to the uncertainty generated by such a big political event, and the FTSE 100 index reaching a record high won't have helped matters.
European equity funds are buoyed by the introduction of quantitative easing, which means more money being pumped into the economy to be used in investments.
We saw retail investors switching record amounts out of UK equity funds and into European equity funds, developing a trend seen over the previous couple of months, said Daniel Godfrey, The Investment Association chief executive.
food + drinkThere are surprises in the list
Life and Style
tech
Arts and Entertainment
newsIt is terrible at guessing how old celebrities are, too
Life and Style
ebooksA special investigation by Andy McSmith
News
What happens to your body when you give up sugar?
2
We are offering one lucky reader the chance to win a seven night self-catering holiday for two. What are you waiting for? Enter now.

Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:56:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The foods with high amounts of hidden sugar</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea3427/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Clife0Estyle0Cfood0Eand0Edrink0Cthe0Efoods0Ewith0Ehigh0Eamounts0Eof0Ehidden0Esugar0E10A2182530Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Life &gt; Food and Drink
The foods with high amounts of hidden sugar
We know chocolate and fizzy drinks are bad for our teeth - but there are plenty of other foods which we might not realise are full of sugar
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
With the ease of cheap ready meals and rise of binge drinking culture, it is no surprise that the younger generation are consuming more sugar than ever.
As a guide, it is recommended that women should not consume more than 25 grams of added sugar per day and mens intake is not recommended to exceed 36 grams. Added sugarsare present in processed or prepared foods and natural sugars are those that occur naturally, such as the sugars present in milk and fruits.
No matter what age you are, you must become aware of the hidden added sugar in every day foods to avoid restorative dental work and maintain good oral health. If you are going to be consuming sugary foods, it is best to eat them after meals rather than snacking and grazing all day as this will limit the contact that your teeth has with sugar so your teeth are not under constant attack.
It comes as no surprise that chocolate, fizzy drinks and sweet treats are full of added sugar and bad for our teeth. However, there are other surprising culprits that we might not associate with being a cause for concern. Every time you eat or drink anything sugary, the sugar reacts with the plaque in your mouth which in turn produces harmful acids that can damage our teeth. Although it may not be immediately obvious, there are certain products to look out for that can contribute to dental decay.
Here are some of the worst offenders for hidden sugar:
Salad Dressing
Getting your greens is essential for diet and nutrition but be wary of the salad dressings that you are using. Sweet French dressings and vinaigrette can have up to 7 grams of sugar in one serving and with oil-based dressings claiming to be low in fat, that is often because they have been pumped full of sugar to compensate and enhance the flavour. Look out for ingredients such as dextrose, honey, glucose and maltose which are essentially variations on sugar and can be equally detrimental to our oral health.
For a lower-sugar option opt for a light homemade vinegar and olive oil dressing. Full fat mayonnaise also tends to contain less sugar than a reduced fat option and given that it is made from dairy, the calcium rich contents helps to keep teeth healthy and stop you from developing gum disease.
Soups and Sauces
Although they taste savoury not sweet, many pasta sauces have between 6 and 12 grams of sugar per serving  the same amount as a slice of cake! Look at the traffic light system that many supermarkets put on the front of their products to indicate sugar, salt and fat content.
Vegetable soups and pasta sauces high in tomatoes can also be acidic and lead to enamel erosion and dental decay when consumed regularly. I recommend rinsing your mouth with water after consumption to limit the damage to your teeth.
Breakfast smoothies
Fruits natural sugar, fructose, is a common cause of cavities as the bacteria in the mouth feeds on it. Fruit and vegetable juices also tend to be extremely acidic and the high acid content can severely damage the enamel of your teeth in a similar way to fizzy drinks. Although fruit and vegetables are considered healthy acids, this is only the case when they are consumed as a whole, rather than as a concentrated juice.
Adding milk, which is alkaline, to your smoothies can help to counteract the acid damage to teeth and its calcium rich properties can boost your oral health and strengthen teeth. Drinking through a straw is also advisable.
Breakfast Bars and Yoghurts
Although they might make for a quick breakfast option in the morning, many processed foods contain a lot of sugar. The higher up it appears in the list of ingredients, the more sugar there is in the product. Plain yoghurt contains naturally occurring sugars but often the fruity, highly flavoured yoghurts add lots of sugar to enhance and sweeten the flavour. Energy and granola bars can also be very deceptive and despite branding stating how healthy they are, experts have warned that these bars often contain as much sugar as a chocolate bar.
I advise my patients to eat unsweetened Greek yoghurt for a more tooth-friendly option and if you want to add a little extra flavour, opt for unsweetened muesli.
Bread
Surprisingly, many supermarket sandwiches have added sugar to sweeten the bitter taste and research has shown that in some brands, a slice of white or wholemeal bread can contain up to half a teaspoon of sugar. Experts advise that six teaspoons of sugar each day should be the maximum.
Bread also takes on a gummy consistency when chewed that can allow small particles to get trapped between teeth and make them extremely tough to budge. To get rid of stuck particles, flossing as part of your oral hygiene routing is vital.
Alcohol
The excessive amount of sugar that is present in alcoholic drinks is often overlooked as it is so easy to have a few too many on a Friday night, but not only is this damaging our liver, it is detrimental to the deterioration of our oral health. In just one pint of cider there can be up to 20g of sugar and in rich spirits such as sherry there can be up to 20 grams in a double measure.
The large amount of sugar in alcohol erodes your tooth enamel and can lead to tooth decay. The sugar content in alcohol which, when broken down in your mouth, creates an acidic breeding ground for bacteria and plaque.
To help minimise the damage caused by sugar when drinking alcohol, I recommend opting for wine, champagne or bottled beer as a serving of these drinks contain around 2 grams of sugar which is definitely safer for your teeth. It is a good idea to alternate alcoholic drinks with a glass of water to rinse, this will help minimise the damage caused by sugar.
Read more:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:52:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>100 million-year-old insect discovered perfectly preserved</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5961/sc/32/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cscience0C10A0A0Emillionyearold0Einsect0Ediscovered0Eperfectly0Epreserved0E10A2186340Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:48:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kendall Jenner's face becomes the first ever victim of drone vandalism</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea595f/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cpeople0Ckendall0Ejenners0Eface0Ebecomes0Ethe0Efirst0Eever0Evictim0Eof0Edrone0Evandalism0E10A2186230Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Kendall Jenner's face becomes the first ever victim of drone vandalism
The vandalism was the work of street artist Katsu
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Kendall Jenner possesses one of the most coveted faces in the fashion industry, fronting campaigns from Givenchy to Balmain in 2015.
Its also just scored an unusual world record, as the first official victim of drone vandalism.
Jenners Calvin Klein campaign is currently on one of the biggest billboards in New York City, but on Wednesday morning a scrawl of red lines appeared across her visage as a hacked drone made free and easy with some spray paint.
The vandalism was actually the work of street artist Katsu, who has since released a video of said incident in action:
It turned out surprisingly well, he told Wired of the unusual piece. It's exciting to see its first potential use as a device for vandalism.
Seventy per cent of the concentration is in maintaining this equilibrium with the two dimensional surface while you are painting, he added of the tense process that took less than a minute to achieve.
The most amazing drone pictures of 2014

It's a bit frightening, he added of the ease in which he illegally tagged her face using the equipment.
ebooksA special investigation by Andy McSmith
News
What happens to your body when you give up sugar?
2
We are offering one lucky reader the chance to win a seven night self-catering holiday for two. What are you waiting for? Enter now.

Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:36:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore riots: How the Western media would cover the unrest if it happened elsewhere</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5956/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Camericas0Cbaltimore0Eriots0Ehow0Ethe0Ewestern0Emedia0Ewould0Ecover0Ethe0Eunrest0Eif0Eit0Ehappened0Eelsewhere0E10A2185810Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
If what is happening in Baltimore happened in a foreign country, here is how Western media would cover it:
International leaders expressed concern over the rising tide of racism and state violence in America, especially concerning the treatment of ethnic minorities in the country and the corruption in state security forces around the country when handling cases of police brutality. The latest crisis is taking place in Baltimore, Maryland, a once-bustling city on the countrys Eastern Seaboard, where an unarmed man named Freddie Gray died from a severed spine while in police custody.
Black Americans, a minority ethnic group, are killed by state security forces at a rate higher than the white majority population. Young, black American males are 21 times more likely to be shot by police than white American males.
Baltimore riots: In pictures

The United Kingdom expressed concern over the troubling turn of events in America in the last several months. The countrys foreign ministry released a statement: We call on the American regime to rein in the state security agents who have been brutalizing members of Americas ethnic minority groups. The equal application of the rule of law, as well as the respect for human rights of all citizens, black or white, is essential for a healthy democracy. Britain has always maintained a keen interest in America, a former colony.
Palestine has offered continued assistance to American pro-democracy activists, sending anti-tear-gas kits to those protesting police brutality in various American cities. Egyptian pro-democracy groups have also said they will be sharing their past experience with U.S.-made counter-protest weapons.
Peaceful protesters in Baltimore (AP)
A statement from the United Nations said, We condemn the militarization and police brutality that we have seen in recent months in America, and we strongly urge American state security forces to launch a full investigation into the death of Freddie Gray in Baltimore. There is no excuse for excessive police violence. The U.N. called on the United States to make a concerted effort to make databases of police violence public to improve transparency and cut down on corruption in the justice system.
International analysts predict the seeds of a so-called American Spring, fomented by technology. Its amazing what social media is doing for the cause of justice in America, said a political rights analyst based in Geneva. The black youth of America are showing what 21st-century civil rights activism looks like, using technology, social media and a decentralized organizing strategy to hold authorities accountable and agitate for change. These kids represent what modern-day freedom fighting looks like. The revolution will be tweeted, Periscope-d and Snapchatted.
Local leaders in the American township of Baltimore imposed a state of martial law this week after peaceful protests turned violent. In response, countries around the world have advised darker-skinned nationals against non-essential travel to areas noted for state violence against unarmed people of color, especially in recent hot spots such as New York, Missouri, Oklahoma, South Carolina, Ohio, California, Michigan, Virginia and now Maryland.
(Getty Images)
International human rights groups have appealed to the global community to facilitate asylum for Americas ethnic black minorities. When asked whether the European Union was willing to take on more black refugees risking their lives in fleeing American state violence, an E.U. human rights spokesman said: More black refugees? We are dealing with our own Mediterranean crisis, so now is not really a good time for that for us. Furthermore, we believe in American solutions to American problems. The African Union has not responded to requests for comment.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:22:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man convicted of raping one-day-old baby</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5677/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Ccrime0Cman0Econvicted0Eof0Eraping0Eonedayold0Ebaby0E10A2184220Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:17:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Funeral for unnamed baby: Hundreds gather to mourn for anonymous infant found on Edinburgh railway path</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5674/sc/19/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Chome0Enews0Cfuneral0Efor0Eunnamed0Ebaby0Ehundreds0Egather0Eto0Emourn0Efor0Eanonymous0Einfant0Efound0Eon0Eedinburgh0Erailway0Epath0E10A2184290Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Hundreds of mourners have turned out to pay their respects to a precious baby boy they never knew and whose name remains unknown.
The remains of the child, who would have been almost two today, were found wrapped in a blanket on an old railway path in the Seafield area of Edinburgh in July 2013.
Despite a major investigation and extensive efforts to find the boy's mother and wider family, they have never been traced and his identity remains a mystery.
The youngster was finally laid to rest following a funeral service in the sunshine at the city's Seafield Cemetery, close to the area where he was discovered.
Flowers and tributes at the graveside after the funeral of an unidentified baby boy at Seafield Cemetery, Edinburgh More than 200 mourners gathered to say goodbye to the wee one who may have been up to six weeks old when he died.
Leading the service, Reverend Erica Wishart, of Tranent Parish Church, told mourners: This is the kind of tragedy that surely touches everyone who hears about it. All of us who gather here today are grieving.
We represent everyone in this community and beyond who feels deep sadness that this tiny baby is never going to have the chance to grow up and live his life.
With birdsong audible in the background, Rev Wishart said those gathered may feel "anger and shock" at what had happened, or perhaps a whole range of emotions.
"We are here to say goodbye to this wee one, with the dignity and respect he deserves. We are here to mourn the life that could have been. And we are here to affirm that every life is precious in God's eyes," she said.
"This baby boy may not have been given a name - we may not know where he came from or who gave birth to him - but the Bible tells us that God knew him even before he was born and his whole being - body, soul and spirit - is engraved on the palm of God's hand."
A number of mourners were visibly tearful as the boy's tiny white coffin was lowered into the ground and as a lone piper played.
Members of the public gather round the graveside
The funeral for the boy was arranged by Police Scotland and a number of local community volunteers offered their services.
Cameron McKay, 21, of Cousland, Midlothian, volunteered to play the pipes at the funeral.
Afterwards, he praised the "fantastic" turnout.
"It was quite emotional, really sad actually. Although it was a great turnout, it was quite sad to see all the people."
Margaret Halliday, who works with the support group Angel Wings, which makes burial clothes for babies, was also among the mourners. She made a burial "pocket of love" for the boy.
She said: "I think the turnout is absolutely incredible. It's very moving to think that there are so many people here today just to give this baby some love.
"The poor wee boy, I don't know what his mum must be going through today, it must be horrendous for her. No matter what the circumstances, I just feel for his mum as well."
Onlooker Carol Lind said: "He won't be forgotten about by the Leith community, the Lochend community.
"I'm sure he'll always be remembered, especially by me as I have got family here, and I'm sure he will be looked after."
Following the service, numerous tributes in the form of soft toys, flowers and messages were left by mourners at the graveside.
One message read "The people of Leith will be your family", while another said "Rest in God's arms, goodnight little baby."
Members of the public view flowers and tributes at the graveside
Speaking after the service, Rev Wishart said: "Something like this touches everybody's hearts, I think particularly when it's a child or a baby.
"This is a great community, Leith, it's a strong community, and I know that people were very moved when this first happened a couple of years ago.
"(The turnout's) just been fantastic. It's like a wave of compassion from everyone.
"We had people here from every faith, so this has cut across all sections of the community and I think it's wonderful, the support that people have shown today, giving freely of their time and their resources."
Afterwards, police handed out leaflets, saying their investigation is continuing and they are "still looking for the the vital piece of information which would help identify the child and his mother".
Officers can be contacted on 0131 311 5916 or 101, where any information "will be treated in confidence and assessed and acted on accordingly".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:13:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miley Cyrus’ penis flip-flops are the latest addition to fashion’s phallic trend</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5671/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Clife0Estyle0Cfashion0Cfeatures0Cmiley0Ecyrus0Epenis0Eflipflops0Eare0Ethe0Elatest0Eaddition0Eto0Efashions0Ephallic0Etrend0E10A2184780Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:08:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BBC Question Time election debate: Leaders just can't stop talk about sharing 'darkened rooms' with each other</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5348/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Cgeneralelection0Cbbc0Equestion0Etime0Eelection0Edebate0Eleaders0Ejust0Ecant0Estop0Etalk0Eabout0Esharing0Edarkened0Erooms0Ewith0Eeach0Eother0E10A2183320Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
The three leaders all appeared to have one thing on minds during last nights final pre-election debate: darkened rooms.
David Cameron, Nick Clegg and Ed Miliband all made reference to the darkened room that leaders would disappear into to discuss the future government in the event of a hung parliament.
The three leaders appeared on the BBCs Question Time with David Dimbleby in the last debate before the election next week.
All three faced a tough grilling from an unusually antagonistic audience  but instant ICM pollsters found that voters thought Cameron had delivered the best performance of the evening, emerging with a 44 per cent approval rating to Milibands 38 and Cleggs rather sad 19 per cent.
Cameron spoke about giving away some of the things in your programme, while Miliband added that he wasnt in the business of darkened rooms where you were lopping off bits of your manifesto.
Clegg  who remains hopeful he might get into a darkened room with either the Conservatives or the Labour Party  joked: He keeps talking about darkened rooms, Mr Miliband.
The Independent has got together with May2015.com to produce a poll of polls that produces the most up-to-date data in as close to real time as is possible.
Click the buttons below to explore how the main parties' fortunes have changed:
All data, polls and graphics are courtesy of May2015.com . Click through for daily analysis, in-depth features and all the data you need. (All historical data used is provided by UK Polling Report )
I have to say to you if either of them still think theyre going to win a majority they need to both go and lie down in that darkened room.
But in a shocking turn of events Miliband made possibly the best joke of the evening  albeit with a very low bar  telling the audience: This business of going into a darkened room with Nick Clegg, he said.
Now, I dont like the sound of that at all for a whole range of reasons.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:05:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York woman gives up $95,000 a year job to work in an ice cream parlour in the Caribbean</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea5347/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Ctravel0Cnew0Eyork0Ewoman0Egives0Eup0E950A0A0A0Ea0Eyear0Ejob0Eto0Ework0Ein0Ean0Eice0Ecream0Eparlour0Ein0Ethe0Ecaribbean0E10A2183960Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>New York woman gives up $95,000 a year job to work in an ice cream parlour in the Caribbean
Noelle Hancock found herself feeling increasingly alienated by life in the city
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Most of us dream about one day securing a six-figure dream job, not giving it up to work in an ice cream parlour.
But that's exactly what a journalist who found herself feeling increasingly alienated by life in the city did when she abandoned her $95,000 income and moved to a tiny island in the Caribbean.
Noelle Hancock, a Yale graduate, was feeling overwhelmed and isolated by her life in New York.
In an essay for Cosmopolitan , the 35-year-old wrote: New York is a competitive city; you have to spend most of your time working to afford to live there. And a downside of living among so many ambitious people is they're often over scheduled.
Sometimes I didn't see my closest friends for months at a time. Trying to negotiate a time to meet a friend for drinks was harder than getting into college (and the cocktails about as expensive).
Travel agenda - 24/04/2015
Ms Hancock was constantly thinking about her next holiday, describing herself as stressed, uninspired, and disconnected. On impulse, she asked friends where they could recommend visiting in the Caribbean. Six weeks later, she had terminated the lease on her apartment, sold her belongings and was on a one-way flight to St. John, the smallest of the US Virgin Islands.
Four years after leaving New York, she now works as a bartender on the island.
"Living abroad has exposed me to a different approach to life, one in which you're not expected to settle in one place and do one kind of job," she wrote.
"There are no stoplights on St. John. [...] No chain stores. Limited WiFi. Shoes optional.
"There are no addresses. [...] People gather on the beaches at dusk to watch the sunsets together. I see my friends every day. On our days off, we hike the local ruins, dive, or go boating to the nearby British Virgin Islands.
That's not to say doubts don't creep in on occasion. Seeing old colleagues and acquaintances building successful careers can make me second-guess my choices. One of my friends from college started a little website called Pinterest. Another just won an Emmy for a hit television show she created.
But I have an island. I live in a charmingly ramshackle one-bedroom apartment on a hillside overlooking the sea."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:55:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nick Clegg was actually 'keen' to treble tuition fees, former coalition colleague reveals</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea51e4/sc/33/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Cnick0Eclegg0Ewas0Eactually0Ekeen0Eto0Etreble0Etuition0Efees0Eformer0Ecoalition0Ecolleague0Ereveals0E10A2183260Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Nick Clegg was actually 'keen' to treble tuition fees, former coalition colleague reveals
Coalition agreement author accuses the DPM of 'talking crap' about his broken pledge last night
Jon Stone
Jon Stone
Jon Stone is a reporter for independent.co.uk mainly covering politics. He has previously worked for PoliticsHome, BuzzFeed, and others.
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Nick Clegg was actually keen to treble student tuition fees and is talking crap by claiming he did not want to vote for the policy, a former coalition colleague has said.
Last night the Liberal Democrat leader told a Question Time audience that he was between a rock and a hard place on the broken pledge.
In politics, as in life, sometimes you cant do exactly what you want, he argued. I was absolutely between a rock and a hard place five years ago on that particular policy.
But James O'Shaughnessy, David Camerons former director of policy, says he was in the room in 2010 when the policy was being discussed and that Mr Clegg was keen for it to go ahead.
[Nick] Clegg [is] talking crap on tuition fees, he tweeted. He wasn't between 'rock and hard place'. I was in the room when he decided to vote for it. He was keen.
The policy chief said Mr Clegg was in favour of trebling fees because the plan came from a department headed by a Liberal Democrat minister, Vince Cable, and because he simply agreed with the policy.
In pictures - Student protest in central London
The claim is likely to chime with the suspicions of some Liberal Democrat activists. In 2009, before the last election, the Liberal Democrat leadership launched a bid to remove the free education commitment from the partys manifesto.
We have got to treat people like grown-ups, Mr Clegg said at the time. It is a policy which has significant financial implications. None of us know precisely yet what we can afford. The issue is simply on the affordability.
The attempt was defeated in a vote by party members and the policy was ultimately included in the manifesto.
Mr O'Shaughnessy was David Cameron's director of policy from 2007 to 2011; he co-authored the Coalition's programme for government and played a leading role in managing the Coalition's policy programme. He now works for Portland Communications.
Clegg talking crap on tuition fees. He wasn't between 'rock and hard place'. I was in the room when he decided to vote for it. He was keen.
 James O'Shaughnessy (@jamesosh) April 30, 2015
Two reasons Clegg made LDs vote for 9k fees: 1. He thought that, as it came from LD dept (BIS), they should. 2. He agreed with policy.
 James O'Shaughnessy (@jamesosh) April 30, 2015
For clarity: I respect Clegg voting for 9k fees cos it's a good policy. Just wish he'd admit that rather than saying he was strong armed
 James O'Shaughnessy (@jamesosh) April 30, 2015
In 2012 Mr Clegg apologised for breaking his pledge, telling voters in a video message: It was a pledge made with the best of intentions  but we should not have made a promise we were not absolutely sure we could deliver.
The Liberal Democrats went into the election with a manifesto commitment to abolish all tuition fees and restore free education.
All of the partys MPs also signed a separate commitment, organised by the National Union of Students, to individually vote against any increase in the education charges whether they formed a government or not.
Most of the partys MPs ultimately voted to treble tuition fees from 3,000 to 9,000 despite a provision in the 2010 coalition agreement allowing them to abstain on the vote.
The policy is estimated by the Institute for Fiscal Studies to have saved the Treasury no money and may have even cost the taxpayer more than the old fee level because of its upward pressure on inflation-linked spending.
A Liberal Democrat spokespersontold the Independent that the new tuition fees system was fairer than the old system, but did not comment directly on Mr O'Shaughnessy's claims.
We did not win the election, so we could not deliver every policy that we wanted to, especially as we went into government with a party that was determined to raise fees at a time when there's no money," the spokesperson said.
Instead, Nick Clegg and Vince Cable fought to deliver the fairest deal they could, introducing a form of graduate tax where the wealthiest graduates pay more."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:55:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>David Cameron makes another gaffe: 'This election is all about my career... sorry I mean country'</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea51e2/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Cgeneralelection0Cdavid0Ecameron0Emakes0Eanother0Egaffe0Ethis0Eelection0Eis0Eall0Eabout0Emy0Ecareer0Esorry0Ei0Emean0Ecountry0E10A2183410Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Robert Fisk in Abu Dhabi
The Emirates' out-of-sight migrant workers helping to build the dream projects of its rulers
Vince Cable exclusive interview
Charging fees for employment tribunals was 'a very bad move'
Iwan Rheon is returning to his Welsh roots
Rheon is best known for his role as the Bastard of Bolton. It's gruelling playing a sadistic torturer, he tells Craig McLean, but it hasn't stopped him recording an album of Welsh psychedelia
Everyone is talking about The Trews
Russell Brand's 'true news' videos attract millions of viewers. But today's 'Milibrand' interview introduced his resolutely amateurish style to a whole new crowd
It's time for my close-up
Meet the man who films great whites for a living
Homeless people keep mobile phones
A homeless person with a smartphone is a common sight in the US. And that's creating a network where the 'hobo' community can share information - and fight stigma - like never before
'Queer saint' who bankrolled artworld giants
British culture owes a huge debt to Peter Watson, says Michael Prodger
Pushkin Prizes brings countries together
Ten Scottish schoolchildren and their Russian peers attended a creative writing workshop in the Highlands this week
14 best kids' hoodies
Don't get caught out by that wind on the beach. Zip them up in a lightweight top to see them through summer to autumn
Leicester vs Chelsea player ratings
Eden Hazard has quiet night, so who stood out for Chelsea?
Yorkshire's phenomenal tour de force
Sky rider Ben Swift watched the success of last summer's Grand Depart from the sidelines. Now his county has its own race, and he's excited to be taking part
The acceptable face of the Emirates
Has Abu Dhabi found a way to blend petrodollars with principles, asks Robert Fisk
Escape from Everest base camp
Nick Talbot was sitting in his tent when the tsunami of snow and rock hit. He was lucky to live, unlike his climbing partner just feet away...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:49:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alabama rot: Dog owners put on alert over flesh-eating disease</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea2a03/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Chome0Enews0Calabama0Erot0Edog0Eowners0Eput0Eon0Ealert0Eover0Eflesheating0Edisease0E10A2182120Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Vets have issued a fresh warning to dog owners over the danger of Alabama rot , a dangerous disease affecting dogs that can cause ulcer-like sores on the skin and even kidney failure.
The disease was first identified in the USA in the 1980s, where it affected greyhounds. The disease first surfaced in the UK at the end of 2012, and has affected dogs of all breeds, ages and sizes.
Alabama rot has killed at least 30 dogs in England since it arrived in the country. 46 cases have been confirmed since December 2013, and vets still don't know what causes the disease.
Vets4Pets have released an interactive guide for dog owners in an effort to stop infections, which includes information on known locations where the disease has struck, and tips to stop dogs becoming infected.
The majority of the cases in England have occured in the New Forest area of Hampshire. It is thought the disease is picked up on paws during muddy walks. Although the causes are unknown, it is thought that the disease is picked up on dogs' paws during muddy walks - the guide advises dog owners to wash woodland mud off dogs' feet after walks, and to know the warning signs of the disease, which can included tiredness, vomiting, and redness and swelling around the elbow or knee.
Within 2-7 days of contracting the disease, fatal kidney failure can occur. Some dogs have recovered from the disease through intensive veterinary care, but most have not survived.
All confirmed cases of Alabama Rot so far have been limited to England, mostly in the New Forest region of Hampshire - but vets fear that the disease could spread further into other parts of the country.
New Forest dog owners warned over disease
Although there has been a 460 per cent rise in cases since December 2013 when compared to the period between November 2012 and November 2013, vets were keen to stress that the disease is still very uncommon, and advised dog owners to stay vigilant.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:46:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dozens of Yemen's Houthi rebels killed after taking fight to Saudi Arabia border</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/45ea2a00/sc/7/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0Cdozens0Eof0Eyemens0Ehouthi0Erebels0Ekilled0Eafter0Etaking0Efight0Eto0Esaudi0Earabia0Eborder0E10A2183240Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Dozens of Yemen's Houthi rebels killed after taking fight to Saudi Arabia border

Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A cross-border attack on Saudi Arabia by Yemeni rebel forces resulted in late-night clashes that left three Saudi soldiers and "dozens" of Yemeni rebels dead, according to the Saudi Defence Ministry.
A ministry statement said that a group of Yemen's Shiite rebels attacked border posts and control points in the southern Saudi province of Najran late on Thursday night. Saudi forces, backed by air force fighter jets, repelled the attack, the statement said.
A Saudi-led coalition of mostly Sunni Arab nations has been conducting air strikes inside Yemen for more than a month, seeking to blunt the advance of rebel forces who have overrun the capital, Sanaa, and were advancing deep into southern Yemen. The Shiite rebels, known as Houthis, are allied with military and security forces loyal to ousted former president Ali Abdullah Saleh.
Supporters of the Houthi movement brandish their weapons as they take part in a demonstration against the Saudi-led military 'Decisive Storm' air campaign, in the capital Sanaa, on Wednesday 
Yemen's Western-backed president, Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi, fled the capital earlier this year after being placed under house arrest by the rebels. Hadi temporarily set up a provisional capital in the southern port city of Aden, but later fled the country as the rebels forces advanced on Aden. Hadi now operates from the Saudi capital, Riyadh.
Read more:
New Saudi king swings the axe on his cabinet
Despite more than a month of airstrikes, the campaign has largely failed to halt the rebel advance into southern Yemen. However the Saudi government claims its coalition campaign has destroyed much of the rebel stockpile of missiles and heavy weapons.
The United Nations estimates than more than 500 Yemeni civilians, including more than 100 children, have been killed by airstrikes and violence. But Hadi's government puts the civilian death toll at more than 1000.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
