<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Independent">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:10:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jeremy Clarkson and James May filmed joking about Oscar Pistorius shooting Reeva Steenkamp during live show in South Africa</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798cc3d/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cpeople0Cjeremy0Eclarkson0Eand0Ejames0Emay0Efilmed0Ejoking0Eabout0Eoscar0Epistorius0Eshooting0Ereeva0Esteenkamp0Eduring0Elive0Eshow0Ein0Esouth0Eafrica0E10A3478310Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Jeremy Clarkson and James May filmed joking about Oscar Pistorius shooting Reeva Steenkamp during live show in South Africa
Pair joked about shooting at their show in Johannesburg
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Jeremy Clarkson and James May were apparently filmed joking about the killing of Reeva Steenkamp by the Paralympian athlete Oscar Pistorius during their live show in South Africa.
Clarkson pretended to have shot an audience member after accidentally hitting him with a paintball pellet during their Clarkson, Hammond &amp; May Live show in Johannesburg.
A video of the exchange filmed by a member of the audience showed the former Top Gear presenter saying: Ive hit someone in the audience. [] I thought he was a burglar. His co-host May responded: Was that a member of the audience that you shot in the bathroom? It cant be a burglar then can it. Clarkson then quipped: I may have to go to prison for 20 seconds for that.
The joke appears to be a reference to Steenkamps death, who was fatally shot by Pistorius in the bathroom of his home. The athlete was sentenced to five years in prison after being found guilty of culpable homicide over her death but could be released on parole as soon as August .
Top Gear: Who will join Chris Evans behind the wheel?
Clarkson was sacked from Top Gear for attacking a BBC producer and replaced by the BBC Radio 2 and One Show presenter Chris Evans. May and Richard Hammond have chosen not to return to the motoring show, but all three are expected to announce a new TV show within the forthcoming weeks.
Clarkson also hinted about working with a rival broadcaster in a recent column for The Sun, where he wrote: "I won't miss making a car show. Because other broadcasters are available so I don't have to stop doing that. See you on the flip side."
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:07:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Rolling Stone brands plaque marking the band's foundation as 'disgusting'</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798cc3a/sc/23/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cpeople0Cnews0Cformer0Erolling0Estone0Ebrands0Eplaque0Emarking0Ethe0Ebands0Efoundation0Eas0Edisgusting0E10A3478720Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:51:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A man with HIV asked strangers to hold his hand — what happened next brought him to tears</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a62a/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Clife0Estyle0Chealth0Eand0Efamilies0Chealth0Enews0Ca0Eman0Ewith0Ehiv0Easked0Estrangers0Eto0Ehold0Ehis0Ehand0E0Ewhat0Ehappened0Enext0Ebrought0Ehim0Eto0Etears0E10A3479280Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>A man with HIV asked strangers to hold his hand  what happened next brought him to tears
Janne from Finland said: 'I am HIV-positive. Touch me!'
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A man named Janne stood in the centre of the Finnish capital Helsinki with closed eyes and extended arms. The signs either side of him read, in both English and Finnish: "I am HIV-positive. Touch me!"
In a video released by Finnish broadcasting company Yle Kioski to coincide with Pride Week in Helsinki, Janne asked strangers to touch him.
He wanted to challenge the long-held stigma of HIV/AIDS. Here's what happened:
At first passersby appeared reluctant to touch Janne, perhaps because of his condition, perhaps because it's just not something you see everyday.
But it isn't long before his hand is held, and his shoulder clasped. From there, people embraced him  men, women, children.
Janne used this sign
He closed his eyes and reached out
Some people appeared confused
But then they started to hold his hand
And clutch his shoulder
And Janne was moved to tears
Janne offered his 'thanks' to those who touched him: "Kiitos".
He was overwhelmed by the support, and began to cry.
Perhaps attitudes to HIV truly have changed.
Glastonbury 2015
News
ebookA delicious collection of 50 meaty main courses
Sport
people
News
tvSpoilers if you don't know yet
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:48:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia hotel attack: Gunmen kill 'at least 19' in shooting at seaside town of Sousse</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4799cf3d/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cafrica0Ctunisia0Ehotel0Eattack0Elive0E10A3478910Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
At least 27 people are reported to have been killed in a shooting at a hotel in the Tunisian seaside town of Sousse.
Tunisia's interior ministry said two gunmen had opened fire on the beach between two hotels at the tourist resort, and that one was still on the run.
Security sources told the Reuters news agency that an exchange of gunfire had been reported at the scene, and that one gunman has been killed.
An official with the interior ministry said the death toll had risen to 27 and that it included foreign nationals. It was a dramatic increase from an earlier report of a handful of deaths.
Sousse sits on the Mediterranean Sea and is highly popular with British tourists, and is cited on holiday operator Thomson's list of prime destinations for Britons in Tunisia.
Man decapitated at French factory 'by attacker waving black flag'
Speaking to Sky News from the hotel, one British tourist travelling with his family said they had been told to remain inside and not to go down to the beach.
He said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he told Sky News. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
Timeline: The emergence of Isis
The attack comes only three months after three Islamist gunmen shot dead dozens of people at the Bardo museum in the countrys capital Tunis. The countrys tourist industry has been on high alert since the attack.
Experts said the Sousse attack was more likely to be the work of Isis militants than any other terror group, though there was no immediate claim of responsibility.
It came after an attack on a French factory just outside Lyon and a bombing of a Shia mosque in Kuwait earlier on Friday, both of which were reported to be Isis-linked.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:48:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen attack hotel in Tunisian seaside town of Sousse</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a628/sc/40/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cafrica0Ctunisia0Ehotel0Eattack0Elive0E10A3478910Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
At least 27 people are reported to have been killed in a shooting at a hotel in the Tunisian seaside town of Sousse.
Tunisia's interior ministry said two gunmen had opened fire on the beach between two hotels at the tourist resort, and that one was still on the run.
Security sources told the Reuters news agency that an exchange of gunfire had been reported at the scene, and that one gunman has been killed.
An official with the interior ministry said the death toll had risen to 27 and that it included foreign nationals. It was a dramatic increase from an earlier report of a handful of deaths.
Sousse sits on the Mediterranean Sea and is highly popular with British tourists, and is cited on holiday operator Thomson's list of prime destinations for Britons in Tunisia.
Man decapitated at French factory 'by attacker waving black flag'
Speaking to Sky News from the hotel, one British tourist travelling with his family said they had been told to remain inside and not to go down to the beach.
He said he was on the beach and heard what "we thought was firecrackers going off" 100 yards away, followed by an explosion from the next hotel complex along.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he told Sky News. He said his son said he had seen someone get shot on the beach.
Timeline: The emergence of Isis
The attack comes only three months after three Islamist gunmen shot dead dozens of people at the Bardo museum in the countrys capital Tunis. The countrys tourist industry has been on high alert since the attack.
Experts said the Sousse attack was more likely to be the work of Isis militants than any other terror group, though there was no immediate claim of responsibility.
It came after an attack on a French factory just outside Lyon and a bombing of a Shia mosque in Kuwait earlier on Friday, both of which were reported to be Isis-linked.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:42:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>20-year-old MP Mhairi Black follows up election triumph with a first-class honours in politics</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a4d7/sc/6/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0C20Ayearold0Emp0Emhairi0Eblack0Efollows0Eup0Eelection0Etriumph0Ewith0Ea0Efirstclass0Ehonours0Ein0Epolitics0E10A3476270Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Last month she became the youngest MP in 350 years; this month she secured a first-class honours degree  20 year-old Mhairi Black must be worried she is peaking too soon in life.
The SNP MP for Paisley and Renfrewshire South is attending her graduation at Glasgow University today, where she will have a chance to catch up with her fellow graduates after a hectic end to her time as a student.
But while her peers at the graduation ceremony will be stressing about their next move and frantically trying to find a job, Ms Black will be able to enjoy a day off from her 67,000 a year job at Westminster, which could soon go up to 74,000.
"I'm really delighted and looking forward to celebrating the day with my parents and other students," she told BBC Radio Scotland.
Mhairi Black, Britain's youngest member of parliament since 1667, greets Labour candidate Douglas Alexander during the declaration of the general election results for Paisley and Renfrewshire South Her final exam was on Scottish politics, so perhaps it was unsurprising that she got a first. And as an MP she was able to revise in the House of Commons library, which must be the mostappropriate place to prepare for exams on British politics, but an experience she described as "nuts".
She told ITV's Lorraine show: "I had a really bizarre moment because I finally had time just to sit and be quiet in the library that is in the Commons and I was sitting going: Im studying for a politics exam in the House of Commons library. Its nuts but its good.
Read more:
The SNP adventure arrives in Westminister - but how long before these new MPs go native?
The SNP adventure arrives in Westminister - but how long before these new MPs go native?
Ms Black's astonishing victory at the election will now be studied by future students of British politics, after she became the youngest MP sincethe 13-year-old Christopher Monck in 1667.
Her first-class honours degree is all-the-more impressive considering she spent her final year at university campaigning to boot out one of Labour's top figures - their former shadow foreign secretary Douglas Alexander.
Her multi-tasking succeeded, managing to overturn his 16,000 majority to win the southwest Glasgow seat. She now enjoys a majority of more than 5,684 votes, which puts her in a good position to hold the seat in 2020 and stay in her well-paid job for at least until she turns 30.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:38:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Right To Buy has 'stolen' £90m funding for building London council housing</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a4d6/sc/8/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Cright0Eto0Ebuy0Ehas0Estolen0E90Am0Efunding0Efor0Ebuilding0Elondon0Ecouncil0Ehousing0E10A34790A50Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Right To Buy has 'stolen' 90m funding for building London council housing
Labour says the Treasury's cut should be ploughed into housebuilding where it is needed
Jon Stone
Jon Stone
Jon Stone is a reporter for independent.co.uk mainly covering politics. He has previously worked for PoliticsHome, BuzzFeed, and others.
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
The Governments Right To Buy policy has stolen 90m funding for building council housing in London , Labour has said.
Ministers admitted in a letter that tens of million of pounds from the receipts of council house sales had not been directed back to the capital but sent to the Treasury.
The Treasury cut of sales comes despite a massive shortfall in the Governments promise to replace any homes sold off under the policy.
Nationally, 26,619 homes have been sold under Right To Buy since 2012 when the policy was revamped by the Coalition government.
Of those, 3,337 have been replaced, according to figures released by the Department for Communities and Local Government.
Tom Copley, the partys housing spokesperson at City Hall, argued that the policy of diverting money away from London housebuilding was exacerbating the housing crisis there.
Despite promising that Right to Buy would result in a new home for each one sold the last Government effectively stole 90m which was meant to be spent on new homes for the capital. As a result many councils are finding it impossible to replace their lost homes, he said.
'Uninhabitable' Kensington flat on sale for over half a million

Londons housing market is already in crisis, diverting money which was meant to be reinvested in new homes is a total betrayal. You have to wonder whether the policy was intentionally designed this way to reduce the number of council homes in London.
The revelation about Right To Buy comes as Labour leadership candidate Jeremy Corbyn suggests extending the right to private tenants .
The Government is already committed to extending the policy to housing associations, which are private, not-for-profit landlords.
Private rents in Britain are the highest in the EU, according to the official agency Eurostat. London rents are now double the national average, however.
The capitals population grew by half a million last year to 64,596,800, but housebuilding is not keeping pace with demand and prices and rents are still rising.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:38:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Watch: California student finally becomes college graduate - at 99-years-old</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a4d5/sc/33/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Camericas0Cwatch0Ecalifornia0Estudent0Efinally0Ebecomes0Ecollege0Egraduate0E0Eat0E99yearsold0E10A3478570Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A woman who lived through the Great Depression in the 1930s and the Civil Rights Movement from 1954-1968 has been celebrating after making it through another landmark event  college.
99-year-old Doreetha Daniels can now call herself a graduate after finally receiving her Associate of Arts degree in social science from College of the Canyons in California.
Beginning her studies at the college in 2009, Ms Daniels suffered a few setbacks, including two strokes and temporary vision loss  which resulted in her losing her drivers licence.
But the former student persevered and was determined to walk across the stage to collect her degree before her 100th birthday.
To the many who have wondered why Ms Daniels would event attempt such a task at her age, the graduate simply says she had always lived life to the fullest and achieved many things  but never completed her education.
Taking to the podium on graduation day, Ms Daniels earned cheers and tears from the audience as she told them: 99, here I am.
I accomplished what I wanted to do and this is my dream come true.
My grandchildren inspired me because they were all adults, working, and working on their masters. So, I said, Well, Im not doing anything and Im tired of my hobbies, so Im gonna go to school.
It wasnt all plain-sailing for the student, though, as she revealed there were some minor bumps in the road  college-level math and statistics courses.
It was all worth it though and she said: Its been 63 years since Ive taken algebra even. But Ive learned a lot.
Offering some words of advice to her younger counterparts, Ms Daniels added: Dont give up. Do it.
Dont let anybody discourage you. Say that, Im going to do it, and do it for yourself.
When the bumps come, just pick yourself up and say, Im going to go ahead, and go ahead.
Watch an inspiring Ms Daniels on graduation day:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:24:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bridget Jones 3: Filming expect to start on Bridget Jones's Baby later this year</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a4d4/sc/28/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Carts0Eentertainment0Cfilms0Cnews0Cbridget0Ejones0E30Efilming0Eexpect0Eto0Estart0Eon0Ebridget0Ejoness0Ebaby0Elater0Ethis0Eyear0E10A3478120Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:07:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Michelle Watt found dead at home aged 38</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c6bb/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cpeople0Cmichelle0Ewatt0Efound0Edead0Eat0Ehome0Eaged0E380E10A3477780Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Michelle Watt found dead at home aged 38
Television presenter was best known for 60 Minute Makeover
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Daytime television presenter Michelle Watt has died aged 38.
The TV personality, best known for presenting 60 Minute Makeover, was found at the Stirlingshire home she shared with husband Paul Kerr, 43, and daughter Jaymi, five.
Police Scotland, called to the home at around 6.15pm on Wednesday, confirmed to The Independent that the death is not being treated as suspicious.
Daughter of boxing legend Jim Watt, she worked on a variety of TV shows  fronting the National Lottery Daily Play and the Live New Year Show  and was known in the industry for her warm personality and hard-work.
Notable deaths in 2015
It is the second tragedy to strike the family. Her elder brother Jim died in 1995 in a car-crash aged just 17. Ms Watt, who named her daughter after her deceased brother, told The Sun that her family miss him every day.
TV personalities and local celebrities expressed their sadness over her death, with Loraine Kelly  a champion of Ms Watts when she started out in the industry  tweeting: Absolutely shocked to hear of death of Michelle Watt. Lovely woman and a fantastic mum. Thoughts with her family and everyone who loved her.
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:06:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK's 'structurally unfair' asylum appeals process suspended by court after legal challenge</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c6ba/sc/31/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cuk0Cpolitics0Cuks0Estructurally0Eunfair0Easylum0Eappeals0Eprocess0Esuspended0Eby0Ecourt0Eafter0Elegal0Echallenge0E10A3477240Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>UK's 'structurally unfair' asylum appeals process suspended by court after legal challenge
A charity had argued that the fast-track process was unfair
Jon Stone
Jon Stone
Jon Stone is a reporter for independent.co.uk mainly covering politics. He has previously worked for PoliticsHome, BuzzFeed, and others.
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
A court has suspended the UKs fast-track asylum appeals system after a legal challenge by a charity that says it is structurally unfair.
Lawyers from Action Detention argued that it was unlawful for asylum seekers to be detained during their appeals process even when there was a good chance their case could be valid.
The ruling means that the Home Office can no longer detain asylum seekers during their appeal simply for claiming asylum, and that the systems tight deadlines can no longer be imposed upon applicants.
The High Court had previously ordered the appeals process to be suspended, but the Court of Appeal had said the Government could keep the system running while an appeal by ministers was heart.
The appeal court has now agreed that the system should be suspended, however.
Speaking from outside the Court of Appeal today Jerome Phelps, the director of Action Detention, said the Government should develop a new approach to asylum appeals.
In pictures: Migrant boat disaster

We are delighted that asylum-seekers will no longer face a detained appeals process that is so unfair as to be unlawful. It is unfortunate that it has taken so many court rulings to finally suspend this deeply flawed process, he said.
People seeking protection from war and persecution deserve better from British justice. We hope that the government will take this opportunity to reflect and develop a different approach that is fair.
The charity says many applicants processed through the fast-track scheme are from countries with a recent history of armed conflict, including Afghanistan and Sri Lanka.
The current system has been in place for a decade.
The Ministry of Justice was contacted to comment on this story. The Home Office said it was preparing a response.
Glastonbury 2015
News
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
Sport
people
News
tvSpoilers if you don't know yet
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Andy Murray route to the Wimbledon 2015 final</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c959/sc/13/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Csport0Ctennis0Candy0Emurray0Eroute0Eto0Ethe0Ewimbledon0E20A150Efinal0E10A3477390Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Andy Murray route to the Wimbledon 2015 final
The Scot faces a tough task if he is to clinch a second title
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Follow Simon Rice
Friday 26 June 2015
Andy Murray may have to beat every other member of the 'big four' if he is to add a second title to his 2013 Wimbledon triumph.
Here, we take a look at his possible route to the 2015 title...
Round 1 - Mikhail Kukushkin
The world number 58 from Kazakhstan. The 27-year-old has met Murray twice before and lost both. The most recent meeting was at the 2012 Australian Open which Murray won in straight sets.
Round 2 - Robin Haase
Murray last played the world number 73 at last year's US Open, winning over four sets. It was his fourth meeting with the Dutch 28-year-old of which Murray has won three. The only victory for Haase came in their first meeting back in 2008.

Round 3 - Andreas Seppi
Like Haase, the only time Seppi managed to beat Murray was when they first played each other back in 2006. Although that victory for the world number 27 came on grass which might give the Italian some hope. They've met six times since and Murray has won the lot. The most recent was on clay in the Davis Cup last year.
Round 4 - Jo-Wilfried Tsonga
The French world number 12 will offer the first real test of Murray's Wimbledon credentials. The 30-year-old has the capability to beat the best on his day, although he will have to upset the form book if he is to defeat Murray. The Scot leads 10-3 in the head-to-head stakes and has lost just once in their last 10 meetings. They met in the quarter-finals of Wimbledon 2012 with Murray recovering from a first-set loss to win over four.
Jo-Wilfried Tsonga 
Quarter-final - Rafael Nadal/David Ferrer
Nadal is the loose cannon in the draw - seeded at number 10 and threatening to make a mockery of that placing. Should he reach the quarter-finals, Murray will be taking on a player he has met three times at Wimbledon and never beaten. Nadal might not be in peak form but with 14 Grand Slams under his belt, this could be a really tough test.
Rafael Nadal 
It could well be that Ferrer is the player awaiting Murray, with the Spaniard ranked number seven in the world at the moment. He and Murray met in the quarter-finals of Wimbledon in 2012 where Murray advanced over four sets. They last played at this year's French Open, with Murray winning that particular quarter-final as well.
Ferrer against Murray at the French Open 
Semi-final - Roger Federer
The world number two has been written off a few times over recent years and whilst he remains without a Grand Slam victory since victory at Wimbledon in 2012, he continues to go deep in nearly every tournament he plays and looks capable of going the whole way. Murray enjoys an enviable record against the Swiss compared to most - with 11 victories and 12 defeats. Their most recent meeting saw Federer win at the ATP World Tour Finals last year whilst Murray's most recent win against the 17-time Grand Slam winner came in the semi-finals of the 2013 Australian Open. They last met at Wimbledon in the 2012 final which left a defeated Murray in tears. However, they did play on the grass courts of the All England Club a few weeks later in the Olympic final, in which Murray won gold.
Murray reached the first Wimbledon final of his career in 2012 - but was beaten by Federer 
Final - Novak Djokovic
Until the French Open final, Djokovic looked unstoppable. But Stan Wawrinka proved that the Serb can be beaten and with it gave everyone else hope that the world number one won't simply march to a third Wimbledon title. Djokovic holds an impressive 19-8 head-to-head record over the player born a week before him. However, there are some positives for Murray to take from their previous meetings. Murray's last two victories over Djokovic came in Grand Slam finals - the 2012 US Open and 2013 Wimbledon. Also, they've only ever met twice on grass - and Murray has won both. That 2013 final and at the Olympics the year before.
Murray and Djokovic embrace after the five-set thriller at this year's French Open 
Djokovic though has won the last eight meetings, the most recent of which was in the semi-finals at this year's French Open.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait mosque explosion: Possible Isis bomb attack launched on Shia Muslims during Ramadan Friday prayers</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c6b9/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0Ckuwait0Emosque0Eexplosion0Epossible0Eisis0Ebomb0Eattack0Elaunched0Eon0Eshia0Emuslims0Eduring0Eramadan0Efriday0Eprayers0E10A347740A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Isis militants have claimed responsibility for a deadly bomb attack on a Shia mosque during Friday prayers in Kuwait, just a couple of hours after an attack on a factory in the south of France.
At least 13 people have died following the explosion at the al-Imam al-Sadiq mosque in al-Sawaber, with images posted to Twitter showing the extent of the devastation and what appeared to be a number of bodies lying among the rubble.
In a statement posted via its affiliated social media accounts, Isis said it had carried out the attack which occurred at the height of Ramadan prayers when the mosque would have been at its busiest.
People file out of the mosque after the bomb attack at the al-Imam al-Sadiq mosque
The statement identified the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said the target was a "temple of the rejectionists" - a term used by Isis to refer to Shia Muslims.
In the immediate aftermath of the attack, Quilliams Charlie Winter suggested that Isis supporters on Twitter were getting very animated over the reports.
Man decapitated at French factory 'by attacker waving black flag'
Earlier, the Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said "eight casualties have been taken to the Emiri hospital, two in critical condition". It was unclear whether any of the eight were among those reported dead.
There was shock among some Twitter users that the attack was carried out on Muslims praying on a Friday during the holy month of Ramadan.
There has not yet been a claim of responsibility in relation to the attack Meanwhile in France, an attack believed to involve two men carrying black Islamist flags was launched on the Air Products factory near Lyon.
One man has been arrested, while the decapitated remains of a body have been founded. Several others have been reported injured.
And in Tunisia at least one gunman is reported to have been killed in an assault on a hotel in the Tunisian seaside town of Sousse .
The attack came three months after three Islamist gunmen shot dead dozens of people at the Bardo museum in the coutrys capital Tunis.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:00:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait mosque explosion: 'Isis' bombs Shia Muslims during Ramadan Friday prayers</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798a6f0/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0Ckuwait0Emosque0Eexplosion0Epossible0Eisis0Ebomb0Eattack0Elaunched0Eon0Eshia0Emuslims0Eduring0Eramadan0Efriday0Eprayers0E10A347740A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Isis militants have claimed responsibility for a deadly bomb attack on a Shia mosque during Friday prayers in Kuwait, just a couple of hours after an attack on a factory in the south of France.
At least 13 people have died following the explosion at the al-Imam al-Sadiq mosque in al-Sawaber, with images posted to Twitter showing the extent of the devastation and what appeared to be a number of bodies lying among the rubble.
In a statement posted via its affiliated social media accounts, Isis said it had carried out the attack which occurred at the height of Ramadan prayers when the mosque would have been at its busiest.
People file out of the mosque after the bomb attack at the al-Imam al-Sadiq mosque
The statement identified the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said the target was a "temple of the rejectionists" - a term used by Isis to refer to Shia Muslims.
In the immediate aftermath of the attack, Quilliams Charlie Winter suggested that Isis supporters on Twitter were getting very animated over the reports.
Man decapitated at French factory 'by attacker waving black flag'
Earlier, the Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said "eight casualties have been taken to the Emiri hospital, two in critical condition". It was unclear whether any of the eight were among those reported dead.
There was shock among some Twitter users that the attack was carried out on Muslims praying on a Friday during the holy month of Ramadan.
There has not yet been a claim of responsibility in relation to the attack Meanwhile in France, an attack believed to involve two men carrying black Islamist flags was launched on the Air Products factory near Lyon.
One man has been arrested, while the decapitated remains of a body have been founded. Several others have been reported injured.
And in Tunisia at least one gunman is reported to have been killed in an assault on a hotel in the Tunisian seaside town of Sousse .
The attack came three months after three Islamist gunmen shot dead dozens of people at the Bardo museum in the coutrys capital Tunis.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:49:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Palestinians hand dossier detailing alleged war crimes by Israel in Gaza to ICC</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c3f5/sc/20/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Cmiddle0Eeast0Cpalestinians0Ehand0Edossier0Edetailing0Ealleged0Ewar0Ecrimes0Eby0Eisrael0Ein0Egaza0Eto0Eicc0E10A3476110Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; World &gt; Middle East
Palestinians hand dossier detailing alleged war crimes by Israel in Gaza to ICC
Foreign minister submits files in person at the Hague court, to feed into preliminary investigation that could lead to charges against both sides
Friday 26 June 2015
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
The Palestinians have handed International Criminal Court prosecutors a dossier detailing alleged Israeli war crimes in Gaza.
Riyad al-Maliki, foreign minister of the Palestinian Authority, submitted the files in person at the Hague court, to feed into an investigation by ICC prosecutor Fatou Bensouda into possible crimes on Palestinian territory.
The preliminary probe aims to establish if there is enough evidence to merit opening a full-scale investigation that could ultimately lead to charges against both Israelis and Palestinians.
The move comes days after a separate investigation by the United Nations Human Rights Council accused both sides of committing possible war crimes in last summer's Gaza War.
The Palestinian Authority joined the international court this year but Israel is not a member and rejects the courts authority.
Parts of eastern Gaza are still in ruins, a year on from the 50-day war
Mr al-Malikis file, based on findings by a Palestinian commission of inquiry and information from non-government groups, also contains evidence illegal Israeli settlement-building in the West Bank and East Jerusalem.
Ms Bensouda's initial probe aims to establish if there is enough evidence to merit opening a full-scale investigation that could ultimately lead to charges against both Israelis and Palestinians. It is not clear how long the process will take.

Mr al-Maliki said the information forms "a compelling case for the prompt opening of an investigation."
He said it included details on Israel's settlements and military offensive throughout the occupied Palestinian territories, particularly last year's Gaza War, and also outlined allegations of crimes committed against Palestinian prisoners.
The filing, "confirms that the absence of accountability has led to the recurrence of violations and crimes and will continue to do so if gone unchecked," the Palestinians said in a statement before the filing on Thursday.
READ MORE: Both Israelis and Palestinians may have committed war crimes, UN Gaza inquiry finds
Israel dismissed the submission as politically motivated, as it did the UN probe.
"This is a Palestinian attempt to manipulate and politicise the judicial mechanisms of the ICC," said Emmanuel Nahshon, spokesman of the Israeli Foreign Ministry. "We hope that the prosecutor will not fall in that trap."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:47:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kris Jenner talks about Caitlyn Jenner's transition for first time since Vanity Fair cover</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c3f3/sc/14/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cpeople0Ckris0Ejenner0Etalks0Eabout0Ecaitlyn0Ejenners0Etransition0Efor0Efirst0Etime0Esince0Evanity0Efair0Ecover0E10A34750A80Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; People
Kris Jenner talks about Caitlyn Jenner's transition for first time since Vanity Fair cover
The head of the Kardashian empire has spoken out about her 'passive-aggressive' marriage, but supported Caitlyn for following her dream
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Since debuting on the cover of Vanity Fair last month, Caitlyn Jenner has been inundated with support from prominent figures like Lady Gaga, Demi Moore and Barack Obama.
And now Kris Jenner, Kardashian empress and ex-wife to Caitlyn, has told reporters she is a big fan of the iconic Annie Leibovitz-shot cover, describing it as beautiful.
Speaking to Extra at Cannes this week, Jenner, who has only just seen the piece despite being interviewed as part of the profile on Caitlyn, said I think its amazing.
I think that someone following their dream is truly inspirational to a lot of people  you have to do what makes you happy.
Jenners support come after she discusses the hardships involved in being married to someone with gender dysphoria in the magazine.
She tells author Buzz Bissinger that the end of their marriage was the most passive-aggressive thing I think Ive ever experienced.
Inspirational quotes about LGBT rights
She added that she wished Caitlyn had told her about the issue before, saying: Why would you want to be married and have kids if this is what you wanted since you were a little boy? Why would you not explain this to me?
Caitlyn, however, has spoken about the good times shared between the pair during their 23 year marriage. She tweeted: Reading the VF article reminded me of the love and good times Kris and I shared for so many years. Wouldn't trade that time for anything!
The rest of the Kardashian-Jenner clan have been hugely supportive of Caitlyn. Step-daughter Kim told Entertainment Tonight I actually went to the shoot, and that was my first time meeting Caitlyn. Shes beautiful, and Im so proud that she can just be her authentic self. I guess thats what life is about.
Read more:
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:38:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China criticises the US over 'terrible' human rights situation and 'grim racial division'</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c3f2/sc/31/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Casia0Cchina0Ecriticises0Ethe0Eus0Eover0Eterrible0Ehuman0Erights0Esituation0Eand0Egrim0Eracial0Edivision0E10A3475740Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>China criticises the US over 'terrible' human rights situation and 'grim racial division'
New report aims at exposing US double standards on human rights
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
China has released a scathing report on the state of human rights in the United States.
In the seven-page document , published by Xinhua news agency, China's State Council Information Office is highly critical of recent racial tensions in the US, gun violence, torture offences and rising inequality.
Not only is the situation in the US "increasingly grave," according to the report, "the US violated human rights in other countries in a more brazen manner, and was given more 'red cards' in the international human rights field".
The report comes just days after the US State Department's annual analysis on human rights around the world, and follows three days of high-level talks between the countries in Washington DC.
China has been issuing this US-centric human rights report for the last 16 years  a transparent attempt to expose the country's double standards.
President Obama and John Kerry met the Chinese delegation at the White House The report, which was compiled using US media articles, says: "The US is a country with grim problems of racial discrimination, and institutional discrimination against ethnic minorities continued.
"Serious racial bias persisted in the police and justice systems. Minority groups and indigenous people are subject to unfairness in environment, election, health care, housing, education and other fields."
The US was also last year "haunted by spreading guns, frequent occurrence of violent crimes, which threatened citizens' civil rights."
The two countries have often clashed over human rights, especially since 1989 when the US enforced sanctions on China after its bloody response to pro-democracy protests in Tianamen Square.
China has long rejected US criticism of its human rights record, arguing that it has lifted millions out of poverty.
So far under President Xi Jinping, promises to improve citizens democracy and human rights have been undermined by a forceful crackdown on dissidents and activists.
Glastonbury 2015
News
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
Sport
people
News
tvSpoilers if you don't know yet
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:35:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tennessee motorway wreck leaves six dead and nine injured, say police</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c3f1/sc/3/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cworld0Camericas0Ctennessee0Emotorway0Ewreck0Eleaves0Esix0Edead0Eand0Enine0Einjured0Esay0Epolice0E10A347460A0Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Tennessee motorway wreck leaves six dead and nine injured, say police
One police officer described the horrific incident as being 'one of the worst crashes I've ever seen'
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
At least six people have died and nine others have been injured in a huge motorway pile-up in Tennessee, say police .
Authorities say that at least 15 people in 9 vehicles were involved in the crash. The incident took place at around 7pm yesterday evening in Chattanooga.
None of the victims identities have yet been released as family members of the deceased are still being informed of the tragedy.
While information is still being obtained, it is confirmed there are multiple fatalities #chanews cause undetermined pic.twitter.com/XZC83Hleds
 Chattanooga Police (@ChattanoogaPD) June 26, 2015
At least 9 people are currently being treated for injuries in local hospitals.
Investigators worked overnight to establish what caused the fatal crash.
UPDATE: Police on scene report a total of 9 vehicles, over 15 people involved, 6 of the individuals succumbed to their injuries #chanews
 Chattanooga Police (@ChattanoogaPD) June 26, 2015
The states Department of Transportation told NBC that a least one semi-trailer carrying cargo was involved in the crash, which is believed to have resulted in many of the other vehicles being completely wrecked in the pile-up.
Crash with multiple deaths on I-75N at Ooltewah Exit will have highway shut down several hours. @WRCB on scene. pic.twitter.com/5YWddmkFxp
 Derrall Stalvey (@Derrall) June 26, 2015
Northbound lanes of I-75 remained closed this morning as officials sought to tend to the injured, remove the deceased and clear the vehicles from the roads.

Eye witness photos showed vehicles on fire with flames extending across the motorway amid the crash debris.
Police Chief Fred Fletcher from Chattanooga Police told reporters last night: My heart goes out to all individuals involved in this tragic incident. This is one of the worst crashes Ive ever seen.
Glastonbury 2015
News
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
Sport
people
News
tvSpoilers if you don't know yet
News
Dutch city of Utrecht to experiment with a universal, unconditional 'basic income'
3
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:35:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tesco's first quarter sales down 1.3% but heralded as 'step in the right direction'</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c3eb/sc/28/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Cbusiness0Cnews0Ctescos0Efirst0Equarter0Esales0Edown0E130Ebut0Eheralded0Eas0Estep0Ein0Ethe0Eright0Edirection0E10A3474820Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>News &gt; Business &gt; Business News
Tesco's first quarter sales down 1.3% but heralded as 'step in the right direction'
Chief executive Dave Lewis said that volatility in the company's short term results was likely to remain due to a challenging market
Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
Tesco has said that it has taken another step in the right direction after UK like-for-like sales fell by 1.3 per cent in the first quarter of the financial year.
Despite the fall, the supermarket giant said that the results had been an improvement on the 4 per cent fall in the same period last year. The figures are a 1.7 per cent decrease on the previous quarters results.
Dave Lewis, chief executive of Tesco, said that the companys short-term performance was likely to remain volatile while the market was challenging .
The companys sales in Ireland fell by 4.4 per cent compared to 5.6 per cent one year ago, while the Asian revenue decreased by 3 per cent, a slight increase on the first quarter of last year.
Tesco announced that figures from Kantar Worldpanel, a market research organisation, showed that 180,000 more customers had visited the supermarket chain in the 12 weeks to 24 May.
Mr Lewis said: These first quarter results represent another step in the right direction.
We set to serve our customers a little better every day and the improvements we are making are starting to have an effect.
Tesco's boss knows which side his bread is buttered
This improvements have come during the restructuring of our office and store management teams, which testifies to the focus, skill and commitment of colleagues across the business.
The results come ahead of a Tesco annual shareholder meeting amid concern among investors over its chairman and pay-offs to its former chief executive.
Philip Clarke, former chief executive of Tesco, was given a 1.2million pay-off in February on top of his 764,000 salary until mid-January.
Annual figures released in April showed that Tesco had suffered one of the biggest losses in corporate history at 6.4bn and would find it challenging to return to profit this year.
Additional Reporting: PA
glastonbury 2015: live
News
people
News
tvSpoilers if you don't know yet
Arts and Entertainment
ebooksAn introduction to the ground rules of British democracy
News
Man who recorded doctors mocking him during an operation sues anesthesiologist and practice for $500,000
2
Go
Amama Mbabazi: 'If I didn't fear Idi Amin then, I won't have fear now'
Uganda's former Prime Minister plans to end his erstwhile revolutionary comrade's 29 years of presidential rule
Sainted fraternity of heckler-squashers
After Barack Obama coolly rebuffed a heckler in the White House this week, John Walsh examines the admirable art of dealing with unwanted interruptions
Bring Your Dog To Work Day
Is having a mutt in your meeting productive?
The lost art of eating heart
Cardiac cuisine is muscling in on the nose-to-tail menu
Blue Planet to White House
President Obama interviews David Attenborough in unique encounter for BBC1
Empathy Museum: Walk in my shoes
Philosopher Roman Krznaric believes there are few ills that can't be solved with empathy  and he's created a roving Empathy Museum to prove it
Stepping out for the summer: 12 best wedges
More glam than flats, but with more wear-all-day potential than heels, theyre the perfect summer compromise
Petra Kvitova: Retaining her Wimbledon title is all in the mind for Czech star
It has been a tough year so far for the 2014 champion, forced to take two months off with exhaustion. However, a fresh mental attitude has turned things around
An international gagging order?
Israel's far right seeks to cripple human rights groups which monitor abuses in the Occupied Territories
Could a leap second cause chaos?
Next Tuesday night, a planned 'leap second' will delay July, momentarily. This quirky practice of recalibration could have some unwanted consequences, discovers Simon Usborne
No mod Cons
Post-punk duo Sleaford Mods let rip at top Tories, Blur and a male model
The flags that cause controversy
Pressure is mounting to ban the Confederate banner after the Charleston shooting. Gillian Orr flags up some other offenders
Crowdfunding is growing up
Crowdfunding used to be the wild child of finance. Now it's become a big business, it's having to knuckle down and face greater scrutiny
Disney to give Charles Darwin the Indiana Jones treatment
Hollywood production will shine fresh light on the Father of Evolution
Homesickness in the modern age
We are never really cut off these days, but does technology make you feel better or worse when you are away?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:28:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Malala in America: Education advocate takes the US by storm ahead of speech in San Jose, California</title>
        <Link>http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/266/f/3492/s/4798c3ea/sc/28/l/0L0Sindependent0O0Cnews0Ceducation0Ceducation0Enews0Cmalala0Ein0Eamerica0Eeducation0Eadvocate0Etakes0Ethe0Eus0Eby0Estorm0Eahead0Eof0Espeech0Ein0Esan0Ejose0Ecalifornia0E10A3474430Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Your friend's email address
Your email address
Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms &amp; Policies
Email
She has filled-out arenas, prompted legions of fans wherever she has been, stormed the capital to speak with lawmakers, left a top talk-show host speechless  twice  has a 2013 best-selling autobiography, which is still lingering in the world book charts, and will appear in a docu-film about her life later this year.
With her trademark forename, its clear she has well and truly cracked America and the nation keeps on falling for her over and over.
Shes not a pop or rockstar-cum-humanitarian  but with her humble dupatta casually draped over her head  she is instantly recognisable as Malala: the girl who, at 15, took a Taliban bullet to the head when she dared to stand up for girls education.
Armed with a life-story worthy of a Hollywood blockbuster, the 17-year-old Pakistani activist  and the youngest ever person to win the Nobel Peace Prize  has been in the US over the past week to spread the message which has taken the world by storm: books, not bullets.
Speaking loud, clear and confident, Malala to spoke to a 5,000-strong crowd in Denver , Colorado, on Wednesday evening and recalled that fateful day in October 2012 when the Taliban boarded her school bus in Pakistan.
Wearing a mask, she remembered, the gunman shouted: Which one of you is Malala? Speak up, otherwise I will shoot you all. When she valiantly and unwaveringly stood up and replied: I am Malala, the gunman shot her in the head and fled.
Malala was treated at Birmingham's Queen Elizabeth Hospital after she was shot by the Taliban in Pakistan in 2012
She told the Denver audience: I really believed I had two options [that day]: one was to remain silent and wait to be killed  or speak up and then be killed.
I chose the second one.
The day of the Charleston church shooting was the day Malala was to appear on The Daily Show with Jon Stewart to speak about her US trip and upcoming film, He Named Me Malala . Her words of comfort, and condolences, left an already subdued Stewart speechless.
Having already visited Congress in Capitol Hill On Tuesday, Malala urged lawmakers to invest more in education for young people, telling them: It is time that a bold and clear commitment is made by the United States to increase funding and support governments around the world to provide 12 years of free primary and secondary education for everyone by 2030.
A surprise visit en-route to the Denver speech took place when Malala visited inmates at the citys high-security Womens Correctional Facility where she encouraged the offenders to forgive and rehabilitate themselves and head down the path of learning.
Tonight, Malala is due to speak to a 4,000-strong crowd at San Jose State Universitys multi-million dollar arena, the Event Centre.
One young student at the university, 19-year-old Fatema Elbakoury, can barely contain her excitement ahead of the talk as she tells San Jose Mercury News the influence Malala has had on her life: I was raised Muslim in post-9/11 America and, at times, I doubted my own faith. But when Malala came into the picture, all of that changed for me.
The 17-year-old visited Kenya last June to 'empower girls through education'
Seeing how simultaneously liberated and devout she is taught me that Islam and feminism are not mutually exclusive.
Deepika Verma, 26, moved to San Jose from India and wouldnt miss hearing Malala speak at the Event Centre tonight: Because Im a girl and I belong to a family that thinks girls should not get educated  that they should be kept home and take care of the family  I fought for my education.
That's why I follow her. What she did is truly inspiring. Its my dream that I should help girls get an education in my town in India.
Shay Lari-Hosain admires Malala for telling President Obama last year that she disapproved of US drone strikes in Pakistan: Thats the voice of our generation thats telling people drone strikes shouldnt happen.
Malala is a huge force in combating the radicalisation and regressive conservatism thats gaining traction in Pakistan. Shes an inspiration to me and many others because she gives us hope that we can make a difference.
Izabel Cardoso, 12, who wants to change the world as we know it says: She defied the rules about what people say children can do.
'Thank you to my father for not clipping my wings and for letting me fly' - Malala shows her medal during the Nobel Peace Prize awards ceremony in Oslo last year
Its weird to think that someone so powerful  whos doing so much  is exactly your age, 17-year-old Sara Ashary, tells the site.
Here I am, sitting in math class, bored, and heres Malala speaking to all these really powerful people and not even breaking a sweat. Its crazy.
My family is Pakistani so, whenever we get positive news about Pakistan, its a really joyful occasion for us.
At tonights lecture  which will be hosted by the author of the best-selling novels The Kite Runner and A Thousand Splendid Suns  Khaled Hosseini will, no doubt, recall his visit to a Syrian refugee camp in Jordan last month  where he met a youngster dubbed the Syrian Malala.
I met a 16-year-old Syrian girl there named Muzoon who had met Malala when she visited the camp, Hosseini recalled.
This girl felt so inspired by Malala  and saw so much of herself in Malala  that she now goes around the camp from shelter to shelter and advocates education for girls. She speaks out against child labour and against early marriage.
In the middle of nowhere  in a remote part of the world  here was an example of just how inspiring Malala can be.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
