<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:44:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne rescues 593 migrants off coast of Libya</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/l%C3%A9-eithne-rescues-593-migrants-off-coast-of-libya-1.2265662</Link>
        <Description>Irish Naval Service vessel carries out six rescue operations in North African region    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
L Eithne rescues 593 migrants off coast of Libya
Irish Naval Service vessel carries out six rescue operations in North African region
Migrants picked up by L Eithne crew earlier this month. Photograph: L Eithne
Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 15:03
First published: Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 14:44
Some 593 people have been rescued from six vessels off the Libyan coast by the Irish ship L Eithne.
The Defence Forces said the rescue operations commenced at 4am Irish time when 101 migrants were taken from a rubber craft 50 nautical miles northwest of Tripoli.
It quickly proceeded to five more consecutive rescue operations, which were completed at 1pm on Sunday.
Total of 519 migrants rescued by L Eithne in latest operations
There were 496 men, 92 women and five children rescued and taken safely on board the ship, according to provisional figures.
A Defence Forces spokesman said the vessel was now awaiting direction from the Italian Maritime Rescue Co-Ordination Centre for its next tasking.
Eithne departed Naval Service headquarters in Haulbowline, Cork, on May 16th to assist the Italian authorities in the humanitarian search and rescue operations in the Mediterranean. Search and rescue operations began on May 28th.
The crew on the Irish ship has now rescued more than 2,700 people.
A Naval Service vessel will be deployed in the Mediterranean for a period of up to six months over the summer.
Earlier this month, vessels from Germany , Britain, Italy and other countries took on board some 3,000 people who had been crammed on to just five small boats in the Mediterranean.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:21:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Famous Irish soldier’s WW1 grave may hold different remains</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/famous-irish-soldier-s-ww1-grave-may-hold-different-remains-1.2265624</Link>
        <Description>Resting place of first World War ‘boy soldier’ outside Ypres debated by Belgian teacher    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Famous Irish soldiers WW1 grave may hold different remains
Resting place of first World War boy soldier outside Ypres debated by Belgian teacher
Aurel Sercu believes that the remains in John Condons grave in Poelcapelle cemetery belong to Irish-born rifleman Patrick Fitzsimmons. Photograph: Wernervc/Wikimedia Commons
Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 12:46
First published: Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 12:21
There is no first World War grave more visited or more controversial than that of the boy soldier from Waterford city Pte John Condon .
Condon was with the 2nd battalion of the Royal Irish Regiment when he was killed at Mouse Trap Farm near Ypres on May 24th, 1915.
His headstone states that he was 14 when he died. The Commonwealth War Graves Commission (CWGC) recognises Condon as the youngest British soldier to have died in the war.
New project hopes to find out how many Irishmen died in the first World War
His grave at Poelcapelle cemetery outside Ypres attracts coach loads of tourists usually schoolchildren. He has inspired novels, songs, poems and a play.
There is also a monument to his memory in his native Waterford unveiled last year and a service to mark the 100th anniversary of his death was held last month.
However, the documentary evidence suggests that John Condon was not 14 but 18 when he died. His birth certificate states that he was born on October 16th, 1896. He is listed in the 1901 census as being 4 and in 1911 as 14.
Retired Belgian schoolteacher Aurel Sercu has spent the last 13 years researching the short life of Condon and now maintains that he is not buried in grave LVI F8 in Poelcapelle cemetery.
Condons remains were only discovered eight years after he died. He was identified by a piece of boot which was stamped with the inscription 6322 4/RIR.
The battlefield clearance team assumed the RIR stood for the Royal Irish Regiment and 6322 was Condons service number.
Mr Sercu believes the boot belongs to another Irish-born soldier Rifleman Patrick Fitzsimmons from Raphael Street, Belfast. He was serving with the Royal Irish Rifles and was killed at 35 years of age on June 16th, 1915, three weeks after John Condon.
He too had the service number 6322. Fitzsimmons enlisted with the 4th battalion of the Royal Irish Rifles (RIR) so 6322 4/RIR would also match his service record.
Highly unusual
Condons remains were found 3km away from Mouse Trap Farm in Railway Wood. It would be highly unusual for the remains of an unidentified soldier to be found so far away from where he fell.
Significantly, the regimental diary for the Royal Irish Rifles reveals that on June 16th, 1915, it was stationed between Witte Poort Farm and railway. This is where the body that is in Condons grave was located in 1923.
In what became known as the Battle of Bellewaarde, the Royal Irish Rifles suffered more than 300 casualties in an assault on the German trenches which was met with a terrific artillery bombardment. Fitzsimmons died during this assault.
His remains were never identified and his name is on the New Menin Gate to the missing in Ypres.
It has taken Mr Sercu until now to track down relatives of the man he believes is buried in Condons grave. In the intervening years he wrote to every Fitzsimmons in the Belfast phone book without success until he finally tracked down a retired British soldier Kenneth Hanna based in Cheshire. He is Fitzsimmonss great-nephew.
One hundred years to the day after his relative died, Mr Hanna and his son Adrian visited both Railway Wood and Condons grave or as he believes the grave of their relative.
Clearly from the stamping identified and because of the regimental battle histories, it cannot possibly be John Condon, Mr Hanna says.
Im convinced those remains buried in John Condons grave are Patrick Fitzsimmonss.
The only way the issue can be definitively resolved is through an exhumation and DNA test, something Mr Hanna acknowledges would be very controversial and hurtful to the Condon family who are entirely blameless.
My honest feeling is that both soldiers gave their lives for the cause of freedom. That they are commemorated in error is a fact of history. To switch now would create a huge controversy.
Mr Sercu says he is satisfied that his research is correct, but the issue should go no further as neither DNA testing nor a change of headstones would be palatable after 92 years.
In other words leaving alone, at least as far as I am concerned, would be the best option, he said.
Too late
Sonny Condon , whose father Nicholas was John Condons cousin and best friend, says it is too late at this remove to know definitively the truth about so many aspects relating to the John Condon story.
Mistakes can be made, but my father said he was 14 and they were mates. Unfortunately, all the people who can answer these questions are gone. To me John Condon was a symbol of youth and the futility of war.
For its part the CWCG continues to hold the view that Condon was the youngest British soldier to die in the war.
Spokesman Peter Francis said if anybody wishes to raise the issue of the soldier buried in Condons grave they should submit their request to the Joint Casualty and Compassionate Centre, a unit of the British army, for investigation.
He stated that the army graves registration teams who did the battlefield clearances after the war did an incredibly difficult job and were rather expert at what they did. There were rather stringent guidelines. Some of those guidelines are still in place today.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:44:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Labour Party support falls in separate opinion polls </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/labour-party-support-falls-in-separate-opinion-polls-1.2265599</Link>
        <Description>While Fine Gael support is relatively steady, their coalition partner is under pressure    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Labour Party support falls in separate opinion polls
While Fine Gael support is relatively steady, their coalition partner is under pressure
Labour Party leader Joan Burton. Separate opinion polls have suggested a fall in support for her party.
Topics:
First published: Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 10:44
Labour Party support has shown a decline in separate political opinion polls published on Sunday.
According to a Millward Brown poll for the Sunday Independent, the Labour Party is on 6 per cent (a fall of 2 percentage points) while their coalition partners Fine Gael have gained four points to 29 per cent, when dont knows are excluded.
The Millward Brown poll was carried out between June 16th and 19th and the results are compared to a previous poll in April this year. The margin of error is 3.1 per cent.
Noel Whelan: Its the economy, stupid: why FG is on the up
The strength of the other parties was: Fianna Fail 23 per cent, a rise of 4 points; Sinn Fein on 21 per cent down 3 percentage points; The Labour Party on 6 per cent, the Green Party on 1 per cent, down 2 points, and Independents and Others unchanged on 20 per cent.
Within this grouping are the Socialist Party on 2 per cent, Renua Ireland on I per cent, and People Before Profit also on 1 per cent.
If the results were reflected in a general election result it suggests the current Coalition would struggle to be returned without a third party.
The monthly Red C tracking poll for The Sunday Business Post has Labour on 7 per cent, a fall of 3 points. Its poll suggests Fine Gael support is unchanged at 28 per cent, Sinn Fein down three points on 18 per cent and Fianna Fail up 1 point to 20 per cent.
The most significant gains were for Independents and others which showed a 5 point rise to 27 per cent.
This poll was conducted last Monday, Tuesday and Wednesday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Clocks to go back one leap second on Tuesday</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/science/clocks-to-go-back-one-leap-second-on-tuesday-1.2265536</Link>
        <Description>Move used by timekeepers to keep up with alteration in Earth’s spin is under debate   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Clocks to go back one leap second on Tuesday
Move used by timekeepers to keep up with alteration in Earths spin is under debate
Due to slowing down of Earths rotation the solar day is getting longer each year. To compensate timekeepers add a second to the year to make sure our atomic clocks are synchronised to to the solar day.
Fintan Burke
Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 11:15
First published: Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 10:00
On July 30th an extra second will be added to the days length, making this coming Tuesday 24 hours and one second long.
The move is often used by international timekeepers to keep up with tiny alterations to the Earths spin.
This represents only the 26th second that has been added since the practice began in 1972  however, it may also be the last.
Daylight saving time: why do the clocks change?
It has been known for some time that the Earths rotation is gradually slowing down. Because of this, the natural or solar day is getting longer each year. To compensate for this, official timekeepers need to add a second to days to make sure our atomic clocks  the most accurate measurements of time humanity has  are synchronised to this solar day.
If we did not use leap seconds our atomic clocks would become two minutes fast by 2100, according to the UKs National Measurement Office.
Although the addition of the extra second will be insignificant to many, the previous leap second in June 2012 wreaked havoc online; popular websites such as Reddit and LinkedIn slowed to a halt.
In an echo of the Y2K fears of the late 1990s, Australian airline Qantas had to switch to manual bookings after its online system failed entirely.
Delay
Since this years leap second will occur on a work day, there are now concerns that computerised micro-transactions worth millions may be lost in the international stock market as countries experience the delay at different points.
Because of these complications, official timekeepers the world over have suggested abandoning the idea of leap seconds entirely.
Announcements opposing leap seconds were made by China , Australia , Japan , and South Korea at a special meeting of the Asia-Pacific Telecommunity earlier this year.
However, a UK-based roundtable found last year that more than 60 per cent of the British public supported keeping the extra second, arguing that various social and cultural issues would be affected, as well as arguing that computer scientists could easily come up with a solution.
Some companies such as Amazon and Google choose to spread the extra second over the course of a day to prevent any such problems.
For the moment leap seconds will continue to be added when needed until at least 2020. Nonetheless the international community will debate whether to keep our notion of a solar day  which includes leap seconds  as the official day at a special conference in November.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:23:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man critically injured in Dublin city centre stabbing  </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/man-critically-injured-in-dublin-city-centre-stabbing-1.2265591</Link>
        <Description>Victim  being treated for facial injuries at St James’s Hospital after attack in Temple Bar    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Man critically injured in Dublin city centre stabbing
Victim  being treated for facial injuries at St Jamess Hospital after attack in Temple Bar
Garda are investigating a stabbing in Temple Bar in Dublin on Saturday night.
Topics:
Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 09:46
First published: Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 08:23
A man in his early thirties has been seriously injured in a stabbing in Dublin city centre on Saturday night.
The stabbing happened at 7.30pm on Cope St in the Temple Bar area.
The man was taken to St Jamess Hospital for treatment to facial injuries after he was stabbed multiple times.
His condition is described as critical.
No one has been arrested in connection with the incident.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 20:43:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dublin explodes with colour as thousands come out for Pride</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/dublin-explodes-with-colour-as-thousands-come-out-for-pride-1.2265550</Link>
        <Description>Organisers say 2015 parade twice as big in wake of same-sex marriage referendum   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Dublin explodes with colour as thousands come out for Pride
Organisers say 2015 parade twice as big in wake of same-sex marriage referendum
Upwards of 50,000 people walked, shimmied and disco-danced their way through Dublin today for Gay Pride. Organisers say the 2015 parade was twice as big in the wake of the same-sex marriage referendum.
A couple takes part in the annual Gay Pride Parade in Dublin. Photograph: Getty
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 18:47
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 18:43
OConnell Street, host to numerous protests against austerity and water charges in recent months, gave way to unbridled joy on Saturday as upwards of 50,000 people paraded for Gay Pride.
People of all ages and from across the world  with even a few from Roscommon-South Leitrim  walked, shimmied and disco-danced their way along the route from Parnell Square to Merrion Square.
Dublin city centre was a blaze of Pride hours before the parades start time of 1.30pm with people flying rainbow flags, wrapping rainbow flags around themselves and garlanding each other with multi-coloured flower leis. For today at least, Dublin was to be the capital-of-love.
Many were there in fancy-dress and drag  as golden angels, toreadors, flamenco dancers, Batman, priests and one man who was dressed as Robin was heard to say: Hes had a much-maligned life living under the shadow of Batman.
Senator David Norris described the atmosphere as absolutely wonderful.
The crowds on OConnell St were the biggest hed ever seen at the event, he said with the Yes vote in the marriage equality referendum last month bringing thousands out to celebrate.
It feels like everyone is gay in Dublin today. I think it becoming too fashionable, he joked. In fact I think Ill surprise everyone and come out as straight.
Patricia and Kevin, a couple in their 50s from Bray, Co Wicklow, said they had never been on a Gay Pride march before but they were there: because we have a son and were proud of him. He was a DJ and was somewhere nearby setting up for a party.
Jose Montilla, from Venezuela was there with his boyfriend, Kristof Baraniecki, from Poland. The parade was amazing said Mr Baraniecki. This country is much better gay-wise than Poland. Its much more comfortable.
Niamh McDonald from Wicklow said she was there for equality adding We need a bit of this in Ireland, a bit of joy but added: Theres still a way to go on tackling transphobia.
Heading up the parade were the main LGBTI representative groups  the Gay Lesbian Equality Network, LGBT Noise, the youth group BelongTo, Transgender Equality Network Ireland and the champions of the referendum, Marriage Equality. Also there was the Irish Council for Civil Liberties.
Numerous workers paraded behind their employers banners with the IT industry there in force. Banners from Linkedin, Yahoo, Airbnb, Yelp, Ebay, Dropbox, Paypal, Microsoft and Facebook were there as were Citibank, Mastercard, Bank Of Ireland and restaurant-chain Nandos was represented with a banner saying Worth coming out for.
All political parties were represented including Fianna Fil, Sinn Fin, the Anti-Austerity Alliance, People Before Profit and the Socialist Workers Party.
Tnaiste Joan Burton and Minister for Equality Aodhn  Riordin among those behind the Labour banner while TDs Regina Doherty, Derek Keating, Jerry Buttimer , Minister for Transport Pascal Donohoe ,Minister for Health Leo Varadkar and Minister for Children James Reilly were among those behind a Fine Gael banner saying Thank you for voting Yes.
University student unions, as well as youth organisations like Scouting Ireland were represented.
Perhaps the largest single contingent of young people danced and paraded behind a float representing the George pub.
By the time the parade reached its destination its tail was just leaving Parnell Square.
Grinne Healy of Marriage Equality told The Irish Times the parade had been massive and double the size of last year.
Its fabulous. Something perhaps were not so good at is to stop and celebrate what we have achieved. Today is a celebration of what so many people have worked over a decade to achieve  marriage equality.
There is more to do. The two key things for me are to get the gender recognition legislation through and then to get rid of Section 37 of the Employment Equality Act. The next equality issues are reproductive rights and income inequality.
I think there is a sense of hope that we can say Yes to these other issues too now. But today is about celebrating, and Dublin looked great today.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:55:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man arrested after bomb discovered in west Belfast</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/man-arrested-after-bomb-discovered-in-west-belfast-1.2265544</Link>
        <Description>Device found by police during planned search of house in Lenadoon Avenue   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Man arrested after bomb discovered in west Belfast
Device found by police during planned search of house in Lenadoon Avenue
The man is at Antrim police station for questioning. File photograph: Trevor McBride
Amanda Ferguson
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 17:55
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 17:55
A man is being questioned by police following the discovery of a bomb at a house in west Belfast on Friday night.
An improvised explosive device was found during a planned search of a house in Lenadoon Avenue at around 8pm on Friday, police have said.
A number of people were moved from their homes while army bomb officers made the device safe.
Det Insp Stuart Griffin of PSNI Serious Crime Branch said: This planned search was carried out at premises in Lenadoon Avenue around 8pm.
Members of the community had to be moved from their homes while the search was carried out. I would like to thank the community for their patience and understanding during the operation.
One man was arrested. He is at Antrim police station for questioning.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:18:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beaumont ‘may face charges’ over closure of transplant programme</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/health/beaumont-may-face-charges-over-closure-of-transplant-programme-1.2265528</Link>
        <Description> Patients suffering due to lack of pancreas transplants at hospital, says  David Hickey   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Beaumont may face charges over closure of transplant programme
Patients suffering due to lack of pancreas transplants at hospital, says  David Hickey
Retired surgeon David Hickey at the Beaumont Hospital pancreas transplant unit. Since his retirement the unit has closed and no transplants have been performed. File photograph: Aidan Crawley
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 17:20
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 17:18
Beaumont Hospital and the Health Service Executive could find themselves facing corporate manslaughter charges over the closure of the pancreas transplant programme in the hospital, a meeting of patients has been told.
Patients on the waiting list for a transplant are dying because of the failure of the hospital to carry out any pancreas transplants since the beginning of this year, according to retired surgeon David Hickey .
Mr Hickey performed all 118 pancreas transplants done so far in Ireland but this work has ceased since his retirement and Beaumont says it will be transferred to St Vincents Hospital.
Concern after Beaumont post-transplant clinic closes
In addition, the hospital has told post-transplant patients, who are at high risk of infection, they must go to overcrowded emergency departments for urgent care following the decision to close a specialised outpatient clinic.
With the closure of the clinic, more than 80 patients have been told to go to local hospitals for regular care, but they fear this service will be inferior to that provided in Beaumont.
More than 50 people attended the meeting in Liberty Hall, which was organised by three patients who have had transplants.
In limbo
Fiona Burke , a double transplant recipient from Annaghdown, Co Galway, said Beaumont had left patients in limbo though its actions.
Ms Burke said she hadnt looked back a single day since receiving new kidneys and a pancreas transplanted by Mr Hickey. She got married in 2002 and later gave birth to a boy, Jake, who is now a six-year-old and full of life.
Everything was going well until last Friday, when I was told the outpatient clinic in Beaumont was closing and I should access services in Galway. We had a wonderful team in Beaumont but this was like a loss in the family. We have to fight to get it back, she told the meeting.
A couple of managers in Beaumont flicked a switch, ticked a box and saved the hospital a few hundred thousand euro a year, Mr Hickey commented.
Mark Murphy , chief executive of the Irish Kidney Association (IKA), said he had never seen a group of patients being let go by a hospital as transplant patients had been since January.
Youve been thrown to the wolves, he told the meeting.
Mr Murphy expressed doubt about official figures indicating there are just 11 patients on the waiting list for a transplant, eight for a kidney/pancreas and three for a pancreas alone.
Mr Hickey said transplant patients in Beaumont were treated in a Portacabin, with a view of a toilet through the window. Amnesty International would have it closed down as a prison if it could, he said.
Beaumont declined an invitation to attend the meeting, saying direct communication with transplant patients and engagement with their representative body, the Irish Kidney Association, was the most appropriate way to deal with the issues.
Critical
A number of speakers at the meeting were critical of the association for not advocating more strongly on the issue.
There has been nothing from the IKA other than woolly comments, said Mr Hickey, who said it needed to give the hospital a kick in the boll***s and stop being nice.
Mr Hickey accused the hospital of waiting for years and years until he left to close down the pancreas transplant programme. He accused middle managers of hijacking the health system and grinding it into the ground.
Beaumont says it has agreed with St Vincents to develop a collaborative approach to pancreas transplants.
This will begin with joint assessment clinics in Beaumont at the end of July.
The hospital was unable to say when pancreas transplants will resume.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 17:05:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heatwave to follow weekend of dry spells and showers </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/environment/heatwave-to-follow-weekend-of-dry-spells-and-showers-1.2265502</Link>
        <Description>Temperatures in mid-20s expected next week after weather clears on Sunday   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Heatwave to follow weekend of dry spells and showers
Temperatures in mid-20s expected next week after weather clears on Sunday
The real warm weather from the south is due to arrive on Wednesday, bringing serious heat for the first time this summer. Photograph: Bryan OBrien/The Irish Times
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 17:03
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 15:05
There may be a heatwave on the way but we will have to wait to break out the sunscreen.
Temperatures over the weekend will be similar to the past week according to Met ireann , with bright and mostly dry weather that will become cloudy on Saturday afternoon.
Rainfall will spread across the country on Saturday night, including some heavy falls in the south and east. However, it will clear on Sunday morning, bringing slightly fresher temperatures of 16-20 degrees.
Weather: check the 5-day forecast in your area, tides and weather warnings
Monday will be a hazy day with temperatures of 18-20 degrees. It will get warmer on Tuesday, reaching highs of 22 degrees.
The real warm weather is due to arrive on Wednesday, bringing temperatures between 20-25 degrees across Ireland , according to the forecaster.
Forecaster Klara Finkele says the warmer weather will rise up from the Bay of Biscay on Wednesday and Thursday.
However, she warns that high levels of humidity will bring a risk of thunderstorms and heavy downpours.
Weather from the Bay of Biscay tends to be quite unstable, its warm and very moisture laden so were certainly going to keep an eye on the rain, said Ms Finkele.
Warm air holds more humidity and moisture so it can lead to heavy downpours.
The UK is also set to enjoy next weeks warm weather, with a Spanish plume of hot air moving north, bringing temperatures up into the early 30s.
France , Italy and Spain have been experiencing particularly hot weather in recent days, with parts of southern Europe on track to break records for June temperatures, according to the Weather Channel.
How to protect your skin from the sun
The Irish Cancer Society has warned people to take care in the sunshine, particularly the elderly and young children.
Parents are advised to dress babies under six months in loose-fitting clothes with long sleeves and to keep them in the shade as much as possible.
Children should wear hats and sun glasses in the sunshine and use sunscreen with SPF 30 or higher. Sunscreen should be reapplied every two hours.
Adults are also advised to spend time in the shade, wear a hat and sunglasses, and to use sunscreen with SPF 15 or higher.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:53:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>€3.5m Kerry Gaeltacht enterprise centre opened</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/3-5m-kerry-gaeltacht-enterprise-centre-opened-1.2265489</Link>
        <Description>Over 2,500 students to attend courses at centre worth €7 million to local economy   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
3.5m Kerry Gaeltacht enterprise centre opened
Over 2,500 students to attend courses at centre worth 7 million to local economy
Nell N Sh, Caoimhe N Dhubhain, Orla N Dhubhain and Marta N Loinsigh welcoming guests to the official opening of the new 3.5 million Irish language and enterprise development centre. Photograph: Don MacMonagle
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 14:05
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 13:53
A new Irish language and enterprise development centre in the Kerry Gaeltacht is expected to boost the local economy to the tune of 7m.
Located in Baile an Fheirtaraigh in the heart of the Corca Dhuibhne Gaeltacht, the 3.5m Lrionad Forbartha Gaeilge agus Gaeltachta will provide a range of Irish language-based activities and courses as well as pre-school and family support services.
Courses held in the centre are expected to attract over 2,500 students this year alone.
Stark warning for future of Irish in Gaeltacht areas
Co-funded by dars na Gaeltachta , the Department of Arts, Heritage and Gaeltacht and Comharchumann Forbartha Chorca Dhuibhne, the centre will also support both new and existing business.
Opening the centre on Friday, Minister of State, Jimmy Deenihan said he was pleased that such a significant investment has been made in the area.
Since it was founded, the Comharchumann has been organising activities through Irish, said Minister Deenihan, and this new centre is a significant accomplishment by the Comharchumann, the local community and dars na Gaeltachta, and will assist in further developing and promoting these activities.
Toms Mac Gearailt, the Chairperson of Comharchumann Forbartha Chorca Dhuibhne, said the Comharchumann is extremely proud of this development centre.
The Lrionad will ensure that there is a permanent facility available in the area that will benefit the community, support the maintenance of the Irish language and provide employment for generations to come, he said.
He said that 2,500 students will attend courses in the Lrionad this year, and that these courses will be worth 7 million to the Corca Dhuibhne economy.
Chief Executive of dars na Gaeltachta Steve  Clin said the centre would help increase employment with the development of local business.
Modern enterprise facilities are required in the area and this development now ensures that the business development needs of Corca Dhuibhne are catered for and will help attract more employment to the area.
Mr  Clin said Comharchumann had pioneered Irish language activities in the area and that the new centre would strengthen this work.
The Lrionad will act as the supportive backbone to reinforce Irish as a community language in the area and offer a language haven for native speakers and learners alike for years to come.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 13:03:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> Flanagan confirms three Irish deaths in Tunisia attacks  </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/flanagan-confirms-three-irish-deaths-in-tunisia-attacks-1.2265460</Link>
        <Description>Relatives of Co Westmeath couple Laurence and Martina Hayes contacted by officials    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Flanagan confirms three Irish deaths in Tunisia attacks
Relatives of Co Westmeath couple Laurence and Martina Hayes contacted by officials
Images
A German tourist recounts the moment a gunman began firing on beachgoers in an attack that killed at least 38 people. Video: Reuters
Tourists pray beside flowers placed in tribute to the people killed in a terror attack on a beach in front of the imperial Marhaba Hotel in Sousse,Tunisia, on Sunday. Photograph: EPA
Lorna Carty, from Co Meath, who was killed in a terrorist attack at a resort in Tunisia.
Tourists leave Tunisia at the Enfidha International airport on Saturday  in the aftermath of a shooting attack in which 38 people were killed. Photograph: Getty
An undated image made available on Twitter by the Tunisian branch of the Islamic State (IS) group on Saturday, reportedly shows the alleged gunman. The IS group identified the man by the nom de guerre of Abu Yahya al-Qayrawani and Tunisian security forces idenfied him as     Tunisian student Seifeddine Rezgui. Photograph: AFP
Tourists lay flowers in tribute to the people killed in a terror attack on a beach in front of the imperial Marhaba Hotel in al-Sousse. Photograph: EPA
Passengers thought to be British leave the Imperial Marhaba Hotel. Photograph: Getty
People gather for a candle light rally in solidarity with the victims of a deadly attack on the Imperial Marhabada hotel. Photograph: EPA
A screengrab from Sky News showing  Seifeddine Rezgui on the beach ear the Imperial Marhabada hotel with a gun shortly before the attack in which 39 people were killed. Photograph: Sky News
Previous Image
Sun, Jun 28, 2015, 15:06
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 11:03
Irish tourists intending to travel to Tunisia over the coming weeks should exercise extreme caution, the Minister for Foreign Affairs has said.
Charlie Flanagan issued the warning has he confirmed that three Irish citizens died in Fridays terror attack. Mr Flanagan said he had been in contact with their families over recent days.
Laurence and Martina Hayes, a couple in their 50s from Athlone, Co Westmeath and Lorna Carty from Robinstown , Co Meath, were killed in the attack on Sousse.
Sincere sympathy to the Hayes family Athlone who suffered their tragic losses in the terror shooting in Tunisia.
Islamic State suicide bomber kills 25 in Kuwait mosque
The Minister said he did not believe any further Irish people were injured in the incident and he urged those planning to travel to the region to be extremely vigilant and extreme caution.
He told RTEs This Week programme: I would urge those there to continue to liaise with tour operators on the ground and with the consular assistance from Foreign Affairs.
My travel advice for Tunisia is to exercise extreme caution. Anyone wishing to visit the region, anyone with holiday plans over the next few days or weeks I wish to acknowledge the Tunisian authorities have declared the incident to be over but nevertheless I would urge Irish citizens heading there and those in Tunisia to remain extremely vigilant, to follow instructions given to them by the police, the tour operators, the hotels.
Mr Flanagan said he was not in the business of imposing travel bans but his advice for anyone travelling there was to exercise extreme caution.
Relatives of Laurence and Martina Hayes have been contacted by Irish officials, a Department of Foreign Affairs spokeswoman said. The department has set up an information line for those affected by the attack: 00353 1 408 2000.
Westmeath Gaelic Athletic Association (GAA) has tweeted a message of condolence to the family. Sincere sympathy to the Hayes family Athlone who suffered their tragic losses in the terror shooting in Tunisia, it said.
The Irish ambassador accredited to Tunisia, David Cooney, is working with Irish citizens still in the country.
Ms Carty, a nurse and mother of two adult children, had travelled to Tunisia with her husband Declan, a well-known dairy farmer.
The couple received the Tunisian holiday as a gift from a relative as Mr Carty was recovering from heart surgery.
Their daughter Hazel (18) had just completed her Leaving Cert and is believed to have been notified of her mothers death while on holiday in Turkey .
Their son Simon (21), a science student at UCD, was at home in Robinstown. The authorities are gradually identifying those killed in the attack.
One of the British victims has been named as Adrian Evans, who worked for Sandwell Council in the West Midlands . Joel Richards, reported to be Mr Evanss nephew, was also named as a victim.
It is understood Mr Richards was a student at the University of Worcester.
Birmingham-based Gaelic football club James Connollys GFC also paid tribute to Mr Richards, tweeting that the club was devastated to learn of his death.
They said he was an exceptionally-talented footballer who represented both club and county with conviction on numerous occasions. Mr Richardss 16-year-old brother Owen is reported to have survived the attack.
The attack has seen thousands of tourists rush to leave Tunisia. An Aer Lingus flight from Monastir arrived in Dublin last night and other Irish holidaymakers in the country are expected to cut short their holiday and return home. It is unclear how many Irish nationals were in Tunisia at the time of the attack.
Sunway managing director Tanya Airey has offered her sincere condolences to all Irish nationals affected by the attack. The Irish tour operator provides holidays to Tunisia.
The company flies weekly on Fridays to Tunisia. She said a number of Irish Sunway holidaymakers had decided over the weekend to remain in Tunisia.
The tour operator is expected to make a call this week on whether to allow those booked to depart on Friday to travel to Tunisia.
In a tweet she noted that the department advises extreme caution but has not issued a do not travel notice.
Irish citizens returning on Friday night told RT of the chaos during the attack, describing a large explosion and gunfire. Many praised the staff for the assistance they gave guests.
Six nationalities are among the 39 dead.
They are thought to have been killed by a 23-year-old Tunisian aviation student Seifeddine Rezgui who disguised himself as a tourist and began firing at holidaymakers on a beach using a Kalashnikov hidden in a beach umbrella. Islamic State has claimed responsibility for the attack.
Fifteen of the dead are from Britain.
Confirming the figure, British foreign minister Tobias Ellwood said the Sousse atrocity was the most significant terrorist attack on British people since July 7th, 2005, when 52 people were killed.
Speaking at the Foreign Office, Mr Ellwood said: Sadly, I can confirm that at least 15 British nationals were killed in yesterdays atrocity but I should stress that the number may well rise as several more have been seriously injured in this horrific attack.
Additional reporting agencies
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 12:46:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘It feels like everyone is gay in Dublin today’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/it-feels-like-everyone-is-gay-in-dublin-today-1.2265458</Link>
        <Description>Thousands  celebrate Gay Pride  just weeks after Ireland voted for same-sex marriage   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
It feels like everyone is gay in Dublin today
Thousands  celebrate Gay Pride  just weeks after Ireland voted for same-sex marriage
The parade started at the Garden of Remembrance, Parnell Square, at 1.30pm, before heading down OConnell St, crossing the Liffey and then culminating at the specially constructed Pride Village at Merrion Square. Photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Previous Image
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 10:46
Thousands have taken to the streets of Dublin to celebrate the annual Dublin LGBTQ Pride Parade.
Rainbow flags and balloons were in evidence as dancers in colourful costumes joined marchers along the route against the background sound of whistles and music.
Senator David Norris described the atmosphere as absolutely wonderful. He said the crowds on OConnell St were the biggest hes ever seen at the event.
Same-sex vote shows Irelands pioneering leadership - Kenny
The result of the same-sex marriage referendum along with yesterdays decision by the US Supreme Court to give same-sex couples the right to marry has added to the sense of celebration.
Senator Norris said: We led the way on gay marriage, adding that it was wonderful to see the [US]Supreme Court ruling yesterday.
It feels like everyone is gay in Dublin today, he said.
I think its becoming too fashionable, he joked, before adding:  I think Ill come out as straight!
A number of other politicians were also in attendance including Tnaiste Joan Burton, Minister Alex White, Sinn Fins Gerry Adams , Lynn Boylan , Mary Lou McDonald and former Fianna Fil Senator Averil Power.
Along with the citizens of Dublin, staff from Ebay, Facebook , Paypal , the Irish Red Cross and the Bank of Ireland carried colourful banners and balloons.
A Facebook banner read: Equality rocks, thank you Ireland.
Recently featured in the Lonely Planet guide to the best gay pride celebrations in the world, the Dublin LGBTQ Pride Parade is expected to attract record crowds some 32 years after it was first held.
The parade started at the Garden of Remembrance, Parnell Square, at 1.30pm, before heading down OConnell St, crossing the Liffey and then culminating at the specially constructed Pride Village at Merrion Square.
Ongoing works on the Luas line meant the parade could not cross the river at OConnell Bridge this year but instead it turned left on to Eden Quay before crossing the Liffey at the Talbot Memorial Bridge.
Grand Marshals Grinne Healy, Mark Kelly and Brian Sheehan , will address the crowd at the Pride Village.
Participants will be entertained by Le Galaxie, Jerry Fish , ELM, MC Panti Bliss and Veda. A community zone, family area and costumes will also be on hand.
Dublin Pride has grown from a single-day event first held in 1983 to a week-long celebration featuring art exhibitions, music and other cultural events.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 11:45:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teenager dies after being hit by car in Finglas</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/teenager-dies-after-being-hit-by-car-in-finglas-1.2265449</Link>
        <Description>Gardaí investigate incident in Dublin in which pedestrian suffered fatal injuries   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Teenager dies after being hit by car in Finglas
Garda investigate incident in Dublin in which pedestrian suffered fatal injuries
Garda are appealing for information after a 16-year-old died at the Mater hospital in Dublin after being seriously injured in a road traffic incident in Finglas. File photograph: Frank Miller/The Irish Times
Topics:
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 09:45
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 09:45
Garda in Finglas are investigating a fatal incident in which a teenager was hit by a car close to the junction of Tolka Valley Road and St Helenas Road, Finglas, Dublin 11, at approximately 11.30pm on Friday.
A pedestrian (16) was seriously injured and he was taken to the Mater hospital but was pronounced dead early on Saturday. The driver and passenger were both uninjured.
The road was closed to facilitate a Garda forensic collision examination but has since reopened.
Garda are appealing for witnesses to this incident to contact them at Finglas Garda Station on 01-6667500, the Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda Station.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 10:25:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Finucane family pledge to continue campaigning for public inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/finucane-family-pledge-to-continue-campaigning-for-public-inquiry-1.2265437</Link>
        <Description>Court rules British prime minister had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Finucane family pledge to continue campaigning for public inquiry
Court rules British prime minister had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry
John Finucane, son of Pat Finucane speaking with media outside Belfasts High Court. Photograph: Liam McBurney/PA Wire
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 08:25
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 08:25
The Finucane family has pledged to continue campaigning for a public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane , despite failing in a judicial review seeking to compel the British prime minister to hold such an investigation.
Lord Justice Stephens at Belfast High Court upheld the right of David Cameron to refuse a full-scale public inquiry into the 1989 UDA killing of the Belfast solicitor, notwithstanding that such a commitment was given under the British Labour government following the 2001 Weston Park peace process talks in England.
He dismissed the application except in relation to a continuing procedural obligation on the state to investigate the murder. Rather than an inquiry, Mr Cameron commissioned a review of the murder case by British lawyer Sir Desmond de Silva QC.
De Silva report
In his 500-page report, Mr de Silva said there was a significant doubt as to whether Mr Finucane would have been murdered in front of his family at their north Belfast home had it not been for the different strands of involvement by elements of the British state.
He found that a series of positive actions by employees of the British state actively furthered and facilitated his murder and there was a relentless effort to defeat the ends of justice in the aftermath of his killing.
My review of the evidence relating to Patrick Finucanes case has left me in no doubt that agents of the State were involved in carrying out serious violations of human rights up to and including murder, he reported.
This, however, failed to satisfy the Finucane family, with the solicitors widow Geraldine describing the report as a sham and a whitewash.
Direct evidence
In his judgment, which took two hours and five minutes to read, Lord Justice Stephens rejected the sham claim and that there was no direct evidence of a closed mind on the part of the UK government.

He referred to how inquiries into the killings of Billy Wright , Rosemary Nelson and Robert Hamill and into Bloody Sunday cost 304 million. He found that a full independent inquiry would be costly, protracted and could not be confined to narrow issues surrounding the murder.
The judge also found that the British government had not met its obligations to conduct a prompt investigation of new evidence into Mr Finucanes murder uncovered by the de Silva report. He invited lawyers for the Finucane family and the British government back to court on Tuesday to further discuss this element of his ruling.
The judicial review was taken by Geraldine Finucane , who did not attend the reading of the judgment. Solicitor John Finucane , a son of Mr Finucane, attended the hearing with his sister Katherine and his two uncles Seamus and Martin.
John Finucane said the family would press ahead with their campaign. He said politically there should be a public inquiry while legally they would attend Tuesdays hearing and consider what to do next. This could involve appealing yesterdays ruling, he said.
We have been on a campaign for 26 years. We have had numerous setbacks, numerous successes along that way. We see today not as a setback which would end our campaign once and for all, he said outside the court.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 08:44:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bodies of Séamus Wright and Kevin McKee believed found</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/bodies-of-s%C3%A9amus-wright-and-kevin-mckee-believed-found-1.2265431</Link>
        <Description>Families of men present as remains removed almost 45 years after disappearance    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Bodies of Samus Wright and Kevin McKee believed found
Families of men present as remains removed almost 45 years after disappearance
Members of the Wright and McKee famies and  members of the Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains at  Coghalstown, Co Meath.  Photograph: Alan Betson
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 08:10
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 06:44
Almost 43 years after Samus Wright and Kevin McKee were abducted by the IRA, two hearses crossed a field at Coghalstown, Co Meath, on Friday to collect what is believed to be their remains from an unmarked grave.
The hearses had held off, parked in the grounds of the Wilkinstown Community Centre nearby, until the families of the two men had arrived to pay their respects.
A small group comprising local priest Fr John OBrien, Geoff Knupfer and staff of the Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains, stood with the families as the remains were placed in coffins.
The Bosnia-based group that names the nameless
They then walked slowly behind the hearses as they travelled back across the field to an impromptu car park near a cattle shed.
The families later released a joint statement saying they hoped they could at last see an end to the torment that has lasted over 40 years and bring Samus and Kevin home. They added: We want to thank the Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains and whoever provided information to the ICLVR.
Without that information this would never have happened. While this will change the lives of our families our thoughts are with the Lynskey family and all those who still wait for the news that their loved ones have been found. We pray for them.
Both families asked for privacy. Wright and McKee both disappeared in Belfast on October 2nd, 1972. It is widely believed they were taken and interrogated by the IRA for a period of weeks before being killed by an IRA killing squad called the unknowns.
Wright, who was aged 25, was an asphalt worker and was married. McKee, who was 17, was also from Belfast.
Postmortem
Mr Knupfer said the remains would be taken to Dublin where a postmortem would be carried out, most likely on Monday. Following this DNA samples would be taken from the remains to confirm what the commission already thought very likely.
The commission has been stripping away topsoil from a six hectare area of the reclaimed bog at Coghalstown, about 10km north of Navan, since March.
Earlier this week, the commission was looking for the body of former Cistercian monkJoe Lynskey when they discovered the remains believed to be Wright and McKee.
Mr Knupfer said the commission organised its digs on the basis of intelligence received and did not dig on a speculative basis. He said the search for the remains of Lynskey would continue in coming weeks.
The Lynskey family said in a statement said they were grateful to the commission and to those who had engaged with it in the search.
Sinn Fin president Gerry Adams welcomed news that remains had been discovered.
The uncertainty over who has been recovered must be hugely traumatic for the families involved.
I am sure that the commission will move as speedily as it can to verify the identity of those who have been found, he said.
Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald said she hopes the suffering of at least some of the families will now be eased.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 08:41:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Who are the Disappeared?</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/who-are-the-disappeared-1.2265430</Link>
        <Description>Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains lists 16 people who had ‘disappeared’ before the Belfast Agreement   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Who are the Disappeared?
Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains lists 16 people who had disappeared before the Belfast Agreement
Undated handout photo of Jean McConville (left) with three of her children.
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 06:46
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 06:41
Samus Wright (25) and Kevin McKee (17) were from Belfast and went missing on October 2nd, 1972. Remains discovered at Coghalstown, Co Meath, on Thursday are believed to be theirs.
Joe Lynskey from Belfast was 45 when he went missing during the summer of 1972. His remains have yet to be located.
Jean McConville (37) was a widowed mother of 10 who was abducted and killed in December 1972. Her remains were found at Shelling Hill beach, Co Louth, in August 2003.
The Bosnia-based group that names the nameless
Peter Wilson (21) disappeared from his home in west Belfast in August 1973. His remains were found at Waterfoot beach, Co Antrim, in November 2010.
Eamon Molloy (21) was abducted from his home in Belfast in July 1975. His body was discovered in a coffin in a cemetery near Dundalk in 1999.
Captain Robert Nairac (29) of the Grenadier Guards was abducted in Co Antrim in May 1977 and killed. His remains have yet to be recovered.
Brendan Megraw (23) from west Belfast was abducted from his home in April 1978. His remains were recovered in October 2014 in Oristown, Co Meath.
John McClory (18) and Brian McKinney (22) were from west Belfast and were abducted and killed in May 1978. Their remains were discovered in bogland at Colgagh, Iniskeen, Co Monaghan, in 1999.
Gerry Evans (24) from Crossmaglen, Co Armagh, disappeared in March 1979. His remains were recovered from a site in Carrickrobin, Co Louth, in October 2010.
Danny McIlhone (19) from west Belfast went missing in July 1981. His remains were recovered in bogland near the Blessington Lakes in Co Wicklow in 2008.
Charlie Armstrong (54) from Crossmaglen in Co Armagh was abducted and killed in August 1981. His remains were recovered in July 2010 in Co Monaghan.
Eugene Simons (26) disappeared on New Years Day 1981. His body was found on May 24th, 1984 in a bog in Knockbridge, Dundalk, Co Louth.
Seamus Ruddy (33), from Newry, disappeared in May 1985. His remains have not yet been recovered.
Columba McVeigh (19) from Donaghmore, Co Tyrone, was abducted and killed in October 1975. His remains have yet to be recovered.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Remember violence. Don’t glorify it</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/remember-violence-don-t-glorify-it-1.2264207</Link>
        <Description>We must seize the centenary of the Easter Rising and the Battle of the Somme as a chance to transform conflict on the island of Ireland    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Remember violence. Dont glorify it
We must seize the centenary of the Easter Rising and the Battle of the Somme as a chance to transform conflict on the island of Ireland
Over the top: soldiers on the first day of Battle of the Somme, in July 1916, which for some is a key foundational moment in the creation of Northern Ireland. Photograph: Art Archive/Imperial War Museum/Getty
Revolutionary aim: Irish Citizen Army soldiers on the roof of Liberty Hall in Dublin just after the 1916 Rising, for many a key moment in securing the independence of Ireland and the eventual establishment of a republic. Photograph: Robert Hunt/Windmill Books/UIG via Getty
Previous Image
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 02:00

The people of Ireland, north and south, are in an enviable position on the eve of the centenary of 1916. We have the opportunity to end a century of violence, enmity and misunderstanding between us for good. Much has been achieved, but much remains to be done.
Diversity and difference are increasingly seen as positives  note last months marriage-equality referendum in the Republic  but our traditional differences of green and orange still generate fear and division for many. Political and sectarian violence has, thankfully, largely stopped, but have we created the conditions in which they will never be tolerated again? Not yet.
How we remember and publicly commemorate the past is an important element in our ongoing peacebuilding efforts.
There is much to remember in this decade of centenaries, but 1916, the year in which both the Easter Rising and the first World Wars Battle of the Somme took place, is particularly important.
For many the Easter Rising is a key moment in securing the independence of Ireland and the eventual establishment of a separate republic. For others the Battle of the Somme is a key foundational moment in the creation of Northern Ireland.
These two narratives are contested and in many ways symbolise the deep, traditional divisions on this island. For that reason we must seize the centenary of these two events as an opportunity to transform violent conflict and build peace.
Today the Glencree Centre for Peace and Reconciliation , in Co Wicklow, is hosting 1916 and the Ethics of Memory  an event at which President Michael D Higgins will be the opening speaker  to consider how it is most appropriate to remember the year 1916. There will be a wide range of participants from diverse backgrounds and political viewpoints from across the island.
Peacebuilding
Although Glencrees primary role is to provide a space where differing views can be exchanged, we need to consider some key issues. There are also important reasons why the way we remember the past is important for peacebuilding.
One is that acts of remembering, such as Queen Elizabeth bowing her head in the Garden of Remembrance in Dublin on May 17th, 2011, have the power to be transformative.
This was a moment when most Irish people were deeply impressed by a simple act of respect and openness to their history by the queen  an act that, at a stroke, led to a striking improvement in relations between Britain and Ireland. A seed was sown, with a simple bow . . . she remembered our losses, she remembered her own, as Luka Bloom described it in his song.
Another, which we have come to learn in Glencree after 40 difficult years of peacebuilding, is that without confronting the hard issues of our past there can be no lasting change towards a peaceful future. Dealing with that past is central to peacebuilding.
The Troubles clearly had some of their roots in what happened a century ago, in an earlier period of brutal political and sectarian violence. If we choose to remember only our sides narrative about what happened 100 years ago we will make understanding the more recent conflict and overcoming the deep divisions it opened up even more difficult. So it is important that we look at our own interpretation of the past and be open to hearing others perspectives  something that the prominent northern Methodist minister Dr Johnston McMaster, who will also speak today, calls narrative hospitality.
This is not to suggest that shared commemoration is necessarily appropriate, but it does require us at least to ensure that commemorations are as inoffensive as possible to others  which requires asking others what they would find offensive. Nationalists and republicans need to ask unionists that question, and unionists need to do the same to their historic antagonists.
Dialogue
Dialogue, a key approach that Glencree uses in its peacebuilding work, is important here, as it offers the opportunity to genuinely hear the other and be heard by them and allows for a joint working-through of difficult issues. Dialogue is a key part of the Glencree event today.
It is also important that we remember forgotten narratives of the centenary period. The dominant nationalist/unionist state building narratives of the Easter Rising and the Battle of the Somme often drown out the voices of other significant groups.
We must rediscover the voices of women and the suffragette movement, pacifists and conscientious objectors, the labour movement and, of course, the civilians  including children  who were caught up in these conflicts not of their making.
Conflict resolution
Finally, if we are to achieve a long-term peaceful future for the island we love and share, it is vital that we commit ourselves to nonviolent and nonadversarial approaches to resolving conflict. Conflict is inevitable; violence is not. This is an important reason why we need to guard very carefully against any glorification of violence as part of our commemorations.
It has been pleasing to observe that there has been little noticeable glorification of violence in commemorations to date, but there is still a risk of it happening, particularly as we get closer to the anniversary of the actual events of the spring and summer of 1916, and as people remember the courage and sacrifice of those who all fought for their concepts of country, culture, identity and freedom.
As the eminent philosopher Onora ONeill  who has strong British and Irish elements in her background and will also be participating today  has argued, what we should remember above all is that we have spent much of the past century killing and deriding others with whom we share these islands. She even questions whether any of this should be commemorated at all.
I would not go as far as that. But it is crucial that we remember with sadness, and with as much mutual understanding as we can muster, the pain caused and divisions created by the conflicts of 100 years ago, and vow that they will never be allowed to happen to this island again.
William Devas is chief executive of Glencree Centre for Peace and Reconciliation; glencree.ie
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 02:00

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berkeley: Students  thought sloped balcony was intentional</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/berkeley-students-thought-sloped-balcony-was-intentional-1.2264495</Link>
        <Description>District attorney given witness accounts from  lawyers’ investigation into tragedy   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Berkeley: Students  thought sloped balcony was intentional
District attorney given witness accounts from  lawyers investigation into tragedy
The broken wooden supports exposed after the collapse of a balcony in Berkeley, California, on June 16th.  Photograph: Jim Wilson/The New York Times
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 01:03
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 01:03
Legal papers show two students at a party in Berkeley last week say they saw a balcony sloping unusually before it collapsed, killing six Irish students. However, they initially believed the slope may have been an intended design rather than a sign of deterioration in the structure.
Lawyers for parents of one of the six victims of the disaster told investigators that two students at the 21st birthday party in the Library Gardens student apartment block when the balcony collapsed on June 16th provided statements about what appeared to be an unusual slope.
The witnesses, who have been named by the lawyers for the parents of Ashley Donohoe (22), Rohnert Park, California , thought the balcony may have been designed with an intended slight slope downwards toward the street.
Berkeley investigation to look at bringing criminal charges
However, in hindsight the students thought this may be evidence there was a visible deterioration in the balcony structure, according to the lawyers for Ms Donohoes family.
San Francisco law firm Rains Lucia Stern , which is representing George and Jackie Donohoe , met Alameda County district attorney Nancy OMalley on Thursday afternoon shortly after Ms OMalley announced a criminal and civil investigation into the collapse.
The lawyers presented Ms OMalley, who is responsible for prosecuting crime in Berkeley, with evidence from their investigation into the tragedy at Kittredge Street showing a litany of ignored problems at the property, including leaks, rot and flooding, dating back years.
The Donohoes, through their lawyers, told the district attorney they were concerned a proper, independent investigation had not yet been done and called for such an inquiry to identify any potential design or construction flaws and determine if any responsible parties should be criminally prosecuted.
The family expressed satisfaction that Ms OMalleys office had opened a criminal investigation.
The law firm, whose staff includes former police investigators, handed over a large amount of information and potential leads from its own investigation. The firm produced evidence that it claims shows a history of water infiltration and balcony decay at the property dating back to 2010, referring to an online review posted by one tenant at the property.
Also handed over were photographs showing water staining to the exterior of the fourth- floor balcony before the incident. The lawyers argue that the staining should have made the propertys owners BlackRock and management company Greystar on notice that an inspection of the balcony was necessary.
The photographs showing the exterior of the balcony surface were taken in April 2008, July 2009 and April 2011.
The law firm told the district attorney the complex had a history of poor management and failure to respond to maintenance problems. They provided evidence showing complaints to the City of Berkeleys housing enforcement unit concerning violations including holes in walls, trip hazards from damaged floors, loose metal strips in doorways, inoperable ceiling fans and missing exit signs.
There is a clear indication both from the evidence in terms of staining on the exterior of the building and the pointed complaints from the residents themselves that the people responsible for the building should have known that there was a looming problem, said Harry Stern , a lawyer at Rains Lucia Stern.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miriam Lord: Ann Widdecombe puts best foot forward at pro-life bash</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/miriam-lord-ann-widdecombe-puts-best-foot-forward-at-pro-life-bash-1.2264635</Link>
        <Description>Former Tory minister is special guest at Ceiliúradh Cois Life    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Miriam Lord: Ann Widdecombe puts best foot forward at pro-life bash
Former Tory minister is special guest at Ceiliradh Cois Life
Former British government minister Rt Hon Ann Widdecombe, seen with Senator Ronan Mullen,  was given a rousing reception by more than 500 guests in the Round Room of the Mansion House. Photograph: Gareth Chaney Collins
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 01:03
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 01:03
Big night on Wednesday for the pro-life campaign. It hosted its inaugural annual fundraising dinner in the Mansion House. Special guest at Ceiliradh Cois Life was former Tory minister Ann Widdecombe, who was given a rousing reception by over 500 guests in the Round Room.
Other speakers included Spirit Radio broadcaster, Wendy Grace and Senator Rnn Mullen. Earlier, Rnn escorted Dame Ann to a lunch in her honour at the papal nuncios residence in the Phoenix Park.
Later in the evening, a potentially unpleasant incident was avoided when Aodhn  Rordin, Minister of State for Equality, pitched up at the door of the pro-life ball and sought admittance.
Miriam Lord: SF lose plot in pursuit of Nama outrage
He was turned away because he had no ticket, which is understandable because he thought he was attending the Ringsend and District Respond to Drugs Awards, on in another part of the building.
It was a pity, really, because Aodhn could have gone in and continued his spat with Rnn Mullen. And Mattie McGrath. Its all to do with Twitter and acrimonious exchanges between the Senator and Minister this week.
McGrath twice took up the cudgels on behalf of the Senator during the Dils Order of Business.
On Tuesday, he informed the Ceann Comhairle he wanted to raise an item about the tweeting system.
What tweeting system, asked the chair, wearily.
Tweetest thing
I have to ask because it goes on. There is an adage that if there are too many tweets, the tweeter becomes a twat. Are we going to have government by tweets? asked McGrath.
Minister  Rordin today sent a terribly insulting tweet to people who happen to be pro-life. he complained.
The Tipperary TD told the Taoiseach to rein in his Ministers. He was also unhappy with tweets from Leo Varadkar over the free GP scheme for the under-sixes.
He returned to the topic the next day. Varadkar and  Rordin were tweeting about unsavoury issues and insulting GPs and pro-life supporters. The Broadcasting Bill should be amended to deal with this outrageous type of behaviour.
Dame Widdecombe visited Leinster House on Thursday as a guest of Senator Mullen and Senator Jim Walsh. Its nice to see them recovering from their same-sex marriage setback.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Educate Together takes legal advice on admissions</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/educate-together-takes-legal-advice-on-admissions-1.2264527</Link>
        <Description>Body says   the enrolment policy exemption for  older schools  ‘could be discriminatory’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Educate Together takes legal advice on admissions
Body says   the enrolment policy exemption for  older schools could be discriminatory
Educate Together chief executive Paul Rowe
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 10:08
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 01:03
Educate Together is taking legal advice on admissions regulations from the Department of Education which could be discriminatory.
It says hundreds of parents, who prefer not to have their children baptised, are being blocked from accessing their schools.
Educate Together, which operates 77 schools across the State, argues that the stipulation, announced in 2011, that new schools must prioritise children from the catchment area, is denying parents who live outside the catchment area of an Educate Together school, their choice of school for their children.
Students in direct provision working hard for college place
In contrast, older schools  the vast majority of which are denominational  can continue to prioritise on the basis of religion. Baptised children from outside the catchment may be preferred over non-baptised children living locally.
According to Educate Together chief executive Paul Rowe , this means some parents whose children are not baptised face difficulties accessing local schools and may find it impossible to get into Educate Together schools further away, given that most are hugely oversubscribed.
Mr Rowe said it had been hoped the 2015 Admissions To School Bill would address the issue of religious schools, which are publicly funded, being allowed to prefer baptised children.
Minister for Education Jan OSullivan has said the legislation was drafted in the context of the Constitution and equality legislation. We cant within that take away the provision whereby schools can protect their own ethos.
Educate Together schools
Educate Together schools have become increasingly oversubscribed, with hundreds of parent from outside school catchment areas applying for junior infants places, particularly in Dublin.
Some of the schools are receiving four, five or six times more applications than available places, said Mr Rowe.
For example, Balbriggan ET national school has 258 applications for 48 places. Holywell national school in in Swords , Co Dublin has 335 applications for 90 places, while Castleknock ET national school has 350 applications for 58 places.
Mr Rowe says the restrictions on new schools, compelling them to prefer children from the local area, may contradict powers granted to boards of management over this area under the Education Act.
Educate Together has, like other patron bodies, sought legal advice on the issue, he said. The fundamental underlying issue however, is that many more Educate Together schools are needed."
It could also be necessary for Ireland to comply with its international legal obligations.
A spokeswoman from the department said: The reason for establishing new schools is to serve a local community where a local demand exists and hence priority is given to pupils from the local area."
The United Nations has repeatedly called on Ireland to end religious discrimination in publicly-funded schools.
Most recently this week, the UN Council on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights in Geneva called on Ireland to take all necessary measures to bring all relevant laws, including the Equal Status Acts 2001 and the Education (Admission to Schools) Bill 2015, in line with the international human rights standards and to increase the number of non-denominational schools at the primary and post-primary education levels.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
