<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:03:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man successfully appeals acquittal for  murdering mother </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/man-successfully-appeals-acquittal-for-murdering-mother-1.2196886</Link>
        <Description>Paul Henry faces retrial after being found not guilty by reason of insanity   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Man successfully appeals acquittal for  murdering mother
Paul Henry faces retrial after being found not guilty by reason of insanity
Paul Henry: acquitted of the murder of his mother by reason of insanity
Topics:
Fri, May 1, 2015, 14:03
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 14:03
A Roscommon man acquitted of murdering his mother by reason of insanity last year has successfully appealed his acquittal and now faces a retrial.
Paul Henry (29), who lived with his mother Ann Henry at the time, had pleaded not  guilty to her murder at The Spinney, Abbeystown, Roscommon in September 2011.
A jury acquitted Henry of the murder by reason of insanity at a Castlebar sitting of the Central Criminal Court and he was sent to the Central Mental Hospital by Mr Justice Paul Carney on May 7th,  2014.
Mr Henry had sought a retrial so he could plead and be convicted of manslaughter by reason of diminished responsibility, thereby incurring a determinative sentence rather than being under an indefinite regime at the Central Mental Hospital possibly for the rest of his life.
The Director of Public Prosecutions sought to have the insanity verdict upheld.
The Court of Appeal first determined that it had jurisdiction to consider the appeal because it is a Constitutional court in contrast to its predecessor.
The three-judge court went on to find that there was an element of misdirection by the trial judge to the jury.
Mr Justice George Birmingham , who sat with Mr Justice Garrett Sheehan and Mr Justice John Edwards , ordered a retrial.
The case for retrial will be listed in the Central Criminal Court in two weeks time, the court heard.
Mr Justice Garrett Sheehan had suggested during counsels submissions that the outcome for Henry could be substantially different depending on the verdict.
The current outcome had lead to detention in the Central Mental Hospital and treatment on heavy medication whereas a conviction for murder would have lead to a completely different regime in terms of his health.
Mr Justice Sheehan had suggested Henry might have a better life in prison than in the Central Mental Hospital even if he gets a life sentence.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title> ‘No sense’ of any strain between Honohan and Cabinet - Burton</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/no-sense-of-any-strain-between-honohan-and-cabinet-burton-1.2196866</Link>
        <Description>Release of  Central Bank report  overshadowed by news of governor’s decision to quit   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
No sense of any strain between Honohan and Cabinet - Burton
Release of  Central Bank report  overshadowed by news of governors decision to quit
Governor of the Central Bank of Ireland,  Patrick Honohan, who is to step down. The release of the Central Banks annual report on Friday was overshadowed by news of Prof Honohans decision.  Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Kathryn Hayes
Fri, May 1, 2015, 14:00
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:50
The Tnaiste has said she had no sense of any strained relationship between governor of the Central Bank Patrick Honohan and the Government.
The release of the Central Banks annual report on Friday was overshadowed by news of Prof Honohans decision to step down.
Prof Honohan confirmed he intends to retire at the end of the year, nine months before his seven-year term was due to end.
Euro membership not to blame for Irelands crisis: Honohan
Sterling conviction
Speaking in Limerick this Friday, Joan Burton described Prof Honohan as a person of clear and sterling conviction who had done huge service to the country.
The Central Bank governor had a professional and amicable relationship with members of the Government, she added.
Mr Honohan has said he is leaving the post because it is the right time to go.
The Tnaiste said finding a replacement would be a priority for the Government.
When asked whether Prof Honohans early resignation was prompted by a strained relationship with the Government, as speculated in some reports, Ms Burton said: I dont have any sense of that, speaking for myself.
Public interest
The Tnaiste said the most outstanding thing about Mr Honohan is his absolute dedication to the public interest.
He is somebody who, although from the world of academia, has been extremely pleasant and easy to deal with.
He is a person of very clear and sterling conviction, but I would have thought he has absolutely business-like and professional and amicable relationships with members of the Government.
Stressing the important role played by the Central Bank in the countrys economic recovery, Ms Burton said: The outstanding thing about Governor Honohan is his absolute dedication to the public interest in Ireland and to the Central Bank being part of the recovery, and the turning around of Ireland. In fact he has done huge service to the country.
Governor Honohan has certainly given some previous hints that he might retire at a particular age.
Regulatory model failed
Clearly the governor will have to put some mechanism in place in relation to his successor, but what is important is that we know from what happened in terms of the crash in Ireland that we had a regulatory model which failed and failed very very badly - to the cost of vast numbers of people in Ireland and vast number of businesses.
Ms Burton said it is crucial that the independence of the Central Bank is respected, given the role it has played in rebuilding the banks and ensuring they can function as normal, sensible and prudent lending institutions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:36:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rejection for Bruton, even for altruistic reason, is still rejection</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/rejection-for-bruton-even-for-altruistic-reason-is-still-rejection-1.2196847</Link>
        <Description>Analysis: Fine Gael faces more local rebellions over  strict gender quota rules   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Rejection for Bruton, even for altruistic reason, is still rejection
Analysis: Fine Gael faces more local rebellions over  strict gender quota rules
Minister for Jobs and Enterprise Richard Bruton became collateral damage in a row between the local organisation and party headquarters on Thursday over a gender quota directive. Photograph: The Irish Times
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:36

If the level of political embarrassment was colour-graded, Fine Gael would be scarlet after its shambolic convention in Dublin Bay North on Thursday night.
The partys leading deputy in the capital, Minister for Jobs and Enterprise Richard Bruton , became collateral damage in a row between the local organisation and party headquarters over a gender quota directive.
The directive was stark. One male and one female candidate only were to be selected in the new five-seat constituency which combines two former three-seaters: Dublin North Central and Dublin North East.
Kenny wants Fine Gael election candidates in place by October
With Terence Flanagan having flown the coop, Bruton was the only sitting TD. The edict from Mount St meant the party could not run two male candidates.
For Naoise O Muir, a popular councillor, former lord mayor, and a candidate in the last general election, the implications of the directive were blunt: he had to put his ambitions on hold.
His career has been leading to a tilt at national politics - he was the last unelected candidate standing as Brutons running mate in Dublin North Central in 2011.
If Fine Gael had a marginal chance of winning a second seat in Dublin Bay North, he reckoned he was best-placed. Stephanie Regan , who was unsuccessful in the local elections, was chosen as the female candidate.
O Muirs supporters convinced delegates at Clontarf Convention that should he get the nod at convention, Bruton would be added to the ticket by the partys national executive. This happened at on lunchtime on Friday.
In his speech O Muir is said to have told the meeting if he were not to succeed, his chances of getting added to the ticket were minimal.
A Fine Gael member who attended the meeting told the Irish Times delegates agreed with his argument, had huge sympathy for his plight and voted tactically: People were ticked off that we were being used as headquarters experimental laboratory for too long.
While the vote was non-personal with party HQ (personified by general secretary Tom Curran) in its sights, the optics were still bad for Bruton. His woes were compounded by reports that Regan came second in the first count, relegating him to third. Rejection, even for altruistic purposes, is still rejection.
The problem here as in other constituencies stems from the new rules on gender quota. Each party must have a minimum of 30 per cent female candidates, otherwise it will lose significant State funding. The rules introduced by Phil Hogan have proven to be controversial within parties. Experienced and ambitious male politicians resented being excluded by a stroke of a pen rather than by a vote of their peers in constituencies.
Fine Gael has 11 women TDs among its 71-strong contingent in the Dil. As of now, none of its Deputies has indicated they will be standing down after the next election.
To satisfy its gender quotes that party will have to field 90 candidates or more. It will mean that virtually all of its new candidates will be women.
The problem is most manifest in constituencies where there is a single male deputy in situ and the convention is told to select one male and one female. It means delegates are left with a Hobsons choice - of backing or rejecting the sitting Deputy.
This has happened already in other Dublin constituencies. In Dublin West , Cllr Kieran Dennison withdrew with some protest after a one male candidate directive: Leo Varadkar is Fine Gaels sitting TD there.
Senator Catherine Noone , who had no connection with Dublin West, was chosen as the female candidate. Similarly in Dublin Bay South, Kieran Binchy had to take on sitting TD Eoghan Murphy for the single male slot - Cllr Kate OConnell won the other place in a contest with Linda OShea Farren.
A lot of ire is being directed at party headquarters but its task is not easy. The quota imposes onerous burdens and there is a clear desire to field female candidates who have chances of winning seats - not just token add-ons.
But it very unpopular with local organisations, especially when there are strong male candidates who have spent years toiling in the fields.
A senior party source said that conventions will always throw up anomalies - in Galway West in 2011 sitting TD Pardaic McCormack failed to get through convention and stood down. In fact the party ran four candidates then.
And with John OMahony moving into Galway West, it looks like it may have to run four again to satisfy gender quotes (the three TDs - OMahony, Sean Kyne and Brian Walsh - as well as Sen Hildegarde Naughton).
The next two Fine Gael conventions scheduled are for Tipperary on May 8th and Dublin South West on May 25. Tipperary has two sitting TDs so that should not be a problem, while it has no TDs in Dublin South West since Brian Hayes became an MEP. Neither should lead to controversy but others may cause some ructions.
Fine Gaels national executive will decide on Friday afternoon to add Richard Bruton to the ticket. Three candidates in a complex new constituency does not look like a smart strategy.
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:36

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:54:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cork stag group wearing Hitler masks in Prague ‘repulsive’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/cork-stag-group-wearing-hitler-masks-in-prague-repulsive-1.2196804</Link>
        <Description>Irish bar owner says group abused customers and slapped female waiting staff   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Cork stag group wearing Hitler masks in Prague repulsive
Irish bar owner says group abused customers and slapped female waiting staff
Men from Cork on a stag party in Prague last weekend wore Adolf Hitler masks and verbally abused customers, pub owner Frank Haughton said. Photograph: Thinkstock
Topics:
Fri, May 1, 2015, 12:58
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 12:54
A group of men from Cork wore Hitler masks and verbally abused customers at a pub in the centre of Prague while on a stag party trip last weekend, the Irish owner of a pub has said.
Frank Haughton , who owns Caffreys Irish Bar in the old town square in the Czech capital said about 25 men were part of the group who rather misbehaved. They also slapped female waiting staff on their backsides and spoke about fairly deviant sex acts, he said.
While its not appropriate to wear Hitler masks anyway probably it was somewhat insensitive to wear them so close to the Jewish quarter in Prague, Mr Haughton said.
In a letter to a newspaper published today, the bar owner said he had witnessed only two stag parties in the truly repulsive category and that both of them had come from Ireland .
He told RTs John Murray show that the men involved in last weekends incident were asked by other customers who were sitting in the outdoor seating area to remove the masks and the insensitivity was pointed out to them.
The abusive language that they returned to some customers, including some quite elderly customers, was truly not the kind of stuff you want to hear on the airwaves, Mr Haughton said.
He said the group was really, really offensive to one elderly couple who tried to get the men to desist from wearing the masks.
People on stag parties often had a theme, he said. Some would dress quite normal, but others would come dressed as babies or dressed as women.
But these guys, their identifying symbol was the Hitler mask.
There were other incidents involving the group where they slapped the bottoms of female waiting staff and tried to grab them.
Eventually, we just stopped serving them and asked them to leave.
Mr Haughton said the language from the group was fairly red. Some were rather more vociferous than others.
They eventually left with some protest, lets put it that way.
The bar owner, who is also the proprietor of the James Joyce pub in the city, said the sad bit was that the men ranged in age from perhaps 30 up to 55 or older.
There were men among these people who should have known better and who should have pulled the slightly younger guys into line.
Mr Haughton said the overall behaviour of the men showed such a bad image of Ireland and it shows such a bad image of any group.
Normally, the pub would see very little trouble from stag parties.
Some of them might get noisy, but generally the pub had a good relationship with them.
We get to know the leader and we build a relationship with them that stops things getting out of control, but with these guys it just wasnt possible.
Mr Haughton, who has been in Prague for 23 years said the group was very much the exception rather than the rule.
Its a shame when its the Irish group that tops the pile in being without doubt the worst group Ive ever seen.
He said his staff had been very upset and he believed such men know how out of order they are in the back of their own minds.
They simply wouldnt be tolerated in a Czech bar.
They head for the Irish bars thinking they will get some Irish sympathy there, that Paddy will welcome Paddy.
Mr Haughton said he had written a letter to a newspaper in the hope that family members of the men might identify them and let them know what they thought of their behaviour and how they had let themselves down, their families down and Ireland down.
I would ask them to take a good look at themselves and to consider their behaviour if they ever travel abroad again.
Mr Haughton said the experience made him more cautious and he would now engage security staff on the door of the pub after last weekends experience.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:52:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Catholic group says IDA call for Yes vote on marriage ‘completely unacceptable’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/catholic-group-says-ida-call-for-yes-vote-on-marriage-completely-unacceptable-1.2196801</Link>
        <Description>David Quinn of Iona Institute says chief executive stepped outside proper remit   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Catholic group says IDA call for Yes vote on marriage completely unacceptable
David Quinn of Iona Institute says chief executive stepped outside proper remit
David Quinn of the Iona Institute said the call by the IDA chief executive for a Yes vote in the marriage referendum was completely unacceptable. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Topics:
Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:45
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 12:52
The IDA has stepped far outside its proper remit in calling for aYes vote in the forthcoming referendum on marriage, a Catholic group has said.
Chife executive of the investment body, Martin Shanahan , told The Irish Times in an interview a Yes vote would be in the States economic interest.
He also said a No vote against same-sex marriage would send a very negative signal to the world of international business.
Children have right to a mother and father, No vote event told
Responding on Friday, director of the Iona Institute David Quinn said the call was completely unacceptable.
By intervening in the referendum in this way, the IDA is stepping far outside its proper remit. It is simply risible for it to pretend that its brief to improve Irelands economic prospects gives it permission to do this.
On this basis, why not say what government we should vote for next time? Who we have in Government is much more relevant for the economy and for our multi-nationals than our definition of marriage.
Mr Quinn said many major economies did not have same-sex marriage and there was no evidence that this affects them in any way.
The intervention by the IDA in this debate is simply one more example of a major institution of Official Ireland breaking its normal stance of neutrality in these matters to strong-arm Irish people into voting No.
If we vote No it will not affect the Irish economy in any way, shape or form.
Companies supported by the IDA employ more than 174,000 people in Ireland .
Mr Shanahan said in the interview that many of its clients were on record on this matter here and in the US.
Overwhelmingly I think large multinationals in the US have come out in favour of same-sex marriage, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:41:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man jailed for life for Real IRA murder of Eamon Kelly</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/man-jailed-for-life-for-real-ira-murder-of-eamon-kelly-1.2196783</Link>
        <Description>Veteran criminal shot dead outside his Dublin home two years ago   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Man jailed for life for Real IRA murder of Eamon Kelly
Veteran criminal shot dead outside his Dublin home two years ago
Mourners, including convicted  INLA killer  Dessie OHare (front left), carry the   remains of Eamon Kelly  after his funeral mass at St Brigi ds Church, Killester in December 2012. Photograph: Colin Keegan/Collins, Dublin.
Topics:
Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:16
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 12:41
A Dublin man has been jailed for life by the Special Criminal Court for the Real IRA murder of veteran criminal Eamon Kelly over two years ago.
Sean Connolly (35), of Bernard Curtis House, Bluebell, Dublin pleaded guilty on Tuesday to the murder of Eamon Kelly at Furry Park Road, Killester on December 4th, 2012.
The court heard Connolly was arrested a short time after he shot Kelly four times in the back as he returned home from Ladbrokes betting shop in Killester.
A crime boss who changed with the times
Det Garda ine Ni Cathain of the Special Detective Unit arrested Connolly as he walked towards the entrance of Clontarf Castle 20 minutes after the shooting.
The court heard firearms residue on Connolly matched eight spent 9mm cartridges found at the murder scene, that accelerant found on his shoes matched that used to burn out a black Lexus car used in the killing and that Connolly made admissions to garda after his arrest in which he admitted his part in the murder.
Det Insp Paul Scott, the senior investigating officer, said that garda had warned Kelly his life was in danger after an unsuccessful attempt to shoot him in 2012 had failed when the gun jammed.
We were satisfied from the investigation that this was a highly professional operation carried out by the IRA, he said.
He said Kelly had cracked ribs following a fall at his home a couple of weeks before the murder and that his mobility was impaired. Witnesses at the scene saw him trying to run away from the gunman and towards his house before he was shot in the back.
He said that three of the four bullets that his Kelly exited through his body and the fourth was found in his body at the postmortem. The gunshots had caused damage to his vital organs.
Kellys daughter, Alison, who gave a victim impact statement to the court, said the murder of her father had caused pain and suffering to all her family.
He was my closest confidant, friend and father, she said, adding that her fathers life was brutally taken away.
He lived for his family but his murder has destroyed our lives, she said.
Mr Justice Paul Butler , presiding at the three judge non-jury court, said the murder was  a most heinous crime and the court was not in a position to do anything about sentencing as the sentence was mandatory.
The court sentenced Connolly to life imprisonment.
Eamon Kelly(65) was one of the countrys longest serving criminal figures, having been involved in organised crime for more than four decades.
In the early 1970s he used a carpet business in Dublins north inner city as a front for his criminal activities, which included armed robbery and extortion.
He was associated with the Official IRA, although he never joined the republican movement. Kelly used the threat of the Official IRA to back up his extortion activities and to terrorise other criminals while he built his criminal empire.
He also contributed funds to the Official IRA and helped them with armed robberies as part of their fund-raising activities.
The carpet business was wound up by the High Court in 1981 and a liquidator was appointed on behalf of the Revenue Commissioners over unpaid bills.
His association with the Official IRA led to his conviction in 1984 for the stabbing of a man outside the old Workers Party Club in Gardiner Street. He was jailed for 10 years but following an appeal a retrial was ordered and he was sentenced to three years.
Kelly was jailed in 1993 for smuggling a large shipment of cocaine into the country, one of the first criminals jailed for importing the drug.
He was sentenced to 14 years after he was caught with almost a kilo of cocaine worth an estimated 500,000.
Kelly was linked to other major crime figures, such as Martin Hyland and Eamon Dunne and it is believed he fell foul of the Real IRA gang led by Alan Ryan who was himself murdered by a drugs gang.
It is believed Kelly had refused to pay protection money to the Real IRA and this led to an unsuccessful attempt on his life in 2010.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:09:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jury finds man (52)   guilty of Drogheda  axe murder </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/criminal-court/jury-finds-man-52-guilty-of-drogheda-axe-murder-1.2196677</Link>
        <Description>Marius Gaizutis killed Audrius Butkus  in Co Louth in 2013   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Jury finds man (52)   guilty of Drogheda  axe murder
Marius Gaizutis killed Audrius Butkus  in Co Louth in 2013
Marius Gaizutis of Marsh Road, Drogheda, Co Louth: found guilty of murder.
Topics:
Fri, May 1, 2015, 12:11
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 12:09
A 52-year-old man has been found guilty at the Central Criminal Court of murdering a man with an axe.
Marius Gaizutis of Marsh Road, Drogheda, Co Louth was charged with murdering Audrius Butkus (44) at that address on September 9th or 10th, 2013.
Gaizutis pleaded not guilty to murder but guilty to manslaughter when he was arraigned before the Central Criminal Court over a week ago.
Man  (50) charged in Co Louth with murder of Audrius Butkus
His plea was not acceptable to the State and a jury was sworn in to try him.
The Central Criminal Court jury which was made up of four women and eight men found Gaizutis guilty of the charge on Friday by unanimous verdict after deliberating for two hours and 40 minutes.
Ms Justice Margaret Heneghan thanked the jury members for the important work they did and exempted them from jury service for the next 20 years.
The court will sit again on Friday to fix a sentencing date.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:57:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge rejects woman’s claim symphysiotomy was unjustified </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/high-court/judge-rejects-woman-s-claim-symphysiotomy-was-unjustified-1.2196652</Link>
        <Description>Mother had alleged unnecessary procedure carried out on her    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Judge rejects womans claim symphysiotomy was unjustified
Mother had alleged unnecessary procedure carried out on her
Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:10
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 11:57
A High Court judge has rejected a claim by a 74-year old woman that an unjustified symphysiotomy was performed on her 12 days before the birth of her first baby at a Dublin hospital in 1963.
The case was regarded as a test case for those suing over symphysiotomies, a procedure which involved the breaking of the pelvis.
The woman, who asked to remain anonymous, was in court today with dozens of supporters when Mr Justice Kevin Cross dismissed her claim, heard over 15 days. Costs of the case will be decided later.
Woman (71) settles action over symphysiotomy
The woman claimed she suffered lifelong pain following the procedure and could not bond with her baby daughter after the birth because she was in such pain she could not even lift the child out of her cot. She said she felt very disillusioned, later had a nervous breakdown and took to her bed for a time.
In her action, the woman alleged she had a non-emergency symphysiotomy which left her with life long pain, incontinence and restricted mobility.
In his judgment,Mr Justice Cross said there was no doubt the procedure would not be carried out today or on any date after the introduction of active management of labour from the mid 1960s by the new master of the National Maternity Hospital .
This remarkable woman has suffered throughout her life as a result of the effects of this operation, the judge said.
He said he was not making any general observations about the effects of symphysiotomies on patients and was aware there is still a limited place for symphysiotomies especially in countries with limited hospital facilities and where mothers have great distances to travel. He also accepted that claims that symphysiotomies produce generally significant adverse effects on mothers is hotly in dispute.
In this case, this woman, whether as a result of the timing of the symphysiotomy or otherwise did suffer, and continued to suffer the consequences throughout her life, he said.
He accepted medical practice develops and that every procedure, now common place, must once have been unprecedented and may well have been very controversial.
The judge said he had concluded that, in Dublin maternity hospitals in 1963, it was accepted that trial of labour was not always required for a consultant to conclude a vaginal delivery would not be possible and that, in those cases, prophylactic symphysiotomy, as was performed in this case, was a reasonable, though limited option.
In this case, hospital notes and other factors convinced the treating doctors a vaginal delivery would not be possible and a symphysiotomy was performed which, at the time, they had reason to believe was not generally adverse in its effect on the mother and it was safer as far as the child was concerned, the judge said.
He had also concluded, given the real fears of multiple caesarean sections and the perceived benign effects of symphysiotomy, and also given the widespread acceptance of this practice among leading consultants in certain Dublin maternity hospitals, that this plaintiff had not established this practice was one with such inherent defects that ought to have been obvious to any person giving the matter due consideration.
There was also no evidence of any peer criticism of the plaintiffs procedure, he added.
The judge ruled the practice of prophylactic symphysiotomy in 1963 was not a practice without justification and the strength of the defence was such it was impossible to conclude the woman had proved her case.
The fact the procedure was carried out 12 days before the birth may have been causative of some of her injuries but the time delay of itself was not a factor that could be added to the case to establish liability, he found.
In the circumstances, he must conclude this remarkable lady, whose story indeed deserves to be told, must fail in her case.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:39:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Commuters voice frustration and support for bus strike</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/consumer/commuters-voice-frustration-and-support-for-bus-strike-1.2196621</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of thousands of passengers face travel disruptions on Friday and Saturday   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Commuters voice frustration and support for bus strike
Hundreds of thousands of passengers face travel disruptions on Friday and Saturday
Hundreds of thousands of bus passengers are facing travel disruptions  as a result of the industrial action which was prompted by plans announced last year by the National Transport Authority to put out to tender 10 per cent of routes. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Sorcha Pollak, Ciarn D'Arcy
Fri, May 1, 2015, 11:47
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 11:39
Commuters across the State were forced to find alternative transport to get to work on Friday morning as Dublin Bus and Bus ireann bus drivers began a 48-hour strike over the potential privatisation of bus routes.
Emma Drohan from Celbridge had to drive to Leixlip to catch a train into Tara Street station rather than taking her usual bus from Lucan into the city. The journey took an hour instead of the usual 40 minutes.
I dont really have much sympathy for bus drivers because I think at the end of the day youve got to be realistic, its inevitable that its going to happen, said Ms Drohan. You hear stories of the government pumping money into a loss making company, and you kind of go look, its our money going in there so its time for a change really.
Dublin Bus, Bus ireann set to sue trade unions for losses
Linda Kennedy from Rush in Co Dublin was more sympathetic to bus drivers on the picket line, saying strike action was needed to bring about justice.
Ms Kennedy, who usually takes two buses to work, had to get a lift to the station, take a train into the city and then a Dublin Bike for the final stretch across the city centre.
Its not such a big deal, its just a bit more expensive on the train, she said. I feel these things are necessary, they dont happen for no reason. Its just a pity there wasnt a way of working it out.
Hundreds of thousands of bus passengers will face travel disruptions on Friday and Saturday as a result of the industrial action which was prompted by plans announced last year by the National Transport Authority to put out to tender 10 per cent of routes.
In Blanchardstown, Ike Ugu voiced his frustration at having to take a circuitous route into the city centre.
I have to walk all the way to the train station to see if I can catch a train, and Im not sure if Im even going to catch it. Its just a big hassle, when the buses arent running a lot of average people suffer. Its not fair.
I sympathise with every worker, people have rights to protest. However, in protesting, they have to consider the ordinary people, and sympathise and empathise with them too, he said.
Also travelling from Blanchardstowm, Mark Cummins was happy to adjust his normal commute as a result of the industrial action.
I think its a minor inconvenience for what theyre going through, he said. I think the bus drivers are being completely shafted. Sometimes strong-arm tactics are needed, and if you have the power to disrupt the system like theyre doing now then they should do it.
Siobhn McGee said privatisation would have an overwhelmingly negative impact on transport services across the State.
I dont believe buses should be privatised, I believe they should be properly managed. The English trains never run on time because they were privatised and were split up into little bits with hundreds of little companies which is totally unmanageable.
Bill McCanley, a member of Siptu who joined the picket line outside Phibsborough Dublin Bus depot at 4am on Friday, said the unions totally reject allegations that the industrial action was the result of an illegal ballot .
Mr McCanley was responding to the legal letters sent by Dublin Bus and Bus ireann to Siptu and National Bus and Rail Unions (NBRU) which stated if industrial action went ahead they would have no alternative but to issue proceedings immediately against you seeking damages for the losses suffered.
The provocative commentary by the management out of Dublin Bus and Bus ireann last night certainly had the opposite effect that they thought they might have had because we wont be intimidated by that sort of stuff, said Mr McCanley.
We know we have done this ballot correct, we know this is a trade dispute and weve said all along through the Siptu six points exactly what were about. We consider that provocative and an attempt to intimidate their staff.
Liam Weston, Siptu shop steward for Dublin Bus in Phibsboro, said bus drivers apologised for any inconvenience caused to commuters but maintained the strike needed to go ahead.
None of the drivers took the decision lightly, said Mr Weston. A lot of these drivers see the same passengers everyday, they dont want to disrupt their customers.
Although we are fighting for our own rights we are also fighting to keep public transport public. Passengers suffer ultimately in the end.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:57:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cork strikers say bus plan ‘privatisation by stealth’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/cork-strikers-say-bus-plan-privatisation-by-stealth-1.2196588</Link>
        <Description>Workers dismissive of Minister’s promise on job security under new dispensation   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Cork strikers say bus plan privatisation by stealth
Workers dismissive of Ministers promise on job security under new dispensation
Hundreds of thousands of bus passengers across the country face travel disruption as a result of the industrial action. Photograph: Eric Luke/The Irish Times
Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:42
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 10:57
Striking Bus ireann workers in Cork this morning expressed fears that the Governments plan to put 10 per cent of Bus ireann routes out for tender is privatisation by stealth.
Around a dozen or so NBRU and Siptu members were on picket duty on a deserted Bus ireann terminal at Parnell Place as the public appeared to have made alternative travel arrangements.
There was no sign of any tourists left stranded by the two day stoppage and the Bus ireann workers on picket duty referred any media queries to shop stewards on picket duty at the Capwell garage.
Dublin Bus, Bus ireann set to sue trade unions for losses
Bus ireann employs around 300 drivers in Cork with some two thirds of drivers being represented by the NBRU and the remaining one third being Siptu members.
Around 50 or so bus drivers drawn from both unions were on picket duty at the Capwell garage where NBRU branch chairman, Stephen McKelvey summed up the mood of the drivers.
We honestly dont want to be here and we dont want to be discommoding the public on a bank holiday weekend but we were left with no alternative as a result of the government proposal.
Siptu shop stewards, Pat Hartnett was dismissive of Minister for Transport, Paschal Donohues promise that no Bus ireann or Dublin Bus driver would lose his job under the Government plan.
The Minister at the moment is telling us that he is guaranteeing us our contracts but thats only word of mouth  that minister could be gone in the next election in twelve months time.
NBRU national executive member Ger O Donovan said that they believed that the opening up of 10 per cent of routes was a move designed to attract private bus operators from the UK.
At the end of the day, none of the private operators here in Cork are going to get any of these routes they need a 30 million a year turnover and they dont have that money behind them.
Its going to be the big private operators from across the water  thats the whole idea behind this  it is 10 per cent now but next year it will be 20 per cent and before we know it, 50 per cent of our routes will be gone.
NBRU National Executive member, Leonard Kelly warned that it will be the travelling public who will ultimate suffer as the private operators will focus just on profit and not provide a social service.
He instanced the case in West Cork where Bus ireann has dropped its Old Head of Kinsale and Garrettstown service in order to have meet NTA requirements for hourly departures from Kinsale.
I wouldnt make it out to Old Head of Kinsale and back into Kinsale to leave there on the hour  thats a social service for elderly people living in outlying areas and thats now gone, he said.
Privatisation is going to eliminate that social service element that Bus ireann provides for elderly people living in isolated rural areas who are dependent on bus service for their daily needs.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:32:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘A pain but fundamentally right’: commuters on   social media </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/consumer/a-pain-but-fundamentally-right-commuters-on-social-media-1.2196539</Link>
        <Description>People take to Twitter and Facebook over bus strike disruptions    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
A pain but fundamentally right: commuters on   social media
People take to Twitter and Facebook over bus strike disruptions
Topics:
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 09:32
Hundreds of thousands of commuters can expect disruptions  today as the  48-hr bus strike gets  underway.
Bus ireann and Dublin Bus drivers have picketed bus depots after last-minute  negotiations with the Labour Relations Commission collapsed.
The industrial action  was prompted by plans announced last year by the National Transport Authority to put out to tender 10 per cent of routes with further tranche of routes being put out to tender in 2019.
#Busstrike on Twitter
 Hailo Ireland (@HailoIreland) May 1, 2015
The Luas and DART today be like... #busstrike pic.twitter.com/w1lkuudKNf
 Jim Corr (@therealjimcorr) May 1, 2015
"Say 'discommode' again." #BusStrike
 Niall de Buitlear (@nialldebuitlear) April 30, 2015
It's disappointing that bus lanes will be closed to traffic tomorrow, during the #busstrike
 Alan Farrell TD (@AlanFarrell) April 30, 2015
One of the few positive things about the #busstrike : cycling into work this morning was a delight. It was like being in a different city.
 Christine Bohan (@ChristineBohan) May 1, 2015
Fight privatisation! Show your support for our bus drivers - Join this Thunderclap http://t.co/z7CXuP1Qyg #busstrike
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:47:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The strike by bus workers: the questions and answers</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/the-strike-by-bus-workers-the-questions-and-answers-1.2196510</Link>
        <Description>What are the issues surrounding the Dublin Bus and Bus Éireann stoppage?   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
The strike by bus workers: the questions and answers
What are the issues surrounding the Dublin Bus and Bus ireann stoppage?
A strike poster photographed at Broadstone depot during. Photograph: Brenda Fitzsimons/The Irish Times
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 08:47
What is this dispute about?
The strike action at Dublin Bus and Bus ireann centres on opposition by unions at the companies to moves by the National Transport Authority to put out to tender 10 per cent of routes currently operated by the State-owned transport firms. The unions fear that if the routes are privatised following this tender process this would result in a deterioration of their members terms and conditions. They also contend they are fighting to protect the future of publicly-provided transport services.
Has the Government not given assurances to bus workers?
The Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe has guaranteed that no Dublin Bus and Bus ireann employee will be forced to transfer against their will to a private operator even if the State companies lose the right to provide some services under the planned tendering process.
However the unions have a number of otherconcerns, particularly what will happen in 2019 when they fear many more existing routes could be put out to tender under the next wave of reforms in the sector.
What the National Transport Authority said
It has said it cannot say at this stage how many, if any other Dublin Bus and Bus ireann routes will be put out to tender in 2019.
It has also pointed out that even under the existing plan to put out to tender 10 per cent of services, the State companies can take part in this process and the routes may not go to private operators.
What do the unions want?
The trade union Siptu has set out a 6-point agenda which it says will have to be addressed as part of any resolution. This includes clarification of the legislative position regarding what will happen in 2019.
It is also seeking that labour costs be excluded from the tendering process for routes and that a registered employment agreement for the sector be put in place which would place a legal floor under terms and conditions for staff.
What is the position of the bus companies?
On Thursday evening after last-ditch resolution efforts failed the State-owned bus companies upped the ante and announced they are to sue the trade unions for losses incurred as a result of the strike.
Dublin Bus and Bus ireann have contended that the industrial action is illegal.
The companies have maintained that the move to tender bus routes was a decision of the National Transport Authority which was implementing Government policy. They have said they have no power or authority to amend or revise the plan in any way. They have also contended that industrial relations issues have been addressed in the assurances given that no workers will be forced to move to private operatorsagainst their will.
The companies have maintained that they will lose about 3 million as a result of the industrial action.
Dublin Bus and Bus ireann also face having fines of 150,000 and 80,000 respectively imposed by the National Transport Authority for every day services are not provided.
The trade unions have strongly rejected the allegation that the strike is illegal.
If the companies believe the strike is illegal, why did they not seek and injunction to try to prevent it?
It seems inconceivable that the companies only came to its conclusion last night that the strike was unlawful. However it would appear that a decision was taken to continue along the industrial relations route as far as possible until this finally collapsed yesterday evening.
What will happen next?
Five further days of strike action at the two companies are scheduled to take place over the coming weeks. The Labour Relations Commission has urged all parties to return to talks with a view to finding a resolution.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:35:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Men face sentence over attack on mother and daughter</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/men-face-sentence-over-attack-on-mother-and-daughter-1.2196503</Link>
        <Description>Michael Murphy and Garrett Hill convicted of assaulting the women outside Cork city bar    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Men face sentence over attack on mother and daughter
Michael Murphy and Garrett Hill convicted of assaulting the women outside Cork city bar
The Soho bar in Cork city where two women were assaulted in February 2014.
Fri, May 1, 2015, 08:35
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 08:35
Two men are due for sentence on Friday after they were found guilty by a jury of assaulting a woman and her mother outside a Cork city pub over a year ago.
The jury of seven men and five women took just two and a half hours to find Michael Murphy (32) and Garrett Hill (33) each guilty of the two separate charges.
Murphy with an address at Woodfield Hall, Station Road, Blarney, Co Cork, had denied a charge of assault causing harm to Laura OCallaghan outside the Soho bar in Cork city on February 16th, 2014.
Hill with an address at The View, Gleann Na Ri, Tower, Blarney, had denied a charge of assault causing harm to Breda OCallaghan OConnell, Ms OCallaghans mother, inside Soho on the same date.
Det Garda Kevin McCarthy said it was clear to him from the CCTV footage from the scene that Hill assaulted Ms OCallaghan OConnell and that Murphy assaulted Laura OCallaghan.
The jury whhich had also viewed the CCTV footage, came back on Thursday afternoon to find Murphy guilty of the assault on Ms OCallaghan and Hill guilty of assaulting her mother.
During the trial which started on Tuesday at Cork Circuit Criminal Court , the State withdrew charges that Murphy and Hill threw a petrol bomb at Ms OCallaghans house in Blarney.
The two had been charged that they intentionally or recklessly threw a lit petrol bomb into Ms OCallaghans house at Woodfield Hall, Station Road in Blarney on February 17th, 2014.
Following the mens conviction, Judge Sean O Donnabhain told them their status had changed irrevocably and he remanded them in custody for sentence.
When a jury was being sworn in on Monday for the trial which began on Tuesday, Murphy stood up and addressed Judge O Donnabhain in the packed courtroom on Washington St.
My Lord, could I address the court, he asked. I hope that when I am found not guilty, the people who made the allegations will be prosecuted for making false statements, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:35:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two men held over fatal stabbing at house in Co Limerick</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/two-men-held-over-fatal-stabbing-at-house-in-co-limerick-1.2196491</Link>
        <Description>Body of a man (31) from Limerick city found at house in Pallasgreen last night    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Two men held over fatal stabbing at house in Co Limerick
Body of a man (31) from Limerick city found at house in Pallasgreen last night
Garda are investigating the fatal stabbing of a man in Co Limerick last night.
Kathryn Hayes
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 07:35
Two men have been arrested in connection with a fatal stabbing in Co Limerick overnight.
The victim, a 31-year-old man from Limerick city, was found at a house in The Grove Estate in Pallasgreen at around 11.20pm on Thursday night.
He was pronounced dead and his body remains at the scene. Its believed he suffered a number of stab wounds.
A 34-year-old woman was taken to University Hospital Limerick with a suspected stab wound.
Her injuries are described as non life-threatening.
A Garda spokesman said it was too early to confirm a motive for the incident and would not comment on reports that the victim had tried to intervene in dispute between a woman and another man.
Garda believe up to eight young people were in the house at the time.
Two men, aged 20 and 32 years, were arrested at the scene in connection with the death and are being questioned at Henry Street and Roxboro Road Garda stations under Section 4 of the Criminal Justice Act, 1984.
The victim who has not yet been identified is from Limerick city.
Detectives are trying to establish his connection to the address where he was found.
The Grove Estate is a council estate in Pallasgreen which is located about 25km from Limerick city.
The murder scene has been preserved and the Offices of the State Pathologist have been notified.
Garda are appealing for witnesses or anyone with information to contact them at Bruff Garda station on 061 382940, The Garda Confidential Line 1800 666111 or any Garda Station.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:06:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Union says bus workers’ resolve will harden after legal action</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/union-says-bus-workers-resolve-will-harden-after-legal-action-1.2196482</Link>
        <Description>Hundreds of thousands of people affected by 48-hour strike action across country   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Union says bus workers resolve will harden after legal action
Hundreds of thousands of people affected by 48-hour strike action across country
Images
SIPTU members in Broadstone and Phibsboro were on strike from 4am over privatisation of the service. Commuters across the city faced disruption to their routes.  Sorcha Pollock reports.
NBRU and Siptu members protest outside the Dublin Bus depot in Summerhill this morning. A picket was placed on the depot at 4am where some 240 drivers work. Photograph: anna  Caolla/The Irish Times
The picket line at Phibsboro Depot this morning as members of Siptu and NBRU start their strike. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Workers picket the bus depot at Phibsboro this morning. Photograph: Sorcha Pollak/The Irish Times
Commuters queue to get on to the Luas Red Line at Heuston Station this morning. Photograph: Damien Cullen/The Irish Times
Previous Image
anna  Caolla, Martin Wall
Topics:
Fri, May 1, 2015, 13:56
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 07:06
A trade union has warned legal proceedings being brought by Dublin Bus and Bus ireann over the 48-hour bus strike which started on Friday morning will only harden of the resolve of striking workers.
The companies are to lodge papers in the High Court on Friday as part of a claim against Siptu and the National Bus and Rail Union (NBRU) to recover millions of euro in lost revenue and fines that will be imposed on foot of the disruption to services.
No Dublin Bus and Bus ireann services have been in operation since midnight in a dispute over plans by the National Transport Authority to put out to tender 10 per cent of routes currently operated by the State-owned companies.
Hundreds of thousands of people have had their travel plans disrupted as a result of the strike.
Tanaiste Joan Burton urged all those involved to sit down and try to negotiate.
I hope all parties will sit down and negotiate the only way to resolve a dispute like this is to sit down and have negotiations, and I hope it will possible to do that as quickly as possible
A Bus ireann spokeswoman said that it had gone to court as a last resort.
The transport companies say the strike is illegal, a charge rejected by trade unions.
In a letter issued Friday, the general secretary of the NBRU Dermot OLeary criticised management in both companies as well as in the National Transport Authority.
He said a recent intervention by the chief executive of the Authority Anne Graham had led to a crystallisation of the fears and concerns of members.
Mr OLeary said the legal action being initiated by the chief executives of the two State transport companies had done a disservice to your employees and our customers, attacking workers and their representatives.
He said this could but lead to a hardening of staff resolve.
The NBRU remains implacably opposed to privatisation. We will continue to highlight this flawed ideologically-based attempt to hijack publicly-owned bus companies. We will continue to highlight the fact that this policy is a bad deal for the taxpayer and we will continue to focus on our contention that this is a race to the bottom.
Employers group Ibec said the industrial action would cause massive and unnecessary disruption to the travelling public and businesses alike. It urged all parties to the dispute to resume talks with a view to resolving the issue.
Minister for Transport, Tourism and Sport Paschal Donohoe has addressed the workers industrial relations concerns regarding the potential transfer of employees to operators in the private sector. The remaining issues are questions of public policy and as such are not appropriately advanced under the protections of the Industrial Relations Act, 1990.
Speaking at the Dublin bus depot in Summerhill, NBRU representative Brendan Hayden said he and his colleagues were protesting over the plans to put routes out to tender.
It is off-the-wall that they are proceeding with this. There is no need for privatisation. Unfortunately while we were invited to the LRC, the NTA/Government had nothing to offer. We are just looking for the protection of our pay and conditions in 2019 and not just now.
Dublin Bus says it will lose revenue of 600,000 per day as a result of the strike while Bus ireann expects to lose revenues of 1.5 million.
Talks to avert the strike broke down last night after 2 1/2 hours of discussion at the Labour Relations Commission (LRC) with both sides blaming the other for the impasse.
The bus companies expect that up to 1.1 million bus journeys will face disruption over the 48-hour period. Dublin Bus said it normally carries 450,000 customers on a Friday and 400,000 customers on Saturday while Bus ireann said the strike would result in the loss of an estimated 250,000 passenger journeys.
Drivers at Dublin Bus and Bus ireann voted overwhelmingly in April to back strike action in protest. NBRU members in Dublin Bus voted by 92 per cent while those in Bus ireann voted by 91 per cent in favour of industrial action.
Garda said they and local authorities will continue to monitor the situation but at this stage there is no plan to open the bus lanes up to other motorists.
Garda are advising motorists to allow extra time when planning their journey during the strike.
Mr Donohoe said the strike action was unjustified and will cause considerable damage to an economy that is in recovery, have financial implications for the bus companies who are only just getting back on their feet and discommode the travelling public who are attempting to go about their daily business.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Reviews of X-rays and scans to take place at other hospitals where locums worked </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/reviews-of-x-rays-and-scans-to-take-place-at-other-hospitals-where-locums-worked-1.2195985</Link>
        <Description>Errors found in about 100 cases after thousands of X-rays reviewed, says  Leo Varadkar    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Reviews of X-rays and scans to take place at other hospitals where locums worked
Errors found in about 100 cases after thousands of X-rays reviewed, says  Leo Varadkar
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar: We will always have locums.  Photograph: Colin Keegan/Collins Dublin
Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
About 100 of the thousands of X-rays and other scans reviewed because of errors identified in the work of three locum radiologists required a follow-up, Minister for Health Leo Varadkar has said.
However, he told the Dil that reviews would be conducted at a number of other hospitals where two of the three locum radiologists identified as having made errors worked.
Reviews of the work of a third locum, where a delayed cancer diagnosis was identified, have been completed.
Mr Varadkar said thousands of X-rays were reviewed and only a small fraction  100 or so  required follow-up and a repeat scan.
Support
Very regrettably, one incident of delayed diagnosis has been confirmed, and the HSE is following up appropriately with this patient to provide whatever support is necessary.
The X-rays and other scans were reviewed when mistakes were identified in the work of the three locum radiologists employed by the HSE.
However, the Minister stressed, we will always have locums, particularly in smaller hospitals, because in a small hospital with three or four radiologists or cardiologists or whatever, when someones on maternity leave, or someones out sick or someones away, theyre very dependent on locums.
In bigger hospitals its different. If youve a rota of 15 or 16, you can cover for one or two absences.
Fine Gael   TD for Louth Fergus ODowd said there was a major sense of dj vu about the new revelations regarding cases of misdiagnosis following incidents at Tallaght hospital and Our Lady of Lourdes Hospital in Drogheda in 2008.
He said he was concerned at the lack of a dynamic within the HSE to deal with this issue.
Heads must roll as a consequence of what has happened, he said.
No findings
Mr Varadkar said: I think its very important to bear in mind that no findings have yet been made against any of the consultants referred to.
Independent Roscommon-South Leitrim TD Denis Naughten asked what was being done to protect patients in the UK and Australia, where he said the three doctors now worked.
Mr Varadkar said measures have been taken to contact the hospitals overseas in which these three doctors are working.
As part of the HSEs risk assessment process, it may require an audit of work carried out by locum consultants in other hospitals.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Young back marriage equality but less keen on voting – report</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/young-back-marriage-equality-but-less-keen-on-voting-report-1.2195858</Link>
        <Description>Survey not funded by any interest group or organisation involved in the referendum    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Young back marriage equality but less keen on voting  report
Survey not funded by any interest group or organisation involved in the referendum
Only 6% of young people agree that the referendum has an impact on existing marriage between a man and a woman. Photograph: Getty Images
Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
Some 90 per cent of 18- to 35-year-olds say they would vote Yes in the same sex marriage referendum, but only 55 per cent say they are likely to cast a ballot on May 22nd.
Some 1,000 young people across the State were surveyed for the Youth and Marriage Equality report by the marketing agency Thinkhouse.
Some 94 per cent agreed with the statement Marriage Equality supports a fair and equal Ireland where all people are treated the same.
Same-sex marriage referendum: a legal review
We wanted to get a sense of what youth feel about the referendum. This is the biggest civil rights movement of this generation and it is important for us to see how young people feel about it, Elaine Verdon of Thinkhouse said.
The report was not funded by any interest group or organisation involved in the referendum, Ms Verdon said.
Only 6 per cent of young people agreed that the referendum has an impact on existing marriage between a man and a woman, while 40 per cent said that the referendum will have an effect on children.
The survey found that 66 per cent of respondents agreed with the statement the Marriage Equality referendum will impact the rights of same-sex couples as parents.
Some 81 per cent of respondents said they were a registered voter, with one in four saying they are interested in Irish politics.
Some 53 per cent said they voted in the last general election.
Undecided
When asked which political party they would give their first preference vote to in an election, 42 per cent were undecided, 21 per cent said they would vote for an independent.
When it comes to seeking information on the referendum, 18- to 35-year-olds rank social media highest as a source (77 per cent), followed by family and friends at 60 per cent.
We will have to see whether the passion of young people on social media reaches the ballot box, said Verdon. I think it is easy to say something, but acting on it is totally different.
When asked How many referendums are taking place on May 22nd? one in five of those surveyed assumed they would be asked to vote on one referendum, not two.
Some 32 per cent of respondents said they feel the Government does not care about their opinions and Ms Verdon says that this disaffection may affect the outcome of the referendums as a lot of young people say they are not voting because they are annoyed at the Government .
Deadline
Young people want to see change, said Ms Verdon, even if they may struggle getting out to vote. Marriage equality matters to young people, so the 55 per cent figure of those who say they will vote may go up by May 22nd, she said.
Whether its yes or no, people should exercise their right to vote.
Meanwhile, the National Youth Council of Ireland (NYCI) is urging young people to make sure they have registered to vote in time for the referendums before the deadline on Tuesday. It estimates that some 120,000 18- to 25-year- olds are not registered.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Jan O’Sullivan signals further movement on junior cycle reform</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/education/jan-o-sullivan-signals-further-movement-on-junior-cycle-reform-1.2195910</Link>
        <Description>Joint Managerial Body says evidence of discrimination lacking to justify admissions Bill   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Jan OSullivan signals further movement on junior cycle reform
Joint Managerial Body says evidence of discrimination lacking to justify admissions Bill
Minister for Education Jan OSullivan says an agreement with teacher unions over junior cycle reform is within closer reach than at any point over the last few years. Photograph: Cyril Byrne
Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
The Minister for Education has indicated a willingness to further water down planned junior cycle reforms to achieve agreement with teacher unions.
However, Jan OSullivan said she would not compromise on key principles, including the need to give prominence and importance to classroom-based assessment.
Addressing a meeting of school managers in Co Kerry , she said: I dont have a magic fix to this issue that I can announce today. But I will say that I believe that agreement is within closer reach than at any point over the last few years.
Responding to concern from delegates about uncertainty created by teachers non-co-operation with training ahead of the start of junior cycle assessments for English next year, the Minister said I would hope that we will be able to re-engage with the teaching unions in the very near future and to resolve the dispute very quickly.
Industrial action
No further talks are scheduled but an attempt at restarting them is expected to take place after the unions carry out their latest industrial action, a lunchtime demonstration at all schools next Thursday.
Ms OSullivan was speaking at the annual meeting of the Joint Managerial Body (JMB), which represents the boards of management of two-thirds of secondary schools, including those under Catholic patronage.
In his address to the conference, JMB president Fr Paul Connell criticised the Ministers decision to push ahead with the Admission to Schools Bill despite what he described as a lack of evidence of discrimination by school managers.
Resent
What we particularly resent is the implication that our schools are involved in some sort of nefarious activity with our admissions and we are not open and inclusive.
He also criticised public commentary around the recent unsuccessful Supreme Court case taken by a Traveller boy against CBS High School in Clonmel, Co Tipperary.
Fr Connell pointed out that the school had always enrolled Travellers and a further 29 pupils were unsuccessful in getting a place the year the boy applied.
School managers suffered from repetitive change injury and we will soon be legislated out of existence.
On the junior cycle, the JMB has proposed a further amendment to the reform plan to try to break the stalemate between the Minister and the unions which would see the school-based assessment of students work further divorced from the State-certified exams.
JMB general secretary Ferdia Kelly said it was proposing that the compromise proposals set out by Dr Pauric Travers be further revised so instead of assessing two pieces of written work teachers would carry out two in-class evaluations of different kinds of learning.
He proposed schools would then report on the outcomes of this assessment to parents through an agreed report template around the Easter of third year along with a record of the students achievement in other areas of learning.
This would replace the proposed Profile of Achievement, which intends to record all facets of the students work, including exam performance, at the end of junior cycle.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bank of Ireland evidence contradicts AIB’s about timing of blanket guarantee </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/bank-of-ireland-evidence-contradicts-aib-s-about-timing-of-blanket-guarantee-1.2195878</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Bank of Ireland evidence contradicts AIBs about timing of blanket guarantee
Former Bank of Ireland chief executive Brian Goggin at Leinster House following the Joint Committee of Inquiry into the Banking Crisis. Photo: Gareth Chaney Collins
Fri, May 1, 2015, 08:41
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
Former chief executive of Bank of Ireland Brian Goggin has contradicted evidence given by Allied Irish Banks about the night of the bank guarantee.
Mr Goggin told the Oireachtas banking inquiry the decision to introduce a blanket guarantee was agreed and known when he left Government Buildings at 3.30am on September 30th, 2008.
He said the two banks were in a meeting at 2am when the decision was relayed to them.
It was the worst day of my life, Brian Goggin tells bank inquiry
At that juncture it is my recollection that we were informed a blanket guarantee was being provided. When I left at 3.30 am, there was no ambiguity about what was being done on that night. A blanket guarantee.
Fine Gael TD Kieran ODonnell said AIB chief executive Eugene Sheehy had told the inquiry he learned of the blanket guarantee in the media the following morning and thought a four-bank cover would be put in place.
Mr Goggin said he was aware of the evidence given by the former AIB executives. He added: It was a meeting chaired by the taoiseach. There were two banks there. My recollection is that it occurred when we came back into the room at 2am.
He said it was his recollection AIB was in the meeting room with Bank of Ireland.
AIB executives have already told the inquiry they left Government Buildings unaware of the decision reached. The inquirys chairman Ciaran Lynch later said there was space to bring witnesses back in.
Mr Goggin described the night of the guarantee as the worst of his life. He said former taoiseach Brian Cowen was very much in charge on the the night and minister for finance Brian Lenihan was doing the running around.
Bank of Ireland had been put on notice on September 29th that Anglo Irish Bank was going to default the next day. This was a grave piece of news to receive, he said, and he knew something catastrophic was about to happen.
He confirmed Bank of Ireland had been asked earlier on September 29th to consider taking over Irish Life and Permanent in the scenario where Irish Nationwide and Anglo were to fall. He met two officials from Anglo at 2.30pm that day. We agreed to meeting as a matter of courtesy. Both the chairman and chief executive came to Bank of Ireland Baggot Street for that meeting.
The chairman mentioned they had a liability maturing in the amount of 1.5 billion or 2 billion  something of that magnitude  and they were unable to honour that commitment. They asked Bank of Ireland to acquire Anglo. We told them we had no interest. We politely told them we couldnt be of any assistance.
Mr Goggin said he knew Anglo chairman Sean Fitzpatrick, had also called AIB but that meeting was cancelled.
He said he and the chairman of Bank of Ireland, Richard Burrows, felt a responsibility to request a meeting with the government about the gravity of what was approaching.
He said Bank of Ireland and AIB told  the government at 2am on the night of the guarantee they could provide  10 billion to Anglo Irish Bank. The mood changed and there was a sense of relief the default of Anglo had been prevented, he said.
Dreadful predicament
Mr Goggin told the inquiry the government was in a dreadful predicament and didnt have much of an alternative but to introduce a guarantee.
The entire day and the night of the 29th September was the worst day of my life. The pressure, the stress, the issues I was trying to deal with  it was incredibly stressful and traumatic. As it was for government members and officials.
He was questioned by Mr ODonnell about a possible draft guarantee being produced on the night. Mr ODonnell said the inquiry committee had received minutes suggesting Bank of Ireland and AIB had brought a document to the government. Mr Goggin said he had no recollection of it and had made several queries to try to find out whether one existed, but to no avail.
He confirmed he proposed all bondholders be included in the guarantee.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dáil Sketch: Questions about everything except the long break </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/d%C3%A1il-sketch-questions-about-everything-except-the-long-break-1.2195979</Link>
        <Description>Seán Fleming compares Alex White to ventriloquist’s dummy after prepared reply     </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Dil Sketch: Questions about everything except the long break
Sen Fleming compares Alex White to ventriloquists dummy after prepared reply
Alex White: deputised for Tnaiste Joan  Burton at Opposition Leaders Questions. Photograph: Alan Betson
First published: Fri, May 1, 2015, 01:00
Government and Opposition took exception to the line of questioning at a heated Opposition Leaders Questions.
The chamber came to life, despite the close-to-comatose atmosphere generated by the debate since Tuesday on the Governments spring statement. Minister for Communications, Energy and Natural Resources Alex White was deputising for Tnaiste Joan Burton. He was asked by Fianna Fils Sen Fleming if the Government found the banks refusal to reduce mortgage interest rates acceptable. White read from a prepared brief, emphasising, among other things, that Minister for Finance Michael Noonan had no statutory role in the matter. Fleming claimed that White sounded like a ventriloquists dummy.
White repeated  the Minister had no statutory power to reduce rates. If I am wrong in that, maybe the deputy might correct me, he said.
The Minister putting a question to the TD questioning him was too much for Fleming. He jumped to his feet and declared: The Minister has directed a question to me.
Leas Cheann Comhairle Michael Kitt said the Minister should be allowed to answer Flemings initial question.
If the Minister will withdraw his question, I will sit down, said Fleming.
As the noisy exchanges continued, Kitt adjourned the House for five minutes.
White was later upset by a question from Sinn Fins Peadar Tibn on Siteserv . Tibn wanted to know if any Cabinet members were aware of any Siteserv shareholder with access to IBRC information at the time of the sale.The potentially explosive nature of the question angered White. He said he was not aware of any such person, adding that the manner in which the question was posed was the same as making unfounded allegations.
History trawl
Independent TD Clare Daly did a history trawl when she questioned White on the bus strike. Surveying the Government ranks, where Fine Gael backbenchers sat in vocal support of White, she referred to Eoin ODuffys descendants sitting behind the Minister.
This prompted Fine Gaels Dinny McGinley to look behind him and stare into party colleague Bernard Durkans eyes. That did not last long.
Daly then targeted Labour , noting bus workers would be striking on May Day, international workers day, against a decision made by a Government made up of the party founded by James Connolly to defend workers rights. Daly told the Minister that Connolly would turn in his grave the next time Labour showed up at a memorial service.
Soon it was back to the spring statement debate, which came to a merciful end before the Dil began its bank holiday break, stretching to next Wednesday. There were no questions asked about that.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
