<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:38:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bid to reunite owners with stolen items worth €150,000</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/bid-to-reunite-owners-with-stolen-items-worth-150-000-1.2276292</Link>
        <Description>Ten boats, 74 outboard engines and a caravan  among   property found during searches   </Description>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:27:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Archbishop says woman was 20 when they first had sex</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/high-court/ex-archbishop-says-woman-was-20-when-they-first-had-sex-1.2264055</Link>
        <Description>Burke says he paid €176,000 to Nigerian woman at RTÉ Mission to Prey High Court case   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Ex-Archbishop says woman was 20 when they first had sex
Burke says he paid 176,000 to Nigerian woman at RT Mission to Prey High Court case
Former Archbishop of Benin Richard Burke pictured leaving the Four Courts on Thursday. Photograph: Courts Collins
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 13:28
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 13:27
A former Catholic Archbishop has told the High Court he first had sex with a Nigerian woman in 1989 when she was aged 20 and he was aged 40.
Co Tipperary-born Richard Burke (66) said he later paid sums totalling about  176,000 sought by Dolores Atwood .
He also agreed to have sex with her in an hotel in Canada in 2009 after she asked him to do that when he told her he could not pay her another  200,000 sought by her, he said.
Mr Burke said he felt terrorised by Ms Atwood and feared she would disclose their relationship which would bring disgrace and shame on himself, his family and his ministry.
Mr Burke said he first met Ms Atwood in 1986 or 1987 when she was aged 17 or 18 and he first had sex with her in 1989 when she was aged 20 in his bedroom in Cathedral House in Warri city in Nigeria . He did not know her when she was aged 13 or 14, he said.
He was ordained a Bishop in 1996 and an Archbishop in December 2007, the jury heard.
He was giving evidence in his continuing action alleging he was defamed in the RT Prime Time Investigates Mission to Prey programme of May 23rd 2011. RT denies defamation and has pleaded a defence of truth concerning the content related to Mr Burke.
Today, Mr Burke said he believed he first met Ms Atwood, born in August 1969, about 1986 or 1987 when she came to his office.
Ms Atwood told him she had been a confidante of another priest who was transferred from the cathedral parish about 1986 and soon afterwards was killed in a car accident, he said. He attributed his relationship with her as commencing after that priest was killed.
When his counsel said Ms Atwood told Prime Time about an event that happened when she was about the age of 13 in hospital, he said there was an event in hospital similar to that.
He said the first time he had sex with Ms Atwood was either September or October 1989 and the hospital event was after that. He had sex with her three more times before he returned to Ireland in 1990 and, while he was in Ireland, letters passed between them, he said.
He said Ms Atwood later married and moved to Canada, he believed that was about 1995. He was ordained Bishop of Warri in 1996 and had continuing contact with her between 1996 and 2003.
In 2003, he said she called him asking him to meet her in Lagos and spend three nights in an hotel and give her $4000 in cash, which he did.
Between 2003 and 2005, there was increasing phone contact between them, he said. The phone conversations had been about once a month or every three weeks but increased to between once weekly and ten days and the calls could last one or two hours and sometimes longer.
The calls sometimes became very uneasy and unpleasant for him because she was expressing a feeling for me I could not reciprocate, she was demanding intimacy.
He was devastated when he later learned she had phoned his brother in the family home in Tipperary and also his sister in Dublin.
He said Ms Atwood then phoned him demanding money and he eventually met her in the airport of Halifax in Nova Scotia by appointment in October 2007 and gave her a bank draft for  26,000 which she said was the full amount of all the phone calls.
He was incredibly worried if he did not hand over that money, she would reveal they had an intimate relationship.
He said he received more phone calls from October 2007 from Ms Atwood that were menacing, threatening, aggressive, abusive and demanding. He recorded a call of October 25th 2007 in which she gave him four options and told him to choose one.
One option was they would meet anywhere in the world over the next year any place and be together for at least one week, a minimum five days, and have full sexual intercourse, to be fully and totally intimate.
A second option was to give her  10,000 a year for five years, a third was they would meet somewhere and discuss it and the fourth was they should be together again the way we used to be.
He received another call about 11pm on November 7th 2007 where he was subject to a tirade of abuse from Ms Atwood for about three hours. That arose where he was to meet her in Lagos on November 8th to respond to the four options but she insisted the meeting was to have been on November 7th, he said.
Ms Atwood would not hear his explanation there was a clear arrangement for the 8th, he said.
She unleashed a tirade of abuse, saying he was treading on her and not to do that. That was the first time she mentioned :Youre a paedophile, he said.
Rather than give her  10,000 a year for five years, which was an eternity of prolonging this nightmare, he decided to try and end it once and for all and give her  50,000 in one payment.
She had said as God is my witness, I will never again bring up the matter of intimacy, we will be good friends, intimacy never, never again, he said.
He grabbed onto that phrase, chose the  50,000 payment, arranged to meet her in Dublin at the end of July 2008 and paid her that  50,000 in a bank draft and  5,000 cash.
After about a month, Ms Atwood started phoning again and demanding more money, he said. She was demanding  100,000 which he raised partly from his own and partly from diocesan funds. He met her in London and gave her a bank draft for  90,000 and 10,000 cash, he said.
He paid her because I was simply terrorised and afraid she would reveal we had a relationship when she was 20 and I was 40 which revelation would bring disgrace on himself and his ministry. I was ashamed, I was utterly terrified.
Under cross-examination, he said he regarded himself as someone about whom Ms Atwood had lied and lied extensively about.
Asked what kind of person he is, he said he would say truthful, sincere, generous, available, committed and flawed.
When Paul OHiggins SC said the Prime Time programme was about priests rightly or wrongly said to have abused young people and teenagers, he said that, in his case, it was clearly and unequivocally said that I was a child abuser.
He agreed the RT programme was not the first time the allegations by Ms Atwood had been made public and they had been featured in some newspapers.
The case continues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:09:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government position on Finucane inquiry ‘remains unchanged’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/government-position-on-finucane-inquiry-remains-unchanged-1.2263964</Link>
        <Description>Minister Charlie Flanagan says British commitments on independent inquiry ‘should be honoured’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Government position on Finucane inquiry remains unchanged
Minister Charlie Flanagan says British commitments on independent inquiry should be honoured
Minister for Foreign Affairs, Charlie Flanagan. Photograph: Dara Mac Donaill/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:11
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:09
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan has said the Government will closely study todays judgment by the High Court in Belfast on the case of murdered solicitor Pat Finucane .
In a statement issued following Justice Stephens judgment on the legal challenge taken against the British governments decision not to hold a public inquiry into the murder, Mr Flanagan said:
I note this mornings judgement in the judicial review and will be studying it closely.
Kenny to raise British and loyalist collusion with Cameron, Dail told
The Irish Governments position remains unchanged. We continue to believe that an independent public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane, in line with the political commitments made by the British and Irish Governments at Weston Park in 2001, should be honoured.
Mr Stephens ruled this morning that British prime minister David Cameron did not act unlawfully when he refused a public inquiry into the murder by loyalists of Mr Finucane.
Delivering his reserved judgment, Mr Justice Stephens said: I uphold that the decision was lawful and accordingly I dismiss that part of the challenge.
In his statement, Mr Flanagan said the Government has consistently raised the matter with the British government.
I raised it most recently with Secretary of State for Northern Ireland Theresa Villiers on 19 May. Taoiseach Enda Kenny discussed the case with Mr Cameron when they met in London last week, Mr Flanagan added.
My thoughts at this time are with Geraldine Finucane and all the Finucane family, who have campaigned so tirelessly for more than a quarter of a century in pursuit of the full truth in the case of Pat Finucane, including the role of collusion in his murder.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:06:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Meath remains believed to be of Séamus Wright and Kevin McKee</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/meath-remains-believed-to-be-of-s%C3%A9amus-wright-and-kevin-mckee-1.2263949</Link>
        <Description>Bogland search for Joe Lynskey remains to continue   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Meath remains believed to be of Samus Wright and Kevin McKee
Bogland search for Joe Lynskey remains to continue
Local priest Father John OBrien with members of Samus Wrights family at the site in Coghalstown, Co Meath. Photograph: PA
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 13:27
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:06
Two bodies unearthed in a field in Co Meath in a search in Co Meath are now believed to be the those of Samus Wright and Kevin McKee who were abducted and killed by the IRA in the 1970s.
Seamus Wright went missing on October 2nd, 1972. He was married and from Belfast. Kevin McKee was also from Belfast and he disappeared on the same day.
DNA samples from the remains discovered on the site at Coghalstown have been sent for testing and the remains themselves are due to be taken away later on Friday.
More than one body found in dig for Disappeared
The family of Mr Wright have arrived at the scene about 10kms north of Navan and relatives of Mr McKee are expected there shortly.
The Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains which has been painstakingly stripping away topsoil from the reclaimed bog since March said the search would continue for the remains of former Cistercian priest Joe Lynskey who the IRA said they killed and buried in the area.
Speaking to the media at the site of the excavation, Commission spokesman Geoff Knupfer said the mood among those present was one of elation and sadness.
He said he believed the discovery of the remains, if established to be MrWright and Mr McKee would bring closure to the families of the men.
The forensic dig at Coghalstown involved the slow examination of more than six hectares of reclaimed bog. A sniffer dog was also brought in late last year to help locate human remains.
All of the disappeared were buried in unmarked graves. Searches have recovered the remains of a number of the disappeared based on information provided since the Belfast Agreement.
A statement issued on behalf of the Lynskey family yesterday said they were grateful to the commission and to those who had engaged with it in the search.
Sinn Fin president Gerry Adams TD welcomed news that remains had been discovered.
The uncertainty over who has been recovered must be hugely traumatic for the families involved. I am sure that the commission will move as speedily as it can to verify the identity of those who have been found, he said.
The list of disappeared includes Gareth OConnor, who was murdered in 2003. His body was recovered on June 11th, 2005 at Victoria Quay, Newry Canal, Co Louth. The commission has investigated 16 abductions and murders.
To date, the remains of 10 of the disappeared have been recovered, the most recent being Brendan Megraw, whose remains were found in Oristown bog, also in Co Meath, last October.
Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald said she hopes the suffering of at least some of the families will now be eased.
The work of the Commission is complex but it is a humanitarian task aimed at ending the suffering of those families brutalised by the disappearance of their loved ones so many years ago, she said.
The Commission will continue its work to find the remains of those who have yet to be found.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:30:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Belfast High Court rejects call for Finucane inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/belfast-high-court-rejects-call-for-finucane-inquiry-1.2263902</Link>
        <Description>Court rules British prime minister had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Belfast High Court rejects call for Finucane inquiry
Court rules British prime minister had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry
Geraldine Finucane (right), the widow of murdered Belfast solicitor Pat Finucane. Photograph: Andrew Winning/Reuters
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:53
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 11:30
The High Court in Belfast has rejected a call by the Finucane family for a decision that would have compelled the British prime minister David Cameron to hold a public inquiry into Pat Finucanes murder.
Lord Justice Stephens in issuing his findings on a judicial review taken by the Finucane family found today that Mr Cameron had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry into the Belfast solicitors murder.
Mr Finucane was shot dead by a UDA gang in front of his wife Geraldine and family at their north Belfast home in 1989. The British government has apologised and accepted that there was official collusion in his murder but has refused to hold a full-scale public inquiry, as the family has been demanding.
Kenny to raise British and loyalist collusion with Cameron, Dail told
Rather than holding a public inquiry the British government commissioned a review of the murder case by British lawyer Sir Desmond de Silva.
In his 2012 500-page report Sir Desmond reported that there was a significant doubt as to whether Mr Finucane would have been murdered had it not been for the different strands of involvement by elements of the British state.
He found that a series of positive actions by employees of the British state actively furthered and facilitated his murder and there was a relentless effort to defeat the ends of justice in the aftermath of his killing.
My review of the evidence relating to Patrick Finucanes case has left me in no doubt that agents of the State were involved in carrying out serious violations of human rights up to and including murder, it says.
Sir Desmond however said he did not believe there was an over-arching state conspiracy to murder Mr Finucane but that an extraordinary state of affairs was created in which both the British army and the RUC special branch had prior notice of a series of planned UDA assassinations, yet nothing was done to prevent the attacks.
The report said there were three UDA conspiracies to murder Mr Finucane that were known to RUC special branch and or MI5. These were in 1981, 1985 and 1988/89 and on none of these occasions was Mr Finucane warned of the threat against his life.
Mr Cameron said the shocking levels of collusion exposed by the report was unacceptable and apologised to the Finucane family: I am deeply sorry, he said. However, he again ruled out establishing an independent public inquiry.
At the time Mr Finucanes widow Geraldine dismissed the report a as a sham... a whitewash... a confidence trick. She renewed her call for a full public inquiry into her husbands death and said, This report is not the truth.
The family followed up that review by taking the judicial review. Today Lord Justice Stephens ruled against the family on their main call for a public inquiry.
Speaking after the ruling, Minister for Foreign Affairs and Trade Charlie Flanagan said: The Irish Governments position remains unchanged. We continue to believe that an independent public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane, in line with the political commitments made by the British and Irish Governments at Weston Park in 2001, should be honoured.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:11:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Who said heatwave? Temperatures set to hit 25C</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/environment/who-said-heatwave-temperatures-set-to-hit-25c-1.2263892</Link>
        <Description>Mini heatwave set to hit Irish shores with humid and warm weather across the nation   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Who said heatwave? Temperatures set to hit 25C
Mini heatwave set to hit Irish shores with humid and warm weather across the nation
Dubliners packed out the city's parks and public spaces today to enjoy sunshine and temperatures in the high teens.
Temperatures are expected to hit 25 degrees  next Wednesday. Photograph: Frank Miller /The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:22
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 11:11
Grab the sunscreen and air out the swimwear because theres sunshine headed our way and this time its bringing some real heat.
A mini heatwave is set to hit Irish shores next week with Met ireann predicting temperatures in the mid-twenties.
According to the forecaster, temperatures will hit 25 degrees across the country next Wednesday, bringing warm and very humid weather.
The warm weather will move from the continent to Ireland, bringing sunshine and real heat for the first time this summer.
Forecaster Klara Finkele says temperatures will remain in the late teens and early twenties over the weekend and into early next week before the warmer weather rises up from the Bay of Biscay on Wednesday and Thursday.
However, she warns that high levels of humidity will bring a risk of thunderstorms and heavy downpours.
Weather from the Bay of Biscay tends to be quite unstable, its warm and very moisture laden so were certainly going to keep an eye on the rain, said Ms Finkele. Warm air holds more humidity and moisture so it can lead to heavy downpours.
Temperatures over the weekend will be similar to recent days, with bright and mostly dry weather on Saturday that will become cloudy in the afternoon.
Rainfall will spread across the country on Saturday night but will clear on Sunday morning , bringing slightly fresher temperatures of 16-20 degrees.
Monday will be a hazy day with temperatures of 18-20 degrees. The weather will get warmer on Tuesday and temperatures are set to reach 22 degrees.
The real warm weather from the south is due to arrive on Wednesday, bringing temperatures between 20-25 degrees across Ireland.
The United Kingdom is also set to enjoy next weeks warm weather, with a Spanish plume of hot air moving north, bringing temperatures up into the early 30s . France , Italy and Spain have been experiencing particularly hot weather in recent days, with parts of southern Europe on track to break records for June temperatures, according to the Weather Channel.
How to protect your skin from the sun
The Irish Cancer Society has warned people to take care in the sunshine, particularly the elderly and young children.
Parents are advised to dress babies under six months in loose-fitting clothes with long sleeves and to keep them in the shade as much as possible.
Children should wear hats and sun glasses in the sunshine and use sunscreen with SPF 30 or higher. Sunscreen should be reapplied every two hours.
Adults are also advised to spend time in the shade, wear a hat and sunglasses, and to use sunscreen with SPF 15 or higher.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:01:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Water bill amendments will bring ‘clarity’, says Minister </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/water-bill-amendments-will-bring-clarity-says-minister-1.2263889</Link>
        <Description>Paudie Coffey fails to confirm whether tenants face eviction if they do not pay water bill   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Water bill amendments will bring clarity, says Minister
Paudie Coffey fails to confirm whether tenants face eviction if they do not pay water bill
Minister of State at the Department of the Environment Paudie Coffey. Photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:40
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 11:01
Irish Water provisions, which ensure a house cannot be sold until charges are paid, have been introduced to bring clarity and certainty for landlords and tenants, according to a Minister of State Paudie Coffey .
The Minister of State at the Department of the Environment described claims that tenants who dont pay their Irish Water bills could face eviction as scaremongering on the part of the opposition.
Speaking on RTs Morning Ireland, Mr Coffey said the amendments to the bill had been introduced to create a method of enforcement to ensure that those who are not compliant and are refusing to pay, that they do pay.
Thousands march in anti-water charges protest in Dublin
Minister for the Environment Alan Kelly has introduced 33 pages of amendments to the Environment Miscellaneous Provisions Bill.
It contains a number of changes, including the setting up of a database for the water conservation grant and provisions to ensure a house cant be sold until the charges are paid. The Bill also obliges local authority tenants to pay their water charges.
Mr Coffey failed to confirm whether tenants would be evicted if they did not pay their bill, saying payment was a matter for the landlord and tenant as is the case in any contract situation for tenancy.
Asked if the landlord would have to pay if the tenant failed to do so, he said the owner of the property would be responsible for discharging any unpaid bills before selling the home.
We want to see people compliant with the law and we dont want to see people ending up in trouble and thats why were making measures that we feel are fair and bring certainty to the whole area.
Mr Coffey said users who applied for the Water Conservation Grant worth 100 before June 30th could expect to receive the money before the end of this year.
He also said an independent test due to be carried out by Eurostat , the EU statistics agency, was imminent and would take place in the next few weeks or possibly months at the latest.
Mr Coffey said he was unaware of how many people had actually paid their water bill so far, adding that it was a matter for Irish Water to respond to.
I understand theres a board meeting due to happen next week... and I would encourage them to publish the payment figures then.
People before Profit TD Richard Boyd Barrett said earlier this week the amendments to the bill were desperate, devious and discriminatoryand were aimed at undermining the national movement against water charges.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:00:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyers for parents of Berkeley victim present claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/lawyers-for-parents-of-berkeley-victim-present-claims-1.2263390</Link>
        <Description>Lawyers for Ashley Donohoe’s parents claim student at party said balcony was ‘sloping’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Lawyers for parents of Berkeley victim present claims
Lawyers for Ashley Donohoes parents claim student at party said balcony was sloping
Images
Alameda County District Attorney Nancy O'Malley announces her office has launched an official, formal investigation into the Berkeley balcony collapse. Video: Alameda County District Attorney's Office
San Francisco law firm Rains Lucia Stern  representing George and Jackie Donohoe, the Irish parents of the late Ashley Donohoe (above) of Rohnert Park, California  presented  findings to Alameda County District Attorney Nancy OMalley on Thursday.
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 09:43
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 05:00
American lawyers for the parents of one of the six students killed in the Berkeley balcony collapse have presented evidence to the local district attorney which, they claim, shows a litany of ignored problems at the California building dating back years.
San Francisco law firm Rains Lucia Stern  representing George and Jackie Donohoe , the Irish parents of Ashley Donohoe (22) of Rohnert Park, California  presented their findings to Alameda County District Attorney Nancy OMalley on Thursday, shortly after she formally announced a criminal investigation into the June 16th balcony collapse that killed six and injured seven more.
Ms OMalley told reporters that each family of the six victims deserve to have this matter thoroughly and extensively investigated.
Balcony was sloping downwards before collapse, witness claims
She promised to examine whether there was enough evidence to prosecute a criminal negligence case.
The findings presented by the lawyers for the Donohoes include a statement from a student who was at the 21st birthday party on the night of the collapse. She said the balcony was sloping downwards, away from the building towards the street, before it collapsed.
Water infiltration
The law firm maintains there was a history of water infiltration and balcony decay at the Library Gardens building at 2020 Kittredge Street dating back to at least 2010.
They presented the District Attorney and her officials with photographs of water damage to the buildings exterior at the fourth-floor balcony showing streaking and staining as far back as 2008.
Complaints of rot, roof and plumbing leaks and flooding were made as recently as three months before the collapse, the law firm has said, and the failure by management to act led the residents to complain to housing authorities.
Before the district attorney took over the investigation, the law firm sent legal letters to the buildings owner Blackrock, property manager Greystar and to city officials, raising concern that the initial investigation into the balcony failure may not be truly independent or neutral.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Balcony was sloping downwards before collapse, witness claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/balcony-was-sloping-downwards-before-collapse-witness-claims-1.2263394</Link>
        <Description>Parents of victim Ashley Donohoe raised concerns about impartiality of investigation   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Balcony was sloping downwards before collapse, witness claims
Parents of victim Ashley Donohoe raised concerns about impartiality of investigation
Images
Alameda County District Attorney Nancy O'Malley announces her office has launched an official, formal investigation into the Berkeley balcony collapse. Video: Alameda County District Attorney's Office
The remaining wood from the Library Gardens apartment building balcony that collapsed  in Berkeley, California, killing six Irish students. Photograph: AP Photo/Jeff Chiu
George and Jackie Donohoe, the Irish parents of the late Ashley Donohoe (above), through their lawyers, contacted the owners and property managers of the Library Gardens student accommodation block in Berkeley, California, where the fatal June 16th incident occurred. They demanded notification of where the destroyed balcony was preserved.
Previous Image
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 09:29
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 05:00
Lawyers acting for the parents of one of the six students killed in Berkeleys balcony collapse sent legal letters over the past week calling for evidence to be preserved and raising concerns that the City of Berkeleys investigation may not have been truly independent.
George and Jackie Donohoe , the Irish parents of Ashley Donohoe (22), of Rohnert Park, California , through their lawyers, contacted the owners and property managers of the Library Gardens student accommodation block where the June 16th incident occurred.
They demanded notification of where the destroyed balcony was preserved.
Lawyers for parents of Berkeley victim present claims
In addition, the familys lawyers from the San Francisco firm Rains Lucia Stern met the Alameda County district attorney, Nancy OMalley, her second-in-command, Kevin Dunleavy , and a number of their officials to present the law firms findings of what they believe was wrong with the building.
Preserved evidence
At the outset, the familys main concern was that the initial investigation by the city was not independent and that the evidence was not being preserved for an independent and impartial analysis.
Ms OMalleys announcement on Thursday that she would carry out a criminal and civil investigation into the collapse has allayed their concerns somewhat.
Ms OMalley said the remains of the collapsed fourth-floor balcony and a third-floor balcony beneath that was removed are being preserved by Berkeley police and the county sheriff.
Harry Stern , a partner with Rains Lucia Stern, said the Donohoes retained the firm as a priority to make sure that a proper independent impartial investigation was being conducted because there were some very disturbing indications early on about what was happening.
Mr Stern said they were very heartened that Ms OMalley and Mr Dunleavy have taken over this investigation, describing it as a step in the right direction.
Not only are they independent, the district attorney department has the resources and expertise to conduct this kind of complex investigation. And, moreover, the two of them are very sensitive to the nature of this tragedy.
The law firm presented the DA with its own evidence, including a statement from an Irish student who was at the party on the night of the incident.
She said the balcony was sloping downwards away from the building towards the street before the collapse occurred.
History of decay
There was a history of water infiltration and balcony decay dating back to at least 2010, the lawyers claim. They presented the DA and her staff with a number of photographs showing water damage to the exterior of the balcony as far back as 2008.
They claim these signs should have put somebody responsible on notice that there could be a problem that needed to be investigated.
They also presented the county prosecutors with evidence of complaints of rot, roof leaks, plumbing leaks and flooding, some of which occurred as recently as three months ago.
Complaints were made to the City of Berkeley housing authority because the existing building management failed to act or were unresponsive to the complaints and concerns, the lawyers say.
Letters seen by The Irish Times show the Donohoes raised concerns about the investigation as soon as three days after the incident.
They wrote to Berkeley mayor Tom Bates , city manager Christine Daniel and planning and development director Eric Angstadt on June 19th, urging them to hire engineers and contractors who would independently and impartially provide a neutral and detailed analysis of the cause of this incident.
At the time, it had appeared Belfor Property Restoration , the company hired by the buildings owner, BlackRock , to remove the third-floor balcony, had been hired by a potentially responsible party.
How can a potentially responsible party conduct a truly independent investigation? the lawyers asked in the letter.
On Tuesday, the lawyers in a follow-up letter wrote to BlackRock, Greystar , the propertys management company that looked after the property for them, and Belfor.
The letter was sent just hours after the citys building inspectors concluded in a report that the fourth-floor balcony appeared severely dry rotted.
Balcony failure
The Donohoe family is grieving the loss of their loved one. . . they have also discovered information that causes them great concern that the investigation into the cause of the balcony failure may not be truly independent or neutral, Joseph Lucia , one of the lawyers at Rains Lucia Stern, told them.
Due to these concerns, the Donohoe family has requested that we contact you regarding the investigation of what occurred so there can be an independent and impartial analysis of the cause of the deadly balcony collapse.
The lawyers added that ensuring an independent and impartial analysis will allow for a swift and just conclusion of culpability, whether it be civil and/or criminal in nature.
The lawyers said that the findings of the city building inspectors report had only increased the amount of concern for the Donohoe family.
The family was particularly concerned at the very limited nature of the citys investigation because it was limited to the direct observations of the citys building and safety division in the immediate aftermath of the collapse and because forensic examination and laboratory tests were outside the scope of the review.
The lawyers noted there have been contractors, structural engineers and architects hired and paid for by BlackRock and Greystar to perform tests and analysis.
BlackRock has responded to the Donohoes attorneys telling them - before the District Attorney took possession of the balconies - they would co-operate by giving them access to the apartment building and other materials when made available to all parties.
BlackRock told them they would carry out further demolition and repairs starting on July 1st.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seán Haughey to be added to Fianna Fáil ticket</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/se%C3%A1n-haughey-to-be-added-to-fianna-f%C3%A1il-ticket-1.2263314</Link>
        <Description>TD Peter Fitzpatrick decides to run for Fine Gael after previously ruling himself out    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Sen Haughey to be added to Fianna Fil ticket
TD Peter Fitzpatrick decides to run for Fine Gael after previously ruling himself out
Sen Haughey: surprisingly defeated by Deirdre Heney at the Fianna Fil convention for the Dublin Bay North constituency.   Photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:04
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:04
Fianna Fil is likely to add former junior minister Sen Haughey to a general election ticket following his surprise defeat at a constituency selection convention earlier this week. Mr Haughey was beaten by Deirdre Heney , a councillor, at the Fianna Fil convention for the Dublin Bay North constituency, even though he was widely seen as the favourite.
The directive from party headquarters was to select just one candidate and Ms Heney has said she believes a single-candidate strategy is the best approach to take a seat in the five-seater constituency.
The decision whether or not to add Mr Haughey will be made by the Fianna Fil constituency committee, chaired by Cork North West TD Michael Moynihan . The task for the party is choosing which is the best option to win a seat, said one source, adding more likely than not Mr Haughey would be added.
Peter Fitzpatrick goes back on decision not to run for  Fine Gael
Mr Haughey, a son of former taoiseach Charles Haughey , did not return calls but party sources suggested he had been somewhat complacent in his approach to the convention. It was also suggested that some members who were supporters of Averil Power  who was expected to contest the convention but resigned from Fianna Fil  had switched to Ms Heney.
Separately, a councillor who lost out at a recent selection convention has left Fianna Fil, claiming he has become disillusioned with the party. Alan Coleman , the mayor of Cork county, says he will now stand as an Independent in Cork South West. He lost a Fianna Fil selection convention to fellow councillor, Margaret Murphy OMahony.
Meanwhile, a Fine Gael TD who said he was not standing for the party has changed his mind following a meeting with Taoiseach Enda Kenny. Louth TD Peter Fitzpatrick is understood to have secured a commitment from the Fine Gael hierarchy that the party ticket in the constituency would comprise only two candidates.
After announcing he was not standing for Fine Gael, Mr Fitzpatrick then suggested he could stand under a different banner, which reduced sympathy for him in the party. We mostly felt sorry for him, but that annoyed people, said one TD.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece crisis response likened to mutiny on ‘Bounty’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/greece-crisis-response-likened-to-mutiny-on-bounty-1.2263335</Link>
        <Description>‘EU and euro zone ministers  continuing to beat and punish Greece until its morale improves or it does what they want’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Greece crisis response likened to mutiny on Bounty
EU and euro zone ministers  continuing to beat and punish Greece until its morale improves or it does what they want
Senator Mark Daly: said Germany seemed to forget the 1953 London debt agreement whereby nearly 50% of its debt was written off.Photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:03
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:03
There were exchanges between Fianna Fil and Fine Gael in the Seanad over the Greek crisis. Mark Daly of Fianna Fil said the attitude of some of the EU governments could be likened to that of Captain Bligh of the mutiny on the Bounty.
When ordering some of the members of his crew to be given 50 lashes, he said the beatings would continue until morale improved. That is exactly what we are seeing in Europe where the EU and euro zone ministers are continuing to beat and punish Greece until its morale improves or it does what they want.
Paul Coghlan of Fine Gael remarked: That is a load of baloney.
Mr Daly said Germany seemed to forget the 1953 London debt agreement whereby nearly 50 per cent of its debt was written off. Greece might have incurred debt because of reckless spending but the Germans incurred the debt because they caused a world war, and yet they seem to be insisting that Greece would have to suffer the humiliation of a Versailles Treaty-type arrangement.
Maurice Cummins of Fine Gael, said reaching agreement for Greece would create certainty for the Greek people and secure their future. The euro zone has an obligation to Greece in this difficult time, but Greece has an obligation to itself. It certainly needs to reform the economy and return it to sustainable growth, which is not the case at the moment, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>National Concert Hall could benefit from pharma support</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/national-concert-hall-could-benefit-from-pharma-support-1.2263213</Link>
        <Description>Dáil debates Bill to put NCH on equal footing with other national cultural institutions   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
National Concert Hall could benefit from pharma support
Dil debates Bill to put NCH on equal footing with other national cultural institutions
Minister for Arts Heather Humphreys: I want to see it [the National Concert Hall] developed  as a world-class venue that showcases the highest standard of musical excellence. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
Pharmaceutical companies could have a philanthropic role in the work of the National Concert Hall , it has been suggested in the Dil.
Fianna Fil arts spokesman Sen  Fearghal said the concert hall was bringing music therapy into Irish hospitals and he asked if there was sufficiently widespread public appreciation of the work being done in that area.
Old and overmedicated: the drug problem in our nursing homes
He suggested that the NCH could benefit from pharmaceutical companies based in Ireland and the industry could realise the benefit of being associated with the work of the concert hall.
Mr  Fearghal was speaking during a debate on the National Cultural Institutions (National Concert Hall) Bill to change the National Concert Hall Company from a company limited by guarantee into a statutory body.
The change is expected to facilitate greater transparency and accountability in corporate governance and puts the concert hall on an equal footing with other national statutory cultural bodies.
Minister for Arts Heather Humphreys , who introduced the Bill, said Mr  Fearghals suggestion was a good idea and it should be progressed. She supported the business-to-arts initiative which offers businesses great opportunities to support the arts and said engaging with the arts helped employees to think outside the box and has proved to be very worthwhile.
She described the NCH as a major cultural asset. I want to see it developed as a world-class venue that showcases the highest standard of musical excellence. She added that the NCH should have clarity on all governance and operational issues. The Bill sets the number of board members at nine and the first board appointments will be staggered at three, four and five years to ensure continuity. Appointments will focus on a broad range of skills and expertise including, of course, musical experience.
Audience figures are on the rise at the venue which contributed 38 million directly to the local economy last year, the Minister said. The venue had a turnover of 6.8 million, ticket sales of just over 7 million. It hosted almost 900 events with some 330,000 people in attendance.
Refurbishment plans include the creation of a 130-seat performance space in the Kevin Barry rooms, where the Treaty ratification debates took place, and the transformation of the old medical library into a new 500-seat recital hall.
The 1,200 seat-auditorium will also be refurbished and a jazz club will be established, along with rehearsal spaces and recording studios. A series of concerts each day during Easter week next year will commemorate the 1916 Rising.
Mr  Fearghal said an arms-length approach in ministerial direction was vitally important but he suggested that we have moved from an intolerable level of ministerial involvement to a point where there seems to be a total absence of ministerial oversight. He said Fianna Fil opposed as a regressive act the amalgamation of the National Archives, the National Library and the Irish Manuscripts Commission.
Sinn Fin arts spokeswoman Sandra McLellan said the Bill provided the opportunity to acknowledge the importance of the National Concert Hall as a national asset.
Ms McLellan said that until recently, 70 per cent of the concert halls funding came from ticket sales, which she described as an encouraging figure that demonstrates peoples appetite for the arts.
Independent TD Finian McGrath said a country without arts is a country without a soul. People often ignored the great work being done in the arts, the number of people it employed, how the arts lift the countrys spirit and their significant financial contribution to the country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rheumatology clinics cancelled for 850 people in Galway, Dáil told </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/rheumatology-clinics-cancelled-for-850-people-in-galway-d%C3%A1il-told-1.2263265</Link>
        <Description>Minister Alex White promises one further  consultant from October   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Rheumatology clinics cancelled for 850 people in Galway, Dil told
Minister Alex White promises one further  consultant from October
Dara Calleary (Fianna Fil): asked if it was acceptable that a consultant had gone on maternity leave  and would not be replaced until September.  Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
More than 850 people were told this week by two Galway hospitals that all outpatient rheumatology clinics for July and August had been cancelled, Fianna Fil TD Dara Calleary told the Dil.
He said University College Hospital and Merlin Park University Hospital had said emergency outpatient appointments would be dealt with on a case-by-case basis. Already, he added, 1,500 people were on waiting lists at Merlin Park for outpatient rheumatology appointments.
When a person is diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis, there is a 12-week window within which there is a chance of dealing with the condition if he or she gets treatment, Mr Calleary added. If it goes longer, perhaps to 2 years, which is the length of time people are spending on the waiting list at the moment, the patients chance of beating that condition are severely restricted.
Mr Calleary asked if it was acceptable that a consultant had gone on maternity leave this week and would not be replaced until September, demonstrating a lack of planning. Is it acceptable that the appointment of a new rheumatology consultant to Manorhamilton, which was promised by the Taoiseach in December, still has not taken place ? he asked.
Is it acceptable that a consultant attached to Beaumont, one of our key hospitals, would tell a patient, as has happened this week, that he or she would be better off having urgent surgery at a private hospital because at Beaumont the wait would be 14 weeks ?
Minister for Communications, Energy and Natural Resources Alex White , who was taking Opposition Leaders Questions on the Governments behalf, said the HSE had advised that because of consultant staff shortages, a number of rheumatology outpatient clinics in Galway University Hospital were being postponed. New appointments would be scheduled as soon as possible and urgent patients would continue to be seen. Clinics in Manorhamilton would continue as normal, he added.
Mr White said there were currently three consultants covering outpatient clinics and an emergency intake and consult service in Galway University Hospital, as well as a day ward service in Merlin Park.
From October 1st, he added, there would be four consultant rheumatologists at Galway University Hospital. When extra medical staff are in place, the extra outpatient clinics will have to be held and will be held, Mr White said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Whistleblower makes new Ansbacher claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/whistleblower-makes-new-ansbacher-claims-1.2263295</Link>
        <Description> Document not circulated to PAC members as committee  told allegations were outside  its  remit   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Whistleblower makes new Ansbacher claims
Document not circulated to PAC members as committee  told allegations were outside  its  remit
Mary Lou McDonald: found to have breached Dil privilege by naming the politicians in the Dil chamber.   Photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
A whistleblower has named another former politician as having an Ansbacher account in a fresh document sent to politicians. Gerry Ryan , an official in the Department of Jobs , Enterprise and Innovation , had sent fresh correspondence to the Public Accounts Committee .
However, following legal advice, the document was not circulated to members and the committee was told the allegations were outside their remit. It is understood Mr Ryan criticised assurances by Revenue that all of his claims were investigated. He also named another politician who he alleges had an offshore account used to evade tax in the document sent to the committee.
PAC gets fresh whistleblower claims over Ansbacher accounts
The decision came down to a vote with only two members  Independent TD Shane Ross and Sinn Fin TD Mary Lou McDonald  voting in favour.
The committee met in private and Fine Gaels Patrick ODonovan said the letter should not be sent to members because it would then be read into the Dil chamber and produced in the media. This was said to be a direct reference to Ms McDonald who was found to have breached Dil privilege by naming the politicians in the chamber.
Fine Gael TD John Deasy told Mr Ross and Ms McDonald if they wanted the information they should contact Mr Ryan and seek the document. Afterwards, Mr Deasy said there had been no ambiguity about the legal advice. The legal adviser probably repeated five times that the committee had no remit to accept any part of correspondence, he said.
Mr Ryan is a senior official in the Department of Jobs, Enterprise and Innovation. He had served as the authorised officer under company law who investigated Ansbacher accounts in the Cayman Islands. He contended in a dossier given to the committee that a number of named former senior politicians had held such offshore accounts. This was denied by the politicians.
Revenue officials appeared before the committee and rejected the allegations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Banking Inquiry told of warning over  repeat  Lehman’s scenario </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/banking-inquiry-told-of-warning-over-repeat-lehman-s-scenario-1.2263160</Link>
        <Description>Central Bank chief Patrick Honohan insists bailout necessary regardless of  bank guarantee   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Banking Inquiry told of warning over  repeat  Lehmans scenario
Central Bank chief Patrick Honohan insists bailout necessary regardless of  bank guarantee
Patrick Honohan, governor of the Central Bank of Ireland, arriving at the Banking Inquiry at Leinster House, Dublin, June 25th, 2015. Photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A senior European official warned that Ireland could be a Lehman Brothers moment for Europe , the banking inquiry was told on Thursday.
It was a reference to the massive bankruptcy filing of the US-based global financial services company in 2008, not long before the issuing of the bank guarantee in Ireland.
Governor of the Central Bank Patrick Honohan told the committee when he joined the bank in 2009 there were no concerns about Ireland.
Banking Inquiry: Full coverage
Mr Honohan said this attitude changed dramatically in August 2010 and Ireland was the centre of attention.
I remember one senior colleague saying, Im afraid that Greece is Europes Bear Stearns but Ireland will be Europes Lehmans. That was in September 2010.
So, the view of Ireland had changed dramatically and it had changed dramatically because people had woken up to the scale of the banking losses being incurred by the State, and paid for, and the prospective budgetary situation.
Mr Honohan described how he first raised the prospect of a bailout with then minister for finance Brian Lenihan in April 2010.
Mr Lenihan told him Brussels was saying Portugal was next in line for the programme.
One month later, International Monetary Fund chief of mission to Ireland Ashoka Mody contacted Mr Honohan offering a precautionary line of credit.
The governor told the committee that Merrion Street rejected the proposal - but declined to say who made that call.
Mr Honohan told Mr Mody: I said Try it, it might be a good idea. They [the government] might not like it, but try it. It did not go anywhere.
Mr Honohan said he wrote to the European Central Bank raising concerns about the emerging problems in July 2010.
Dead silence
He said he expected an early meeting and to be quizzed about what was going on. Instead, he said, there was dead silence.
I thought this is good news, they must have figured it out for themselves. I wrote them another letter in August with the full information.
I did get a response then. Concern and anxiety was starting to build there.
Mr Honohan insisted the country would have needed a bailout, regardless of the bank guarantee.
He said the economic and banking crash had cost the State 100 billion - and that figure was still growing.
Mr Honohan said not guaranteeing the six institutions in September 2008 would have saved 10 billion at the most.
He said: All in all, a possible net economic saving in the area of 2-10 billion could be imagined, but surely no more than that.
If so, by September 2008, well over 90 per cent of the net economic cost to Ireland of the boom and bust had become unavoidable.
Mr Honohan said he wanted to put a figure on it because the narrative had been focused on whether the guarantee was the right decision. He said this was the least important question, but the most over-analysed.
He denied the ECB would ever have pulled funding from Ireland. It never would have availed of that decision, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine months for boy who stole from home of sleeping mother </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/nine-months-for-boy-who-stole-from-home-of-sleeping-mother-1.2263318</Link>
        <Description>Teenager was taken into care after death of  family member in tragic circumstances   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Nine months for boy who stole from home of sleeping mother
Teenager was taken into care after death of  family member in tragic circumstances
Dublin District Court, Smithfield. Photograph: Alan Betson
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A teenage boy in care who stole from the home of a woman, while she and her two small children were sleeping, has been sentenced to nine months in custody and nine months on probation.
The boy, who had previously pleaded guilty to the burglary and other theft charges, had been found by garda on one occasion through a stolen phones tracker app; he was living in a tent behind a garage.
On Thursday, in courtroom 55, in the Dublin District Childrens Court , Smithfield, the boys story and the impact his crime had on one of his victims unfolded.
The 16-year-old sat to the right of Judge John OConnor. . He leaned on his elbows on the long table he shared with solicitors and garda. His hands were clasped together and his chin rested on them, as the sentence hearing proceeded.
A garda reminded the judge of the charges against the boy, for which he was remanded in custody earlier this month.
Unlocked cars
Last September, the boy found unlocked cars and stole items including a camera and laptops from them. On September 6th, during the night, he entered the home of a woman in Bray, Co Wicklow, after noticing a key had been left in the front door. He stole her laptop from the kitchen, 500 from her purse and her keys, before going upstairs into her bedroom and stealing her phone. She and her two young children remained asleep.
All of the items stolen were recovered, except for the cash, the garda said.
In her victim impact statement, read into the record by a garda, the woman said her world had been turned upside down by the robbery.
She did not sleep for two weeks afterwards and worried about what might have happened if she or her children had woken. She felt her home had been invaded and she had failed to protect her children. Her property was taken for which she had worked so hard, as a single parent, she said, and it was truly frightening and horrific that the thief had taken her keys.
Domino effect
She could no longer live in the house and had to move to a smaller one, with higher rent. There had been a domino effect and it was one of the worst experiences of her life. Yes, it has changed my view of Ireland, she said.
Judge OConnor read out the probation report on the boy. It said the Child and Family Agency was involved with his family since 2011 and the boy was taken into care last year, after the death of a family member in tragic circumstances.
He ran away from foster carers and was missing in care.
The probation officer said he had formed the impression the boy carried out the crimes to meet his basic needs. He also said the boy struggled since the death of the family member and there were concerns he misused tablets.
He had dropped out of secondary school but was going to school since being in custody, in a childrens detention centre. He had settled well, and his behaviour was excellent, but there were concerns about his mental health.
The boys solicitor said his client had got involved with a very negative peer group, and there was a belief he needed the money to live. He was also fully co-operative with garda.
The judge said it was tragic the boy had such a terrible youth, but his lifestyle was now so pro-criminal that something had to be done. He said he was not unconscious of the boys circumstances and hoped he would be successful in his school course.
The boy nodded his head at the judge and signed a form. He will appear in court again next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eoghan Ó Neachtain joins company with Fine Gael links</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/eoghan-%C3%B3-neachtain-joins-company-with-fine-gael-links-1.2263367</Link>
        <Description> Spokesman worked for Bertie Ahern, Brian Cowen and Enda Kenny   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Eoghan  Neachtain joins company with Fine Gael links
Spokesman worked for Bertie Ahern, Brian Cowen and Enda Kenny
Eoghan  Neachtain assisting German chancellor Angela Merkel in  Dublin in 2008. Photograph: Eric Luke
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A former government press secretary who served three different taoisigh has been appointed as a director of a public relations company with strong Fine Gael links.
Eoghan  Neachtain served as spokesman for Bertie Ahern , Brian Cowen and Enda Kenny during his career in government. He is understood to be the only person to serve as government press secretary in three administrations.
Mr  Neachtain, who also worked in the semi-State sector, has been made director of public affairs at Heneghan PR.
The company was founded by Pat Heneghan , one of Garret FitzGeralds so-called national handlers, and also employed Bill OHerlihy, Frank Flannery and Enda Marren .
Mr  Neachtain has also served in the Irish Defence Forces . He is a regular contributor on national radio and television and is well known as a rugby analyst on TG4 .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Simon Coveney receives report on 1981 attack on soldiers in Lebanon </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/simon-coveney-receives-report-on-1981-attack-on-soldiers-in-lebanon-1.2263374</Link>
        <Description>Pte Hugh Doherty died and Pte Kevin Joyce disappeared in action with  UN Interim Force   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Simon Coveney receives report on 1981 attack on soldiers in Lebanon
Pte Hugh Doherty died and Pte Kevin Joyce disappeared in action with  UN Interim Force
Pte Hugh Doherty, of Letterkenny, Co Donegal, who was killed in Lebanon. Photograph: Declan Doherty
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
Minister for Defence Simon Coveney has received a report on the death of one soldier and the disappearance of another in Lebanon in 1981.
The report, an independent review of the investigation into the death of Pte Hugh Doherty and the disappearance of Pte Kevin Joyce (Caomhn Seoighe), is expected to be published in the coming days.
The two men were serving with the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon, manning an observation post at Dayr Ntar, when they came under attack.
Pte Doherty was later found dead from gunshot wounds and Pte Joyce was missing. The attackers are unknown. To date, no information has been elicited to lead to the recovery of Pte Joyces remains.
The review of the deaths and subsequent investigations was carried out by retired High Court Judge Roderick Murphy, at Mr Coveneys request.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brendan Smyth’s victims to sue Garda for damages</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/brendan-smyth-s-victims-to-sue-garda-for-damages-1.2263205</Link>
        <Description>Evidence to Historical Institutional Abuse inquiry has prompted legal proceedings   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Brendan Smyths victims to sue Garda for damages
Evidence to Historical Institutional Abuse inquiry has prompted legal proceedings
Victims of paedophile priest Brendan Smyth are to sue An Garda Siochna over its failure to take action when they were allegedly notified in the 1970s that Smyth was a child sex abuser. Photograph: Alan Betson
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
Victims of paedophile priest Brendan Smyth are to sue An Garda Sochna for damages over its failure to take action when they were allegedly notified in the early 1970s that Smyth was a child sex abuser, it was stated on Thursday.
Belfast solicitor Kevin Winters said he was instructed to take legal proceedings against the Garda following evidence provided to the Historical Institutional Abuse Inquiry on Thursday that garda in Finglas were alerted in 1973 that Smyth was suffering from paedophilia.
That information emerged through the disclosure of confidential documents from St Patricks Hospital in Dublin where in 1973 Smyth was receiving psychiatric treatment for his sexual propensities.
Sean Brady says abuse kept secret to save churchs good name
Letter
A number of victims of Smyths abuse have asked us to write to the Garda Commissioner to find out why they didnt act on a letter sent to Finglas Garda station in 1973, said Mr Winters.
Our clients are shocked to learn that the document didnt alert garda and the authorities to the very real risk of future abuse by Smyth.
It has been deeply re-traumatising for them to learn about the contents of this letter and to that end feel they have no alternative but to issue civil proceedings for damages for what on the face of it was an appalling failure to take meaningful steps to prevent crimes against the innocent and vulnerable.
A Garda spokesman said that as the inquiry is ongoing it would be inappropriate to comment.
Margaret McGuckian of victims group Savia said it was beyond comprehension to think that so many peoples lives could have been different had the authorities acted sooner.
It is a bad day for the garda but we also want to know why it took so long for these documents to be handed over. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First  Irish death  over  online pills  may  force a reckoning </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/health/first-irish-death-over-online-pills-may-force-a-reckoning-1.2263378</Link>
        <Description>Crackdown on illegal medicines about to get tougher as online trade continues to grow   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
First  Irish death  over  online pills  may  force a reckoning
Crackdown on illegal medicines about to get tougher as online trade continues to grow
No internet pharmacy, whether legitimate or not in another country, can supply drugs to customers in Ireland. That hasnt stopped the flow of medicines into Ireland from overseas merchants hawking their wares on the web.
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
Warnings about the dangers of purchasing medicines on the internet have become commonplace in recent years, but the first known Irish death of a person from consuming pills bought illegally online may finally force people to take heed.
The law, which predates the internet era, is clear: mail order of prescription-only medicines, including internet supply, is illegal.
That means no internet pharmacy, whether legitimate or not in another country, can supply drugs to customers in Ireland.
Discredited DNP raises bodys metabolic rate and can  damage  liver and kidneys
That hasnt stopped the flow of medicines into Ireland from overseas merchants hawking their wares on the web.
It is impossible to know exactly how much use consumers are making of the internet to satisfy their drug requirements, but the rising level of seizures of counterfeit and illegal medicines seized is one indicator.
Last week, the Irish authorities put on display a sample of the 142,000 tablets and capsules they seized as part of an international operation over a single week in over 100 countries.
Painkillers
The value of the haul, over 430,000, gives an indication of the size of the trade. Sedatives, painkillers, weight loss products, anabolic steroids and erectile dysfunction products were among the items seized after they arrived from Singapore, the US, India, the UK and other countries.
There are many strands, and many linked dangers, to the growing international trade in prescription medicines. Some Irish consumers have undoubtedly been driven online by the high cost of their prescription drugs at home.
Others seek unfettered access to medicines for which they would normally need a prescription. Still others want to procure products which are illegal in Ireland.
Taking any medicine without proper medical supervision is risky. Issues arise as to dosage, pre-existing conditions, combinations with other drugs and the availability of follow-up treatment.
The other main problem is the lack of quality control in relation to much of what is being sold online. Up to half of the medicines seized in Ireland have been found to be unreliable and potentially harmful.
Often, the medicine doesnt actually include the claimed active ingredient or includes the wrong dosage. Products may be bulked up with harmful substances, or passed off as natural or herbal when they are anything but.
Awareness
Most consumers of online medicines must have some level of awareness of these risks, but show themselves willing to take them anyway.
DNP (Dinitrophenol), the drug implicated in the death of a young man in mid-May, has been on the banned drug list for almost 80 years. Originally an industrial compound used in the manufacture of explosives, its potential for causing side-effects and even death have been known for some time.
The drug is often marketed to bodybuilders keen to lose fat and maximise a ripped or muscular appearance. Even in this milieu the dangers of DNP are well-known, yet a minority continues to use it, believing the advantage of massive fat loss outweighs these risks.
Some have paid for this belief with their life; worldwide, DNP has been linked to more than 60 deaths.
The authorities  the Garda Sochna , Revenues Customs &amp; Excise service and the Health Products Regulatory Authority  have made arrests and closed down websites in pursuit of their investigations into the trade of illegal medicines.
International co-operation is increasing under the leadership of Interpol , so there is at least a chance the purveyors of deadly chemicals may be pursued. However, the international trade in drugs is not going to disappear any time soon.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RTÉ lied about abuse, former archbishop tells High Court jury</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/high-court/rt%C3%A9-lied-about-abuse-former-archbishop-tells-high-court-jury-1.2263344</Link>
        <Description>Richard Burke  paid woman €176,000 to keep quiet about relationship, counsel says   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
RT lied about abuse, former archbishop tells High Court jury
Richard Burke  paid woman 176,000 to keep quiet about relationship, counsel says
Former Archbishop of Benin Richard Burke pictured leaving the Four Courts yesterday. Photograph: Courts Collins
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A former Catholicarchbishop has told a High Court jury that he was portrayed during an RT television programme as leading a young girl upstairs to his bedroom to sexually abuse, sexually assault and rape her.
I could not believe my eyes, Richard Burke said. This did not happen. I did not do that. What is portrayed there is a lie. When his counsel, Jack Fitzgerald SC, asked, Are you a paedophile? he replied, No.
Mr Burke (66), from Co Tipperary, said he was living in London with a member of his order, the Kiltegan Fathers , when Prime Time Investigates: Mission to Prey was screened on May 23rd, 2011.
He could not get access to RT TV, but his niece sent him texts which, as the programme went on, progressed from this is bad to this is really bad to, in essence, this is as bad as it can be. On getting those texts, my heart began to sink and sink and sink into darkness, utter fear.
He was unable to watch the full programme until about a month later when he saw it at his sisters home. His impression was that he was being accused of being a paedophile, especially in a section involving a dramatisation where a young girl was led upstairs.
A reference by the reporter that he had declined to be interviewed gave me a hook to hang on to because he got no invitation to respond to the claims being made, he said. That was tiny in comparison to the feeling of helplessness.

Evidence
Mr Burke has begun his evidence in his action against RT alleging he was defamed in the Mission to Prey programme, which included an interview with a Nigerian woman, Dolores Atwood . Mr Burke claims he had sexual relations with Ms Atwood, now aged 45, as an adult but not when she was under age. Having spent decades in Nigeria after his ordination in 1975, he tendered his resignation as archbishop of Benin in April 2010 over his failure to adhere to his vow of celibacy.

RT denies defamation and pleads a defence of truth concerning the contents of the programme relating to Mr Burke. It denies that the content bears some of the meanings alleged by Mr Burke, including that he was a rapist.
Mr Fitzgerald has told the jury that Ms Atwood leaned on Mr Burke about their relationship and that he had paid her 176,000, plus $4,300, to keep quiet. Counsel said he had also mistakenly told the jury that Ms Atwood sought an additional 50,000, when that sum was part of the 176,000.
Some of the 176,000 had come out of diocesan funds, money that Mr Burke had made an agreement with the Vatican to repay, counsel said.
The case continues.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:44:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>LÉ Eithne rescues 593 migrants off coast of Libya</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/l%C3%A9-eithne-rescues-593-migrants-off-coast-of-libya-1.2265662</Link>
        <Description>Irish Naval Service vessel carries out six rescue operations in North African region    </Description>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Bid to reunite owners with stolen items worth 150,000
Ten boats, 74 outboard engines and a caravan  among   property found during searches
Could this be your boat? Photograph: Garda/facebook
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:38
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:38
Missing a boat, trailer, or outboard engine? Well, you could be in luck as garda are looking to reunite owners with stolen goods worth about 150,000.
Among the items waiting to be reclaimed are ten boats, 16 trailers, 74 outboard engines, one caravan and two generators.
The property was found by garda during a number of searches in Portlaoise, Co Laois on June 25th and 26th as part of an investigation into boat engine thefts.
Recovered property appeal for owners Portlaoise Garda, all 127 images of property now available here http://t.co/d1GJnbPN1k ph 057 8674100
 Garda Info (@gardainfo) July 7, 2015
Det Sgt John Healy , from Portlaoise Garda station, said people who have had outboard engines or property stolen lately should look at the photographs.
We are appealing to people all over the country who may have had an outboard engine stolen to look at the photos and see if their engine is amongst the property we have here, he said.
We feel that the engines could belong to people countrywide, so were asking everyone from Killybegs to Castletownbere to look.
Those who think they have spotted property which was stolen from them are asked to email portlaoise.property@garda.ie or ring (057) 8674100 to arrange a viewing.
To view all to photographs click here www.facebook.com/angardasiochana
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:19:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anglo trial hears of concerns raised on ‘Denis O’Brien’ account</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/circuit-court/anglo-trial-hears-of-concerns-raised-on-denis-o-brien-account-1.2276288</Link>
        <Description>Brian Gillespie  didn’t believe it was ‘the Denis O’Brien most people have in their minds’    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Anglo trial hears of concerns raised on Denis OBrien account
Brian Gillespie  didnt believe it was the Denis OBrien most people have in their minds
Former Anglo Irish Bank official Tiarnan OMahoney at Dublin Circuit Criminal Court on Tuesday. Photograph: Court Collins
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:24
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:19
When Anglo Irish Bank was making a return to Revenue in 2003 related to non-resident accounts, former chairman Sean FitzPatrick raised concerns about an account held by Denis OBrien, the trial of three former bank officials has been told.
Brian Gillespie , former head of compliance at Anglo, said Mr FitzPatrick was concerned about Mr OBrien, whom he referred to as my mate Denis. But Mr Gillespie reassured him it was not the same Mr OBrien.
I didnt believe, I do not believe for a second, it was anything to do with the Denis OBrien most people have in their minds, he said.
Anglo trial told origin of payment to account disappeared
It was a different individual who genuinely was a non-resident in the UK.
Cross-examining, Brendan Grehan SC, for Tiarnan OMahoney, asked Mr Gillespie what Mr FitzPatricks response was to his reassurance.
He described me as a bit naive, Mr Gillespie responded.
Aoife Maguire (60) of Rothe Abbey , South Circular Road, Kilmainham, Dublin, Bernard Daly (65) of Collins Avenue West, Whitehall, Dublin and Mr OMahoney (54) of Glen Pines , Enniskerry , Co Wicklow have been charged with trying to hide accounts, connected to the former chairman of the bank, Sean FitzPatrick, from Revenue between March 2003 and December 2004.
They have pleaded not guilty.
Mr Gillespie was involved with a team preparing a list of non-resident accounts to be sent to Revenue as part of a High Court order in 2003. He was removed from the team before the list was sent, the court has been told.
Under cross-examination, Mr Gillespie detailed three meetings he had in the office of Mr FitzPatrick in and around May 2003. He agreed with Mr Grehan that the meetings were held after Revenue obtained the High Court order and before the information was provided.
He said the meetings involved just the two of them. On the first occasion he did not know what was going to be discussed. He said Mr FitzPatrick was querying why accounts held by his brother-in-law John Peter OToole were being included in the return to revenue. He said he was aware Mr FitzPatrick was concerned about a relative being reported to Revenue and he was protective of family members in a normal way.
He said Mr FitzPatrick gave him a potted history and said Mr OToole had lived in the UK and now lived in Australia and was supporting his mother.
Mr Gillespie said he explained the list being sent was not a list of bogus non-resident accounts, it was a list of accounts that fitted the criteria laid down in the High Court order.
A week or 10 days later, he was summoned to Mr FitzPatricks office again.
Round two, so to speak? Mr Grehan suggested.
I didnt see it as a boxing match, Mr Gillespie responded, to laughter in the court.
He said on this occasion, Mr FitzPatrick told him of a conversation with a director of the bank, Peter Killen . Mr FitzPatrick said Mr Killeen told him just tell Brian to delete the account.
Asked by Mr Grehan if he got a chance to respond to the comment, Mr Gillespie said he did not have the opportunity; it was part of a monologue.
He said at the end, he reminded Mr FitzPatrick of the High Court order and said they had no choice but to comply. He said the meeting was inconclusive.
How do you know when to leave? Mr Grehan asked.
As soon as you get an opportunity, Mr Gillespie answered.
Mr Gillespie said, at a third meeting a week or 10 days later, Mr FitzPatrick told him again he was concerned.
He said he didnt mind telling me he was losing sleep over it, he said.
Mr FitzPatrick repeated that he had a conversation with Mr Killen, but on this occasion, said he told Mr Killen I should just tell Brian to delete the account. Mr Gillespie said it crossed his mind at the time if the conversation had taken place at all or whether Mr FitzPatrick was confused.
At no time did he ask me to delete the account ... but if I was to find it within myself not to report the account he would be greatly pleased, Mr Gillespie said.
He said there was no way he was going to leave it out of the court order.
Mr Grehan suggested Mr FitzPatrick was putting the burden on his shoulders.
He didnt instruct me ... it was clear what he wanted, Mr Gillespie responded.
He also agreed with Mr Grehan that Mr FitzPatrick had mentioned that he wanted Mr Gillespie to be comfortable with his actions in case he was ever part of a tribunal. And it was also at this meeting that Mr FitzPatrick raised concerns about Mr OBrien.
Asked by Sean Guerin SC, for Mr Daly, if Mr FitzPatrick was a man who was used to getting his way, Mr Gillespie said that was fair.
The case continues before Judge Patrick McCartan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:10:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pat Rabbitte departure big blow to Labour ahead of election</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/pat-rabbitte-departure-big-blow-to-labour-ahead-of-election-1.2276283</Link>
        <Description>Analysis: Party already lost wealth of experience in Eamon Gilmore and Ruairí Quinn   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Pat Rabbitte departure big blow to Labour ahead of election
Analysis: Party already lost wealth of experience in Eamon Gilmore and Ruair Quinn
Pat Rabbitte has confirmed that he will not stand for re-election. Photograph: Dara Mac Donaill / The Irish Times
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:10

Pat Rabbitte ended months of speculation yesterday by confirming he will not stand for re-election.
The former Labour leader told his party colleagues of his decision last night.
The news is a big blow to the Labour party who have already lost two of its former leaders in Eamon Gilmore and Ruair Quinn.
Labours Pat Rabbitte will not run in general election
With them they take a wealth of experience that the Labour party desperately needs going into what will be a critical general election for them.
Some would say it is out with the old and in with the new. But there is no new - there are no natural successors for any of the three men in their constituencies.
Mr Rabbittes departure is a double blow for Labour because he was one of a few TDs who was guaranteed re-election.
A recent internal poll showed he would be the third candidate elected in Dublin South West.
His constituency colleague Eamonn Maloney was on an unelectable 3 per cent in the Labour poll.
So with him he takes a safe Labour seat - one of only a few the party has. Leader Joan Burton and deputy leader Alan Kellys seats are hardly secure in what are two extremely tough constituencies.
Relations between Ms Burton and Mr Rabbitte were practically non-existent, but as the TD packs his bags and heads for radio and TV studios across the country, even Ms Burton must be concerned about his departure.
Mr Rabbitte wasnt the first and he might not be the last.There are also question marks over whether TDs Sean Kenny , Jack Wall , Kathleen Lynch and Eamonn Maloney will run again.
The election will be a bruising one for the Labour party.
The latest poll showed them slump to 7 per cent and with their most experienced troops jumping overboard, things are looking bleak for the Labour party.
Joan Burton already had a huge task ahead of her to convince the electorate to trust Labour again.
That infamous job of work to do just got a lot tougher.
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:10

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:37:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man arrested in lead up to Prince Charles’ visit seeks bail </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/man-arrested-in-lead-up-to-prince-charles-visit-seeks-bail-1.2276273</Link>
        <Description>Donal O Coisdealbha charged with membership of an unlawful organisation     </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Man arrested in lead up to Prince Charles visit seeks bail
Donal O Coisdealbha charged with membership of an unlawful organisation
A file image showing Prince Charles arriving at the National University of Ireland in Galway on May 18th. Photograph: Darren Staples/Retuers
Topics:
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 12:37
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 12:37
A man arrested on IRA and explosives charges in the lead up to Prince Charles official State visit will make a renewed bail application later this month.
Donal O Coisdealbha (23), of Abbeyfield, Killester Dublin 15, was charged with membership of an unlawful organisation styling itself the Irish Republican Army , otherwise glaigh na hireann, otherwise the IRA within the State on May 13th 2015.
Mr O Coisdealbha was also charged with possession of a component part of an improvised explosive device namely a time and power unit also known as a TPU at the personal storage locker under the control of Donal O Coisdealbha at Protector Life Sciences, National University of Ireland Maynooth, Co Kildare under such circumstances as to give rise to a reasonable suspicion that he had not got it in his possession for a lawful purpose on May 13th, 2015.
Counsel for Mr O Coisdealbha, Dean Kelly BL, told the non-jury Special Criminal Court on Tuesday that his side intended to make a renewed bail application.
Bail had been refused in May, Mr Kelly said.
The refusal was appealed to the High Court and upheld.
Mr Kelly said part of the material on which Mr O Coisdealbha was refused bail may be other than was first thought.
His case will be that the transcription of an alleged telephone call involving Mr O Coisdealbha was transcribed in a certain way and should be transcribed in a different way.
There wasnt the first suggestion of any wrongdoing, Mr Kelly said, but it was central to the refusal.
Circumstances had changed enormously.
Counsel for the Director of Public Prosecutions , Vincent Heneghan BL, said it was part of the reason for refusal not the central part.
Mr Justice Tony Hunt , presiding alongside Judge Alison Lindsay and Judge Cormac Dunne , listed the bail application for Tuesday July 21st next.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Divide by Sheep | Game Review</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/culture/games/game-reviews/divide-by-sheep-game-review-1.2276247</Link>
        <Description>Dark humour meets maths in this clever puzzle game   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Divide by Sheep | Game Review
Dark humour meets maths in this clever puzzle game
Game Title: Divide By Sheep
Publisher: TinyBuild
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 12:30
 
I am not really a maths person. Its not that Im particularly bad at it, its just that long division and algebra arent really my favourite ways to pass the time. So when Divide by Sheep landed on my desk, it caused a little trepidation.
But as far as puzzle games go, Divide By Sheep is a twisted tale. The Grim Reaper is feeling a little lonely and has decided that hed like a few friends to keep him company. His buddy of choice? A few fluffy sheep, the odd wolf here and there, maybe a pig or two - you know, the usual companions.
His method of persuasion is to send a flood that will drown them all, leaving the animals stranded in groups of varying sizes on tiny islands with different obstacles and traps in between, from fences to predators. Your objective is to negotiate these obstacles and get a certain number of animals to a liferaft to earn stars. Too many and the life raft sinks; too few and it just wont go anywhere.
Sliced sheep
For each puzzle, you complete, you get a star. Getting three stars means that you, effectively, win the level. The sheep dont always come out the best though. Some have been flipped through lasers, which slice the sheep in half. They get taped back together on the raft when theyre rescued, but in the meantime, they take up double the space, which you have to factor in when making your calculations.
At times, its like the fox, chicken and sack of grain riddle. Except the fox is a wolf, the chicken is a sheep and the sack of grain is an exploding platform made from TNT. The wolves will eat whatever sheep land on their platform, which is a nice way of trimming the herd when you need to. Its also a way of keep a TNT-loaded platform from exploding when you remove the sheep; the wolf is so weighed down by its meal, it will no longer flip to the other platforms.
The replay value is decent, because getting all three stars on many of the later levels is fiendishly difficult. Stars serves a purpose besides bragging rights: you need a certain number to unlock the next world. Getting a single star is enough to move on to the next level, but sooner or later youll need the others to progress. At the moment, there are 120 levels spread across four worlds, but theres the promise of more coming soon.
Divide By Sheep wont quite make you a maths genius, but its certainly fun. Worth a shot.
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 12:30
 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:04:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hospitals advised on improving safety and quality</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/health/hospitals-advised-on-improving-safety-and-quality-1.2276262</Link>
        <Description>Hiqa says improvements do not require additional financial resources   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Hospitals advised on improving safety and quality
Hiqa says improvements do not require additional financial resources
A new report by Hiqa has highlighted the frequency of recommendations repeated in healthcare reports for Irish hospitals and healthcare providers
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 12:04
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 12:04
Hospitals and other healthcare providers have been provided with new guidance for improving quality and safety by linking recommendations in official reports with national standards.
A report from the Health Information and Quality Authority (Hiqa) highlights the frequency with which recommendations in its reports are linked to national standards for providing quality healthcare.
To date, Hiqa has completed seven investigations, one statutory inquiry and three reviews. These include reports into hospitals in Ennis, Mallow, Portlaoise and Galway, prompted by specific adverse events.
The resulting reports have made 232 recommendations requiring hospitals to ensure their model of service is well planned, clearly articulated and fully understood by all those involved in providing it.
The largest group of recommendations, 40 in total, in the reports related to the need for formalised accountability and governance. Twenty-two recommendations related to the importance of the correct model of care, and 16 each on evidence of best practice ad monitoring the effectiveness of healthcare. Fourteen related to the importance of integrated care, management arrangements and monitoring arrangements for acting on opportunities to improve care.
The authority says many improvements to patient safety do not involve additional financial resources. Rather, they involve commitment of competent individuals to planning, managing and working in the service to ensure effective safe practices.
It says: It is recognised that all individuals working in healthcare can improve patient safety by engaging with patients and their families, learning from errors, sharing the learning across the service and communicating effectively within and across the healthcare team.
Understanding all of the contributory issues that lead to errors is fundamental for considering the changes that need to be put in place to try to prevent the same errors being repeated.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:15:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stormont committee to ‘drill down to details’ of Nama row</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/stormont-committee-to-drill-down-to-details-of-nama-row-1.2276227</Link>
        <Description>Mick Wallace alleges NI politician or party may have been set to benefit £7 million from sale   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Stormont committee to drill down to details of Nama row
Mick Wallace alleges NI politician or party may have been set to benefit 7 million from sale
The Parliament Buildings in the Stormont Estate in Belfast. Photograph: PA/Paul Faith.
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:32
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 11:15
The Stormont finance committee met today to discuss the allegations by independent TD Mick Wallace that a Northern Ireland politician or party may have been set to benefit by up to 7 million as a result of a Nama sale.
The meeting was convened by the Sinn Fin chairman of the committee Daithi McKay who said that there are questions that need to be answered and they need to be answered quickly arising from Mr Wallaces claims.
Opening the meeting Mr McKay said it was important to drill down and get to the details of the case. He said there was also an issue of public confidence around the claims.
Nama affair makes businesses nervous
Sinn Fin committee member Mairtin O Muilleoir said that the Leinster House Public Accounts Committee was also examining the allegations and it was important that there should be close cooperation between the PAC and the Stormont finance committee.
Ulster Unionist MLA Leslie Cree said the claims were casting a shadow on all of us and it was therefore important to try to get to the bottom of the case.
The decision to hold the emergency meeting of the finance committee today follows from concerns expressed in the Dil last week by Mr Wallace about the sale, known as Project Eagle, of a Nama 850-property portfolio in Northern Ireland. The portfolio, originally valued at 4.5 billion, was sold to the US private equity firm Cerberus for less than 1.5 billion.
Mr Wallace said that a routine audit at Tughans solicitors had found that 7 million relating to the sale had been diverted to an Isle of Man account reportedly earmarked for a Northern Ireland politician or political party.
Mr O Muilleoir said it had to be established was Nama somehow compromised in the sale of the huge portfolio in that was there less money paid than should have been paid.
He said the committee should also seek to establish were there any kick-backs paid to anybody involved or were there any fixers involved in the process.
The committee today came up with a provisional list of people and businesses who should be invited to give evidence to its inquiry. It hopes to hold its first hearings on Wednesday and Thursday of next week.
Committee chairman Mr McKay said We will be inviting a number of key players concerned. A number of these players have said that they have nothing to hide, that they have done nothing untoward, so there should no issue with them attending.
Among several witnesses it wants to hear from are Ian Coulter, Tughans solicitors and the Law Society in Northern Ireland.
Mr Coulter is the former managing partner of Tughans in whose personal Isle of Man account, according to Tughans, the 7 million was lodged.
Tughans said that money was retrieved and that Mr Coulter subsequently left the company.
He also stood down as head of the Confederation of British Industry in Northern Ireland. The Law Society is investigating the alleged actions of Mr Coulter.
It also wants to hear evidence from Brian Rowntree and Frank Cushnahan who were Northern Ireland advisors to Nama. It also wants to speak to Mr Cushnahan in his capacity as an advisor to Tughans and his linkage to the disposal of Namas Northern Ireland portfolio.
It wants to hear from Nama and from Mr Wallace who, as the finance chairman Mr McKay said today, with his allegations kicked the whole thing off last week.
He obviously has some information that would be useful to the committee, and we would certainly welcome his participation in our inquiries, he said.
The committee also wants to speak to representatives from Cerebrus who bought the portfolio and from Pimco, another US investment firm, which had been interested in purchasing the 850-property portfolio.
The committee also decided that former DUP finance minister Sammy Wilson who was involved in Nama discussions with the late Minister for Finance Brian Lenihan should be asked to give evidence.
It also said any politicians who had relevant dealings with Cerebrus and/or Pimco should give evidence.
SDLP committee member Dominic Bradley said that one of key allegations was that politicians were involved. It would be remiss to call legal personnel and business people and property speculators and so on and not to call politicians, he said.
There is evidence that politicians met with Pimco and with Cerebrus. I think those politicians should be witnesses during our investigations. Otherwise we would stand to be accused of calling on others except politicians to task, he added.
The chairman Mr McKay agreed. He said, We are making a public call today that if any elected representatives have information that is of relevance to the committee they should bring it forward and bring it forward now and not say somewhere down the line that they were not aware of this call.
DUP committee member Paul Girvan said it was important to start hearing evidence as soon as possible as with the rumours of political involvement in a dirty scheme there was a cloud hanging over this place.
Potentially that has an impact on how this institution is viewed, albeit probably not very well, I think it is vitally important that we move as quickly as possible to get some resolutions to the matter, he added.
Committee chairman Mr McKay said that the committee had the power to compel witnesses to give evidence.
He said if there were indications that some people would not take up invitations to attend then the committee should consider using those compulsion powers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:51:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Noonan had no issue with Varoufakis, Howlin says </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/noonan-had-no-issue-with-varoufakis-howlin-says-1.2276178</Link>
        <Description>‘You see shocking pictures of people crying because they’ve no money or in rubbish bins’    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Noonan had no issue with Varoufakis, Howlin says
You see shocking pictures of people crying because theyve no money or in rubbish bins
Former Greek finance minister Yanis Varoufakis: Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin said his colleague Michael Noonan had no issue with Mr Varoufakis.
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 09:51
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 09:51
Minister for Finance Michael Noonan did not have a problem with former Greek finance minister Yanis Varoufakis , according to Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin .
Mr Varoufakis , who has been replaced by Euclid Tsakalotos, said on Monday he had been made aware some eurogroup participants would prefer him to be absent from meetings.
Mr Howlin said denied Mr Noonan had taken this stance.
No, as far as Im aware...Michael has never said anything to me in relation to Yanis Varoufakis, he said on his way into a Cabinet meeting on Tuesday.
We deal with whoever is there and theres been a variety of ministers from a variety of countries, some of whose views we agree with, some of whose views we dont, and we work collaboratively with everybody.
Mr Howlin said while there had been a certain amount of excitement about the changes in political personalities in Greece in recent days, this was a serious time and the Greek people were suffering grievously.
You see shocking pictures of people crying because theyve no money or scrambling in rubbish bins for food. Thats a reality that is unacceptable and we need to find solutions to ensure that the people of Greece have dignity into the future.
He said there was a great longing for solidarity across Europe .
I know from the Irish Government perspective we want a deal to be struck. We want Greece to be part of the euro zone and remain a strong vibrant part of the union, and I hope that terms can be agreed that are fair to everybody to achieve that objective.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:20:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rabbitte would have contested election if still in Cabinet </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/rabbitte-would-have-contested-election-if-still-in-cabinet-1.2276166</Link>
        <Description>Brendan Howlin says Pat Rabbitte’s decision not to contest election is a ‘loss to politics’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Rabbitte would have contested election if still in Cabinet
Brendan Howlin says Pat Rabbittes decision not to contest election is a loss to politics
Former minister for communication Pat Rabbitte who said he had nothing lined for when he left politics. Photograph: The Irish Times.
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 13:13
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 09:20
Former Labour Party leader and minister for communication Pat Rabbitte has said he would be obligated to contest the election if still a Minister.
Speaking on RT radio about his decision to not to contest the next general election, Mr Rabbitte denied the decision was him taking issue with being demoted by Tnaiste Joan Burton.
Mr Rabbitte said: If you look at the record it has been a year since the Cabinet reshuffle. I have promoted and advocated for the party consistently over the past 12 months.
Labours Pat Rabbitte will not run in general election
He also rejected a suggestion his decision would result in the loss of a Labour Party seat in Dublin South West. He said there were a fine set of Labour public representatives who could replace him.
The former Labour leader also said he didnt know what Minister for Public Expenditure Brendan Howlin meant when he referenced a significant new role for him. Mr Rabbitte said: I have nothing lined up.
Mr Rabbitte has previously been tipped to take up a presenting role with Newstalk, though sources at the station have rejected speculation that Mr Rabbitte could succeed George Hook as presenter of the stations evening programme.
Mr Howlin said Mr Rabbittes departure would be a loss to the political system and not only the Labour Party.
I talked to him over the last number of weeks. Hes making a personal choice for himself on what is the right thing for him to do at this stage of his own life and hes decided not to contest the next Dil election.
I think hell be a very strong advocate for Labour during the campaign, a very strong voice for Labour and I would suspect hell have a significant role after the election in public affairs in Ireland ,  said Mr Howlin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:17:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Grab your hat, sunscreen and brolly: It’ll be ‘changeable’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/environment/grab-your-hat-sunscreen-and-brolly-it-ll-be-changeable-1.2276162</Link>
        <Description>Week will start with thundery bursts of rain before hot and humid temperatures arrive   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Grab your hat, sunscreen and brolly: Itll be changeable
Week will start with thundery bursts of rain before hot and humid temperatures arrive
Rainfall radar on Tuesday. Image: www.met.ie
Previous Image
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 11:16
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 09:17
Grab everything- sunscreen, umbrellas and hats - as were in for a week of Irelands wonderful  changeable weather.
The week will start with blustery and thundery showers and wind before hot and humid temperatures will take over mid-week. To complete the sequence the week will end with fresh, cooler conditions making their way across Ireland by the weekend.
Today will be very blustery with heavy and thundery bursts of rain. But dont despair, there will be bright and sunny spells through the day.
Weather: check the 5-day forecast in your area, tides and weather warnings
Highest temperatures will reach 18 degrees and there will be strong and gusty southwest winds, especially in the western and southern coasts.
A marine weather warning for small air craft has been issued on Tuesday for west to southwest winds that will increase to force six on Irish Sea coasts.
There will be showers during the early morning on Wednesday but these will die out midday.
The winds will ease for a dry, bright and sunny day with a top temperature hitting 20 degrees.
Night will bring unexpected cool temperatures for July as it drops between 6 to 8 degrees with mist patches at dawn.
The sun will return on Thursday but it will not stay for long as the cloud and drizzle take over during the day.
A warm front is expected to move in from the Atlantic and spread damp weather to Ulster in the evening.
It will be hot and humid in most parts of the country as temperatures with temperatures reaching 21 degrees.
The west coast will have some relief with a light fresh southerly breeze.
Friday will stay warm and humid with hazy sunny spells at 22 degrees.
Drizzle and fog will introduce themselves during the day before a cold front sweeps across Ireland during the afternoon bringing rain.
It will be fresher during the weekend with sunshine and scattered showers on Saturday.
Sunday will be cloudier and have spells of rain with temperatures around the mid to high teens.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ministers pay tribute to ‘heroic work’ of LÉ Eithne crew</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/ministers-pay-tribute-to-heroic-work-of-l%C3%A9-eithne-crew-1.2276145</Link>
        <Description>Naval Service ship has rescued 3,376 people since May deployment in Mediterranean   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Ministers pay tribute to heroic work of L Eithne crew
Naval Service ship has rescued 3,376 people since May deployment in Mediterranean
Irish naval ship L Eithne arrives with rescued migrants at the Palermo harbor in Italy on Tuesday, June 30th, 2015. Photograph: AP/Alessandro Fucarini.
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 08:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 08:00
Three Government ministers have paid tribute in Malta on Tuesday to the captain and crew of the Naval Service patrol ship L Eithne for their rescue of over 3,300 migrants in the Mediterranean Sea.
Minister for Defence and Marine Simon Coveney, Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald and Minister of State for Development Sen Sherlock flew in to the Maltese capital, Valletta to visit the ship at its berth in Valletta harbour.
Since its deployment in mid- May on the Naval Services first overseas humanitarian mission, the L Eithne has conducted 22 operations , and rescued 3,376 people of various nationalities from overcrowded and often unseaworthy craft, ranging from barges to wooden boats.
Some 2,664 of those rescued have been male, while 533 were female and 179 were children, including small babies, of various nationalities.
They were among an estimated 150,000 who have embarked in unseaworthy and overcrowded craft from the Libyan coast so far this year.
L Eithnes commanding officer Cdr Pearse ODonnell welcomed the delegation to the patrol ship, which berthed early on Monday below Vallettas Saluting Battery.
The delegation included Defence Forces chief of staff Lieut-Gen Conor OBoyle, Irish ambassador to Malta Pdraig MacCoscair and Department of Defence secretary-general Maurice Quinn.
Describing the work of the ship in the Mediterranean as invaluable, Mr Coveney said that Irelands focus would remain on continuing to assist the Italian authorities in the humanitarian search and rescue operation efforts to prevent further tragedy and loss of life at sea.
The L Eithne is due to be replaced by the L Niamh on humanitarian patrols, while decommissioned patrol ship L Aoife is also due to be presented to Malta to assist in its rescue efforts.
Ms Fitzgerald praised the exemplary professionalism of the crew of the L Eithne.
We are proud of them and the work they are doing under the Irish flag,she said. She said there were no easy answers to migration, which she described as one of the biggest challenges facing the EU, but said that Ireland was committed to doing its part in solidarity with our fellow Europeans.
She said the deployment of the L Eithne showed the real difference that Ireland,as a comparatively small member state, can make, and pledged to continue to do what we can when we can as the situation evolves.
Heroic work
Mr Sherlock described as very humbling the heroic work of the Defence Forces, and said Ireland was making a significant contribution to addressing the root causes of displacement, notably through our humanitarian and development assistance in the Horn of Africa and other regions of Africa, and the humanitarian support which we provide in Syria and the region.
The latest EU initiative was taken after an estimated 900 migrants drowned in the Mediterranean in April, making it the worst migrant disaster in European waters so far.
The L Eithne has been working with an Italian co-ordinated migrant humanitarian search and rescue operation, along with British and German ships and other vessels, including a privately-run rescue operation based in Malta, the Migrant Offshore Aid Station (MOAS).
Documents recently released under Freedom of Information legislation to RT indicate that Ireland did not support search and rescue missions in the Mediterranean  including Italys Mare Nostrum mission from late 2013- at high-level EU meetings for two years before the L Eithne was deployed to the region.
Italy had launched its Mare Nostrum mission in late 2013 after 366 migrants drowned off the island of Lampedusa, but the politically unpopular project was replaced last year by a more limited EU Triton operation which was focused on border control.
Almost 4,500 migrants from the Middle East and Africa drowned during the period covered by the documents, according to International Organization for Migration figures quoted by RT.
Malta, as the southernmost and smallest EU state, borders the area of operation some 45 to 60 kilometres off the Libyan coast. However under an agreement between Italy and Malta, most of the migrants are being landed in Sicily and southern Italian ports, with many then continuing their flight to other European states, including Germany and Sweden.
Unfair burden
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan said at the weekend that an unfair burden had been placed on countries in the region such as Italy and Malta, and he said he believed it was important that the EU strengthens its approach to what is a humanitarian crisis of huge dimensions, he added.
UN Human Rights commissioner Zeid Raad al-Hussein has recently called for a more humane, less mean-spirited response, and urged EU states to take a more comprehensive approach which focused less on enforcement at borders and more on resettlement of some of the worlds most vulnerable people.
The UN commissioner described the EUs proposed resettlement quota of 20,000 as wholly inadequate to the magnitude of this crisis, and called for far greater emphasis on expanding channels for migration into Europe, including for low-skilled labour and family reunification.
NUI Galways Irish Centre for Human Rights director Prof Michael OFlaherty has said the EUs proposed resettlement quota of 20,000 refugees is in stark contrast to the 100,000 people taken in after the break-up of Yugoslavia: Offering shelter to 20,000 people is a shadow of what Europe was willing to do 20 years ago, he said last month.
Under EU law, Ireland and Britain have an automatic opt-out on most EU justice and home affairs legislation, which covers migration and asylum issues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:21:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Donohoe refuses to commit to €850m Cork-Limerick road</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/donohoe-refuses-to-commit-to-850m-cork-limerick-road-1.2276139</Link>
        <Description>Minister says N20 motorway project in competition with other roads for funds   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Donohoe refuses to commit to 850m Cork-Limerick road
Minister says N20 motorway project in competition with other roads for funds
A sign for the N20 is seen on the approach road to Limerick city. The Minister for Transport has declined to commit to the 850m estimated cost for an upgrade of the route linking Limerick and Cork.
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 07:21
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 07:21
Minister for Transport, Paschal Donohoe has played down the possibility of work proceeding on the 850 million Cork- Limerick motorway, saying the project would be in competition with a number of other road upgrades for scarce resources.
Mr Donohoe said the upgrade of the Cork-Limerick road to motorway status was only one of a number of projects in Co Cork seeking funding for and any decision would be on the basis of which project offered best value and benefit to the region.
The last time that the Cork to Limerick road project was evaluated from a funding point of view, the approximate cost of it was 800 million and what I need to do now is weigh the cost of that project up against the competing demands in the city and county of Cork alone.
These include, for example, the need for investment in the Ringaskiddy Road, investment in the Dunkettle Interchange while I also have colleagues within the county of Cork pressing on me the need for investment in the Cork -Kerry Road.
All of these are projects that cost money and I need to weigh all those up to ensure that whatever money is available to this government and the government that comes after it, is well spent to support the recovery that is underway in Cork in the most effective and efficient way possible.
Mr Donohoe said he would be meeting with Cork Chamber and other interest groups as well as Oireachtas colleagues from Cork to hear their views on improving infrastructure in the county before making any decision on where funding was to be allocated.
Earlier this year, Minister of State Sean Sherlock told The Irish Times the N20 upgrade was essential for balanced regional development to ensure Cork and Limerick continue to grow as a counter weight to Dublin and the east coast.
Mr Sherlock conceded he didnt see the full estimated 850 million being made available in the immediate future but believed it would be possible to re-activate the project and have some monies allocated to at least allow preparatory work be done on the planning process.
According to an informed source, a relatively small sum of 5 to 8 million would allow the preparatory work on planning to be completed but when asked about this, Mr Donohoe was reluctant to commit any funds to upgrading the Cork-Limerick road.
As much as I would like to see projects like this go-ahead I can only give the go-ahead to money being spent on road projects if I am absolutely confident if the exchequer has available to them all of the funding they need to complete the project in its entirety, he said.
Sean ONeill of the NRA said earlier this year 150 million of the 850 million cost was allocated for land purchase with the remainder to be spent on planning and design, survey works, site investigation, archaeological examination, environmental mitigation measures and construction.
Mr ONeill said the NRA had looked at a number of routes.
The selected route submitted for planning, east of Mallow and Buttevant but west of Charleville, would have required the compulsory purchase of 16 residences and a total of 905 hectares affecting 235 farms and approximately 247 other properties, Mr ONeill told The Irish Times.
A motorway along this route would have involved the construction of 44 new road bridges, eight major river bridges, a number of smaller water crossings and two railway crossings, as well as 64kms of local roads including national, regional, local and private-access roads.
The motorway would extend for about 80km from the junction with the proposed Cork northern ring road near Blarney outside Cork city to the junction with the N21 at Attyflynn in Co Limerick and it would cut the travel time between Attyflynn and Blarney from 61 minutes to 45 minutes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Care assistant: ‘I worry my job will disappear at any moment’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/care-assistant-i-worry-my-job-will-disappear-at-any-moment-1.2275350</Link>
        <Description>  Elizabeth Cloherty and others in a like situation have no contract and little sense of security    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Care assistant: I worry my job will disappear at any moment
Elizabeth Cloherty and others in a like situation have no contract and little sense of security
Elizabeth Cloherty, a care assistant, has no complaints about pay or the hours she gets. She is concerned, however, about what the future holds. File photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
Elizabeth Cloherty, a care assistant, loves her work and has little complaint about her pay. But life still feels precarious.
I know theres a lot of controversy about zero hours contracts. In my case I dont even have a contract.
Shes been employed by a company for nearly three years which provides care-staff for people with intellectual disabilities who live in a residential centre.
Living wage set at 11.50, a third more than minimum wage
Its demanding work: it requires building up trust with residents, learning their likes and dislikes, and having the patience to help them fulfil their potential. But its also insecure. The last employee to get a contract at her place of work was a few years ago.
It means that I cant apply for a mortgage. At least Im just 25 years of age so its not a major concern right now. But there are older people with kids that dont have the security of a contract.
No pay complaints
She has no complaints about the pay  which starts at 11.80 an hour  or the hours she gets. She is concerned, however, about what the future holds.
The worrying thing is not knowing if your job could disappear at any moment. If theres a takeover, theres every chance a new firm could bring its own people with them. That makes you nervous about the future.
She sees little prospect of the situation changing  especially for new recruits who come armed with college degrees.
With zero hour contracts a lot of people feel under pressure to work whatever hours are offered  even if it means driving miles for just a few hours of work. They worry if they turn it down they might not get work again.
She feels its only right there should be greater protection for longer-term staff. Employers shouldnt be able to use staff as they please. A persons length of service should trigger rights, such as minimum hours.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Primary principals reveal plan for small rural schools</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/education/primary-principals-reveal-plan-for-small-rural-schools-1.2275459</Link>
        <Description>Organisation says proposals will guarantee that  existing school buildings remain open   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Primary principals reveal plan for small rural schools
Organisation says proposals will guarantee that  existing school buildings remain open
The Irish Primary Principals Network (IPPN) has drawn up a plan for small rural schools. File photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA Wire
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
The organisation representing primary school principals has drawn up a plan aimed at tackling the large number of small schools in rural Ireland .
The proposals would see schools pooling resources and cooperating on management and teaching functions, but stop short of full mergers.
The Irish Primary Principals Network (IPPN) says the plan will guarantee that existing school buildings remain open, noting that local communities are very attached to their small schools and are convinced of their value, both academically and socially.
Schools need more teachers and classrooms, says Minister
The plan will also put vulnerable schools on a more sustainable footing, and allow for greater sharing of professional expertise, the organisation says, in a draft position paper.
The document has been produced as part of a consultation process with the Department of Education and Skills aimed at creating a new protocol for managing small schools.
Earlier this year, the Government announced it was rejecting the recommendations of a long-awaited value for money report into small schools.
This called for all one- or two-teacher schools located within 2km of a similar school to be closed or amalgamated by the end of the 2014/15 school year, and for others located up to 8km apart to be reorganised through amalgamation or federation.
It is understood that political considerations weighed heavily on the decision.
Documents obtained by The Irish Times showed that 32 of 200 small schools earmarked for amalgamation under the plan were in Taoiseach Enda Kennys Mayo constituency.
The IPPN says: There is no empirical evidence to prove that pupils fare either better or worse academically in small schools. There are, however, social implications for children in the very smallest schools.
Health and safety as well as child protection considerations need also to be examined.
There are few other countries in the world, and certainly none in Europe , with as high a proportion of small schools.
Three levels of engagement
The IPPN proposes three levels of engagement between small schools: cooperative leadership, clustered leadership and federated leadership.
Cooperative leadership would involve schools sharing some teaching resources, administrative and caretaking functions, while retaining complete independence.
Clustered Leadership would involve the sharing of functions such as management, procurement and curriculum planning, while each school would still retain its own principal and board of management.
However, there would be at least one joint meeting of boards a year, along with shared staff meetings.
Federated leadership would mean one principal and one board of management across multiple campuses, but parents and children retain their school building in their own local community.
The IPPN says one of the advantages of this federation model over traditional amalgamation is that there would be no additional accommodation or school transport required in most cases.
In addition, federation offers a structure that allows the principal to engage more fully in leading learning as well as facilitating staff mobility.
Lower threshold
In rejecting the report last February, the department lowered the threshold for the appointment of a third teacher from 56 pupils to 53, and a second teacher from 20 to 19 from September 2015.
It also said it would write to patrons of all one-teacher schools located within 8km of another school of similar patronage to invite them to reflect on their future sustainability and to offer department supports if they decide to amalgamate.
The department said it had not written to any school yet, as it was developing the amalgamation protocol with the education partners.
However, it said it had identified 12 one-teacher schools it planned to write to in the first instance, four of them in Co Mayo, two each in Co Clare , Co Cork and Co Kerry and one each in Co Galway and Co Roscommon.
Some 43 per cent of the States 3,200 primary schools have fewer than 100 pupils, and about 95 per cent of them are under Catholic patronage.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Consumers need new  insurance legislation, report says</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/consumers-need-new-insurance-legislation-report-says-1.2275584</Link>
        <Description>Law Reform Commission  warns of ‘vicious devices and traps’ in existing contracts   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Consumers need new  insurance legislation, report says
Law Reform Commission  warns of vicious devices and traps in existing contracts
The Law Reform Commission has recommended new legislation on insurance contracts. File photograph: Getty Images/iStockphoto
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
New consumer legislation designed to remove vicious devices and traps for the unwary from insurance contracts has been recommended by the Law Reform Commission .
In a report published today, the commission recommends warranties should be abolished from insurance contracts, changes should be made to the duty of disclosure and there should be proportionate remedies for innocent or negligent mistakes by consumers.
The aim of the Report on Consumer Insurance Contracts, part of the commissions third programme of law reform, is to reform and rebalance the duties of insurers and consumers, including small businesses, the commission has said.
Universal health insurance could cost up to 3,000 for adult
The commission president, retired High Court judge Mr Justice John Quirke , told The Irish Times it was ridiculous that an insurance company could refuse to pay out household insurance after a fire on the basis, for example, that the householder did not have a burglar alarm.
Abolished
Under current legislation, this is permitted where the requirement to have the alarm was a warranty or condition of the contract, but should be abolished.
A number of English courts have described warranties as vicious devices and traps for the unwary; they are not very popular in the courts, Mr Justice Quirke said.
He said insurance contract law caused problems for consumers mainly because most laws had their origins in the 16th and 17th centuries, when sailing ships were crossing the Atlantic and the contents were being insured.
They were hammered out between people who had equal bargaining powers, he said.
But in modern times, contracts are between multinational conglomerates and ordinary people, and there are not equal bargaining rights or bargaining capacities.
We want to ensure these problems dont cause injustice, Mr Justice Quirke said.
The commission makes 105 recommendations, including changes to the law on disclosure, which dates back to 1776.
It imposes a duty on a consumer to disclose information that a hypothetical prudent insurer might rely on in deciding whether to insure that consumer.
If it is not disclosed, the insurer can refuse to pay a claim.
Mr Justice Quirke said the obligation of identifying this information should be placed on the insurer, and there should also be proportionate remedies for consumers if they fail to disclose.
There can be an absolutely innocent failure to disclose something and if that is the case, then instead of the insurer being able to refuse completely to honour the agreement, the misrepresentation should be examined and investigated to discover whether it is innocent, negligent or fraudulent, he said.
If it is fraudulent, the contract should be voided completely, but if it is innocent or negligent, the insurer shouldnt be allowed to just simply walk away and say we wont cover this; they should be required to apply proportionate remedies for the consumer.
The commission also recommends the abolition of a requirement of a consumer to have an insurable interest in what is being insured, which dates back to 1774, when gambling was disapproved of and people took out insurance policies on, for example, the life of King George III.
Mr Justice Quirke said that nowadays it referred to situations where, for example, a son or daughter took out a policy on their fathers home when the father was unable to.
The insurance company could accept the payment for such a policy. However, if a claim is made, the company may say the son or daughter has no insurable interest in the house and they can refuse to pay.
Beneficiaries
The commission also recommends third parties, who were intended to be the beneficiaries under an insurance contract, should be permitted to make a direct claim against the insurer.
This could benefit, for example, a person injured at work when the employer had an insurance policy, but where the business has since gone into liquidation.
The commission has included a proposed draft Consumer Insurance Contracts Bill in its report, which will be published this evening by Mr Justice Ronan Keane .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrants  face discrimination and assault, report finds</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/migrants-face-discrimination-and-assault-report-finds-1.2275644</Link>
        <Description>Immigrant Council of Ireland  interviews  young  men on their experiences in Republic   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Migrants  face discrimination and assault, report finds
Immigrant Council of Ireland  interviews  young  men on their experiences in Republic
An  Immigrant Council of Ireland anti-racism campaign. Photograph: Immigrant Council of Ireland website
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
Discrimination, stereotyping and assaults were among the issues reported by a panel of young migrant men interviewed about their experiences in Ireland .
A report by the Immigrant Council of Ireland found that several of the 40 young men spoken to had expressed bitterness at what they believed to be discriminatory treatment.
This treatment was arising in schools, workplaces and on the street, with some of the men saying they felt they had been unfairly targeted by authorities including An Garda Sochna .
Sutherland calls on Ireland to waive its exemption from migrant agreement
Some respondents reported verbal abuse, such as schoolmates and strangers telling them to go back to your own country.
In one instance, a young Muslim man reported being the subject of racist jokes, including being asked if he had a bomb in his bag.
Others said they were subjected to physical assaults, with one reporting being burned with a cigarette by a group of teenagers.
One focus group interviewed as part of the research felt strongly . . . the garda take a nonconfrontational approach and do not challenge local families whose children cause trouble in disadvantaged areas.
Employment
The report also found a strong perception of favouritism in local sports clubs, with a number of participants saying local children were picked over migrants.
One person reported being denied a place in a sports club which he knew was seeking new recruits.
When it came to employment opportunities, a number of interviewees said they had found their recruitment process straightforward and fair at all stages.
However, others expressed frustration at the difficulty in finding employment, which they felt was particularly difficult for young people and even more so for young migrants.
One African man said he had been rejected for a job and told: We dont hire black people here.
Another claimed that anglicising his name had led to his securing job interviews.
The report made several recommendations, including:
- After-school support for migrant pupils from non-English speaking backgrounds;
- An effort to recruit more migrant teachers;
- Changes at third-level which would allow migrant students access to student grants and free fees based on residency as opposed to nationality;
- The provision of diversity and anti-racism training to sports clubs and other organisations, including the extension of such training to all departments of An Garda Sochna;
- Comprehensive reform of the immigration registration system/asylum system;
- A complaints system for those who experience discrimination in accessing public services, and;
- Statutory permanent residence status for under-16s.
The Voices of Young Migrant Men report was part of a wider Migrant Mens Well-Being in Diversity (MiMen) project funded by the European Commission and carried out in seven EU countries including Ireland.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Precarious work: Five solutions to employment stand-off</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/precarious-work-five-solutions-to-employment-stand-off-1.2275379</Link>
        <Description> How State can  ensure economic  flexibility for employers and job security for workers   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Precarious work: Five solutions to employment stand-off
How State can  ensure economic  flexibility for employers and job security for workers
A rally in support of Dunnes Stores workers earlier this year. Photograph: Eric Luke/The Irish Times
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
Trade unions want greater protection for workers. Employers want greater flexibility. But is there a middle ground which can provide both freedom and and job security? Here are five possible solutions to the situation.
1. Restrict zero hours
Low or zero-hour practices are the modern equivalent of a time when workers stood on street corners in the hope of the start.
Nowadays, they wait for a text message to say if or when theyre needed.
In essence, these contracts allow employers to hire staff with no guarantee of work.
They mean that employees work only when they are needed by employers, often at short notice.
While theyre flexible for some, for many it limits them from accessing a second job.
In theory, there is protection against this practice under the Organisation of Working Time Acts.
It gives an employee an entitlement to receive some compensation in respect of the hours they are not required to work in their contracted hours.
This entitlement is calculated on the basis of 15 hours, or 25 per cent of the contract hours, whichever is less.
According to groups like the Irish Congress of Trade Unions (Ictu), in practice, there are ways around this, through understating hours in contracts or stating that an employee is not required to work the hours.
Employers group Ibec, however, has urged the Government not to legislate against zero hour or flexible contracts, saying such a move could be detrimental to the economy.
Instead of banning the practice altogether, restrictions could limit the proportion of the workforce that can be employed using zero-hour type practices, as well as limits on the length of time that posts can be filled using these arrangement.
2. Banded hours
Workers in prearious sections of the economy are vulnerable to having their hours reduced or shifts cancelled.
Dunnes, in particular, has become a lightning rod for these issues, with employees claiming there is little certainty over their working hours.
Some say their hours can be reduced if they complain.
But other large bottom-line retailers like Tesco , Penneys and Supervalu have agreed a form of guaranteed minimum hours for workers known as banded hours agreements.
These reflect the employees actual working hours, along with providing mechanisms to allow for an increase in these hours.
These collective agreements set out the precise details of the operation and provide for extra flexibility during parts of the year when demand sags.
These arrangements mean that employees are aware of their minimum guaranteed weekly working hours and the likely maximum number of hours they will be required to work.
And employers, too, still have flexibility and certainty over staffing their businesses.
3. Living wage
A campaign in the UK to help the low-paid recently signed up its 1,500th company to agree to pay the living wage, the income below which campaigners say it is impossible to make ends meet in the UK and the Republic.
In 2011, the Living Wage Foundation was established to give companies advice, support and accreditation.
Its accredited employers range from independent printers, bookshops and breweries to well-known companies such as Aviva, Nationwide and Nestl.
A spokesman says these businesses recognise that clinging to the national minimum wage is not good for business.
Participating employers, it says, have found that paying a living wage enhanced the quality of the work of their staff, while absenteeism rates tended to fall dramatically.
In the State, a notional living wage has been set by campaigners at 11.50.
In all, its estimated that about one in five workers here earn below this.
Eurostat figures show the State has a greater proportion of low paid workers than other countries.
Overall, more than one in five workers were classified as low paid - earning less than two thirds of average hourly incomes - in a 2010 study.
Most agree a mandatory living wage simply isnt feasible right now - but a State-endorsed Fair Trade style campaign, highlighting the benefits and kudos for employers who sign up to it could see the idea gain major traction.
4. Bargaining rights
The Republic lags behind many other European countries in not providing workers with collective bargaining rights.
This is despite signing up to recognise and protect the right to collectively bargain for pay and conditions.
Under legislation set out by Minister of State Ged Nash, a group of workers in any company would have a right to a hearing at the Labour Court and have their case examined in comparison with similar firms, both unionised and non-unionised.
In such cases, the Labour Court would be permitted to issue a recommendation that is binding in law and could be enforced in the Circuit Court.
The legislation is strongly backed by Labour, but opposed by some in Fine Gael .
TDs such as John Deasy have voiced concern that it could affect foreign direct investment.
Ibec says any collective bargaining must be done on a voluntary basis.
But some labour market experts point out that mandatory provisions in other European countries havent stopped some of the biggest firms in the world investing.
Many on both sides, however, agree that the States industrial relations machinery has served the country well by striking a fair balance between workers rights and attracting investment into the economy.
5. Strings attached to public spending
Public procurement might not be the most exciting of areas in labour law - but the way taxpayers money is spent in tendering for projects can have a profound effect on the way business is done.
Many European countries have adopted socially responsible clauses to procurement involving public authorities.
Both Government and businesses have signalled that such measures may not be legal and would add to the cost of public spending.
However, groups like Ictu say there is scope for a social clause under relevant European directives.
It could, for example, include the payment of a living wage; increased participation of women in the labour market; recruitment of people from disadvantaged areas; or the employment of long-term jobless.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Labour’s Pat Rabbitte will not run in general election </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/labour-s-pat-rabbitte-will-not-run-in-general-election-1.2275700</Link>
        <Description>Alan Shatter  to seek  nomination to contest  new Dublin Rathdown constituency   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Labours Pat Rabbitte will not run in general election
Alan Shatter  to seek  nomination to contest  new Dublin Rathdown constituency
Former leader of the Labour Party Pat Rabbitte has confirmed  he will be stepping down from politics after 26 years.  File photograph: Brenda Fitzsimons/The Irish Times
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
Former Labour Party leader Pat Rabbitte will not contest the next general election.
Mr Rabbitte confirmed on Monday night he will be stepping down from politics after 26 years.
The former minister informed his party colleagues of his decision at selection convention. The Dublin South West TD said he had not intended to make the announcement until after the Dil broke for its summer recess, but felt he had to tell his colleagues at the constituency meeting.
Tnaiste Joan Burton praised Mr Rabbittes contribution to politics and to his party.
She said he would be sorely missed by all in political life.
While Pat has had a significant national profile, he has always worked hard for the entire community in Dublin South West, Ms Burton said.
I know that amidst a lengthy political career, one of his proudest achievements was his involvement in the first National Drugs Strategy during the rainbow government, in an effort to address the drugs scourge in Dublin.
Ms Burton also said Mr Rabbitte would be remembered for the forensic work he did as a member of the Dirt inquiry.*
Public life
Pats wit and insight are unique and I am sure that while he is exiting politics, he will not be lost to Irish public life, she added.
Mr Rabbitte was leader of the Labour Party from 2002- 2007. He more recently served as minister for communications, energy and natural resources, but lost his Cabinet place in a reshuffle after Ms Burtons appointment as party leader last year.
Mr Rabbitte had originally put his name forward for the selection convention, but withdrew it late on Monday night. A recent internal poll suggested he would have been re-elected if he ran again.
Councillor Pamela Kearns is likely to be selected as his replacement. She ran for the party in the byelection won by Anti-Austerity Alliance TD Paul Murphy last October.
Meanwhile, former minister for justice Alan Shatter has said he wants to run for Fine Gael in the next general election.
He said it was his intention to seek a nomination to contest the new Dublin Rathdown constituency, a three-seater which replaces the current five-seat Dublin South following boundary changes.
Privilege
Mr Shatter confirmed his intentions, but admitted he faces a tough battle to get re-elected.
I have had the privilege of representing the people of Dublin South in Dil ireann for over 29 years, he said.
I would hope to continue my work as a Dil member after the next election as one of the Fine Gael deputies representing the smaller three-seat constituency of Dublin Rathdown.
I have no doubt it will be a big challenge for the party to secure two seats but I am up for the challenge. Of course the first important step is to receive a nomination as one of the partys candidates.
He is expected to be joined by his party colleague Olivia Mitchell on the ticket, but she has not yet indicated whether or not she will stand again.
Labours Alex White and Independents Shane Ross and Peter Mathews are expected to stand in Dublin Rathdown, along with Sinn Fins Sorcha Nic Cormaic and Fianna Fils Senator Mary White.
Fine Gaels Dublin Rathdown selection convention is unlikely to be held until September.
*This article was amended on July 7th, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Berkeley injured  making ‘tremendous’ progress</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/berkeley-injured-making-tremendous-progress-1.2275703</Link>
        <Description>Six Dublin students still being treated in California following fatal balcony collapse   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Berkeley injured  making tremendous progress
Six Dublin students still being treated in California following fatal balcony collapse
Aoife Beary, who was injured in the Berkeley balcony collapse.
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
Six Dublin students injured in last months balcony collapse in Berkeley who are still being treated in California have made tremendous progress, according to the Irish Consul in San Francisco .
Five of the seven students injured in the collapse that killed six others are still being treated in hospitals three weeks after the incident.
Two have been discharged from hospital, though one of those remains in the San Francisco Bay Area because he is unable to fly.
With the support of their families, friends and the amazing care they have [received] at the medical facilities, all of the students have made tremendous progress over the past number of days, said Irish Consul in San Francisco Philip Grant .
It has been nothing short of exceptional in a number of cases.
The family of Aoife Beary said she had made steady progress in recent days. She remains in a critical condition and a serious head injury remains her main concern.
The 13 students who fell from the fourth-floor balcony were celebrating Aoifes 21st birthday at the time of the incident in the early hours of June 16th.
Ms Beary, from Blackrock, underwent successful heart surgery in Stanford Medical Centre in Palo Alto near San Francisco on June 26th and her condition has stabilised, her family said on the Facebook page, Friends of Aoife Beary.
Both her medical team and parents are optimistic that she will make a good recovery, the family said.
This will be a long and slow road to recovery over many months to come.
The former Loreto College Foxrock student is said to be awake and reacting to her family but unable to speak because of a tracheotomy.
Aoife is - unexpectedly and very pleasantly - making good progress. Everyone is pleased with how shes doing, said a source close to the families.
Medical rehabilitation
Hannah Waters (21), from Castleknock, and Clodagh Cogley (21) from Milltown, are both being treated in a medical rehabilitation centre in Santa Clara, south of San Francisco.
Ms Waters was critically injured in the fourth-floor balcony collapse and is said to be responding well and undergoing rehabilitation.
Ms Cogley, who suffered two collapsed lungs, a broken shoulder, a broken knee, broken ribs and a broken spinal cord, will remain in hospital in the US for several more weeks.
She has said on Facebook that the chances of her using her legs again are pretty bleak.
Niall Murray (21), from Rathfarnham, who has a hand and leg injuries, has undergone surgeries and is expected to have further surgeries.
He is being treated in two San Francisco hospitals which specialise in repairing the injuries to his limbs.
Jack Halpin (21), from Rathmines, has had multiple surgeries, including an operation for a broken leg.
He is undergoing rehabilitation at John Muir Medical Centre in Walnut Creek, east of San Francisco.
Conor Flynn (22), from Mount Merrion, was discharged from hospital two weeks ago and is staying with his family in the Bay Area.
He is unable to return to Ireland as he recovers from a punctured lung.
He is expected to have a follow-up appointment with doctors in the coming weeks to assess whether he is fit to fly.
Sean Fahey (21), from Rathmines, the first to be released from hospital, was discharged two weeks ago. He has returned to Ireland.
It is too early to say yet which of the remaining five hospitalised students will be the next to be discharged, a source said.
Inter-disciplinary medical teams were starting to assess their conditions, a positive sign of the progress they are making.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:00:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drinking during pregnancy is rife,  study finds</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/health/drinking-during-pregnancy-is-rife-study-finds-1.2275527</Link>
        <Description>Over 75% of Irish women’s pregnancies feature  alcohol use - despite warnings   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
<<<<<<< HEAD
Drinking during pregnancy is rife,  study finds
Over 75% of Irish womens pregnancies feature  alcohol use - despite warnings
Drinking during pregnancy is highly prevalent and socially pervasive in Ireland, research published in the British medical journal BMJ Open says. File photograph: Thinkstock Photos
Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
First published: Tue, Jul 7, 2015, 01:00
More than 75 per cent of Irish womens pregnancies involve exposure to alcohol despite warnings about the health effects of drinking, according to a new study.
Drinking during pregnancy is highly prevalent and socially pervasive in Ireland and other western countries, the research published in the British medical journal BMJ Open says.
More than 45 per cent of Irish women binge drink in the first trimester of their pregnancy, according to one of the three original studies reviewed for the research. The rate of binge drinking falls to just 0.4 per cent in the second trimester.
There is low adherence to guidelines advising complete abstinence from alcohol during pregnancy, while the high prevalence of consumption is pervasive across all social groups.
Smokers are more likely to drink during pregnancy, the study also finds.
The researchers from University College Cork and centres in the UK, Australia and New Zealand looked at the drinking patterns of more than 17,000 Irish women as assessed in two previous Irish studies and one international study.
Alcohol consumption during pregnancy in Ireland was found to vary between 20 per cent and 80 per cent, depending on the original study, and between 40 per cent and 80 per cent in three other countries.
In Ireland, smokers were between 17 per cent and 50 per cent more likely to drink during pregnancy.
Scope research
According to the Scope (Screening for pregnancy endpoints) research which was reviewed for the latest study, 90 per cent of Irish women drank pre-pregnancy, compared to 83 per cent in the UK, 77 per cent in New Zealand and 53 per cent in Australia.
Some 82 per cent of Irish women drank in pregnancy, compared to just 40 per cent in Australia. A total of 80 per cent drank in the first trimester, and 29 per cent in the second.
Caucasian women were more likely to drink while pregnant than non-Caucasians, while younger women tended to have a lower risk of alcohol use.
Development effects
The study says the widespread consumption of even low levels of alcohol during pregnancy is a significant public health concern because it occurs at a time when the growth of the foetus and the development effects are not well understood.
It says healthcare professionals should continue to advise all pregnant women to abstain from alcohol during pregnancy in line with best practice guidelines, irrespective of professionally perceived risk of exposure.
The study also says the dual targeting of smoking and alcohol consumption should be increased and delivered routinely when indicated.
The analysis shows the need for an agreed convention for measuring alcohol use to avoid substantial variation in estimates, according to the authors.
=======
Educate Together takes legal advice on admissions
Body says   the enrolment policy exemption for  older schools could be discriminatory
Educate Together chief executive Paul Rowe
Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 10:08
First published: Sat, Jun 27, 2015, 01:03
Educate Together is taking legal advice on admissions regulations from the Department of Education which could be discriminatory.
It says hundreds of parents, who prefer not to have their children baptised, are being blocked from accessing their schools.
Educate Together, which operates 77 schools across the State, argues that the stipulation, announced in 2011, that new schools must prioritise children from the catchment area, is denying parents who live outside the catchment area of an Educate Together school, their choice of school for their children.
Students in direct provision working hard for college place
In contrast, older schools  the vast majority of which are denominational  can continue to prioritise on the basis of religion. Baptised children from outside the catchment may be preferred over non-baptised children living locally.
According to Educate Together chief executive Paul Rowe , this means some parents whose children are not baptised face difficulties accessing local schools and may find it impossible to get into Educate Together schools further away, given that most are hugely oversubscribed.
Mr Rowe said it had been hoped the 2015 Admissions To School Bill would address the issue of religious schools, which are publicly funded, being allowed to prefer baptised children.
Minister for Education Jan OSullivan has said the legislation was drafted in the context of the Constitution and equality legislation. We cant within that take away the provision whereby schools can protect their own ethos.
Educate Together schools
Educate Together schools have become increasingly oversubscribed, with hundreds of parent from outside school catchment areas applying for junior infants places, particularly in Dublin.
Some of the schools are receiving four, five or six times more applications than available places, said Mr Rowe.
For example, Balbriggan ET national school has 258 applications for 48 places. Holywell national school in in Swords , Co Dublin has 335 applications for 90 places, while Castleknock ET national school has 350 applications for 58 places.
Mr Rowe says the restrictions on new schools, compelling them to prefer children from the local area, may contradict powers granted to boards of management over this area under the Education Act.
Educate Together has, like other patron bodies, sought legal advice on the issue, he said. The fundamental underlying issue however, is that many more Educate Together schools are needed."
It could also be necessary for Ireland to comply with its international legal obligations.
A spokeswoman from the department said: The reason for establishing new schools is to serve a local community where a local demand exists and hence priority is given to pupils from the local area."
The United Nations has repeatedly called on Ireland to end religious discrimination in publicly-funded schools.
Most recently this week, the UN Council on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights in Geneva called on Ireland to take all necessary measures to bring all relevant laws, including the Equal Status Acts 2001 and the Education (Admission to Schools) Bill 2015, in line with the international human rights standards and to increase the number of non-denominational schools at the primary and post-primary education levels.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
