<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:05:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stormont in jeopardy as welfare Bill is blocked</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/stormont-in-jeopardy-as-welfare-bill-is-blocked-1.2227056</Link>
        <Description>Sinn Féin joins forces with SDLP and Green MLA to veto reform proposals   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Stormont in jeopardy as welfare Bill is blocked
Sinn Fin joins forces with SDLP and Green MLA to veto reform proposals
Minister for Finance Arlene Foster  warned that rejection of the welfare proposals would create an unsustainable 604 million (854 million) deficit in the Stormont budget. Photograph: Niall Carson/PA
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:05
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:05
The Northern Assembly last night blocked the final passage of the welfare Bill, triggering a potential crisis that could bring down the Stormont institutions.
Despite a warning by DUP Minister for Finance Arlene Foster that rejection of the welfare proposals would create an unsustainable 604 million (854 million) deficit in the Stormont budget, Sinn Fin, with the support of the SDLP and the single Green member, Steven Agnew , used a blocking mechanism to veto the bill.
They signed a cross-community petition of concern which meant that the Bill could only be carried by a majority of both nationalists and unionists endorsing the welfare changes. In the chamber, 58 MLAs supported the Bill while 39 voted against. However, as a majority of both unionists and nationalists did not support the bill it fell.
Ms Foster warned that such would be the unsustainable state of the Norths budget that circumstances could be created where the British government will be forced to intervene.
United front
In the absence of agreement, the DUP wants Northern Secretary Theresa Villiers to take over responsibility for welfare from the Executive. She, however, is reluctant to go down this route at present.
Ms Villiers previously warned that if the welfare dispute was not settled then the entire Stormont House Agreement, providing 2 billion in grants and loan-raising powers and covering issues such as the Executive budget, corporation tax, public service reform and how to deal with the past, would be placed in jeopardy.
The Sinn Fin Deputy First Minister, Martin McGuinness, called for a united front to resist the welfare cuts.
This is a time when the Executive parties need to stand together to defend our public services, particularly in health, education and welfare. We need to stand up for the people who elect us, rather than acting in the interests of a Tory elite, he said.
Fiscal powers
We need an immediate negotiation with the British government for a budget which protects our public services and for fiscal powers that give us control over our economy, he added.
Ms Foster, however, accused Sinn Fin of opposing welfare reform at the diktat of the partys electoral ambitions in the Republic. Their Dublin bosses cracked the whip and the Sinn Fin Assembly team flipped, she said.
Ms Foster added that Sinn Fin opposition to the Bill was just cheap, self-serving party political posturing and frankly it is pathetic  just to look like tough guys to the rest of the electorate in Northern Ireland and indeed to look like tough guys to the electorate in the Republic of Ireland.
The DUP pressed ahead with the final stage of the Bill despite concerns that it would precipitate a crisis that would jeopardise the Executive and Assembly.
There was some speculation that the cardiac illness of DUP leader and First Minister Peter Robinson might allow for the debate to be postponed.
However, the DUP social development Minister Mervyn Storey said in the Assembly chamber that the debate must proceed. The time for talking is now over.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Harry McGee: Fianna Fáil’s renewal more  rhetoric than reality</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/harry-mcgee-fianna-f%C3%A1il-s-renewal-more-rhetoric-than-reality-1.2227054</Link>
        <Description>  Martin’s attempts at modernisation clash with the party’s conservative base </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Harry McGee: Fianna Fils renewal more  rhetoric than reality
Martins attempts at modernisation clash with the partys conservative base
Micheal Martin,  leader of Fianna Fil, and Senator Averil Power in 2011, during a press conference on political reform. Photograph: Gareth Chaney, Collins
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:05
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:05
All of Fianna Fils 21 TDs are male and not one of them lives in Dublin. The average age of 52 is hardly youthful. Only three of its TDs are in their 30s; seven are in the 40s and the remaining 11 are in their 50s and 60s.
With Averil Powers departure, there is only one woman (Mary White) among its team of 13 in the Seanad; there are also only two Dublin-based Senators, her and Darragh OBrien. The average age of its Senators is 55 and five are in their late 60s or early 70s.
When the social outlook of its 34 parliamentarians is assessed, it is clear there is a majority conservative outlook. Perhaps 17  half of the total  could be regarded as socially conservative with only nine of its members (including party leader Michel Martin) having a more liberal outlook. A further eight would be seen as in the centre ground.
Transport spokesman, Timmy Dooley TD had to agree with a reporter yesterday who characterised the parliamentary party as male, stale and outside the Pale.
Martin is trying to modernise the party, promote women candidates and invoke values that correspond more to 2015 than to the last century. He is dealing with the kind of sclerosis the Tories had in the 1990s when Eurosceptics blocked the modernisers.
Fianna Fil refers to renewal all the time, but it has been a tedious and inchoate process. One member, one vote has come into being but the partys efforts to increase the representation of women has hardly been stellar. It did succeed in getting a small number of promising women councillors elected but its nowhere near its own targets.
Early on Martin realised he needed to speak with forked tongue to the younger generation he wanted to join, as well as to its older conservative base.
There were fault lines there, such as when he tried to promote young candidates for the Seanad, including Power. He also had to concede a free vote on abortion when it became clear only six of his TDs would back the legislation.
Crisis
There is no quick fix for its existential crisis. Former TD Chris Flood says it will take two election cycles, perhaps three.
We are a very traditional and conservative party, said one of its younger TDs. There was always going to be some tension between those who wanted reform and those who were reluctant to move as quickly. The realpolitik is if you move too quickly, you lose some of your core support.
The level of canvassing Power sought for a Yes vote was not realistic in a party where most of its representatives were natural No voters.
Powers dramatic exit took the shine off Fianna Fils byelection victory but the spirited nature of yesterdays party meeting suggests the troops will rally behind Martin.
But rally to what? The party has spoken of being radical and imaginative, of forging a new politics, but theres little evidence of it beyond the rhetoric. It lacks policy and a message that tells voters what the party stands for.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Charlie Flanagan warns on implications of Northern deadlock</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/charlie-flanagan-warns-on-implications-of-northern-deadlock-1.2226856</Link>
        <Description>Minister briefs Cabinet colleagues on  implications of  impasse over welfare reform and budgetary matters   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Charlie Flanagan warns on implications of Northern deadlock
Minister briefs Cabinet colleagues on  implications of  impasse over welfare reform and budgetary matters
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan: These are gains worth fighting for and, working with our partners, the Government is determined that the potential represented by the agreement will be realised. Photograph: Brian Lawless/PA
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:02
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:02
The continuing political deadlock in Northern Ireland on welfare reform has serious implications for the future of the power-sharing Executive, according to Minister for Foreign Affairs and Trade Charlie Flanagan. Mr Flanagan briefed his Cabinet colleagues yesterday on the implications of the impasse over welfare reform and budgetary matters.
He said later that the stability of the political institutions at Stormont and the continued implementation of the totality of the Stormont House Agreement could be in jeopardy as a result.
The Government agreed every possible effort must be made to encourage and support the Northern Ireland Executive parties to reach an agreement on welfare reform that is both politically acceptable and financially viable. To that end, he added, the Government will, in the coming days, remain in close touch with its counterparts in the British government and with the leaders of Northern Ireland Executive parties, as well as with Senator Gary Hart and the US administration who played such a helpful role in the achievement of the Stormont House Agreement.
As well as providing a template for financial stability in Northern Ireland, the Stormont House Agreement, which was concluded at the beginning of the year, represented an agreed way forward for addressing the contentious legacy of the past. These are gains worth fighting for and, working with our partners, the Government is determined that the potential represented by the agreement will be realised, he said.
He also said the Cabinet expressed its regret at the illness of the Northern Ireland First Minister Peter Robinson and conveyed its best wishes for his full and prompt recovery.
After the Cabinet meeting Mr Flanagan left on a trade mission to South Africa but said the unfolding situation in the North was being closely monitored by the Government. The Minister is leading a delegation of 34 Irish companies in a drive to increase Irish exports to South Africa.
The four-day trade mission, organised by Enterprise Ireland, is focused on sectors where Irish companies have particularly strong capabilities, including technology, telecommunications, aviation, engineering, energy and financial services.
During the four days, more than 200 meetings will be held between Irish companies and potential business partners and customers, along with five major networking events.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Viceroy of Ireland’s jewels found in London bank vault</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/viceroy-of-ireland-s-jewels-found-in-london-bank-vault-1.2226609</Link>
        <Description>Star of Order of St Patrick hidden in trunks filled with tiaras and other family treasures   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Viceroy of Irelands jewels found in London bank vault
Star of Order of St Patrick hidden in trunks filled with tiaras and other family treasures
A portrait of Lord Houghton wearing the insignia  by Walter Frederick Osborne, which is in the National Portrait Gallery in London
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:01
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:01
Ceremonial jewels worn by the Viceroy of Ireland 120 years ago have been discovered in a duchesss London bank vault and will be sold at auction on Wednesday. The insignia of the Most Illustrious Order of St Patrick, worn by Lord Houghton while serving as Queen Victorias lord lieutenant of Ireland in Dublin during the 1890s, were inherited by his daughter Mary, Duchess of Roxburghe.
Following her death in England last year at the age of 99, her estate is being sold at Sothebys, whose auctioneers were dispatched to draw up an inventory of her possessions. They found her fathers grand masters badge and star of the Order of St Patrick hidden away in trunks filled with tiaras and other family treasures in the vaults of Hoares private bank.
Sothebys expert David Macdonald described the scene as resembling  Gringotts Wizarding Bank in Harry Potter and said it was really exciting to find the very rare insignia.
GAA medals fetch record prices
The Order of St Patrick was the British monarchys order of chivalry  a branch of the honours system  used to reward those in high office in Ireland. Members  men only and limited at any time to 22  were known as knights of St Patrick and held ceremonies in St Patricks Hall in Dublin Castle, the headquarters of British rule in Ireland.
They wore elaborate costumes including velvet plumed hats sporting red, white and blue feathers, a hooded blue mantle lined with white silk and insignia of collar, badge and star. The badge and star were each engraved with the Latin motto Quis Separabit? (Who will separate us?) The knights commissioned their own sets of badge and star from leading Dublin jewellers including West &amp; Co.
A portrait by Irish artist Walter Frederick Osborne of Lord Houghton wearing his regalia in Dublin in 1894 is in the collection of the National Portrait Gallery in London.
A leading figure in the Liberal Party , Lord Houghton was elevated to become the first Marquess of Crewe and served in various government jobs before becoming chairman of Imperial College, London. He died in 1945.
Sets of the Order of St Patrick insignia very rarely appear on the market and only a few examples are known in museums. Although made of gold and silver, the stones are non-precious. That has not stopped Sothebys from estimating the insignias value at up to 12,000.
The high valuation is linked to their historical significance and enhanced by the mystery surrounding the priceless master set of badge and star  made with pink and white diamonds, emeralds and rubies from the collection of George IIIs wife Queen Charlotte  and presented to the order in 1830. Known as the Irish Crown Jewels, they were stolen from Dublin Castle in 1907  years after Houghton had departed  in a robbery that attracted international media attention and remains one of Irelands greatest unsolved crimes.
The Order of St Patrick became dormant in 1922 following Independence but still exists and Queen Elizabeth remains its sovereign. The last Knight of St Patrick  Prince Henry, Duke of Gloucester  died in 1974.
The auction also features a collection of Victorian Irish art inherited by the duchess from her father, who bought the paintings in Dublin during his term as viceroy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Union warns of job losses after takeover of Aer Lingus</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/union-warns-of-job-losses-after-takeover-of-aer-lingus-1.2227080</Link>
        <Description>Tourism Ireland said the decision would boost tourism to Ireland from North America   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Union warns of job losses after takeover of Aer Lingus
Tourism Ireland said the decision would boost tourism to Ireland from North America
Minister for Transport, Tourism and Sport Paschal Donohoe  made the announcement about the Governments decision. Photograph: Nick Bradshaw
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:01
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:01
The Irish Congress of Trade Unions said it was a matter of very serious concern that the Government had failed to achieve any guarantees on possible job losses and outsourcing in Aer Lingus, despite some progress on issues such as connectivity and slot retention.
Congress general secretary Patricia King said: While there has been some obvious progress, there was also a very clear failure to achieve guarantees that there would be no compulsory redundancies or outsourcing, following any IAG takeover.
She added: Our fears about the loss of existing jobs in the event of an IAG takeover have not been assuaged.
Tourism Ireland said the decision would boost tourism to Ireland from North America. Todays announcement that Aer Lingus, within the IAG family, plans to add four transatlantic flights, increase its fleet by eight new aircraft and carry up to 2.4 million additional passengers by 2020 represents a huge boost for the tourism sector, said the chief executive of Tourism Ireland, Niall Gibbons.
The Irish Hotels Federation said it welcomed the additional guarantees secured by the Government. Its president, Stephen McNally, said the commitment in relation to Aer Lingus s Heathrow slots was a significant development that would provide greater certainty for routes into Dublin, Cork and Shannon airports.
Shannon Airport also welcomed the Governments decision. The chairman of Shannon Group plc, Rose Hynes, said: Its good news; its a positive opportunity for Ireland, will safeguard the Shannon-Heathrow connectivity for seven years and it opens the door to further growth at Shannon.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gardaí know motive for murder of man found in gateway </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/garda%C3%AD-know-motive-for-murder-of-man-found-in-gateway-1.2227037</Link>
        <Description>Detectives identify suspects who killed Dubliner and dumped his body   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Garda know motive for murder of man found in gateway
Detectives identify suspects who killed Dubliner and dumped his body
Garda believe they know the identity of the men who carried out the murder of Dubliner Andrew Guerrine. Photograph: Bryan OBrien
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
Garda investigating the murder of a man whose remains were found dumped by the side of the road believe they have identified the motive for his killing.
Detectives also believe they know the identities of the men who carried out the murder of Dubliner Andrew Guerrine .
The remains of the drug-user and dealer were found in the same gateway on Steelstown Lane, Rathcoole, Co Dublin, where a baby girl was found abandoned almost three weeks ago.
It is believed Mr Guerrine (37), who was in ill health from years of drug abuse, had stolen money from a Dublin crime gang which also feared he may become an informer.
The emergency services were alerted to Mr Guerrines death after receiving a 999 call from a member of the public just before 3am on Saturday. Garda said he was pronounced dead when the emergency services arrived at the scene near Rathcoole close to the N7 and Kildare-Dublin border.
Post
mortem The results of a post
mortem on his remains have not been disclosed for operational reasons, but it is believed his throat was slashed and that he had sustained a number of other serious injuries.
From New Street in Dublins south inner city, Mr Guerrine was well known to garda for his involvement in drug dealing and as an abuser of drugs including heroin.
He had been to prison on numerous occasions and fraternised with members of a well-known Dublin drugs gang which supplies smaller dealers in the regions.
Evidence
Garda believe they have evidence that reveals how the dead man was taken to the spot where his remains were found.
The investigation, which is being led by Supt Brendan Connolly at Clondalkin Garda station, has also identified a number of suspects.
Garda sources said work on trying to establish the movements of those men on Friday night and Saturday morning was going well.
Supt Connolly said the Garda wished to appeal for witnesses who may have been in the area of Steelstown Lane between midnight on Friday and 3am on Saturday.
He said the public could contact Clondalkin Garda station on 01-6667600, the Garda confidential line on 1800-666111 or any Garda station.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>O’Rorke to push TDs for new legislation on assisted suicide </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/o-rorke-to-push-tds-for-new-legislation-on-assisted-suicide-1.2227024</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
ORorke to push TDs for new legislation on assisted suicide
Gail ORorke who was found not guilty of assisted suicide is to meet TDs  to discuss the need for new legislation in the area. Photograph: Cyril Byrne / THE IRISH TIMES
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
A woman found not guilty of assisted suicide is to meet TDs today to discuss the need for new legislation in the area.
Gail ORorke will be joined by Tom Curran , the partner of the late Marie Fleming who went to the High Court and the Supreme Court to challenge the ban on assisted suicide.
The two will meet Independent TD John Halligan to push for new legislation to be debated.
Mr Halligan said: It is great to have her support. We will meet TDs to try to garner some support, calling on people to at least have a debate on the legislation.
Mr Halligan is to introduce the Dying with Dignity Bill in the Dil in two weeks. He said there needed to be a dignified, compassionate and thoughtful debate on the issue.
His Bill, which was drawn up by two barristers, sets out strict criteria before an assisted suicide can take place.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State is selling Aer Lingus for  ‘paltry sum’, Sean Barrett tells Seanad</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/state-is-selling-aer-lingus-for-paltry-sum-sean-barrett-tells-seanad-1.2227081</Link>
        <Description>Transport economist  says BA has no flights from Scotland or  any regional airport to US    </Description>
        <MainBody>Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
Independent Senator Sean Barrett has warned the Government that it is selling the national airline for a paltry sum to a company that provides no service to the US from any Scottish airport or from any British regional location.
Mr Barrett, an economist specialising in transport matters, accused British Airways of conduct that showed contempt for this House, for this parliament, for an independent country.
In the hours before the Cabinet was last night made a decision to sell the States 25 per cent share in Aer Lingus to Willie Walshs AIG group, Mr Barrett said British Airways has gone to a British quango  the Competition and Markets Authority  to force Ryanair to divest its shares in Aer Lingus so that British Airways can take over.
In a strongly worded speech he accused the Government of presiding over the sale of the airline without reference to the Oireachtas transport committee.
We need that national airline. This is an outer offshore island that needs to access transport and from which Aer Lingus had developed nine transatlantic routes.
There are none from Scotland, which was a major factor in the rise of the Scottish National Party in recently elections. That partys transport spokesman Angus Mac Neill said British Airways neglects Scotland. It has no routes to North America.
Track record
Mr Barrett added: We are trying to develop this country yet we are handing over the national airline to an airline whose track record is not to provide services from Belfast, Edinburgh, Glasgow, Manchester, Birmingham or any other region of the UK to North America.
He pointed to The Irish Times Ipsos/MRBI poll which he said showed two-thirds opposed the privatisation of the States share in Aer Lingus.
Fianna Fil Seanad leader Darragh OBrien said 15,000 pensioners suffered savage cuts to their pension benefits which allowed Aer Lingus and the airport to wipe away a 740 million pension deficit in order to fatten the company up for sale.
Labour Seanad leader Ivana Bacik said she had made her view clear that she did not agree with the sale.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aer Lingus: State to keep veto over Heathrow slots </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/aer-lingus-state-to-keep-veto-over-heathrow-slots-1.2227105</Link>
        <Description>National carrier unions, Impact and Siptu, to oppose IAG offer despite assurances  on jobs   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Aer Lingus: State to keep veto over Heathrow slots
National carrier unions, Impact and Siptu, to oppose IAG offer despite assurances  on jobs
Despite late assurances by Aer Lingus that it did not envisage compulsory redundancies or outsourcing, the companys two main unions will opose the deal. Photograph: The Irish Times
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
The State is to get a special share in Aer Lingus safeguarding the airlines slots at Heathrow, in return for backing a 1.4 billion takeover bid for it.
The Government is recommending the sale of the States 25.1 per cent stake in Aer Lingus to International Consolidated Airlines Groups (IAG) and is set to put a motion to the Dil today, followed by a vote on Thursday.
However, Opposition parties are opposing the deal and the two Aer Lingus unions, Impact and Sipptu, have both come out against it, despite a late assurance form Aer Lingus on compulsory redundancy and outsourcing.
Top 1000 Database
Under the terms of IAGs offer, the Minister for Finance will retain a special B share in Aer Lingus which will allow changes to connectivity to be made only with the consent of the government of the day.
A legally binding commitment has also been provided to protect the Aer Lingus brand, as well as ensuring its headquarters are based in Ireland.
The B share will underpin legally binding guarantees on all the airlines existing take-off and landing rights at Heathrow Airport for an unlimited period of time. The current daily services between the London hub and Dublin, Cork and Shannon will be maintained for at least seven years, with the final two years conditional on airport charges not increasing beyond specified levels.
The Government believes Aer Linguss Heathrow slots are critical to maintaining links that are vital to the Republics foreign trade and tourism. Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe said the new share will be held by the Minister for Finance indefinitely because it is needed to oversee the guarantee that we have in relation to the indefinite commitment and guarantee and slot retention. We are confident that is legally robust and we have already received indications that from an operation point of view that it would not be opposed.
The group of Labour TDs who have had concerns about the deal are understood to be broadly happy with the proposals.
However, Clare Labour deputy Michael McNamara, whose primary concerns are around connectivity, said he wanted to see the details of the deal, and would vote against the sale in the Dil if he was not satisfied with it.
IAG is forwarding its offer to the European Commissions competition regulators . Brussels will have to approve any deal before it can go ahead. Aer Lingus shareholders will receive full details of the offer within 28 days.
Ryanair, owner of 29.8 per cent of the airline, is the largest shareholder and its acceptance is needed for the sale to go through. It has said that its board will review any offer it receives on its merits.
The 350 million that the State will earn from the sale will be used for investment in other transport projects, as well as in areas such as broadband.
Fianna Fil transport spokesman Timmy Dooley said the Government was making the wrong decision. An independent Aer Lingus could achieve continued and significant growth over the years ahead through strategic alliances and organic growth.
Sinn Fins Dessie Ellis said he has grave concerns about the effect the deal would have on Irelands connectivity into the future, as well as the threat it posed to workers.
Despite late assurances by Aer Lingus that it did not envisage compulsory redundancies or outsourcing, the companys two main unions will opose the deal.
Siptu said it would vigorously oppose the Government plan due to the failure of the company to provide commitments to workers that it would not impose compulsory redundancies or the outsourcing of jobs. It said it would call on TDs to vote against the Dail motion.
The Impact trade union said it maintained the view that the proposed takeover was bad for jobs, for Aer Lingus workers and for Irelands connectivity and economic development.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Analysis: Crisis on welfare changes nearing climax as Stormont limps on</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/analysis-crisis-on-welfare-changes-nearing-climax-as-stormont-limps-on-1.2227005</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Analysis: Crisis on welfare changes nearing climax as Stormont limps on
Minister for Finance Arlene Foster,  the DUPs Nigel Dodds and Sammy Wilson: Sinn Fen is leading the charge against the welfare change with the SDLP.  Photograph: Kelvin Boyes
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
There was considerable public and indeed political sympathy with the comment of Alliance Assembly member Stewart Dickson yesterday when he referred to the feeling of utter exasperation and the profound sense of dj vu at the latest crisis afflicting Stormont .
Its yet another brinkmanship battle, with Sinn Fin and the SDLP insisting now is not the time to roll over on accepting welfare changes. Unionist and Alliance politicians feel that battle is long over and lost and failure to move on welfare could topple the Stormont institutions.
There were general good wishes for First Minister and DUP leader Peter Robinson and his family in the Assembly chamber yesterday. Senior party members Nigel Dodds , Arlene Foster and Sammy Wilson told reporters while he is treated for his heart condition it is business as usual.
Nonetheless, it has to be a significant concern for the British and Irish governments Stormont is missing a politician with a keen strategic sense. In the meantime, there is stalemate and the Northern Secretary Theresa Villiers must consider what is to happen next. The first request she is likely to face will be from the DUP asking her on behalf of the British government to take over responsibility for welfare from the Executive.
Black hole
Villiers is anxious to resist that demand. She wants the Northern politicians to sort out this mess themselves. But the next pressure is to fully implement the Norths 10 billion budget. However, in the absence of agreement on welfare, that budget, according to DUP Minister of Finance Arlene Foster, will suffer a black hole for the rest of this financial year of up to 600 million. This, she believes, is unsustainable.
Without agreement on the budget, the permanent secretary of the Department of Finance could be called in to implement a reduced budget.
Moreover, again because of the absence of agreement on welfare, part or all of the Stormont House Agreement with its promise of 2 billion over the coming five years could be lost. Also sacrificed would be proposals to deal with the past and to help victims, as well as reductions in corporation tax that could create up to 35,000 jobs.
So, behind all the public exasperation and cynicism, there is a lot at stake here.
Sinn Fin is leading the charge against the welfare change and the SDLP is following in its wake. But the big question for both parties is what will be the consequences of continuing to dig in.
The DUP, the Ulster Unionists and Alliance contend that, if Sinn Fin and the SDLP refuse to budge, welfare recipients wont be any better off while some of the gains made in the Stormont House Agreement could be thrown away. In response, Sinn Fin and the SDLP argue further negotiation could yield more concessions. But these are two parties who dont have any particular leverage with David Cameron or George Osborne .
In the Assembly chamber yesterday, there were assertions by unionist politicians that Sinn Fin in the North was being dictated to by  Gerry Adams and the partys Southern command. It was claimed that, ahead of an Irish general election, the party didnt want to be accused of accepting austerity north of the Border.
This is indeed a political crisis but the climax hasnt been reached yet. Stormont probably can limp on for another few weeks before the really hard decisions have to be taken. Still, there is no doubt the deadlock over welfare reform has the potential to bring down the Northern Executive and Assembly. But there is still time to avert that collapse.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sanctions being finalised to crack down on disruptive TDs</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/sanctions-being-finalised-to-crack-down-on-disruptive-tds-1.2226816</Link>
        <Description>Dáil Committee on Procedure and Privileges to make decision on standing orders    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Sanctions being finalised to crack down on disruptive TDs
Dil Committee on Procedure and Privileges to make decision on standing orders
Sinn Fin deputy leader Mary Lou McDonald, who staged a sit-in in the Dil chamber last November and was found later by the Committee on Procedure and Privileges to have abused parliamentary privilege. Photograph: Colin Keegan/Collins Dublin
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
Tough new sanctions on TDs who behave in a disorderly and disruptive way in the Dil chamber are close to being finalised.
The Dil Committee on Procedure and Privileges (CPP) will shortly make a decision on new standing orders which have been designed in response to a spate of disorderly episodes over the past few years.
The most publicised instances in recent times involved Sinn Fin deputy leader Mary Lou McDonald, who staged a sit-in in the chamber last November and was found later by the CPP to have abused parliamentary privilege.
Sources close to Leinster House authorities say disorder in the chamber, obstruction of Dil business and the misuse of parliamentary privilege are now widely regarded to having a serious reputational impact on the Dil.
Legal expert
Arising from recent incidents the CPP engaged a legal expert to prepare proposals for new sanctions that would equip the Dil with the authority to deal with the undermining of the business of the chamber.
It is understood these draft proposals include the idea of cumulative sanctions that increase the penalty on members who repeatedly obstruct Dil business or abuse parliamentary privilege.
Currently TDs who are suspended from the Dil retain access to committees but under the new CPP proposals they will be suspended from all parliamentary activity.
More importantly, in cases of repeat offences the number of suspension days will be cumulative and TDs could find themselves excluded from all Dil business for long periods.
The practical implications of their non-attendance at Leinster House will mean they are not able to claim expenses during suspension but, more seriously, repeat offenders will be excluded from Dil votes and committee attendance.
An Oireachtas source said the repeated sight of members abusing privilege or obstructing the work of parliament without any meaningful political consequences or sanction was eroding and undermining public trust and faith in the institution to take its own business seriously.
He emphasised, however, the move was designed to impose sanctions on disruptive behaviour and not to limit the freedom of TDs to express their views on matters of public importance.
It is unrelated to the complaint by businessman Denis OBrien about comments made under privilege in the House by Independent TD Catherine Murphy and his demand that the Dil record be amended
New record
In response to a query about the complaint yesterday, an Oireachtas spokesperson said: The notion that the Dil record can be corrected or altered is a misnomer. The Dil record cannot be changed. Members who wish to clarify what they have previously said on the record may make a statement in the House and this then becomes a new record.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taoiseach rules out abortion referendum</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/taoiseach-rules-out-abortion-referendum-1.2226883</Link>
        <Description>No referendum on eighth amendment in Government’s lifetime, Enda Kenny tells Dáil   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Taoiseach rules out abortion referendum
No referendum on eighth amendment in Governments lifetime, Enda Kenny tells Dil
Taoiseach Enda Kenny: I do not believe in abortion on demand, but there are very sensitive stories in respect of fatal foetal abnormalities and other issues. Photograph: Jason Alden/Bloomberg
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
Taoiseach Enda Kenny has firmly ruled out a referendum repealing the controversial 1983 constitutional amendment on the equal right to life of the child and the mother.
He was replying in the Dil to Socialist Party TD Paul Murphy who said the eighth amendment should be repealed in the aftermath of the Yes vote in the marriage equality referendum.
This, said Mr Murphy , would end the barbaric situation where a woman who has chosen to terminate a crisis pregnancy  even in the tragic eventuality of fatal foetal abnormality  or a doctor or anybody else who helped her could be jailed for 14 years.
Mr Kenny replied: Believe me, Deputy Murphy, it is not a case of saying we should have another referendum next week.
I will not do that, and there will not be a referendum on this issue in the lifetime of this Government.
The Taoiseach said the issue deserved the most serious consideration.
I do not believe in abortion on demand, but there are very sensitive stories in respect of fatal foetal abnormalities and other issues, he said.
However, it is not a case of repealing the eighth amendment and that everybody will be happy afterwards.
Mr Kenny said he knew an Oireachtas committee was considering hearings in the late autumn on the issue.
Consequences
In the case of the marriage equality referendum, he said, people were able to point out exactly what the consequences would be.
Believe me, from experience over many years, it is not possible to be as clear in respect of a concept of changing the eighth amendment of the Constitution, Mr Kenny said.
For that reason, the excitement of change created by the vote of the people  and it was the Government that decided to put the referendum to the people by popular vote  is an entirely different matter.
Mr Kenny said the marriage equality referendum was about living, love, commitment and dedication. A repeal of the eighth amendment, empathising with the very many tragic stories he had heard, would deal with other elements that were not clear at all, he said.
Legislation
Mr Murphy said they knew about the tragic case of Savita Halappanavar and the horrific case of Miss Y. Repealing the eighth amendment would allow for the legislation for abortion in whatever circumstances the Government considered.
I am in favour of the full right of women to access abortion but, at the very least, the Government should commit to repeal the eighth amendment, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Plans for  new €150m national  maternity hospital  on hold </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/plans-for-new-150m-national-maternity-hospital-on-hold-1.2227049</Link>
        <Description>Board of St Vincent’s suspends involvement due to dispute with HSE and current hospital    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Plans for  new 150m national  maternity hospital  on hold
Board of St Vincents suspends involvement due to dispute with HSE and current hospital
Leo Varadkar, Minister for Health:  The board wrote  to him saying  until it had evidence of real and constructive engagement on matters of concern, we believe we must pause our engagement with the project. Photograph: Cyril Byrne / The Irish Times
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
The planned 150 million development of a new national maternity hospital on the campus of St Vincents hospital in Dublin has been put on hold.
The relocation of the maternity hospital, one of the largest in the country, from its outdated premises in Holles Street to a modern facility on the St Vincents campus, is a key health project for the Government.
The St Vincents Healthcare Group has suspended its involvement because of a dispute with the HSE and the current National Maternity Hospital over the planned project.
The board of the group told Minister for Health Leo Varadkar , in a letter sent on May 6th, that until it had evidence of real and constructive engagement on matters of concern, we believe we must pause our engagement with the project.
The St Vincents group said there were two matters that had to be resolved before it could commit to final design and planning applications.
Firstly, we need to ensure that St Vincents, the National Maternity Hospital and the HSE have a common and clear understanding of how the integrated facility will be governed and managed once it is complete, to ensure that planned benefits are all delivered.
Adversely affected
Secondly, we need to have involvement in managing the construction project so we can ensure that our delivery of healthcare services on campus would not be adversely affected during the several years required to complete the integrated facility.
In the letter to the Minister, the group said dealing with these two issues had proved to be problematic despite repeated attempts by its representatives to reach an agreement.
Mr Varadkar said last night he would respond to the letter in due course. The issues raised . . . are significant but not insurmountable, he said.
The development of the new maternity hospital was formally announced by former minister for health James Reilly exactly two years ago.
At the time, the National Maternity Hospital said a new facility was urgently needed as its current Holles Street site was no longer fit for purpose.
Relations between the St Vincents group and the HSE have been tense recently over a number of issues, including governance and consultants working in its private hospital.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government to consider slapping ban over Council of Europe ruling</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/government-to-consider-slapping-ban-over-council-of-europe-ruling-1.2226965</Link>
        <Description>Top human rights body says Irish corporal punishment law violates children’s rights   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Government to consider slapping ban over Council of Europe ruling
Top human rights body says Irish corporal punishment law violates childrens rights
While legislation which allowed parents to use force against their children was repealed almost 15 years ago, the defence of reasonable chastisement still exists in common law for parents or child carers
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
The Government will today announce plans to review laws which permit the slapping of children, following a ruling by the Council of Europe that the lack of a clear ban is a violation of young peoples rights.
The Irish Times understands that Europes top human rights body will on Wednesday rule that Irelands laws on corporal punishment are in breach of the European Social Charter, whose signatories promise to protect children and young persons against negligence, violence or exploitation.
While legislation which allowed parents to use force against their children was repealed almost 15 years ago, the defence of reasonable chastisement still exists in common law for parents or child carers.
Corporal punishment: reasonable chastisement no longer acceptable
In response to the ruling, Minister for Children James Reilly is expected to pledge to explicitly ban the smacking of children in foster or residential care through new regulations.
In addition, sources indicate he will announce plans to review the defence of reasonable chastisement, in conjunction with the Department of Justice.
Disciplining children
Studies suggest that while smacking is becoming less socially acceptable in Ireland, it remains widely used as a way of disciplining children on occasion. The Growing Up in Ireland study of three-year-olds found up to 45 per cent of their primary caregivers smacked them sometimes.
In countries where there has been an explicit ban, the use of smacking has tended to fall dramatically.
On Wednesday morning, the Council of Europes committee on social rights is expected to rule that the lack of a clear ban is a violation of article 17 of the European Social Charter.
Following the ruling, a formal resolution noting the rights violation is expected to be made by the council in June.
A spokesman for the council last night declined to comment on the ruling, but said any member state found in violation of the charter faces an international obligation to address the issue.
While Ireland cannot be forced to change its laws by the council, it will face peer pressure from other member states who form part of the council.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Minister pledges women and infant health programme</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/minister-pledges-women-and-infant-health-programme-1.2227041</Link>
        <Description>Leo Varadkar says national programme will improve all maternity services   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Minister pledges women and infant health programme
Leo Varadkar says national programme will improve all maternity services
Minister for Health Leo Varadkar: Modelled on the highly successful national cancer programme, it will provide the leadership and have the authority to deliver the strategy and to drive reform and standardise care across all 19 maternity units
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
A national womens and infants health programme to improve maternity services is to be established by Minister for Health Leo Varadkar .
He told the Dil the programme would span the delivery of services across the country.
Modelled on the highly successful national cancer programme, it will provide the leadership and have the authority to deliver the strategy and to drive reform and standardise care across all 19 maternity units, he added.
Mr Varadkar was replying to a Fianna Fil Private Members motion on infant deaths in Portlaoise hospital.
He said the Hiqa report on the issue had not named any individual and he did not have the power to effect summary dismissals or sanctions against people who were not in his employment.
I do not propose to comment further at this time other than to say that a number of staff have had complaints made to their professional regulatory bodies, relating to their involvement in care in Portlaoise.
These will be investigated in line with standard procedures and the law.
HSE investigation
In addition, the HSE was finalising an investigation in line with its code of governance and disciplinary procedures which might result in action being taken against some individuals in management positions. He welcomed the report, which had followed the 2014 report by the Chief Medical Officer into perinatal deaths at Portlaoise.
I believe that the criticism is justified, and I am disappointed that our health service was found to be so lacking in compassion and care, two core values of the service we strive to deliver.
Mr Varadkar said families and patients were treated badly and it was not only an issue of resources. It costs nothing to care, he said.
Fianna Fils Sen Fleming said the HSE does not want the truth to come out. Mr Fleming, in whose constituency Portlaoise Hospital is located, said I stress that.
He added that the Health Service Executive was already involved in a row over who would be involved in the review of services. It is the culture of top management to protect the HSE.
There had to be an honest discussion about Portlaoise, but he said it would take an outsider to deal with the problem because the HSEs culture is first and foremost to protect the institution.
Fianna Fil health spokesman Billy Kelleher said only for the persistence of the parents, nobody would be any the wiser and the pretence would have continued that the hospital was safe and adequately staffed. He said the previous minister for health made political decisions that needed to be explained, including why Portlaoise was singled out for special treatment in terms of retention of its status.
Sinn Fin health spokesman Caoimhghn  Caolin believed the National Perinatal Epidemiology Centre was not informed about a number of deaths of babies. Nothing was learned or changed following their passing, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former judge to advise on letters to Garda complainants</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/former-judge-to-advise-on-letters-to-garda-complainants-1.2227017</Link>
        <Description>Total of 319 complaints referred to panel of counsel    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Former judge to advise on letters to Garda complainants
Total of 319 complaints referred to panel of counsel
Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald: It is better to take that time now so as to provide complete reassurance on the probity and independence of the entire process from start to finish.
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
A former judge is being appointed to advise on the drafting of letters to those complaining of Garda misconduct, Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald has said.
It is better to take that time now so as to provide complete reassurance on the probity and independence of the entire process from start to finish, the Minister said.
Ms Fitzgerald told the Dil that 319 complaints had been referred to a panel of counsel.
Obviously, the volume and complexity of cases has changed the time frame and has led to the review taking longer than originally anticipated, she added. We wanted counsel to take time to examine all of the cases fully and carefully.
Ms Fitzgerald said there were many cases which had already been through some form of process that involved the courts, the Garda Sochna Ombudsman Commission or some other body.
Ms Fitzgerald was replying to Fianna Fil justice spokesman Niall Collins , who said that in the previous 24 hours, he had received communications from two of the people affected.
At a minimum, the fact that the Minister has now engaged a former member of the judiciary to help draft a reply should be communicated to each of the 319 people involved, he added.
Mr Collins said those who had made complaints were concerned the process was drifting.
Prior to this, they had lost confidence in the processes of State and now this process seems to be dragging on.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘Anomalies’ must be removed when marriage law drawn up, says Norris </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/anomalies-must-be-removed-when-marriage-law-drawn-up-says-norris-1.2227072</Link>
        <Description>Schools with different ethos entitled to transmit values dear to them, says Rónán Mullen   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Anomalies must be removed when marriage law drawn up, says Norris
Schools with different ethos entitled to transmit values dear to them, says Rnn Mullen
Senator David Norris in the courtyard at Dublin Castle for the result of the referendum on marriage equality. He was praised in the Seanad for his decades-long campaign for gay rights
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
Independent Senator David Norris has called for certain anomalies to be ironed out when legislation is drawn up to give effect to the result of the marriage equality referendum.
Mr Norris, who was praised in the Seanad for his decades-long campaign for gay rights, said the anomalies included pension irregularities.
He also pointed to section 37 of the equality legislation, which allows schools, at least theoretically, to dismiss people for their lifestyles being in conflict with the ethos.
NUI Senator Rnn Mullen, who opposed the referendum, said however that rather than having culture wars, we should consider how we can accommodate different visions of important issues.
He called for a generous view in the section 37 debate, and said it was important schools of different denominations and ethos are entitled to transmit the values that are dear to them and reflect their foundational ethos and that of the people who send their children to them.
Human right
Independent Senator Katherine Zappone , who took a legal case to have her Canadian marriage to her spouse Ann Louise Gilligan recognised in Ireland, said that, at the time, her legal counsel argued that our human right to marry each other should exist even if the majority did not agree.
Fianna Fil Senator Denis ODonovan, who described the outcome as a tsunami victory, said that, as a practising Catholic, I believe that unless the Catholic Church takes heed of the seismic shift in Irish society, it will decline further into the abyss.
He said he would like to see a move in the Catholic Church to a more centrist position and to an acknowledgment of how society is evolving.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McAleese's son says FF treated  Averil Power ‘abysmally’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/mcaleese-s-son-says-ff-treated-averil-power-abysmally-1.2226908</Link>
        <Description>Justin McAleese criticises Fianna Fáil’s role in same-sex marriage referendum   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
McAleese's son says FF treated  Averil Power abysmally
Justin McAleese criticises Fianna Fils role in same-sex marriage referendum
Fianna Fil welcomes its latest TD Bobby Aylward (Carlow-Kilkenny) to Leinster House yesterday. Mr Aylward is accompanied by party leader Michel Martin (right) and other supporters. Photograph: Dara Mac Donaill/The Irish Times
Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
First published: Wed, May 27, 2015, 01:00
The son of former president Mary McAleese has criticised Fianna Fils role in the same-sex marriage referendum. Justin McAleese said the party has treated Senator Averil Power, who resigned from the party, abysmally.
In a post on his Facebook account, Mr McAleese, who worked with the Yes Equality campaign, praised Ms Powers efforts in the campaign,
Fianna Fils contribution to the marriage equality referendum is best summed up by the party leaders address at the Ard Fheis on 25 April last which was broadcast on primetime television. A total of 28 words out of a 3,093-word speech were devoted to the referendum. That 0.09% is consistent with the effort put in by the partys TDs during the campaign.
McGee and ORegan report on a very important victory for Fianna Fail
The party meanwhile welcomed its latest TD Bobby Aylward to Leinster House on Tuesday but was still having to defend itself over the departure of Ms Power.
Fianna Fil leader Michel Martin told his parliamentary party meeting to move on from the debacle and to focus all their efforts on the general election.
Mr Martin said he stood by his claims that Ms Power had asked him to orchestrate a selection convention in Dublin Bay North for her own benefit. He told his party the conversation he had with the now Independent Senator was clear and crystal in his mind.
One TD said: Michel said what he had to say and all TDs rowed in behind him. He said he remembered his conversation with Ms Power vividly and said he was not in the business of telling lies.
Mr Martin has accused Ms Power of asking him to prevent Sen Haughey, a councillor, from standing in the constituency. Ms Power said this was outrageous and untrue and said they both had told her she was the preferred candidate.
The Senator said on Tuesday she had found the personal attacks on her by Mr Martin and the party hurtful. The co-ordinated personal attacks have been very personal but I know they are motivated to distract from the lack of vision and leadership in the party. They confirmed for me that I made the right choice.
Mr Martin said it was Mr Aylwards day and denied it had been overshadowed by the departure of Ms Power. He said he had articulated his views on the resignation and did not intend to add to them any further. Things happen in politics and we move on.We dealt with those issues yesterday.
Whip Sen  Fearghail said Ms Powers comments were vicious and offensive and was an attack on the wider Fianna Fil party. Fianna Fil TD Timmy Dooley said it was untrue to say Mr Martin was an ineffective leader. He led from the front. He took a principled position because he believed in it.
Elsewhere, Billy Kelleher TD said he was disappointed by the announcement of Cork member Ken Curtin to resign from party. Mr Kelleher said there were some within the party who did not agree with the referendum but that was reflected across all political parties.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:27:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cliff Taylor: Coalition swayed to sell  by new Heathrow assurances</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/cliff-taylor-coalition-swayed-to-sell-by-new-heathrow-assurances-1.2227091</Link>
        <Description>   Complexity made this seem like the takeover bid that would never end  </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Cliff Taylor: Coalition swayed to sell  by new Heathrow assurances
Complexity made this seem like the takeover bid that would never end
It was clear from day one that the Governments decision would be based on what the deal meant for connectivity and also on its perception of what the political impact would be. Photograph: Getty
First published: Tue, May 26, 2015, 22:27

It has seemed like the takeover bid that would never end and, even at the last minute, contacts on redundancy guarantees and toing and froing with backbenchers led to one final delay.
IAG made its initial bid for Aer Lingus more than six months ago and has been locked in discussions with a Government-appointed committee since February on the basis of a third bid of 2.55 a share.
Finally, yesterday evening, the Cabinet gave the green light, though there is still a road to travel before the takeover goes through.
Top 1000 Database
Generally takeover bids rest on one thing  price.
However, IAG boss Willie Walsh would have been well aware as he launched the bid that he faced a more complex picture. In addition to offering a price that would win acceptance from the airlines disparate group of owners, he knew IAG had to persuade one key shareholder  the Government  that the bid was in the wider national interest.
Cash pile
A few years ago, the State was pressed for cash and would have been under financial pressure to accept a deal to get its hands on the money. Now, with the ability to raise money on the markets at super-low interest rates and a cash pile of 20 billion-plus, the Government will welcome the cash it will get for its stake, but it will make no major difference to the national finances.
It was clear from day one that the Governments decision would be based on what the deal meant for connectivity and also on its perception of what the political impact would be.
The interface in these talks was an expert committee appointed by Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe and comprised of senior civil servants and investment and legal advisers. The agreement to sell the Government stake was based on a lengthy document outlining in detail IAG commitments on the Heathrow slots, the future of the Aer Lingus brand and jobs at the airline.
Part of the delay in finalising a deal was based on the detail and the associated technical and legal complexity. In particular, the Government wanted legally watertight assurances on the Heathrow slots for longer than the original five-year term suggested by IAG and also a mechanism to allow it to veto the sale of these slots at any future date.
A mid-point of about seven years was eventually agreed, but work was needed to ensure that the agreement to give a veto to the Government on the sale of the slots was within EU state aid rules. This appears to have been clarified only in recent weeks.
Formalised
IAG will also have been trying to establish that Aer Linguss biggest shareholder, Ryanair, would sign up to the deal. Ryanair has said it will consider the offer when formalised  should it accept that the deal will almost certainly go through.
It also needs competition approval from the EU Commission, which will complete an initial examination in 35 days, and the acceptance of the bulk of the remaining company shareholders.
Over the past month, a number of the main issues finally fell into place. The key points in dispute between the Government and IAG were sorted out. The European Commission took a positive view on the slot-guarantee mechanism and is not expected to have any major objections on competition grounds.
Contacts continued with the unions, though it was only yesterday that Aer Lingus chief executive Stephen Kavanagh confirmed in a letter to Mr Donohoe that no compulsory redundancies or outsourcing of activities were anticipated.
After considerable coming and going with Coalition backbenchers  particularly Labour TDs from north Dublin  the Government agreement to sell its shares was finally announced.
First published: Tue, May 26, 2015, 22:27

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:17:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mixed reaction to Government’s decision to sell Aer Lingus stake</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/mixed-reaction-to-government-s-decision-to-sell-aer-lingus-stake-1.2227084</Link>
        <Description>ICTU concerned about lack of  guarantees on possible job losses and outsourcing   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Mixed reaction to Governments decision to sell Aer Lingus stake
ICTU concerned about lack of  guarantees on possible job losses and outsourcing
There has been mixed reaction to the news that the government has agreed to approve the sale of its 25 per cent stake in Aer Lingus. Photograph: Getty
Tue, May 26, 2015, 22:19
First published: Tue, May 26, 2015, 22:17
There has been mixed reaction to the news that the government has agreed to approve the sale of its 25 per cent stake in Aer Lingus.
The Irish Congress of Trade Unions (ICTU) said it was concerned the government had failed to achieve any guarantees on possible job losses and outsourcing in Aer Lingus.
Congress General Secretary Patricia King said there are no guarantees that there would be no compulsory redundancies or outsourcing, following an IAG takeover.
Top 1000 Database
Senior management at the airline will benefit hugely from any sale and that contrasts quite sharply with the failure to provide the rest of the staff with certainty, in relation to compulsory redundancies and outsourcing of existing functions, said Ms King.
The Dublin Airport Authority, which operates Dublin and Cork airports, welcomed the Governments decision.
DAA Chief Executive Kevin Toland said: We believe that this transaction, should it be completed, offers significant potential benefits for both Dublin Airport and Cork Airport.
Dublin Airport is already becoming a significant hub for transatlantic travel and this market segment would be further strengthened with IAG as the owner of Aer Lingus. This should enable additional long-haul connections and frequencies into Dublins existing transatlantic hub.
Dublin and Cork airports currently support and facilitate more than 108,000 jobs in the Irish economy and we believe this transaction will lead to increased employment, as IAG expands its Irish operations in the future.
The Irish Hotels Federation (IHF) said it welcomed the additional guarantees secured by the Government from IAG in advance of a potential sale of the States stake in Aer Lingus.
Stephen McNally, IHF President, said the commitment in relation to Aer Lingus Heathrow slots will provide greater certainty for routes into Dublin, Cork and Shannon airports.
Maintaining strong levels of connectivity with our international markets is of vital importance to Irish tourism and the wider economy. We therefore welcome the guarantees given today by IAG and its commitment to continue service levels from Shannon and Cork airports, which provide crucial tourism and business links directly into the South and West of Ireland, said Mr McNally.
Niall Gibbons, CEO of Tourism Ireland, has said the deal represents a huge boost for the tourism sector in Ireland.
Mr Gibbons pointed to the new connections Aer Lingus would have with American Airlines and the oneworld alliance as a benefit that would give Irish tourism the benefit of a larger global sales network.
Sinn Fin Transport Spokesperson Dessie Ellis TD said the deal is a bad one for Ireland in the long term.
It is very disappointing and I have grave concerns for the effect it will have on Irelands connectivity into the future as well as the threat it poses to workers in Aer Lingus and to deferred pension members, he said.
IAG have no interest in Ireland and the government have failed to stand up for the interests of the country instead seeking to make a quick profit as an election looms, he added.
Shannon Group Chairman Rose Hynes welcomed the proposed IAG takeover of Aer Lingus and the Government decision to sell its shareholding in Aer Lingus.
This decision paves the way for IAG to take over Aer Lingus. Its good news; its a positive opportunity for Ireland, will safeguard the Shannon Heathrow connectivity for seven years and it opens the door to further growth at Shannon, she said.
Aer Lingus welcomed the decision by Government to support IAGs proposed offer for the company.
Chairman Colm Barrington said the deal would lead to an increase in jobs at Aer Lingus, the tourism sector and strengthen connectivity to and from Ireland.
This is a compelling transaction for Aer Lingus, its shareholders, its employees, its customers and for Ireland. Shareholders will realise an attractive return through the premium that the IAG offer provides over the level of our share price immediately prior to the announcement of IAGs offer, said Mr Barrington.
The company will reap the commercial and strategic benefits of being part of the much larger and globally diverse IAG Group and as a member of the oneworld alliance of 17 airlines that together carry over 500 million passengers.
This access to greater global scale will accelerate growth across our network, enhance Irelands position as a natural gateway connecting Europe and North America, give Irish tourism access to major traffic flows and customer loyalty programmes and provide better access for business interests and to cargo flows, he said.
Trade union Impact, which represents cabin crew, pilots and some ground staff at Aer Lingus said the deal remains bad for jobs, workers and for Irelands connectivity and economic development.
For the staff at Aer Lingus, there are genuine concerns of compulsory redundancies if the deal goes through, along with the prospect of a further erosion of terms and conditions in the inevitable restructuring of the company, it said.
Any assurances on the future use of the Heathrow slots will evaporate once the seven-year period has elapsed, after which these vital connection points can be moved to where they will make larger profits for the airline.
Thereafter, the interests of IAG shareholders will always trump the interests of the Irish economy and the Irish travelling public.
The Irish Aviation Authority (IAA) welcomed the Governments decision and said British Airways alone accounted for over 10 per cent of the IAAs air traffic management revenue during 2014.
Eamonn Brennan, IAA Chief Executive said, We believe that the proposal as approved by the Government offers significant benefits to Irish aviation, including guaranteed access to London Heathrow from Dublin, Cork and Shannon airports for a sustained period of time. The proposal provides certainty for the future of Aer Lingus.
Failte Ireland CEO Shaun Quinn welcomed the announcement : As an island nation, air access is the lifeblood of Irish tourism and todays developments offer greater certainty regarding Aer Lingus long term sustainability and, consequently, the continued growth of our tourism industry.
I am particularly pleased to note that IAG are committing to an additional eight transatlantic planes based out of Dublin. Given the recent performance of the North American market, this will provide us with the increased access to capitalise on the significant potential to attract even greater visitor numbers from the USA to our shores.
Employers group Ibec said the takeover had the potential to improve air connectivity to Ireland in the future, which would bring with it significant business and tourism benefits.
Ibec Director of Policy and Corporate Affairs Mary Rose Burke said: IAGs plan to use Aer Lingus as a springboard for further growth on the key North Atlantic routes could significantly increase the number and frequency of routes to and from Ireland.
Dublin Chamber of Commerce welcomed the decision to support the IAG purchase of Aer Lingus,
Chief Executive of Dublin Chamber of Commerce Gina Quin said: The decision regarding whether to sell the State stake in Aer Lingus was never going to be easy. IAG has stated an intention to use the acquisition of Aer Lingus as a lever to grow transfer traffic at Irish airports.
International air connectivity enhances the national economy by facilitating investment, exports, workers, clients and tourists, Ms Quin added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
