<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:27:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Archbishop says woman was 20 when they first had sex</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/high-court/ex-archbishop-says-woman-was-20-when-they-first-had-sex-1.2264055</Link>
        <Description>Burke says he paid €176,000 to Nigerian woman at RTÉ Mission to Prey High Court case   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Ex-Archbishop says woman was 20 when they first had sex
Burke says he paid 176,000 to Nigerian woman at RT Mission to Prey High Court case
Former Archbishop of Benin Richard Burke pictured leaving the Four Courts on Thursday. Photograph: Courts Collins
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 13:28
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 13:27
A former Catholic Archbishop has told the High Court he first had sex with a Nigerian woman in 1989 when she was aged 20 and he was aged 40.
Co Tipperary-born Richard Burke (66) said he later paid sums totalling about  176,000 sought by Dolores Atwood .
He also agreed to have sex with her in an hotel in Canada in 2009 after she asked him to do that when he told her he could not pay her another  200,000 sought by her, he said.
Mr Burke said he felt terrorised by Ms Atwood and feared she would disclose their relationship which would bring disgrace and shame on himself, his family and his ministry.
Mr Burke said he first met Ms Atwood in 1986 or 1987 when she was aged 17 or 18 and he first had sex with her in 1989 when she was aged 20 in his bedroom in Cathedral House in Warri city in Nigeria . He did not know her when she was aged 13 or 14, he said.
He was ordained a Bishop in 1996 and an Archbishop in December 2007, the jury heard.
He was giving evidence in his continuing action alleging he was defamed in the RT Prime Time Investigates Mission to Prey programme of May 23rd 2011. RT denies defamation and has pleaded a defence of truth concerning the content related to Mr Burke.
Today, Mr Burke said he believed he first met Ms Atwood, born in August 1969, about 1986 or 1987 when she came to his office.
Ms Atwood told him she had been a confidante of another priest who was transferred from the cathedral parish about 1986 and soon afterwards was killed in a car accident, he said. He attributed his relationship with her as commencing after that priest was killed.
When his counsel said Ms Atwood told Prime Time about an event that happened when she was about the age of 13 in hospital, he said there was an event in hospital similar to that.
He said the first time he had sex with Ms Atwood was either September or October 1989 and the hospital event was after that. He had sex with her three more times before he returned to Ireland in 1990 and, while he was in Ireland, letters passed between them, he said.
He said Ms Atwood later married and moved to Canada, he believed that was about 1995. He was ordained Bishop of Warri in 1996 and had continuing contact with her between 1996 and 2003.
In 2003, he said she called him asking him to meet her in Lagos and spend three nights in an hotel and give her $4000 in cash, which he did.
Between 2003 and 2005, there was increasing phone contact between them, he said. The phone conversations had been about once a month or every three weeks but increased to between once weekly and ten days and the calls could last one or two hours and sometimes longer.
The calls sometimes became very uneasy and unpleasant for him because she was expressing a feeling for me I could not reciprocate, she was demanding intimacy.
He was devastated when he later learned she had phoned his brother in the family home in Tipperary and also his sister in Dublin.
He said Ms Atwood then phoned him demanding money and he eventually met her in the airport of Halifax in Nova Scotia by appointment in October 2007 and gave her a bank draft for  26,000 which she said was the full amount of all the phone calls.
He was incredibly worried if he did not hand over that money, she would reveal they had an intimate relationship.
He said he received more phone calls from October 2007 from Ms Atwood that were menacing, threatening, aggressive, abusive and demanding. He recorded a call of October 25th 2007 in which she gave him four options and told him to choose one.
One option was they would meet anywhere in the world over the next year any place and be together for at least one week, a minimum five days, and have full sexual intercourse, to be fully and totally intimate.
A second option was to give her  10,000 a year for five years, a third was they would meet somewhere and discuss it and the fourth was they should be together again the way we used to be.
He received another call about 11pm on November 7th 2007 where he was subject to a tirade of abuse from Ms Atwood for about three hours. That arose where he was to meet her in Lagos on November 8th to respond to the four options but she insisted the meeting was to have been on November 7th, he said.
Ms Atwood would not hear his explanation there was a clear arrangement for the 8th, he said.
She unleashed a tirade of abuse, saying he was treading on her and not to do that. That was the first time she mentioned :Youre a paedophile, he said.
Rather than give her  10,000 a year for five years, which was an eternity of prolonging this nightmare, he decided to try and end it once and for all and give her  50,000 in one payment.
She had said as God is my witness, I will never again bring up the matter of intimacy, we will be good friends, intimacy never, never again, he said.
He grabbed onto that phrase, chose the  50,000 payment, arranged to meet her in Dublin at the end of July 2008 and paid her that  50,000 in a bank draft and  5,000 cash.
After about a month, Ms Atwood started phoning again and demanding more money, he said. She was demanding  100,000 which he raised partly from his own and partly from diocesan funds. He met her in London and gave her a bank draft for  90,000 and 10,000 cash, he said.
He paid her because I was simply terrorised and afraid she would reveal we had a relationship when she was 20 and I was 40 which revelation would bring disgrace on himself and his ministry. I was ashamed, I was utterly terrified.
Under cross-examination, he said he regarded himself as someone about whom Ms Atwood had lied and lied extensively about.
Asked what kind of person he is, he said he would say truthful, sincere, generous, available, committed and flawed.
When Paul OHiggins SC said the Prime Time programme was about priests rightly or wrongly said to have abused young people and teenagers, he said that, in his case, it was clearly and unequivocally said that I was a child abuser.
He agreed the RT programme was not the first time the allegations by Ms Atwood had been made public and they had been featured in some newspapers.
The case continues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:09:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government position on Finucane inquiry ‘remains unchanged’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/government-position-on-finucane-inquiry-remains-unchanged-1.2263964</Link>
        <Description>Minister Charlie Flanagan says British commitments on independent inquiry ‘should be honoured’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Government position on Finucane inquiry remains unchanged
Minister Charlie Flanagan says British commitments on independent inquiry should be honoured
Minister for Foreign Affairs, Charlie Flanagan. Photograph: Dara Mac Donaill/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:11
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:09
Minister for Foreign Affairs Charlie Flanagan has said the Government will closely study todays judgment by the High Court in Belfast on the case of murdered solicitor Pat Finucane .
In a statement issued following Justice Stephens judgment on the legal challenge taken against the British governments decision not to hold a public inquiry into the murder, Mr Flanagan said:
I note this mornings judgement in the judicial review and will be studying it closely.
Kenny to raise British and loyalist collusion with Cameron, Dail told
The Irish Governments position remains unchanged. We continue to believe that an independent public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane, in line with the political commitments made by the British and Irish Governments at Weston Park in 2001, should be honoured.
Mr Stephens ruled this morning that British prime minister David Cameron did not act unlawfully when he refused a public inquiry into the murder by loyalists of Mr Finucane.
Delivering his reserved judgment, Mr Justice Stephens said: I uphold that the decision was lawful and accordingly I dismiss that part of the challenge.
In his statement, Mr Flanagan said the Government has consistently raised the matter with the British government.
I raised it most recently with Secretary of State for Northern Ireland Theresa Villiers on 19 May. Taoiseach Enda Kenny discussed the case with Mr Cameron when they met in London last week, Mr Flanagan added.
My thoughts at this time are with Geraldine Finucane and all the Finucane family, who have campaigned so tirelessly for more than a quarter of a century in pursuit of the full truth in the case of Pat Finucane, including the role of collusion in his murder.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:06:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Meath remains believed to be of Séamus Wright and Kevin McKee</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/meath-remains-believed-to-be-of-s%C3%A9amus-wright-and-kevin-mckee-1.2263949</Link>
        <Description>Bogland search for Joe Lynskey remains to continue   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Meath remains believed to be of Samus Wright and Kevin McKee
Bogland search for Joe Lynskey remains to continue
Local priest Father John OBrien with members of Samus Wrights family at the site in Coghalstown, Co Meath. Photograph: PA
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 13:27
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:06
Two bodies unearthed in a field in Co Meath in a search in Co Meath are now believed to be the those of Samus Wright and Kevin McKee who were abducted and killed by the IRA in the 1970s.
Seamus Wright went missing on October 2nd, 1972. He was married and from Belfast. Kevin McKee was also from Belfast and he disappeared on the same day.
DNA samples from the remains discovered on the site at Coghalstown have been sent for testing and the remains themselves are due to be taken away later on Friday.
More than one body found in dig for Disappeared
The family of Mr Wright have arrived at the scene about 10kms north of Navan and relatives of Mr McKee are expected there shortly.
The Independent Commission for the Location of Victims Remains which has been painstakingly stripping away topsoil from the reclaimed bog since March said the search would continue for the remains of former Cistercian priest Joe Lynskey who the IRA said they killed and buried in the area.
Speaking to the media at the site of the excavation, Commission spokesman Geoff Knupfer said the mood among those present was one of elation and sadness.
He said he believed the discovery of the remains, if established to be MrWright and Mr McKee would bring closure to the families of the men.
The forensic dig at Coghalstown involved the slow examination of more than six hectares of reclaimed bog. A sniffer dog was also brought in late last year to help locate human remains.
All of the disappeared were buried in unmarked graves. Searches have recovered the remains of a number of the disappeared based on information provided since the Belfast Agreement.
A statement issued on behalf of the Lynskey family yesterday said they were grateful to the commission and to those who had engaged with it in the search.
Sinn Fin president Gerry Adams TD welcomed news that remains had been discovered.
The uncertainty over who has been recovered must be hugely traumatic for the families involved. I am sure that the commission will move as speedily as it can to verify the identity of those who have been found, he said.
The list of disappeared includes Gareth OConnor, who was murdered in 2003. His body was recovered on June 11th, 2005 at Victoria Quay, Newry Canal, Co Louth. The commission has investigated 16 abductions and murders.
To date, the remains of 10 of the disappeared have been recovered, the most recent being Brendan Megraw, whose remains were found in Oristown bog, also in Co Meath, last October.
Minister for Justice Frances Fitzgerald said she hopes the suffering of at least some of the families will now be eased.
The work of the Commission is complex but it is a humanitarian task aimed at ending the suffering of those families brutalised by the disappearance of their loved ones so many years ago, she said.
The Commission will continue its work to find the remains of those who have yet to be found.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:30:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Belfast High Court rejects call for Finucane inquiry</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/belfast-high-court-rejects-call-for-finucane-inquiry-1.2263902</Link>
        <Description>Court rules British prime minister had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Belfast High Court rejects call for Finucane inquiry
Court rules British prime minister had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry
Geraldine Finucane (right), the widow of murdered Belfast solicitor Pat Finucane. Photograph: Andrew Winning/Reuters
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:53
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 11:30
The High Court in Belfast has rejected a call by the Finucane family for a decision that would have compelled the British prime minister David Cameron to hold a public inquiry into Pat Finucanes murder.
Lord Justice Stephens in issuing his findings on a judicial review taken by the Finucane family found today that Mr Cameron had not acted unlawfully in refusing to hold a public inquiry into the Belfast solicitors murder.
Mr Finucane was shot dead by a UDA gang in front of his wife Geraldine and family at their north Belfast home in 1989. The British government has apologised and accepted that there was official collusion in his murder but has refused to hold a full-scale public inquiry, as the family has been demanding.
Kenny to raise British and loyalist collusion with Cameron, Dail told
Rather than holding a public inquiry the British government commissioned a review of the murder case by British lawyer Sir Desmond de Silva.
In his 2012 500-page report Sir Desmond reported that there was a significant doubt as to whether Mr Finucane would have been murdered had it not been for the different strands of involvement by elements of the British state.
He found that a series of positive actions by employees of the British state actively furthered and facilitated his murder and there was a relentless effort to defeat the ends of justice in the aftermath of his killing.
My review of the evidence relating to Patrick Finucanes case has left me in no doubt that agents of the State were involved in carrying out serious violations of human rights up to and including murder, it says.
Sir Desmond however said he did not believe there was an over-arching state conspiracy to murder Mr Finucane but that an extraordinary state of affairs was created in which both the British army and the RUC special branch had prior notice of a series of planned UDA assassinations, yet nothing was done to prevent the attacks.
The report said there were three UDA conspiracies to murder Mr Finucane that were known to RUC special branch and or MI5. These were in 1981, 1985 and 1988/89 and on none of these occasions was Mr Finucane warned of the threat against his life.
Mr Cameron said the shocking levels of collusion exposed by the report was unacceptable and apologised to the Finucane family: I am deeply sorry, he said. However, he again ruled out establishing an independent public inquiry.
At the time Mr Finucanes widow Geraldine dismissed the report a as a sham... a whitewash... a confidence trick. She renewed her call for a full public inquiry into her husbands death and said, This report is not the truth.
The family followed up that review by taking the judicial review. Today Lord Justice Stephens ruled against the family on their main call for a public inquiry.
Speaking after the ruling, Minister for Foreign Affairs and Trade Charlie Flanagan said: The Irish Governments position remains unchanged. We continue to believe that an independent public inquiry into the murder of Pat Finucane, in line with the political commitments made by the British and Irish Governments at Weston Park in 2001, should be honoured.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:11:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Who said heatwave? Temperatures set to hit 25C</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/environment/who-said-heatwave-temperatures-set-to-hit-25c-1.2263892</Link>
        <Description>Mini heatwave set to hit Irish shores with humid and warm weather across the nation   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Who said heatwave? Temperatures set to hit 25C
Mini heatwave set to hit Irish shores with humid and warm weather across the nation
Dubliners packed out the city's parks and public spaces today to enjoy sunshine and temperatures in the high teens.
Temperatures are expected to hit 25 degrees  next Wednesday. Photograph: Frank Miller /The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:22
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 11:11
Grab the sunscreen and air out the swimwear because theres sunshine headed our way and this time its bringing some real heat.
A mini heatwave is set to hit Irish shores next week with Met ireann predicting temperatures in the mid-twenties.
According to the forecaster, temperatures will hit 25 degrees across the country next Wednesday, bringing warm and very humid weather.
The warm weather will move from the continent to Ireland, bringing sunshine and real heat for the first time this summer.
Forecaster Klara Finkele says temperatures will remain in the late teens and early twenties over the weekend and into early next week before the warmer weather rises up from the Bay of Biscay on Wednesday and Thursday.
However, she warns that high levels of humidity will bring a risk of thunderstorms and heavy downpours.
Weather from the Bay of Biscay tends to be quite unstable, its warm and very moisture laden so were certainly going to keep an eye on the rain, said Ms Finkele. Warm air holds more humidity and moisture so it can lead to heavy downpours.
Temperatures over the weekend will be similar to recent days, with bright and mostly dry weather on Saturday that will become cloudy in the afternoon.
Rainfall will spread across the country on Saturday night but will clear on Sunday morning , bringing slightly fresher temperatures of 16-20 degrees.
Monday will be a hazy day with temperatures of 18-20 degrees. The weather will get warmer on Tuesday and temperatures are set to reach 22 degrees.
The real warm weather from the south is due to arrive on Wednesday, bringing temperatures between 20-25 degrees across Ireland.
The United Kingdom is also set to enjoy next weeks warm weather, with a Spanish plume of hot air moving north, bringing temperatures up into the early 30s . France , Italy and Spain have been experiencing particularly hot weather in recent days, with parts of southern Europe on track to break records for June temperatures, according to the Weather Channel.
How to protect your skin from the sun
The Irish Cancer Society has warned people to take care in the sunshine, particularly the elderly and young children.
Parents are advised to dress babies under six months in loose-fitting clothes with long sleeves and to keep them in the shade as much as possible.
Children should wear hats and sun glasses in the sunshine and use sunscreen with SPF 30 or higher. Sunscreen should be reapplied every two hours.
Adults are also advised to spend time in the shade, wear a hat and sunglasses, and to use sunscreen with SPF 15 or higher.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:01:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Water bill amendments will bring ‘clarity’, says Minister </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/water-bill-amendments-will-bring-clarity-says-minister-1.2263889</Link>
        <Description>Paudie Coffey fails to confirm whether tenants face eviction if they do not pay water bill   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Water bill amendments will bring clarity, says Minister
Paudie Coffey fails to confirm whether tenants face eviction if they do not pay water bill
Minister of State at the Department of the Environment Paudie Coffey. Photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 12:40
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 11:01
Irish Water provisions, which ensure a house cannot be sold until charges are paid, have been introduced to bring clarity and certainty for landlords and tenants, according to a Minister of State Paudie Coffey .
The Minister of State at the Department of the Environment described claims that tenants who dont pay their Irish Water bills could face eviction as scaremongering on the part of the opposition.
Speaking on RTs Morning Ireland, Mr Coffey said the amendments to the bill had been introduced to create a method of enforcement to ensure that those who are not compliant and are refusing to pay, that they do pay.
Thousands march in anti-water charges protest in Dublin
Minister for the Environment Alan Kelly has introduced 33 pages of amendments to the Environment Miscellaneous Provisions Bill.
It contains a number of changes, including the setting up of a database for the water conservation grant and provisions to ensure a house cant be sold until the charges are paid. The Bill also obliges local authority tenants to pay their water charges.
Mr Coffey failed to confirm whether tenants would be evicted if they did not pay their bill, saying payment was a matter for the landlord and tenant as is the case in any contract situation for tenancy.
Asked if the landlord would have to pay if the tenant failed to do so, he said the owner of the property would be responsible for discharging any unpaid bills before selling the home.
We want to see people compliant with the law and we dont want to see people ending up in trouble and thats why were making measures that we feel are fair and bring certainty to the whole area.
Mr Coffey said users who applied for the Water Conservation Grant worth 100 before June 30th could expect to receive the money before the end of this year.
He also said an independent test due to be carried out by Eurostat , the EU statistics agency, was imminent and would take place in the next few weeks or possibly months at the latest.
Mr Coffey said he was unaware of how many people had actually paid their water bill so far, adding that it was a matter for Irish Water to respond to.
I understand theres a board meeting due to happen next week... and I would encourage them to publish the payment figures then.
People before Profit TD Richard Boyd Barrett said earlier this week the amendments to the bill were desperate, devious and discriminatoryand were aimed at undermining the national movement against water charges.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:00:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lawyers for parents of Berkeley victim present claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/lawyers-for-parents-of-berkeley-victim-present-claims-1.2263390</Link>
        <Description>Lawyers for Ashley Donohoe’s parents claim student at party said balcony was ‘sloping’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Lawyers for parents of Berkeley victim present claims
Lawyers for Ashley Donohoes parents claim student at party said balcony was sloping
Images
Alameda County District Attorney Nancy O'Malley announces her office has launched an official, formal investigation into the Berkeley balcony collapse. Video: Alameda County District Attorney's Office
San Francisco law firm Rains Lucia Stern  representing George and Jackie Donohoe, the Irish parents of the late Ashley Donohoe (above) of Rohnert Park, California  presented  findings to Alameda County District Attorney Nancy OMalley on Thursday.
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 09:43
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 05:00
American lawyers for the parents of one of the six students killed in the Berkeley balcony collapse have presented evidence to the local district attorney which, they claim, shows a litany of ignored problems at the California building dating back years.
San Francisco law firm Rains Lucia Stern  representing George and Jackie Donohoe , the Irish parents of Ashley Donohoe (22) of Rohnert Park, California  presented their findings to Alameda County District Attorney Nancy OMalley on Thursday, shortly after she formally announced a criminal investigation into the June 16th balcony collapse that killed six and injured seven more.
Ms OMalley told reporters that each family of the six victims deserve to have this matter thoroughly and extensively investigated.
Balcony was sloping downwards before collapse, witness claims
She promised to examine whether there was enough evidence to prosecute a criminal negligence case.
The findings presented by the lawyers for the Donohoes include a statement from a student who was at the 21st birthday party on the night of the collapse. She said the balcony was sloping downwards, away from the building towards the street, before it collapsed.
Water infiltration
The law firm maintains there was a history of water infiltration and balcony decay at the Library Gardens building at 2020 Kittredge Street dating back to at least 2010.
They presented the District Attorney and her officials with photographs of water damage to the buildings exterior at the fourth-floor balcony showing streaking and staining as far back as 2008.
Complaints of rot, roof and plumbing leaks and flooding were made as recently as three months before the collapse, the law firm has said, and the failure by management to act led the residents to complain to housing authorities.
Before the district attorney took over the investigation, the law firm sent legal letters to the buildings owner Blackrock, property manager Greystar and to city officials, raising concern that the initial investigation into the balcony failure may not be truly independent or neutral.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 07:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Balcony was sloping downwards before collapse, witness claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/balcony-was-sloping-downwards-before-collapse-witness-claims-1.2263394</Link>
        <Description>Parents of victim Ashley Donohoe raised concerns about impartiality of investigation   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Balcony was sloping downwards before collapse, witness claims
Parents of victim Ashley Donohoe raised concerns about impartiality of investigation
Images
Alameda County District Attorney Nancy O'Malley announces her office has launched an official, formal investigation into the Berkeley balcony collapse. Video: Alameda County District Attorney's Office
The remaining wood from the Library Gardens apartment building balcony that collapsed  in Berkeley, California, killing six Irish students. Photograph: AP Photo/Jeff Chiu
George and Jackie Donohoe, the Irish parents of the late Ashley Donohoe (above), through their lawyers, contacted the owners and property managers of the Library Gardens student accommodation block in Berkeley, California, where the fatal June 16th incident occurred. They demanded notification of where the destroyed balcony was preserved.
Previous Image
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 09:29
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 05:00
Lawyers acting for the parents of one of the six students killed in Berkeleys balcony collapse sent legal letters over the past week calling for evidence to be preserved and raising concerns that the City of Berkeleys investigation may not have been truly independent.
George and Jackie Donohoe , the Irish parents of Ashley Donohoe (22), of Rohnert Park, California , through their lawyers, contacted the owners and property managers of the Library Gardens student accommodation block where the June 16th incident occurred.
They demanded notification of where the destroyed balcony was preserved.
Lawyers for parents of Berkeley victim present claims
In addition, the familys lawyers from the San Francisco firm Rains Lucia Stern met the Alameda County district attorney, Nancy OMalley, her second-in-command, Kevin Dunleavy , and a number of their officials to present the law firms findings of what they believe was wrong with the building.
Preserved evidence
At the outset, the familys main concern was that the initial investigation by the city was not independent and that the evidence was not being preserved for an independent and impartial analysis.
Ms OMalleys announcement on Thursday that she would carry out a criminal and civil investigation into the collapse has allayed their concerns somewhat.
Ms OMalley said the remains of the collapsed fourth-floor balcony and a third-floor balcony beneath that was removed are being preserved by Berkeley police and the county sheriff.
Harry Stern , a partner with Rains Lucia Stern, said the Donohoes retained the firm as a priority to make sure that a proper independent impartial investigation was being conducted because there were some very disturbing indications early on about what was happening.
Mr Stern said they were very heartened that Ms OMalley and Mr Dunleavy have taken over this investigation, describing it as a step in the right direction.
Not only are they independent, the district attorney department has the resources and expertise to conduct this kind of complex investigation. And, moreover, the two of them are very sensitive to the nature of this tragedy.
The law firm presented the DA with its own evidence, including a statement from an Irish student who was at the party on the night of the incident.
She said the balcony was sloping downwards away from the building towards the street before the collapse occurred.
History of decay
There was a history of water infiltration and balcony decay dating back to at least 2010, the lawyers claim. They presented the DA and her staff with a number of photographs showing water damage to the exterior of the balcony as far back as 2008.
They claim these signs should have put somebody responsible on notice that there could be a problem that needed to be investigated.
They also presented the county prosecutors with evidence of complaints of rot, roof leaks, plumbing leaks and flooding, some of which occurred as recently as three months ago.
Complaints were made to the City of Berkeley housing authority because the existing building management failed to act or were unresponsive to the complaints and concerns, the lawyers say.
Letters seen by The Irish Times show the Donohoes raised concerns about the investigation as soon as three days after the incident.
They wrote to Berkeley mayor Tom Bates , city manager Christine Daniel and planning and development director Eric Angstadt on June 19th, urging them to hire engineers and contractors who would independently and impartially provide a neutral and detailed analysis of the cause of this incident.
At the time, it had appeared Belfor Property Restoration , the company hired by the buildings owner, BlackRock , to remove the third-floor balcony, had been hired by a potentially responsible party.
How can a potentially responsible party conduct a truly independent investigation? the lawyers asked in the letter.
On Tuesday, the lawyers in a follow-up letter wrote to BlackRock, Greystar , the propertys management company that looked after the property for them, and Belfor.
The letter was sent just hours after the citys building inspectors concluded in a report that the fourth-floor balcony appeared severely dry rotted.
Balcony failure
The Donohoe family is grieving the loss of their loved one. . . they have also discovered information that causes them great concern that the investigation into the cause of the balcony failure may not be truly independent or neutral, Joseph Lucia , one of the lawyers at Rains Lucia Stern, told them.
Due to these concerns, the Donohoe family has requested that we contact you regarding the investigation of what occurred so there can be an independent and impartial analysis of the cause of the deadly balcony collapse.
The lawyers added that ensuring an independent and impartial analysis will allow for a swift and just conclusion of culpability, whether it be civil and/or criminal in nature.
The lawyers said that the findings of the city building inspectors report had only increased the amount of concern for the Donohoe family.
The family was particularly concerned at the very limited nature of the citys investigation because it was limited to the direct observations of the citys building and safety division in the immediate aftermath of the collapse and because forensic examination and laboratory tests were outside the scope of the review.
The lawyers noted there have been contractors, structural engineers and architects hired and paid for by BlackRock and Greystar to perform tests and analysis.
BlackRock has responded to the Donohoes attorneys telling them - before the District Attorney took possession of the balconies - they would co-operate by giving them access to the apartment building and other materials when made available to all parties.
BlackRock told them they would carry out further demolition and repairs starting on July 1st.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seán Haughey to be added to Fianna Fáil ticket</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/se%C3%A1n-haughey-to-be-added-to-fianna-f%C3%A1il-ticket-1.2263314</Link>
        <Description>TD Peter Fitzpatrick decides to run for Fine Gael after previously ruling himself out    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Sen Haughey to be added to Fianna Fil ticket
TD Peter Fitzpatrick decides to run for Fine Gael after previously ruling himself out
Sen Haughey: surprisingly defeated by Deirdre Heney at the Fianna Fil convention for the Dublin Bay North constituency.   Photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:04
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:04
Fianna Fil is likely to add former junior minister Sen Haughey to a general election ticket following his surprise defeat at a constituency selection convention earlier this week. Mr Haughey was beaten by Deirdre Heney , a councillor, at the Fianna Fil convention for the Dublin Bay North constituency, even though he was widely seen as the favourite.
The directive from party headquarters was to select just one candidate and Ms Heney has said she believes a single-candidate strategy is the best approach to take a seat in the five-seater constituency.
The decision whether or not to add Mr Haughey will be made by the Fianna Fil constituency committee, chaired by Cork North West TD Michael Moynihan . The task for the party is choosing which is the best option to win a seat, said one source, adding more likely than not Mr Haughey would be added.
Peter Fitzpatrick goes back on decision not to run for  Fine Gael
Mr Haughey, a son of former taoiseach Charles Haughey , did not return calls but party sources suggested he had been somewhat complacent in his approach to the convention. It was also suggested that some members who were supporters of Averil Power  who was expected to contest the convention but resigned from Fianna Fil  had switched to Ms Heney.
Separately, a councillor who lost out at a recent selection convention has left Fianna Fil, claiming he has become disillusioned with the party. Alan Coleman , the mayor of Cork county, says he will now stand as an Independent in Cork South West. He lost a Fianna Fil selection convention to fellow councillor, Margaret Murphy OMahony.
Meanwhile, a Fine Gael TD who said he was not standing for the party has changed his mind following a meeting with Taoiseach Enda Kenny. Louth TD Peter Fitzpatrick is understood to have secured a commitment from the Fine Gael hierarchy that the party ticket in the constituency would comprise only two candidates.
After announcing he was not standing for Fine Gael, Mr Fitzpatrick then suggested he could stand under a different banner, which reduced sympathy for him in the party. We mostly felt sorry for him, but that annoyed people, said one TD.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece crisis response likened to mutiny on ‘Bounty’</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/greece-crisis-response-likened-to-mutiny-on-bounty-1.2263335</Link>
        <Description>‘EU and euro zone ministers  continuing to beat and punish Greece until its morale improves or it does what they want’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Greece crisis response likened to mutiny on Bounty
EU and euro zone ministers  continuing to beat and punish Greece until its morale improves or it does what they want
Senator Mark Daly: said Germany seemed to forget the 1953 London debt agreement whereby nearly 50% of its debt was written off.Photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:03
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:03
There were exchanges between Fianna Fil and Fine Gael in the Seanad over the Greek crisis. Mark Daly of Fianna Fil said the attitude of some of the EU governments could be likened to that of Captain Bligh of the mutiny on the Bounty.
When ordering some of the members of his crew to be given 50 lashes, he said the beatings would continue until morale improved. That is exactly what we are seeing in Europe where the EU and euro zone ministers are continuing to beat and punish Greece until its morale improves or it does what they want.
Paul Coghlan of Fine Gael remarked: That is a load of baloney.
Mr Daly said Germany seemed to forget the 1953 London debt agreement whereby nearly 50 per cent of its debt was written off. Greece might have incurred debt because of reckless spending but the Germans incurred the debt because they caused a world war, and yet they seem to be insisting that Greece would have to suffer the humiliation of a Versailles Treaty-type arrangement.
Maurice Cummins of Fine Gael, said reaching agreement for Greece would create certainty for the Greek people and secure their future. The euro zone has an obligation to Greece in this difficult time, but Greece has an obligation to itself. It certainly needs to reform the economy and return it to sustainable growth, which is not the case at the moment, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>National Concert Hall could benefit from pharma support</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/national-concert-hall-could-benefit-from-pharma-support-1.2263213</Link>
        <Description>Dáil debates Bill to put NCH on equal footing with other national cultural institutions   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
National Concert Hall could benefit from pharma support
Dil debates Bill to put NCH on equal footing with other national cultural institutions
Minister for Arts Heather Humphreys: I want to see it [the National Concert Hall] developed  as a world-class venue that showcases the highest standard of musical excellence. Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
Pharmaceutical companies could have a philanthropic role in the work of the National Concert Hall , it has been suggested in the Dil.
Fianna Fil arts spokesman Sen  Fearghal said the concert hall was bringing music therapy into Irish hospitals and he asked if there was sufficiently widespread public appreciation of the work being done in that area.
Old and overmedicated: the drug problem in our nursing homes
He suggested that the NCH could benefit from pharmaceutical companies based in Ireland and the industry could realise the benefit of being associated with the work of the concert hall.
Mr  Fearghal was speaking during a debate on the National Cultural Institutions (National Concert Hall) Bill to change the National Concert Hall Company from a company limited by guarantee into a statutory body.
The change is expected to facilitate greater transparency and accountability in corporate governance and puts the concert hall on an equal footing with other national statutory cultural bodies.
Minister for Arts Heather Humphreys , who introduced the Bill, said Mr  Fearghals suggestion was a good idea and it should be progressed. She supported the business-to-arts initiative which offers businesses great opportunities to support the arts and said engaging with the arts helped employees to think outside the box and has proved to be very worthwhile.
She described the NCH as a major cultural asset. I want to see it developed as a world-class venue that showcases the highest standard of musical excellence. She added that the NCH should have clarity on all governance and operational issues. The Bill sets the number of board members at nine and the first board appointments will be staggered at three, four and five years to ensure continuity. Appointments will focus on a broad range of skills and expertise including, of course, musical experience.
Audience figures are on the rise at the venue which contributed 38 million directly to the local economy last year, the Minister said. The venue had a turnover of 6.8 million, ticket sales of just over 7 million. It hosted almost 900 events with some 330,000 people in attendance.
Refurbishment plans include the creation of a 130-seat performance space in the Kevin Barry rooms, where the Treaty ratification debates took place, and the transformation of the old medical library into a new 500-seat recital hall.
The 1,200 seat-auditorium will also be refurbished and a jazz club will be established, along with rehearsal spaces and recording studios. A series of concerts each day during Easter week next year will commemorate the 1916 Rising.
Mr  Fearghal said an arms-length approach in ministerial direction was vitally important but he suggested that we have moved from an intolerable level of ministerial involvement to a point where there seems to be a total absence of ministerial oversight. He said Fianna Fil opposed as a regressive act the amalgamation of the National Archives, the National Library and the Irish Manuscripts Commission.
Sinn Fin arts spokeswoman Sandra McLellan said the Bill provided the opportunity to acknowledge the importance of the National Concert Hall as a national asset.
Ms McLellan said that until recently, 70 per cent of the concert halls funding came from ticket sales, which she described as an encouraging figure that demonstrates peoples appetite for the arts.
Independent TD Finian McGrath said a country without arts is a country without a soul. People often ignored the great work being done in the arts, the number of people it employed, how the arts lift the countrys spirit and their significant financial contribution to the country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rheumatology clinics cancelled for 850 people in Galway, Dáil told </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/rheumatology-clinics-cancelled-for-850-people-in-galway-d%C3%A1il-told-1.2263265</Link>
        <Description>Minister Alex White promises one further  consultant from October   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Rheumatology clinics cancelled for 850 people in Galway, Dil told
Minister Alex White promises one further  consultant from October
Dara Calleary (Fianna Fil): asked if it was acceptable that a consultant had gone on maternity leave  and would not be replaced until September.  Photograph: Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
More than 850 people were told this week by two Galway hospitals that all outpatient rheumatology clinics for July and August had been cancelled, Fianna Fil TD Dara Calleary told the Dil.
He said University College Hospital and Merlin Park University Hospital had said emergency outpatient appointments would be dealt with on a case-by-case basis. Already, he added, 1,500 people were on waiting lists at Merlin Park for outpatient rheumatology appointments.
When a person is diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis, there is a 12-week window within which there is a chance of dealing with the condition if he or she gets treatment, Mr Calleary added. If it goes longer, perhaps to 2 years, which is the length of time people are spending on the waiting list at the moment, the patients chance of beating that condition are severely restricted.
Mr Calleary asked if it was acceptable that a consultant had gone on maternity leave this week and would not be replaced until September, demonstrating a lack of planning. Is it acceptable that the appointment of a new rheumatology consultant to Manorhamilton, which was promised by the Taoiseach in December, still has not taken place ? he asked.
Is it acceptable that a consultant attached to Beaumont, one of our key hospitals, would tell a patient, as has happened this week, that he or she would be better off having urgent surgery at a private hospital because at Beaumont the wait would be 14 weeks ?
Minister for Communications, Energy and Natural Resources Alex White , who was taking Opposition Leaders Questions on the Governments behalf, said the HSE had advised that because of consultant staff shortages, a number of rheumatology outpatient clinics in Galway University Hospital were being postponed. New appointments would be scheduled as soon as possible and urgent patients would continue to be seen. Clinics in Manorhamilton would continue as normal, he added.
Mr White said there were currently three consultants covering outpatient clinics and an emergency intake and consult service in Galway University Hospital, as well as a day ward service in Merlin Park.
From October 1st, he added, there would be four consultant rheumatologists at Galway University Hospital. When extra medical staff are in place, the extra outpatient clinics will have to be held and will be held, Mr White said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Whistleblower makes new Ansbacher claims</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/whistleblower-makes-new-ansbacher-claims-1.2263295</Link>
        <Description> Document not circulated to PAC members as committee  told allegations were outside  its  remit   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Whistleblower makes new Ansbacher claims
Document not circulated to PAC members as committee  told allegations were outside  its  remit
Mary Lou McDonald: found to have breached Dil privilege by naming the politicians in the Dil chamber.   Photograph: Alan Betson/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:02
A whistleblower has named another former politician as having an Ansbacher account in a fresh document sent to politicians. Gerry Ryan , an official in the Department of Jobs , Enterprise and Innovation , had sent fresh correspondence to the Public Accounts Committee .
However, following legal advice, the document was not circulated to members and the committee was told the allegations were outside their remit. It is understood Mr Ryan criticised assurances by Revenue that all of his claims were investigated. He also named another politician who he alleges had an offshore account used to evade tax in the document sent to the committee.
PAC gets fresh whistleblower claims over Ansbacher accounts
The decision came down to a vote with only two members  Independent TD Shane Ross and Sinn Fin TD Mary Lou McDonald  voting in favour.
The committee met in private and Fine Gaels Patrick ODonovan said the letter should not be sent to members because it would then be read into the Dil chamber and produced in the media. This was said to be a direct reference to Ms McDonald who was found to have breached Dil privilege by naming the politicians in the chamber.
Fine Gael TD John Deasy told Mr Ross and Ms McDonald if they wanted the information they should contact Mr Ryan and seek the document. Afterwards, Mr Deasy said there had been no ambiguity about the legal advice. The legal adviser probably repeated five times that the committee had no remit to accept any part of correspondence, he said.
Mr Ryan is a senior official in the Department of Jobs, Enterprise and Innovation. He had served as the authorised officer under company law who investigated Ansbacher accounts in the Cayman Islands. He contended in a dossier given to the committee that a number of named former senior politicians had held such offshore accounts. This was denied by the politicians.
Revenue officials appeared before the committee and rejected the allegations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Banking Inquiry told of warning over  repeat  Lehman’s scenario </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/banking-inquiry-told-of-warning-over-repeat-lehman-s-scenario-1.2263160</Link>
        <Description>Central Bank chief Patrick Honohan insists bailout necessary regardless of  bank guarantee   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Banking Inquiry told of warning over  repeat  Lehmans scenario
Central Bank chief Patrick Honohan insists bailout necessary regardless of  bank guarantee
Patrick Honohan, governor of the Central Bank of Ireland, arriving at the Banking Inquiry at Leinster House, Dublin, June 25th, 2015. Photograph: Dara Mac Dnaill/The Irish Times
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A senior European official warned that Ireland could be a Lehman Brothers moment for Europe , the banking inquiry was told on Thursday.
It was a reference to the massive bankruptcy filing of the US-based global financial services company in 2008, not long before the issuing of the bank guarantee in Ireland.
Governor of the Central Bank Patrick Honohan told the committee when he joined the bank in 2009 there were no concerns about Ireland.
Banking Inquiry: Full coverage
Mr Honohan said this attitude changed dramatically in August 2010 and Ireland was the centre of attention.
I remember one senior colleague saying, Im afraid that Greece is Europes Bear Stearns but Ireland will be Europes Lehmans. That was in September 2010.
So, the view of Ireland had changed dramatically and it had changed dramatically because people had woken up to the scale of the banking losses being incurred by the State, and paid for, and the prospective budgetary situation.
Mr Honohan described how he first raised the prospect of a bailout with then minister for finance Brian Lenihan in April 2010.
Mr Lenihan told him Brussels was saying Portugal was next in line for the programme.
One month later, International Monetary Fund chief of mission to Ireland Ashoka Mody contacted Mr Honohan offering a precautionary line of credit.
The governor told the committee that Merrion Street rejected the proposal - but declined to say who made that call.
Mr Honohan told Mr Mody: I said Try it, it might be a good idea. They [the government] might not like it, but try it. It did not go anywhere.
Mr Honohan said he wrote to the European Central Bank raising concerns about the emerging problems in July 2010.
Dead silence
He said he expected an early meeting and to be quizzed about what was going on. Instead, he said, there was dead silence.
I thought this is good news, they must have figured it out for themselves. I wrote them another letter in August with the full information.
I did get a response then. Concern and anxiety was starting to build there.
Mr Honohan insisted the country would have needed a bailout, regardless of the bank guarantee.
He said the economic and banking crash had cost the State 100 billion - and that figure was still growing.
Mr Honohan said not guaranteeing the six institutions in September 2008 would have saved 10 billion at the most.
He said: All in all, a possible net economic saving in the area of 2-10 billion could be imagined, but surely no more than that.
If so, by September 2008, well over 90 per cent of the net economic cost to Ireland of the boom and bust had become unavoidable.
Mr Honohan said he wanted to put a figure on it because the narrative had been focused on whether the guarantee was the right decision. He said this was the least important question, but the most over-analysed.
He denied the ECB would ever have pulled funding from Ireland. It never would have availed of that decision, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nine months for boy who stole from home of sleeping mother </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/nine-months-for-boy-who-stole-from-home-of-sleeping-mother-1.2263318</Link>
        <Description>Teenager was taken into care after death of  family member in tragic circumstances   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Nine months for boy who stole from home of sleeping mother
Teenager was taken into care after death of  family member in tragic circumstances
Dublin District Court, Smithfield. Photograph: Alan Betson
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A teenage boy in care who stole from the home of a woman, while she and her two small children were sleeping, has been sentenced to nine months in custody and nine months on probation.
The boy, who had previously pleaded guilty to the burglary and other theft charges, had been found by garda on one occasion through a stolen phones tracker app; he was living in a tent behind a garage.
On Thursday, in courtroom 55, in the Dublin District Childrens Court , Smithfield, the boys story and the impact his crime had on one of his victims unfolded.
The 16-year-old sat to the right of Judge John OConnor. . He leaned on his elbows on the long table he shared with solicitors and garda. His hands were clasped together and his chin rested on them, as the sentence hearing proceeded.
A garda reminded the judge of the charges against the boy, for which he was remanded in custody earlier this month.
Unlocked cars
Last September, the boy found unlocked cars and stole items including a camera and laptops from them. On September 6th, during the night, he entered the home of a woman in Bray, Co Wicklow, after noticing a key had been left in the front door. He stole her laptop from the kitchen, 500 from her purse and her keys, before going upstairs into her bedroom and stealing her phone. She and her two young children remained asleep.
All of the items stolen were recovered, except for the cash, the garda said.
In her victim impact statement, read into the record by a garda, the woman said her world had been turned upside down by the robbery.
She did not sleep for two weeks afterwards and worried about what might have happened if she or her children had woken. She felt her home had been invaded and she had failed to protect her children. Her property was taken for which she had worked so hard, as a single parent, she said, and it was truly frightening and horrific that the thief had taken her keys.
Domino effect
She could no longer live in the house and had to move to a smaller one, with higher rent. There had been a domino effect and it was one of the worst experiences of her life. Yes, it has changed my view of Ireland, she said.
Judge OConnor read out the probation report on the boy. It said the Child and Family Agency was involved with his family since 2011 and the boy was taken into care last year, after the death of a family member in tragic circumstances.
He ran away from foster carers and was missing in care.
The probation officer said he had formed the impression the boy carried out the crimes to meet his basic needs. He also said the boy struggled since the death of the family member and there were concerns he misused tablets.
He had dropped out of secondary school but was going to school since being in custody, in a childrens detention centre. He had settled well, and his behaviour was excellent, but there were concerns about his mental health.
The boys solicitor said his client had got involved with a very negative peer group, and there was a belief he needed the money to live. He was also fully co-operative with garda.
The judge said it was tragic the boy had such a terrible youth, but his lifestyle was now so pro-criminal that something had to be done. He said he was not unconscious of the boys circumstances and hoped he would be successful in his school course.
The boy nodded his head at the judge and signed a form. He will appear in court again next month.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eoghan Ó Neachtain joins company with Fine Gael links</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/eoghan-%C3%B3-neachtain-joins-company-with-fine-gael-links-1.2263367</Link>
        <Description> Spokesman worked for Bertie Ahern, Brian Cowen and Enda Kenny   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Eoghan  Neachtain joins company with Fine Gael links
Spokesman worked for Bertie Ahern, Brian Cowen and Enda Kenny
Eoghan  Neachtain assisting German chancellor Angela Merkel in  Dublin in 2008. Photograph: Eric Luke
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A former government press secretary who served three different taoisigh has been appointed as a director of a public relations company with strong Fine Gael links.
Eoghan  Neachtain served as spokesman for Bertie Ahern , Brian Cowen and Enda Kenny during his career in government. He is understood to be the only person to serve as government press secretary in three administrations.
Mr  Neachtain, who also worked in the semi-State sector, has been made director of public affairs at Heneghan PR.
The company was founded by Pat Heneghan , one of Garret FitzGeralds so-called national handlers, and also employed Bill OHerlihy, Frank Flannery and Enda Marren .
Mr  Neachtain has also served in the Irish Defence Forces . He is a regular contributor on national radio and television and is well known as a rugby analyst on TG4 .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Simon Coveney receives report on 1981 attack on soldiers in Lebanon </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/simon-coveney-receives-report-on-1981-attack-on-soldiers-in-lebanon-1.2263374</Link>
        <Description>Pte Hugh Doherty died and Pte Kevin Joyce disappeared in action with  UN Interim Force   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Simon Coveney receives report on 1981 attack on soldiers in Lebanon
Pte Hugh Doherty died and Pte Kevin Joyce disappeared in action with  UN Interim Force
Pte Hugh Doherty, of Letterkenny, Co Donegal, who was killed in Lebanon. Photograph: Declan Doherty
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
Minister for Defence Simon Coveney has received a report on the death of one soldier and the disappearance of another in Lebanon in 1981.
The report, an independent review of the investigation into the death of Pte Hugh Doherty and the disappearance of Pte Kevin Joyce (Caomhn Seoighe), is expected to be published in the coming days.
The two men were serving with the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon, manning an observation post at Dayr Ntar, when they came under attack.
Pte Doherty was later found dead from gunshot wounds and Pte Joyce was missing. The attackers are unknown. To date, no information has been elicited to lead to the recovery of Pte Joyces remains.
The review of the deaths and subsequent investigations was carried out by retired High Court Judge Roderick Murphy, at Mr Coveneys request.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brendan Smyth’s victims to sue Garda for damages</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/brendan-smyth-s-victims-to-sue-garda-for-damages-1.2263205</Link>
        <Description>Evidence to Historical Institutional Abuse inquiry has prompted legal proceedings   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Brendan Smyths victims to sue Garda for damages
Evidence to Historical Institutional Abuse inquiry has prompted legal proceedings
Victims of paedophile priest Brendan Smyth are to sue An Garda Siochna over its failure to take action when they were allegedly notified in the 1970s that Smyth was a child sex abuser. Photograph: Alan Betson
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
Victims of paedophile priest Brendan Smyth are to sue An Garda Sochna for damages over its failure to take action when they were allegedly notified in the early 1970s that Smyth was a child sex abuser, it was stated on Thursday.
Belfast solicitor Kevin Winters said he was instructed to take legal proceedings against the Garda following evidence provided to the Historical Institutional Abuse Inquiry on Thursday that garda in Finglas were alerted in 1973 that Smyth was suffering from paedophilia.
That information emerged through the disclosure of confidential documents from St Patricks Hospital in Dublin where in 1973 Smyth was receiving psychiatric treatment for his sexual propensities.
Sean Brady says abuse kept secret to save churchs good name
Letter
A number of victims of Smyths abuse have asked us to write to the Garda Commissioner to find out why they didnt act on a letter sent to Finglas Garda station in 1973, said Mr Winters.
Our clients are shocked to learn that the document didnt alert garda and the authorities to the very real risk of future abuse by Smyth.
It has been deeply re-traumatising for them to learn about the contents of this letter and to that end feel they have no alternative but to issue civil proceedings for damages for what on the face of it was an appalling failure to take meaningful steps to prevent crimes against the innocent and vulnerable.
A Garda spokesman said that as the inquiry is ongoing it would be inappropriate to comment.
Margaret McGuckian of victims group Savia said it was beyond comprehension to think that so many peoples lives could have been different had the authorities acted sooner.
It is a bad day for the garda but we also want to know why it took so long for these documents to be handed over. 
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First  Irish death  over  online pills  may  force a reckoning </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/health/first-irish-death-over-online-pills-may-force-a-reckoning-1.2263378</Link>
        <Description>Crackdown on illegal medicines about to get tougher as online trade continues to grow   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
First  Irish death  over  online pills  may  force a reckoning
Crackdown on illegal medicines about to get tougher as online trade continues to grow
No internet pharmacy, whether legitimate or not in another country, can supply drugs to customers in Ireland. That hasnt stopped the flow of medicines into Ireland from overseas merchants hawking their wares on the web.
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
Warnings about the dangers of purchasing medicines on the internet have become commonplace in recent years, but the first known Irish death of a person from consuming pills bought illegally online may finally force people to take heed.
The law, which predates the internet era, is clear: mail order of prescription-only medicines, including internet supply, is illegal.
That means no internet pharmacy, whether legitimate or not in another country, can supply drugs to customers in Ireland.
Discredited DNP raises bodys metabolic rate and can  damage  liver and kidneys
That hasnt stopped the flow of medicines into Ireland from overseas merchants hawking their wares on the web.
It is impossible to know exactly how much use consumers are making of the internet to satisfy their drug requirements, but the rising level of seizures of counterfeit and illegal medicines seized is one indicator.
Last week, the Irish authorities put on display a sample of the 142,000 tablets and capsules they seized as part of an international operation over a single week in over 100 countries.
Painkillers
The value of the haul, over 430,000, gives an indication of the size of the trade. Sedatives, painkillers, weight loss products, anabolic steroids and erectile dysfunction products were among the items seized after they arrived from Singapore, the US, India, the UK and other countries.
There are many strands, and many linked dangers, to the growing international trade in prescription medicines. Some Irish consumers have undoubtedly been driven online by the high cost of their prescription drugs at home.
Others seek unfettered access to medicines for which they would normally need a prescription. Still others want to procure products which are illegal in Ireland.
Taking any medicine without proper medical supervision is risky. Issues arise as to dosage, pre-existing conditions, combinations with other drugs and the availability of follow-up treatment.
The other main problem is the lack of quality control in relation to much of what is being sold online. Up to half of the medicines seized in Ireland have been found to be unreliable and potentially harmful.
Often, the medicine doesnt actually include the claimed active ingredient or includes the wrong dosage. Products may be bulked up with harmful substances, or passed off as natural or herbal when they are anything but.
Awareness
Most consumers of online medicines must have some level of awareness of these risks, but show themselves willing to take them anyway.
DNP (Dinitrophenol), the drug implicated in the death of a young man in mid-May, has been on the banned drug list for almost 80 years. Originally an industrial compound used in the manufacture of explosives, its potential for causing side-effects and even death have been known for some time.
The drug is often marketed to bodybuilders keen to lose fat and maximise a ripped or muscular appearance. Even in this milieu the dangers of DNP are well-known, yet a minority continues to use it, believing the advantage of massive fat loss outweighs these risks.
Some have paid for this belief with their life; worldwide, DNP has been linked to more than 60 deaths.
The authorities  the Garda Sochna , Revenues Customs &amp; Excise service and the Health Products Regulatory Authority  have made arrests and closed down websites in pursuit of their investigations into the trade of illegal medicines.
International co-operation is increasing under the leadership of Interpol , so there is at least a chance the purveyors of deadly chemicals may be pursued. However, the international trade in drugs is not going to disappear any time soon.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>RTÉ lied about abuse, former archbishop tells High Court jury</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/high-court/rt%C3%A9-lied-about-abuse-former-archbishop-tells-high-court-jury-1.2263344</Link>
        <Description>Richard Burke  paid woman €176,000 to keep quiet about relationship, counsel says   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
RT lied about abuse, former archbishop tells High Court jury
Richard Burke  paid woman 176,000 to keep quiet about relationship, counsel says
Former Archbishop of Benin Richard Burke pictured leaving the Four Courts yesterday. Photograph: Courts Collins
Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, Jun 26, 2015, 01:00
A former Catholicarchbishop has told a High Court jury that he was portrayed during an RT television programme as leading a young girl upstairs to his bedroom to sexually abuse, sexually assault and rape her.
I could not believe my eyes, Richard Burke said. This did not happen. I did not do that. What is portrayed there is a lie. When his counsel, Jack Fitzgerald SC, asked, Are you a paedophile? he replied, No.
Mr Burke (66), from Co Tipperary, said he was living in London with a member of his order, the Kiltegan Fathers , when Prime Time Investigates: Mission to Prey was screened on May 23rd, 2011.
He could not get access to RT TV, but his niece sent him texts which, as the programme went on, progressed from this is bad to this is really bad to, in essence, this is as bad as it can be. On getting those texts, my heart began to sink and sink and sink into darkness, utter fear.
He was unable to watch the full programme until about a month later when he saw it at his sisters home. His impression was that he was being accused of being a paedophile, especially in a section involving a dramatisation where a young girl was led upstairs.
A reference by the reporter that he had declined to be interviewed gave me a hook to hang on to because he got no invitation to respond to the claims being made, he said. That was tiny in comparison to the feeling of helplessness.

Evidence
Mr Burke has begun his evidence in his action against RT alleging he was defamed in the Mission to Prey programme, which included an interview with a Nigerian woman, Dolores Atwood . Mr Burke claims he had sexual relations with Ms Atwood, now aged 45, as an adult but not when she was under age. Having spent decades in Nigeria after his ordination in 1975, he tendered his resignation as archbishop of Benin in April 2010 over his failure to adhere to his vow of celibacy.

RT denies defamation and pleads a defence of truth concerning the contents of the programme relating to Mr Burke. It denies that the content bears some of the meanings alleged by Mr Burke, including that he was a rapist.
Mr Fitzgerald has told the jury that Ms Atwood leaned on Mr Burke about their relationship and that he had paid her 176,000, plus $4,300, to keep quiet. Counsel said he had also mistakenly told the jury that Ms Atwood sought an additional 50,000, when that sum was part of the 176,000.
Some of the 176,000 had come out of diocesan funds, money that Mr Burke had made an agreement with the Vatican to repay, counsel said.
The case continues.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
