<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="irishtimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More than €100 million for refurbishing housing</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/more-than-100-million-for-refurbishing-housing-1.2230053</Link>
        <Description>Half the money will go to adapting housing to fit it out for older and disabled people   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
More than 100 million for refurbishing housing
Half the money will go to adapting housing to fit it out for older and disabled people
Homes built for older people in Gorey, Co Wexford
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
More than 100 million is to be spent on refurbishing empty social housing and adapting private homes for older and disabled people.
Most of the money, 91 million has been allocated by the Department of the Environment, with 10 million from local authority grants and the local property tax (LPT).
More than 1,000 vacant local authority flats and houses will be refurbished for people on the social housing waiting list at a cost of over 20 million. Dublin city and Cork city will receive the largest allocations, at just under 4.4 million and more than 3.6 million respectively. Priority for these homes will be given families facing homelessness.
Half of all the funding, 50 million, will be available for adapting private houses for older or disabled people. The money can be used to build extensions or for the adaptation or homes to improve mobility, through installing stair lifts or access ramps. Half of that funding will come from the exchequer and the remaining money from local authorities. Most of the local authority money, just over 15 million, will come from property tax receipts.
A further 11 million will be made available for local authority house adaptations and extensions to meet the needs of tenants with a disability and to deal with overcrowding.
The remaining 20 million will be used to improve local authority flats and houses to make them more energy efficient. Property tax will fund just under 2 million of this work.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Switching could cut 15,000 mortgages by €1,000 a year, Patrick Honohan says</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/switching-could-cut-15-000-mortgages-by-1-000-a-year-patrick-honohan-says-1.2230040</Link>
        <Description>Borrower inertia lessens impetus for Central Bank to intervene on rates, says governor   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Switching could cut 15,000 mortgages by 1,000 a year, Patrick Honohan says
Borrower inertia lessens impetus for Central Bank to intervene on rates, says governor
Central Bank governor Patrick Honohan: If people were more active in the switching market, it might keep banks on their toes and we would encourage that. Photograph: Cyril Byrne
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
As many as 15,000 holders of standard variable-rate (SVR) mortgages could see their repayments fall by more than 1,000 a year simply by switching provider, the governor of the Central Bank has claimed.
Patrick Honohan said Irish banks knew there was inertia on the part of borrowers who could switch. This had lessened any imperative for them to aggressively compete in the market by lowering their rates to gain and retain market share.
Mr Honohan told the Oireachtas finance committee that the Central Bank had in recent weeks looked through figures provided to them by the States banks and found that there were up to 15,000 people who, if they had the time to get out and do the sums, could save a four-figure sum in a year.
If people were more active in the switching market, it might keep banks on their toes and we would encourage that.
While Mr Honohan said he would welcome interest rate cuts for SVR mortgage holders, he warned against any Government intervention that would force banks to lower their rates, saying such a move would damage the economy.
He had a firm conviction that the administrative control of interest rates would be bad for the country as a whole. In the medium term there could be a case for Government intervention. Such intervention would have a stultifying effect on bank efficiency and a chilling effect on bank competition, he added.
Competition, he said, was borrowers main protection against banks inflating the interest rates. He said the level of competition in the banking sector at present was too low.
Mr Honohan was challenged by Fianna Fils Sen Fleming about his reliance on the god of competition to protect borrowers from excessively high SVR mortgages. He reminded Mr Honohan that competition from overseas banks sparked a rate-price war that fuelled the boom and deepened the bust.
Mr Honohan conceded the point and said he wanted to get back to a situation where there were five or six players who are competitors. He added that you can have too much competition as well as too little.
People Before Profit TD Richard Boyd Barrett also challenged Mr Honohan on his
faith in competition to make the mortgage market fair.
Control of retail interest rates is a kind of Rubicon, Mr Boyd Barrett said. It has a signalling value far in excess of what you might think.
In reference to the recently introduced mortgage lending rules aimed at cooling the market, Mr Honohan said he was not dissatisfied with subsequent developments.
CSO figures for April show prices nationally rose by 0.6 per cent and are now 15.8 per cent higher than a year ago.
In Dublin, prices increased by 1 per cent last month, reflecting an annual inflation rate at 20.2 per cent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Public service staff in line for €1,000 pay boost next year</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/public-service-staff-in-line-for-1-000-pay-boost-next-year-1.2230008</Link>
        <Description>Pay restoration deal set to be offered in talks over  Haddington Road extension   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Public service staff in line for 1,000 pay boost next year
Pay restoration deal set to be offered in talks over  Haddington Road extension
Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin has indicated  his priority in the pay restoration talks would be to assist those on low pay. Photograph: Eric Luke
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Staff in public service appear to be set for an increase in earnings of about 1,000 next year under a proposed pay restoration deal between the Government and trade unions.
A pay rise in 2017 has also been considered as part of an overall two-year extension to the existing Haddington Road agreement.
The increase in earnings next year would come from changes in the application of the public service pension levy, which was introduced in 2009 and averaged at about 7.5 per cent.
Government wants unions to re-affirm commitments on disputes
As some low-paid workers would not benefit proportionately from this mechanism, they may receive a top -up pay rise next year.
An overall deal would also involve increases for public service pensioners who faced cuts during the years of economic crisis.
Any boost for public service staff earnings that might be agreed for a second year is likely to come from an increase in pay rates rather than further changes to the pension levy.
Talks on an overall public service pay restoration agreement were continuing last night and informed sources said that at that stage no formal pay offer had been presented to the parties.
A wide range of other non-pay issues had been addressed as part of the talks, which had been under way for the last fortnight.

Labour costs
Under one key proposal, it is understood new restrictions will be put in place on any new outsourcing initiative. Sources said that, under the proposal, labour costs would have to be excluded from any cost-benefit analysis of the outsourcing of any service. This issue has been a priority for Siptu.

In return for pay restoration, trade unions representing staff in the public service would be obliged to reaffirm commitments to solve disputes by peaceful means through binding arbitration.
Government sources have argued there had been some slippage in relation to industrial relations peace in the public service in recent times.

Flexibilities
A senior Government source last night told The Irish Times the draft agreement involved a recommitment to and extension of the Haddington Road flexibilities and a strengthening of the mechanisms designed to facilitate change and reform the public service.

The relationship between pay and reform has been established and will not be broken.
The Government gave a commitment last year that it would begin the unwinding of financial emergency legislation that underpinned various cuts in public service pay and pensions introduced since 2009.
Minister for Public Expenditure and Reform Brendan Howlin indicated over recent weeks that his priority in the pay restoration talks would be to assist those on low pay.
Trade unions had argued that this could best be achieved by means of a flat-rate increase  secured by changing the application of the pension levy  rather than through a percentage-based rise, which would give greater benefit to the better-off.
The talks on public service pay restoration, which have been under way since May 11th, are being facilitated by the Labour Relations Commission .
Any outcome of the talks would have to be put out to ballot by trade unions and other bodies representing about 300,000 staff across the public service.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All roads lead to Royal County Down despite Rory’s bogeys </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/all-roads-lead-to-royal-county-down-despite-rory-s-bogeys-1.2229988</Link>
        <Description>Predicted attendance of 90,000 could have been even higher, tourism officials  say   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
All roads lead to Royal County Down despite Rorys bogeys
Predicted attendance of 90,000 could have been even higher, tourism officials  say
Large crowds gather around the 10th green during day one of the Irish Open at Royal County Down. Photograph: PA
Fri, May 29, 2015, 03:07
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
The Irish Open attendance figures are predicted to be off the charts at Newcastle. As dogged golf fans ignored the squalling showers that swept over Slieve Donard and across Royal County Down, officials were expecting more than 90,000 to arrive during the week.
That figure could have been more, according to Tourism Northern Ireland , as the organisers restricted numbers to maintain spectator comfort and to protect the sand dunes out of which the natural golf course has been sculpted.
The figures may be slightly more than that but its capped every day at around 20,000 because of keeping the integrity of the course and to ensure the visitor experience is protected, said Kathryn Thomson of Tourism Northern Ireland.
Benefactors dig deep for chance to play with worlds number one
Even at the pro-am, a celebrity-driven event that takes place before the four-day competition begins, 11,000 visitors came through the gate. The Irish Open has not had that many fans attend a pro-am before. In 2012 when it was held up the coast at Royal Portrush, the pro-am attracted 10,000 visitors. Usually the attendance would be closer to half that.
Ticket sales
The percentage of ticket sales to people from outside Northern Ireland is also higher than in 2012, when it was 15 per cent. This year more than 30 per cent came from outside the North, with 28 per cent from the Republic.

Yes, its partly the Rory [McIlroy] factor but also we had some of our local celebrities playing, said Thomson .  James Nesbitt [actor] was playing. Paddy Kielty [comedian] was playing as well as some sports personalities such as Australian cricketer Shane Warne , AP McCoy [jockey], Pat Jennings [football] and Dennis Taylor [snooker].
McIlroy was the star attraction yesterday and brought people in, although playing partner Rickie Fowler also drew his fair share of admirers. McIlroy and Fowler are the rocknroll kids of the game, but the first day was more Rickie rockin and Rory rolling over.
The fans stuck with McIlroy as he struggled with his game. Around some of the amphitheatre-shaped greens, hundreds spread across the dunes, squatting in the sheltered sides, out of the driving rain.
Come on, Rickie, its not California ,  shouted a female fan at the tanned Fowler after a gale almost swept him off the rise at the second tee box.
Oh my god, sighed another from among the huge gallery as McIlroys score, one of the worst of the day, loomed into view at the 17th hole. It was blue, a bad colour in golf; eight over par is an even worse number in golf.
By the end, those fans were both sympathetic and stunned. McIlroy hit four bogeys from the 15th hole before bringing his first day to a close with a wretched 80.
But the Ulster fans again proved themselves to be among the most enthusiastic in Europe . It is only the second time in European Tour history an event has sold out in advance. The first was in Royal Portrush two years' ago.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Patrick Neary tells  inquiry regulatory system  did not work </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/patrick-neary-tells-inquiry-regulatory-system-did-not-work-1.2230031</Link>
        <Description>Former regulator apologises for insufficient measures and inability to deal with crisis   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Patrick Neary tells  inquiry regulatory system  did not work
Former regulator apologises for insufficient measures and inability to deal with crisis
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Former financial regulator Patrick Neary has told the Oireachtas banking inquiry he had bought into a system of regulation that didnt work .
In his evidence to the committee on Thursday, Mr Neary said that, with hindsight, the supervisory measures taken by the Irish Financial Services Regulatory Authority (IFSRA) were not sufficient to meet the challenges posed by the crisis and the recession that emerged.
I am deeply sorry about that, he said. I regret that very deeply.
Passing the buck
He was questioned about his time as chief executive of IFSRA between February 2006 and January 2009 by committee members including Fine Gael TD Kieran ODonnell.
It was a period where I bought into a system of regulation that didnt work. The system failed and I regret that, he said.
Mr Neary said that the IFSRA relied on the banks for analysis of risk management, believing them to be best placed to know their own business.
He was asked by committee chairman Ciarn Lynch of Labour if the fact that the banks were four times the size of the Irish economy had not been a matter of concern.
The warnings that were coming from the Central Bank certainly did not create a concern that actions needed to be taken. They were benign and the conclusion was that we had a soft landing, Mr Neary replied.
He said commentaries from other bodies such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and OECD backed up this view.
Professional
However, when accused of having an extremely cosy relationship with the banks by Socialist TD Joe Higgins , Mr Neary said he really did not know what that meant. He said there was dialogue and a professional relationship but he would not go any further than that to describe the relationship.
Mr Neary said he regretted not keeping a minute of an informal meeting he had with then Anglo Irish Bank chief executive David Drumm in September 2007, which he accepted had turned out to be very important.
Under questioning from Fianna Fil finance spokesman Michael McGrath, he said Mr Drumm came to him suggesting there were rumours that businessman Sen Quinn was active in the CFD [contracts for difference market].
Mr Neary said he tried to make some inquiries but nobody had anything hard and fast about Mr Quinn and his CFDs. He said the facts were established on Good Friday in March 2008.
In January 2008, he met Mr Quinn, who volunteered that he had some CFDs.
I took him to mean that whatever CFDs he had in financial stock, that he had converted it into a holding and shares, Mr Neary said.
Golfballs
Labour Senator Susan OKeeffe raised the production of golfballs featuring the logo of the financial regulator.
Mr Neary said when he became aware of the branded golf balls, meant to be used as promotional materials, they were discontinued.
It was a mistake. There were a very small number of them purchased and it was discontinued very quickly, he said.
When it was unearthed it was discontinued. I regret that. It shouldnt have happened.
He was also questioned by Sinn Fin finance spokesman Pearse Doherty , who asked Mr Neary why he did nothing despite knowing Anglo and Irish Nationwide were lending to a very small number of individuals.
Mr Neary said he could not conceive of a situation where the regulator would intervene in a relationship between bankers and clients.
It is inconceivable that the regulator can determine who or who doesnt get a credit from a bank as a customer of that bank.
Mr Doherty asked again: Why did you do nothing?
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FG Senator Pat O’Neill: Aer Lingus deal  right for airline and for Ireland </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/fg-senator-pat-o-neill-aer-lingus-deal-right-for-airline-and-for-ireland-1.2230011</Link>
        <Description>Independent David Norris insists Ireland should have a State-owned airline    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
FG Senator Pat ONeill: Aer Lingus deal  right for airline and for Ireland
Independent David Norris insists Ireland should have a State-owned airline
David Norris: When the Fianna Fil government denationalised Aer Lingus, I spoke and voted against that. Photograph: Eric Luke/THE IRISH TIMES
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Fine Gael Senator Pat ONeill said the sale of the Governments Aer Lingus share was right for the airline and the country.
We are a small island nation and connectivity to mainland Europe , the UK and the US is one of the most important things we have, he said.
Dil backs sale of State stake in  Aer Lingus
Mr ONeill said commitments had been given by IAG on connectivity and the Heathrow slots.
Independent Senator Feargal Quinn said he had always felt a particular pride when he saw the Aer Lingus shamrock logo on an aircraft on the runway in a foreign airport. The danger of losing that is something none of us wants.
Mr Quinn said he was inclined to support the objective of the deal, having weighed up all the pros and cons. It seems to be the best deal we can get, he added.
Independent Senator David Norris said Ireland should have an independent, stand-alone and State-owned airline. When the Fianna Fil government denationalised Aer Lingus, I spoke and voted against that, he added.
Mr Norris said some of the money from the sale should be set aside to resolve the disgraceful situation whereby deferred Aer Lingus pensioners had been squeezed out of their rightful entitlements.
Kathryn Reilly , of Sinn Fin, said the sale was wrong for Ireland: Aer Lingus is worth infinitely more to Ireland than the 335 million the Government will get for cashing in on the 25 per cent stake that Fianna Fil left the State with.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aylward and Power moves suggest FF renewal losing steam </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/aylward-and-power-moves-suggest-ff-renewal-losing-steam-1.2229914</Link>
        <Description>Hard for Fianna Fáil  to escape image  its new politics is  identical to its old approach   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Aylward and Power moves suggest FF renewal losing steam
Hard for Fianna Fil  to escape image  its new politics is  identical to its old approach
Fianna Fil TD Bobby Aylward arrives triumphantly at the Dil after his win in the Carlow-Kilkenny byelection, and Senator Averil Power announces her resignation from Fianna Fil at Government Buildings. Photographs: Colin Keegan/Collins; Cyril Byrne/The Irish Times
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00

Two events over the course of the week have suggested Fianna Fils renewal drive is beginning to lose steam: the election of a member of the old guard, Bobby Aylward , in the Carlow-Kilkenny byelection, and the abrupt departure of Senator Averil Power - the partys poster-figure for youth and advancement of women politicians.
That impression may well have been reinforced by the five selection conventions the party held over the past two nights, where former TDs ( John Curran in Dublin Mid West; Martin Mansergh in Tipperary and Charlie OConnor in Dublin South West) all threw their hats into the ring.
It has made it hard for the party to escape the image that its new politics is more or less identical to its old approach.
Fianna Fils Bobby Aylward returns to Leinster House
Humiliating loss
While Fianna Fil suffered a debilitating and humiliating loss in the 2011 general election, it is not - in reality - possible for a political party to effect a scorched earth approach to renewing itself, because it will often result in the eclipse of its remaining supporters who stood behind the party through thick and thin.
Fine Gael found itself in a roughly similar position in 2002 (although the scale of its collapse was more modest).
One of its big achievements was to bring a raft of new candidates forward ( Leo Varadkar and Lucinda Creighton were the most prominent).
However, it must also be remembered that many of the gains Fine Gael made in 2007 were seats gained by seasoned TDs who had lost out in 2002, including Alan Shatter , Charlie Flanagan , Michael Creed , and Brian Hayes .
Sen Barrett, then in his 60s, also returned to the Dil in 2007 after a long absence.
The reality is, as a seasoned political commentator said on Thursday, a party needs to put its best team on the field. You just cant put out the under-21s.
Cork North West TD for Fianna Fil Michael Moynihan says Fianna Fil will comfortably surpass the new electoral rule that holds that 30 per cent of its candidates will be women.
The party has also pointed out that while the returning veterans have grabbed most media attention, the party will be fielding more new (and young) candidates than at any time since its foundation.
A cursory glance through the 40 constituencies illustrates that mix.
In Mayo for example, Lisa Chambers will be Dara Callearys running mate. In Galway West , where the convention was held on Thursday night, the party pursued a one-male, one female candidate strategy, with Mary Hoade the favourite to join incumbent amon  Cuv.
The modernising one-member one-vote system will favour more established politicians. Like other parties, Fianna Fil is likely to add candidates onto the ticket to achieve balance on gender and age.
Other veterans who may return include Pat the Cope Gallagher in Donegal and Mary Hanafin in Dn Laoghaire .
Referendum campaign
It is less likely that Pat Carey will return in Dublin North West, but given his significant part in the Yes Equality referendum campaign, the party would welcome him back with open arms. All of them would have biddable chances of winning seats.
But there is a raft of young candidates, with the chance that enough will get through to reinvigorate the party - as the likes as Varadkar and Creighton did for Fine Gael.
In Cork South West the three leading candidates are all women - Gillian Coughlan , Margaret Murphy OMahony and Deirdre Kelly .
In Kerry, highly regarded Waterville councillor Norma Moriarty will join John Brassil on the ticket.
In Tipperary, Siobhn Ambrose has been mentioned as a candidate, and in Waterford Mary Butler was the front-runner to have won the selection convention on Thursday.
In Dublin, Catherine Ardagh is likely to be selected as the candidate in Dublin South Central, while Laura Reid may be in the mix in Dublin North West.
With Averil Powers departure, Deirdre Heney is likely to join Sean Haughey on the ticket in Dublin Bay North.
Other young candidates (and prospective candidates) include James Lawless in Kildare North ; Aaron OSullivan in Cork East ; Jack Chambers in Dublin West ; Malcolm Byrne in Wexford , and Cormac Devlin , who might come through the gap in the highly competitive Dn Laoghaire convention.
Three very high-profile women candidates - Mary Hanafin, Kate Feeney and Lisa Chambers - have also been mentioned for this constituency.
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pearse McAuley  faces charges relating to threats on wife’s life</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/district-court/pearse-mcauley-faces-charges-relating-to-threats-on-wife-s-life-1.2230072</Link>
        <Description>Republican ordered to appear in Cavan Circuit Court following Stephen’s Day incident   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Pearse McAuley  faces charges relating to threats on wifes life
Republican ordered to appear in Cavan Circuit Court following Stephens Day incident
Pearse McAuley: has been ordered to appear before Cavan Circuit Court next Wednesday
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Republican Pearse McAuley has been ordered to appear before Cavan Circuit Court next Wednesday in connection with an alleged assault on his wife and making threats to others.
Mr McAuley (50) appeared before a sitting of Cavan District Court yesterday. He is facing four charges, including threatening to kill or cause serious harm to Pauline Tully McAuley at Keelderry, Kilnaleck , Co Cavan on Christmas Eve. He is also charged with assaulting Ms Tully McAuley causing her harm on the same occasion.
In addition, he is charged with threatening to kill or cause serious harm to Ms Tully McAuleys brother, Thomas Tully . He is also charged with threatening to kill or cause serious harm to a neighbour, Samus Leddy.
The offences are all alleged to have been committed on the same day.
Mr McAuley was remanded in custody to Castlerea Prison following his initial court appearance in Co Cavan on December 26th.
He did not speak during the five-minute hearing.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dáil backs sale of State stake in  Aer Lingus</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/d%C3%A1il-backs-sale-of-state-stake-in-aer-lingus-1.2230081</Link>
        <Description>Clare TD expresses concerns about connectivity as motion passed by 74 votes to 51   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Dil backs sale of State stake in  Aer Lingus
Clare TD expresses concerns about connectivity as motion passed by 74 votes to 51
The Dil has approved the sale of the States stake in Aer Lingus to International Airlines Group. File photograph: Paul Faith/AFP/Getty Images
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
The Dil has approved the sale of the States stake in Aer Lingus to International Airlines Group (IAG) following an ill-tempered two-day debate.
The motion was passed by 74 votes to 51.
Labour TD Michael McNamara was the only Coalition deputy to vote against the motion. He told the Dil that while much had been done to meet his concerns, there were outstanding issues.
Ryanair shareholders seek answers on Aer Lingus
There are questions I have . . . questions unanswered, and, in that context, I am not prepared to gamble with what I believe is the key to the economic development of all of this State.
Mr McNamara said next year would mark the centenary of the Rising and there would be talk of developing all of the country equally.
The Clare TD said one of the key factors in attracting US companies to Shannon was its connectivity to the US.
Driver of growth
Shannon Airport was established to be the driver of growth in the midwest and it had achieved that up to the time Fianna Fil in its wisdom decided to abandon it in favour of Dublin.
Nevertheless, for a long period in its history it was the driver of growth in the midwest and it is again, largely because of decisions this Government has taken and which I have supported.
Mr McNamara said while the protections in the sale agreement were welcome, those around the Dil a lot longer than him would recall that a similar golden or B share scenario was put in place to give the government a veto over the sale of the sugar division when Greencore was privatised.
A few years later doubts were cast on that agreement in a European Court of Justice ruling.
Key role
Dublin North Labour TD Brendan Ryan said that, with party colleagues, he had played a key role in ensuring the initial offer from IAG was unacceptable to the Government.
Once a bid was made for Aer Lingus, we had to respond to the world as it was, not the world Sinn Fin or the far left pretended it was.
Mr Ryan said Aer Lingus was not a commercial semi-State company like the ESB and Ervia. It is a private company with shareholders, of which the State is one. The company has always been subject to a takeover bid.
He said under the deal the Minister for Finance would have the ability to block any proposed disposal by Aer Lingus of any of its Heathrow slots indefinitely.
This provides stronger protection for the State than the current arrangement, under which the State cannot prevent a reallocation, reassignment or cessation of use of the Heathrow airport slots.
He said the Minister would also be able to block a proposal by Aer Lingus to change its company name, brand and head office location and place of incorporation from Ireland .
This commitment is unlimited in time and provides protection that, again, is not available under the current arrangement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Subsidised fees for after-school care being considered</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/subsidised-fees-for-after-school-care-being-considered-1.2229955</Link>
        <Description>Coalition mulls  childcare cost measures with lower income groups paying less    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Subsidised fees for after-school care being considered
Coalition mulls  childcare cost measures with lower income groups paying less
Minister for Children James Reilly has established a group to examine the issue of childcare, and it is due to issue its final report by the end of June. File photograph: Frank Perry/AFP/Getty Images
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Parents would pay subsidised fees for after-school care for children, with those in lower income groups paying less, under measures being considered by the Coalition to address childcare costs.
Minister for Children James Reilly has established a group to examine the issue of childcare, and it is due to issue its final report by the end of June.
An after-school programme exists for low income and unemployed parents, with the State contributing 40 for each child, with a maximum fee of 15 a week payable by parents.
Sources said this may be widened to take in parents in other income groups, although contributions would rise for those earning more.
Safety standards
A draft copy of the groups report, seen by The Irish Times, cites the example of New Zealand , where subsidies are provided for children attending services that meet certain safety and quality standards.
The New Zealand model sees care programmes open from 7am to 8.30am before school, as well as running until 5.30pm after school.
Programmes are also in place during holidays.
The draft reports other recommendations include paid paternity leave, and extending periods of shared parental leave to as much as a year, which would be phased in over a number of years.
While a childcare tax credit was considered, and favoured by many parents surveyed by the group, it would involve a substantial cost to the exchequer, upwards of 640 million per annum and is unlikely to be put in place.
A spokesman for Dr Reilly said: There are likely to be several further draft reports developed before the group completes its work.
Recommendations are subject to debate and may therefore be changed, revised, may become more detailed, or indeed removed entirely.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Aer Lingus: Tánaiste says sale of stake no risk to Irish jobs </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/aer-lingus-t%C3%A1naiste-says-sale-of-stake-no-risk-to-irish-jobs-1.2229974</Link>
        <Description>Company is committed to regular interaction with unions, Joan Burton insists    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Aer Lingus: Tnaiste says sale of stake no risk to Irish jobs
Company is committed to regular interaction with unions, Joan Burton insists
Joan Burton: It has no impact or inference for employment in Aer Lingus in Ireland. Photograph: Eric Luke/The Irish Times
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Tnaiste Joan Burton insisted jobs would be protected in the sale of the Governments stake in Aer Lingus .
She said the airline had been involved in significant recruitment in the recent past.
Dil backs sale of State stake in  Aer Lingus
This is an airline that is going to expand, she said.
She added the company was committed to a regular and structured interaction with the trade unions relating to terms and conditions of employees.
Ms Burton said the House would shortly consider legislation on registered employment agreements. She said the airline customer had been forgotten in the debate on the issue.
Ms Burton said the key issue in a consultants report was that it referred to business abroad. So it has no impact or inference for employment in Aer Lingus in Ireland ,  she added.
She said Nyras, as she understood it, was a consultancy company engaged by Aer Lingus to carry out confidential analysis of the airlines cost structure.
The report was an internal document in a private company and it would not be common for Government departments and the Cabinet to receive a copy, she added.
Fianna Fil spokesman Timmy Dooley said the vote on the Governments motion allowing the sale to go ahead should be postponed so there could be further debate on the issue.
We can sit next week to do it, in line with original promises made by the Government, he added. We can look at these so-called legal guarantees, the emergence of this B share and whether it is all it is made out to be and so on.
Sinn Fin deputy leader Mary Lou McDonald said the deal contained vague or, at least, qualified promises of no compulsory redundancies and no out-sourcing. The pensioners are to get nothing, but the executives are to enjoy a bonanza, pay-outs of the scale of a bonanza, she added.
Renua Ireland TD Lucinda Creighton said IAG had the resources to invest in stock and aircraft to which Aer Lingus otherwise would not have access. Companies that cannot invest and renew die, she added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>McNamara loses whip but still wants to run for Labour</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/mcnamara-loses-whip-but-still-wants-to-run-for-labour-1.2230048</Link>
        <Description>Clare deputy was only Coalition member to vote against Aer Lingus stake sale to IAG   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
McNamara loses whip but still wants to run for Labour
Clare deputy was only Coalition member to vote against Aer Lingus stake sale to IAG
Michael McNamara TD: I believe the Labour Party has done a good job in government. Photograph: Eric Luke
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Clare TD Michael McNamara has said he wants to run for the Labour Party in the forthcoming general election, despite losing the party whip in the Dil.
Mr McNamara was the only Coalition deputy to vote against the proposed sale of the States 25 per cent stake in Aer Lingus to International Airlines Group (IAG) when it was put to a Dil vote yesterday.
Speaking afterwards, Mr McNamara said he still hoped to stand for Labour at the next election and party sources indicated he will be given a favourable hearing if he applies to rejoin the parliamentary party in the coming months.
Labour TD calls on Taoiseach to drive  domestic immigration reform after US visit
I want to stand for the Labour Party at the next election. I believe the Labour Party has done a good job in government, Mr McNamara said.
Party whip Emmet Stagg said the consequences of voting against the party were well known, and automatically involved expulsion from the parliamentary party.
Mr Stagg said it was open to Mr McNamara to apply to the rejoin the parliamentary party, and his application would be considered by TDs and Senators at such a time.
Mr McNamara said the issue of connectivity is hugely important to him and expressed concern about the so-called golden share in the airline, which will be held by the Minister for Finance and gives the State a veto over any future sale of slots at Heathrow airport.
In the past, that hasnt worked, it hasnt been enforceable, Mr McNamara said. Ultimately IAG is a business, it is purely a business. It is solely in the business of making money.
While Shannon Airport is in his Clare constituency, Mr McNamara said there is more concern locally about AI  artificial insemination of cattle  than IAG.
Mr McNamara is the sixth Labour TD to lose the whip after voting against the Government since the Coalition took office.
Two of them, Tommy Broughan and Risn Shortall, remain Independent TDs and are strongly critical of the Government.
Colm Keaveney, who voted against the Social Welfare Bill in 2012, later joined Fianna Fil while Patrick Nulty resigned his seat in Dublin West.
However, Westmeath TD Willie Penrose, who resigned as minister of state in protest at the closure of Mullingar Army barracks, rejoined the parliamentary party after losing the whip for a period.
Speaking last night, Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe said he regretted Mr McNamaras decision but repeated his view that the sale of the States 25 per cent share in Aer Lingus was in the best interests of the company and the country.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Garda arrested over alleged media role in Roma children case </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/garda-arrested-over-alleged-media-role-in-roma-children-case-1.2229928</Link>
        <Description>Arrest follows 2013 incidents where children taken from families over abduction fears   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Garda arrested over alleged media role in Roma children case
Arrest follows 2013 incidents where children taken from families over abduction fears
Former Ombudsman for Children Emily Logan in a report published last July concluded that information about one of two children taken from their homes in October 2013 in Westmeath and Dublin had on the balance of probability been disclosed by a member of the Garda to the journalist who wrote the initial reports on the first child being taken. File photograph: Frank Miller/The Irish Times
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
A senior Garda officer has been arrested over his alleged dealings with the media when members of the force took two Roma children from their families after their skin, eye and hair colour aroused suspicions around the childrens parentage.
The officer now under arrest has already had his phone examined and his office searched under warrant.
His arrest on Thursday morning was anticipated but has been greeted with surprise in Garda and security circles as he was authorised to speak to the media at the time of the contentious events and had been instructed to do so.
The National Union of Journalists said there were unusual aspects to the case that it would be watching very closely.
It would be important that nothing would happen that would damage the release of information in the public interest, said NUJ Irish secretary Seamus Dooley .
Balance of probability
The former Ombudsman for Children Emily Logan in a report published last July concluded information about one of two children taken from their homes in October 2013 in Westmeath and Dublin had on the balance of probability been disclosed by a member of the Garda to the journalist who wrote the initial reports on the first child being taken.
It went on to say that all parties involved in the case regarded this development as deeply troubling and highly regrettable.
The information reported did not lead to the children being taken. Instead, it confirmed the Garda had taken them, with the event becoming a major embarrassment to the force.
The families were forced to undergo DNA testing to prove their link to the children, after which they were returned to their parents.
Ms Logan said the disclosure of the information about one of the children may have amounted to a breach of discipline and/or an offence.
While she did not recommend a criminal investigation, Garda Commissioner Noirin OSullivan was quick to establish an inquiry.
Senior officer
That inquiry identified a senior officer based in Garda Headquarters, Phoenix Park, Dublin, as a suspect and it is he who was arrested at 7.30am on Thursday. He went to a Garda station in Dublin by arrangement.
A number of Garda sources said they were surprised the allegations were being treated as a criminal matter rather than a possible professional error.
The two Roma children were taken from their families by the Garda in October 2013 and briefly held in the care of the HSE before being returned when DNA evidence established the familial link.
Members of the public relayed suspicions the children had been abducted because their hair, eyes and skin were not the same colour as the Roma family groups they were living with.
The reports to the Garda were prompted by a case in the international media at the time about a blonde-haired, blue-eyed child having allegedly been abducted by a Roma couple in Greece .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge allows children in care to take holiday abroad</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/crime-and-law/courts/district-court/judge-allows-children-in-care-to-take-holiday-abroad-1.2229939</Link>
        <Description>Parents tell  court they fear influence  of ‘filthy rich’ foster carers over young children   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Judge allows children in care to take holiday abroad
Parents tell  court they fear influence  of filthy rich foster carers over young children
The Dublin District Family Court has heard a social worker and court-appointed guardian said two  children in interim care should be allowed to take a holiday with their foster carers. They were looking forward to it and were very excited. File photograph: Getty Images
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
Two young children in interim care are to be allowed to travel abroad on holiday with their foster carers after a judge at the Dublin District Family Court dispensed with the need for their parents permission.
The childrens parents had refused permission, fearing the filthy rich foster carers were influencing the children, particularly their daughter.
She has things: a horse, lambs named after her . . . they are showing her a life that no one could provide, the mother said.
The young children were taken into care in early 2014 on an interim basis.
The reasons were not outlined in court, but they include serious allegations of abuse which the parents have vigorously denied.
The court was told the foster carers, who were sourced through a private foster agency, booked a holiday for themselves, the foster children and other family members. The parents were not informed until early this month, and they refused permission.
Access visits
The foster carers told the children of the holiday and told them their parents were not consenting.
The court also heard the younger of the two children had been refusing to attend access visits with her parents since earlier this year.
She had said she did not want to go back to Ma and Da because they are poor and her foster carers are rich and have loads of things.
The childrens mother said she felt in her heart if her daughter had a break from the carers while they took the holiday, she would resume attending access visits.
She said her son had run into an access visit and asked whether he and his sister could go on holiday. He described a house facing a beach with two jacuzzis and big swimming pools, she said.
Thats not normal . . . Ive asked for them to have a normal life, she said.
She and her husband had come under pressure to change their minds about permission over the holiday, the mother said.
She thought highly of the foster mother, but the family was filthy rich and she believed her daughter was being pulled away from her. She was also angry she and her husband had been made to look like the bad guys.
Excited
The Child and Family Agency solicitor apologised to the parents and acknowledged the matter had not been handled correctly.
The social worker and the court-appointed guardian said the children should be allowed to take the holiday. They were looking forward to it and were very excited.
The social worker said the foster carers were doing everything in their power to encourage the girl to attend access visits with her parents. She also said the girl wouldnt be riding ponies on access visit days, and she did not believe lifestyle was an issue.
Judge Brendan Toale said he accepted the parents views were genuinely held and not motivated by spite or other unworthy motivations.
He said the interests of the children had not been well served by their unnecessary involvement in the holiday proposal.
He said the court was being asked to pick up the pieces of the debacle, and it was reprehensible.
There had been a systemic failure and a failure of professional standards, and he believed what happened had exacerbated the concerns and suspicions of the parents.
He said it was in the best interests of the children the holiday go ahead and ordered that the children were to be informed about it appropriately, and it was not to be presented as a victory or a defeat for anyone.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dáil Sketch: Selling silver not enough to tarnish prospect of a  week off</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/oireachtas/d%C3%A1il-sketch-selling-silver-not-enough-to-tarnish-prospect-of-a-week-off-1.2229961</Link>
        <Description>Labour’s Michael McNamara votes against Government motion on Aer Lingus sale    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Dil Sketch: Selling silver not enough to tarnish prospect of a  week off
Labours Michael McNamara votes against Government motion on Aer Lingus sale
Michael McNamara said he was not prepared to gamble with what I believe is the key to the economic development of all of this State. Photograph: Eric Luke/ THE IRISH TIMES
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
The decision was finally made to sell off some of the family silver in the Dil yesterday.
It was removed from the States sideboard amid bitter exchanges and recrimination among the Leinster House political family.
One family member expected to support the sale could not bring himself to do so.
Dil backs sale of State stake in  Aer Lingus
Clare Labour TD Michael McNamara voted against the Government motion to sell its Aer Lingus share.
Government and Opposition traded insults over the two-day debate and, then, yesterday evening, it was time for the vote.
McNamara took his place next to former leader Eamon Gilmore and quickly pressed the No button. He later walked with the Opposition into the Nl lobby when Sinn Fins Dessie Ellis called a walk-through vote.
Comfortable majority
The Government, as expected, had a comfortable majority of 74 votes to 51.
Earlier, McNamara had confirmed rumours sweeping Leinster House that he would oppose the motion.
Addressing Minister for Transport Paschal Donohoe across the chamber, he conceded that much had been done to meet Labour Party concerns about the sale.
The Minister listened carefully, cradling a near-empty glass of water in his hands.
McNamara said there were outstanding issues.
There are questions I have . . . questions unanswered, and, in that context, I am not prepared to gamble with what I believe is the key to the economic development of all of this State, he added.
He talked of previous sales. Where is Irish Sugar now ? he asked. When I was canvassing for the Labour Party recently, I saw its rusting remains on the outskirts of Carlow town.
McNamara said he appreciated that the Minister had taken time with his officials, very late on Wednesday night, in an attempt to allay his fears. But it was not enough.
The Minister had his glass of water replenished and he took a sip.
By then, it was very clear his Coalition colleague would be voting against the motion and there was no way back.
Earlier, McNamara listened as the Fianna Fil leader Michel Martin strongly criticised the Government for the sale.
Martin accused the Coalition of engaging in a snow job and pretending all was rosy in the aviation garden.
What is a snow job ?, asked McNamara.
Martin replied that it was a Cork expression. It is a colloquial phrase, he added.
McNamara had the expression of somebody who believed one could learn something new every day.
Meanwhile, with the family silver sold, the Dil took a weeks holidays.
These might be lean times, with an empty aviation sideboard, but the long June break in the constituency retreat remains firmly in place.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Claim that hundreds of deaths in North  happened due to collusion</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/claim-that-hundreds-of-deaths-in-north-happened-due-to-collusion-1.2230050</Link>
        <Description>Nuala O’Loan says that some paramilitaries recruited as informants were “serial killers”   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Claim that hundreds of deaths in North  happened due to collusion
Nuala OLoan says that some paramilitaries recruited as informants were serial killers
Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
First published: Fri, May 29, 2015, 01:00
The former Northern Ireland Police Ombudsman Baroness Nuala OLoan has claimed that hundreds and hundreds of deaths happened in Northern Ireland as a result of security force collusion.
Baroness OLoan said that some paramilitary informants recruited by the British army and the RUC were serial killers.
Her claims were disputed by the PSNI chief constable George Hamilton .
Baroness OLoan made her allegations on Thursday nights BBC Panorama programme, Britains Secret Terror Deals, which examined the extent of security force collusion with republican and loyalist paramilitaries
She said that the police and British army allowed informers to commit crimes, up to and including murder, with impunity.
Justice
They were running informants and they were using them. Their argument was that by so doing they were saving lives, but hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of people died because those people were not brought to justice and werent stopped in their tracks, she said.
Many of them were killers and some of them were serial killers.
The programme dealt with killings such as that of the 1976 IRA Kingsmill Massacre of 10 Protestants, the 1982 UDA shooting of five Catholics in Sean Grahams bookies on the Ormeau Road in Belfast, the 1989 UDA murder of Belfast solicitor Pat Finucane , the 2001 Loyalist Volunteer Force murder of Sunday World journalist Martin OHagan and the IRA murder of RUC constable Colleen McMurray in Newry , Co Down, in 1992.
It also addressed some of the killings carried out by members of the so-called Glenanne Gang allegedly comprised of members of the UVF, RUC and British army.
They included the killings of 34 people in the 1974 Dublin-Monaghan bombings.
The programme also referred to how the current Police Ombudsman Dr Michael Maguire is investigating claims that both RUC and PSNI officers did not conduct proper murder inquiries into more than 60 murders because they were protecting informers or that there was police collusion in the murders.
Mr Hamilton queried Baroness OLoans assessment of the scale of killings and said informers saved thousands of lives.
No rules
He conceded however that during the Troubles, there were no rules governing how security force handlers dealt with paramilitary agents.
He told the BBC, My understanding is that there were hundreds if not thousands of lives saved through the work of informants and police and, in those days, (British) army working with those informants. Im not saying that everything that was done was done to the standards of today.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:12:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FF’s Mansergh loses out at Tipperary selection convention </title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/ff-s-mansergh-loses-out-at-tipperary-selection-convention-1.2230111</Link>
        <Description>Ex-ICMSA president among general election candidates chosen in several constituencies   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
FFs Mansergh loses out at Tipperary selection convention
Ex-ICMSA president among general election candidates chosen in several constituencies
Fianna Fil has selected a former president of the Irish Creamery Milk Suppliers Association, Jackie Cahill (above) to contest the the new five-seat Tipperary constituency in the general election. File photograph: Brenda Fitzsimons/The Irish Times.
Former minister of state and government adviser Dr Martin Mansergh who, with 37 votes out of the 852 cast, won the fewest first preferences at the Fianna Fil Tipperary selection convention.Photograph: Eric Luke / The Irish Times.
Previous Image
Thu, May 28, 2015, 23:29
First published: Thu, May 28, 2015, 23:12
Fianna Fil has selected a former president of the Irish Creamery Milk Suppliers Association to contest the the new five-seat Tipperary constituency in the general election.
Jackie Cahill edged out Michael Smith Junior, a son of the former TD of the same name, in a tight convention in Thurles.
Three other candidates contested the convention, including former minister of state and government adviser Dr Martin Mansergh who, with 37 votes out of the 852 cast, won the fewest first preferences. Councillors Siobhn Ambrose and Imelda Goldsboro also contested.
Fianna Fils Bobby Aylward returns to Leinster House
The Tipperary convention was one of four held by Fianna Fil on Thursday night.
In Waterford, Portlaw-based councillor Mary Butler was selected in a contest between four candidates. First elected as a councillor last year, Ms Butler will be hoping to recapture a seat for the party in this four-seat constituency.
In Dublin South West, front-runner John Lahart was selected ahead of Charlie OConnor and Emma Murphy. Mr OConnor is a former TD in this constituency which has been expanded from four seats to five. The party has no Dil deputy in Dublin at present.
In Galway West, where three candidates were being selected, sitting TD Eamon O Cuv and Mary Hoade were expected to be chosen at a convention that ran late into the night.
In Tipperary, Mr Cahill was 18 votes behind Mr Smith with 305 votes, compared to 323 votes for his rival on the fourth count. He overtook the Nenagh-based councillor in the final count when 217 votes were distributed.
The next general election will be the first to see a unified five-seat Tipperary constituency, replacing the outgoing Tipperary South and Tipperary North three-seaters. Six outgoing TDs along with the Fianna Fil candidate or candidates will contest the five seats.
In Dublin South West, Mr Lahart won with 32 votes to 22 for Mr OConnor and nine for Ms Murphy.
It is expected that candidates will be added to the slate by party headquarters in at least one of the four constituencies.
Fianna Fil changed its voting system after its disastrous general election in 2011 and candidates are now selected on a one-member one-vote system, as used by Fine Gael . It replaces an arcane system where each cumann (unit) of the party had a number of votes.
The party is now expected to hold a spate of conventions over the next few weeks, including the the keenly anticipated contests Dublin Bay North and in Dun Laoghaire. Following the departure of Averil Power from the party, Fianna Fil looks set to select Sen Haughey and Deirdre Heaney for Dublin Bay North.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:06:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fantasy football: Ireland’s women politicians line out</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/ireland/irish-news/fantasy-football-ireland-s-women-politicians-line-out-1.2230045</Link>
        <Description>We have Stephanie Roche managing our fantasy football politician team    </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Fantasy football: Irelands women politicians line out
We have Stephanie Roche managing our fantasy football politician team
Given that Stephanie Roche has time on her hands, we decided to give her the notional job of managing our fantasy football team.
Thu, May 28, 2015, 22:06
First published: Thu, May 28, 2015, 22:06
Its the FA Cup final this weekend. The English Premiership season has ended. The mess at Fifa rumbles on. Irish goal queen Stephanie Roche has had her contract with US soccer team Houston Dash ended after three months. It really is a funny old time for the beautiful game.
Given that Steph has time on her hands, we decided to give her the notional job of managing our fantasy football team. Selection was limited to woman members of Dil ireann and Seanad ireann. Roche was not a selector, she just has to manage the team now she has it in her capable hands.
There are 25 women out of 166 members of the 31st Dil, so the soccer talent pool for women is limited. (Although, arguably, its not exactly brimming with male talent either.) Some 19 of the 60 members of Seanad ireann are women. Our Cup truly runneth over.
The first XI
Striker - Clare Daly:
You need a striker to make daring forays into opposition territory. Daly does this with knobs on. Even when shes playing away in Shannon. Only this week, she was tackling Taoiseach Enda Kenny over his sale of the States 25 per cent share in Aer Lingus. She shoots, she scores, she climbs fences.
Striker - Catherine Murphy:
Another independent-minded forager. She can use her head, which is always an asset up front. She may find the ball, but she is still looking for a full independent inquiry into a number of matters, including the 2012 sale of Siteserv to a company controlled by Denis OBrien. Her team-mates should get the ball up to her more often.
Attacking midfielder - Mary Lou McDonald:
Well, would you get in her way? The playmaker for Sinn Fin can also easily switch to defence when it comes to her leader Gerry Adams. But it is for her playmaking ability she gets the spot.
Defensive midfield - Ciara Conway:
You need a young pair of legs for this position. And Conway should get a chance to work on her defence as the next general election looms. Conway played it straight when she defied expectations by not voting for Clare Dalys Bill to allow for abortion in cases of fatal foetal abnormality in February, thus proving herself to be a team player. She will Labour for the full 90.
Left wing - Ruth Coppinger:
Socialist Party TD Coppinger didnt get the Dil to support her Bill to Repeal the Eighth Amendment to the Constitution this month. But she put in a hard tackle when she said that she has no confidence in Sen Barrett as Ceann Comhairle and accused him of having an element of misogyny in his dealings. She got the man and the ball.
Right wing - Fidelma Healy Eames:
This is her natural position. Need we say more? The Independent senator said it was political correctness gone mad that she was the only female member of the Oireachtas campaigning for a No vote in the Marriage Equality referendum. Whatever the final score, she will be able to deal with being on the losing side.
Left back - Averil Power:
You could laugh at her position on the team, but youd probably deny it. It is only your word against hers, after all. When she quit Fianna Fil, Power said that not only had the party failed to step up to the plate for the same-sex marriage referendum, the strategy she was asked to develop on improving female participation in the party has largely been ignored. She said that Fianna Fil lacks vision, courage and leadership. Timmy Dooley disagrees. Being one of the gang of 141 men in the Dil, he is not eligible for selection here. But he would probably make it on merit, of course.
Centre back - Joan Burton:
The Tnaiste and Labour Party leader has just won a battle, but will she win the war? Were handing her a lot of work to do at the back, but sitting next to Taoiseach Enda Kenny has forced her to be a team player. She is used to the c-word. We mean compromise - or centre-back. Of course.
Centre back - Kathleen Lynch:
Never afraid to get stuck in, the Minister of State at the Department of Health said repealing the Eighth Amendment is very do-able following the passing of the same-sex marriage referendum. Defensive duties will be her raison detre from now until the election. Think John Arne Riise.
Right back - Mary Mitchell OConnor:
The Dn Laoghaire Fine Gael TD is going to wear the strip weve picked with aplomb. Know for her distinctly colourful dress sense, the VIP style award winner is one player who will be able to carry off those bright orange soccer boots. Watch and learn, Denis Irwin.
Goalkeeper - Frances Fitzgerald:
With the longest, most celebrated career of all, Irelands Minister for Justice just had to be the last line of defence. A fan of Averil Powers, Fitzgerald praised the former Fianna Filers constructive approach to politics.
Fitzgerald is ready for anything you can fire at her. Safe pair of hands.
Player/Manager - Stephanie Roche:
The striker for the Republic of Irelands womens team, Roches October 2013 goal for Peamount United was the runner-up for the 2014 Fifa Puskas award for the best goal of the year. Has plenty of time and experience to manage these obstreperous lassies.
Kitman - Mick Wallace. You can have any colour you like, ladies, as long as its pink.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:30:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Government keen to ‘maintain dialogue’ with Vatican</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/social-affairs/religion-and-beliefs/government-keen-to-maintain-dialogue-with-vatican-1.2229959</Link>
        <Description>Vatican’s Secretary of State called the referendum result a ‘defeat for humanity’   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Government keen to maintain dialogue with Vatican
Vaticans Secretary of State called the referendum result a defeat for humanity
On Tuesday evening Cardinal Piestro Parolin, the Vaticans Secretary of State, called the referendum result a defeat for humanity.Photograph: EPA/LOsservatore Romano/Handout
Thu, May 28, 2015, 21:32
First published: Thu, May 28, 2015, 21:30
The Department of Foreign Affairs says Ireland is keen to maintain an ongoing dialogue with the Holy See , notwithstanding the outspokenly negative comments by the Vaticans Secretary of State about the Yes victory in the same-sex marriage referendum.
On Tuesday evening Cardinal Piestro Parolin called the referendum result a defeat for humanity. The last time that the Holy See and Ireland exchanged such bitter words came in the Dil in July 2011 when Taoiseach Enda Kenny upbraided the Vatican , speaking of the dysfunction, disconnection, elitism, the narcissism that dominate the culture of the Vatican to this day, in relation to the Holy Sees handling of the clerical sex abuse crisis.
Four months after that speech, the strain in relations became palpable when then Tnaiste Eamon Gilmore announced Ireland would be closing its Embassy to the Holy See.
Vatican stands by Cardinals remarks on referendum
Given that Ireland only last November mended its fences with the Vatican by opening a new Embassy to the Holy See, the department is keen to play down the impact of Cardinal Parolins categoric rejection of the Irish peoples sovereign will, saying yesterday:
We are aware of media reports of comments made by the Holy Sees Secretary of State Cardinal Pietro Parolin. We are also aware of comments made by Roman Catholic Church leaders in Ireland. The Government maintains ongoing dialogue with the Holy See through our Ambassador to the Holy See based in Rome.
The Government of Ireland has welcomed the passing of the recent marriage equality referendum...This positive vote means the Minister for Justice and Equality will seek Government approval imminently for the Marriage Bill, drafting of which is currently underway.
Once approved by Government, her aim is to introduce the legislation into the Oireachtas. This legislation, once enacted, will give effect to the right of same-sex couples to marry in Ireland on the same basis as opposite-sex couples.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Catherine Murphy makes Denis O’Brien claims in Dáil</title>
        <Link>http://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/catherine-murphy-makes-denis-o-brien-claims-in-d%C3%A1il-1.2229946</Link>
        <Description>O’Brien says  information was false and claims were an abuse of Dáil privilege   </Description>
        <MainBody>By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our Cookie Policy .
X
Catherine Murphy makes Denis OBrien claims in Dil
OBrien says  information was false and claims were an abuse of Dil privilege
Lawyers acting on  behalf of Denis OBrien claimed  details spoken about in the Dil were covered by an existing temporary injunction that Mr OBrien succeeded in getting after High Court proceedings. Photograph: Dara Mac Donaill
Thu, May 28, 2015, 23:02
First published: Thu, May 28, 2015, 21:20
Independent TD Catherine Murphy has made new claims in the Dil about businessman Denis OBriens banking arrangements with IBRC, formerly Anglo Irish Bank .
Ms Murphy gave what she said were details of banking arrangements he sought to retain when the special liquidator was appointed to wind up IBRC.
The move was met by an immediate denial from OBrien, who claimed the information was false and that it was an abuse of Dil privilege.
Denis OBrien granted injunction against RT
Lawyers acting on his behalf also claimed the details were covered by an existing temporary injunction that Mr OBrien succeeded in getting after High Court proceedings last week.
Ms Murphy has previously claimed Mr OBrien had written to IBRCs special liquidator Kieran Wallace seeking the same terms IBRC had allowed him, which was to pay off his own loans in his own time at low interest rates.
The sale of Siteserv to Mr OBrien has become embroiled in controversy and is the subject of a formal review by the IBRCs liquidator. The terms under which the company, which carries out a wide variety of services, including water meter installation, was sold are part of that review.
Separately, Mike Aynsley , the former chief executive of IBRC, released a lengthy statement, taking issue with other comments by Ms Murphy, who was moving a Private Members Bill through the Dil.
The Bills aim is to permit the Comptroller &amp; Auditor General to investigate the Siteserv sale and other IBRC transactions.
Management team
Mr Aynsley rejected any suggestion that he or any of the banks management team had acted improperly.
He said that under controls introduced in the bank, it was not possible for either the chief executive or any other member of management to make a commitment to any client such as that alleged by Ms Murphy without the prior approval of the credit committee.
Mr Aynsley said he could not discuss specific situations. However, he said that in all cases the banks aim was to recover as much of the loan as possible.
Performing clients were expected to repay 100 per cent, he said. He said that for larger clients it was often necessary to schedule repayments over a longer period.
Last night Ms Murphy stood by her comments in the Dil. I am a public representative. Information came to me, from a number of reliable sources, that is, without doubt, in the public interest, she said.
I have a duty to put that information into the public domain and I fully intend to fulfil my democratic mandate.
I will not be intimidated or distracted by libellous statements accusing me of wrongdoing, she said.
Ms Murphys comments in the Dil were published on the Oireachtas website.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
