<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Latimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 05:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA President Sepp Blatter faces growing pressure to resign</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-fifa-soccer-20150529-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Embattled FIFA President Sepp Blatter took a pounding Thursday from politicians and sports figures, many of whom called for his resignation amid the far-reaching corruption scandal hitting the soccer world.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>FIFA President Sepp Blatter faces growing pressure to resign
FIFA scandal
Gian Vaitl / Avaaz
Protesters in Zurich, Switzerland, call for the resignation of FIFA President Sepp Blatter.
Protesters in Zurich, Switzerland, call for the resignation of FIFA President Sepp Blatter. (Gian Vaitl / Avaaz)
Amid allegations of corruption, FIFA president is urged to step down
FIFA President Sepp Blatter dismisses critics calling for his resignation
Embattled FIFA President Sepp Blatter took a pounding Thursday from politicians and sports figures, many of whom called for his resignation amid the far-reaching corruption scandal hitting the soccer world.
Blatter, however, gave his critics no quarter and appeared poised to fight on.
As he took the stage at the opening of FIFA's annual Congress in Zurich, he maintained an air of implacability, distancing himself from the 14 men indicted on bribery-related charges.
"The actions of individuals bring shame and humiliation on football and demand action and change from us all," he told delegates at a music-themed ceremony that kicked off the governing body's event. "We cannot allow the reputation of football and FIFA to be dragged through the mud any longer.
U.S. Soccer President Sunil Gulati said Sepp Blatters reelection for a fifth term as FIFAs top executive is far from certain, saying he expects Jordanian Prince Ali bin Al-Hussein to make a strong showing in Fridays vote at the annual meeting of soccer's governing body in Zurich, Switzerland. ( Kevin Baxter )
"I know many people hold me ultimately responsible," he said, but "I cannot monitor everyone all the time."
A FIFA election scheduled at the organization's headquarters Friday morning, in which Blatter, 79, of Switzerland is pitted against the upstart candidate Prince Ali bin al Hussein of Jordan for the presidency, is expected to go on as planned. Blatter is favored to win a fifth four-year term despite the scandal.
The U.S. Department of Justice on Wednesday brought a 47-count indictment against FIFA executives and those they do business with on charges of racketeering, wire fraud and money laundering, alleging that officials had taken more than $150 million in bribes. A parallel investigation has been launched by Swiss authorities over FIFA's awarding of the World Cup host status to Russia in 2018 and Qatar in 2022.
8
Blatter's remarks came at the end of an often surprising day, with Europeans welcoming a U.S. intervention and even the Conservative and Labor parties agreeing in Britain. Left-leaning members of Parliament struck out hard against Blatter, and British Prime Minister David Cameron and Conservative Culture Secretary John Whittingdale called on the FIFA leader to step down.
Meanwhile, French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said he wanted the election postponed.
Visa became the loudest voice among a group of FIFA sponsors, a group historically less likely to rattle the cage, to criticize the organization. In a statement, the credit card giant said it would "reassess our partnership" if "swift and immediate steps to address these issues" weren't taken, though it did not name Blatter specifically.
Michel Platini, the France-born head of the
European soccer federation UEFA and a longtime Blatter critic, made a strongly worded plea for change.
"We cannot continue like this," he said at a news conference Thursday, suggesting that patronage was keeping Blatter in power.
The scandal has highlighted the polarizing power of Blatter, who over his 17 years at the helm of FIFA has built a multibillion-dollar empire that is the envy of many executives, but has also drawn frequent criticism for a stern and secretive style.
Despite the outcry by a number of delegates from larger soccer nations, each of the 209 FIFA member associations receive an equal vote at the election, and it's difficult to predict how the tally will break down.
The largest number of FIFA members come from the Africa contingent, which, with 56, holds two more votes than Europe, and Blatter is seen as popular on that continent. The Asian federation, which pledged support to Blatter on Thursday, is third with 47 votes.
0
Blatter seemed to be appealing to the FIFA swing vote and public sympathy in remarks Thursday that suggested a need for stricter enforcement of the law.
"It must fall to me to be responsible for the well-being and reputation for our organization and to find a way to fix things," he said.
To critics, the statement of accountability sounded like FIFA's business-as-usual approach of shunning outside oversight.
Other variables remain in play in the election. They include members who might feel it's time for a change after this week's embarrassing headlines, and, at the other end of the spectrum, some who believe the charges are an unwanted American intrusion.
The investigation came to light Wednesday via surprising early-morning arrests at the Baur Au Lac, an upscale hotel in central Zurich, in which FBI agents paid visits to a number of FIFA executives, with one even hustled out a side entrance hidden by a bedsheet.
The mood Thursday at the Baur Au Lac was convivial, with little sign of the drama of the day before. Representatives of national associations mingled on a restaurant terrace to eat, drink and backslap with old colleagues. There were few signs of the security that locked down the hotel Wednesday.
But conversations about Blatter could be heard at meals and in lounges, and Cameron's position was called out on more than one occasion.
If Blatter were to remain in office, it could set the stage for more turmoil, especially as the case continues against the 14 who have been indicted. U.S. authorities say that prosecution of FIFA is just beginning, and Swiss authorities have only begun sifting through materials in their investigation.
Coupled with a strong backlash against Blatter from soccer's highest ranks, his reelection could set the stage for boycotts or other fissures within FIFA.
Platini said he planned a meeting of UEFA members next weekend in Berlin, the site of the Champion's League final, on the federation's participation in FIFA events. He did not rule out the possibility of boycotts.
Chris Bryant, a Labor member of the British Parliament, suggested that if the World Cups went ahead in Russia and Qatar, other football associations should consider breakaway events at those times.
But Russian President Vladimir Putin described the investigations as "yet another evident attempt to derail Mr. Blatter's reelection" and introduced a geopolitical element when he said that the U.S.-led arrests had an ulterior motive  to throw into question Russia's host status.
Some skeptics, however, said that many of those speaking out had a stake in the matter. Russia was named a host country, but tournament bids by both England and the United States were denied.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Africa is shaken by FIFA corruption probe investigation</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-fifa-south-africa-20150529-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>In the spring of 2004, a frail, unwell Nelson Mandela ignored his doctor's advice and flew halfway around the globe to meet with a prominent soccer official.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>South Africa is shaken by FIFA corruption probe investigation
Nelson Mandela
Franck Fife / AFP/Getty Images
Nelson Mandela, with Capetown Archbishop Desmond Tutu, raises the Jules Rimet World Cup in Zurich in 2004, after FIFA announced that South Africa would host the 2010 World Cup.
Nelson Mandela, with Capetown Archbishop Desmond Tutu, raises the Jules Rimet World Cup in Zurich in 2004, after FIFA announced that South Africa would host the 2010 World Cup.
(Franck Fife / AFP/Getty Images)
Travel
Jack Warner demanded Mandela's presence for FIFA lobbying, says South Africa organizing committee chairman
In the spring of 2004, a frail, unwell Nelson Mandela ignored his doctor's advice and flew halfway around the globe to meet with a prominent soccer official.
The purpose of the trip to Trinidad and Tobago was simple: Mandela hoped to win Jack Warner's support, persuading him and other officials of FIFA, soccer's ruling body, to hold the 2010 World Cup in South Africa.
At the time, the visit seemed like a resounding success.
But a sweeping indictment unveiled by U.S. prosecutors this week paints a different picture, one in which the South African government  apparently unbeknown to Mandela  may have won the right to host the international tournament by paying at least $10 million in bribes.
On Thursday, the allegations spread anger and sadness across a country that now sees one of its proudest moments tainted.
Embattled FIFA President Sepp Blatter took a pounding Thursday from politicians and sports figures, many of whom called for his resignation amid the far-reaching corruption scandal hitting the soccer world. ( Steven Zeitchik )
The real damage "is to our own psyche," wrote Stephen Grootes, a columnist for the Daily Maverick online newspaper. "It's not just that officials had to be bribed; it's that the World Cup was a chance for us to be a special nation again."
South African Sports Minister Fikile Mbalula vehemently denied the charges and accused the U.S. of reaching "beyond its borders" by indicting 14 people, including Warner and eight other present and former FIFA officials, on racketeering charges.
Warner, who faces eight criminal counts in the U.S. and had surrendered to authorities in Trinidad, was granted a $395,000 bond Thursday after spending the night in jail. He left by ambulance, complaining of exhaustion, the Associated Press reported.
8
Much of the Department of Justice case revolves around the former FIFA vice president, including his role in the selection of South Africa to host the 2010 World Cup. There are allegations that a South African soccer official gave a briefcase stuffed with U.S. currency in stacks of $10,000 to Warner's representative and that secretive wire transfers were made from a Swiss account to a bank in New York.
"FIFA executives and others corrupted the process by using bribes to influence the hosting decision," U.S. Atty. General Loretta Lynch said.
With South Africa competing against Morocco and Egypt to be the 2010 host, Warner's backing was considered vital.
Mandela was not mentioned in the indictment. His role as a lobbyist for the bid was detailed by Irvin Khoza, chairman of South Africa's organizing committee, at a university forum in Johannesburg in 2009.
"Jack bluntly told us that if we wanted his vote, we must bring Mandela to the Caribbean," Khoza said.
Khoza and other senior officials, including Danny Jordaan, a key figure in the bid, pressed Mandela to go, but doctors advised against the trip because the former South African president was in poor health.
"However, we finally got the go-ahead when we arranged for a special flight, two doctors and a whole lot of medical equipment to accompany Mandela," Khoza said. "But it was not to be, when we were summoned by the government to Pretoria. Here, we were told that Mandela could not go to the Caribbean."
Mandela eventually traveled to Trinidad and Tobago in April 2004, sparking a tug-of-war between Warner and Trinidadian government officials over who should have the right to meet him at the airport.
0
The South African leader arrived in Port of Spain too weak to climb the steps of a podium where he was to address a waiting crowd, the Associated Press reported at the time.
Warner reportedly boasted about Mandela traveling against doctors' advice. Straining credibility, the FIFA official even told reporters that Mandela was concerned that violence would erupt if South Africa lost its bid for the World Cup.
"As Mr. Mandela told me, he doesn't know what will happen if their bid fails," Warner was quoted as saying. "They are so passionate about it, and it's getting very dangerous."
There was no suggestion of any threat of violence over the issue in South Africa at the time.
South Africa eventually won the right to host the event. Mandela was in Zurich for the May 2004 announcement and famously declared: "I feel like a young man of 15."
The very different account of South Africa's successful campaign  detailed in the U.S. indictment  dates to the early 2000s.
At one point, prosecutors say, a South African official met with a member of Warner's family in a Paris hotel room and handed over a briefcase filled with those $10,000 bundles. The family member then flew back to Trinidad and Tobago and gave the briefcase to Warner.
The indictment also alleges that Moroccan officials had offered to pay $1 million in exchange for Warner's vote but that South Africa subsequently upped the ante to $10 million, the money headed to a Caribbean soccer organization to "support the African diaspora."
When South African officials later balked at paying directly from government coffers, arrangements were made to take the money from FIFA funds that were earmarked to support the World Cup, the indictment says.
Through the early weeks of 2008, prosecutors allege, installments of $616,000,
$1.6 million and nearly
$8 million were wired from a FIFA account in Switzerland to a Bank of America correspondent account in New York that was controlled by Warner.
Prosecutors say he skimmed about $1 million of that money for personal use.
Though the indictment alleges that two unnamed co-conspirators, listed as No. 15 and No. 16, were high-ranking officials from South Africa's bid committees, Mbalula insisted Thursday that his country paid no bribes.
"We didn't run a spaza shop or picnic," he said, referring to small, informal convenience shops common in South African townships. "We ran a proper process. We're clear we've not done anything untoward."
Grootes expressed indignation that a beloved former leader had been dragged into the mess.
"We didn't know then the cost," the columnist wrote. "And particularly the cost to Nelson Mandela, shipping around the world to satisfy the craving of some two-bit crook."
Times staff reporter David Wharton contributed to this report.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Volcano erupts on small island in southern Japan</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-volcano-eruption-japan-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, and authorities ordered residents to evacuate the island.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Volcano erupts on small island in southern Japan
By Associated Press
Volcanic Eruptions
Residents of a small island in southern Japan are told to evacuate after a volcano erupts
A volcano erupted on a small island in southern Japan on Friday, and authorities ordered residents to evacuate the island.
8
Mount Shindake erupted about 10 a.m. in spectacular fashion, spewing towering black-gray clouds into the sky.
The Japan Meteorological Agency reported that pyroclastic flows from the volcano had reached the shore to the northwest.
The government was surveying the island by helicopter to assess damage.
The national broadcaster NHK cited local officials as saying that 80 residents had taken refuge in a shelter on the island.
The U.S. military has begun to carefully but publicly challenge Chinese island-building on disputed reefs and shoals in the South China Sea, creating fresh tension in a potential global tinderbox as both countries shift forces into the area. ( David S. Cloud )
About 140 people live on Kuchinoerabu island in the Ryukyu archipelago, 50 miles (80 kilometers) southwest of the main southern island of Kyushu. Tourism and fishing are the main activities on the heavily forested, mountainous island, which is a national park.
The Japan Meterological Agency raised the volcano alert level to five, the highest on its scale. Shindake also erupted in August last year for the first time since 1980.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:43:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin declares Russian military deaths in peacetime state secrets</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-russia-putin-military-deaths-secret-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin signed a decree on Thursday outlawing disclosure of military deaths in peacetime, a move apparently aimed at hiding evidence of Russian military involvement in the war in eastern Ukraine.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Putin declares Russian military deaths in peacetime state secrets
Ukraine crisis
AFP/Getty Images
Russian armored vehicles are readied May 23 for transport on a freight train from the town of Matveev Kurgan, 13 miles from the Ukrainian border.
Russian armored vehicles are readied May 23 for transport on a freight train from the town of Matveev Kurgan, 13 miles from the Ukrainian border.
(AFP/Getty Images)
Russian decree making peacetime military deaths state secrets apparently aims to hide Ukraine involvement
Russian President Vladimir Putin revises state secret list to outlaw disclosure of peacetime military deaths
Amnesty International says Russian banning of peacetime military death disclosures has 'sinister undertones'
Russian President Vladimir Putin signed a decree on Thursday outlawing disclosure of military deaths in peacetime, a move apparently aimed at hiding evidence of Russian military involvement in the war in eastern Ukraine.
The decree published on the government information portal amends a 1995 list of state secrets to add military deaths "in peacetime during special operations" to the already classified "information disclosing losses in manpower in wartime," the Tass news agency reported.
Ukraine fighting
AFP/Getty Images
Russian military vehicles at a camp at the Kuzminsky training ground in the Rostov region, about 30 miles from the Russian-Ukrainian border.
Russian military vehicles at a camp at the Kuzminsky training ground in the Rostov region, about 30 miles from the Russian-Ukrainian border.
(AFP/Getty Images)
Putin has denied funneling Russian troops or arms to pro-Russia separatists waging war against Ukrainian government forces for control of the country's eastern industrial region along the Don River basin, known as the Donbas. But captured active-duty Russian troops, including two special forces officers taken prisoner this month, have conceded to Ukrainian authorities that they were dispatched by the Russian military to back the separatists.
0
Media attempts to report on funerals of Russian soldiers whose bodies were returned from the Donbas battlefields have also been disrupted, with reporters and activists beaten when discovered at the gravesides.
Amnesty International denounced the new decree as an infringement on press freedom and an apparent attempt to hide illegal involvement in a sovereign neighbor's affairs.
Not only is this decree a blatant attack on freedom of expression, it also has sinister undertones that will intensify speculation President Putin has something to hide  specifically losses incurred by Russias military in Ukraine, John Dalhuisen, Amnestys Europe and Central Asia director, said in a statement posted on the rights group's website.
Dalhuisen said the move also increases fear for the safety of Russian journalists and activists "who have already faced harassment for trying to independently cover the conflict in Ukraine.
His statement cited an Aug. 29 incident in the northwest Pskov region when local lawmaker Lev Shlosberg was hospitalized with head injuries after being beaten, reportedly for disclosing the first secret funerals of Russian war dead from Ukraine onhis Pskovskaya Guberniya online news site.
U.N. rights agencies estimate that at least 6,300 people -- many of them civilians -- have been killed in eastern Ukraine since the separatists seized the governing headquarters of the Donetsk and Luhansk regions in April 2014. The Ukrainian government says the death toll is more than 8,600.
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain's EU membership at heart of Cameron's European tour</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-britain-eu-membership-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Hot on the heels of his election victory, Prime Minister David Cameron embarked on a whirlwind two-day tour of Europe aimed at renegotiating Britain’s membership in the European Union.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Britain's EU membership at heart of Cameron's European tour
French President Receives British Prime Minister David Cameron At Elysee Palace In Paris
Thierry Chesnot / Getty Images
British Prime Minister David Cameron, left, shakes hands with French President Francois Hollande after a press conference at the Elysee Palace in Paris on Thursday.
British Prime Minister David Cameron, left, shakes hands with French President Francois Hollande after a press conference at the Elysee Palace in Paris on Thursday.
(Thierry Chesnot / Getty Images)
Britain's Cameron embarks on 2-day tour of Europe over EU issues
Cameron pledge of a referendum on European Union membership is at heart of British prime minister's visits
Hot on the heels of his election victory, Prime Minister David Cameron embarked on a whirlwind two-day tour of Europe aimed at renegotiating Britains membership in the European Union.
Cameron met with leaders in Holland and France on Thursday and plans to travel to Poland and Germany on Friday as part of his campaign to secure substantive changes ahead of a referendum on whether the British public wants to stay in or leave the EU.
The meetings are unlikely to bring immediate results, yet they will provide a crucial litmus test of how open each country is to negotiation.
Former British Prime Minister Tony Blair announced in a letter to the United Nations chief on Wednesday that he will step down as the world body's special Middle East envoy at the end of June, British news media reported, citing unnamed diplomatic sources. ( Carol J. Williams )
A referendum on Britains membership of the EU was one of Camerons key promises to voters who gave his Conservative Party a solid parliamentary victory earlier this month.
Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said Cameron would warn the European leaders that the ballot initiative is not a matter to be taken lightly. Unless they agree to Camerons reforms, he said, the British public will likely vote to leave.
8
We are confident that our counterparts in Europe understand the importance of this issue, Hammond told reporters Thursday. [And] understand that if these issues are not addressed the British people will not give their endorsement to the proposition that Britain should remain part of the European Union.
The reforms Cameron is expected to be asking for include a limit on the number of EU migrants entering the U.K., and tougher rules for those already in Britain.
More specifically, the prime minister is reportedly looking to block unemployed EU migrants from claiming benefits, forcing them to wait four years before claiming in-work benefits.
Cameron will also tryto gain Britain more powers to block new EU laws as well as an opt-out option from the EU's commitment to ever closer union.
In 1973 Britain joined the bloc that now numbers 28 countriesand while EU membership brings many benefits, including the creation of the worlds largest single market, it also requires adherence to European law, which has proved divisive, especially on issues of immigration, border control and human rights.
The right-wing U.K. Independence Party, which secured 13% of the votes in the election, made an exit from the EU one of its key campaign pledges and Camerons decision to give voters a choice on the issue was partly a way to win support among those enticed by the move to leave the EU.
A parliamentary bill published Thursday outlined details of the referendum and states it must be held by Dec. 31, 2017.
0
Voters will be asked the question: Should the United Kingdom remain a member of the European Union? meaning a yes vote will be a vote in favor of staying part of the EU.
This is a key difference from last years vote for Scottish independence where yes was a vote to break away.
Hammond has not ruled out that the vote could be held as early as next year, but stressed its more important that we get it right than that we get it quickly.
We are absolutely determined to deliver on this agenda, he added.
Camerons first stop on his whistle-stop tour was in Holland, where he had lunch with his counterpart, Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte.
As he arrived, Cameron told reporters that the focus of their discussions would be growth and jobs, and the need for flexibility.
He likened Britains relationship with Holland to old friends and like-minded allies.
Later in the afternoon, Cameron traveled to the Elysee Palace in Paris to meet with French President Francois Hollande.
On Friday he will meet Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz in Warsaw and German Chancellor Angela Merkel in Berlin. The British government has been told by lawyers that reforms will require changes to EU treaties, a move that has been resisted by other leaders and could potentially open up the EU to a plethora of demands from member nations.
In a sign of the early opposition Cameron is likely to face in his meetings, French politician Christophe Premat told the BBC that the looming referendum could not be used as a threat in the negotiations.
We respect that a referendum will be held in Great Britain, thats the destiny of the people in the U.K. Thats correct. But, at the same time, we cant use the referendum as a threat in order to have more space in the renegotiation, he said. The method should be approached in another way. That might be the message of President Hollande to David Cameron tonight.
Boyle is a special correspondent.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin casts FIFA scandal as U.S. plot to wreck Russia's 2018 World Cup</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-fifa-russia-putin-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin reacted Thursday with trademark indifference to the bribery scandal plaguing the world soccer federation FIFA, denying any wrongdoing by Russia and accusing the United States of trying to wreck his country's hosting of the 2018 World Cup.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Putin casts FIFA scandal as U.S. plot to wreck Russia's 2018 World Cup
Putin says FIFA arrests show U.S. meddling abroad
Russian President Vladimir Putin says FIFA arrests show U.S. meddling abroad.
Russian President Vladimir Putin says FIFA arrests show U.S. meddling abroad.
FIFA World Cup
Russian President Vladimir Putin suggests a U.S. agenda behind allegations of FIFA bribery
Russian President Vladimir Putin reacted Thursday with trademark indifference to the bribery scandal plaguing the world soccer federation FIFA, denying any wrongdoing by Russia and accusing the United States of trying to wreck his country's hosting of the 2018 World Cup.
FIFA officials arrested in corruption case Read more stories
In televised comments from the Kremlin, Putin called it "odd" that U.S. prosecutors had brought charges of corruption and bribery against 14 soccer officials for alleged crimes, including accepting $150 million in bribes, that occurred outside the United States and involved mostly foreign citizens.
A separate investigation launched by Swiss authorities is aimed at determining whether inappropriate influence was exercised in FIFA's decisions to award the next World Cup to Russia and the 2022 tournament to the Persian Gulf state of Qatar.
Russia "has nothing to do with it," Putin said of the scandal and allegations that Moscow secured the coveted hosting rights through some form of subterfuge.
cComments
I'll tell you what the U.S. GOVERNMENT DOES that no other government around the world does (?) That is protecting the "Right to Privacy." If all other countries are getting left out of--trade secrets, they should not take it out on the Audience and the Football Games. It's...
victor.ramirez18
49
The bombshell U.S. accusations against senior soccer figures contained in a 47-count indictment released Wednesday has shaken the administration of the world's most popular sport and spurred mounting calls for FIFA President Sepp Blatter to resign.
Blatter, who is not among the accused, was expected to secure a fifth term as FIFA chief at the organization's annual meeting in Zurich, Switzerland, when the presidency is up for a vote on Friday. But the corruption allegations have prompted key sponsors of the World Cup, including Visa, Coca-Cola and Adidas, to demand reform within the soccer federation to ensure "ethical practices."
Putin cast the movement to derail Blatter's candidacy to stay at FIFA's helm as a move engineered by the United States to get Russia's 2018 hosting revoked.
"As we all know, on Friday FIFA was to elect its president, and Mr. Blatter has every chance to be reelected," Putin said. "We are aware of the pressure that was put on him to prevent the 2018 World Cup in Russia."
Putin likened the alleged attempt to punish Blatter to the charges brought against NSA leaker Edward Snowden and WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange for their exposure of massive U.S. government surveillance of millions of citizens' private phone calls, emails and texts.
Our American counterparts, unfortunately, are using the same methods to reach their goals and illegally persecute people. I don't rule out that this is the case in relation to FIFA, Putin said. I have no doubt that this is yet another obvious attempt to derail Mr. Blatter's reelection as FIFA president."
U.S.-Russian relations have fallen to a post-Cold War low following Russia's seizure and annexation of Ukraine's Crimea region and its backing for separatist rebels occupying two large regions of eastern Ukraine.
Putin has cast the conflict in Ukraine as the result of U.S. and NATO encroachment into Russia's traditional sphere of influence, a campaign he contends is aimed at deposing him and installing more Western-leaning and pliable figures in the Kremlin and other former Soviet states.
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Africa denies $10-million bribe to secure 2010 FIFA World Cup</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-south-africa-denies-fifa-bribe-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>South African Sports Minister Fikile Mbalula on Thursday vehemently denied allegations that South Africa bribed FIFA officials with $10 million to secure soccer’s World Cup in 2010, and accused the United States of going “beyond its borders” by indicting 14 people, including FIFA officials, on...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>0
Some critics questioned the haste with which Mbalula dismissed the detailed allegations in the U.S. indictment. On page 80 of the 162-page indictment, it is alleged that then-FIFA official Jack Warner cultivated ties with South African sports officials after the countrys unsuccessful 2006 bid to host the World Cup.
A South African official met a member of Warners family in a Paris hotel room and handed him a briefcase containing bundles of $10,000 bills, according to the indictment. The family member immediately flew back Warner's home of Trinidad and Tobago and handed the briefcase to him, according to the indictment.
As South Africa and Morocco faced off for the right to host the 2010 World Cup, Moroccan officials offered Warner a $1-million bribe in exchange for his promise to vote for Morocco in the executive committee secret ballot to decide who would get the event, the indictment said.
According to the indictment, high-ranking South African government officials and members of the countrys bid committee were willing to pay a $10-million bribe in order to secure the votes of Warner and two others on the executive committee. The payment was to be disguised as money to support the African diaspora, the indictment said.
In May 2004, South Africa was named the successful bidder in a ceremony attended by Mandela.
It later turned out that South Africa was unable to make the payment directly from government funds, the indictment said. Instead, the money was taken from FIFA funds that were transferred to South Africa to support the World Cup, according to the indictment.
In his news conference Thursday, Mbalula insisted that no payment was made from the South African government to FIFA officials. However, the allegation is that the money was subtracted from FIFAs payments to South Africa.
South Africas opposition Democratic Alliance called Thursday for an investigation and demanded that Jordaan, head of the football association, appear before parliaments committee on sports to explain what happened.
As the CEO of the bid committee, Danny Jordaan oversaw the 2010 bid strategy. His role in these allegations must be probed, said Solly Malatsi of the Democratic Alliance. A transaction of the magnitude of $10 million would not have happened without the knowledge of the most senior figures leading the countrys bid for the World Cup, he said.
It is a national shame that one of the proudest moments for our democratic nation has been tarnished by this latest scandal, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Romero beatification signals Pope Francis' plan for Catholic Church</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-direction-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis' decision to beatify assassinated Salvadoran Archbishop Oscar Romero offers the most clear signal yet of the pope's determination to refocus the direction of the world's largest Christian organization.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Romero beatification signals Pope Francis' plan for Catholic Church
Pope Francis
Alessandro di Meo, European Pressphoto Agency
Many see Pope Francis as the epitome of inclusiveness.
Many see Pope Francis as the epitome of inclusiveness. (Alessandro di Meo, European Pressphoto Agency)
Salvadoran archbishop's beatification emphasizes Pope Francis' focus on 'a poor church for the poor'
Salvadoran Archbishop Oscar Romero's beatification seen as a symbolic moment in Francis' papacy
Pope Francis' decision to beatify assassinated Salvadoran Archbishop Oscar Romero offers the most clear signal yet of the pope's determination to refocus the direction of the world's largest Christian organization.
Francis ended years of debate when he declared Romero, a pivotal figure in the Roman Catholic Church's struggle with conservative and progressive forces, a martyr. Doing so cleared the way for Romero's beatification  the step before sainthood  which took place in El Salvador on Saturday.
Romero's advocacy for the poor in especially violent, difficult times of war and repression fell squarely in line with Francis' emphasis on "a poor church for the poor," a theme that he inaugurated in the first days after his election to the papacy in March 2013 as the first pontiff from the Americas.
Oscar Romero
Oscar Rivera, European Pressphoto Agency
A portrait of slain Roman Catholic Archbishop Oscar Romero is carried in a procession in San Salvador.
A portrait of slain Roman Catholic Archbishop Oscar Romero is carried in a procession in San Salvador. (Oscar Rivera, European Pressphoto Agency)
A forceful and often solitary voice for those killed, kidnapped and tortured in an El Salvador sliding into civil war, Romero established a record that enabled Francis to sweep aside claims by some that the Salvadoran archbishop's work was more political than pastoral and tainted with leftist leanings. Romero was slain by a right-wing death squad as he said Mass 35 years ago.
"Romero is an icon of the church that Francis is seeking to build," said Elisabetta Pique, an expert on the papacy and author of "Pope Francis: Life and Revolution." It is a church "with pastors that are close to the people and especially to the marginalized and those who suffer most. The beatification is another clear sign of the direction of his papacy."
8
An earlier signal from the pope about the direction he wanted to take the church came in his little-noticed meeting with the Peruvian founder of Liberation Theology, a philosophy that was soundly out of favor with Pope John Paul II, who believed, or was convinced by his most conservative advisors, that it injected Marxism into work for the poor.
Father Gustavo Gutierrez and his supporters were shunned and punished for decades by the Vatican and church hierarchy, which did its best to replace progressive bishops with those from ultraconservative groups such as Opus Dei and the Legion of Christ. An invitation for him to meet with Francis about six months after the pope's ascension, not announced and only later confirmed by the Vatican, was a remarkable shift in attitude, and, in the view of many, a vindication for Liberation Theology.
Francis "is saying things I've wanted my church to say for a long time," said Rep. Jim McGovern, a Democrat from Massachusetts and a Catholic who attended the Romero beatification. As a congressional staffer in the 1980s, he became something of an expert on El Salvador and witnessed the myriad attempts by church conservatives, and the U.S. government, to vilify Romero and the left.
Romero is an icon of the church that Francis is seeking to build. - Elisabetta Pique, an expert on the papacy
"I am hoping this is not just a moment in history but will last and that you are going to see a more vibrant church, more outspoken on behalf of the poor, and governments that will address poverty," McGovern said. "Francis has made all this possible."
The United States under the Reagan administration continued to back the right-wing Salvadoran government as a bulwark against communism, even as Romero, other priests, American nuns, labor organizers and thousands more were killed.
In 1978, two years before Romero's death, a Polish bishop became pope. John Paul II was guided organically by his fight against, and suffering under, communism. Some observers say that made him tone-deaf to fights against rightists who painted the enemy as Marxist. Romero recalled in his diary his thwarted efforts to make John Paul understand the persecution of his church by a brutal right-wing regime.
@auto-de-fe Correction 'you all drink from the same poisoned well.' Might be a good idea to go to another watering hole.
Nacho Zaragoza
21
The shift under Francis, telegraphed in his first days as pope, has been noticeable: his decision to wash the feet of the poor and a Muslim during Easter week; his statement that he would not "judge" homosexuals; his current focus on climate change as a scourge threatening the planet; his affable humility, including his refusal to take on papal trappings of luxury.
Although his predecessor, Benedict XVI, is the one who formally reopened the Romero case for sainthood, he was a dogmatic conservative more interested in a pure, if smaller, Catholic Church. Francis, by contrast, is the epitome of inclusiveness.
This evolution unnerves conservative forces within the Catholic Church, including in the United States, where he will visit in September, but perhaps no more visibly than in San Salvador, the capital, the day after the beatification at Sunday Mass.
At the Divine Providence chapel where Romero was slain, worshipers, many wearing "St. Romero" T-shirts, filled the pews; a reverential portrait of "Monsignor" graced the altar along with a burst of brilliant flowers.
But up the skirts of the hills surrounding the city, to the wealthiest suburbs, the story was different, more formal, more solemn. Only one or two small Romero posters decorated those large and overflowing Catholic sanctuaries.
At the Immaculate Conception church in the suburb of Santa Tecla, the Mass was officially dedicated to Romero, but the sermon was about materialism and abortion, how a woman, thinking her body is her own, can kill a baby inside her as easily as removing a thorn from a foot.
At the Monte Elena Catholic Church, where Romero T-shirts gave way to Carolina Herrera designer bags, and nannies and bodyguards populated the gardens, a huge portrait of Opus Dei founder Josemaria Escriva, fast-tracked to sainthood by John Paul in 2002, took prominent position near the altar. A tiny poster of Romero, advocating conversion and reconciliation, not the slain archbishop's usual themes, was on a back wall.
Lorena Duque de Rodriguez, congregant at Monte Elena and vice rector at a local university, said the beatification of Romero, which she supported, had been politicized by both sides.
"It is an uncomfortable theme, people hate to touch it," said Duque, who, like so many Salvadorans, counts much of her family in the Los Angeles area. "People say, 'Let's not talk about it. That's a political subject.'"
A United Nations Truth Commission, after the end of El Salvador's civil war in 1992, determined that Romero was killed on the orders of army Maj. Roberto D'Aubuisson, who founded both the death squads that terrorized the country and the Arena political party that ruled for two decades until 2009. D'Aubuisson and his closest collaborators, in turn, have said they were acting on orders from the richest Salvadoran landowners and coffee tycoons, whose economic status quo was threatened by Romero's support for the poor.
D'Aubuisson's sister, Marisa, split from the family decades ago and was always a staunch supporter of Romero, inspired, she said in an interview, by the scenes of poverty and desperation she saw in El Salvador.
"It was a blessing that Pope Francis arrived, a Latin American who had lived under the repression of Argentina and understood the context of El Salvador," Marisa D'Aubuisson de Martinez said. "That was very different from John Paul II, whose suffering under communism prevented him from understanding what was happening here. He did not understand our reality."
Pope Francis' new direction has irritated some of the more conservative members of the church, especially in the U.S., but other Vatican observers warn it would be a mistake to cast Francis as a left-winger, noting his shift also has a lot to do with changing history.
"The further we got from the Cold War, the better Romero looked," said Father Thomas Reese, a Jesuit  like Francis  who analyzes Vatican affairs for the National Catholic Reporter. "Nevertheless, the beatification does mark a big change in the church's orientation and is a symbolic moment in Francis' papacy."
Times staff writer Wilkinson reported from San Salvador and special correspondent Kington from Vatican City.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Helping Nepal's children cope with 'immense trauma' of 7.8 earthquake</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-nepal-quake-children-20150528-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Amid row after row of tents in Tundikhel, an open field in the center of this earthquake-ravaged capital, is a big blue tarpaulin under which children buzz about with colorful balloons and clay.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Helping Nepal's children cope with 'immense trauma' of 7.8 earthquake
Aftermath of Nepal earthquakes
Harish Tyagi / European Pressphoto Agency
"Children are very resilient," says Ramsey Ben-Achour, a UNICEF child protection specialist. Above, a temporary shelter near Katmandu, Nepal.
"Children are very resilient," says Ramsey Ben-Achour, a UNICEF child protection specialist. Above, a temporary shelter near Katmandu, Nepal.
(Harish Tyagi / European Pressphoto Agency)
By Bhrikuti Rai
Children account for more than one-quarter of the nearly 9,000 killed and 21,000 injured in the Nepal quake
Closure of schools since the Nepal quake adds to the feeling of instability for children
Nepalese authorities say teachers will be trained to help children cope with quake anxiety when schools reopen
Amid row after row of tents in Tundikhel, an open field in the center of this earthquake-ravaged capital, is a big blue tarpaulin under which children buzz about with colorful balloons and clay.
Indira Khadka, 28, sat on a gray mat beside dozens of tiny pairs of slippers and watched her 2-year-old son, Ishan, build a house with wooden blocks.
The earth rattled yet again. ( Bhrikuti Rai )
"I am relieved to see him finally playing and laughing," said Khadka, whose family has lived in Tundikhel since a massive aftershock on May 12 damaged the room she rents in central Katmandu. "He has lost his appetite since we started camping out here last week."
Since a magnitude 7.8 earthquake struck Nepal last month  and a series of aftershocks caused more destruction and frayed nerves  almost 1 million children have been unable to return to damaged school buildings, according to UNICEF estimates.
The state of limbo has exacerbated the toll on some of Nepal's most vulnerable, as children and their parents are forced to seek stability in temporary spaces set up by aid agencies and others in devastated towns and tent camps like Tundikhel.
"Children need some form of stability to overcome the immense trauma," said Ramsey Ben-Achour, a UNICEF child protection specialist who recently visited the temporary learning center in Tundikhel.
"However, children are very resilient and as soon as schools reopen, they'll feel normal again."
Children accounted for more than one-quarter of the nearly 9,000 killed and 21,000 injured in the April 25 temblor, according to official figures. Schools closed after the quake were scheduled to reopen May 15, but that was pushed back by two weeks after the major aftershock caused more serious damage.
People are more worried now after May 12, and the apprehension in elders passes on to the children who will end up suffering the most in the absence of any emotional outlet. - Nirjala Bhattarai, counselor in Katmandu, Nepal
Rita Upreti, a fourth-grader, has been living with her family in Tundikhel, playing in the tents and drawing pictures of what she remembers of Katmandu before the earthquake.
"I was watching TV when the first earthquake struck," she said. "I hid under the bed until the shaking stopped and then ran outside."
She showed a sketch of the city's skyline featuring the iconic nine-story Dharahara tower, which collapsed in the quake, burying scores of people. Her ancestral home in Kavre district, east of Katmandu, was destroyed too, and the rented room where she lives with her parents in the capital was also severely damaged.
She spoke enthusiastically about returning to school, but her voice soon trailed off.
0
"How will we take our midterm exams if the school buildings aren't repaired soon?" she said. "There is no way to run outside of the school if another earthquake strikes."
UNICEF and local and international aid agencies have opened temporary spaces for children such as the tent city in Tundikhel and are providing counseling. Experts hope the services will assist children vulnerable to post-disaster trauma, along with parents who are also struggling with anxiety because of the damage and frequent aftershocks.
"People are more worried now after May 12, and the apprehension in elders passes on to the children, who will end up suffering the most in the absence of any emotional outlet," said Nirjala Bhattarai, a psychological counselor in Katmandu.
Nepal's earthquake preparedness policies have neglected mental health issues, she said, requiring local and international agencies to intervene with emergency programs.
"All we ever talked about was about physical safety during and after the earthquake," she said. "It is about time we also include psychological first aid and intervention in our awareness programs."
Nepalese authorities have said they are planning to train schoolteachers to help children cope with their anxiety when schools reopen May 31.
"It is a big challenge to address the growing concern of mental health, especially among children," Health Minister Khagaraj Adhikari said at a recent news conference. "Our institutions alone will not be sufficient."
Ministry officials have yet to assess the number of people who need counseling after the earthquake, but say they have begun training teachers in some districts and mobilizing psychiatric teams.
"With so many aftershocks, people are bound to be anxious," Adhikari said. "We hope to give them, especially children, some form of stability once they return to classrooms."
Rai is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 00:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Despite FIFA  bribery scandal, soccer's popularity still high in Europe</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-fifa-corruption-reaction-20150527-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>European soccer fans reacted with a mix of satisfaction and world-weariness to the news Wednesday that top officials of FIFA, the world sport’s governing body, had been indicted on corruption charges.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>"Under Sepp Blatter, FIFA has become a disgrace and a painful embarrassment to those of us who care about football deeply," Maradona wrote.
Some in the soccer establishment, however, were less condemnatory.
Arsene Wenger, who manages Britains Arsenal club, called the events embarrassing but cautioned against snap judgments, saying, "Sometimes I think now we are too quick to convict people who have not been proven guilty."
Many in Europe were taken aback by the involvement of U.S. law enforcement.
A Maccabi Tel Aviv fan on vacation from Israel said he was still unclear on why the actions had stretched across the Atlantic.
FIFA is imploding. The best thing that could possibly happen to the beautiful game. - Gary Lineker, sports broadcaster and retired English striker
"The part that surprised me was the FBI getting involved, said the man, who gave his name as Yochanan, who like a number of others, declined to provide a last name because he was criticizing a high-profile institution. Isn't this in Europe?"
(The FBI says it is investigating suspected licensing and merchandising wrongdoing in the Americas, with a secondary focus on actions elsewhere. Swiss authorities haveseparately opened an inquiry of the awarding of the World Cup to Russia in 2018 and Qatar in 2022, and have raided FIFA's offices in Zurich.)
Many commentators used the burgeoning scandal as a chance to channel their inner wag.
The spectacle of Zurich hotel workers shielding indicted officials with abed sheet lent itself to a high degree of mockery online.
"In my culture, this is how the bride enters the marriage hall," one Twitter user noted.
The online betting service Paddy Power made its feelings known by riffing on a scheduled Blatter re-election bid: "Despite the arrest of #FIFA Officials on corruption charges, Sepp says he remains confident of getting 107% of the vote in Friday's election," the company quipped on its Twitter account.
An Athens cab driver, who said he does not follow football, even drew parallels to the corruption scandals involving Greek officials in recent years.
"There is corruption on the whole planet, said the driver, who identified himself only as Panagiotis. Anywhere there is power. So Greek politicians or soccer officials, whats the difference, really?
Special correspondent Christina Boyle in London contributed to this report.
For more news from Europe, follow @ZeitchikLAT on Twitter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
