<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Latimes">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>19 reported killed in attack on Tunisian beach</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-attack-tunisian-beach-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Gunmen struck a popular Tunisian beach resort on Friday, and state television said 19 people were killed. It was the second major strike in just over three months against a tourist target in the North African country.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>19 reported killed in attack on Tunisian beach
Tunisia beach
Bechir Bettaieb / AFP/Getty Images
An October 2013 photo of tourists enjoying the beach near a four-star hotel in Sousse, a popular destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital.
An October 2013 photo of tourists enjoying the beach near a four-star hotel in Sousse, a popular destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital.
(Bechir Bettaieb / AFP/Getty Images)
8
The shooting attack took place outside a beachfront hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, at noontime on a hot summer day when the seaside was crowded with visitors. Sousse, about 90 miles south of Tunis, is a popular destination for tourists traveling from Europe as well as elsewhere in the country and the region.
0
There was no immediate claim of responsibility.
Tunisias tourism industry suffered a devastating blow on March 18, when attackers hit the Bardo National Museum in the capital, whose antiquities were a major draw for visitors. That attack left 21 people dead, most of them European tourists on a cruise-ship stopover. Militants declaring allegiance to the Islamic State claimed responsibility.
The tourism sector is crucial for the economy in Tunisia, which is considered the only real success story in the wake of the Arab Spring uprisings more than four years ago. The country has been relatively politically stable, especially compared with its chaos-riven neighbor Libya, but the calm has been punctuated by occasional Islamist attacks, and economic stagnation and joblessness are major concerns.
Staff writer King reported from Cairo and special correspondent Hassan from Berlin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS claims blast at Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-is-claims-blast-at-shiite-mosque-in-kuwait-s-capital-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for a deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>IS claims blast at Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait's capital
Attack on Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque
YASSER AL-ZAYYAT / AFP/Getty Images
Kuwaiti security forces gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
Kuwaiti security forces gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
(YASSER AL-ZAYYAT / AFP/Getty Images)
By Associated Press
The Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for a deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
A post on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claims the explosion was the work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt.
The attack was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group calling itself the Najd Province, the same group that claimed responsibility for a pair of attacks on two Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading, explosion at French factory called terrorist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-explosion-beheading-terror-probe-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading, explosion at French factory called terrorist attack
Attack at French factory
Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier after an attack.
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier after an attack.
(Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images)
Francois Hollande
One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said.
One suspect has been arrested in connection with the attack, said French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve, adding that intelligence services had identified the man as a potential extremist in 2006 but stopped monitoring him two years later.
Attack at French factory
Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images
French security stand next to the enclosed area where a decapitated body was found near the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier.
French security stand next to the enclosed area where a decapitated body was found near the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier.
(Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images)
Cazeneuve named the suspect as Yessim Salim or Yacine Sali, according to conflicting spellings given in various news reports.
Speaking in Brussels before a planned European Union summit, Hollande said the attack was carried out shortly before 10 a.m. by one or possibly two men in a car who clearly intended to blow up the Air Products factory in the town of Saint Quentin Fallavier, near the city of Grenoble. The plant manufactures industrial gases.
Hollande said there was no doubt that it was a terrorist assault. French anti-terrorist prosecutors have opened an investigation.
cComments
One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said. And President...
John Gury
5
French media reported that the severed head of the decapitated victim was found hanging on the factory fence, near a flag bearing Arabic inscriptions. Hollande said that a message of some sort had been written on the body.
The other victims were hurt in an explosion set off when the attackers rammed their car into the factory gates, according to news reports. The severity of the injuries was not immediately clear.
The gruesome violence came less than six months after the Jan. 7 rampage in Paris at the headquarters of Charlie Hebdo, the satirical magazine targeted because of its cartoons of the prophet Mohammad, and a Jewish supermarket. Twenty people were killed, including the three attackers.
France has been on alert for further attacks. In April, an Algerian national linked by authorities to Al Qaeda and Islamic State was arrested on suspicion of plotting a gun attack on churches in Paris.
Security was stepped up at other sites in the region where Fridays attack occurred, for fear that the incident might either be a prelude to a larger assault or inspiration for copycats.
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," Alain Juppe, a former French premier, said via Twitter. "The [French] state must do everything possible to protect its citizens."
Air Products is a U.S.-owned company founded in 1940 and headquartered in Allentown, Pa. It has offices around the world, including more than a dozen in Europe.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber protests turn violent in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-uber-france-taxi-html-20150625-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Cars overturned. Roads blockaded with flaming tires. That's what happens when the U.S. sharing economy tangles with French protectionism. French taxi drivers protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against Uber, which is facing fierce opposition from traditional cabs. Hundreds...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Francois Hollande
Cars overturned. Roads blockaded with flaming tires. That's what happens when the U.S. sharing economy tangles with French protectionism.
French taxi drivers protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against Uber, which is facing fierce opposition from traditional cabs.
Hundreds of French taxi drivers took to the streets Thursday in sometimes violent protest against Uber, blocking access to major airports and train stations, and attacking vehicles suspected of working for the popular car service, which they accuse of stealing their livelihoods.
A taxi driver argues with a riot police officer standing guard during a demonstration at the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout on June 25 in Paris.
The violence follows weeks of escalating tension over the San Francisco-based firm's decision to continue offering its low-cost UberPop service despite an October law that bars companies from connecting passengers with unregistered drivers.
French taxi unions accuse UberPop of ignoring repeated court rulings and complain that police have turned a blind eye to the operation. The country's interior minister, Bernard Cazeneuve, said Thursday that the service must be shut down, citing the serious public order disturbances and development of this illegal activity.
The company has appealed the judgments and says it is waiting for a final decision from France's constitutional court, which began deliberating on the matter Tuesday.
Thomas Meister, an Uber spokesman, accused Cazeneuve of disregarding the legal process. The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is illegal or not, Meister told reporters.
Uber has faced repeated pushback from taxi operators and regulators as it has expanded into more than 300 cities across six continents. In an attempt to win over skeptical local authorities, the company has touted its potential to create jobs, reduce congestion and boost tax revenue.
A taxi driver holds a placard which reads, "Stop Uber, stop listening," during a protest in Paris.
Chief Executive Travis Kalanick made the case in January that many taxis in Europe operate off-grid and that Uber could be a way to bring them into compliance with local safety regulations and tax obligations.
The argument, however, does not appear to have swayed many European governments or taxi companies. More than a dozen lawsuits have been filed in recent months in countries across the continent, where some analysts say the company is in danger of being shut down or becoming so entangled in legislation as to be neutered.
In France, the battle is seen as the epitome of the culture clash between American free-market values and French economic protectionism.
They're very protectionist of their culture, their way of life, their way of doing things, said Hugh Tallents, a partner at the New York management consulting firm Cg42. It's not unheard of for unions to strike on a moment's notice or to retaliate against disruptive market forces.
Police officers stand next to a burned car during a taxi drivers demonstration in Paris.  French taxis are on strike around the country,  after weeks of rising tensions over Uber's ride-share service.
Tallents suggested that Uber might have to incorporate a little more cultural sensitivity into its operating model as it continues to expand.
Uber's strategy is one where they go in and take a very active approach.... They know their window for shoring up share and gaining riders and drivers is short because there are a lot of hungry competitors out there, he said. People will be looking at France as the poster child of how things can go wrong. I don't think this will necessarily derail Uber. But I think it could give them pause.
French taxi drivers complain that services such as Uber have an unfair advantage because their drivers don't pay for licenses that can cost up to $270,000. Some don't pay taxes and social charges, either, according to French officials. Cazeneuve berated Uber as a company that with arrogance applies none of the rules of law of the republic.
We are faced with permanent provocation, Serge Metz, the head of the taxi company G7, told French television. There can be only one response: a firm and systematic seizure of offending vehicles.
Travelers who were caught in the gridlock caused by anti-Uber protests walk along a freeway toward the Charles de Gaulle airport near Paris on June 25.
Uber counters that the taxi drivers are an outdated lobby fixed on defending their monopoly at the expense of customer needs. The company estimates that its smartphone app has about 400,000 French users a month.
Visitors to the French capital can testify to the frequent difficulty of finding a cab in Paris. French taxi drivers have also faced complaints of being resistant to change, including the use of credit cards and GPS technology.
An estimated 2,800 taxi drivers took part in Thursday's strike, setting up about 30 blockades across France, including on roads leading to Paris' Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports. Lines of travelers could be seen trudging along busy highways, dragging their luggage behind them, to catch flights and trains. Riot police fired tear gas to clear protesting drivers from the ring road around Paris.
There were reports in the French media of gangs of taxi drivers hunting down drivers they suspected of operating for Uber at the two airports and of attacks on some private-hire cars and even licensed taxis that were not taking part in the protests.
Among those caught up in the violence was actress-musician Courtney Love, whose ride was ambushed by anti-Uber protesters.
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
They're beating the cars with metal bats. This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad, she tweeted.
In another tweet, Love lambasted the French president: Francois Hollande where are the ... police??? is it legal for your people to attack visitors?
The singer was rescued by two men on a motorcycle but said she had been scared out of her wits.
In the eastern city of Strasbourg, there were reports of taxi drivers posing as Uber customers to lure drivers to isolated spots where they and their vehicles were attacked.
Meister, the Uber spokesman, described the attacks as totally scandalous and the actions of yobs.
It's a small minority of taxi drivers who are not doing their profession any favors, he said.
It is not unusual for French industrial action to turn violent. This week, striking workers at the MyFerryLink transportation company blocked access to the Channel Tunnel. Eurostar trains were canceled for the afternoon after the rail company said strikers had damaged sections of the track. Riot police were eventually called in to drag the protesters away as they sang the French national anthem, La Marseillaise.
In 1999, a French sheep farmer became a national hero when he led a group to dismantle a McDonald's restaurant that was being built in the south of France. Jose Bove was protesting against restrictions imposed by the Clinton administration on imported Roquefort cheese.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry's challenge as Iran talks resume: Avoid sharp turns</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-kerry-iran-talks-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Secretary of State John F. Kerry and his team are returning to international negotiations at a 19th century palace this weekend with a bounty of unsolicited advice on how they can wring a better nuclear agreement from Iran.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>1
The administration and the other world powers at the negotiating table agree with Corker that access to military bases is essential to any deal. But theyre not likely to get immediate access to sensitive Iranian sites.
The negotiators are planning to give Iran a number of days time to challenge any request from United Nations inspectors for access to an undeclared nuclear site.
On Wednesday, a group of respected former officials laid out in a letter their requirements for a nuclear deal. Their prescription was noteworthy because the group included former members of the administrations first-term inner circle on Iran -- Gary Samore, President Obamas former adviser on weapons of mass destruction; Robert Einhorn, former State Department nonproliferation chief; and Dennis Ross, former top administration advisor on the Middle East.
The groups negotiating advice tracked pretty closely with what the administration has been demanding. The former officials warned that they might not be able to support the deal if the administration caved at the last minute on key demands.
Interestingly, the groups strongest criticism of the administration was over President Obamas reluctance to do more with the U.S. military to halt the moves of Iranian forces and their armed proxies in the Middle East. The former officials said that to meet Irans threat fully, the administration needed to do more to train allied forces in Syria and Iraq, set up a safe haven in Syria, and stiffen resistance to Iranian arms shipment and harassment of commercial shipping in regional waters.
The American Israel Public Affairs Committee, the leading pro-Israel lobby, has laid out five requirements for a good deal. The agreement must authorize aggressive inspections; answer all questions about past nuclear research; lift sanctions only after Iran complies with obligations to scale back its program; restrain the nuclear program for decades; and dismantle Irans nuclear infrastructure, the group says.
The deal is sure to fall short of several of those goals. The six countries arent demanding dismantlement of excess Iranian centrifuges, for example; theyll be put in storage and monitored.
The six powers have given up hope of getting Iran to answer all the questions about its past nuclear research. Such a probe could take years, and still not answer all of the U.N.s questions about past nuclear work.
Iran would lose a lot if it acknowledged past research on nuclear devices, because that would puncture its claim that it has never sought the bomb.
So instead, the negotiators are bargaining over a specific list of steps Iran will be required to take, to try to answer some of the most important questions about past bomb research. Once Iran has completed those actions, the world powers will be willing to start lifting sanctions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As talks break down, European negotiators race to avoid a Greek tragedy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-talks-break-down-europe-greece-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Attempts to forge an agreement over Greece's troubled finances ended in failure Thursday, just five days before the Mediterranean country is due to make a loan repayment or risk going into default.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>As talks break down, European negotiators race to avoid a Greek tragedy
European leaders meet over Greek debt crisis in Brussels
Olivier Hoslet / European Pressphoto Agency
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, left, and Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a meeting of European leaders in Brussels on Thursday.
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, left, and Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a meeting of European leaders in Brussels on Thursday.
(Olivier Hoslet / European Pressphoto Agency)
Donald Tusk
Attempts to forge an agreement over Greeces troubled finances ended in failure Thursday, just five days before the Mediterranean country is due to make a loan repayment or risk going into default.
Finance ministers from the 19-nation Eurozone gathered in Brussels said they would meet again Saturday to try to bridge the glaring differences between Athens and its international creditors in order to stave off the threat of a bankruptcy that could force Greece to abandon the common euro currency.
Greece bailout
Daniel Ochoa de Olza / Associated Press
A woman holds her wallet in her mouth after buying some fruit at a market in central Athens on Thursday.
A woman holds her wallet in her mouth after buying some fruit at a market in central Athens on Thursday.
(Daniel Ochoa de Olza / Associated Press)
It will need still many hours. The last hours have been really critical, European Union President Donald Tusk said, adding: But I have a good hunch that, unlike in Sophocles' tragedies, this Greek story will have a happy end.
It was a rare note of optimism on a day marked by more of the acrimony  especially between Greece and Germany, the EUs biggest economy  that has made reaching a deal difficult.
8
An agreement is necessary to unlock the final installment of funds from two bailouts that Athens has received from international lenders totaling about $270 billion. Without it, Greece will be unable to repay $1.8 billion it owes the International Monetary Fund by Tuesday's deadline.
The two sides are at odds over how Greece plans to keep its budget in surplus so it can service its debt even as its economy languishes in a deep and damaging depression.
Hopes of a deal received a boost earlier this week after new proposals were put forward by Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras. Elected on an anti-austerity platform, Tsipras left-wing administration has pledged to hold the line on protecting pensions and public-sector wages, and has proposed raising more money through higher taxes, particularly on businesses.
Tsipras has also demanded some sort of debt relief or writedown, without which most economists say Greece will find it impossible to return to growth because of the staggering amount of public debt it must pay off.
But the creditor countries and institutions sent back Tsipras plan replete with corrections and objections written in red ink, saying that raising tax would hamper growth and insisting on more spending cuts.
cComments
@freedomguy Why would you want the EU to unravel? The entire idea behind it was that countries that do business with each other don't go to war with each other. The Common Market then the European Community and now the EU have kept the peace in Europe since WWII...
affableman
14
The Greek leader accused Eurozone negotiators of trying to humiliate his country, while senior German officials complained that Athens had taken a step backward.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel said Thursday that reaching an agreement was essential before the markets opened Monday and before Greek banks, operating on a lifeline from the European Central Bank, ran out of money. Worried depositors have pulled out billions of euros over the past several days in what analysts describe as, if not a full-on run, then at least a slow jog on the banks.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, who heads the group of 19 Eurozone finance ministers, said a fresh round of counterproposals arrived from Greece too late Thursday to be properly evaluated and voted on by European Union leaders gathering for a two-day summit.
On a number of issues there is still a wide gap with the Greek authorities, Dijsselbloem told reporters.
Down-to-the-wire negotiations with Greece have been the norm throughout the 5-year-old euro debt crisis, as both sides stake out maximalist positions and challenge each other to blink.
While this iteration might follow the same script, analysts warn that time is truly running short. Even if an agreement is reached among European leaders in Brussels, the deal will then be subject to approval by various national parliaments.
That includes both Germany and Greece itself, where Tsipras faces a potential revolt from backbenchers who believe he has already backtracked too much on their partys anti-austerity pledges. In Berlin, Merkel also must face down disgruntled lawmakers who feel Greece has gotten away with too much.
Follow @HenryHChu on Twitter for coverage of Europe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. sharply criticizes Iran's human rights record on eve of nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-rights-report-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  On the eve of talks to conclude a landmark nuclear deal with Iran, the Obama administration Thursday identified the Tehran government as one of the world's worst abusers of human rights.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. sharply criticizes Iran's human rights record on eve of nuclear talks
John Kerry
Cliff Owen / Associated Press
Secretary of State John F. Kerry leaves the lectern after presenting the State Department's annual human rights report in Washington. Kerry remains on crutches as he recovers from a bicycle accident.
Secretary of State John F. Kerry leaves the lectern after presenting the State Department's annual human rights report in Washington. Kerry remains on crutches as he recovers from a bicycle accident.
(Cliff Owen / Associated Press)
The Obama administration on Friday removed Cuba from the U.S. list of state sponsors of international terrorism, taking an important step toward the presidents goal of improving relations between the two longtime adversaries. ( Paul Richter )
In its annual report on human rights around the world, the State Department cited the theocratic government for depriving its citizens of a range of freedoms, including the right to choose their leaders through free elections. The report portrayed the Iranian justice system as harsh and arbitrary, particularly in cases involving the government's political opponents, and said senior officials do not punish officials who commit abuses.
Some of the most serious abuses in the past year grew from the governments disregard for the physical safety of citizens, whom authorities arbitrarily and unlawfully detained, tortured or killed, the report said.
Iran was among a handful of countries singled out by Secretary of State John F. Kerry in an introduction to the report. The department also criticized the rights records of Cuba, Myanmar and Vietnam, countries with which the administration is trying to improve relations.
8
Cubas government was cited for harassment of political opponents, a lack of free speech, intimidation and abusive detentions. The report also said that Russia has become increasingly authoritarian and has moved to deny free speech.
Many of the abuses alleged in the report had been catalogued by the State Department in past years reports. But this year's volume has had more visibility than normal because of the nuclear negotiations with Iran.
The report was supposed to have been released on Feb. 25. The adminstration's critics had charged that the State Department was delaying its release to avoid provoking Iran and possibly hurting prospects for a nuclear deal.
State Department officials have said the release was delayed because of the hectic travel schedule of the secretary, who customarily is present at the reports release to give it visibility.
Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas), a presidential hopeful, had proposed fining the State Department for further delays.
Yea they should be more like our friends in Egypt , Arabia , Israel , Columbia etc
Preci Gil
5
Without identifying him by name, the report cited the case of Washington Post reporter Jason Rezaian, a dual U.S.-Iranian citizen, who was imprisoned last July in Iran and is now on trial on unspecified charges. Rezaian has been denied legal representation and U.S. consular help and is at risk because of health problems and psychological stress, the report said.
The report said the Iranian government has severely restricted freedoms of assembly, speech, religion and the press.
It detailed a variety of abuses in the judicial system, including disappearances, judicially sanctioned amputations, and violence against political adversaries. Iran has the second-highest rate of executions in the world and often ignores guarantees of due process made in the countrys own constitution, the report charged.
The report also questioned the political legitimacy of Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who will make the ultimate decision on whether Iran accepts a nuclear deal.
Khamenei dominates key power structures, the report said, noting that while many Iranians take part in elections, an unelected body screens out candidates deemed unacceptable.
The report acknowledged that much of its information came second-hand, through private human rights advocacy groups, because the United States doesnt have diplomatic relations with Iran.
For more on U.S. foreign policy, follow @RichtPau
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea unveils new airport with shops, pharmacy and ... a chocolate fountain?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-north-korea-new-airport-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  North Korea has finished building an international airport terminal, state media reported Thursday, and photos show leader Kim Jong Un inspecting rather swanky amenities that include a jewelry store, a pharmacy and a coffee bar with - is that a chocolate fountain?
	</Description>
        <MainBody>North Korea unveils new airport with shops, pharmacy and ... a chocolate fountain?
New terminal of Pyongyang airport
Rodong Sinmun / EPA
An undated picture released by the Rodong Sinmun, the newspaper of the North Korea ruling Workers party, shows the newly built terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in North Korea.
An undated picture released by the Rodong Sinmun, the newspaper of the North Korea ruling Workers party, shows the newly built terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in North Korea.
(Rodong Sinmun / EPA)
Kim Jong Un
North Korea has finished building an international airport terminal, state media reported Thursday, and photos show leader Kim Jong Un inspecting rather swanky amenities that include a jewelry store, a pharmacy and a coffee bar withis that a chocolate fountain?
In a speech on cybersecurity, U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry on Monday singled out North Korea as a violator of Internet freedom and took the reclusive country to task for Novembers hacking attack on Sony Pictures. ( Steven Borowiec )
It was unclear what international assistance impoverished North Korea received for constructing the two-story terminal, or how much it cost. A 30-photo slide show published by the state-run Korean Central News Agency showed Kim touring the terminal with his wife and a group of about a dozen people. Numerous photos showed the entourage in various states of laughter.
The facility, which also has a new control tower, willopen July 1, the agency said. It replaces a terminal that dated to the 1950s and may be part of efforts by Kim to increase the countrys appeal to tourists and earn foreign currency.
Wait until they see that planes don't have propellers anymore!
drnuclear1
19
Since Kim took the helm of North Korea three years ago, he has opened a variety of tourist attractions, including a ski resort, and invited foreign celebrities such as Dennis Rodman to the country. Overseasrunners have been invited to participate in the Pyongyang marathon. But Kim also has periodically closed the country to visitors, most recently this spring, when borders were shut purportedly because of fears of Ebola.
Just a few airlines, including North Koreas state-run Air Koryo, and Air China, operate flights into Pyongyang. Most tourists are from China and Russia.
Kim praised the soldier-builders who worked on the terminal, the construction of which was a cherished wish of his father, the late leader Kim Jong Il, KCNA said. The Associated Press reported in October that laborers were constructing the terminal largely by hand or with simple tools, with patriotic music blaring from loudspeakers. Huge signs urged the workers to carry out their duties with Korea Speed, AP reported.
Photos of the facility showed at least 12 check-in counters; an immigration desk featuring modern, automated, glass entry gates; a clothing shop; a gift shop; a duty-free store; and several restaurants. There also was a newsstand stocked with what looked like magazines and North Korean flags. Travelers will have use of luggage carts.
The state-run news agency said a master plan called for construction of high-speed railways and motorway from the airport to the city center to ensure smooth traffic. North Korea is known for its paucity of buses, cars and other vehicles, not to mention a scarcity of fuel.
Accompanying Kim were senior officials, including Hwang Pyong So, considered to be North Koreas No. 2 official; Premier Pak Pong Ju; and Kim Yang Gon, director of the United Front Work Department. Kims wife, Ri Sol Ju, was also in attendance, wearing a seafoam green skirt suit.
Follow @JulieMakLAT for news fromAsia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State opens multi-pronged offensive in northern Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-islamic-state-syria-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Islamic State fighters on Thursday attacked Kobani, the Syrian town on the Turkish border they besieged for months before being repulsed in January by Kurdish militias assisted by punishing airstrikes from a U.S.-led coalition.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>2
Isso accused Turkey of being complicit in the attack on Kobani, charging that Islamic State fighters entered Kobani from Turkish territory. Turkish officials dismissed that claim, saying they possessed "concrete evidence that there was no crossing from the Turkish side," according to Agence France-Presse.
Last week, Kurdish-led forces routed Islamic State fighters who almost a year earlier had seized the border town of Tal Abyad. That offensive, backed by coalition airstrikes, cut off the Islamic State's main supply route to Raqqa, some 50 miles south. It also gave Kurdish forces an opportunity to consolidate two areas in northeastern Syria under their control, as well as opening up a corridor to Iraqi Kurdistan.
Elsewhere in Syria, 51 rebel factions operating in the southern province of Daraa announced a campaign to wrest control of areas of Daraa city from the government. SANA reported that an attack by terrorists -- the governments standard description of rebel factions -- had been thwarted, with fighter jets pounding rebel targets in surrounding villages.
The news agency also denied that the rebels had taken control of the strategic Daraa-Damascus road, one of two main highways linking southern Syria to Damascus, the capital and seat of power of President Bashar Assad.
The rebel operation, dubbed "Southern Storm," was spearheaded by factions associated with the Southern Front, a coalition of so-called moderate fighters. If successful, it would grant the rebels a rear supply base to mount operations on Damascus, a scant 59 miles north, as well as creating a contiguous zone of rebel control stretching from Kuneitra province, bordering the Israeli-held Golan Heights, to the outskirts of the Druze city of Suweida.
The Syrian Observatory put the death toll at 14 on the rebel side but did not give casualty figures for civilians or government forces.
The battle for Daraa city comes after a recent string of important gains for the Southern Front. Opposition activists claim the battlefield successes are the result of an intense three-month period of supply and armament for the coalition from a logistics hub located in the Jordanian capital Amman, staffed by operatives from a number of intelligence services, including the CIA.
Bulos is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Temperatures cool, but death toll tops 1,000 in Pakistani heat wave</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-death-toll-pakistan-heat-wave-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The toll from the sweltering heat wave in Pakistan's largest city continued to rise Thursday, surpassing more than 1,000 dead, according to state-run television, even as temperatures began to cool off.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Temperatures cool, but death toll tops 1,000 in Pakistani heat wave
Pakistan heat wave
Shahzaib Akber / European Pressphoto Agency
A tiger cools off with a large lump of ice at the Karachi Zoo, in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
A tiger cools off with a large lump of ice at the Karachi Zoo, in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
(Shahzaib Akber / European Pressphoto Agency)
By Aoun Sahi
Droughts and Heat Waves
The toll from the sweltering heat wave in Pakistan's largest city continued to rise Thursday, surpassing more than 1,000 dead, according to state-run television, even as temperatures began to cool off.
The high temperature in Karachi was 100 degrees Fahrenheit, closer to seasonal averages and several degrees cooler than earlier in the week, as a sea breeze blew over the port city, officials said. The temperature had reached 113 degrees Sunday.
Pakistan heat wave
Shakil Adil / Associated Press
A man covers his head with a wet towel to avoid heatstroke in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
A man covers his head with a wet towel to avoid heatstroke in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
(Shakil Adil / Associated Press)
"The temperature will remain normal in the coming days," said Ghulam Rasool, head of Pakistan's government meteorological office.
The number of victims arriving at hospitals in the southern port city slowed considerably, although 35 bodies were received at morgues operated by the Edhi Welfare Organization, said the group's spokesman, Anwar Kazmi.
It was the lowest number of bodies seen all week at the morgues, which received 750 heat stroke victims over the last five days, Kazmi said.
State-run broadcaster PTV put the death toll at over 1,000.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber protests turn violent in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-france-uber-protest-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  French taxi drivers overturned cars, burned tires and blocked access to airports and train stations in a second day of violent protest Thursday against competition from the ride-sharing service Uber.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>In another tweet, Love lambasted the French president: Francois Hollande where are the ... police??? is it legal for your people to attack visitors? Get your ass to the airport. Wtf???
The singer later added that she had been "scared out of her wits."
An estimated 2,800 taxi drivers took part in the strike, setting up around 30 roadblocks across France, including on roads leading to Paris' Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports. Some visitors had to walk between terminals and along busy roads to catch flights and trains.
There were reports in the French media of gangs of taxi drivers hunting down drivers they suspected of operating for Uber at the two airports and of attacks on some private-hire cars and even licensed taxis that were not taking part in the protests.
In the eastern city of Strasbourg, there were reports of taxi drivers posing as Uber customers to lure drivers to isolated spots where they and their vehicles were attacked. [Link in French]
Thomas Meister, an Uber spokesman, described the assaults as totally scandalous and the actions of yobs.
Its a small minority of taxi drivers who are not doing their profession any favors, he said.
France's interior minister, Bernard Cazeneuve, has called for a nationwide legal clampdown on UberPOP, citing the "serious public order disturbances and development of this illegal activity."
Meister accused the minister of disregarding the normal legal process.
"The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is illegal or not, Meister told French journalists.
In October, France passed a law banning any service that puts passengers in touch with unregistered drivers. Uber has contested the measure, saying it is counter to business freedom.
Willsher is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin manages to stabilize ruble, but Russian economy still staggers</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-russia-resilient-ruble-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Russia's ruble has been on a roller-coaster ride, posting the second-biggest drop in value of world currencies in 2014, then bouncing back this year with the highest rise against the dollar, euro, pound and yen.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin manages to stabilize ruble, but Russian economy still staggers
Russian economic woes
Ivan Sekretarev / Associated Press
Russia has delved deeply into its hard-currency trove, using up $150 billion to put an end to its currencys roller-coaster ride. Above, an exchange office in Moscow in December.
Russia has delved deeply into its hard-currency trove, using up $150 billion to put an end to its currencys roller-coaster ride. Above, an exchange office in Moscow in December.
(Ivan Sekretarev / Associated Press)
European Union
Russia's ruble has been on a roller-coaster ride, posting the second-biggest drop in value of world currencies in 2014, then bouncing back this year with the highest rise against the dollar, euro, pound and yen.
The ruble's dizzying comeback, though, is due neither to an economic boom nor to sustainable intervention by the Russian Central Bank. And it came at a steep price.
Steadying the ruble at about 50 to the dollar has drained the country's hard-currency trove of $150 billion, more than a quarter of the reserves on hand at the end of 2013. Those cash infusions have done little to cheer Russian consumers or businesses: Inflation remains at more than 16% and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development predicts that the overall economy will shrink by 4.5% this year.
People know not to blame Putin. They know it is all the fault of Obama and the Ukrainian fascists that they have to suffer economically to confront these evil people. - Sergei Guriev, former rector of Moscow's New Economic School, mocking the prevailing sentiment
And stabilizing the ruble was achieved only after President Vladimir Putin shook down Russia's oligarchs for what he considered their fair share toward arresting the currency's tumble, a tactic unavailable to the stewards of a free-market democracy.
"There is no strategy and no vision. It's all 'live for today,'" said economist Sergei Guriev, a former rector of Moscow's New Economic School living in self-imposed exile in Paris.
Russia's disappearing middle class and the working poor are paying the price for the Kremlin's economic fiddling, Guriev said. He points to an average 10% drop in real income last year, a jump in mortgage defaults and rising food and utility prices.
A $500-billion, decade-long military modernization program augurs even grimmer years to come.
Car sales in Russia dropped 42% in April from the same month last year, the Assn. of European Businesses reported last month. The share of Russians who can afford no more than the absolute necessities has soared to 20%, the highest since polling on the subject began a decade ago, the Nielsen research firm reported last month.
8
Even during the 2009 recession, the report noted, only 7% of respondents said they could afford nothing more than food and shelter.
"But people know not to blame Putin. They know it is all the fault of Obama and the Ukrainian fascists that they have to suffer economically to confront these evil people," Guriev said, mocking the prevailing public attitude molded by a lavishly funded propaganda campaign on state-run television.
"In Russia we say that there's the television and there's the fridge," said the economist, who until last year was part of the Kremlin's financial inner circle. "People believe what they see on television, but when they don't see anything in the fridge they stop believing. If the government doesn't have the cash it needs and sees that its propaganda is no longer convincing, it may embark on a new military adventure to make people believe again."
The economy was ticking along with healthy growth in most recent years until Russian troops seized Ukraine's Crimea region in 2014. The United States and the European Union imposed sanctions on Moscow for its violation of international law and its neighbor's sovereignty.
Those measures, which cut off international lending and blacklisted dozens of Kremlin kingpins, have coincided with the decline of world oil prices to half their value of a year ago. And in spite of repeated pledges by Putin to diversify the economy since he first took office in 2000, Russia remained dependent on oil and gas sales for more than half of its income when the latest financial crisis hit.
cComments
@donchjohn Yes Poreshenko was installed by the popular vote of the Ukrainians. The previous president for 9 months was not put in by the US but was elected by the Parliament of the Ukraine to be speaker of the parliament in this position he was the next in charge when the previous president...
angelabirch
11
The government in April revised its 2016 budget to take into consideration the decline in expected energy revenue, which originally had been calculated at $100 a barrel for oil. The deficit spending now envisioned for next year will eat up an additional $200 billion from the hard-currency reserves, and more if the military modernization project continues to be exempt from the budget cuts forced on almost every other economic sector.
Putin has micromanaged the financial crisis in much the same away as he has guided the country's geopolitical strategy. He summoned his nation's captains of industry to the Kremlin for an emergency session Dec. 16, when the ruble was trading at 80 to the dollar. According to the RBK business journal, he told them that the ruble's collapse threatened their welfare as well as that of the country and that they had an obligation to repatriate the money they had stashed in foreign banks.
There was no official edict issued, and the journal observed that the Kremlin has limited means of controlling how oligarchs or ordinary citizens handle their finances.
Putin did declare a "capital amnesty" after the December meeting, and the State Duma, the lower house of the parliament, has been struggling since then to draft legislation aimed at assuring offshore depositors that repatriating their capital won't lead to investigations of whether they came by it legally. A history of nationalizations, corruption and asset seizures has undermined faith in the security of Russia-based wealth, explaining the flight of more than $150 billion in capital last year alone.
But lost on none of the oligarchs was the unspoken threat of reprisals if they failed to do their part to halt the ruble's free-fall. Memories were still fresh of the September house arrest of oil magnate Vladimir Yevtushenkov and seizure of his assets, not to mention the 10 years that former billionaire Mikhail Khodorkovsky spent in prison for challenging Putin's political domination.
The billionaire owners of Lukoil, Severstal, Norilsk Nickel and three dozen other major enterprises had converted enough of their hard-currency holdings by late February to boost the ruble's value to about 60 to the dollar. Igor Sechin, head of the oil monopoly Rosneft, told the Tass news agency that he had sold $93 billion for rubles in 2014.
The winter run on the ruble was triggered by the converging effects of sanctions and the nadir in oil prices that flirted with $45 a barrel in December. Oil has lately traded for about $60 a barrel.
Putin has brushed off sanctions as little more than an irritant and banned European food imports in retaliation. He has ordered major importers to buy Russian-made goods to replace the components they used to get from Western manufacturers, though domestic production can't ramp up to meet the new demand when the scant credit available from Russian banks comes with double-digit interest rates.
As national coffers emptied late last year, Putin ordered 10% across-the-board cuts in government-funded services for regions and municipalities, with only pensions and the ambitious defense overhaul spared the budget ax.
Government economists have revealed little about the brainstorming that goes on behind the Kremlin's closed doors or their own candid views on Putin's handling of the crisis. But academics and independent economists willing to comment from their lofty remove see little to suggest that the current problems will be short-lived.
"There is nothing good" in the mid- or long-term forecast, concluded Alexander Savelyev, a senior scholar at the Russian Academy of Sciences' Institute of World Economy and International Relations. "And the majority of experts expect further decline."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-indians-mock-jindal-candidacy-20150625-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir. It probably wasn't the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted. Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindal's campaign kickoff...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy
Bobby Jindal
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
(Gerald Herbert / Associated Press)
As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir.
It probably wasnt the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted.
Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindals campaign kickoff announcement, particularly for the 44-year-old Republicans line that he was tanned, rested and ready to run. It was widely seen as an attempt to play down his skin color to appeal to conservative voters, and fit with what Jindals critics say is a longstanding effort to disassociate himself from his Indian heritage.
The Twitter hashtag #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite trended in India for several hours.
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite that he couldn't win a spelling bee if he tried.
 VeeGee Narendra (@VeGeEn) June 25, 2015
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite he's never been randomly selected at the airport
 Misha Choudhry (@MishaChoudhry) June 25, 2015
Some of Indias leading newspapers ran front-page mentions of Jindals announcement, although the coverage was less than effusive. Lalit K. Jha, longtime Washington correspondent for the Press Trust of India, wrote in a news report that Jindals announcement has failed to generate much enthusiasm among the Indian-Americans because of his recent statements in which he sought to distance himself from being an Indian-American.
Jindal was born in Louisiana in 1971 to Indian immigrants from the northern state of Punjab. As a child he changed his birth name, Piyush, to Bobby after the character from The Brady Bunch. Raised by devout Hindus, he converted to Catholicism as a teenager and says his faith inspires his conservative principles, including a staunch opposition to same-sex marriage.
Jindal invoked his parents at the start of his kickoff speech Wednesday but used the word India only once: in his oft-repeated accusation that Democrats were dividing the country along ethnic, gender and class lines.We are not Indian Americans, Irish Americans, African Americans, rich Americans or poor Americans, he said. We are all Americans.
Jindal enters the Republican presidential race near the bottom of the pack and has failed to inspire much support from U.S. voters of Indian origin, most of whom lean Democratic.
Bobby has never supported a single Indian issue, he refused to join the India Caucus when he was a congressman [on] Capitol Hill and is conspicuously absent from any event with a visiting Indian leader, Shashi Tharoor, an Indian politician and author, wrote in a recent book, India Shastra.
It is as if he wants to forget he is Indian, and would like voters to forget it too.
Jindal is an object of fascination for a rising Indian middle class that assiduously tracks their countrys stature in the world. When Prime Minister Narendra Modi led scores of countries in marking the first International Day of Yoga last weekend, many Indians beamed with pride.
But they are less charitable when it comes to Indians abroad who are seen to betray their heritage. Preet Bharara, the U.S. attorney in Manhattan, has received less than favorable press coverage for the perception that he has targeted Wall Street executives with South Asian roots, such as Sri Lankan-born hedge fund billionaire Raj Rajaratnam, for prosecution of financial crimes.
Young Indians flooded social media sites with sarcastic comments when Jindal unveiled his official governors portrait earlier this year because his skin looked shockingly white. A photo his office tweeted this week of his family playing Monopoly inspired mockery because his young children had their shoes on inside the house, a cultural no-no here.
 Gov. Bobby Jindal (@BobbyJindal) June 23, 2015
Mihir Sharma, a columnist for the Business Standard newspaper, accused Indian Americans of a tendency to turn viciously on those they see as less Indian. But even he balanced his words with a critique of the candidate.
Typical: smug Indians trying to shame Bobby Jindal for his choices on identity, and not his awful politics, Sharma tweeted.
cComments
Wow, well I guess it's showtime for the republicans with the "minorities" they have running. Ann Coulter on Fox said this "Id really like to like Nikki Haley, since she is a Republican. On the other hand, she is an immigrant and does not understand America's...
KING JAMES - 1
at 1:46 AM June 26, 2015
There are three groups that make up the majority of the GOP: 1. Religious Right (American Taliban) 2. Social Conservatives (Amer i-Qaeda) 3. Corporatists (American Oligarchs) The Religious Right and Social Conservatives are the primary voting blocks in terms of boots on the ground and voting....
KING JAMES - 1
at 1:44 AM June 26, 2015
@montanoso , exactly......it's funny....and they hear his rhetoric and are insulted..
KING JAMES - 1
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistani activists risk death in speaking out against religious extremism</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pakistan-progressives-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Pin-drop silence followed as social activist Jibran Nasir, 28, screened a documentary on sectarian and religious violence in Pakistan. Nasir, who was on a six-week speaking tour of the United States, is among the few outspoken voices in Pakistan when it comes to religious extremism.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistani activists risk death in speaking out against religious extremism
Pakistanis protest activist's slaying
Rizwan Tabassum / AFP/Getty Images
Activists gather in Karachi, Pakistan, in April to protest the slaying of rights advocate Sabeen Mahmud. She was slain after she left a Karachi meeting about missing people in Baluchistan.
Activists gather in Karachi, Pakistan, in April to protest the slaying of rights advocate Sabeen Mahmud. She was slain after she left a Karachi meeting about missing people in Baluchistan. (Rizwan Tabassum / AFP/Getty Images)
By Saher Baloch
Human Rights Watch
Pin-drop silence followed as social activist Jibran Nasir, 28, screened a documentary on sectarian and religious violence in Pakistan. Nasir, who was on a six-week speaking tour of the United States, is among the few outspoken voices in Pakistan when it comes to religious extremism.
But the overall situation appears bleak. A few hours after Nasir's talk last month at Pomona College on sectarianism and apathy, 45 members of a subsect of Karachi's Shiite Muslim community were killed in an attack by Sunni Muslim militants.
Pakistan activist Jibran Nasir
Irfan Khan / Los Angeles Times
Social activist Jibran Nasir, one of the few outspoken voices on religious extremism in Pakistan, gave a talk in May at Pomona College on sectarianism and apathy in his home country.
Social activist Jibran Nasir, one of the few outspoken voices on religious extremism in Pakistan, gave a talk in May at Pomona College on sectarianism and apathy in his home country. (Irfan Khan / Los Angeles Times)
In recent weeks, a string of slayings in Karachi and beyond has presented a grim picture for minorities in Sunni-dominated Pakistan, as well as for Pakistani human rights activists and others who speak out against injustices.
In late April, activist Sabeen Mahmud, 40, was struck and killed by four bullets after she left a Karachi meeting on missing people in Baluchistan, the strife-torn, mineral-rich province in western Pakistan. The session, titled "Unsilencing Baluchistan: Take 2," had been scheduled to be held earlier in the month at the prestigious Lahore University of Management Sciences but was called off, reportedly after pressure from the government. Sabeen, who agreed to hold it instead at her Second Floor forum, was killed.
8
Several days later, a professor in the Mass Communications Department at Karachi University, Syed Waheed-ur-Rehman, was gunned down. His slaying remains unsolved.
Meanwhile, a senior educator and member of the government advisory board for textbooks and curriculum in Karachi, Bernadette L. Dean, fled Pakistan after receiving death threats from people she has referred to as "members of a political party."
"We must give credit to people in Pakistan who are still willing to stand up and be counted," said Ali Dayan Hasan, former director of Human Rights Watch in Islamabad, the capital. "But we must not overestimate their numbers or underestimate the risk to their lives. They are still a beleaguered and besieged minority."
In an article he wrote in Guernica magazine in April 2014 after his friend and journalist Raza Rumi survived an attack in Lahore, he referred to the term "liberal extremist." It is a title given to those who publicly condemn prejudice and abuse or are touted as "Western agents," said Hasan, now a fellow at the United States Institute of Peace in Washington.
"But I have an aversion to this term liberal or progressive," he said in a phone interview with the Los Angeles Times. "Because these are the universal values of tolerance and pluralism that are under attack. These values are not and should not be limited to a particular group of people to speak for."
@AndrewWiggin you found a way to lump a whole other group of people with a one word description too... good for you!
Sully Isdaman
2
"Pakistan  and the cities, in particular  are becoming increasingly dangerous for liberal thought," said Zohra Yusuf, chairwoman of the Human Rights Commission of Pakistan. "The intelligentsia is being targeted. The space is shrinking for liberal thinking while those propagating hatred towards minority communities carry on their campaigns unchecked. There is no clear policy on banned or militant outfits and the government is still reluctant to register madrassas or put any pressure on them."
Authorities recently arrested four highly educated Pakistani men who they said were responsible for several targeted killings in Karachi. The assailants, the authorities said, had all graduated from college, with degrees in engineering, business and Islamic studies.
The announcement drew suspicion from some quarters that the arrests had been made hastily because of mounting pressure. Previously, officials had blamed the spate of killings on "interference by rival states, particularly the Indian intelligence agency, RAW."
"There might be perhaps some truth to this fact," Hasan said. "But it does not take away from the fact that the state persistently fails to protect its citizens. If the state doesn't wish to be seen as a failed one, it must ensure security."
The arrests were also met with shock in some quarters, that well-educated, tech-savvy young adults would turn to a life of militancy.
After showing the video and concluding his talk, Nasir was asked by a member of the audience in Claremont: "What are you doing for your security and how should we help you?"
Nasir responded that he doesn't believe in personal security. He appeared frustrated by a similar question during an informal discussion later at the home of one of the event's organizers.
"That's the problem," he said. "Don't help me. Just be there when something happens and be counted. It's as simple as that."
Baloch, a reporter from Pakistan, is a visiting journalist at The Times sponsored by the Daniel Pearl Foundation in partnership with the Alfred Friendly Press Fellowships.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 06:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombian army's top leadership not facing justice in killings, report says</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-colombia-killings-human-rights-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Twenty-five-year-old street vendor Mauricio Duarte Guzman went out to play billiards one night in his rural Colombian home town of Gigante and never came home. His mother found him dead the next day in an army morgue, tagged by the local brigade as a rebel killed in combat.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Colombian army's top leadership not facing justice in killings, report says
Colombian officials at a military ceremony
Mauricio Dueas Castaeda / EPA
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos, right, and new Defense Minister Luis Carlos Villegas review army troops during a military ceremony in Bogota. A newreport indicates that top Colombian army brass knew or should have known about the extrajudicial killingsof hundreds of civilianslabeled as rebels.
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos, right, and new Defense Minister Luis Carlos Villegas review army troops during a military ceremony in Bogota. A newreport indicates that top Colombian army brass knew or should have known about the extrajudicial killingsof hundreds of civilianslabeled as rebels.
(Mauricio Dueas Castaeda / EPA)
Human Rights Watch
Twenty-five-year-old street vendor Mauricio Duarte Guzman went out to play billiards one night in his rural Colombian home town of Gigante and never came home. His mother found him dead the next day in an army morgue, tagged by the local brigade as a rebel killed in combat.
Guzmans mother, Hilda Guzman, said her son was one of several people from her town in southern Huila province who disappeared in 2007 during a wave of so-called false positive slayings. The cases involved unemployed, handicapped and otherwise disadvantaged youths across the country who were allegedly kidnapped and killed by military units and then identified as leftist guerrillas to inflate body counts.
Human Rights Watch report on Colombia killings
Leonardo Munoz / EPA
Jose Miguel Vivanco, director of Human Rights Watch for the Americas, speaks in Bogota, Colombia, during the presentation of a report on civilian killings.


Jose Miguel Vivanco, director of Human Rights Watch for the Americas, speaks in Bogota, Colombia, during the presentation of a report on civilian killings.


(Leonardo Munoz / EPA)
He was a good, healthy boy who had nothing to do with the rebels, and he was despicably murdered, Hilda Guzman said in an interview. Eight years later, I havent forgotten him, and I am still waiting for justice. The government has yet to pay me reparations.
Cases such as Guzmans are not rare, activists say. A report issued Wednesday by Human Rights Watch accused the Colombian military of widespread and systematic extrajudicial killings of hundreds of civilians between 2002 and 2008, when the armed forces progress in the nation's decades-long war was measured largely by the number of rebels killed in action.
While Colombias false positive atrocities have been known about for years, the HRW report said it has obtained previously unpublished prosecutorial evidence indicating that top Colombian army brass knew or should have known about the extrajudicial killings and that they should face criminal charges. Among those implicated is armed forces commander army Gen. Juan Pablo Rodriguez Barragan, the report said.
8
False positive killings amount to one of the worst mass atrocities in the Western Hemisphere in recent years, and there is mounting evidence that many senior army officers bear responsibility, said Jose Miguel Vivanco, HRWs Americas executive director. Yet the army officials in charge at the time of the killings have escaped justice and even ascended to the top of the military command.
Army representatives have denied special treatment for top-level officers, saying that 900 cases have been brought before various courts. The Colombian attorney generals office is known to have investigated at least 3,700 cases of extrajudicial killings.
El Tiempo newspaper of Bogota reported Wednesday that four generals, including former army commander Gen. Mario Montoya, have been called to testify by a special prosecutor appointed by the Supreme Court in connection with reportedfalse positives.
Citing overwhelming caseloads, the HRW report criticized the slow pace of justice, saying that so far, mostly lower ranking soldiers have been convicted. Vivanco called on the Colombian government to add prosecutors to pursue charges more aggressively against unit commanders, claiming that only a handful of colonels and no generals have been convicted.
Ramiro Orjuela, a Bogota-based human rights attorney who helped research the HRW report, said the slow pace of prosecutions of army leadership is because ofa lack of political will. ... This is a very precise demonstration of how the attorney generals office remains fearful of the army leadership, who are extremely powerful. Potential witnesses in these cases have been threatened and even killed.
cComments
Hey leave them along , this is our puppet government that we are loading up with money and military equipment , we will even be stablishing a nuke sub base there, to help us control the Latin Americas, and desstablelize countries like Venezuela , if they do give our oil barons. 30yrs oil...
Preci Gil
1
HRW also called on the U.S. government to review its military and anti-terrorism aid program that under Plan Colombia has totaled more than $9 billion since 2000. U.S. officials should enforce the Leahy Law passed by Congress in 1996, which calls on the government to withhold military aid to units suspected of human rights crimes, HRWs report said.
The report confirms past studies, including a groundbreaking 2008 report by the International Observation Mission on Extrajudicial Executions and Impunity in Colombia, a joint effort by 13 international human rights experts that helped bring the false positive atrocities to light.
This (HRW) report confirms what we all knew: that responsibility for the extrajudicial execution scandal in Colombia reaches top leadership, said Lisa Haugaard of the Washington-based Latin America Working Group think tank. To help complete the 2008 study, Haugaard said she interviewed witnesses and family members linked to 130 deaths.
What we heard was shockingly similar: groups of soldiers detaining poor young men taken in civilian clothes, who were later found dead in army morgues dressed in guerrilla uniforms, Haugaard said.
A preliminary version of the 2008 report was released prior to a mass killing that broke the false positives scandal wide open. That case involved 26 young men from a poor Bogota suburb who were promised work in North Santander province, but who instead were slain and claimed as rebel fighters killed in action.
Last year, an extensive report by the New Yorkbased peace advocacy group Fellowship of Reconciliation, or FOR, also linked false positive killings to specific Colombian army units and commanders who had received training at the U.S. Armys Ft. Benning and other installations.
John Lindsay-Poland, a former FOR official who managed the study and is now with the American Friends Service Committee, said the FOR and HRW studies are especially relevant because the U.S. government is using Colombian officers to train foreign militaries in Central America and the Middle East.
The findings of FOR and HRW show that Colombian military leadership is not a model that should be exported, and the U.S. training of these officers should be evaluated for its impact on human rights abuses, Lindsay-Poland said.
The accusations against Colombian military brass arealso relevant, Lindsay-Poland said, because of the peace negotiations underway in Havana between the Colombian government and Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, or FARC,rebels that aim to end the long-running conflict.
The peace talks are stuck on transitional justice issues, including whether rebel or military commanders will face trials and possible prison time for crimes against humanity. Both Vivanco and Lindsay-Poland warn that terms of any peace deal should not include impunity for army officials convicted of criminal involvement in false positives.
Kraul is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France denounces U.S. spying exposed by WikiLeaks</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-france-hollande-wikileaks-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  French President Francois Hollande held a crisis meeting of the country's Defense Council on Wednesday after newspapers published WikiLeaks documents showing that the United States eavesdropped on him and two predecessors.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>France denounces U.S. spying exposed by WikiLeaks
French President Francois Hollande
Michel Euler / Associated Press
The Defense Council of French President Francois Hollande, shown this week at a European Union summit in Brussels, convened an emergency meeting on June 23.
The Defense Council of French President Francois Hollande, shown this week at a European Union summit in Brussels, convened an emergency meeting on June 23.
(Michel Euler / Associated Press)
European Debt Crisis
French President Francois Hollande held a crisis meeting of the country's Defense Council on Wednesday after newspapers published WikiLeaks documents showing that the United States eavesdropped on him and two predecessors.
After the meeting, the council issued a statement lambasting U.S. spying as unacceptable and declaring that France had demanded two years ago that the National Security Agency stop snooping on its leaders.
Hollande spoke to President Obama on Wednesday afternoon as lawmakers across the political spectrum insisted the French president demand a formal apology. After the telephone conversation, the Elysee Palace issued a statement saying Obama had reiterated a firm pledge made two years ago, after allegations of U.S. spying on French officials first emerged, that the practice had been halted.
France: Spying on allies 'unacceptable'
France has summoned the U.S. ambassador to explain allegations by the group WikiLeaks that the U.S. has been spying on French presidents.
France has summoned the U.S. ambassador to explain allegations by the group WikiLeaks that the U.S. has been spying on French presidents.
See more videos
A White House statement said Obama had reiterated that we are not targeting and will not target the communications of the French president. The statement made no admission of prior spying, nor ruled out intelligence-gathering efforts on the French more broadly.
We are committed to our productive and indispensable intelligence relationship with France, which allows us to make progress against shared threats, including international terrorism and proliferation, among others, the White House said.
The president feted Hollande during a 2014 state visit to Washington, and the two leaders emphasized their deepening ties.
The latest WikiLeaks revelations, first published in the daily newspaper Liberation and the investigative news website Mediapart, allege that the NSA eavesdropped on telephone conversations of former Presidents Jacques Chirac and Nicolas Sarkozy as well as Hollande.
WikiLeaks spokesman Kristinn Hrafnsson said he was confident the documents were authentic, the Associated Press reported.
8
Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius summoned the American ambassador to Paris, Jane Hartley, to his office Wednesday evening to demand an explanation over the spying claims, which sparked indignation and anger in France.
These are unacceptable facts that have already been the subject of clarification between the U.S. and France, notably at the end of 2013 when the first revelations were made and during a state visit by the president of the republic to the United States in February 2014, read the Defense Council statement.
Promises were made by the American authorities. They must remember and strictly respect them. France, which has reinforced its control and protection measures, will not tolerate any scheming that threatens its security and the protection of its interests, it read.
In 2013, documents released by NSA leaker Edward Snowden showed that the United States had intercepted about 70 million pieces of data on French telecommunications. Snowden also revealed that the U.S. had been monitoring the cellphone communications of German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
After the Merkel disclosures, Obama ordered a review of NSA spying on allies. Afterward, U.S. officials said Obama had ordered a halt to surveillance of the leaders of allied countries and their aides.
The WikiLeaks website listed the contents of what it called Espionnage Elysee (Elysee Spying), a collection of top secret intelligence reports and technical data from five major intercepts of communications involving high level officials from successive French governments over the last 10 years, including the three presidents.
Enter Europe's excuse to spy on their OWN people under the guise of the US spying.
trutherluther
86
Transcripts of eavesdropping on telephone conversations and emails covered subjects including a top United Nations appointment, the Middle East peace process and the handling of the Greek debt crisis as well as the leadership and future of the European Union.
One document reportedly shows phone numbers listed by the NSA as top French official intercept targets, including that of the president's cellphone, with some digits crossed out. Other senior officials, including the Elysee secretary general, the Foreign Ministry spokesman, the presidential advisor for Africa and the secretary of state for trade, also had their conversations recorded, according to the leaked documents.
A purported intelligence report from March 2010 follows an intercepted communication from Sarkozy expressing his frustration with U.S. spying on France.
In another, from 2008, Sarkozy reportedly talks about the global economic crisis. The president blamed many of the current economic problems on mistakes made by the U.S. government, but believes that Washington is now heeding some of his advice, the document says.
In the National Assembly on Wednesday, Prime Minister Manuel Valls repeated that the United States systematic and continued spying on the leaders of foreign countries was not legitimate, not acceptable and not normal.
This information is extremely serious, Valls told lawmakers. It's not legitimate in the name of national interests to carry out eavesdropping  and, no, France does not spy on its European partners or its allies.
France will not tolerate any scheming that threatens its security and fundamental interest, Valls added. He said the U.S. now had to make an effort to repair the damage caused by the revelations.
U.S. National Security Council spokesman Ned Price said in a statement that the American government would not comment on the specifics of the leak.
As a general matter, we do not conduct any foreign intelligence surveillance activities unless there is a specific and validated national security purpose. This applies to ordinary citizens and world leaders alike, he said.
French government spokesman Stephane Le Foll said a senior French intelligence official was being sent to the United States for talks with his counterparts.
The WikiLeaks revelations came just hours before members of Parliament were expected to approve a bill giving the French intelligence services sweeping new powers to snoop on their own people. Critics have said the law would be a threat to individual liberties, but the government argues the measures are necessary after the January attacks in Paris by Islamist extremists.
Willsher is a special correspondent. Times staff writer Michael A. Memoli in Washington contributed to this report.
ALSO:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 22:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia and the West rattle sabers and renew sanctions</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-russia-west-cold-war-rhetoric-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Though Russian and Western officials repeatedly claim they don't want a return to Cold War-era hostility, both sides have renewed sanctions and toughened their military posture in recent days.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia and the West rattle sabers and renew sanctions
Vladimir Putin
Sergei Karpukhin / European Pressphoto Agency
Russian President Vladimir Putin, with Kremlin Chief of Staff Sergei Ivanov at his left, speaks during a June 24 Kremlin meeting at which he a decree extending a ban on food imports from the European Union.
Russian President Vladimir Putin, with Kremlin Chief of Staff Sergei Ivanov at his left, speaks during a June 24 Kremlin meeting at which he a decree extending a ban on food imports from the European Union.
(Sergei Karpukhin / European Pressphoto Agency)
Ukraine Crisis (2013-2014)
Though Russian and Western officials repeatedly claim they don't want a return to Cold War-era hostility, both sides have renewed sanctions and toughened their military posture in recent days.
Russian President Vladimir Putin on Wednesday extended for an additional year his country's ban on most food imports from the European Union, two days after the 28-nation Western bloc announced that its sanctions on Russia will be prolonged to the end of January 2016.
The tit-for-tat embargoes -- which hurt the countries imposing them as well as those targeted -- show the intractability of the conflict in Ukraine that prompted the measures last year.
Ben Hodges
Maciej Kulczynski / European Pressphoto Agency
Lt. Gen. Ben Hodges, commander of U.S. forces in Europe, speaks at a transatlantic defense meeting in Wroclaw, Poland, on June 12.
Lt. Gen. Ben Hodges, commander of U.S. forces in Europe, speaks at a transatlantic defense meeting in Wroclaw, Poland, on June 12.
(Maciej Kulczynski / European Pressphoto Agency)
The EU and the United States cut off Russian access to international financial institutions nearly a year ago and have blacklisted dozens of Kremlin officials and business kingpins seen as fomenting the violence in eastern Ukraine that has killed more than 6,400 people.
The European and U.S. sanctions on Russia have been renewed as the Western allies try to pressure Putin to refrain from supporting separatist rebels in the neighboring country that, like Russia, was part of the Soviet Union before its 1991 breakup.
Putin claims the pro-Russia separatists are independently waging war against the Kiev government but Western satellite imagery and the confessions of captured Russian soldiers bolster Ukrainian leaders' accusations that Moscow is orchestrating the rebellion.
8
"Russia is actively and massively fueling this conflict, Lt. Gen. Ben Hodges, the commander of U.S. forces in Europe, told the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe on Tuesday, according to excerpts of his briefing released Wednesday. Disputing Putin's claim that any Russians in the Ukraine battle are there at their own volition, Hodges said "these are not volunteers or mercenaries; they are trained, equipped and uniformed active-duty Russian soldiers.
Hodges' briefing to the Vienna-based European security agency coincided with a meeting of the foreign ministers of Russia, Ukraine, France and Germany in Paris in an apparently unsuccessful attempt to rescue the Feb. 12 peace plan hammered out in the Belarus capital of Minsk but repeatedly violated in recent weeks.
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov told reporters that the four top diplomats committed their countries to ensuring that the Minsk accord doesn't completely collapse. But he alluded to "powers who would like to destroy this process," an apparent reference to the United States, which is not party to the informal negotiating forum known as the Normandy Four.
Urban combat and artillery exchanges ebbed after the Minsk agreement was signed four months ago by Ukraine's warring factions and endorsed by Putin, who pledged to use his influence with the separatists to end the bloodshed. But the lull in heavy fighting was mostly due to harsh winter weather and the seas of mud that followed in early spring, as artillery exchanges escalated after the mud dried last month and tanks and armored vehicles could maneuver again.
European leaders endorsed their sanctions extension on Monday after concluding that Putin hadn't done enough to fulfill his pledge to work for peace in Ukraine.
USA and Russia. so self righteous that we each boast the need to engulf human race in potential threat of nuclear war, again. inflated national egos.wars r' us.
cynicalretiree
3
The Russian government sent a request to Putin on Tuesday to prolong Moscow's ban on food imports from European Union countries, going the Western bloc one better by extending the retaliatory ban through June 24, 2016.
Russia and the U.S.-led North Atlantic Treaty Organization have also stepped up arms production and deployment in moves each side claims were prompted by the other's aggressive actions. Putin announced last week that at least 40 new nuclear-armed intercontinental ballistic missiles will be added to Russia's defenses by the end of this year, and NATO plans to position new forces and weaponry in Eastern European allies' territory to guard against any threat of Russian hostility.
U.S. Defense Secretary Ashton Carter, on a tour of NATO's Eastern European flank this week, has said that tanks, armored vehicles and other military hardware would be deployed to member countries made nervous by Russia's involvement in the Ukraine crisis. Carter said the equipment would be moved to Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania and Bulgaria -- all former Soviet republics or satellites that Moscow still considers part of its "sphere of influence."
Russia had been diplomatically courting some EU states in recent months in apparent hopes of getting one of them to break ranks on the sanctions extension, as all 28 member states have to agree on such matters.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was in Russia last week to meet with Putin and left with a $2.77-billion deal to build and operate part of a planned Russian pipeline project. The pipeline is intended to bypass Ukraine and deliver natural gas to Western European customers.
A senior Russian lawmaker, Federation Council President Valentina Matviyenko, told the Tass news agency that special consideration should be given to European Union countries that have "actively opposed the policy of sanctions." She named Greece, Hungary and Cyprus as examples of states with which Russia should resume normal trade, although all three ultimately did vote to extend sanctions.
Russian Agriculture Minister Alexander Tkachev, however, hailed the cutoff of European food imports as a stimulus for Russia's own farm output.
"We are grateful to our European and American colleagues who made us take a fresh look at agriculture, forced us to find our potential," he said Wednesday, according to Tass.
"Against sanctions the agriculture sector has a tendency to grow. Weve learned not only to survive, but to work in this situation," Tkachev said. "If our Western partners believe that the sanctions set us back many years, they are deeply mistaken."
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 20:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama to families of hostages held by terrorists: 'We will stand by you'</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-hostage-policy-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  President Obama said Wednesday the U.S. government has at times failed the families of Americans held hostage overseas by communicating poorly or failing to coordinate recovery efforts, but he promised Wednesday that "that ends today" with a set of new policies.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>3
Some family members are concerned about other components of the new policy. In particular, some are skeptical of the idea of keeping the FBI in charge of a process that they feel has let them down.
The wife of Warren Weinstein, a government contractor killed in a U.S. drone strike againsthis Al Qaeda captors this year, said in a statement that she thinks the setup wont allow for enough interagency coordination.
One senior administration official said the FBI was chosen to lead the operation because of its experience in conducting investigations, gathering intelligence and supporting crime victims. The attorney general will establish within the FBI an interagency hostage recovery operation that fuses together representatives from the departments of Justice, State, Treasury and Defense as well as intelligence officials.
The hostage rescue system that Obama set up is not an FBI organization, the official said, but rather will bring the requisite expertise from all departments and agencies to bear on the recovery of Americans taken hostage overseas. The official requested anonymity to discuss the new policy in advance of the presidents announcement.
The new plans were crafted as part of a sweeping policy review over several months, a process that also included interviews with families.
In addition to the FBI-led group, the presidents National Security Council will have a hostage response group that meets every week to keep an eye on hostage recovery strategies and lend help. A special presidential envoy for hostage affairs will be charged with coordinating U.S. diplomacy on hostage matters.
He quoted Diane Foley, the mother of James Foley, as saying, "As Americans, we can do better."
I totally agree, Obama said. We must do better.
For more White House coverage, follow @cparsons
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 14:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China's Internet users do a body check, from belly buttons to collarbones</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-chinese-internet-body-belly-buttons-collarbones-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  First came the Belly Button Challenge. Then it was a long legs test. Next up came a collarbone competition, plus feats to demonstrate the depth of one's dimples and the fullness of one's eyelashes.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>China's Internet users do a body check, from belly buttons to collarbones
China and body image
Fred Dufour / AFP/Getty Images
People exercise at the Aimin Fat Reduction Hospital in Tianjin, China. Internet memes supposedly gauging physical attractiveness have gained popularity in the country.
People exercise at the Aimin Fat Reduction Hospital in Tianjin, China. Internet memes supposedly gauging physical attractiveness have gained popularity in the country.
(Fred Dufour / AFP/Getty Images)
Medical Research
First came the Belly Button Challenge. Then it was a long legs test. Next up came a collarbone competition, plus feats to demonstrate the depth of ones dimples and the fullness of ones eyelashes.
In recent weeks, Internet users in mainland China have been going gaga over online memes supposedly aimed at testing  or telegraphing  how fit and attractive ones figure is. While being chubby was once regarded as a sign of health and wealth in a country frequently beset by famine, China in recent years has witnessed a growing body-consciousness, with weight-loss clinics, breast-enhancement centers and plastic surgery hospitals all gaining in popularity.
The worlds two biggest economies have been eyeing each other warily lately. Like two heavyweight contenders angling for a match, the U.S. and China have been managing a hugely productive economic relationship  two-way trade hit $590 billion last year  all the while trying to figure out who runs... ( Kim Murphy )
As China has urbanized and modernized, it has also grown fatter. A study by researchers at the University of Washington published last year in the journal the Lancet found that 28% of Chinese men and 27% of women were overweight or obese. The rate of childhood obesity has also been rising at an alarming clip.
The Belly Button Challenge peaked in mid-June, with thousands of people posting selfies showing their attempts to touch their navels by reaching one arm around their backs in a yoga-style pose. To date, the topic has garnered more than 130 million hits on Weibo, Chinas Twitter-like microblogging service.
8
Exactly what touched off the Belly Button Challenge remains unclear, though some online postings claimed U.S. scientists had discovered that the inability to complete the feat was an indicator that one needed to slim down.
A variety of celebrities  mostly super-slim young women with narrow waists  seized the opportunity to post photos of themselves in the pose; tour guides in Hunan province posed for pictures of themselves in red bikinis contorting themselves like pretzels. A young woman in Chongqing  who weighs about 100 pounds and stands about 5 feet 1 -- spent days trying to complete the challenge but ended up with a dislocated shoulder, the Chongqing News reported .
State-run media have reported on the trend and tried to tamp it down a bit, with the Communist Party mouthpiece Peoples Daily quoting a personal trainer in Nanjing as saying that the ability to complete the test might just mean one is rather flexible or simply has long arms. I cant do it either, said the trainer, Xie Wei.
Others have mocked the trend. In one widely reposted message, one commentator urged Chinese to go ahead and eat. American scientists, he joked, had discovered that some primates were incompletely evolved, with their excessively long arms not accustomed to walking upright.
-----------
Looks the Chinese are just as crazy as Americans when it comes to the Internet.
rtamtc
8:32 p.m.: An earlier version of this post incorrectly said Chinese actor Tong Dawei posted the message urging people to eat.
-----------
But netizens have just seemed to move from gazing at their navels to other parts of their physiques.
When 24-year-old Chinese Canadian singer Kris Wu, 6 feet 2, posted a photo of himself stretched out on a couch, his legs occupying the entire sofa, it set off another viral fad. Fans issued a challenge to others to sit with friends on a couch and see how many people their legs could stretch across.
Inveighed the state-run China Daily: People with long limbs are simply born that way, and for those with short limbs, stretching over many people on a couch will have to remain a distant dream.
Next up came the collarbone challenge, with young women showing off the depths of their clavicle hollows by filling the depressions with stacks of coins or even eggs.
Critics of the trend  a resurrection of a fad that first surfaced two years ago  said the collarbone meme was just an opportunity for attention-starved youths to draw attention to their chest areas from their bare midriffs.
Those with neither flat bellies nor sexy necklines, however, were not to be left out. Up next came women showing off the depths of their dimples by demonstrating how they could hold pen-caps in their cheek depressions, and others balancing multiple Q-tips or toothpicks on their eyelashes.
Chinese Internet users also took the opportunity to repost photos from this springs short-lived Hold a Coke Can With Your Breasts challenge, which was initially touted as a breast-cancer awareness project but was later revealed to have been initiated by an American adult entertainment casting company.
Put Coke between your breasts and coins on collarbones, reach your bellybutton from behind, keep the pen cap in your dimples, leave toothpicks on your eyelashes, one fed-up Chinese Internet user wrote on Weibo. Id like to report you monsters who can do all these to the police.
Nicole Liu and Harvard Zhang in The Times' Beijing bureau contributed to this report.
Follow @JulieMakLAT for news from China
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Greece, migrants relive harrowing boat journeys, but onstage</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-c1-greece-refugee-theater-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  After trekking hundreds of miles through fierce climates and villages filled with murderous bandits, the migrants had finally reached their destination.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>1
On this night, the migrants were rehearsing for a show at an Athens cultural festival. Titled "We Are the Persians," it weaves their back stories into a series of reenactments, with the goal of providing a more human picture of the migrant crisis. As they pulled the boat across the stage to represent their journeys, the scene was surreal, at once a pointed reminder of their struggles and an inadequate simulation of them.
An Afghan named Khalil practiced a scene that had him reenacting his detention by the Greek coast guard. He and other migrants picked up guns to replicate their captors' poses, then threw themselves on the floor while dramatic music played.
"They held guns to us," he belted out theatrically. "They took our money. They kept us in terrible places."
Khalil, 25, fled Afghanistan about 10 years ago at the urging of his father, who worried that an increasingly active Taliban in their town would either kill or recruit his son. After hiding out in Greece for years, he was granted asylum last year.
It might seem uncomfortable to relive, multiple times each rehearsal night, what you've spent years trying to forget. But those who went through the ordeal say that the opposite has proved to be the case. With its blend of larger artistic goals and concrete technical requirements, theater offers a unique kind of escape. The more a moment becomes about blocking, the less it's about lost friends and a fear of death.
"It was very hard at first to go through it again," Khalil said as he inhaled deeply on a cigarette during a rehearsal break. "But each time it got a little easier. And it was easy to act  all I had to do was remember the fear."
::
Markopoulou and AMAKA had previously worked with prisoners, and then shortly after began working with migrants. About three years ago, she began dealing with this particular group, betting that they might take to it more easily than psychiatric therapy.
For the first year, most of the young men didn't even speak. Markopoulou, a director known for ambitious projects such as a touring version of "The Iliad," instead tried to get them comfortable moving in unusual ways. Soon she graduated to improv exercises.
And this month, she and the migrants put on a major production for the first time, staging several performances of "We Are the Persians" at the popular Athens Festival. The audience of about 150 at each performance was moved, by the stories onstage and back stories that inspired them.
The migrant actors were also paid for performing for the first time. The off-stage group  including Markopoulou and the crew of set, lighting and other designers  is typically volunteer-based and was also paid for the first time.
To some, the idea of expending effort in this way might seem strange; migrants need employment, not Eugene O'Neill. But the actors say that the advantages will stay with them a lot longer than a few added euros.
"On the one hand, I want to show how hard the trip was, because it's not really what people here think," Reza, who has a mix of swagger and thoughtfulness, said as he took a break from rehearsing. "They hear 'boats' and they don't realize what we go through. But I also do it for me, to remind me of what happened, so that I never forget."
Reza's family fled Afghanistan for Iran before he was born. As part of the Hazara minority, they spoke a dialect similar to that used by many Iranians. But Afghans weren't accorded the same rights in Iran as natives. Reza faced heavy discrimination and eventually fled. En route from Iran to the Turkish coast, a good friend died under the forbidding conditions.
For all the peril of their pre-Europe lives, migrants begin to face a new set difficulties only after they arrive. Khalil has seen his family scatter across Europe and Asia, and he hasn't seen any of them since he left Afghanistan. Reza, meanwhile, lacks an asylum card, so he can't leave the country to visit family members in Iran. Starting a new family here isn't possible either, because without those papers he is prohibited from marrying. Most of the migrants live in especially poor parts of Athens, where drug use and homelessness are high.
But they have also found reasons to be optimistic, and rehearsal is interrupted several times as the actors are struck with a case of the giggles, often in the most oppressive scenes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 03:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. no longer will prosecute families who try to pay ransom for hostages</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-hostage-policy-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Relatives who try to pay ransom to free a family member being held hostage by terrorists will no longer face the threat of prosecution under a new policy from the Obama administration that seeks to streamline U.S. rescue efforts after several high-profile deaths.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. no longer will prosecute families who try to pay ransom for hostages
James Foley
Steven Senne / Associated Press
Journalist James Foley in Boston in 2011. President Obama ordered an extensive review of hostage recovery practices after the beheadings last summer of Foley and fellow American journalist Steve Sotloff.
Journalist James Foley in Boston in 2011. President Obama ordered an extensive review of hostage recovery practices after the beheadings last summer of Foley and fellow American journalist Steve Sotloff.
(Steven Senne / Associated Press)
Kidnapping
Relatives who try to pay ransom to free a family member being held hostage by terrorists will no longer face the threat of prosecution under a new policy from the Obama administration that seeks to streamline U.S. rescue efforts after several high-profile deaths.
President Obama plans to announce the new policy Wednesday as part of a broader set of guidelines on hostage crises, the result of a lengthy policy review. The overall goal is to coordinate the wide-ranging resources of the federal government to try to secure the return of American hostages, officials said.
The review is also an effort to deal more humanely with the panic-stricken families of abducted Americans, whose complaints about U.S. government handling of their cases have beset the Obama administration during a painful year that has seen notorious cases of abduction, threats and videotaped killings.
Shirley Sotloff
Jim Lo Scalzo / European Pressphto Agency
Shirley Sotloff, mother of slain journalist Steven Sotloff, at a Newseum event in Washington on June 8. Families of abducted Americans complained about the government's handling of their cases.
Shirley Sotloff, mother of slain journalist Steven Sotloff, at a Newseum event in Washington on June 8. Families of abducted Americans complained about the government's handling of their cases.
(Jim Lo Scalzo / European Pressphto Agency)
Families say they have received confusing messages from the government. One agency would threaten relatives with prosecution for talking about ransoms while another offered to facilitate such payments, for example.
The new policy also will keep the FBI in charge of managing hostage crises, despite the requests of families who believe the current structure fails to give negotiators enough power to operate.
The U.S. government will continue its long-standing policy of refusing to pay ransoms, senior administration officials said, or to negotiate with terrorists, as some European countries do.
8
The resources of the United States government are not going to be used to make concessions to terrorists, White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest said Tuesday, in the administrations only public comments about the forthcoming policy. We do not want to open the door to even more Americans being vulnerable to a hostage-taking.
Critics charged that the changes dont go far enough to solve long-running problems in the efforts to free Americans from captivity, including two dozen now held around the world.
Wholesale changes are needed, but whats being put forward is nothing more than window dressing, I fear, said Rep. Duncan Hunter (R-Alpine), a Marine veteran and member of the House Armed Services Committee. Its a pathetic response to a serious problem that has plagued the ability of the U.S. to successfully recover Americans held captive in the post-9/11 era.
Some family members of past and current hostages expressed concern about the plan to continue housing the bureaucracy at the FBI. Many had asked that the president appoint a hostage czar who reported to Obama and would have the authority to direct the Pentagon, State Department, FBI and intelligence networks as needed to coordinate rescue efforts.
Elaine Weinstein, whose husband, Warren, was a government contractor accidentally killed by a U.S. drone strike in Pakistan this year while being held hostage by Al Qaeda, said Tuesday that the information she and her family received in their 3 1/2-year ordeal was inconsistent at best and utterly disappointing.
She expressed concern about the decision to keep housing the hostage-rescue unit at the FBI. She said a better home would have been the presidents National Security Council, both to improve coordination and to ensure that those debating counter-terrorism activities and hostage recovery efforts were sitting in the same room.
@affableman And when someone in your immediate family is in line to get their head cut off, I'm sure you'll feel the same way.
Ryan Knight
14
We hope to be the last family that fails to receive the level of coordinated government support that those who serve abroad deserve when trouble finds them, she said.
Hunter said another issue with FBI leadership is that the bureau is not set up to rescue hostages in hostile areas. Even though the FBI official leading rescue efforts will have deputies from the Pentagon and State Department, he or she wont have real authority to command them, he said.
The presidents team decided to keep the hostage recovery effort at the FBI because the infrastructure was already in place at the bureau, said a U.S. official, who agreed to discuss the details of the changes on condition of anonymity because the results of the White House review had not been publicly released.
Obama ordered an extensive review of the hostage recovery practices last fall, looking into how the government deals with the threats and with the families of hostages. It followed the searing images of the executions last summer of American journalists James Foley and Steve Sotloff, carried out and broadcast by Islamic State extremists.
Since then, the White House has slowly moved from staunch opposition to conversations about ransom between hostages families and kidnappers to a position that one administration official described as more humane.
As a result of the policy changes, families will not be discouraged from communicating directly with hostage-takers  a new flexibility that analysts said could have operational benefits.
If you are open to communications, by definition youre going to know more about what it is the hostage-takers want and what their bottom lines might be, said Bruce Riedel, a former CIA official now at the Brookings Institution.
Also, if the new policy is seen as a clear White House directive, he said, that will give more power to the FBI official overseeing hostage rescue efforts.
The Office of the Director of National Intelligence will appoint a so-called issue manager for hostage affairs, charged with compiling information from different intelligence agencies and working to quickly declassify relevant details to provide family members and lawmakers with new information concerning a hostage, the U.S. official said.
Earnest acknowledged that improving communications with relatives was a high priority.
The changes do not come easily at the White House. Some advisors cautioned against giving families more latitude to discuss and pay ransoms out of fear that it would make Americans overseas more attractive to kidnappers.
Thats a huge worry, Riedel said. Thats why theyre saying that the no concessions rule will remain the policy of the United States.
For news from Washington, follow @cparsons and @ByBrianBennett

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 02:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Opposition leader ends hunger strike after Venezuela sets election date</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-venezuela-opposition-election-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Venezuelan opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez ended his 30-day hunger strike Tuesday after the government scheduled legislative elections for Dec. 6, thereby meeting his demand.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Opposition leader ends hunger strike after Venezuela sets election date
Venezuela opposition hunger strike
Ariana Cubillos / Associated Press
Lilian Tintori, center, wife of jailed opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez, is flanked by Patricia Ceballos, wife of jailed San Cristobal Mayor Daniel Ceballos, and an opposition member who was on hunger strike, at a news conference in Caracas, Venezuela.
Lilian Tintori, center, wife of jailed opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez, is flanked by Patricia Ceballos, wife of jailed San Cristobal Mayor Daniel Ceballos, and an opposition member who was on hunger strike, at a news conference in Caracas, Venezuela.
(Ariana Cubillos / Associated Press)
8
By setting a date for National Assembly elections, Tibisay Lucena, head of the electoral council, on Monday ended weeks of speculation that the socialist government of President Nicolas Maduro might call off the vote. Lucena said the vote was never in doubt.
When a friend texted me that coffee and toilet paper were on the shelves of an eastern Caracas supermarket, I raced to El Patio outlet hoping against hope that the increasingly scarce household items would still be available. ( Mery Mogollon )
Lopez's wife, Lilian Tintori, on Tuesday read a statement from her husband in which he asked 104 other hunger strikers to end their fasts as well.
We took on this protest not to die but so that all of us Venezuelans can live with dignity  I will continue the struggle for a better Venezuela, Lopez said in his note.
A former mayor of a Caracas borough, Lopez has been detained at a military base prison near Caracas, the Venezuelan capital, since February 2014 on charges of incitement to violence. He denies the charges and claims they are politically motivated.
Probably working for the worlds super rich oil barons
Preci Gil
1
Lopez was arrested after Maduro opponents took to the streets last year to protest hyperinflation, high crime and scarcities of basic foodstuffs. Violent confrontations with authorities across the country left 43 dead and 850 injured.
Various human rights and international political leaders, including former Spanish Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez, have demanded that Lopez be freed, along with Mayors Daniel Ceballos of San Cristobal and Antonio Ledezma of Caracas, who are being held on charges of rebellion and conspiracy, respectively.
A caravan of buses carrying a group of Brazilian politicians who traveled to Venezuela last week in a show of support for Lopez was blocked on an airport road by pro-government protesters. The Brazilian government issued a formal protest over the incident.
Ordinarily, the date for National Assembly voting to elect deputies for five-year terms is determined much earlier in the year to allow for a longer campaign season. Maduros United Socialist Party of Venezuela and allies hold a 99-seat majority in the 165-member body.
Some opposition figures were concerned that Maduro, whose popularity has been battered by a worsening economy and food scarcities, might call off the elections so as not to risk losing control of the assembly.
In a speech at a Caracas auditorium Monday, Maduro indicated he would not take loss of assembly control sitting down.
If the right wing takes control of the assembly, serious things will happen. It will unleash a process of street confrontations, Maduro said. I will be the first to go to the streets.
Lopez and other opposition members are also calling for international monitors for December election results in light of disputed voting in the 2013 presidential election to replace Hugo Chavez, who died in March of that year.
Special correspondents Mogollon and Kraul reported from Caracas and Bogota, Colombia, respectively.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 01:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Ebola cases frustrate hopes of defeating the virus in Sierra Leone</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-sierra-leone-ebola-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Two new Ebola cases have been identified in Sierra Leone's capital in recent days, frustrating hopes that the deadly virus may have been defeated there.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>New Ebola cases frustrate hopes of defeating the virus in Sierra Leone
Ebola in Sierra Leone
Michael Duff / Associated Press
A team of health workers searches for people suffering from Ebola during an education drive in Freetown, Sierra Leone, in March.
A team of health workers searches for people suffering from Ebola during an education drive in Freetown, Sierra Leone, in March.
(Michael Duff / Associated Press)
Ebola
Two new Ebola cases have been identified in Sierra Leone's capital in recent days, frustrating hopes that the deadly virus may have been defeated there.
The announcement by the countrys National Ebola Response Center followed a resurgence of cases in the northeast of the country, where President Ernest Bai Koroma this month ordered troops to enforce quarantines and a nighttime curfew in the districts of Kambia and Port Loko.
Caption Ebola in Liberia
John Moore / Getty Images
Sanitized gloves and boots hang to dry as a burial team collects Ebola victims from a Ministry of Health treatment center for cremation on Oct. 2 in Monrovia, Liberia.
Sanitized gloves and boots hang to dry as a burial team collects Ebola victims from a Ministry of Health treatment center for cremation on Oct. 2 in Monrovia, Liberia. (John Moore / Getty Images)
Caption Ebola in Liberia
Pascal Guyot / AFP/Getty Images
Medical personnel at the Ebola treatment center at Island hospital in Monrovia, Liberia, disinfect people who had brought patients suspected of having the Ebola virus on Oct. 2.
Medical personnel at the Ebola treatment center at Island hospital in Monrovia, Liberia, disinfect people who had brought patients suspected of having the Ebola virus on Oct. 2. (Pascal Guyot / AFP/Getty Images)
See more galleries
Complacency is our biggest challenge, Koroma said in announcing the measures. Now more than ever is the time we must all remain vigilant in our households and communities.
Sierra Leone was one of the West African countries hardest hit by the Ebola outbreak, accounting for nearly a third of the 11,000 people killed since last year, according to figures released by the World Health Organization.
Neighboring Liberia was declared Ebola-free in May, and the number of known cases in Sierra Leone dropped to just two that month. But the figure has increased again, with 14 cases recorded in Kambia and Port Loko in the week ending June 15, the WHO said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 00:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ferry strike disrupts traffic across English Channel; migrants add to chaos</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-ferry-strike-english-channel-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Migrants swarmed British-bound vehicles in the French port of Calais on Tuesday after a strike by ferry workers severely disrupted services across the English Channel, shutting down the cross-channel tunnel and stranding thousands of passengers.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Ferry strike disrupts traffic across English Channel; migrants add to chaos
MyFerryLink strike
Kamil Zihnioglu / Associated Press
An information board shows that Eurostar trains are suspended for the rest of the day at Gare du Nord station in Paris on June 23, 2015.
An information board shows that Eurostar trains are suspended for the rest of the day at Gare du Nord station in Paris on June 23, 2015.
(Kamil Zihnioglu / Associated Press)
France
Migrants swarmed British-bound vehicles in the French port of Calais on Tuesday after a strike by ferry workers severely disrupted services across the English Channel, shutting down the cross-channel tunnel and stranding thousands of passengers.
The ferry strike diverted vehicles to the Channel Tunnel, causing a massive traffic jam that was exacerbated when strikers entered part of the tunnel and set fires, helping to sow chaos.
MyFerryLink strike
Philippe Huguen / AFP/Getty Images
Striking employees of the French company MyFerryLink, a cross-channel ferry service, stand near a burning-tire barricade as they block access to the Channel Tunnel in Calais, France.
Striking employees of the French company MyFerryLink, a cross-channel ferry service, stand near a burning-tire barricade as they block access to the Channel Tunnel in Calais, France.
(Philippe Huguen / AFP/Getty Images)
Images broadcast on television showed large groups of migrants, most from North Africa and the Middle East, running after slow-moving or stationary trucks and clambering on board in the hope of traveling to Britain through the Channel Tunnel undetected.
The British Foreign Office issued a warning to all drivers along that route to keep their doors locked and secure any unattended vehicles to keep people from illegally entering the country.
The suspension [of services] meant there were lots of vehicles having to queue on the motorway, and [that] is an invitation to migrants to climb on board, Eurotunnel spokesman John Keefe said.
Keefe said some of the migrants had broken into trucks, threatened drivers and damaged the goods on board in an attempt to get into Britain without papers.
Pretty much everything they are doing is illegal, he said.
We will spend most of this evening pulling migrants off trucks  our requirement is to make sure that no one is on board when they go into the tunnel.
The wildcat strike was carried out by MyFerryLink workers who are concerned about job losses.
Brown is tempted to bullet train across the ocean to transport all the potential future Democrat voters to California. But his Sacramento friends might not be so eager because they are from a different culture.
AndrewWiggin
2
They blocked ferry traffic during two separate actions on Tuesday - for a few hours in the early morning and then later in the afternoon, Eurotunnel said.
The action caused severe gridlock for vehicles either trying to make their way to the port or onto the Channel Tunnel bound for England, as well as for drivers trying to make French-bound journeys on the English side of the Channel.
Later in the day, the workers also broke into the Eurotunnel terminal, got onto the tracks, threw rubble around and set fire to tires causing huge plumes of smoke, Keefe said.
Eurotunnel trains carry vehicles through the tunnel. Its service was briefly suspended but was running again by evening, with some delays.
However, EuroStar, which runs a high-speed passenger train through the tunnel, said all its services would be suspended until the morning, bringing disruption to passengers trying to board at Paris Gare du Nord and Londons St. Pancras Station.
Ferry traffic resumed from the port by evening following earlier disruptions.
The days events shone a new spotlight on a migrant camp at Calais, which has swelled to an estimated 3,000 people.
Calais Deputy Mayor Philippe Mignonet told the BBC that it was hyper critical to say the migrant situation was Calais responsibility.
Calais is not the destination. ... The fact that they wanted to get in trucks, thats because they want to go to England, so that means that England is the magnet, he said. The English government has got to realize that it is not our responsibility.
They go through Calais to get to England, and I wish them good luck, he added.
Boyle is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 23:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China hacking? Beijing is also a victim, foreign minister says in interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-china-foreign-minister-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The world's two biggest economies have been eyeing each other warily lately. Like two heavyweight contenders angling for a match, the U.S. and China have been managing a hugely productive economic relationship - two-way trade hit $590 billion last year - all the while trying to figure out who runs...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>China hacking? Beijing is also a victim, foreign minister says in interview
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi
Attila Kisbenedek / AFP/Getty Images
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with the Los Angeles Times in Beijing ahead of talks between his country and the U.S.
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with the Los Angeles Times in Beijing ahead of talks between his country and the U.S.
(Attila Kisbenedek / AFP/Getty Images)
We are 'not competitors, much less adversaries,' Chinese foreign minister says of U.S.
China says it's also the victim of wide-scale computer hacking
Chinese foreign minister calls for new superpower model in the post-Cold War age
The worlds two biggest economies have been eyeing each other warily lately. Like two heavyweight contenders angling for a match, the U.S. and China have been managing a hugely productive economic relationship  two-way trade hit $590 billion last year  all the while trying to figure out who runs the world.
The two nations have forged common ground on big-ticket items such as climate change and concerns over nuclear proliferation in North Korea and Iran. But theres been tension over Chinas moves to secure disputed territory in the South China Sea, and accusations that recent large-scale hacking of U.S. government computers had a Chinese fingerprint.
Both nations are hurrying to lock in separate Pacific trade agreements that stand to give them a powerful foothold in commerce across Asia.
The investigation into the cyberattack on computers at the U.S. Office of Personnel Management is proceeding on the theory that the hack was directed by the Chinese government and aimed at uncovering sensitive, personal information that could have been used to blackmail or bribe government employees... ( Brian Bennett and Richard A. Serrano )
More than 400 Chinese officials are in Washington this week for talks aimed at making progress in a relationship regarded by almost everyone as vital. On the eve of the talks that began Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with the Los Angeles Times in Beijing as part of a delegation hosted by the New York-based Asia Society. The interview has been edited for length and clarity.
You have emphasized that China and the U.S. are not competitors, much less adversaries, but what about the allegations of computer hacking that the U.S. administration makes against China? Was China behind the hacking of the federal Office of Personnel Management computers?
The position of the Chinese government is very clear: The Chinese government opposes any hacking activities or the theft of commercial secrets. This is the set policy of the Chinese government, and we have very strict regulations.
8
I wonder if there is any foundation for the accusation. In this Internet age, it takes cooperation and mutual understanding to create healthy, stable, open and fair cyberspace in the world. We should not have irresponsible finger-pointing at each other.
As a matter of fact, China has suffered from hacking. Every day, China is subject to more than 300 large-scale hacking activities, and every month, more than 10,000 Chinese websites are changed by hackers, and 80% of the government websites are attacked. We have evidence to show that many of these hacking activities come from the U.S. We cannot say who inside the U.S., but these attacks come from U.S. soil.
So we think that China and the United States should have equal-footed and candid dialogue on this. The United States is a mature, major cyberpower, while China is also emerging fast as a major cybercountry. We hope that cyberspace will become an area of further cooperation between our two countries, instead of a source of friction.
What do you say to those voices in the U.S. who are saying that 40 years of efforts to engage China have not produced results, and it may be time to consider that confrontation makes more sense than engagement?
I dont think this is representative of mainstream public opinion in the United States. This only comes from a handful of people. I think the United States will stick to the path that it thinks is right, and also the path that enjoys the support and endorsement of the American people.
If the engagement policy of the United States is designed to turn China into another United States  I think that is impossible. Because our two countries have very different history, cultural backgrounds, and we are also at very different levels of development. But if this policy is designed for mutually beneficial and win-win outcomes, then we can choose to cooperate with each other; we can respect the differences and we can look for areas where our interests converge.
cComments
It might be the "stated" policy of the Chinese government to oppose hacking but who's to say their own equivalent to our NSA isn't doing so autonomously?(actually, this could very well be the case that the left hand doesn't know what the right hand is doing because...
Resident  Boomer
1
In the past 10 years, what do you think is the biggest mistake the U.S. has made in its relationship with China? And vice versa, what is the biggest single error your government has made in its relationship with the U.S.?
Im afraid you have too pessimistic a perception in raising this question. Instead of thinking of the mistakes and errors, why not think of the achievements?
An important agreement that we reached between our two countries in recent years is to work together to build a new model of a major-country relationship.
Some argue that it will mean a world of G2 [in which China and the U.S. jointly tackle the worlds problems], but China does not subscribe to this view  in the first place, because we do not believe that world affairs can be decided by one or two countries.
The second inaccurate contention we hear is that China is seeking parity with the United States. This is not true. Because the United States is the biggest developed country, and China is the biggest developing country. We still have a very big gap between us.
Our goal is that by the centenary of the founding of the People's Republic, that is, by 2049, China will become a medium-income developed country; and even by then, there will be a big gap between China and the United States.
Others argue that China is trying to keep a low profile in order to avoid conflicts with the United States, so that one day it can replace the status of the United States. This is totally groundless.
The original purpose of having this new model of major country relationship between us is really simple. That is to avoid a repeat of the historic pattern in which an emerging country is destined to have conflict with an established power.
To have this new model of a major country relationship, we need to have three things. The first element is nonconflict, nonconfrontation. Second, we need to have a win-win cooperation, and we need to reject the thinking that winner takes it all. And third, we need to have mutual respect. Some American friends may have misgivings about this mutual respect. They find it hard to accept, because they think it means the U.S. has to accept all demands from China. This is an inaccurate interpretation. Mutual respect means, in our view, not to impose ones will upon others.
China has drafted a law on regulating nongovernmental organizations. Some in the government warned that the spread of Western ideas could lead to instability. What are those ideas that you would prefer not be spread? And if the U.S. is behind this, whats its agenda?
China is an open society, and there are a large number of NGOs in China, but China is yet to have a dedicated law that can provide for rule-based regulation of NGOs. The development of this draft law is part of our effort to rule the country according to law, and also part of our effort to align China with the international community. So we think we deserve understanding and support for this.
I think for those NGOs who are dedicated to promoting exchanges and cooperation with the Chinese people in accordance with Chinese laws, this draft law will not bring about any obstacles to their activities, but rather it will only facilitate their work and give them better support and guarantees.
But indeed all countries have their different national conditions, so foreign NGOs need to respect the national conditions of those countries and also respect their local laws and regulations.
For instance, the constitution provides that China is a socialist country with the Communist Party of China as the ruling party. So if anyone wants to challenge this, if anyone calls on others to oust the Communist Party of China, then he has broken the law. Because this is so written in the Chinese Constitution.
8
As far as I know, many foreign NGOs have worked very hard to benefit peoples livelihood in China, and also work to promote social harmony, so we have a high degree of recognition of these things.
China has recently announced that it has halted some controversial construction work on one of several disputed islands in the South China Sea that have been the object of friction involving China, its neighbors and even the United States. Is this work stoppage a response to international criticism?
Yes, the ministry has just released this news because the relevant construction project is nearing completion. We have anticipated comments from the media saying that China had to stop the construction because of pressure from the U.S. Well, this is totally not true. But we cannot simply go on with construction work forever, simply because we are afraid of such comments from the media. At some point we have to stop because the construction plan is completed.
cComments
It might be the "stated" policy of the Chinese government to oppose hacking but who's to say their own equivalent to our NSA isn't doing so autonomously?(actually, this could very well be the case that the left hand doesn't know what the right hand is doing because...
Resident  Boomer
1
Incidentally, I want to tell you that construction on the islands and reefs in the South China Sea did not start yesterday, and it was not started first by China. We need to be very clear about this. Vietnam and the Philippines started large-scale construction work 20 or 30 years ago on islands they had illegally occupied. And China has all along exercised great restraint.
I think there is one basic fact that the international community has to learn, and that is that the islands and reefs of the Spratly Islands we are talking about are Chinese territory. I think the U.S. knows better than anyone else about this. Because at the end of the Second World War, China retook the sovereignty over these Spratly Islands from the Japanese troops which occupied these islands, and it was a joint operation between China and the United States. The Chinese retook the sovereignty with the support of U.S. military vessels.
Even into the late 1960s, there were never any objections from Vietnam and the Philippines about Chinas sovereignty over these islands.
But as you know that after that, there was a 10-year Cultural Revolution in China, a period of great turbulence here, so China was kept too busy here to look after those islands and reefs, and it gave other countries some opportunities. Another element was at play, in that there was some wild speculation about rich oil and gas reserves in that part of the world, so the neighboring countries started to occupy those islands and reefs one by one, and that is the source of the current status quo, the claims led by five countries or six parties. China has sovereignty over these islands and reefs, and our sovereignty has been seriously infringed upon. This is the basic reality.
But despite all this, China is still for a peaceful settlement to the disputes, through dialogue and consultation. We will remain committed to this, and there will not be any change to this position.
You mentioned that the world cant be ruled by a G2, but do you worry that Chinas actions in the South China Sea create a binary equation in the rest of the region  that youre either with China, or youre with the United States? It has been suggested that one of the reasons 20 countries in the region wanted to join the Trans-Pacific Partnership proposed by President Obama was that they wanted to be with America.
I dont think we should run the risk of oversimplifying this by interpreting the situation like this. As I mentioned earlier, China and the United States are having cooperation at various levels and in various fields. So if China and the United States are cooperating, then there is no question of asking those regional countries to take sides with one or the other.
President Xi said the Pacific Ocean is vast enough for both China and the United States. China is not only a major land country, but also a major maritime country, because we have a long coastline.
And as the Chinese economy continues to grow, and as China has closer economic interactions with other countries, it is only natural that China has closer links with the sea. So under this context, it is time for China and the United States to sit down and explore maritime cooperation.
Now, between China and the United States we have this military-to-military engagement. We are talking about a code of conduct for sea or air encounter. This is mainly a preventive act, but I think what is more important is that we sit down and explore cooperation.
As for TPP, I see it as an economic and trade treaty. We dont want to overpoliticize it. Rather, we hope that the TPP will not affect the free trade regime under the World Trade Organization mechanism. Now some American friends may think that now that there is a TPP, the U.S. can do without [the World Trade Organization]. So I think more thinking is needed on whether this kind of thinking is good for the U.S. or not.
On North Korea: A lot of people are puzzled as to why China, which is clearly the senior partner in that relationship, is unable to exert more control over the regime in North Korea.
Both China and the DPRK [Democratic People's Republic of Korea] are independent countries. So the relationship between us is a state-to-state relationship, not a relationship between a senior and a junior. Of course in dealing with the DPRK, China has to follow the norms of international relations, including noninterference in internal affairs. Of course, as the DPRKs neighbor, we want to see a DPRK that enjoys social stability, economic growth and better lives for their people.
We have been telling this to the DPRK that their pursuit of nuclear weapons will not bring safety or security, but rather it will bring a danger, and it does a disservice not only to the DPRK itself, but also to its neighbors and the entire region.
But what the DPRK has been telling us is that it is facing a real and immediate military threat from the U.S. So the DPRK has attributed the purpose of its nuclear program to one thing, and that is to counter the immediate military threat from the U.S.
I think you can perfectly understand this. China cannot settle or resolve this. So we hope that the U.S. and the DPRK can have face-to-face talks. We can provide whatever facilitation you need. If this problem is solved, and if you have normalization of the bilateral relationship, then China is more than ready to provide guarantee for the security and peace in the peninsula and also the region, because we count this as our obligation and our responsibility.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iranian leader's motives unclear as nuclear talks resume</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-iran-nuclear-2-20150628-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  As international negotiators gathered here Saturday for what is supposed to be a final round of nuclear diplomacy with Iran, the hope of achieving a deal hinges on a mystery: What does Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei really want?
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Iranian leader's motives unclear as nuclear talks resume
Ayatollah Ali Khamenei
Office of the Iranian Supreme Leader / Associated Press
Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei in recent weeks has moved away from understandings his negotiators had seemed to agree on.
Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei in recent weeks has moved away from understandings his negotiators had seemed to agree on. (Office of the Iranian Supreme Leader / Associated Press)
Hassan Rouhani
As international negotiators gathered here Saturday for what is supposed to be a final round of nuclear diplomacy with Iran, the hope of achieving a deal hinges on a mystery: What does Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei really want?
An agreement limiting Iran's nuclear program would potentially be the most important diplomatic achievement of the decade, and it has seemed increasingly within reach since April 2, when negotiators reached a tentative deal.
But in recent weeks, Khamenei has moved away from understandings his negotiators had appeared to agree on. In particular, he has said he would refuse to allow international inspectors access to sites of suspected nuclear activity, including military bases.
In 2012, President Obama made it plain in a letter to Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei that any attempt to close the strategic Strait of Hormuz would be met with American force. ( Paul Richter )
The six world powers seeking the agreement have called scrutiny of Iran's military sites a necessary part of any deal to prevent Iran from cheating on a nuclear accord. Khamenei and other top Iranian officials and lawmakers have repeatedly insisted that they will refuse such access.
Western officials still believe odds favor a deal after almost two years of bargaining. Some believe Khamenei is only seeking advantage ahead of the June 30 negotiating deadline.
But in Washington and European capitals, concern has deepened in recent weeks that Khamenei may truly be unwilling  or perhaps politically unable  to make the concessions needed to seal a fundamental compromise with foreign powers.
"People expected the Iranians to spout off, then simmer down," said Richard Nephew, who was a member of the U.S. negotiating team until earlier this year. "But they haven't; they've dug in deeper."
8
As Secretary of State John F. Kerry and other diplomats gathered at a former Habsburg palace here over the weekend, they insisted a deal was within reach, even as they conceded questions that seemed resolved in April are again in dispute.
"Everybody would like to see an agreement, but we have to work through some tough issues," Kerry said Saturday before a meeting with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif.
Negotiations were expected to continue past the deadline by at least a few days and could last until mid-July. The final days will probably feature threats, all-nighters and perhaps even some theatrical departures, diplomats said.
Those who see Khamenei's tough statements as a negotiating tactic note that each side nonetheless has compelling strategic reasons to want a deal. The U.S. and the five other world powers involved in the talks  Britain, France, Germany, China and Russia  are hoping to postpone the threat of the Iranian nuclear program for at least 10 to 15 years; Iran desperately needs relief from punishing economic sanctions and seeks to end its status as international pariah.
Yet an agreement would be a huge step for an Iranian elite whose authority and personal wealth has been built on four decades of resistance to the United States. And Khamenei knows that among ordinary Iranians, much of the credit for the deal would not go to him and the hard-liners who back him, but to their more moderate rivals, including Iranian President Hassan Rouhani.
"An elite firestorm" over the issues of inspections and the United Nations' desire to look into Iran's past nuclear weapons research has clearly threatened the supreme leader, wrote Cliff Kupchan, chairman of the Eurasia Group risk-consulting firm, in a report this month.
cComments
@Preci Gil if you carefully research the history, Israel forced Jewish settlers out of Gaza in 2005. Christian Science Monitor had photos of Jews weeping &amp; protesting the order to leave.in later years, qassam rockets arrived in Gaza. Hamas would not resist the urge to aim &amp; launch them.at...
cynicalretiree
20
Since the April 2 tentative agreement, conservatives in parliament, the religious establishment, state media and the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps, all key parts of Khamenei's power base, have voiced criticism. There have been mass demonstrations and personal attacks on the negotiators, including during Friday prayers in Tehran.
The idea of inspections on military bases has generated particular controversy, with many in Iran saying the plan offends the country's dignity and treats it in a manner that no other country would allow.
How much Khamenei responds to such pressure remains a matter of intense debate among U.S. and allied officials.
The bargaining that began in September 2013 has allowed U.S. officials insights into the Iranian government they have not had in the 36 years since the Iranian Revolution. They now have regular access to top Iranian officials; U.S. diplomats have a congenial personal relationship with Iran's suave foreign minister, Zarif.
But the 75-year-old Khamenei remains an enigma. Within the U.S. government, opinions differ on the extent to which he is the decider, and on whether he can only struggle to shape a consensus of the most powerful political forces within the Iranian elite.
U.S. analysts see Khamenei as a weaker leader than his predecessor, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, the founder of the Islamic Republic, who had more charisma and broader public support. Khamenei has struggled to juggle the goals of his hard-line inner circle with public demands for a better economy through an end to sanctions and an increase in foreign investment.
Last July, negotiators thought they had a deal, but Khamenei dashed their hopes just before a deadline by demanding that Iran's nuclear program, instead of shrinking, be allowed to expand many-fold over the course of a deal that he said should last for only seven years. Khamenei's red lines later melted away, as he seemed to accept a sharply constrained uranium-enrichment program and a longer duration for the nuclear deal.
When Khamenei appeared to accept the interim deal in April, some analysts and former U.S. officials said it appeared that the leader was turning out to be a pragmatist, rather than a fire-breathing revolutionary, as he had described himself. Now those judgments are again in doubt, particularly after a nationally televised speech Wednesday in which Khamenei seemed to rule out many of the compromises that Iranian negotiators had accepted.
In the speech, he said Iran must have relief from sanctions at the start of any agreement, not after it had taken verifiable steps to scale back its nuclear program, as previously agreed. He also said Iran wouldn't agree to a decadelong freeze in its uranium enrichment, as stipulated in April.
Khamenei made other provocative statements that appeared aimed at encouraging hard-liners. He claimed that President Obama had secretly offered to recognize Iran as a nuclear state in 2013 and appeared to be boasting that Iran's ability to enrich uranium to 20% put it within easy reach of having material usable in a bomb, noted Ray Takeyh, an Iran specialist at the Council on Foreign Relations.
Khamenei also again ruled out "unconventional" activities by inspectors, including access to military bases and interviews with nuclear scientists.
The supreme leader may have several goals in mind. He may be trying to force a reopening and renegotiation of settled issues, following a pattern seen in past Iranian negotiations. He could be trying to temporarily placate hard-line constituencies at home, with a plan to back off later. Or he could have decided that pressure from the Revolutionary Guard and other conservative institutions has left him no choice but to jettison previous commitments, even if doing so threatens the deal.
Khamenei could pay a huge price for throwing up demands that would sink the deal. Iran could be blamed for a diplomatic collapse, raising the chances that world powers would agree to maintain, or even toughen, the sanctions that are crushing Iran's economy.
But his moves, at the very least, may make it impossible to complete the deal within a period even close to the current deadline. His negotiators now face a daunting task of squaring their past promises with the leader's pronouncements.
For the Obama administration, the effective deadline to complete the deal is around July 5. If the agreement isn't in hand then, the administration probably won't be able to meet a congressional deadline to provide lawmakers the text and all supporting documents by July 10. If the administration misses that deadline, Congress gets an additional month to review the deal, putting a final decision off to mid-September at the earliest.
Nephew, the former negotiator, says he remains optimistic that a deal will be struck. "It's so important, for so many strategic reasons, for both sides," he said. "But it could also fall apart."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece bankruptcy looms as creditors reject bailout extension</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-bankruptcy-looms-closer-20150627-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Greece moved closer to a perilous bankruptcy Saturday after talks over a bailout package broke down with its creditors, who rejected any emergency extension of the aid that has kept the debt-ridden Mediterranean nation afloat.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece bankruptcy looms as creditors reject bailout extension
Greece economy
Simela Pantzartzi / European Pressphoto Agency
People wait in line to withdraw cash from an ATM at an Athens shopping center on Saturday.

People wait in line to withdraw cash from an ATM at an Athens shopping center on Saturday.

European Union
Greece moved closer to a perilous bankruptcy Saturday after talks over a bailout package broke down with its creditors, who rejected any emergency extension of the aid that has kept the debt-ridden Mediterranean nation afloat.
A spot of good news came Sunday when the European Central Bank decided to continue emergency funding to Greeks cash-strapped banks, which it has provided for months. Observers had feared that the ECB might cut off that lifeline, which would have left many Greek banks broke and unable to function.
European Union finance ministers and major lenders warned Greece on Thursday that catastrophe looms within days for the heavily indebted country unless it brings a credible plan for reforming the economy to eleventh-hour negotiations now at an impasse. ( Carol J. Williams )
But the ECB froze the level of its aid, adding to the pressure that the banks are already feeling after depositors have withdrawn billions of euros over the past few weeks. Media outlets reported lines of worried customers at some ATMs in Greece on Sunday but no widespread panic.
Greeces financial turmoil increased Saturday when the other 18 nations that share the euro with Greece said they would not grant a grace period or await the outcome of a snap referendum the Greek government plans to hold next weekend on the bailout proposals on offer from international lenders. Without a deal in hand, Athens is expected to run out of money by Tuesday and default on a payment it owes the International Monetary Fund.
8
Such a default could throw the Greek economy into chaos, shut down the countrys banks and threaten its membership in the Eurozone. The ill effects could spread to neighboring nations and even the global economy.
European officials blamed Greeces left-wing government for unilaterally breaking off negotiations by announcing early Saturday its surprise intention to conduct a referendum on the creditors proposals  and to actively campaign against their approval.
The process wasnt finished, as far as we were concerned. The proposals werent definitive. They werent formally discussed or decided upon, said Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the leader of the Eurozones finance ministers. That is a sad decision for Greece, because it has closed the door on further talks where the door was still open in my mind.
But Greek officials accused their creditors of backing them into a corner and refusing to budge on a bailout formula prescribing more of the same austerity that has made the Greek economy contract by 25% in the last five years.
Early Sunday, the Greek parliament, led by Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' anti-austerity Syriza party, voted to put the creditors' proposed bailout terms to a referendum July 5. Of parliament's 300 lawmakers, 178 voted in favor and 120 against, with two people absent.
@Beast of Burden Care to back that thought up........?
Brianontheranch
81
To cheers from his backbenchers, Tsipras declared that Greece would not be bullied into submission by its European partners and urged his compatriots to vote no in the plebiscite. But opposition leaders accused him of putting the country's membership in the European Union at risk.
The move to hold a referendum took Greeces negotiating partners by surprise. Analysts said that if it was a ploy to scare them into sweetening the deal, then it backfired spectacularly, with the other Eurozone nations digging in their heels. Instead of talking about new solutions Saturday, Dijsselbloem spoke of insulating the rest of Europe from the fallout of a Greek default.
The euro area authorities stand ready to do whatever is necessary to ensure financial stability of the euro area, financial ministers said in a statement after the collapse of talks Saturday.
Some Eurozone officials also said that the referendum would essentially be moot, because Greece's bailout will have expired by then and the Eurozone's proposals would no longer be applicable.
Despite the brinkmanship, the Eurozone remains eager to see a deal struck. Although nations such as Germany and France feel they can weather the consequences of a Greek default and its potential exit from the euro, they know that the loss of one of its members would raise serious questions over the stability of the currency.
The Greek finance minister, Yanis Varoufakis, warned as much when he criticized the Eurozones decision not to extend the current bailout by a few days to allow the referendum to take place.
Especially given that there is a very high probability that Greeks will go against our recommendation and vote in favor of the institutions proposal, that refusal will certainly damage the credibility of the [Eurozone] as a democratic union of partner member states, and Im very much afraid that that damage will be permanent, Varoufakis said.
Amid the harsh rhetoric on both sides, at least one Eurozone nation, France, expressed hope that a solution could still be found and offered to mediate.
Other Eurozone officials took pains to emphasize that Greece remained a member of their club  even though their joint statement came with the footnote: Supported by all members of the Eurogroup except the Greek member.
Copyright  2015, Los Angeles Times
UPDATE
6:58 a.m. June 28: This article was updated to include the European Central Bank's decision to continue emergency funding.
5:50 p.m.: This article was updated to include the vote in the Greek parliament.
The first version of this article was published at 1:25 p.m. June 27.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:56:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait names Saudi man as suicide bomber in mosque attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-kuwait-mosque-attack-20150628-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Kuwait said Sunday that the bomber who killed at least 27 worshipers at a Shiite Muslim mosque on Friday had been identified as a young Saudi national who arrived in the Persian Gulf emirate only hours before the attack.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait names Saudi man as suicide bomber in mosque attack
Kuwait mosque
Raed Qutena / European Pressphoto Agency
Worshipers stop for body checks before entering the Grand Mosque in Kuwait in the aftermath of Friday's bombing.
Worshipers stop for body checks before entering the Grand Mosque in Kuwait in the aftermath of Friday's bombing.
(Raed Qutena / European Pressphoto Agency)
Kuwait said Sunday that the bomber who killed at least 27 worshipers at a Shiite Muslim mosque on Friday had been identified as a young Saudi national who arrived in the Persian Gulf emirate only hours before the attack.
Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa
This photo released by the Kuwait News Agency shows Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa.
This photo released by the Kuwait News Agency shows Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa.
(Associated Press)
The attack raised fresh worries about the growing reach of the jihadists of the Islamic State, an affiliate of which claimed responsibility for the bombing. The disclosure of the bombers nationality, reported by Kuwaits official news agency, also heightened fears about the radicalization of youth in Saudi Arabia, Kuwaits powerful and oil-rich neighbor.
For normally tranquil Kuwait, the attack marked a devastating spillover of sectarian strife that has been sweeping the region, to which the emirate had previously been largely immune. It was the first strike of its kind in the tiny state, whose hereditary emirs are Sunni Muslim, but has a long tradition of peaceful co-existence with a sizeable Shiite minority. 
8
The bomber was identified by Kuwaits Interior Ministry as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen Al-Gabbaa, born in 1992. Authorities said he had flown into Kuwaits international airport at dawn on the day of the noontime attack at one of the emirates oldest Shiite mosques.
Chilling security footage that later surfaced on social media showed the white-robed assailant taking a moment to gaze out at a crowd of up to 2,000 men, nearly all of them prostrated in mid-prayer, before blowing himself up.
In addition to those killed, more than 250 were wounded, with the interior of the landmark Imam Sadiq mosque left strewn with bloody debris and broken bodies. The attacks symbolic significance was magnified by taking place during the holy month of Ramadan, and at Friday noon prayers, the most important of the Muslim week.
Kuwaiti authorities also said Sunday they had detained the driver of the vehicle that brought the attacker to the mosque. He was identified as a member of the countrys large and downtrodden stateless population known as bidoon.
0
The Interior Ministry said it was still investigating the plot surrounding the bombing, but described an alleged accomplice arrested earlier as involved with a deviant ideology -- a term generally used to characterize Islamist militancy. A government-linked newspaper said seven suspects were in custody, with a wave of arrests having begun on Friday, hours after the blast.
The bombing was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State calling itself Najd Province, a historic reference to the region surrounding the Saudi capital of Riyadh. Offshoots of the group generally assign themselves names affiliated with their geographic base.
The Sunni extremists of the Islamic State consider Shiites to be heretics, and have repeatedly called on followers to target them. Similar attacks have taken place at mosques in Saudi Arabia and in Yemen, where a Saudi-led Sunni military coalition has carried out more than three months of bombing targeting Shiite Muslim rebels known as Houthis.
The Islamic State has urged stepped-up attacks during Ramadan, which began last week. The group also claimed responsibility for an assault Friday on a beach resort in Tunisia that left at least 38 people dead, most of them European tourists.
Kuwait on Saturday declared a day of mourning for the mosque victims, with Sunni religious leaders and thousands of Kuwaitis joining in paying tribute.
Staff writer King reported from Cairo and special correspondent Hassan from Berlin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds still in hospital after fire at Taiwan water park</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-taiwan-water-park-fire-20150627-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Hundreds still in hospital after fire at Taiwan water park
Raw: Video captures fire at Taiwan water park
Authorities say a fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party June 27at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 400 people, many seriously.
Authorities say a fire on a music stage spread into a crowd of spectators at a party June 27at a Taiwan water park, injuring more than 400 people, many seriously.
By Associated Press
More than 400 people, many of them seriously burned, remained in hospitals Sunday after a fire spread into a crowd of spectators at a music party at a Taiwan water park, authorities said.
Caption Taiwan water park fire
AFP/Getty Images
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City.
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City.
(AFP/Getty Images)
Caption Taiwan water park fire
Associated Press
An injured womanafter the fire atFormosa Water Park in New Taipei City.
An injured womanafter the fire atFormosa Water Park in New Taipei City.
(Associated Press)
See more galleries
The fire late Saturday was sparked by an accidental explosion of a colored theatrical powder thrown from the stage in front of about 1,000 people, the local fire agency and media said. The powder for the one-time event called Color Play Asia ignited along the ground, mainly burning people's lower bodies, said Wang Wei-sheng, a liaison with the New Taipei City fire department command center.
The exact cause of the fire was still being investigated, but Taiwan Premier Mao Chih-kuo banned public activities that use the colored powder.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tourists stream out of Tunisia after massacre at beach resort</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-tourists-flee-tunisia-20150627-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  As hundreds of frightened tourists fled Tunisia on Saturday, the North African country's leaders announced stringent new security measures in response to a massacre at a popular Mediterranean resort that left at least 38 people dead, nearly two-thirds of them British visitors.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Tourists stream out of Tunisia after massacre at beach resort
Attack in Tunisia
Flowers mark the scene the morning after a mass shooting in Sousse, Tunisia.
Flowers mark the scene the morning after a mass shooting in Sousse, Tunisia.
(Darko Vojinovic / Associated Press)
Islamic State
As hundreds of frightened tourists fled Tunisia on Saturday, the North African countrys leaders announced stringent new security measures in response to a massacre at a popular Mediterranean resort that left at least 38 people dead, nearly two-thirds of them British visitors.
The mass shooting on Friday in the coastal city of Sousse was the worst terror strike in the modern history of Tunisia, which had been considered an island of relative stability in an increasingly volatile region.
Caption Attack in Tunisia
A young woman lays flowers at the massacre scene in Sousse, Tunisia.
A young woman lays flowers at the massacre scene in Sousse, Tunisia.
(Darko Vojinovic / Associated Press)
Flowers mark the scene the morning after a mass shooting in Sousse, Tunisia.
Flowers mark the scene the morning after a mass shooting in Sousse, Tunisia.
(Darko Vojinovic / Associated Press)
See more galleries
Within hours of the attack, diplomats, airlines and tour operators stepped in to provide bus transport from the stricken hotel and neighboring resorts to the nearest airport for flights out. More than a dozen evacuation flights took off overnight and at least 10 more were scheduled Saturday, the French news agency AFP reported. It said at least 2,500 foreign visitors expected to be repatriated by days end.
Elsewhere in the region, the Persian Gulf emirate of Kuwait declared a national day of mourning for victims of its own tragedy on Friday, the bombing of a crowded Shiite mosque. The death toll in that strike, the first of its kind in Kuwait, rose to 27, with more than 200 injured.
As it did in Kuwait, Islamic State claimed responsibility for the attack in Tunisia. The jihadist group had also asserted that it carried out a deadly attack in March on a landmark museum in the capital, Tunis, though that claim was later called into question by Tunisian authorities, who blamed an Al Qaeda offshoot instead.
The museum attack left more than 20 people dead, and most of those victims, too, were European tourists.
Tunisian authorities emphasized that the motives and methods in Fridays assault remained under investigation. The one known assailant, shot dead by security forces, was identified as a student at a university in Kairouan, an inland city known for its piety.
In preparation for the attack, the gunman disguised himself as a beachgoer, in shorts and a T-shirt, and used a beach umbrella to conceal his Kalashnikov assault rifle. Terrified swimmers and sunbathers scattered as he raked the hotel beach and pool area with gunfire.
In a triumphalist statement issued hours after the attack, Islamic State asserted online that it had targeted infidels at the seaside resort, adding that the victims were mostly from Crusader countries that are fighting  the Caliphate, a reference to the groups self-declared state in parts of Iraq and Syria.
38 people dead in a shooting spree but where's the front page outrage? Since it's international and not about white people and it can't be connected to gun control in the US.
Consumer Probe
46
Tunisian officials announced Saturday that the 38 dead in the Sousse shootings included 24 British nationals  a heavy toll that British Prime Minister David Cameron had warned his public to expect as the magnitude of the assault became clear. The targeted hotel was popular with package tours originating in the United Kingdom.
The others killed included seven Tunisians, three Belgians, a Russian, a Ukrainian and a German, said Kamel Jendoubi, a Tunisian government minister. One victims nationality had not been determined, he said, though Irish authorities had previously said one Irish woman was killed.
Heightened safety measures unveiled at an overnight news conference by Prime Minister Habib Essid included the mobilization of army reservists for deployment to tourist-heavy areas such as beach resorts and archaeological sites, and the planned shutdown of some 80 mosques operating outside official controls and accused of spreading venom.
The prime minister also hinted at the possibility of a broader crackdown on political parties and other entities acting outside the constitution, a move that could prompt a backlash from Tunisiassizable Islamist bloc.
Islamists won power at the polls following the countrys 2010-11 uprising, which set off a wave of pro-democracy revolts across the region. But after a disastrous run at ruling Tunisia, the Islamists later ceded power and agreed to work in cooperation with a secular-minded administration. 
Still reeling from the March museum attack, Tunisia now faces a heavy new blow to its tourist trade, a mainstay of the faltering economy. Economic discontent was a driving force behind the uprising against longtime dictator Zine Abidine Ben Ali that erupted nearly five years ago, and chronic joblessness among young men is viewed as heightening the lure of Islamic extremism.
Tunisia has been the source of thousands of Islamic State recruits for the battlefield in Syria, and authorities fear their return home could have a deeply destabilizing effect. Chaos in neighboring Libya has also rattled Tunisia; the museum attackers were reported to have received training there. 
Staff writer King reported from Cairo and special correspondent Hassan from Berlin.
Twitter: @laurakingLAT
UPDATE
12:58 p.m.: This story has been updated with additional information about the nationality of the victims.
7:55 a.m. This story was updated with the announcement of a day of mourning in Kuwait and Islamic State assertions about the attack in Tunisia.
This story was originally published at 3:52 a.m.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State militants routed from Syria border city</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-islamic-state-militants-routed-from-syria-border-city-20150627-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Kurdish fighters in the Syrian border city of Kobani, backed by U.S.-led airstrikes, said Saturday they had expelled Islamic State militants who went on a killing spree months after having been routed by Kurdish forces.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State militants routed from Syria border city
Turkey Syrian Islamic State
Yasin Akgul / AP
People standing on the Turkish side of the border with Syria, on the outskirts of Suruc, Turkey, watch as smoke rises over Kobani, in Syria, on Saturday.
People standing on the Turkish side of the border with Syria, on the outskirts of Suruc, Turkey, watch as smoke rises over Kobani, in Syria, on Saturday.
(Yasin Akgul / AP)
Several months ago, Keith Broomfield informed startled relatives that he had decided to join the fight against Islamic State. ( Alexandra Zavis and Kamiran Sadoun )
The Sunni extremists blasted their way into Kobani, just south of the Turkish border, on Thursday with a series of car bombs, seizing a school and using it as a springboard for apparent revenge attacks. More than 200 people were killed, many of them civilians including women and children, according to activists. The ultimate toll could more than double once bodies in homes and structures are recovered, the activists said after the town had been re-secured.
Kobani assumed outsized significance last year when Islamic State besieged it for months before being driven back in January. Along the way, the city became a symbol of Kurdish defenders determination to fight off the jihadists, and of the Kurds role as the most reliable ground fighters allied with the U.S.-led coalition confronting Islamic State in Syria and Iraq.
These Kurdish fighters are the only ones who are successful against ISIS.Bravo!
honoreelliot
4
Activist Mustafa Ebdi, speaking by phone from Kobani, said at least 250 people were killed during the three-day incursion, a count that could grow to 500, he said. On Saturday, the main Kurdish militia, known as the YPG, blew up the school where Islamic State fighters had been holed up and ejected them from five other areas, he said.
The YPG, also known as the People's Protection Units, is a militia tasked with protecting the Kurdish minority amid Syrias multi-sided civil war. But its presence along the Turkish frontier has infuriated Turkey. The Ankara government considers the force a close cousin of what it deems terrorists of the Kurdish Workers Party or PKK, which battled the Turkish state for decades.
In September, the U.S-led military coalition, in coordination with YPG fighters on the ground, launched withering airstrikes to roll back Islamic States presence in wide swaths of Iraq and Syria. U.S planes kept up an intense barrage as the group pressed its attack on Kobani.
In January, with Kobani reduced to little more than rubble, Islamic State withdrew. But its renewed raid on Kobani may have been meant to surprise and demoralize Kurdish forces, who were buoyed by victory earlier this month in another border town, Tal Abyad.
That battle helped Kurds unite territory under their control and cut off an important supply route Islamic State had used between the Turkish border and its de facto capital, Raqaa, 50 miles to the south.
Although driven from Kobani, Islamic State fighters continued to press an offensive against government-held areas in the northeastern Syrian city of Hasaka, which is jointly held by troops loyal to President Bashar Assad and Kurdish forces. The Reuters news agency reported the government had appealed to residents to take up arms to defend the city.
The U.S.-led coalition said Saturday it had staged 14 airstrikes against Islamic State positions in Syria since Tuesday, including four near Kobani, five near Raqaa and two near Hasaka.
laura.king@latimes.com
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia and NATO raising stakes with military buildups and rhetoric</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-nato-russia-exchange-threats-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Russia and NATO have embarked on rival arms buildups and toughened their posture and rhetoric against each other, raising the security stakes between the two former Cold War adversaries while claiming to be reacting defensively to the other's threats.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia and NATO raising stakes with military buildups and rhetoric
NATO
Geert Vanden Wijngaert / Associated Press
European Council President Donald Tusk, right, speaks with NATO Secretary-General Jens Stoltenberg during a meeting between the Western military alliance and officials of the European Union, which is also enduring strained relations with Russia.
European Council President Donald Tusk, right, speaks with NATO Secretary-General Jens Stoltenberg during a meeting between the Western military alliance and officials of the European Union, which is also enduring strained relations with Russia.
(Geert Vanden Wijngaert / Associated Press)
Though Russian and Western officials repeatedly claim they don't want a return to Cold War-era hostility, both sides have renewed sanctions and toughened their military posture in recent days. ( Carol J. Williams )
Defense ministers of the U.S.-led North Atlantic Treaty Organization wrapped up a two-day gathering in Brussels on Friday that followed announcements that the Pentagon would deploy hundreds of tanks, armored vehicles, artillery and transports to six Eastern European countries that were once part of or allied with the Soviet Union.
As the Western alliance officials firmed up plans for their new rapid-reaction force to respond to dangers they see emanating from Russia and the Middle East, a senior Russian security official cast the moves as evidence that Washington and its "flaccid" European allies are aiming to dominate Russia.
8
They would like very much to see Russia cease to exist as a country, Russian Security Council chief Nikolai Patrushev told the newspaper Kommersant in an interview widely distributed by other state-run media.
Patrushev, who was director of the KGB-successor Federal Security Service for the decade before he was tapped to head the security council in 2008, portrayed the war in Ukraine as a U.S.-instigated disturbance to blame on Russia and undermine the regional balance of power between the Cold War-era rivals.
Russian President Vladimir Putin and other Kremlin officials have issued stern warnings of "consequences" should NATO deploy troops and armaments to Eastern Europe.
U.S. Defense Secretary Ashton Carter announced during his tour this week of NATO's eastern flank that the alliance would be positioning equipment and arms for a bolstering of defenses against any Russian aggression. The military buildup is destined for Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania and Bulgaria -- all former Soviet republics or satellites that Moscow still considers part of its "sphere of influence."
Russia and the United States are embarked on massive military modernization programs that will commit hundreds of billions of dollars to upgrading defenses and armaments.
cComments
This is all so unnecessary. I don't get what Obama and the Nato and EU creeps think they going to acheive from this other than to keep US defense contractors and their shareholders wealthy. Eventually a red line is going to be crossed, and then it will be WWIII or whatever passes for...
jackwelles
3
The Kremlin launched its $500-billion, decade-long defense upgrade in 2010, and Putin has said the program will be spared cutbacks even though the Russian economy is in recession and most other government spending is being pared sharply.
At an arms fair near Moscow this month, Putin announced that at least 40 new nuclear-capable intercontinental ballistic missiles would be deployed by the end of the year to confront what the Kremlin said in its newly revised defense doctrine is the greatest threat to Russian national security: NATO.
Carter responded to Putin's latest reminder to the West of his country's vast nuclear arsenal by telling reporters accompanying him on his European tour that "nuclear weapons are not something that should be the subject of loose rhetoric by world leadership."
On Thursday, Deputy Defense Secretary Robert Work told the House Armed Services Committee that Putin and other Russian leaders were "playing with fire" in raising the specter of nuclear warfare.
The United States, which provides the bulk of NATO's weapons and funding, is also planning a major upgrade of its nuclear armaments that will cost a minimum of $355 billion over the next decade, the congressional representatives were told.
Work appealed to the U.S. lawmakers for more funding for the Pentagon to avoid having to cut into other important defense needs.
"Without additional funding dedicated to strategic forces modernization, sustaining this level of spending will require very, very hard choices and will impact the other parts of the defense portfolio, Work said.
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Militants strike in France, Tunisia and Kuwait, killing as many as 60</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-france-tunisia-kuwait-attacks-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Armed militants struck within hours of each other on three continents Friday, wielding bombs, firearms and a gruesome display of a decapitated head in a demonstration of the growing global reach of Islamist violence.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Militants strike in France, Tunisia and Kuwait, killing as many as 60
Kuwait mosque
Raed Qutena / European Pressphoto Agency
Medical workers and security forces inspect the sceneinside a Shiite mosque in Kuwait City after a bombing, for which the Islamic State claimed responsibility. As many as two dozen people were killed in the attack.
Medical workers and security forces inspect the sceneinside a Shiite mosque in Kuwait City after a bombing, for which the Islamic State claimed responsibility. As many as two dozen people were killed in the attack.
(Raed Qutena / European Pressphoto Agency)
Assault
Armed militants struck within hours of each other on three continents Friday, wielding bombs, firearms and a gruesome display of a decapitated head in a demonstration of the growing global reach of Islamist violence.
The militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing of a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and an attack on a seaside resort in Tunisia, and it may have at least inspired an attack on a gas factory in France. The extremist organization, now controlling large parts of Iraq and Syria, has sought to expand its influence well beyond the Middle East.
As many as 60 people were killed in the attacks, more than half of them by a gunman who went on a rampage outside a hotel popular with foreign holidaymakers on the sunny Tunisian coast. Up to two dozen people died in the bombing of the mosque, and one man was beheaded in France. The violence marred the holy month of Ramadan, which began last week.
Islamists suspected in attack on French gas plant
Assailants rammed a car into a gas plant in France on Friday morning, triggering two blasts. The severed head of previously killed man and a flag with Arabic inscriptions were found at the scene.
Assailants rammed a car into a gas plant in France on Friday morning, triggering two blasts. The severed head of previously killed man and a flag with Arabic inscriptions were found at the scene.
See more videos
An Islamic State leader this week had called on acolytes to use Ramadan, traditionally a time of spiritual reflection and acts of kindness, as an opportunity instead to bring calamity for the infidels.
Be keen to conquer in this holy month and to become exposed to martyrdom, Abu MohammadAdnani, a spokesman for the Sunni militant group, said in an audio message released Tuesday. He urged followers to mount attacks in Libya, Syria and Iraq against Westerners, Shiite Muslims and any Sunni Muslims who opposed Islamic State.
He also warned President Obama of retaliation for the air raids that U.S. forces have helped carry out against the militants.
8
The nearly half-hour audio message was a fresh example of Islamic States sophistication in disseminating its extreme worldview through online and social media, tools that allow the group to project its gospel of violence far outside the territory it rules with an iron fist.
Islamic State has definitely proved itself a lot more capable than major groups in the past at spreading that propaganda, whether it be blogging, the Internet, said Alan Fraser, a Middle East expert at the London-based risk consultancy AKE. And part of the brutality of Islamic States activities in Iraq and Syria [is] designed to get that kind of media attention.
Thats one of its tactics. Its very hard to combat.
Savagery akin to that seen in the groups slickly, and sickly, produced videos of mass executions and beheadings was evident in the attacks Friday, which struck places of work, worship and relaxation in Europe, Asia and Africa, respectively.
The severed head of a previously killed man was hung from a fence near the U.S.-owned gas factory in southeastern France that attackers tried to blow up by ramming a car into the plant about 9:30 a.m. Friday. Flags with Arabic inscriptions lay close by, French media reported.
French President Francois Hollande said a message had been written on the decapitated body. He added that there was no doubt it was a terrorist attack, and French anti-terrorism prosecutors have opened an investigation.
Two other people were injured in the explosion at the Air Products factory in the small town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside the city of Lyon, Hollande said.
A suspect was quickly arrested after the incident and, though prosecutors said he refused to talk, was identified as 35-year-old delivery truck driver Yassin Sahli, who was known to workers at the plant. Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said that French intelligence services had designatedSahli in 2006 as a potential extremist but stopped monitoring him two years later for undisclosed reasons.
cComments
France is most likely on the cusp of a ramp up in fundamentalist/extremist domestic violence. Arguably, France has over 5 million Muslims, many of them marginalized. They have a bit of historical dirty laundry in Tunisia and Syria that has not been forgotten nor forgiven. Until they get a...
DougInTheCanyon
12
Before being detained for questioning, a woman who said she was Sahlis wife told Europe 1 radio that she had been married to her husband for a decade and that they and their three children were normal Muslims who led a normal family life.
I don't know whats going on. Its not possible, she said in an increasingly distraught voice, describing her husband as very, very calm.
French media reported that the beheaded man was Sahlis employer, the boss of a local transport company.
The gruesome violence in France came less than six months after the Jan. 7 rampage in Paris at the headquarters of Charlie Hebdo, the satirical magazine targeted because of its cartoons of the prophet Muhammad, and a Jewish supermarket. Twenty people were killed, including the three attackers.
France has been on alert for further attacks. In April, an Algerian national linked by authorities to Al Qaeda and Islamic State was arrested on suspicion of plotting a gun attack on churches in Paris.
Security was stepped up at other sites in the region where Fridays assault occurred, for fear that the incident might either serve as a prelude to a larger attack elsewhere or inspiration for copycats.
In Tunisia, a gunman disguised as a bather killed at least 37 people with a Kalashnikov rifle that he hid under a beach umbrella and used to strafe the pool and shore area of a hotel in Sousse, a popular vacation spot about 90 miles south of the capital, Tunis.
Terrified swimmers dashed out of the surf to find cover. Sunbathers were shot dead in their lounge chairs on the private beach fronting the Hotel Riu Imperial Marhaba.
Many of the dead were European travelers, according to Tunisian officials. Britain confirmed that at least five British nationals were killed.
Vacationer Steve Johnson told the BBC that he and others barricaded themselves in the hotel spa to wait until they were told it was safe to come out.
We heard what we thought was fireworks, he said. Then people were screaming and starting to run in all directions.
An official from the Tunisian Interior Ministry told Tunisian radio that the gunman was killed by security forces. The official identified the attacker as a student from the city of Kairouan, 35 miles inland from Sousse.
It was the second major strike in three months on the crucial tourist industry in the North African nation, which had been one of the few bright spots to emerge from the Arab Spring uprisings that tried to bring more democracy to the region. In March, attackers shot dead 21 visitors, most of them Europeancruise passengers, at the Bardo National Museum in Tunis.
------------
FOR THE RECORD
5:10 p.m.: A previous version of this post said most of the Bardo National Museum victims were Egyptian cruise passengers. They were European passengers.
------------
Militants declaring allegiance to Islamic State claimed responsibility for that assault.
Friday's rampage was praised on a forum associated with Islamic State. A Tunisian calling himself Abou Anas said gleefully on Twitter: Didnt we tell you that this is a month of conquests, a hard blow to tourism.
He characterized the dead as apostate crusaders and added: Hahahaha.
In the only one of Fridays three attacks that Islamic State said it directly instigated, a suicide bomber blew himself up inside a Shiite Muslim mosque in Kuwait. The Persian Gulf nation has witnessed a recent rise in sectarian tensions between Sunni and Shiite Muslims.
Video footage showed dazed, white-clad worshipers milling about in the smoke from the blast, which killed up to two dozen people.
Despite the close timing of the three attacks in France, Tunisia and Kuwait, a Pentagon spokesman said it was too soon to tell whether they were coordinated centrally or coincidental.
We continue to look into it, U.S. Army Col. Steve Warren said. Were collecting intelligence as rapidly as possible.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 02:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks signal opposition to plan that would avert looming default</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-europe-bailout-default-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  With the threat of economic catastrophe less than four days away, Greek officials and their international creditors continued to clash Friday over how to raise the money the Balkan nation needs to keep up with debt payments and get an extension on its bailout program.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greeks signal opposition to plan that would avert looming default
Greece euro
Louisa Gouliamaki / AFP/Getty Images
A couple rests on the Pnyx hill near the Acropolis in Athens on Friday while Greek officials were still wrangling with creditors on a bailout program extension to avert a default that looms in four days.
A couple rests on the Pnyx hill near the Acropolis in Athens on Friday while Greek officials were still wrangling with creditors on a bailout program extension to avert a default that looms in four days.
(Louisa Gouliamaki / AFP/Getty Images)
European Union
With the threat of economic catastrophe less than four days away, Greek officials and their international creditors continued to clash Friday over how to raise the money the Balkan nation needs to keep up with debt payments and get an extension on its bailout program.
Early Saturday, after an emergency Cabinet meeting in Athens, Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras announced he wouldcall a referendum July 5 to poll Greeks' willingness to endure more budget and services cuts. The nation'sdevelopment minister urged voters to say "no."
The differences between the budget-balancing visions of Greece's radical leftist government and the "troika" of lenders owed $270 billion boil down to the former seeking to put the austerity burdens on profitable businesses and the creditors demanding cuts to pensions and government salaries.
Alexis Tsipras
Geert Vanden Wijngaert / Associated Press
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras looked confidentdespite his country's looming default as he left a European Union summit in Brussels on Friday.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras looked confidentdespite his country's looming default as he left a European Union summit in Brussels on Friday.
(Geert Vanden Wijngaert / Associated Press)
While no formal negotiations took place on Friday, the Greek delegation reportedly submitted a slightly revised proposal with concessions on raising the retirement age and eliminating pension supplements for the lowest earners. But Athens reportedly hasn't budged in its insistence on raising the money it needs on the backs of business.
There were also reports by European media of an offer from the creditors to extend Greece's bailout program by five months, until November, and provide an additional $13.4 billion to help Athens meet its obligations, on condition the heavily indebted country commit to a strict timetable for budget reforms.
8
Tsipras denounced the creditors' insistence on more budget cuts as "an ultimatum that is against the values of Europe." And in a move apparently aimed at getting another week's delay in making a $1.8-billion debt payment, Tsipras announced he would call a referendum to measure public support for the new belt-tightening demands. There was no immediate word from the creditors, who have insisted on a viable and politically endorsed reform plan by Tuesday.
Greek Development Minister Panagiotis Lafazanis predicted that his countrymen would answer "with a resounding no," the Associated Press reported from the emergency session that ended in the wee hours Saturday.
Tsipras and his Syriza party came to power in January after campaigning on promises to ease the painful austerity measures imposed by the creditors overseeing the bailout program. Five years of cuts to the government payroll and public services have contributed to Greece's economy contracting by 25% since 2010 and job losses that have left 26% of working-age Greeks unemployed.
Tsipras and his delegation to the negotiations raised hopes early this week with new offers to boost business taxes and raise enough future revenue to persuade the creditors to release the last $8 billion left in the bailout fund before the rescue program expires Tuesday.
But officials of the lending institutions -- the International Monetary Fund, the European Central Bank and the European Commission -- have said they fear putting the burden on business will suppress growth and scuttle long-term prospects for economic stability in Greece. The creditors want Athens to accelerate its plan for raising the retirement age to 67 and to phase out "solidarity grants" currently paid to retirees with the lowest incomes.
That divergence of priorities led the two sides to an impasse Thursday. The talks in Brussels between Greek officials and the foreign ministers of the other 18 countries that use the euro common currency failed to produce a plan to secure enough new borrowing to make the $1.8-billion payment on IMF debt due by Tuesday.
"We're expecting the payment to be made June 30, IMF spokesman Gerry Rice said at the fund's headquarters in Washington, making clear that there will be no grace period offered to Athens.
cComments
@the_PB, Reading a bit more the 300 billion must include private debt. Federal debt is 175% of GDP, a high but manageable number if they get the financing. Fix the culture of tax evasion and excessive bureaucracy. The Greeks have simply run out of room to borrow.
the_PB
6
Tuesday is also the last day of the current bailout program, and if no deal has been reached on an extension or renewal, the $8 billion left in the fund will revert to the lenders and Greece will be cut off from further operating funds and cash infusions to keep the banks solvent.
Fear of that default has already caused a run on euro deposits in Greek banks over the last two weeks, compelling the European Central Bank to provide almost daily emergency liquidity funds to deter full-scale panic. If the bailout program expires and Greece misses its Tuesday debt payment, the ECB would have neither obligation nor interest in providing more euro infusions, forcing Athens to issue a national currency that would quickly lose value versus the euro.
Tsipras and Greek Finance Minister YanisVaroufakis have been resistant to the creditors' insistence on spending cuts, in particular any that would hurt already struggling pensioners, in a standoff that suggests they expect their Eurozone colleagues and creditors to make further concessions to protect the integrity of the common currency union. Analysts are divided on how widespread would be the economic fallout if Greece were to drop out of the Eurozone but many think the other Eurozone countries are loathe to gamble on an assumption that there would be little or no damage to their own well-being.
Leaders of the 28-nation European Union met in Brussels on Thursday for their semi-annual summit and issued a stern message to Greece and its European creditors to get a deal done this weekend.
"Leaders expect the Eurogroup to conclude this process at their meeting on Saturday, European Commission President Donald Tusk said early Friday.
Even if the Greek delegation manages to agree with the lenders on the reforms needed to get the last of the bailout funds released so Athens can make its IMF payment, the deal would still face hurdles in getting endorsement by the Syriza-dominated parliament. Many of the deputies elected for their promises to get austerity eased could face public backlash and ouster if they give their approval to the deeper and even more painful cuts demanded by the lenders.
A copy of the latest proposal submitted by Athens, obtained by Britain's Financial Times and posted on the newspaper's website, suggests that the Greeks have retreated from some earlier concessions to end special tax exemptions for Greek islands and raise taxes on processed foods.
Those backtracks, coupled with Athens' continued refusal to make spending cuts instead of tax hikes, could scuttle the weekend talks and the prospects for averting default -- unless other Eurozone countries want to keep Greece within the currency alliance more than the Greeks themselves want to stay in.
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7

Copyright  2015, Los Angeles Times
UPDATE
4:55 p.m.: This story has been updated to add that the Greek development minister is appealing to voters to reject creditors' terms for extending bailout and averting default.
4:00 p.m.: This story has been updated to add that Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras has called for a July 5 referendum.
This story was originally published at 12:33 p.m.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 00:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air Products: The firm targeted in suspected terrorist attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-air-products-attack-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The facility targeted in a suspected terror attack Friday in southeastern France is an American-owned industrial gas plant.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>0
Emergency services were deployed to the site and all those who work there were evacuated, the statement said.
Air Products officials said security had been increased at its operations around the world as a precautionary measure. The company has facilities in more than 50 countries employing more than 21,000 people.
Founded in 1940, Air Products is a Fortune 500 company , placing at no. 284 on this year's list ranking the largest U.S. corporations, with more than $10 billion in annual sales.
The company is one of the world's largest suppliers of industrial gas, breaking down air to form oxygen, nitrogen and other components used in construction, oil refining, healthcare and other industries. It also produces specialty chemicals for electronics companies and equipment used in the energy sector.
Its French subsidiary, created in 1990, employs about 400 people. It is described on the company's website as the third largest producer of atmospheric gases in France, with more than 15% of the market. [Link in French]
Seifi Ghasemi, a native of Iran, took over as chief executive of Air Products last summer, replacing John McGlade after a protracted battle with billionaire investor William Ackman, who had complained that the company was trailing its competitors.
"This incident reinforces that we all need to take safety and security very seriously, every day, and remain vigilant in everything we do," Ghasemi said in a statement Friday. "I am very glad to know that all of our employees are safe and accounted for.
For more international news, follow @alexzavis on Twitter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 37 reported killed in attack on Tunisian beach</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-attack-tunisian-beach-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  A gunman disguised as a bather, with an automatic weapon concealed under a beach umbrella he carried, raked a seaside hotel's shore and pool area with bullets on Friday, killing at least 37 people, many of them European visitors, and injuring dozens more, Tunisian officials said.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>At least 37 reported killed in attack on Tunisian beach
Tunisia terrorism
Fethi Belaid / AFP/Getty Images
Tunisian security forces stand in front of the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital on June 26.
Tunisian security forces stand in front of the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital on June 26.
(Fethi Belaid / AFP/Getty Images)
Arab Spring
A gunman disguised as a bather, with an automatic weapon concealed under a beach umbrella he carried, raked a seaside hotels shore and pool area with bullets on Friday, killing at least 37 people, many of them European visitors, and injuring dozens more, Tunisian officials said.
It was the second major strike in just over three months against a tourist target in the North African country, rare in the region for its progressive and secularist traditions and one of the few beacons of relative stability in the wake of the Arab Spring uprisings more than four years ago.
Islamic State militants stopped short of claiming responsibility for the attack, but it was praised on a forum associated with the extremist group.
Islamic State jihadists engaged in a bloody rampage in the Kurdish-majority Syrian city of Kobani and its environs on Friday, officials said, executing at least 142 civilians before withdrawing as vicious fighting continued in the town for a second day. ( Nabih Bulos )
The assault took place outside a beach hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, at noontime on a hot summer day when the seaside was crowded with visitors. The city, about 90 miles south of the capital, Tunis, is a popular destination for tourists traveling from Europe as well as elsewhere in the country and the region, attracting many package visitors from Britain.
Officials initially believed there were two attackers, but later said the strike appeared to have been carried out by a lone gunman, who was shot dead. Tunisian media later reported the arrest of two accomplices.
8
There was no immediate claim of responsibility, though suspicion fell on Islamist militants who have sought to destablize Tunisia by harming its fragile economy. Tunisias Health Ministry said the dead included nationals from Tunisia, Britain, Germany and Belgium, and the Irish government said one of its citizens had been killed.
A Tunisian calling himself Abou Anas, who is affiliated with the Islamic State-affiliated forum Ifriqiyah Media, tweeted gleefully after the attack: Didnt we tell you that this is a month of conquests, a hard blow to tourism. He characterized the dead as apostate crusaders and added: Hahahaha.
Witnesses to Fridays attack described terrified swimmers dashing from the surf to run for cover and sunbathers shot dead in their lounge chairs on the private beach fronting the Imperial Marhaba hotel -- named for an Arabic greeting. British vacationer Steve Johnson told the BBC that he and others barricaded themselves in the hotel spa to wait until they were told it was safe to emerge.
We heard what we thought was fireworks, then people were screaming and starting to run in all directions, he said. Another vacationer, Briton Gary Pine, told Channel 4 in London that he heard dozens of gunshots.
You could hear the bullets whizzing through the air, he said. I was happy to get of that beach, as youd imagine.
@NOTATE REDMOND Exactly. A cheap vacation is not worth it if you can loose your life there.
larry20111
13
The assailant sneaked into the complex by dressing like a beachgoer and carrying a beach umbrella under which he hid a Kalashnikov rifle, senior Interior Ministry official Rafiq Chelli told Tunisias Radio Mosaique. He identified the attacker, who he said was killed by security forces, as a student from the city of Kairouan, 35 miles inland from Sousse.
It was not the only terror attack to rattle the region on Friday. In Kuwait, an explosion at a Shiite Muslim mosque killed up to 24 people, according to news reports  the latest in a string of sectarian bombings in the Persian Gulf region at a time of rising Shiite-Sunni tensions. Islamic State, which says it has carried out similar attacks in Saudi Arabia and Yemen, claimed responsibility.
At the scene of the shooting in Sousse, police swiftly converged on the waterfront, blocking off access to the hotel and neighboring resorts as an army helicopter buzzed overhead, witnesses said. A Tunisian radio reporter at the scene said security forces handled the body of the slain attacker with extreme care, apparently in case he had been carrying explosives.
Tunisias tourism industry had already suffered a devastating blow on March 18, when attackers hit the Bardo National Museum in the capital, whose antiquities were a major draw for visitors. That attack left 21 people dead, most of them European tourists on a cruise-ship stopover. Militants declaring allegiance to the Islamic State claimed responsibility.
The tourism sector is crucial for the economy in Tunisia, which is considered the only real success story in the wake uprisings that swept the region, the first of them beginning in Tunisia in late 2010. The country has been relatively politically stable, especially compared with its chaos-riven neighbor Libya, but the calm has been punctuated by occasional Islamist attacks, and economic stagnation and joblessness are major concerns.
Radicalization of young Tunisians has been a worsening worry for Tunisian authorities. The country has been by some reckonings the largest source of recruits to the Islamic State, with more than 3,000 young men having slipped away to fight in Syria or Iraq.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 20:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Korean conscientious objectors keep up fight against military service</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-korea-conscientious-objectors-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  It was a prison term, Lee Min-young says, that he had been anticipating his whole life, and on Friday it was finally confirmed: The 25-year-old was sent to spend 18 months behind bars.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>South Korean conscientious objectors keep up fight against military service
South Korean conscientious objector Lee Min-young
Steven Borowiec / For The Times
Conscientious objector Lee Min-young, 25, was ordered to spend 18 months in prison for refusing to serve in the South Korean military. 
Conscientious objector Lee Min-young, 25, was ordered to spend 18 months in prison for refusing to serve in the South Korean military. 
(Steven Borowiec / For The Times)
By Steven Borowiec
Lee Myung-bak
It was a prison term, Lee Min-young says, that he had been anticipating his whole life, and on Friday it was finally confirmed: The 25-year-old was sent to spend 18 months behind bars.
That is Lees punishment for objecting to South Koreas mandatory military service for all able-bodied men. The question of how to respect the civil and religious rights of those who refuse combat duty faces South Korean politicians and military seeking to maintain a fighting force capable of deterring North Korea.
Lee is from a family of Jehovahs Witnesses and says that military service requirements to fire a weapon, and possibly engage in combat with North Korean soldiers, conflict with his religious beliefs.
When Kim Dong-hyun arrived at work on April 16 last year, he turned on his computer and noticed a news alert: A ferry was sinking off South Korea's south coast. In an instant, Kim, 53, was overcome with dread, realizing the ship was carrying his only daughter, Da-young. ( Steven Borowiec )
Lee has also worried that his refusal to serve might hurt his prospects for career and marriage. If I go to jail, Ill be stigmatized forever. That stigma will be like a wall between me and the rest of society for the rest of my life, Lee said in an interview last month. Still, he said he was holding fast to his beliefs, pointing to a passage from the Book of Proverbs as the basis for his decision: Rejoice not when thine enemy falleth, and let not thine heart be glad when he stumbleth. Lest the Lord see it, and it displease him.
8
Some 600 conscientious objectors are currently behind bars in South Korea, most of them Jehovahs Witnesses, for refusing to serve in the 650,000-strong military. Though South Korea has several alternative service options for men like Lee, including working in administrative roles in government offices, even these recruits must go through a month of combat training  a requirement that some find unacceptable.
Jehovahs Witness groups estimate that 18,000 South Korean men have served time for being conscientious objectors. South Koreas mandatory military service has its roots in the 1950-53 Korean War. An armistice agreement ended the combat, but a peace treaty has never been signed. Actual conflict between North and South is rare but not unheard of; the last case involving casualties came in 2010, when two soldiers and two civilians were killed when North Korea shelled a South Korean island.
Proponents of mandatory service argue that South Korea must maintain a large, combat-ready military to deter North Korea and respond in case of an attack. Peace is not a birthright, but can only be preserved through military readiness, South Koreas Ministry of National Defense says in an e-book published on its website. (About 28,500 U.S. troops are also stationed in South Korea.)
In May, Amnesty International released a report on South Koreas conscientious objectors, calling on the government to release the 600 men currently incarcerated on such charges.
It seems that conscientious objectors can be given non-combat related duties that do not require combat training. Stretcher bearers, medics, cooks, etc., would fall into such categories. Besides, you would not want to trust a conscientious objector handling a weapon.
rtamtc
2
Military service is seen as a patriotic duty by mainstream society due to the security situation in the Korean peninsula. Men who do not fulfill this duty are often considered to be traitors, Amnesty wrote in the report, which found that more than 90% of jailed conscientious objectors in the world are South Korean.
In 2007, under liberal President Roh Moo-hyun, the South Korean government announced plans to expand alternative service options for conscientious objectors, but those plans were put on ice with the election of the conservative Lee Myung-bak the following year.
In May, a South Korean court acquitted three men facing charges for refusal of military service. All three gave religion as their reason.
It is necessary to provide a harmonious interpretation of freedom of conscience under the constitution and the duty of national defense prescribed in the constitution, as these two constitutional values come in conflict with each other, the court ruling stated.
Provincial courts have twice before issued similar rulings that were later overturned by the Supreme Court. In the case last month of the three objectors, the ruling will be reviewed by the Supreme Court and is likely to be overturned, in line with precedent.
Lee said last month that he had been encouraged by the May ruling. He was not available for comment after his own hearing Friday in the Supreme Court, his last and whose outcome he cannot appeal.
Lee was taken into custody Friday and will probably be transferred directly to a prison where he will serve out his sentence, said Steven Park, public information officer for the Jehovahs Witnesses Korea branch, that advises conscientious objectors.
Lee said in May he hadnt yet decided on a particular career to embark on once he is released, but he planned to spend his time in prison praying and making plans. His family operates a small jewelry store in Yangpyeong, about an hour east of Seoul.
Despite his loss of freedom, he said he had no regrets about objecting to military service.
Militaries are supposed to exist to work for peace, but even though we have this huge military, were not safe, Lee said. We need some other way of achieving peace -- not through force.
Borowiec is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 19:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading, explosion at French factory called terrorist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-explosion-beheading-terror-probe-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading, explosion at French factory called terrorist attack
Islamists suspected in attack on French gas plant
Assailants rammed a car into a gas plant in France on Friday morning, triggering two blasts. The severed head of previously killed man and a flag with Arabic inscriptions were found at the scene.
Assailants rammed a car into a gas plant in France on Friday morning, triggering two blasts. The severed head of previously killed man and a flag with Arabic inscriptions were found at the scene.
Terrorism
One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said.
One suspect has been arrested in connection with the attack, said French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve, adding that intelligence services had identified the man as a potential extremist in 2006 but stopped monitoring him two years later.
The facility targeted in a suspected terror attack Friday in southeastern France is an American-owned industrial gas plant. ( Alexandra Zavis )
Cazeneuve named the suspect as Yessim Salim or Yacine Sali, according to conflicting spellings given in various news reports.
In response, Hollande called a crisis meeting of France's Defense Council on Friday afternoon. Gerard Larcher, president of the Senate, the French upper house of parliament, described the attack as "intolerable" and said there was a sense of "deep shock" across France.
8
Speaking in Brussels on Friday morning before a planned European Union summit, Hollande said the attack was carried out shortly before 10 a.m. by one or possibly two men in a car who clearly intended to blow up the Air Products factory in the small town of Saint Quentin Fallavier, near the city of Lyon. The plant manufactures industrial gases.
Hollande said there was no doubt that it was a terrorist assault. French anti-terrorist prosecutors have opened an investigation.
French media reported that the severed head of the decapitated victim was found hanging on the factory fence, near a flag bearing Arabic inscriptions. Hollande said that a message of some sort had been written on the body.
The victim was a 50-year-old man who may have been the arrested man's employer at a transport company that had dealings with the factory, French officials and media reports said.
The other victims were hurt in an explosion set off when the attackers rammed their car into the factory gates, according to news reports. The severity of the injuries was not immediately clear.
A woman identified as the suspect's wife told Europe 1 radio that she had been married to her husband since 2005 and that they and their three children were "normal Muslims" who led "a normal family life."
"I don't know what's going on. It's not possible," she said, describing her husband as "very, very calm."
She said he worked as a delivery driver and usually left each morning at 7 a.m. and returned between noon and 2 p.m. But on Friday he did not return.
"War is the terrorism of the rich and powerful and terrorism is the war of the poor and powerless." -Peter Ustinov.
moonpuckey
74
Gendarmes quickly sealed off roads around the Air Products factory and referred inquiries to the public prosecutors office more than 50 miles away in the city of Grenoble.
A 23-year-old man who gave his name as Mehdi and who lives close to the factory expressed his contempt for the attackers.
I am a young Muslim who is keeping Ramadan right now. To carry out this attack on a Friday during the holy month is not respectful of Islam, said Mehdi, who was dressed in a long white djellaba. These people may call themselves Muslims, but they are not.
"I say to them, you do not have the right to cut off someone's head; you do not have the right to explode anything near our homes not far from where we live with our children, our nieces and nephews.
The gruesome violence came less than six months after the Jan. 7 rampage in Paris at the headquarters of Charlie Hebdo, the satirical magazine targeted because of its cartoons of the prophet Muhammad, and a Jewish supermarket. Twenty people were killed, including the three attackers.
France has been on alert for further attacks. In April, an Algerian national linked by authorities to Al Qaeda and Islamic State was arrested on suspicion of plotting a gun attack on churches in Paris.
Security was stepped up at other sites in the region where Fridays attack occurred, for fear that the incident might either be a prelude to a larger assault or inspiration for copycats.
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," Alain Juppe, a former French premier, said via Twitter. "The [French] state must do everything possible to protect its citizens."
Air Products is a U.S.-owned company founded in 1940 and headquartered in Allentown, Pa. It has offices around the world, including more than a dozen in Europe.
Staff writer Chu and special correspondent Boyle reported from London. Special correspondent Willsher reported from Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, France.
UPDATE
9:52 a.m.: This article was updated with new details and background.
5 a.m.: This article was updated with comments from Hollande and other details from the scene.
3:08 a.m.: This article was updated with new details and background.
This article was first posted at 2:55 a.m.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 18:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State said to kill scores in Syrian border city</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-kobani-killings-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Islamic State jihadists engaged in a bloody rampage in the Kurdish-majority Syrian city of Kobani and its environs on Friday, officials said, executing at least 142 civilians before withdrawing as vicious fighting continued in the town for a second day.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State said to kill scores in Syrian border city
Turkey Syria Islamic State
Associated Press
Turkish soldiersin the city of Suruc watch as smoke billows from the Syrian city of Kobani across the border following attacks by Islamic State militants.
Turkish soldiersin the city of Suruc watch as smoke billows from the Syrian city of Kobani across the border following attacks by Islamic State militants.
(Associated Press)
United Nations
Islamic State jihadists engaged in a bloody rampage in the Kurdish-majority Syrian city of Kobani and its environs on Friday, officials said, executing at least 142 civilians before withdrawing as vicious fighting continued in the town for a second day.
Idriss Naasan, vice minister for foreign affairs in Kobani's Kurdish administration, said Islamic State's aim was to terrorize the population of the community near the Turkish border, which was the scene of heavy fighting last year.
Several months ago, Keith Broomfield informed startled relatives that he had decided to join the fight against Islamic State. ( Alexandra Zavis and Kamiran Sadoun )
"They tried to kill the largest number of civilians, so they roamed around neighborhoods and targeted them," said Naasan, explaining that many women and children had been taken hostage by the militant group, complicating efforts to rout the extremists from the town.
He said the YPG, a Syrian Kurdish militia that has emerged as a powerful force against Islamic State, "has them surrounded from four points, but fighting continues because they are using civilians as human shields."
8
Rami Abdul Rahman, director of the pro-opposition monitor the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, described the attack as "a crime against humanity ... it's a barbaric massacre" in an interview with Sky News Arabia on Friday.
"The executions were perpetrated against entire families, [they were] completely exterminated," he said, adding that the death total would make this the second largest massacre perpetrated by the group. At least 28 Islamic State militants were killed in the clashes.
Kurdish activists uploaded scores of pictures showing victims of the rampage through Kobani as well as grim images of freshly dug trenches interspersed with lines of brick.
On Thursday, Islamic State fighters disguised as YPG fighters infiltrated Kobani after detonating a car bomb near the Mursitpinar crossing with Turkey. The group also struck the village of Brakh Botan, leaving tens of villagers dead as it made its way towards Kobani, 20 miles to the north.
Must have been a video that set them off.
InkandQuill
3
It was the first attack on Kobani in six months, after YPG forces, backed by U.S. planes, thwarted a four-month campaign by Islamic State to take the town. Yet, despite thousands of tons of ordnance pounding Islamic State targets, the group has maintained its presence in the northeastern region of Syria.
Meanwhile, Syrian army units continued to battle Islamic State militants in the northeastern city of Hasakeh, where fighting has displaced an estimated 60,000 civilians, according to the United Nations. The U.N. on Thursday also warned that the violence could spur an exodus of 200,000 refugees towards the border city of Qamishli, 45 miles northeast.
Hasakeh province governor Mohammad Za'al Al-Ali reassured civilians that the city was secure and the army and national defense units would remain in place.
"This is a call to the citizens of Hasakeh to return to their homes and be steadfast in them," said Ali in an interview with Syrian State news broadcaster SANA on Friday, denying reports of withdrawals by police and army units from state institutions from the city.
"We must not believe the rumors and lies spread by opportunists."
Many Kurds blame Islamic State's rampage against Kurdish areas in Syria on neighboring Turkey, whom they accuse of granting open access to the militant group across its more than 500-mile border with Syria. They also point to recent successes by Kurdish and Syrian opposition forces against Islamic State, such as in the border town of Tel Abyad, 36 miles east of Kobani.
"The aim is to obstruct the joint forces that are liberating these areas of terrorists," explained Naasan, blaming "regional agendas that are afraid of the Kurds enjoying their right to self-determination."
Turkey, on the other hand, sees the YPG as little more than a branch of the Kurdistan Workers' Party, with which it has been locked for more than 30 years in warfare.
Bulos is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State claims blast at Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-is-claims-blast-at-shiite-mosque-in-kuwait-s-capital-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The Islamic State group claimed responsibility for a deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State claims blast at Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital
Attack on Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque
YASSER AL-ZAYYAT / AFP/Getty Images
Kuwaiti security forces gather outside the Shiite Imam Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
Kuwaiti security forces gather outside the Shiite Imam Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
(YASSER AL-ZAYYAT / AFP/Getty Images)
By Associated Press
The Islamic State group claimed responsibility for a deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
8
A posting on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group said the attack was carried out by a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt. The attack was claimed by an IS affiliate calling itself the Najd Province, the same group that claimed a pair of bombing attacks on Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
Mosque bomb kills dozens in Kuwait
Dozens were killed in a suicide bombing targeting worshippers at a Shiite Muslim mosque in Kuwait.
Dozens were killed in a suicide bombing targeting worshippers at a Shiite Muslim mosque in Kuwait.
See more videos
Friday's explosion struck the Imam Sadiq Mosque in the neighborhood of al-Sawabir, a residential and shopping district of Kuwait City. Paramedics on the scene said at least two people were killed, but the death toll was expected to rise. One eyewitness told The Associated Press that he saw at least 10 dead bodies. Police formed a cordon around the mosque's complex immediately after the explosion, banning people from entering or gathering near the area. Ambulances could be seen ferrying the wounded from the site.
@B Blats No it doesn't. It's nutty.
revolting
5
"We couldn't see anything, so we went straight to the wounded and tried to carry them out. We left the dead," said witness Hassan al-Haddad, 21, who said he saw several dead bodies.
Abdullah al-Saffar, who was at the mosque, said the explosion took place just after midday Friday prayers. Friday midday prayers are typically the most crowded of the week, and attendance increases during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan, which started last week.
Another witness, Ahmad al-Shawaf, said worshippers were standing shoulder to shoulder in group prayer when the explosion struck near the door of the mosque, behind some of the worshippers. Al-Shawaf said the explosion took place near the end of a second prayer that is traditional to Shiites and that follows the main midday Friday prayer.
He said witnesses standing behind him said they saw a man walk in, stand in the back with other congregants and detonate his device.
Mohammed al-Faili, 32, said that his 70 year-old father was killed in the explosion and two of his brothers were also wounded. Speaking to the AP by telephone, he said he was not at the mosque at the time of the explosion but was heading to the morgue to identify his father's body.
The Islamic State group regards Shiite Muslims as heretics, and refers to them derogatively as "rafideen" or "rejectionists." The IS Twitter statement said the bomber had targeted a "temple of the apostates."
Kuwaiti Justice, Religious Endowment and Islamic Affairs Minister Yacoub al-Sanna described the attack as a "terrorist and cowardly action which threatens our nation and works at tearing apart the national unity."
Al-Sanna told the official state agency KUNA that, the government would take all necessary measure to ensure protection of houses of worship. "Kuwait was and will remain the oasis of security and safety to all components of the Kuwaiti society and sects," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France, Uber in culture crash: Taxi drivers violently protest ride-share app</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-uber-france-taxi-html-20150625-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Cars overturned. Roads blockaded with flaming tires. That's what happens when the U.S. sharing economy tangles with French protectionism. French taxi drivers protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against Uber, which is facing fierce opposition from traditional cabs. Hundreds...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Francois Hollande
Cars overturned. Roads blockaded with flaming tires. That's what happens when the U.S. sharing economy tangles with French protectionism.
French taxi drivers protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against Uber, which is facing fierce opposition from traditional cabs.
Hundreds of French taxi drivers took to the streets Thursday in sometimes violent protest against Uber, blocking access to major airports and train stations, and attacking vehicles suspected of working for the popular car service, which they accuse of stealing their livelihoods.
A taxi driver argues with a riot police officer standing guard during a demonstration at the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout on June 25 in Paris.
The violence follows weeks of escalating tension over the San Francisco-based firm's decision to continue offering its low-cost UberPop service despite an October law that bars companies from connecting passengers with unregistered drivers.
French taxi unions accuse UberPop of ignoring repeated court rulings and complain that police have turned a blind eye to the operation. The country's interior minister, Bernard Cazeneuve, said Thursday that the service must be shut down, citing the serious public order disturbances and development of this illegal activity.
The company has appealed the judgments and says it is waiting for a final decision from France's constitutional court, which began deliberating on the matter Tuesday.
Thomas Meister, an Uber spokesman, accused Cazeneuve of disregarding the legal process. The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is illegal or not, Meister told reporters.
Uber has faced repeated pushback from taxi operators and regulators as it has expanded into more than 300 cities across six continents. In an attempt to win over skeptical local authorities, the company has touted its potential to create jobs, reduce congestion and boost tax revenue.
A taxi driver holds a placard which reads, "Stop Uber, stop listening," during a protest in Paris.
Chief Executive Travis Kalanick made the case in January that many taxis in Europe operate off-grid and that Uber could be a way to bring them into compliance with local safety regulations and tax obligations.
The argument, however, does not appear to have swayed many European governments or taxi companies. More than a dozen lawsuits have been filed in recent months in countries across the continent, where some analysts say the company is in danger of being shut down or becoming so entangled in legislation as to be neutered.
In France, the battle is seen as the epitome of the culture clash between American free-market values and French economic protectionism.
They're very protectionist of their culture, their way of life, their way of doing things, said Hugh Tallents, a partner at the New York management consulting firm Cg42. It's not unheard of for unions to strike on a moment's notice or to retaliate against disruptive market forces.
Police officers stand next to a burned car during a taxi drivers demonstration in Paris.  French taxis are on strike around the country,  after weeks of rising tensions over Uber's ride-share service.
Tallents suggested that Uber might have to incorporate a little more cultural sensitivity into its operating model as it continues to expand.
Uber's strategy is one where they go in and take a very active approach.... They know their window for shoring up share and gaining riders and drivers is short because there are a lot of hungry competitors out there, he said. People will be looking at France as the poster child of how things can go wrong. I don't think this will necessarily derail Uber. But I think it could give them pause.
French taxi drivers complain that services such as Uber have an unfair advantage because their drivers don't pay for licenses that can cost up to $270,000. Some don't pay taxes and social charges, either, according to French officials. Cazeneuve berated Uber as a company that with arrogance applies none of the rules of law of the republic.
We are faced with permanent provocation, Serge Metz, the head of the taxi company G7, told French television. There can be only one response: a firm and systematic seizure of offending vehicles.
Travelers who were caught in the gridlock caused by anti-Uber protests walk along a freeway toward the Charles de Gaulle airport near Paris on June 25.
Uber counters that the taxi drivers are an outdated lobby fixed on defending their monopoly at the expense of customer needs. The company estimates that its smartphone app has about 400,000 French users a month.
Visitors to the French capital can testify to the frequent difficulty of finding a cab in Paris. French taxi drivers have also faced complaints of being resistant to change, including the use of credit cards and GPS technology.
An estimated 2,800 taxi drivers took part in Thursday's strike, setting up about 30 blockades across France, including on roads leading to Paris' Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports. Lines of travelers could be seen trudging along busy highways, dragging their luggage behind them, to catch flights and trains. Riot police fired tear gas to clear protesting drivers from the ring road around Paris.
There were reports in the French media of gangs of taxi drivers hunting down drivers they suspected of operating for Uber at the two airports and of attacks on some private-hire cars and even licensed taxis that were not taking part in the protests.
Among those caught up in the violence was actress-musician Courtney Love, whose ride was ambushed by anti-Uber protesters.
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
They're beating the cars with metal bats. This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad, she tweeted.
In another tweet, Love lambasted the French president: Francois Hollande where are the ... police??? is it legal for your people to attack visitors?
The singer was rescued by two men on a motorcycle but said she had been scared out of her wits.
In the eastern city of Strasbourg, there were reports of taxi drivers posing as Uber customers to lure drivers to isolated spots where they and their vehicles were attacked.
Meister, the Uber spokesman, described the attacks as totally scandalous and the actions of yobs.
It's a small minority of taxi drivers who are not doing their profession any favors, he said.
It is not unusual for French industrial action to turn violent. This week, striking workers at the MyFerryLink transportation company blocked access to the Channel Tunnel. Eurostar trains were canceled for the afternoon after the rail company said strikers had damaged sections of the track. Riot police were eventually called in to drag the protesters away as they sang the French national anthem, La Marseillaise.
In 1999, a French sheep farmer became a national hero when he led a group to dismantle a McDonald's restaurant that was being built in the south of France. Jose Bove was protesting against restrictions imposed by the Clinton administration on imported Roquefort cheese.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry's challenge as Iran talks resume: Avoid sharp turns</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-kerry-iran-talks-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Secretary of State John F. Kerry and his team are returning to international negotiations at a 19th century palace this weekend with a bounty of unsolicited advice on how they can wring a better nuclear agreement from Iran.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>4
The administration and the other world powers at the negotiating table agree with Corker that access to military bases is essential to any deal. But theyre not likely to get immediate access to sensitive Iranian sites.
The negotiators are planning to give Iran a number of days time to challenge any request from United Nations inspectors for access to an undeclared nuclear site.
On Wednesday, a group of respected former officials laid out in a letter their requirements for a nuclear deal. Their prescription was noteworthy because the group included former members of the administrations first-term inner circle on Iran -- Gary Samore, President Obamas former adviser on weapons of mass destruction; Robert Einhorn, former State Department nonproliferation chief; and Dennis Ross, former top administration advisor on the Middle East.
The groups negotiating advice tracked pretty closely with what the administration has been demanding. The former officials warned that they might not be able to support the deal if the administration caved at the last minute on key demands.
Interestingly, the groups strongest criticism of the administration was over President Obamas reluctance to do more with the U.S. military to halt the moves of Iranian forces and their armed proxies in the Middle East. The former officials said that to meet Irans threat fully, the administration needed to do more to train allied forces in Syria and Iraq, set up a safe haven in Syria, and stiffen resistance to Iranian arms shipment and harassment of commercial shipping in regional waters.
The American Israel Public Affairs Committee, the leading pro-Israel lobby, has laid out five requirements for a good deal. The agreement must authorize aggressive inspections; answer all questions about past nuclear research; lift sanctions only after Iran complies with obligations to scale back its program; restrain the nuclear program for decades; and dismantle Irans nuclear infrastructure, the group says.
The deal is sure to fall short of several of those goals. The six countries arent demanding dismantlement of excess Iranian centrifuges, for example; theyll be put in storage and monitored.
The six powers have given up hope of getting Iran to answer all the questions about its past nuclear research. Such a probe could take years, and still not answer all of the U.N.s questions about past nuclear work.
Iran would lose a lot if it acknowledged past research on nuclear devices, because that would puncture its claim that it has never sought the bomb.
So instead, the negotiators are bargaining over a specific list of steps Iran will be required to take, to try to answer some of the most important questions about past bomb research. Once Iran has completed those actions, the world powers will be willing to start lifting sanctions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As talks break down, European negotiators race to avoid a Greek tragedy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-talks-break-down-europe-greece-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Attempts to forge an agreement over Greece's troubled finances ended in failure Thursday, just five days before the Mediterranean country is due to make a loan repayment or risk going into default.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>As talks break down, European negotiators race to avoid a Greek tragedy
European leaders meet over Greek debt crisis in Brussels
Olivier Hoslet / European Pressphoto Agency
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, left, and Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a meeting of European leaders in Brussels on Thursday.
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, left, and Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a meeting of European leaders in Brussels on Thursday.
(Olivier Hoslet / European Pressphoto Agency)
European Debt Crisis
Attempts to forge an agreement over Greeces troubled finances ended in failure Thursday, just five days before the Mediterranean country is due to make a loan repayment or risk going into default.
Finance ministers from the 19-nation Eurozone gathered in Brussels said they would meet again Saturday to try to bridge the glaring differences between Athens and its international creditors in order to stave off the threat of a bankruptcy that could force Greece to abandon the common euro currency.
Greece bailout
Daniel Ochoa de Olza / Associated Press
A woman holds her wallet in her mouth after buying some fruit at a market in central Athens on Thursday.
A woman holds her wallet in her mouth after buying some fruit at a market in central Athens on Thursday.
(Daniel Ochoa de Olza / Associated Press)
It will need still many hours. The last hours have been really critical, European Union President Donald Tusk said, adding: But I have a good hunch that, unlike in Sophocles' tragedies, this Greek story will have a happy end.
It was a rare note of optimism on a day marked by more of the acrimony  especially between Greece and Germany, the EUs biggest economy  that has made reaching a deal difficult.
8
An agreement is necessary to unlock the final installment of funds from two bailouts that Athens has received from international lenders totaling about $270 billion. Without it, Greece will be unable to repay $1.8 billion it owes the International Monetary Fund by Tuesday's deadline.
The two sides are at odds over how Greece plans to keep its budget in surplus so it can service its debt even as its economy languishes in a deep and damaging depression.
Hopes of a deal received a boost earlier this week after new proposals were put forward by Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras. Elected on an anti-austerity platform, Tsipras left-wing administration has pledged to hold the line on protecting pensions and public-sector wages, and has proposed raising more money through higher taxes, particularly on businesses.
Tsipras has also demanded some sort of debt relief or writedown, without which most economists say Greece will find it impossible to return to growth because of the staggering amount of public debt it must pay off.
But the creditor countries and institutions sent back Tsipras plan replete with corrections and objections written in red ink, saying that raising tax would hamper growth and insisting on more spending cuts.
@affableman *ahem* Signed the US's nuclear stockpile....
Brianontheranch
17
The Greek leader accused Eurozone negotiators of trying to humiliate his country, while senior German officials complained that Athens had taken a step backward.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel said Thursday that reaching an agreement was essential before the markets opened Monday and before Greek banks, operating on a lifeline from the European Central Bank, ran out of money. Worried depositors have pulled out billions of euros over the past several days in what analysts describe as, if not a full-on run, then at least a slow jog on the banks.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, who heads the group of 19 Eurozone finance ministers, said a fresh round of counterproposals arrived from Greece too late Thursday to be properly evaluated and voted on by European Union leaders gathering for a two-day summit.
On a number of issues there is still a wide gap with the Greek authorities, Dijsselbloem told reporters.
Down-to-the-wire negotiations with Greece have been the norm throughout the 5-year-old euro debt crisis, as both sides stake out maximalist positions and challenge each other to blink.
While this iteration might follow the same script, analysts warn that time is truly running short. Even if an agreement is reached among European leaders in Brussels, the deal will then be subject to approval by various national parliaments.
That includes both Germany and Greece itself, where Tsipras faces a potential revolt from backbenchers who believe he has already backtracked too much on their partys anti-austerity pledges. In Berlin, Merkel also must face down disgruntled lawmakers who feel Greece has gotten away with too much.
Follow @HenryHChu on Twitter for coverage of Europe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. sharply criticizes Iran's human rights record on eve of nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-rights-report-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  On the eve of talks to conclude a landmark nuclear deal with Iran, the Obama administration Thursday identified the Tehran government as one of the world's worst abusers of human rights.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. sharply criticizes Iran's human rights record on eve of nuclear talks
John Kerry
Cliff Owen / Associated Press
Secretary of State John F. Kerry leaves the lectern after presenting the State Department's annual human rights report in Washington. Kerry remains on crutches as he recovers from a bicycle accident.
Secretary of State John F. Kerry leaves the lectern after presenting the State Department's annual human rights report in Washington. Kerry remains on crutches as he recovers from a bicycle accident.
(Cliff Owen / Associated Press)
The Obama administration on Friday removed Cuba from the U.S. list of state sponsors of international terrorism, taking an important step toward the presidents goal of improving relations between the two longtime adversaries. ( Paul Richter )
In its annual report on human rights around the world, the State Department cited the theocratic government for depriving its citizens of a range of freedoms, including the right to choose their leaders through free elections. The report portrayed the Iranian justice system as harsh and arbitrary, particularly in cases involving the government's political opponents, and said senior officials do not punish officials who commit abuses.
Some of the most serious abuses in the past year grew from the governments disregard for the physical safety of citizens, whom authorities arbitrarily and unlawfully detained, tortured or killed, the report said.
Iran was among a handful of countries singled out by Secretary of State John F. Kerry in an introduction to the report. The department also criticized the rights records of Cuba, Myanmar and Vietnam, countries with which the administration is trying to improve relations.
8
Cubas government was cited for harassment of political opponents, a lack of free speech, intimidation and abusive detentions. The report also said that Russia has become increasingly authoritarian and has moved to deny free speech.
Many of the abuses alleged in the report had been catalogued by the State Department in past years reports. But this year's volume has had more visibility than normal because of the nuclear negotiations with Iran.
The report was supposed to have been released on Feb. 25. The adminstration's critics had charged that the State Department was delaying its release to avoid provoking Iran and possibly hurting prospects for a nuclear deal.
State Department officials have said the release was delayed because of the hectic travel schedule of the secretary, who customarily is present at the reports release to give it visibility.
Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas), a presidential hopeful, had proposed fining the State Department for further delays.
I am ashamed to realize that our human rights record is far worse than Iran's. Let's do a body count for the last 20 years and see who has a bigger pile of dead innocents.
Brain Police
6
Without identifying him by name, the report cited the case of Washington Post reporter Jason Rezaian, a dual U.S.-Iranian citizen, who was imprisoned last July in Iran and is now on trial on unspecified charges. Rezaian has been denied legal representation and U.S. consular help and is at risk because of health problems and psychological stress, the report said.
The report said the Iranian government has severely restricted freedoms of assembly, speech, religion and the press.
It detailed a variety of abuses in the judicial system, including disappearances, judicially sanctioned amputations, and violence against political adversaries. Iran has the second-highest rate of executions in the world and often ignores guarantees of due process made in the countrys own constitution, the report charged.
The report also questioned the political legitimacy of Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who will make the ultimate decision on whether Iran accepts a nuclear deal.
Khamenei dominates key power structures, the report said, noting that while many Iranians take part in elections, an unelected body screens out candidates deemed unacceptable.
The report acknowledged that much of its information came second-hand, through private human rights advocacy groups, because the United States doesnt have diplomatic relations with Iran.
For more on U.S. foreign policy, follow @RichtPau
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea unveils new airport with shops, pharmacy and ... a chocolate fountain?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-north-korea-new-airport-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  North Korea has finished building an international airport terminal, state media reported Thursday, and photos show leader Kim Jong Un inspecting rather swanky amenities that include a jewelry store, a pharmacy and a coffee bar with - is that a chocolate fountain?
	</Description>
        <MainBody>North Korea unveils new airport with shops, pharmacy and ... a chocolate fountain?
New terminal of Pyongyang airport
Rodong Sinmun / EPA
An undated picture released by the Rodong Sinmun, the newspaper of the North Korea ruling Workers party, shows the newly built terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in North Korea.
An undated picture released by the Rodong Sinmun, the newspaper of the North Korea ruling Workers party, shows the newly built terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in North Korea.
(Rodong Sinmun / EPA)
Ri Sol Ju
North Korea has finished building an international airport terminal, state media reported Thursday, and photos show leader Kim Jong Un inspecting rather swanky amenities that include a jewelry store, a pharmacy and a coffee bar withis that a chocolate fountain?
In a speech on cybersecurity, U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry on Monday singled out North Korea as a violator of Internet freedom and took the reclusive country to task for Novembers hacking attack on Sony Pictures. ( Steven Borowiec )
It was unclear what international assistance impoverished North Korea received for constructing the two-story terminal, or how much it cost. A 30-photo slide show published by the state-run Korean Central News Agency showed Kim touring the terminal with his wife and a group of about a dozen people. Numerous photos showed the entourage in various states of laughter.
The facility, which also has a new control tower, willopen July 1, the agency said. It replaces a terminal that dated to the 1950s and may be part of efforts by Kim to increase the countrys appeal to tourists and earn foreign currency.
What a joke. They won't let citizens leave, because they would defect and who in their right mind would want to visit there (Dennis Rodman qualifies to go), why do they need an international airport?
garymichaeldoan
20
Since Kim took the helm of North Korea three years ago, he has opened a variety of tourist attractions, including a ski resort, and invited foreign celebrities such as Dennis Rodman to the country. Overseasrunners have been invited to participate in the Pyongyang marathon. But Kim also has periodically closed the country to visitors, most recently this spring, when borders were shut purportedly because of fears of Ebola.
Just a few airlines, including North Koreas state-run Air Koryo, and Air China, operate flights into Pyongyang. Most tourists are from China and Russia.
Kim praised the soldier-builders who worked on the terminal, the construction of which was a cherished wish of his father, the late leader Kim Jong Il, KCNA said. The Associated Press reported in October that laborers were constructing the terminal largely by hand or with simple tools, with patriotic music blaring from loudspeakers. Huge signs urged the workers to carry out their duties with Korea Speed, AP reported.
Photos of the facility showed at least 12 check-in counters; an immigration desk featuring modern, automated, glass entry gates; a clothing shop; a gift shop; a duty-free store; and several restaurants. There also was a newsstand stocked with what looked like magazines and North Korean flags. Travelers will have use of luggage carts.
The state-run news agency said a master plan called for construction of high-speed railways and motorway from the airport to the city center to ensure smooth traffic. North Korea is known for its paucity of buses, cars and other vehicles, not to mention a scarcity of fuel.
Accompanying Kim were senior officials, including Hwang Pyong So, considered to be North Koreas No. 2 official; Premier Pak Pong Ju; and Kim Yang Gon, director of the United Front Work Department. Kims wife, Ri Sol Ju, was also in attendance, wearing a seafoam green skirt suit.
Follow @JulieMakLAT for news fromAsia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State opens multi-pronged offensive in northern Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-islamic-state-syria-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Islamic State fighters on Thursday attacked Kobani, the Syrian town on the Turkish border they besieged for months before being repulsed in January by Kurdish militias assisted by punishing airstrikes from a U.S.-led coalition.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>2
Isso accused Turkey of being complicit in the attack on Kobani, charging that Islamic State fighters entered Kobani from Turkish territory. Turkish officials dismissed that claim, saying they possessed "concrete evidence that there was no crossing from the Turkish side," according to Agence France-Presse.
Last week, Kurdish-led forces routed Islamic State fighters who almost a year earlier had seized the border town of Tal Abyad. That offensive, backed by coalition airstrikes, cut off the Islamic State's main supply route to Raqqa, some 50 miles south. It also gave Kurdish forces an opportunity to consolidate two areas in northeastern Syria under their control, as well as opening up a corridor to Iraqi Kurdistan.
Elsewhere in Syria, 51 rebel factions operating in the southern province of Daraa announced a campaign to wrest control of areas of Daraa city from the government. SANA reported that an attack by terrorists -- the governments standard description of rebel factions -- had been thwarted, with fighter jets pounding rebel targets in surrounding villages.
The news agency also denied that the rebels had taken control of the strategic Daraa-Damascus road, one of two main highways linking southern Syria to Damascus, the capital and seat of power of President Bashar Assad.
The rebel operation, dubbed "Southern Storm," was spearheaded by factions associated with the Southern Front, a coalition of so-called moderate fighters. If successful, it would grant the rebels a rear supply base to mount operations on Damascus, a scant 59 miles north, as well as creating a contiguous zone of rebel control stretching from Kuneitra province, bordering the Israeli-held Golan Heights, to the outskirts of the Druze city of Suweida.
The Syrian Observatory put the death toll at 14 on the rebel side but did not give casualty figures for civilians or government forces.
The battle for Daraa city comes after a recent string of important gains for the Southern Front. Opposition activists claim the battlefield successes are the result of an intense three-month period of supply and armament for the coalition from a logistics hub located in the Jordanian capital Amman, staffed by operatives from a number of intelligence services, including the CIA.
Bulos is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Temperatures cool, but death toll tops 1,000 in Pakistani heat wave</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-death-toll-pakistan-heat-wave-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The toll from the sweltering heat wave in Pakistan's largest city continued to rise Thursday, surpassing more than 1,000 dead, according to state-run television, even as temperatures began to cool off.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Temperatures cool, but death toll tops 1,000 in Pakistani heat wave
Pakistan heat wave
Shahzaib Akber / European Pressphoto Agency
A tiger cools off with a large lump of ice at the Karachi Zoo, in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
A tiger cools off with a large lump of ice at the Karachi Zoo, in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
(Shahzaib Akber / European Pressphoto Agency)
By Aoun Sahi
Droughts and Heat Waves
The toll from the sweltering heat wave in Pakistan's largest city continued to rise Thursday, surpassing more than 1,000 dead, according to state-run television, even as temperatures began to cool off.
The high temperature in Karachi was 100 degrees Fahrenheit, closer to seasonal averages and several degrees cooler than earlier in the week, as a sea breeze blew over the port city, officials said. The temperature had reached 113 degrees Sunday.
Pakistan heat wave
Shakil Adil / Associated Press
A man covers his head with a wet towel to avoid heatstroke in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
A man covers his head with a wet towel to avoid heatstroke in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
(Shakil Adil / Associated Press)
"The temperature will remain normal in the coming days," said Ghulam Rasool, head of Pakistan's government meteorological office.
The number of victims arriving at hospitals in the southern port city slowed considerably, although 35 bodies were received at morgues operated by the Edhi Welfare Organization, said the group's spokesman, Anwar Kazmi.
It was the lowest number of bodies seen all week at the morgues, which received 750 heat stroke victims over the last five days, Kazmi said.
State-run broadcaster PTV put the death toll at over 1,000.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber protests turn violent in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-france-uber-protest-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  French taxi drivers overturned cars, burned tires and blocked access to airports and train stations in a second day of violent protest Thursday against competition from the ride-sharing service Uber.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>In another tweet, Love lambasted the French president: Francois Hollande where are the ... police??? is it legal for your people to attack visitors? Get your ass to the airport. Wtf???
The singer later added that she had been "scared out of her wits."
An estimated 2,800 taxi drivers took part in the strike, setting up around 30 roadblocks across France, including on roads leading to Paris' Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports. Some visitors had to walk between terminals and along busy roads to catch flights and trains.
There were reports in the French media of gangs of taxi drivers hunting down drivers they suspected of operating for Uber at the two airports and of attacks on some private-hire cars and even licensed taxis that were not taking part in the protests.
In the eastern city of Strasbourg, there were reports of taxi drivers posing as Uber customers to lure drivers to isolated spots where they and their vehicles were attacked. [Link in French]
Thomas Meister, an Uber spokesman, described the assaults as totally scandalous and the actions of yobs.
Its a small minority of taxi drivers who are not doing their profession any favors, he said.
France's interior minister, Bernard Cazeneuve, has called for a nationwide legal clampdown on UberPOP, citing the "serious public order disturbances and development of this illegal activity."
Meister accused the minister of disregarding the normal legal process.
"The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is illegal or not, Meister told French journalists.
In October, France passed a law banning any service that puts passengers in touch with unregistered drivers. Uber has contested the measure, saying it is counter to business freedom.
Willsher is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin manages to stabilize ruble, but Russian economy still staggers</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-russia-resilient-ruble-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Russia's ruble has been on a roller-coaster ride, posting the second-biggest drop in value of world currencies in 2014, then bouncing back this year with the highest rise against the dollar, euro, pound and yen.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin manages to stabilize ruble, but Russian economy still staggers
Russian economic woes
Ivan Sekretarev / Associated Press
Russia has delved deeply into its hard-currency trove, using up $150 billion to put an end to its currencys roller-coaster ride. Above, an exchange office in Moscow in December.
Russia has delved deeply into its hard-currency trove, using up $150 billion to put an end to its currencys roller-coaster ride. Above, an exchange office in Moscow in December.
(Ivan Sekretarev / Associated Press)
Temporary Assistance for Needy Families
Russia's ruble has been on a roller-coaster ride, posting the second-biggest drop in value of world currencies in 2014, then bouncing back this year with the highest rise against the dollar, euro, pound and yen.
The ruble's dizzying comeback, though, is due neither to an economic boom nor to sustainable intervention by the Russian Central Bank. And it came at a steep price.
Steadying the ruble at about 50 to the dollar has drained the country's hard-currency trove of $150 billion, more than a quarter of the reserves on hand at the end of 2013. Those cash infusions have done little to cheer Russian consumers or businesses: Inflation remains at more than 16% and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development predicts that the overall economy will shrink by 4.5% this year.
People know not to blame Putin. They know it is all the fault of Obama and the Ukrainian fascists that they have to suffer economically to confront these evil people. - Sergei Guriev, former rector of Moscow's New Economic School, mocking the prevailing sentiment
And stabilizing the ruble was achieved only after President Vladimir Putin shook down Russia's oligarchs for what he considered their fair share toward arresting the currency's tumble, a tactic unavailable to the stewards of a free-market democracy.
"There is no strategy and no vision. It's all 'live for today,'" said economist Sergei Guriev, a former rector of Moscow's New Economic School living in self-imposed exile in Paris.
Russia's disappearing middle class and the working poor are paying the price for the Kremlin's economic fiddling, Guriev said. He points to an average 10% drop in real income last year, a jump in mortgage defaults and rising food and utility prices.
A $500-billion, decade-long military modernization program augurs even grimmer years to come.
Car sales in Russia dropped 42% in April from the same month last year, the Assn. of European Businesses reported last month. The share of Russians who can afford no more than the absolute necessities has soared to 20%, the highest since polling on the subject began a decade ago, the Nielsen research firm reported last month.
8
Even during the 2009 recession, the report noted, only 7% of respondents said they could afford nothing more than food and shelter.
"But people know not to blame Putin. They know it is all the fault of Obama and the Ukrainian fascists that they have to suffer economically to confront these evil people," Guriev said, mocking the prevailing public attitude molded by a lavishly funded propaganda campaign on state-run television.
"In Russia we say that there's the television and there's the fridge," said the economist, who until last year was part of the Kremlin's financial inner circle. "People believe what they see on television, but when they don't see anything in the fridge they stop believing. If the government doesn't have the cash it needs and sees that its propaganda is no longer convincing, it may embark on a new military adventure to make people believe again."
The economy was ticking along with healthy growth in most recent years until Russian troops seized Ukraine's Crimea region in 2014. The United States and the European Union imposed sanctions on Moscow for its violation of international law and its neighbor's sovereignty.
Those measures, which cut off international lending and blacklisted dozens of Kremlin kingpins, have coincided with the decline of world oil prices to half their value of a year ago. And in spite of repeated pledges by Putin to diversify the economy since he first took office in 2000, Russia remained dependent on oil and gas sales for more than half of its income when the latest financial crisis hit.
cComments
@donchjohn Yes Poreshenko was installed by the popular vote of the Ukrainians. The previous president for 9 months was not put in by the US but was elected by the Parliament of the Ukraine to be speaker of the parliament in this position he was the next in charge when the previous president...
angelabirch
11
The government in April revised its 2016 budget to take into consideration the decline in expected energy revenue, which originally had been calculated at $100 a barrel for oil. The deficit spending now envisioned for next year will eat up an additional $200 billion from the hard-currency reserves, and more if the military modernization project continues to be exempt from the budget cuts forced on almost every other economic sector.
Putin has micromanaged the financial crisis in much the same away as he has guided the country's geopolitical strategy. He summoned his nation's captains of industry to the Kremlin for an emergency session Dec. 16, when the ruble was trading at 80 to the dollar. According to the RBK business journal, he told them that the ruble's collapse threatened their welfare as well as that of the country and that they had an obligation to repatriate the money they had stashed in foreign banks.
There was no official edict issued, and the journal observed that the Kremlin has limited means of controlling how oligarchs or ordinary citizens handle their finances.
Putin did declare a "capital amnesty" after the December meeting, and the State Duma, the lower house of the parliament, has been struggling since then to draft legislation aimed at assuring offshore depositors that repatriating their capital won't lead to investigations of whether they came by it legally. A history of nationalizations, corruption and asset seizures has undermined faith in the security of Russia-based wealth, explaining the flight of more than $150 billion in capital last year alone.
But lost on none of the oligarchs was the unspoken threat of reprisals if they failed to do their part to halt the ruble's free-fall. Memories were still fresh of the September house arrest of oil magnate Vladimir Yevtushenkov and seizure of his assets, not to mention the 10 years that former billionaire Mikhail Khodorkovsky spent in prison for challenging Putin's political domination.
The billionaire owners of Lukoil, Severstal, Norilsk Nickel and three dozen other major enterprises had converted enough of their hard-currency holdings by late February to boost the ruble's value to about 60 to the dollar. Igor Sechin, head of the oil monopoly Rosneft, told the Tass news agency that he had sold $93 billion for rubles in 2014.
The winter run on the ruble was triggered by the converging effects of sanctions and the nadir in oil prices that flirted with $45 a barrel in December. Oil has lately traded for about $60 a barrel.
Putin has brushed off sanctions as little more than an irritant and banned European food imports in retaliation. He has ordered major importers to buy Russian-made goods to replace the components they used to get from Western manufacturers, though domestic production can't ramp up to meet the new demand when the scant credit available from Russian banks comes with double-digit interest rates.
As national coffers emptied late last year, Putin ordered 10% across-the-board cuts in government-funded services for regions and municipalities, with only pensions and the ambitious defense overhaul spared the budget ax.
Government economists have revealed little about the brainstorming that goes on behind the Kremlin's closed doors or their own candid views on Putin's handling of the crisis. But academics and independent economists willing to comment from their lofty remove see little to suggest that the current problems will be short-lived.
"There is nothing good" in the mid- or long-term forecast, concluded Alexander Savelyev, a senior scholar at the Russian Academy of Sciences' Institute of World Economy and International Relations. "And the majority of experts expect further decline."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-indians-mock-jindal-candidacy-20150625-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir. It probably wasn't the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted. Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindal's campaign kickoff...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy
Bobby Jindal
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
(Gerald Herbert / Associated Press)
As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir.
It probably wasnt the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted.
Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindals campaign kickoff announcement, particularly for the 44-year-old Republicans line that he was tanned, rested and ready to run. It was widely seen as an attempt to play down his skin color to appeal to conservative voters, and fit with what Jindals critics say is a longstanding effort to disassociate himself from his Indian heritage.
The Twitter hashtag #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite trended in India for several hours.
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite that he couldn't win a spelling bee if he tried.
 VeeGee Narendra (@VeGeEn) June 25, 2015
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite he's never been randomly selected at the airport
 Misha Choudhry (@MishaChoudhry) June 25, 2015
Some of Indias leading newspapers ran front-page mentions of Jindals announcement, although the coverage was less than effusive. Lalit K. Jha, longtime Washington correspondent for the Press Trust of India, wrote in a news report that Jindals announcement has failed to generate much enthusiasm among the Indian-Americans because of his recent statements in which he sought to distance himself from being an Indian-American.
Jindal was born in Louisiana in 1971 to Indian immigrants from the northern state of Punjab. As a child he changed his birth name, Piyush, to Bobby after the character from The Brady Bunch. Raised by devout Hindus, he converted to Catholicism as a teenager and says his faith inspires his conservative principles, including a staunch opposition to same-sex marriage.
Jindal invoked his parents at the start of his kickoff speech Wednesday but used the word India only once: in his oft-repeated accusation that Democrats were dividing the country along ethnic, gender and class lines.We are not Indian Americans, Irish Americans, African Americans, rich Americans or poor Americans, he said. We are all Americans.
Jindal enters the Republican presidential race near the bottom of the pack and has failed to inspire much support from U.S. voters of Indian origin, most of whom lean Democratic.
Bobby has never supported a single Indian issue, he refused to join the India Caucus when he was a congressman [on] Capitol Hill and is conspicuously absent from any event with a visiting Indian leader, Shashi Tharoor, an Indian politician and author, wrote in a recent book, India Shastra.
It is as if he wants to forget he is Indian, and would like voters to forget it too.
Jindal is an object of fascination for a rising Indian middle class that assiduously tracks their countrys stature in the world. When Prime Minister Narendra Modi led scores of countries in marking the first International Day of Yoga last weekend, many Indians beamed with pride.
But they are less charitable when it comes to Indians abroad who are seen to betray their heritage. Preet Bharara, the U.S. attorney in Manhattan, has received less than favorable press coverage for the perception that he has targeted Wall Street executives with South Asian roots, such as Sri Lankan-born hedge fund billionaire Raj Rajaratnam, for prosecution of financial crimes.
Young Indians flooded social media sites with sarcastic comments when Jindal unveiled his official governors portrait earlier this year because his skin looked shockingly white. A photo his office tweeted this week of his family playing Monopoly inspired mockery because his young children had their shoes on inside the house, a cultural no-no here.
 Gov. Bobby Jindal (@BobbyJindal) June 23, 2015
Mihir Sharma, a columnist for the Business Standard newspaper, accused Indian Americans of a tendency to turn viciously on those they see as less Indian. But even he balanced his words with a critique of the candidate.
Typical: smug Indians trying to shame Bobby Jindal for his choices on identity, and not his awful politics, Sharma tweeted.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
