<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Latimes">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Evangelicals take their fight with Satan to the streets of Sao Paulo</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-ff-brazil-street-preachers-20150707-story.html</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>19 reported killed in attack on Tunisian beach</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-attack-tunisian-beach-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Gunmen struck a popular Tunisian beach resort on Friday, and state television said 19 people were killed. It was the second major strike in just over three months against a tourist target in the North African country.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>19 reported killed in attack on Tunisian beach
Tunisia beach
Bechir Bettaieb / AFP/Getty Images
An October 2013 photo of tourists enjoying the beach near a four-star hotel in Sousse, a popular destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital.
An October 2013 photo of tourists enjoying the beach near a four-star hotel in Sousse, a popular destination 90 miles south of the Tunisian capital.
(Bechir Bettaieb / AFP/Getty Images)
8
The shooting attack took place outside a beachfront hotel in the Tunisian city of Sousse, at noontime on a hot summer day when the seaside was crowded with visitors. Sousse, about 90 miles south of Tunis, is a popular destination for tourists traveling from Europe as well as elsewhere in the country and the region.
0
There was no immediate claim of responsibility.
Tunisias tourism industry suffered a devastating blow on March 18, when attackers hit the Bardo National Museum in the capital, whose antiquities were a major draw for visitors. That attack left 21 people dead, most of them European tourists on a cruise-ship stopover. Militants declaring allegiance to the Islamic State claimed responsibility.
The tourism sector is crucial for the economy in Tunisia, which is considered the only real success story in the wake of the Arab Spring uprisings more than four years ago. The country has been relatively politically stable, especially compared with its chaos-riven neighbor Libya, but the calm has been punctuated by occasional Islamist attacks, and economic stagnation and joblessness are major concerns.
Staff writer King reported from Cairo and special correspondent Hassan from Berlin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>IS claims blast at Shiite mosque in Kuwait's capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-is-claims-blast-at-shiite-mosque-in-kuwait-s-capital-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for a deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>IS claims blast at Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait's capital
Attack on Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque
YASSER AL-ZAYYAT / AFP/Getty Images
Kuwaiti security forces gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
Kuwaiti security forces gather outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers on June 26, 2015, in Kuwait City.
(YASSER AL-ZAYYAT / AFP/Getty Images)
By Associated Press
The Islamic State group has claimed responsibility for a deadly explosion that struck a Shiite mosque in the Kuwaiti capital after Friday prayers.
A post on a Twitter account known to belong to the Islamic State group claims the explosion was the work of a suicide bomber wearing an explosive belt.
The attack was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group calling itself the Najd Province, the same group that claimed responsibility for a pair of attacks on two Shiite mosques in Saudi Arabia in recent weeks.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Beheading, explosion at French factory called terrorist attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-explosion-beheading-terror-probe-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Beheading, explosion at French factory called terrorist attack
Attack at French factory
Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier after an attack.
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier after an attack.
(Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images)
Francois Hollande
One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said.
One suspect has been arrested in connection with the attack, said French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve, adding that intelligence services had identified the man as a potential extremist in 2006 but stopped monitoring him two years later.
Attack at French factory
Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images
French security stand next to the enclosed area where a decapitated body was found near the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier.
French security stand next to the enclosed area where a decapitated body was found near the Air Products company in Saint Quentin Fallavier.
(Philippe Desmazes / AFP/Getty Images)
Cazeneuve named the suspect as Yessim Salim or Yacine Sali, according to conflicting spellings given in various news reports.
Speaking in Brussels before a planned European Union summit, Hollande said the attack was carried out shortly before 10 a.m. by one or possibly two men in a car who clearly intended to blow up the Air Products factory in the town of Saint Quentin Fallavier, near the city of Grenoble. The plant manufactures industrial gases.
Hollande said there was no doubt that it was a terrorist assault. French anti-terrorist prosecutors have opened an investigation.
cComments
One man was decapitated and at least two other people were injured Friday morning in a terrorist attack on a factory in southeastern France, barely less than six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre by Muslim radicals in Paris, French President Francois Hollande said. And President...
John Gury
5
French media reported that the severed head of the decapitated victim was found hanging on the factory fence, near a flag bearing Arabic inscriptions. Hollande said that a message of some sort had been written on the body.
The other victims were hurt in an explosion set off when the attackers rammed their car into the factory gates, according to news reports. The severity of the injuries was not immediately clear.
The gruesome violence came less than six months after the Jan. 7 rampage in Paris at the headquarters of Charlie Hebdo, the satirical magazine targeted because of its cartoons of the prophet Mohammad, and a Jewish supermarket. Twenty people were killed, including the three attackers.
France has been on alert for further attacks. In April, an Algerian national linked by authorities to Al Qaeda and Islamic State was arrested on suspicion of plotting a gun attack on churches in Paris.
Security was stepped up at other sites in the region where Fridays attack occurred, for fear that the incident might either be a prelude to a larger assault or inspiration for copycats.
"The terrorist threat is at a maximum," Alain Juppe, a former French premier, said via Twitter. "The [French] state must do everything possible to protect its citizens."
Air Products is a U.S.-owned company founded in 1940 and headquartered in Allentown, Pa. It has offices around the world, including more than a dozen in Europe.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber protests turn violent in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-uber-france-taxi-html-20150625-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Cars overturned. Roads blockaded with flaming tires. That's what happens when the U.S. sharing economy tangles with French protectionism. French taxi drivers protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against Uber, which is facing fierce opposition from traditional cabs. Hundreds...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Francois Hollande
Cars overturned. Roads blockaded with flaming tires. That's what happens when the U.S. sharing economy tangles with French protectionism.
French taxi drivers protest in the southern city of Marseille as they demonstrate against Uber, which is facing fierce opposition from traditional cabs.
Hundreds of French taxi drivers took to the streets Thursday in sometimes violent protest against Uber, blocking access to major airports and train stations, and attacking vehicles suspected of working for the popular car service, which they accuse of stealing their livelihoods.
A taxi driver argues with a riot police officer standing guard during a demonstration at the Porte Maillot traffic roundabout on June 25 in Paris.
The violence follows weeks of escalating tension over the San Francisco-based firm's decision to continue offering its low-cost UberPop service despite an October law that bars companies from connecting passengers with unregistered drivers.
French taxi unions accuse UberPop of ignoring repeated court rulings and complain that police have turned a blind eye to the operation. The country's interior minister, Bernard Cazeneuve, said Thursday that the service must be shut down, citing the serious public order disturbances and development of this illegal activity.
The company has appealed the judgments and says it is waiting for a final decision from France's constitutional court, which began deliberating on the matter Tuesday.
Thomas Meister, an Uber spokesman, accused Cazeneuve of disregarding the legal process. The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is illegal or not, Meister told reporters.
Uber has faced repeated pushback from taxi operators and regulators as it has expanded into more than 300 cities across six continents. In an attempt to win over skeptical local authorities, the company has touted its potential to create jobs, reduce congestion and boost tax revenue.
A taxi driver holds a placard which reads, "Stop Uber, stop listening," during a protest in Paris.
Chief Executive Travis Kalanick made the case in January that many taxis in Europe operate off-grid and that Uber could be a way to bring them into compliance with local safety regulations and tax obligations.
The argument, however, does not appear to have swayed many European governments or taxi companies. More than a dozen lawsuits have been filed in recent months in countries across the continent, where some analysts say the company is in danger of being shut down or becoming so entangled in legislation as to be neutered.
In France, the battle is seen as the epitome of the culture clash between American free-market values and French economic protectionism.
They're very protectionist of their culture, their way of life, their way of doing things, said Hugh Tallents, a partner at the New York management consulting firm Cg42. It's not unheard of for unions to strike on a moment's notice or to retaliate against disruptive market forces.
Police officers stand next to a burned car during a taxi drivers demonstration in Paris.  French taxis are on strike around the country,  after weeks of rising tensions over Uber's ride-share service.
Tallents suggested that Uber might have to incorporate a little more cultural sensitivity into its operating model as it continues to expand.
Uber's strategy is one where they go in and take a very active approach.... They know their window for shoring up share and gaining riders and drivers is short because there are a lot of hungry competitors out there, he said. People will be looking at France as the poster child of how things can go wrong. I don't think this will necessarily derail Uber. But I think it could give them pause.
French taxi drivers complain that services such as Uber have an unfair advantage because their drivers don't pay for licenses that can cost up to $270,000. Some don't pay taxes and social charges, either, according to French officials. Cazeneuve berated Uber as a company that with arrogance applies none of the rules of law of the republic.
We are faced with permanent provocation, Serge Metz, the head of the taxi company G7, told French television. There can be only one response: a firm and systematic seizure of offending vehicles.
Travelers who were caught in the gridlock caused by anti-Uber protests walk along a freeway toward the Charles de Gaulle airport near Paris on June 25.
Uber counters that the taxi drivers are an outdated lobby fixed on defending their monopoly at the expense of customer needs. The company estimates that its smartphone app has about 400,000 French users a month.
Visitors to the French capital can testify to the frequent difficulty of finding a cab in Paris. French taxi drivers have also faced complaints of being resistant to change, including the use of credit cards and GPS technology.
An estimated 2,800 taxi drivers took part in Thursday's strike, setting up about 30 blockades across France, including on roads leading to Paris' Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports. Lines of travelers could be seen trudging along busy highways, dragging their luggage behind them, to catch flights and trains. Riot police fired tear gas to clear protesting drivers from the ring road around Paris.
There were reports in the French media of gangs of taxi drivers hunting down drivers they suspected of operating for Uber at the two airports and of attacks on some private-hire cars and even licensed taxis that were not taking part in the protests.
Among those caught up in the violence was actress-musician Courtney Love, whose ride was ambushed by anti-Uber protesters.
they've ambushed our car and are holding our driver hostage. they're beating the cars with metal bats. this is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad
 Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) June 25, 2015
They're beating the cars with metal bats. This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad, she tweeted.
In another tweet, Love lambasted the French president: Francois Hollande where are the ... police??? is it legal for your people to attack visitors?
The singer was rescued by two men on a motorcycle but said she had been scared out of her wits.
In the eastern city of Strasbourg, there were reports of taxi drivers posing as Uber customers to lure drivers to isolated spots where they and their vehicles were attacked.
Meister, the Uber spokesman, described the attacks as totally scandalous and the actions of yobs.
It's a small minority of taxi drivers who are not doing their profession any favors, he said.
It is not unusual for French industrial action to turn violent. This week, striking workers at the MyFerryLink transportation company blocked access to the Channel Tunnel. Eurostar trains were canceled for the afternoon after the rail company said strikers had damaged sections of the track. Riot police were eventually called in to drag the protesters away as they sang the French national anthem, La Marseillaise.
In 1999, a French sheep farmer became a national hero when he led a group to dismantle a McDonald's restaurant that was being built in the south of France. Jose Bove was protesting against restrictions imposed by the Clinton administration on imported Roquefort cheese.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kerry's challenge as Iran talks resume: Avoid sharp turns</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-kerry-iran-talks-20150626-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Secretary of State John F. Kerry and his team are returning to international negotiations at a 19th century palace this weekend with a bounty of unsolicited advice on how they can wring a better nuclear agreement from Iran.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>1
The administration and the other world powers at the negotiating table agree with Corker that access to military bases is essential to any deal. But theyre not likely to get immediate access to sensitive Iranian sites.
The negotiators are planning to give Iran a number of days time to challenge any request from United Nations inspectors for access to an undeclared nuclear site.
On Wednesday, a group of respected former officials laid out in a letter their requirements for a nuclear deal. Their prescription was noteworthy because the group included former members of the administrations first-term inner circle on Iran -- Gary Samore, President Obamas former adviser on weapons of mass destruction; Robert Einhorn, former State Department nonproliferation chief; and Dennis Ross, former top administration advisor on the Middle East.
The groups negotiating advice tracked pretty closely with what the administration has been demanding. The former officials warned that they might not be able to support the deal if the administration caved at the last minute on key demands.
Interestingly, the groups strongest criticism of the administration was over President Obamas reluctance to do more with the U.S. military to halt the moves of Iranian forces and their armed proxies in the Middle East. The former officials said that to meet Irans threat fully, the administration needed to do more to train allied forces in Syria and Iraq, set up a safe haven in Syria, and stiffen resistance to Iranian arms shipment and harassment of commercial shipping in regional waters.
The American Israel Public Affairs Committee, the leading pro-Israel lobby, has laid out five requirements for a good deal. The agreement must authorize aggressive inspections; answer all questions about past nuclear research; lift sanctions only after Iran complies with obligations to scale back its program; restrain the nuclear program for decades; and dismantle Irans nuclear infrastructure, the group says.
The deal is sure to fall short of several of those goals. The six countries arent demanding dismantlement of excess Iranian centrifuges, for example; theyll be put in storage and monitored.
The six powers have given up hope of getting Iran to answer all the questions about its past nuclear research. Such a probe could take years, and still not answer all of the U.N.s questions about past nuclear work.
Iran would lose a lot if it acknowledged past research on nuclear devices, because that would puncture its claim that it has never sought the bomb.
So instead, the negotiators are bargaining over a specific list of steps Iran will be required to take, to try to answer some of the most important questions about past bomb research. Once Iran has completed those actions, the world powers will be willing to start lifting sanctions.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As talks break down, European negotiators race to avoid a Greek tragedy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-talks-break-down-europe-greece-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Attempts to forge an agreement over Greece's troubled finances ended in failure Thursday, just five days before the Mediterranean country is due to make a loan repayment or risk going into default.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>As talks break down, European negotiators race to avoid a Greek tragedy
European leaders meet over Greek debt crisis in Brussels
Olivier Hoslet / European Pressphoto Agency
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, left, and Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a meeting of European leaders in Brussels on Thursday.
Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi, left, and Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras during a meeting of European leaders in Brussels on Thursday.
(Olivier Hoslet / European Pressphoto Agency)
Donald Tusk
Attempts to forge an agreement over Greeces troubled finances ended in failure Thursday, just five days before the Mediterranean country is due to make a loan repayment or risk going into default.
Finance ministers from the 19-nation Eurozone gathered in Brussels said they would meet again Saturday to try to bridge the glaring differences between Athens and its international creditors in order to stave off the threat of a bankruptcy that could force Greece to abandon the common euro currency.
Greece bailout
Daniel Ochoa de Olza / Associated Press
A woman holds her wallet in her mouth after buying some fruit at a market in central Athens on Thursday.
A woman holds her wallet in her mouth after buying some fruit at a market in central Athens on Thursday.
(Daniel Ochoa de Olza / Associated Press)
It will need still many hours. The last hours have been really critical, European Union President Donald Tusk said, adding: But I have a good hunch that, unlike in Sophocles' tragedies, this Greek story will have a happy end.
It was a rare note of optimism on a day marked by more of the acrimony  especially between Greece and Germany, the EUs biggest economy  that has made reaching a deal difficult.
8
An agreement is necessary to unlock the final installment of funds from two bailouts that Athens has received from international lenders totaling about $270 billion. Without it, Greece will be unable to repay $1.8 billion it owes the International Monetary Fund by Tuesday's deadline.
The two sides are at odds over how Greece plans to keep its budget in surplus so it can service its debt even as its economy languishes in a deep and damaging depression.
Hopes of a deal received a boost earlier this week after new proposals were put forward by Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras. Elected on an anti-austerity platform, Tsipras left-wing administration has pledged to hold the line on protecting pensions and public-sector wages, and has proposed raising more money through higher taxes, particularly on businesses.
Tsipras has also demanded some sort of debt relief or writedown, without which most economists say Greece will find it impossible to return to growth because of the staggering amount of public debt it must pay off.
But the creditor countries and institutions sent back Tsipras plan replete with corrections and objections written in red ink, saying that raising tax would hamper growth and insisting on more spending cuts.
cComments
@freedomguy Why would you want the EU to unravel? The entire idea behind it was that countries that do business with each other don't go to war with each other. The Common Market then the European Community and now the EU have kept the peace in Europe since WWII...
affableman
14
The Greek leader accused Eurozone negotiators of trying to humiliate his country, while senior German officials complained that Athens had taken a step backward.
German Chancellor Angela Merkel said Thursday that reaching an agreement was essential before the markets opened Monday and before Greek banks, operating on a lifeline from the European Central Bank, ran out of money. Worried depositors have pulled out billions of euros over the past several days in what analysts describe as, if not a full-on run, then at least a slow jog on the banks.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, who heads the group of 19 Eurozone finance ministers, said a fresh round of counterproposals arrived from Greece too late Thursday to be properly evaluated and voted on by European Union leaders gathering for a two-day summit.
On a number of issues there is still a wide gap with the Greek authorities, Dijsselbloem told reporters.
Down-to-the-wire negotiations with Greece have been the norm throughout the 5-year-old euro debt crisis, as both sides stake out maximalist positions and challenge each other to blink.
While this iteration might follow the same script, analysts warn that time is truly running short. Even if an agreement is reached among European leaders in Brussels, the deal will then be subject to approval by various national parliaments.
That includes both Germany and Greece itself, where Tsipras faces a potential revolt from backbenchers who believe he has already backtracked too much on their partys anti-austerity pledges. In Berlin, Merkel also must face down disgruntled lawmakers who feel Greece has gotten away with too much.
Follow @HenryHChu on Twitter for coverage of Europe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. sharply criticizes Iran's human rights record on eve of nuclear talks</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-rights-report-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  On the eve of talks to conclude a landmark nuclear deal with Iran, the Obama administration Thursday identified the Tehran government as one of the world's worst abusers of human rights.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. sharply criticizes Iran's human rights record on eve of nuclear talks
John Kerry
Cliff Owen / Associated Press
Secretary of State John F. Kerry leaves the lectern after presenting the State Department's annual human rights report in Washington. Kerry remains on crutches as he recovers from a bicycle accident.
Secretary of State John F. Kerry leaves the lectern after presenting the State Department's annual human rights report in Washington. Kerry remains on crutches as he recovers from a bicycle accident.
(Cliff Owen / Associated Press)
The Obama administration on Friday removed Cuba from the U.S. list of state sponsors of international terrorism, taking an important step toward the presidents goal of improving relations between the two longtime adversaries. ( Paul Richter )
In its annual report on human rights around the world, the State Department cited the theocratic government for depriving its citizens of a range of freedoms, including the right to choose their leaders through free elections. The report portrayed the Iranian justice system as harsh and arbitrary, particularly in cases involving the government's political opponents, and said senior officials do not punish officials who commit abuses.
Some of the most serious abuses in the past year grew from the governments disregard for the physical safety of citizens, whom authorities arbitrarily and unlawfully detained, tortured or killed, the report said.
Iran was among a handful of countries singled out by Secretary of State John F. Kerry in an introduction to the report. The department also criticized the rights records of Cuba, Myanmar and Vietnam, countries with which the administration is trying to improve relations.
8
Cubas government was cited for harassment of political opponents, a lack of free speech, intimidation and abusive detentions. The report also said that Russia has become increasingly authoritarian and has moved to deny free speech.
Many of the abuses alleged in the report had been catalogued by the State Department in past years reports. But this year's volume has had more visibility than normal because of the nuclear negotiations with Iran.
The report was supposed to have been released on Feb. 25. The adminstration's critics had charged that the State Department was delaying its release to avoid provoking Iran and possibly hurting prospects for a nuclear deal.
State Department officials have said the release was delayed because of the hectic travel schedule of the secretary, who customarily is present at the reports release to give it visibility.
Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas), a presidential hopeful, had proposed fining the State Department for further delays.
Yea they should be more like our friends in Egypt , Arabia , Israel , Columbia etc
Preci Gil
5
Without identifying him by name, the report cited the case of Washington Post reporter Jason Rezaian, a dual U.S.-Iranian citizen, who was imprisoned last July in Iran and is now on trial on unspecified charges. Rezaian has been denied legal representation and U.S. consular help and is at risk because of health problems and psychological stress, the report said.
The report said the Iranian government has severely restricted freedoms of assembly, speech, religion and the press.
It detailed a variety of abuses in the judicial system, including disappearances, judicially sanctioned amputations, and violence against political adversaries. Iran has the second-highest rate of executions in the world and often ignores guarantees of due process made in the countrys own constitution, the report charged.
The report also questioned the political legitimacy of Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who will make the ultimate decision on whether Iran accepts a nuclear deal.
Khamenei dominates key power structures, the report said, noting that while many Iranians take part in elections, an unelected body screens out candidates deemed unacceptable.
The report acknowledged that much of its information came second-hand, through private human rights advocacy groups, because the United States doesnt have diplomatic relations with Iran.
For more on U.S. foreign policy, follow @RichtPau
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea unveils new airport with shops, pharmacy and ... a chocolate fountain?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-north-korea-new-airport-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  North Korea has finished building an international airport terminal, state media reported Thursday, and photos show leader Kim Jong Un inspecting rather swanky amenities that include a jewelry store, a pharmacy and a coffee bar with - is that a chocolate fountain?
	</Description>
        <MainBody>North Korea unveils new airport with shops, pharmacy and ... a chocolate fountain?
New terminal of Pyongyang airport
Rodong Sinmun / EPA
An undated picture released by the Rodong Sinmun, the newspaper of the North Korea ruling Workers party, shows the newly built terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in North Korea.
An undated picture released by the Rodong Sinmun, the newspaper of the North Korea ruling Workers party, shows the newly built terminal of Pyongyang International Airport in North Korea.
(Rodong Sinmun / EPA)
Kim Jong Un
North Korea has finished building an international airport terminal, state media reported Thursday, and photos show leader Kim Jong Un inspecting rather swanky amenities that include a jewelry store, a pharmacy and a coffee bar withis that a chocolate fountain?
In a speech on cybersecurity, U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry on Monday singled out North Korea as a violator of Internet freedom and took the reclusive country to task for Novembers hacking attack on Sony Pictures. ( Steven Borowiec )
It was unclear what international assistance impoverished North Korea received for constructing the two-story terminal, or how much it cost. A 30-photo slide show published by the state-run Korean Central News Agency showed Kim touring the terminal with his wife and a group of about a dozen people. Numerous photos showed the entourage in various states of laughter.
The facility, which also has a new control tower, willopen July 1, the agency said. It replaces a terminal that dated to the 1950s and may be part of efforts by Kim to increase the countrys appeal to tourists and earn foreign currency.
Wait until they see that planes don't have propellers anymore!
drnuclear1
19
Since Kim took the helm of North Korea three years ago, he has opened a variety of tourist attractions, including a ski resort, and invited foreign celebrities such as Dennis Rodman to the country. Overseasrunners have been invited to participate in the Pyongyang marathon. But Kim also has periodically closed the country to visitors, most recently this spring, when borders were shut purportedly because of fears of Ebola.
Just a few airlines, including North Koreas state-run Air Koryo, and Air China, operate flights into Pyongyang. Most tourists are from China and Russia.
Kim praised the soldier-builders who worked on the terminal, the construction of which was a cherished wish of his father, the late leader Kim Jong Il, KCNA said. The Associated Press reported in October that laborers were constructing the terminal largely by hand or with simple tools, with patriotic music blaring from loudspeakers. Huge signs urged the workers to carry out their duties with Korea Speed, AP reported.
Photos of the facility showed at least 12 check-in counters; an immigration desk featuring modern, automated, glass entry gates; a clothing shop; a gift shop; a duty-free store; and several restaurants. There also was a newsstand stocked with what looked like magazines and North Korean flags. Travelers will have use of luggage carts.
The state-run news agency said a master plan called for construction of high-speed railways and motorway from the airport to the city center to ensure smooth traffic. North Korea is known for its paucity of buses, cars and other vehicles, not to mention a scarcity of fuel.
Accompanying Kim were senior officials, including Hwang Pyong So, considered to be North Koreas No. 2 official; Premier Pak Pong Ju; and Kim Yang Gon, director of the United Front Work Department. Kims wife, Ri Sol Ju, was also in attendance, wearing a seafoam green skirt suit.
Follow @JulieMakLAT for news fromAsia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 19:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State opens multi-pronged offensive in northern Syria</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-islamic-state-syria-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Islamic State fighters on Thursday attacked Kobani, the Syrian town on the Turkish border they besieged for months before being repulsed in January by Kurdish militias assisted by punishing airstrikes from a U.S.-led coalition.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>2
Isso accused Turkey of being complicit in the attack on Kobani, charging that Islamic State fighters entered Kobani from Turkish territory. Turkish officials dismissed that claim, saying they possessed "concrete evidence that there was no crossing from the Turkish side," according to Agence France-Presse.
Last week, Kurdish-led forces routed Islamic State fighters who almost a year earlier had seized the border town of Tal Abyad. That offensive, backed by coalition airstrikes, cut off the Islamic State's main supply route to Raqqa, some 50 miles south. It also gave Kurdish forces an opportunity to consolidate two areas in northeastern Syria under their control, as well as opening up a corridor to Iraqi Kurdistan.
Elsewhere in Syria, 51 rebel factions operating in the southern province of Daraa announced a campaign to wrest control of areas of Daraa city from the government. SANA reported that an attack by terrorists -- the governments standard description of rebel factions -- had been thwarted, with fighter jets pounding rebel targets in surrounding villages.
The news agency also denied that the rebels had taken control of the strategic Daraa-Damascus road, one of two main highways linking southern Syria to Damascus, the capital and seat of power of President Bashar Assad.
The rebel operation, dubbed "Southern Storm," was spearheaded by factions associated with the Southern Front, a coalition of so-called moderate fighters. If successful, it would grant the rebels a rear supply base to mount operations on Damascus, a scant 59 miles north, as well as creating a contiguous zone of rebel control stretching from Kuneitra province, bordering the Israeli-held Golan Heights, to the outskirts of the Druze city of Suweida.
The Syrian Observatory put the death toll at 14 on the rebel side but did not give casualty figures for civilians or government forces.
The battle for Daraa city comes after a recent string of important gains for the Southern Front. Opposition activists claim the battlefield successes are the result of an intense three-month period of supply and armament for the coalition from a logistics hub located in the Jordanian capital Amman, staffed by operatives from a number of intelligence services, including the CIA.
Bulos is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Temperatures cool, but death toll tops 1,000 in Pakistani heat wave</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-death-toll-pakistan-heat-wave-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The toll from the sweltering heat wave in Pakistan's largest city continued to rise Thursday, surpassing more than 1,000 dead, according to state-run television, even as temperatures began to cool off.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Temperatures cool, but death toll tops 1,000 in Pakistani heat wave
Pakistan heat wave
Shahzaib Akber / European Pressphoto Agency
A tiger cools off with a large lump of ice at the Karachi Zoo, in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
A tiger cools off with a large lump of ice at the Karachi Zoo, in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
(Shahzaib Akber / European Pressphoto Agency)
By Aoun Sahi
Droughts and Heat Waves
The toll from the sweltering heat wave in Pakistan's largest city continued to rise Thursday, surpassing more than 1,000 dead, according to state-run television, even as temperatures began to cool off.
The high temperature in Karachi was 100 degrees Fahrenheit, closer to seasonal averages and several degrees cooler than earlier in the week, as a sea breeze blew over the port city, officials said. The temperature had reached 113 degrees Sunday.
Pakistan heat wave
Shakil Adil / Associated Press
A man covers his head with a wet towel to avoid heatstroke in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
A man covers his head with a wet towel to avoid heatstroke in Karachi, Pakistan, on Wednesday.
(Shakil Adil / Associated Press)
"The temperature will remain normal in the coming days," said Ghulam Rasool, head of Pakistan's government meteorological office.
The number of victims arriving at hospitals in the southern port city slowed considerably, although 35 bodies were received at morgues operated by the Edhi Welfare Organization, said the group's spokesman, Anwar Kazmi.
It was the lowest number of bodies seen all week at the morgues, which received 750 heat stroke victims over the last five days, Kazmi said.
State-run broadcaster PTV put the death toll at over 1,000.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Anti-Uber protests turn violent in France</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-france-uber-protest-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  French taxi drivers overturned cars, burned tires and blocked access to airports and train stations in a second day of violent protest Thursday against competition from the ride-sharing service Uber.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>In another tweet, Love lambasted the French president: Francois Hollande where are the ... police??? is it legal for your people to attack visitors? Get your ass to the airport. Wtf???
The singer later added that she had been "scared out of her wits."
An estimated 2,800 taxi drivers took part in the strike, setting up around 30 roadblocks across France, including on roads leading to Paris' Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports. Some visitors had to walk between terminals and along busy roads to catch flights and trains.
There were reports in the French media of gangs of taxi drivers hunting down drivers they suspected of operating for Uber at the two airports and of attacks on some private-hire cars and even licensed taxis that were not taking part in the protests.
In the eastern city of Strasbourg, there were reports of taxi drivers posing as Uber customers to lure drivers to isolated spots where they and their vehicles were attacked. [Link in French]
Thomas Meister, an Uber spokesman, described the assaults as totally scandalous and the actions of yobs.
Its a small minority of taxi drivers who are not doing their profession any favors, he said.
France's interior minister, Bernard Cazeneuve, has called for a nationwide legal clampdown on UberPOP, citing the "serious public order disturbances and development of this illegal activity."
Meister accused the minister of disregarding the normal legal process.
"The way things work in a state of law is that it's for the justice to judge whether something is illegal or not, Meister told French journalists.
In October, France passed a law banning any service that puts passengers in touch with unregistered drivers. Uber has contested the measure, saying it is counter to business freedom.
Willsher is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 14:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin manages to stabilize ruble, but Russian economy still staggers</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-russia-resilient-ruble-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Russia's ruble has been on a roller-coaster ride, posting the second-biggest drop in value of world currencies in 2014, then bouncing back this year with the highest rise against the dollar, euro, pound and yen.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin manages to stabilize ruble, but Russian economy still staggers
Russian economic woes
Ivan Sekretarev / Associated Press
Russia has delved deeply into its hard-currency trove, using up $150 billion to put an end to its currencys roller-coaster ride. Above, an exchange office in Moscow in December.
Russia has delved deeply into its hard-currency trove, using up $150 billion to put an end to its currencys roller-coaster ride. Above, an exchange office in Moscow in December.
(Ivan Sekretarev / Associated Press)
European Union
Russia's ruble has been on a roller-coaster ride, posting the second-biggest drop in value of world currencies in 2014, then bouncing back this year with the highest rise against the dollar, euro, pound and yen.
The ruble's dizzying comeback, though, is due neither to an economic boom nor to sustainable intervention by the Russian Central Bank. And it came at a steep price.
Steadying the ruble at about 50 to the dollar has drained the country's hard-currency trove of $150 billion, more than a quarter of the reserves on hand at the end of 2013. Those cash infusions have done little to cheer Russian consumers or businesses: Inflation remains at more than 16% and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development predicts that the overall economy will shrink by 4.5% this year.
People know not to blame Putin. They know it is all the fault of Obama and the Ukrainian fascists that they have to suffer economically to confront these evil people. - Sergei Guriev, former rector of Moscow's New Economic School, mocking the prevailing sentiment
And stabilizing the ruble was achieved only after President Vladimir Putin shook down Russia's oligarchs for what he considered their fair share toward arresting the currency's tumble, a tactic unavailable to the stewards of a free-market democracy.
"There is no strategy and no vision. It's all 'live for today,'" said economist Sergei Guriev, a former rector of Moscow's New Economic School living in self-imposed exile in Paris.
Russia's disappearing middle class and the working poor are paying the price for the Kremlin's economic fiddling, Guriev said. He points to an average 10% drop in real income last year, a jump in mortgage defaults and rising food and utility prices.
A $500-billion, decade-long military modernization program augurs even grimmer years to come.
Car sales in Russia dropped 42% in April from the same month last year, the Assn. of European Businesses reported last month. The share of Russians who can afford no more than the absolute necessities has soared to 20%, the highest since polling on the subject began a decade ago, the Nielsen research firm reported last month.
8
Even during the 2009 recession, the report noted, only 7% of respondents said they could afford nothing more than food and shelter.
"But people know not to blame Putin. They know it is all the fault of Obama and the Ukrainian fascists that they have to suffer economically to confront these evil people," Guriev said, mocking the prevailing public attitude molded by a lavishly funded propaganda campaign on state-run television.
"In Russia we say that there's the television and there's the fridge," said the economist, who until last year was part of the Kremlin's financial inner circle. "People believe what they see on television, but when they don't see anything in the fridge they stop believing. If the government doesn't have the cash it needs and sees that its propaganda is no longer convincing, it may embark on a new military adventure to make people believe again."
The economy was ticking along with healthy growth in most recent years until Russian troops seized Ukraine's Crimea region in 2014. The United States and the European Union imposed sanctions on Moscow for its violation of international law and its neighbor's sovereignty.
Those measures, which cut off international lending and blacklisted dozens of Kremlin kingpins, have coincided with the decline of world oil prices to half their value of a year ago. And in spite of repeated pledges by Putin to diversify the economy since he first took office in 2000, Russia remained dependent on oil and gas sales for more than half of its income when the latest financial crisis hit.
cComments
@donchjohn Yes Poreshenko was installed by the popular vote of the Ukrainians. The previous president for 9 months was not put in by the US but was elected by the Parliament of the Ukraine to be speaker of the parliament in this position he was the next in charge when the previous president...
angelabirch
11
The government in April revised its 2016 budget to take into consideration the decline in expected energy revenue, which originally had been calculated at $100 a barrel for oil. The deficit spending now envisioned for next year will eat up an additional $200 billion from the hard-currency reserves, and more if the military modernization project continues to be exempt from the budget cuts forced on almost every other economic sector.
Putin has micromanaged the financial crisis in much the same away as he has guided the country's geopolitical strategy. He summoned his nation's captains of industry to the Kremlin for an emergency session Dec. 16, when the ruble was trading at 80 to the dollar. According to the RBK business journal, he told them that the ruble's collapse threatened their welfare as well as that of the country and that they had an obligation to repatriate the money they had stashed in foreign banks.
There was no official edict issued, and the journal observed that the Kremlin has limited means of controlling how oligarchs or ordinary citizens handle their finances.
Putin did declare a "capital amnesty" after the December meeting, and the State Duma, the lower house of the parliament, has been struggling since then to draft legislation aimed at assuring offshore depositors that repatriating their capital won't lead to investigations of whether they came by it legally. A history of nationalizations, corruption and asset seizures has undermined faith in the security of Russia-based wealth, explaining the flight of more than $150 billion in capital last year alone.
But lost on none of the oligarchs was the unspoken threat of reprisals if they failed to do their part to halt the ruble's free-fall. Memories were still fresh of the September house arrest of oil magnate Vladimir Yevtushenkov and seizure of his assets, not to mention the 10 years that former billionaire Mikhail Khodorkovsky spent in prison for challenging Putin's political domination.
The billionaire owners of Lukoil, Severstal, Norilsk Nickel and three dozen other major enterprises had converted enough of their hard-currency holdings by late February to boost the ruble's value to about 60 to the dollar. Igor Sechin, head of the oil monopoly Rosneft, told the Tass news agency that he had sold $93 billion for rubles in 2014.
The winter run on the ruble was triggered by the converging effects of sanctions and the nadir in oil prices that flirted with $45 a barrel in December. Oil has lately traded for about $60 a barrel.
Putin has brushed off sanctions as little more than an irritant and banned European food imports in retaliation. He has ordered major importers to buy Russian-made goods to replace the components they used to get from Western manufacturers, though domestic production can't ramp up to meet the new demand when the scant credit available from Russian banks comes with double-digit interest rates.
As national coffers emptied late last year, Putin ordered 10% across-the-board cuts in government-funded services for regions and municipalities, with only pensions and the ambitious defense overhaul spared the budget ax.
Government economists have revealed little about the brainstorming that goes on behind the Kremlin's closed doors or their own candid views on Putin's handling of the crisis. But academics and independent economists willing to comment from their lofty remove see little to suggest that the current problems will be short-lived.
"There is nothing good" in the mid- or long-term forecast, concluded Alexander Savelyev, a senior scholar at the Russian Academy of Sciences' Institute of World Economy and International Relations. "And the majority of experts expect further decline."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-indians-mock-jindal-candidacy-20150625-htmlstory.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir. It probably wasn't the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted. Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindal's campaign kickoff...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy
Bobby Jindal
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
(Gerald Herbert / Associated Press)
As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir.
It probably wasnt the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted.
Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindals campaign kickoff announcement, particularly for the 44-year-old Republicans line that he was tanned, rested and ready to run. It was widely seen as an attempt to play down his skin color to appeal to conservative voters, and fit with what Jindals critics say is a longstanding effort to disassociate himself from his Indian heritage.
The Twitter hashtag #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite trended in India for several hours.
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite that he couldn't win a spelling bee if he tried.
 VeeGee Narendra (@VeGeEn) June 25, 2015
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite he's never been randomly selected at the airport
 Misha Choudhry (@MishaChoudhry) June 25, 2015
Some of Indias leading newspapers ran front-page mentions of Jindals announcement, although the coverage was less than effusive. Lalit K. Jha, longtime Washington correspondent for the Press Trust of India, wrote in a news report that Jindals announcement has failed to generate much enthusiasm among the Indian-Americans because of his recent statements in which he sought to distance himself from being an Indian-American.
Jindal was born in Louisiana in 1971 to Indian immigrants from the northern state of Punjab. As a child he changed his birth name, Piyush, to Bobby after the character from The Brady Bunch. Raised by devout Hindus, he converted to Catholicism as a teenager and says his faith inspires his conservative principles, including a staunch opposition to same-sex marriage.
Jindal invoked his parents at the start of his kickoff speech Wednesday but used the word India only once: in his oft-repeated accusation that Democrats were dividing the country along ethnic, gender and class lines.We are not Indian Americans, Irish Americans, African Americans, rich Americans or poor Americans, he said. We are all Americans.
Jindal enters the Republican presidential race near the bottom of the pack and has failed to inspire much support from U.S. voters of Indian origin, most of whom lean Democratic.
Bobby has never supported a single Indian issue, he refused to join the India Caucus when he was a congressman [on] Capitol Hill and is conspicuously absent from any event with a visiting Indian leader, Shashi Tharoor, an Indian politician and author, wrote in a recent book, India Shastra.
It is as if he wants to forget he is Indian, and would like voters to forget it too.
Jindal is an object of fascination for a rising Indian middle class that assiduously tracks their countrys stature in the world. When Prime Minister Narendra Modi led scores of countries in marking the first International Day of Yoga last weekend, many Indians beamed with pride.
But they are less charitable when it comes to Indians abroad who are seen to betray their heritage. Preet Bharara, the U.S. attorney in Manhattan, has received less than favorable press coverage for the perception that he has targeted Wall Street executives with South Asian roots, such as Sri Lankan-born hedge fund billionaire Raj Rajaratnam, for prosecution of financial crimes.
Young Indians flooded social media sites with sarcastic comments when Jindal unveiled his official governors portrait earlier this year because his skin looked shockingly white. A photo his office tweeted this week of his family playing Monopoly inspired mockery because his young children had their shoes on inside the house, a cultural no-no here.
 Gov. Bobby Jindal (@BobbyJindal) June 23, 2015
Mihir Sharma, a columnist for the Business Standard newspaper, accused Indian Americans of a tendency to turn viciously on those they see as less Indian. But even he balanced his words with a critique of the candidate.
Typical: smug Indians trying to shame Bobby Jindal for his choices on identity, and not his awful politics, Sharma tweeted.
cComments
Wow, well I guess it's showtime for the republicans with the "minorities" they have running. Ann Coulter on Fox said this "Id really like to like Nikki Haley, since she is a Republican. On the other hand, she is an immigrant and does not understand America's...
KING JAMES - 1
at 1:46 AM June 26, 2015
There are three groups that make up the majority of the GOP: 1. Religious Right (American Taliban) 2. Social Conservatives (Amer i-Qaeda) 3. Corporatists (American Oligarchs) The Religious Right and Social Conservatives are the primary voting blocks in terms of boots on the ground and voting....
KING JAMES - 1
at 1:44 AM June 26, 2015
@montanoso , exactly......it's funny....and they hear his rhetoric and are insulted..
KING JAMES - 1
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pakistani activists risk death in speaking out against religious extremism</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pakistan-progressives-20150625-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Pin-drop silence followed as social activist Jibran Nasir, 28, screened a documentary on sectarian and religious violence in Pakistan. Nasir, who was on a six-week speaking tour of the United States, is among the few outspoken voices in Pakistan when it comes to religious extremism.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Pakistani activists risk death in speaking out against religious extremism
Pakistanis protest activist's slaying
Rizwan Tabassum / AFP/Getty Images
Activists gather in Karachi, Pakistan, in April to protest the slaying of rights advocate Sabeen Mahmud. She was slain after she left a Karachi meeting about missing people in Baluchistan.
Activists gather in Karachi, Pakistan, in April to protest the slaying of rights advocate Sabeen Mahmud. She was slain after she left a Karachi meeting about missing people in Baluchistan. (Rizwan Tabassum / AFP/Getty Images)
By Saher Baloch
Human Rights Watch
Pin-drop silence followed as social activist Jibran Nasir, 28, screened a documentary on sectarian and religious violence in Pakistan. Nasir, who was on a six-week speaking tour of the United States, is among the few outspoken voices in Pakistan when it comes to religious extremism.
But the overall situation appears bleak. A few hours after Nasir's talk last month at Pomona College on sectarianism and apathy, 45 members of a subsect of Karachi's Shiite Muslim community were killed in an attack by Sunni Muslim militants.
Pakistan activist Jibran Nasir
Irfan Khan / Los Angeles Times
Social activist Jibran Nasir, one of the few outspoken voices on religious extremism in Pakistan, gave a talk in May at Pomona College on sectarianism and apathy in his home country.
Social activist Jibran Nasir, one of the few outspoken voices on religious extremism in Pakistan, gave a talk in May at Pomona College on sectarianism and apathy in his home country. (Irfan Khan / Los Angeles Times)
In recent weeks, a string of slayings in Karachi and beyond has presented a grim picture for minorities in Sunni-dominated Pakistan, as well as for Pakistani human rights activists and others who speak out against injustices.
In late April, activist Sabeen Mahmud, 40, was struck and killed by four bullets after she left a Karachi meeting on missing people in Baluchistan, the strife-torn, mineral-rich province in western Pakistan. The session, titled "Unsilencing Baluchistan: Take 2," had been scheduled to be held earlier in the month at the prestigious Lahore University of Management Sciences but was called off, reportedly after pressure from the government. Sabeen, who agreed to hold it instead at her Second Floor forum, was killed.
8
Several days later, a professor in the Mass Communications Department at Karachi University, Syed Waheed-ur-Rehman, was gunned down. His slaying remains unsolved.
Meanwhile, a senior educator and member of the government advisory board for textbooks and curriculum in Karachi, Bernadette L. Dean, fled Pakistan after receiving death threats from people she has referred to as "members of a political party."
"We must give credit to people in Pakistan who are still willing to stand up and be counted," said Ali Dayan Hasan, former director of Human Rights Watch in Islamabad, the capital. "But we must not overestimate their numbers or underestimate the risk to their lives. They are still a beleaguered and besieged minority."
In an article he wrote in Guernica magazine in April 2014 after his friend and journalist Raza Rumi survived an attack in Lahore, he referred to the term "liberal extremist." It is a title given to those who publicly condemn prejudice and abuse or are touted as "Western agents," said Hasan, now a fellow at the United States Institute of Peace in Washington.
"But I have an aversion to this term liberal or progressive," he said in a phone interview with the Los Angeles Times. "Because these are the universal values of tolerance and pluralism that are under attack. These values are not and should not be limited to a particular group of people to speak for."
@AndrewWiggin you found a way to lump a whole other group of people with a one word description too... good for you!
Sully Isdaman
2
"Pakistan  and the cities, in particular  are becoming increasingly dangerous for liberal thought," said Zohra Yusuf, chairwoman of the Human Rights Commission of Pakistan. "The intelligentsia is being targeted. The space is shrinking for liberal thinking while those propagating hatred towards minority communities carry on their campaigns unchecked. There is no clear policy on banned or militant outfits and the government is still reluctant to register madrassas or put any pressure on them."
Authorities recently arrested four highly educated Pakistani men who they said were responsible for several targeted killings in Karachi. The assailants, the authorities said, had all graduated from college, with degrees in engineering, business and Islamic studies.
The announcement drew suspicion from some quarters that the arrests had been made hastily because of mounting pressure. Previously, officials had blamed the spate of killings on "interference by rival states, particularly the Indian intelligence agency, RAW."
"There might be perhaps some truth to this fact," Hasan said. "But it does not take away from the fact that the state persistently fails to protect its citizens. If the state doesn't wish to be seen as a failed one, it must ensure security."
The arrests were also met with shock in some quarters, that well-educated, tech-savvy young adults would turn to a life of militancy.
After showing the video and concluding his talk, Nasir was asked by a member of the audience in Claremont: "What are you doing for your security and how should we help you?"
Nasir responded that he doesn't believe in personal security. He appeared frustrated by a similar question during an informal discussion later at the home of one of the event's organizers.
"That's the problem," he said. "Don't help me. Just be there when something happens and be counted. It's as simple as that."
Baloch, a reporter from Pakistan, is a visiting journalist at The Times sponsored by the Daniel Pearl Foundation in partnership with the Alfred Friendly Press Fellowships.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 06:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Colombian army's top leadership not facing justice in killings, report says</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-colombia-killings-human-rights-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Twenty-five-year-old street vendor Mauricio Duarte Guzman went out to play billiards one night in his rural Colombian home town of Gigante and never came home. His mother found him dead the next day in an army morgue, tagged by the local brigade as a rebel killed in combat.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Colombian army's top leadership not facing justice in killings, report says
Colombian officials at a military ceremony
Mauricio Dueas Castaeda / EPA
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos, right, and new Defense Minister Luis Carlos Villegas review army troops during a military ceremony in Bogota. A newreport indicates that top Colombian army brass knew or should have known about the extrajudicial killingsof hundreds of civilianslabeled as rebels.
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos, right, and new Defense Minister Luis Carlos Villegas review army troops during a military ceremony in Bogota. A newreport indicates that top Colombian army brass knew or should have known about the extrajudicial killingsof hundreds of civilianslabeled as rebels.
(Mauricio Dueas Castaeda / EPA)
Human Rights Watch
Twenty-five-year-old street vendor Mauricio Duarte Guzman went out to play billiards one night in his rural Colombian home town of Gigante and never came home. His mother found him dead the next day in an army morgue, tagged by the local brigade as a rebel killed in combat.
Guzmans mother, Hilda Guzman, said her son was one of several people from her town in southern Huila province who disappeared in 2007 during a wave of so-called false positive slayings. The cases involved unemployed, handicapped and otherwise disadvantaged youths across the country who were allegedly kidnapped and killed by military units and then identified as leftist guerrillas to inflate body counts.
Human Rights Watch report on Colombia killings
Leonardo Munoz / EPA
Jose Miguel Vivanco, director of Human Rights Watch for the Americas, speaks in Bogota, Colombia, during the presentation of a report on civilian killings.


Jose Miguel Vivanco, director of Human Rights Watch for the Americas, speaks in Bogota, Colombia, during the presentation of a report on civilian killings.


(Leonardo Munoz / EPA)
He was a good, healthy boy who had nothing to do with the rebels, and he was despicably murdered, Hilda Guzman said in an interview. Eight years later, I havent forgotten him, and I am still waiting for justice. The government has yet to pay me reparations.
Cases such as Guzmans are not rare, activists say. A report issued Wednesday by Human Rights Watch accused the Colombian military of widespread and systematic extrajudicial killings of hundreds of civilians between 2002 and 2008, when the armed forces progress in the nation's decades-long war was measured largely by the number of rebels killed in action.
While Colombias false positive atrocities have been known about for years, the HRW report said it has obtained previously unpublished prosecutorial evidence indicating that top Colombian army brass knew or should have known about the extrajudicial killings and that they should face criminal charges. Among those implicated is armed forces commander army Gen. Juan Pablo Rodriguez Barragan, the report said.
8
False positive killings amount to one of the worst mass atrocities in the Western Hemisphere in recent years, and there is mounting evidence that many senior army officers bear responsibility, said Jose Miguel Vivanco, HRWs Americas executive director. Yet the army officials in charge at the time of the killings have escaped justice and even ascended to the top of the military command.
Army representatives have denied special treatment for top-level officers, saying that 900 cases have been brought before various courts. The Colombian attorney generals office is known to have investigated at least 3,700 cases of extrajudicial killings.
El Tiempo newspaper of Bogota reported Wednesday that four generals, including former army commander Gen. Mario Montoya, have been called to testify by a special prosecutor appointed by the Supreme Court in connection with reportedfalse positives.
Citing overwhelming caseloads, the HRW report criticized the slow pace of justice, saying that so far, mostly lower ranking soldiers have been convicted. Vivanco called on the Colombian government to add prosecutors to pursue charges more aggressively against unit commanders, claiming that only a handful of colonels and no generals have been convicted.
Ramiro Orjuela, a Bogota-based human rights attorney who helped research the HRW report, said the slow pace of prosecutions of army leadership is because ofa lack of political will. ... This is a very precise demonstration of how the attorney generals office remains fearful of the army leadership, who are extremely powerful. Potential witnesses in these cases have been threatened and even killed.
cComments
Hey leave them along , this is our puppet government that we are loading up with money and military equipment , we will even be stablishing a nuke sub base there, to help us control the Latin Americas, and desstablelize countries like Venezuela , if they do give our oil barons. 30yrs oil...
Preci Gil
1
HRW also called on the U.S. government to review its military and anti-terrorism aid program that under Plan Colombia has totaled more than $9 billion since 2000. U.S. officials should enforce the Leahy Law passed by Congress in 1996, which calls on the government to withhold military aid to units suspected of human rights crimes, HRWs report said.
The report confirms past studies, including a groundbreaking 2008 report by the International Observation Mission on Extrajudicial Executions and Impunity in Colombia, a joint effort by 13 international human rights experts that helped bring the false positive atrocities to light.
This (HRW) report confirms what we all knew: that responsibility for the extrajudicial execution scandal in Colombia reaches top leadership, said Lisa Haugaard of the Washington-based Latin America Working Group think tank. To help complete the 2008 study, Haugaard said she interviewed witnesses and family members linked to 130 deaths.
What we heard was shockingly similar: groups of soldiers detaining poor young men taken in civilian clothes, who were later found dead in army morgues dressed in guerrilla uniforms, Haugaard said.
A preliminary version of the 2008 report was released prior to a mass killing that broke the false positives scandal wide open. That case involved 26 young men from a poor Bogota suburb who were promised work in North Santander province, but who instead were slain and claimed as rebel fighters killed in action.
Last year, an extensive report by the New Yorkbased peace advocacy group Fellowship of Reconciliation, or FOR, also linked false positive killings to specific Colombian army units and commanders who had received training at the U.S. Armys Ft. Benning and other installations.
John Lindsay-Poland, a former FOR official who managed the study and is now with the American Friends Service Committee, said the FOR and HRW studies are especially relevant because the U.S. government is using Colombian officers to train foreign militaries in Central America and the Middle East.
The findings of FOR and HRW show that Colombian military leadership is not a model that should be exported, and the U.S. training of these officers should be evaluated for its impact on human rights abuses, Lindsay-Poland said.
The accusations against Colombian military brass arealso relevant, Lindsay-Poland said, because of the peace negotiations underway in Havana between the Colombian government and Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, or FARC,rebels that aim to end the long-running conflict.
The peace talks are stuck on transitional justice issues, including whether rebel or military commanders will face trials and possible prison time for crimes against humanity. Both Vivanco and Lindsay-Poland warn that terms of any peace deal should not include impunity for army officials convicted of criminal involvement in false positives.
Kraul is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>France denounces U.S. spying exposed by WikiLeaks</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-france-hollande-wikileaks-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  French President Francois Hollande held a crisis meeting of the country's Defense Council on Wednesday after newspapers published WikiLeaks documents showing that the United States eavesdropped on him and two predecessors.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>France denounces U.S. spying exposed by WikiLeaks
French President Francois Hollande
Michel Euler / Associated Press
The Defense Council of French President Francois Hollande, shown this week at a European Union summit in Brussels, convened an emergency meeting on June 23.
The Defense Council of French President Francois Hollande, shown this week at a European Union summit in Brussels, convened an emergency meeting on June 23.
(Michel Euler / Associated Press)
European Debt Crisis
French President Francois Hollande held a crisis meeting of the country's Defense Council on Wednesday after newspapers published WikiLeaks documents showing that the United States eavesdropped on him and two predecessors.
After the meeting, the council issued a statement lambasting U.S. spying as unacceptable and declaring that France had demanded two years ago that the National Security Agency stop snooping on its leaders.
Hollande spoke to President Obama on Wednesday afternoon as lawmakers across the political spectrum insisted the French president demand a formal apology. After the telephone conversation, the Elysee Palace issued a statement saying Obama had reiterated a firm pledge made two years ago, after allegations of U.S. spying on French officials first emerged, that the practice had been halted.
France: Spying on allies 'unacceptable'
France has summoned the U.S. ambassador to explain allegations by the group WikiLeaks that the U.S. has been spying on French presidents.
France has summoned the U.S. ambassador to explain allegations by the group WikiLeaks that the U.S. has been spying on French presidents.
See more videos
A White House statement said Obama had reiterated that we are not targeting and will not target the communications of the French president. The statement made no admission of prior spying, nor ruled out intelligence-gathering efforts on the French more broadly.
We are committed to our productive and indispensable intelligence relationship with France, which allows us to make progress against shared threats, including international terrorism and proliferation, among others, the White House said.
The president feted Hollande during a 2014 state visit to Washington, and the two leaders emphasized their deepening ties.
The latest WikiLeaks revelations, first published in the daily newspaper Liberation and the investigative news website Mediapart, allege that the NSA eavesdropped on telephone conversations of former Presidents Jacques Chirac and Nicolas Sarkozy as well as Hollande.
WikiLeaks spokesman Kristinn Hrafnsson said he was confident the documents were authentic, the Associated Press reported.
8
Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius summoned the American ambassador to Paris, Jane Hartley, to his office Wednesday evening to demand an explanation over the spying claims, which sparked indignation and anger in France.
These are unacceptable facts that have already been the subject of clarification between the U.S. and France, notably at the end of 2013 when the first revelations were made and during a state visit by the president of the republic to the United States in February 2014, read the Defense Council statement.
Promises were made by the American authorities. They must remember and strictly respect them. France, which has reinforced its control and protection measures, will not tolerate any scheming that threatens its security and the protection of its interests, it read.
In 2013, documents released by NSA leaker Edward Snowden showed that the United States had intercepted about 70 million pieces of data on French telecommunications. Snowden also revealed that the U.S. had been monitoring the cellphone communications of German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
After the Merkel disclosures, Obama ordered a review of NSA spying on allies. Afterward, U.S. officials said Obama had ordered a halt to surveillance of the leaders of allied countries and their aides.
The WikiLeaks website listed the contents of what it called Espionnage Elysee (Elysee Spying), a collection of top secret intelligence reports and technical data from five major intercepts of communications involving high level officials from successive French governments over the last 10 years, including the three presidents.
Enter Europe's excuse to spy on their OWN people under the guise of the US spying.
trutherluther
86
Transcripts of eavesdropping on telephone conversations and emails covered subjects including a top United Nations appointment, the Middle East peace process and the handling of the Greek debt crisis as well as the leadership and future of the European Union.
One document reportedly shows phone numbers listed by the NSA as top French official intercept targets, including that of the president's cellphone, with some digits crossed out. Other senior officials, including the Elysee secretary general, the Foreign Ministry spokesman, the presidential advisor for Africa and the secretary of state for trade, also had their conversations recorded, according to the leaked documents.
A purported intelligence report from March 2010 follows an intercepted communication from Sarkozy expressing his frustration with U.S. spying on France.
In another, from 2008, Sarkozy reportedly talks about the global economic crisis. The president blamed many of the current economic problems on mistakes made by the U.S. government, but believes that Washington is now heeding some of his advice, the document says.
In the National Assembly on Wednesday, Prime Minister Manuel Valls repeated that the United States systematic and continued spying on the leaders of foreign countries was not legitimate, not acceptable and not normal.
This information is extremely serious, Valls told lawmakers. It's not legitimate in the name of national interests to carry out eavesdropping  and, no, France does not spy on its European partners or its allies.
France will not tolerate any scheming that threatens its security and fundamental interest, Valls added. He said the U.S. now had to make an effort to repair the damage caused by the revelations.
U.S. National Security Council spokesman Ned Price said in a statement that the American government would not comment on the specifics of the leak.
As a general matter, we do not conduct any foreign intelligence surveillance activities unless there is a specific and validated national security purpose. This applies to ordinary citizens and world leaders alike, he said.
French government spokesman Stephane Le Foll said a senior French intelligence official was being sent to the United States for talks with his counterparts.
The WikiLeaks revelations came just hours before members of Parliament were expected to approve a bill giving the French intelligence services sweeping new powers to snoop on their own people. Critics have said the law would be a threat to individual liberties, but the government argues the measures are necessary after the January attacks in Paris by Islamist extremists.
Willsher is a special correspondent. Times staff writer Michael A. Memoli in Washington contributed to this report.
ALSO:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 22:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Russia and the West rattle sabers and renew sanctions</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-russia-west-cold-war-rhetoric-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Though Russian and Western officials repeatedly claim they don't want a return to Cold War-era hostility, both sides have renewed sanctions and toughened their military posture in recent days.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Russia and the West rattle sabers and renew sanctions
Vladimir Putin
Sergei Karpukhin / European Pressphoto Agency
Russian President Vladimir Putin, with Kremlin Chief of Staff Sergei Ivanov at his left, speaks during a June 24 Kremlin meeting at which he a decree extending a ban on food imports from the European Union.
Russian President Vladimir Putin, with Kremlin Chief of Staff Sergei Ivanov at his left, speaks during a June 24 Kremlin meeting at which he a decree extending a ban on food imports from the European Union.
(Sergei Karpukhin / European Pressphoto Agency)
Ukraine Crisis (2013-2014)
Though Russian and Western officials repeatedly claim they don't want a return to Cold War-era hostility, both sides have renewed sanctions and toughened their military posture in recent days.
Russian President Vladimir Putin on Wednesday extended for an additional year his country's ban on most food imports from the European Union, two days after the 28-nation Western bloc announced that its sanctions on Russia will be prolonged to the end of January 2016.
The tit-for-tat embargoes -- which hurt the countries imposing them as well as those targeted -- show the intractability of the conflict in Ukraine that prompted the measures last year.
Ben Hodges
Maciej Kulczynski / European Pressphoto Agency
Lt. Gen. Ben Hodges, commander of U.S. forces in Europe, speaks at a transatlantic defense meeting in Wroclaw, Poland, on June 12.
Lt. Gen. Ben Hodges, commander of U.S. forces in Europe, speaks at a transatlantic defense meeting in Wroclaw, Poland, on June 12.
(Maciej Kulczynski / European Pressphoto Agency)
The EU and the United States cut off Russian access to international financial institutions nearly a year ago and have blacklisted dozens of Kremlin officials and business kingpins seen as fomenting the violence in eastern Ukraine that has killed more than 6,400 people.
The European and U.S. sanctions on Russia have been renewed as the Western allies try to pressure Putin to refrain from supporting separatist rebels in the neighboring country that, like Russia, was part of the Soviet Union before its 1991 breakup.
Putin claims the pro-Russia separatists are independently waging war against the Kiev government but Western satellite imagery and the confessions of captured Russian soldiers bolster Ukrainian leaders' accusations that Moscow is orchestrating the rebellion.
8
"Russia is actively and massively fueling this conflict, Lt. Gen. Ben Hodges, the commander of U.S. forces in Europe, told the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe on Tuesday, according to excerpts of his briefing released Wednesday. Disputing Putin's claim that any Russians in the Ukraine battle are there at their own volition, Hodges said "these are not volunteers or mercenaries; they are trained, equipped and uniformed active-duty Russian soldiers.
Hodges' briefing to the Vienna-based European security agency coincided with a meeting of the foreign ministers of Russia, Ukraine, France and Germany in Paris in an apparently unsuccessful attempt to rescue the Feb. 12 peace plan hammered out in the Belarus capital of Minsk but repeatedly violated in recent weeks.
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov told reporters that the four top diplomats committed their countries to ensuring that the Minsk accord doesn't completely collapse. But he alluded to "powers who would like to destroy this process," an apparent reference to the United States, which is not party to the informal negotiating forum known as the Normandy Four.
Urban combat and artillery exchanges ebbed after the Minsk agreement was signed four months ago by Ukraine's warring factions and endorsed by Putin, who pledged to use his influence with the separatists to end the bloodshed. But the lull in heavy fighting was mostly due to harsh winter weather and the seas of mud that followed in early spring, as artillery exchanges escalated after the mud dried last month and tanks and armored vehicles could maneuver again.
European leaders endorsed their sanctions extension on Monday after concluding that Putin hadn't done enough to fulfill his pledge to work for peace in Ukraine.
USA and Russia. so self righteous that we each boast the need to engulf human race in potential threat of nuclear war, again. inflated national egos.wars r' us.
cynicalretiree
3
The Russian government sent a request to Putin on Tuesday to prolong Moscow's ban on food imports from European Union countries, going the Western bloc one better by extending the retaliatory ban through June 24, 2016.
Russia and the U.S.-led North Atlantic Treaty Organization have also stepped up arms production and deployment in moves each side claims were prompted by the other's aggressive actions. Putin announced last week that at least 40 new nuclear-armed intercontinental ballistic missiles will be added to Russia's defenses by the end of this year, and NATO plans to position new forces and weaponry in Eastern European allies' territory to guard against any threat of Russian hostility.
U.S. Defense Secretary Ashton Carter, on a tour of NATO's Eastern European flank this week, has said that tanks, armored vehicles and other military hardware would be deployed to member countries made nervous by Russia's involvement in the Ukraine crisis. Carter said the equipment would be moved to Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania and Bulgaria -- all former Soviet republics or satellites that Moscow still considers part of its "sphere of influence."
Russia had been diplomatically courting some EU states in recent months in apparent hopes of getting one of them to break ranks on the sanctions extension, as all 28 member states have to agree on such matters.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras was in Russia last week to meet with Putin and left with a $2.77-billion deal to build and operate part of a planned Russian pipeline project. The pipeline is intended to bypass Ukraine and deliver natural gas to Western European customers.
A senior Russian lawmaker, Federation Council President Valentina Matviyenko, told the Tass news agency that special consideration should be given to European Union countries that have "actively opposed the policy of sanctions." She named Greece, Hungary and Cyprus as examples of states with which Russia should resume normal trade, although all three ultimately did vote to extend sanctions.
Russian Agriculture Minister Alexander Tkachev, however, hailed the cutoff of European food imports as a stimulus for Russia's own farm output.
"We are grateful to our European and American colleagues who made us take a fresh look at agriculture, forced us to find our potential," he said Wednesday, according to Tass.
"Against sanctions the agriculture sector has a tendency to grow. Weve learned not only to survive, but to work in this situation," Tkachev said. "If our Western partners believe that the sanctions set us back many years, they are deeply mistaken."
Follow @cjwilliamslat for the latest international news 24/7

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 20:18:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama to families of hostages held by terrorists: 'We will stand by you'</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-hostage-policy-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  President Obama said Wednesday the U.S. government has at times failed the families of Americans held hostage overseas by communicating poorly or failing to coordinate recovery efforts, but he promised Wednesday that "that ends today" with a set of new policies.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>3
Some family members are concerned about other components of the new policy. In particular, some are skeptical of the idea of keeping the FBI in charge of a process that they feel has let them down.
The wife of Warren Weinstein, a government contractor killed in a U.S. drone strike againsthis Al Qaeda captors this year, said in a statement that she thinks the setup wont allow for enough interagency coordination.
One senior administration official said the FBI was chosen to lead the operation because of its experience in conducting investigations, gathering intelligence and supporting crime victims. The attorney general will establish within the FBI an interagency hostage recovery operation that fuses together representatives from the departments of Justice, State, Treasury and Defense as well as intelligence officials.
The hostage rescue system that Obama set up is not an FBI organization, the official said, but rather will bring the requisite expertise from all departments and agencies to bear on the recovery of Americans taken hostage overseas. The official requested anonymity to discuss the new policy in advance of the presidents announcement.
The new plans were crafted as part of a sweeping policy review over several months, a process that also included interviews with families.
In addition to the FBI-led group, the presidents National Security Council will have a hostage response group that meets every week to keep an eye on hostage recovery strategies and lend help. A special presidential envoy for hostage affairs will be charged with coordinating U.S. diplomacy on hostage matters.
He quoted Diane Foley, the mother of James Foley, as saying, "As Americans, we can do better."
I totally agree, Obama said. We must do better.
For more White House coverage, follow @cparsons
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 14:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China's Internet users do a body check, from belly buttons to collarbones</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-chinese-internet-body-belly-buttons-collarbones-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  First came the Belly Button Challenge. Then it was a long legs test. Next up came a collarbone competition, plus feats to demonstrate the depth of one's dimples and the fullness of one's eyelashes.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>China's Internet users do a body check, from belly buttons to collarbones
China and body image
Fred Dufour / AFP/Getty Images
People exercise at the Aimin Fat Reduction Hospital in Tianjin, China. Internet memes supposedly gauging physical attractiveness have gained popularity in the country.
People exercise at the Aimin Fat Reduction Hospital in Tianjin, China. Internet memes supposedly gauging physical attractiveness have gained popularity in the country.
(Fred Dufour / AFP/Getty Images)
Medical Research
First came the Belly Button Challenge. Then it was a long legs test. Next up came a collarbone competition, plus feats to demonstrate the depth of ones dimples and the fullness of ones eyelashes.
In recent weeks, Internet users in mainland China have been going gaga over online memes supposedly aimed at testing  or telegraphing  how fit and attractive ones figure is. While being chubby was once regarded as a sign of health and wealth in a country frequently beset by famine, China in recent years has witnessed a growing body-consciousness, with weight-loss clinics, breast-enhancement centers and plastic surgery hospitals all gaining in popularity.
The worlds two biggest economies have been eyeing each other warily lately. Like two heavyweight contenders angling for a match, the U.S. and China have been managing a hugely productive economic relationship  two-way trade hit $590 billion last year  all the while trying to figure out who runs... ( Kim Murphy )
As China has urbanized and modernized, it has also grown fatter. A study by researchers at the University of Washington published last year in the journal the Lancet found that 28% of Chinese men and 27% of women were overweight or obese. The rate of childhood obesity has also been rising at an alarming clip.
The Belly Button Challenge peaked in mid-June, with thousands of people posting selfies showing their attempts to touch their navels by reaching one arm around their backs in a yoga-style pose. To date, the topic has garnered more than 130 million hits on Weibo, Chinas Twitter-like microblogging service.
8
Exactly what touched off the Belly Button Challenge remains unclear, though some online postings claimed U.S. scientists had discovered that the inability to complete the feat was an indicator that one needed to slim down.
A variety of celebrities  mostly super-slim young women with narrow waists  seized the opportunity to post photos of themselves in the pose; tour guides in Hunan province posed for pictures of themselves in red bikinis contorting themselves like pretzels. A young woman in Chongqing  who weighs about 100 pounds and stands about 5 feet 1 -- spent days trying to complete the challenge but ended up with a dislocated shoulder, the Chongqing News reported .
State-run media have reported on the trend and tried to tamp it down a bit, with the Communist Party mouthpiece Peoples Daily quoting a personal trainer in Nanjing as saying that the ability to complete the test might just mean one is rather flexible or simply has long arms. I cant do it either, said the trainer, Xie Wei.
Others have mocked the trend. In one widely reposted message, one commentator urged Chinese to go ahead and eat. American scientists, he joked, had discovered that some primates were incompletely evolved, with their excessively long arms not accustomed to walking upright.
-----------
Looks the Chinese are just as crazy as Americans when it comes to the Internet.
rtamtc
8:32 p.m.: An earlier version of this post incorrectly said Chinese actor Tong Dawei posted the message urging people to eat.
-----------
But netizens have just seemed to move from gazing at their navels to other parts of their physiques.
When 24-year-old Chinese Canadian singer Kris Wu, 6 feet 2, posted a photo of himself stretched out on a couch, his legs occupying the entire sofa, it set off another viral fad. Fans issued a challenge to others to sit with friends on a couch and see how many people their legs could stretch across.
Inveighed the state-run China Daily: People with long limbs are simply born that way, and for those with short limbs, stretching over many people on a couch will have to remain a distant dream.
Next up came the collarbone challenge, with young women showing off the depths of their clavicle hollows by filling the depressions with stacks of coins or even eggs.
Critics of the trend  a resurrection of a fad that first surfaced two years ago  said the collarbone meme was just an opportunity for attention-starved youths to draw attention to their chest areas from their bare midriffs.
Those with neither flat bellies nor sexy necklines, however, were not to be left out. Up next came women showing off the depths of their dimples by demonstrating how they could hold pen-caps in their cheek depressions, and others balancing multiple Q-tips or toothpicks on their eyelashes.
Chinese Internet users also took the opportunity to repost photos from this springs short-lived Hold a Coke Can With Your Breasts challenge, which was initially touted as a breast-cancer awareness project but was later revealed to have been initiated by an American adult entertainment casting company.
Put Coke between your breasts and coins on collarbones, reach your bellybutton from behind, keep the pen cap in your dimples, leave toothpicks on your eyelashes, one fed-up Chinese Internet user wrote on Weibo. Id like to report you monsters who can do all these to the police.
Nicole Liu and Harvard Zhang in The Times' Beijing bureau contributed to this report.
Follow @JulieMakLAT for news from China
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Greece, migrants relive harrowing boat journeys, but onstage</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-c1-greece-refugee-theater-20150624-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  After trekking hundreds of miles through fierce climates and villages filled with murderous bandits, the migrants had finally reached their destination.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>1
On this night, the migrants were rehearsing for a show at an Athens cultural festival. Titled "We Are the Persians," it weaves their back stories into a series of reenactments, with the goal of providing a more human picture of the migrant crisis. As they pulled the boat across the stage to represent their journeys, the scene was surreal, at once a pointed reminder of their struggles and an inadequate simulation of them.
An Afghan named Khalil practiced a scene that had him reenacting his detention by the Greek coast guard. He and other migrants picked up guns to replicate their captors' poses, then threw themselves on the floor while dramatic music played.
"They held guns to us," he belted out theatrically. "They took our money. They kept us in terrible places."
Khalil, 25, fled Afghanistan about 10 years ago at the urging of his father, who worried that an increasingly active Taliban in their town would either kill or recruit his son. After hiding out in Greece for years, he was granted asylum last year.
It might seem uncomfortable to relive, multiple times each rehearsal night, what you've spent years trying to forget. But those who went through the ordeal say that the opposite has proved to be the case. With its blend of larger artistic goals and concrete technical requirements, theater offers a unique kind of escape. The more a moment becomes about blocking, the less it's about lost friends and a fear of death.
"It was very hard at first to go through it again," Khalil said as he inhaled deeply on a cigarette during a rehearsal break. "But each time it got a little easier. And it was easy to act  all I had to do was remember the fear."
::
Markopoulou and AMAKA had previously worked with prisoners, and then shortly after began working with migrants. About three years ago, she began dealing with this particular group, betting that they might take to it more easily than psychiatric therapy.
For the first year, most of the young men didn't even speak. Markopoulou, a director known for ambitious projects such as a touring version of "The Iliad," instead tried to get them comfortable moving in unusual ways. Soon she graduated to improv exercises.
And this month, she and the migrants put on a major production for the first time, staging several performances of "We Are the Persians" at the popular Athens Festival. The audience of about 150 at each performance was moved, by the stories onstage and back stories that inspired them.
The migrant actors were also paid for performing for the first time. The off-stage group  including Markopoulou and the crew of set, lighting and other designers  is typically volunteer-based and was also paid for the first time.
To some, the idea of expending effort in this way might seem strange; migrants need employment, not Eugene O'Neill. But the actors say that the advantages will stay with them a lot longer than a few added euros.
"On the one hand, I want to show how hard the trip was, because it's not really what people here think," Reza, who has a mix of swagger and thoughtfulness, said as he took a break from rehearsing. "They hear 'boats' and they don't realize what we go through. But I also do it for me, to remind me of what happened, so that I never forget."
Reza's family fled Afghanistan for Iran before he was born. As part of the Hazara minority, they spoke a dialect similar to that used by many Iranians. But Afghans weren't accorded the same rights in Iran as natives. Reza faced heavy discrimination and eventually fled. En route from Iran to the Turkish coast, a good friend died under the forbidding conditions.
For all the peril of their pre-Europe lives, migrants begin to face a new set difficulties only after they arrive. Khalil has seen his family scatter across Europe and Asia, and he hasn't seen any of them since he left Afghanistan. Reza, meanwhile, lacks an asylum card, so he can't leave the country to visit family members in Iran. Starting a new family here isn't possible either, because without those papers he is prohibited from marrying. Most of the migrants live in especially poor parts of Athens, where drug use and homelessness are high.
But they have also found reasons to be optimistic, and rehearsal is interrupted several times as the actors are struck with a case of the giggles, often in the most oppressive scenes.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 03:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. no longer will prosecute families who try to pay ransom for hostages</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-hostage-policy-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Relatives who try to pay ransom to free a family member being held hostage by terrorists will no longer face the threat of prosecution under a new policy from the Obama administration that seeks to streamline U.S. rescue efforts after several high-profile deaths.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. no longer will prosecute families who try to pay ransom for hostages
James Foley
Steven Senne / Associated Press
Journalist James Foley in Boston in 2011. President Obama ordered an extensive review of hostage recovery practices after the beheadings last summer of Foley and fellow American journalist Steve Sotloff.
Journalist James Foley in Boston in 2011. President Obama ordered an extensive review of hostage recovery practices after the beheadings last summer of Foley and fellow American journalist Steve Sotloff.
(Steven Senne / Associated Press)
Kidnapping
Relatives who try to pay ransom to free a family member being held hostage by terrorists will no longer face the threat of prosecution under a new policy from the Obama administration that seeks to streamline U.S. rescue efforts after several high-profile deaths.
President Obama plans to announce the new policy Wednesday as part of a broader set of guidelines on hostage crises, the result of a lengthy policy review. The overall goal is to coordinate the wide-ranging resources of the federal government to try to secure the return of American hostages, officials said.
The review is also an effort to deal more humanely with the panic-stricken families of abducted Americans, whose complaints about U.S. government handling of their cases have beset the Obama administration during a painful year that has seen notorious cases of abduction, threats and videotaped killings.
Shirley Sotloff
Jim Lo Scalzo / European Pressphto Agency
Shirley Sotloff, mother of slain journalist Steven Sotloff, at a Newseum event in Washington on June 8. Families of abducted Americans complained about the government's handling of their cases.
Shirley Sotloff, mother of slain journalist Steven Sotloff, at a Newseum event in Washington on June 8. Families of abducted Americans complained about the government's handling of their cases.
(Jim Lo Scalzo / European Pressphto Agency)
Families say they have received confusing messages from the government. One agency would threaten relatives with prosecution for talking about ransoms while another offered to facilitate such payments, for example.
The new policy also will keep the FBI in charge of managing hostage crises, despite the requests of families who believe the current structure fails to give negotiators enough power to operate.
The U.S. government will continue its long-standing policy of refusing to pay ransoms, senior administration officials said, or to negotiate with terrorists, as some European countries do.
8
The resources of the United States government are not going to be used to make concessions to terrorists, White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest said Tuesday, in the administrations only public comments about the forthcoming policy. We do not want to open the door to even more Americans being vulnerable to a hostage-taking.
Critics charged that the changes dont go far enough to solve long-running problems in the efforts to free Americans from captivity, including two dozen now held around the world.
Wholesale changes are needed, but whats being put forward is nothing more than window dressing, I fear, said Rep. Duncan Hunter (R-Alpine), a Marine veteran and member of the House Armed Services Committee. Its a pathetic response to a serious problem that has plagued the ability of the U.S. to successfully recover Americans held captive in the post-9/11 era.
Some family members of past and current hostages expressed concern about the plan to continue housing the bureaucracy at the FBI. Many had asked that the president appoint a hostage czar who reported to Obama and would have the authority to direct the Pentagon, State Department, FBI and intelligence networks as needed to coordinate rescue efforts.
Elaine Weinstein, whose husband, Warren, was a government contractor accidentally killed by a U.S. drone strike in Pakistan this year while being held hostage by Al Qaeda, said Tuesday that the information she and her family received in their 3 1/2-year ordeal was inconsistent at best and utterly disappointing.
She expressed concern about the decision to keep housing the hostage-rescue unit at the FBI. She said a better home would have been the presidents National Security Council, both to improve coordination and to ensure that those debating counter-terrorism activities and hostage recovery efforts were sitting in the same room.
@affableman And when someone in your immediate family is in line to get their head cut off, I'm sure you'll feel the same way.
Ryan Knight
14
We hope to be the last family that fails to receive the level of coordinated government support that those who serve abroad deserve when trouble finds them, she said.
Hunter said another issue with FBI leadership is that the bureau is not set up to rescue hostages in hostile areas. Even though the FBI official leading rescue efforts will have deputies from the Pentagon and State Department, he or she wont have real authority to command them, he said.
The presidents team decided to keep the hostage recovery effort at the FBI because the infrastructure was already in place at the bureau, said a U.S. official, who agreed to discuss the details of the changes on condition of anonymity because the results of the White House review had not been publicly released.
Obama ordered an extensive review of the hostage recovery practices last fall, looking into how the government deals with the threats and with the families of hostages. It followed the searing images of the executions last summer of American journalists James Foley and Steve Sotloff, carried out and broadcast by Islamic State extremists.
Since then, the White House has slowly moved from staunch opposition to conversations about ransom between hostages families and kidnappers to a position that one administration official described as more humane.
As a result of the policy changes, families will not be discouraged from communicating directly with hostage-takers  a new flexibility that analysts said could have operational benefits.
If you are open to communications, by definition youre going to know more about what it is the hostage-takers want and what their bottom lines might be, said Bruce Riedel, a former CIA official now at the Brookings Institution.
Also, if the new policy is seen as a clear White House directive, he said, that will give more power to the FBI official overseeing hostage rescue efforts.
The Office of the Director of National Intelligence will appoint a so-called issue manager for hostage affairs, charged with compiling information from different intelligence agencies and working to quickly declassify relevant details to provide family members and lawmakers with new information concerning a hostage, the U.S. official said.
Earnest acknowledged that improving communications with relatives was a high priority.
The changes do not come easily at the White House. Some advisors cautioned against giving families more latitude to discuss and pay ransoms out of fear that it would make Americans overseas more attractive to kidnappers.
Thats a huge worry, Riedel said. Thats why theyre saying that the no concessions rule will remain the policy of the United States.
For news from Washington, follow @cparsons and @ByBrianBennett

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 02:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Opposition leader ends hunger strike after Venezuela sets election date</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-venezuela-opposition-election-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Venezuelan opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez ended his 30-day hunger strike Tuesday after the government scheduled legislative elections for Dec. 6, thereby meeting his demand.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Opposition leader ends hunger strike after Venezuela sets election date
Venezuela opposition hunger strike
Ariana Cubillos / Associated Press
Lilian Tintori, center, wife of jailed opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez, is flanked by Patricia Ceballos, wife of jailed San Cristobal Mayor Daniel Ceballos, and an opposition member who was on hunger strike, at a news conference in Caracas, Venezuela.
Lilian Tintori, center, wife of jailed opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez, is flanked by Patricia Ceballos, wife of jailed San Cristobal Mayor Daniel Ceballos, and an opposition member who was on hunger strike, at a news conference in Caracas, Venezuela.
(Ariana Cubillos / Associated Press)
8
By setting a date for National Assembly elections, Tibisay Lucena, head of the electoral council, on Monday ended weeks of speculation that the socialist government of President Nicolas Maduro might call off the vote. Lucena said the vote was never in doubt.
When a friend texted me that coffee and toilet paper were on the shelves of an eastern Caracas supermarket, I raced to El Patio outlet hoping against hope that the increasingly scarce household items would still be available. ( Mery Mogollon )
Lopez's wife, Lilian Tintori, on Tuesday read a statement from her husband in which he asked 104 other hunger strikers to end their fasts as well.
We took on this protest not to die but so that all of us Venezuelans can live with dignity  I will continue the struggle for a better Venezuela, Lopez said in his note.
A former mayor of a Caracas borough, Lopez has been detained at a military base prison near Caracas, the Venezuelan capital, since February 2014 on charges of incitement to violence. He denies the charges and claims they are politically motivated.
Probably working for the worlds super rich oil barons
Preci Gil
1
Lopez was arrested after Maduro opponents took to the streets last year to protest hyperinflation, high crime and scarcities of basic foodstuffs. Violent confrontations with authorities across the country left 43 dead and 850 injured.
Various human rights and international political leaders, including former Spanish Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez, have demanded that Lopez be freed, along with Mayors Daniel Ceballos of San Cristobal and Antonio Ledezma of Caracas, who are being held on charges of rebellion and conspiracy, respectively.
A caravan of buses carrying a group of Brazilian politicians who traveled to Venezuela last week in a show of support for Lopez was blocked on an airport road by pro-government protesters. The Brazilian government issued a formal protest over the incident.
Ordinarily, the date for National Assembly voting to elect deputies for five-year terms is determined much earlier in the year to allow for a longer campaign season. Maduros United Socialist Party of Venezuela and allies hold a 99-seat majority in the 165-member body.
Some opposition figures were concerned that Maduro, whose popularity has been battered by a worsening economy and food scarcities, might call off the elections so as not to risk losing control of the assembly.
In a speech at a Caracas auditorium Monday, Maduro indicated he would not take loss of assembly control sitting down.
If the right wing takes control of the assembly, serious things will happen. It will unleash a process of street confrontations, Maduro said. I will be the first to go to the streets.
Lopez and other opposition members are also calling for international monitors for December election results in light of disputed voting in the 2013 presidential election to replace Hugo Chavez, who died in March of that year.
Special correspondents Mogollon and Kraul reported from Caracas and Bogota, Colombia, respectively.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 01:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New Ebola cases frustrate hopes of defeating the virus in Sierra Leone</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-sierra-leone-ebola-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Two new Ebola cases have been identified in Sierra Leone's capital in recent days, frustrating hopes that the deadly virus may have been defeated there.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>New Ebola cases frustrate hopes of defeating the virus in Sierra Leone
Ebola in Sierra Leone
Michael Duff / Associated Press
A team of health workers searches for people suffering from Ebola during an education drive in Freetown, Sierra Leone, in March.
A team of health workers searches for people suffering from Ebola during an education drive in Freetown, Sierra Leone, in March.
(Michael Duff / Associated Press)
Ebola
Two new Ebola cases have been identified in Sierra Leone's capital in recent days, frustrating hopes that the deadly virus may have been defeated there.
The announcement by the countrys National Ebola Response Center followed a resurgence of cases in the northeast of the country, where President Ernest Bai Koroma this month ordered troops to enforce quarantines and a nighttime curfew in the districts of Kambia and Port Loko.
Caption Ebola in Liberia
John Moore / Getty Images
Sanitized gloves and boots hang to dry as a burial team collects Ebola victims from a Ministry of Health treatment center for cremation on Oct. 2 in Monrovia, Liberia.
Sanitized gloves and boots hang to dry as a burial team collects Ebola victims from a Ministry of Health treatment center for cremation on Oct. 2 in Monrovia, Liberia. (John Moore / Getty Images)
Caption Ebola in Liberia
Pascal Guyot / AFP/Getty Images
Medical personnel at the Ebola treatment center at Island hospital in Monrovia, Liberia, disinfect people who had brought patients suspected of having the Ebola virus on Oct. 2.
Medical personnel at the Ebola treatment center at Island hospital in Monrovia, Liberia, disinfect people who had brought patients suspected of having the Ebola virus on Oct. 2. (Pascal Guyot / AFP/Getty Images)
See more galleries
Complacency is our biggest challenge, Koroma said in announcing the measures. Now more than ever is the time we must all remain vigilant in our households and communities.
Sierra Leone was one of the West African countries hardest hit by the Ebola outbreak, accounting for nearly a third of the 11,000 people killed since last year, according to figures released by the World Health Organization.
Neighboring Liberia was declared Ebola-free in May, and the number of known cases in Sierra Leone dropped to just two that month. But the figure has increased again, with 14 cases recorded in Kambia and Port Loko in the week ending June 15, the WHO said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 00:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ferry strike disrupts traffic across English Channel; migrants add to chaos</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-ferry-strike-english-channel-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Migrants swarmed British-bound vehicles in the French port of Calais on Tuesday after a strike by ferry workers severely disrupted services across the English Channel, shutting down the cross-channel tunnel and stranding thousands of passengers.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Ferry strike disrupts traffic across English Channel; migrants add to chaos
MyFerryLink strike
Kamil Zihnioglu / Associated Press
An information board shows that Eurostar trains are suspended for the rest of the day at Gare du Nord station in Paris on June 23, 2015.
An information board shows that Eurostar trains are suspended for the rest of the day at Gare du Nord station in Paris on June 23, 2015.
(Kamil Zihnioglu / Associated Press)
France
Migrants swarmed British-bound vehicles in the French port of Calais on Tuesday after a strike by ferry workers severely disrupted services across the English Channel, shutting down the cross-channel tunnel and stranding thousands of passengers.
The ferry strike diverted vehicles to the Channel Tunnel, causing a massive traffic jam that was exacerbated when strikers entered part of the tunnel and set fires, helping to sow chaos.
MyFerryLink strike
Philippe Huguen / AFP/Getty Images
Striking employees of the French company MyFerryLink, a cross-channel ferry service, stand near a burning-tire barricade as they block access to the Channel Tunnel in Calais, France.
Striking employees of the French company MyFerryLink, a cross-channel ferry service, stand near a burning-tire barricade as they block access to the Channel Tunnel in Calais, France.
(Philippe Huguen / AFP/Getty Images)
Images broadcast on television showed large groups of migrants, most from North Africa and the Middle East, running after slow-moving or stationary trucks and clambering on board in the hope of traveling to Britain through the Channel Tunnel undetected.
The British Foreign Office issued a warning to all drivers along that route to keep their doors locked and secure any unattended vehicles to keep people from illegally entering the country.
The suspension [of services] meant there were lots of vehicles having to queue on the motorway, and [that] is an invitation to migrants to climb on board, Eurotunnel spokesman John Keefe said.
Keefe said some of the migrants had broken into trucks, threatened drivers and damaged the goods on board in an attempt to get into Britain without papers.
Pretty much everything they are doing is illegal, he said.
We will spend most of this evening pulling migrants off trucks  our requirement is to make sure that no one is on board when they go into the tunnel.
The wildcat strike was carried out by MyFerryLink workers who are concerned about job losses.
Brown is tempted to bullet train across the ocean to transport all the potential future Democrat voters to California. But his Sacramento friends might not be so eager because they are from a different culture.
AndrewWiggin
2
They blocked ferry traffic during two separate actions on Tuesday - for a few hours in the early morning and then later in the afternoon, Eurotunnel said.
The action caused severe gridlock for vehicles either trying to make their way to the port or onto the Channel Tunnel bound for England, as well as for drivers trying to make French-bound journeys on the English side of the Channel.
Later in the day, the workers also broke into the Eurotunnel terminal, got onto the tracks, threw rubble around and set fire to tires causing huge plumes of smoke, Keefe said.
Eurotunnel trains carry vehicles through the tunnel. Its service was briefly suspended but was running again by evening, with some delays.
However, EuroStar, which runs a high-speed passenger train through the tunnel, said all its services would be suspended until the morning, bringing disruption to passengers trying to board at Paris Gare du Nord and Londons St. Pancras Station.
Ferry traffic resumed from the port by evening following earlier disruptions.
The days events shone a new spotlight on a migrant camp at Calais, which has swelled to an estimated 3,000 people.
Calais Deputy Mayor Philippe Mignonet told the BBC that it was hyper critical to say the migrant situation was Calais responsibility.
Calais is not the destination. ... The fact that they wanted to get in trucks, thats because they want to go to England, so that means that England is the magnet, he said. The English government has got to realize that it is not our responsibility.
They go through Calais to get to England, and I wish them good luck, he added.
Boyle is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Tue Jun 23 23:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China hacking? Beijing is also a victim, foreign minister says in interview</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-china-foreign-minister-20150623-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The world's two biggest economies have been eyeing each other warily lately. Like two heavyweight contenders angling for a match, the U.S. and China have been managing a hugely productive economic relationship - two-way trade hit $590 billion last year - all the while trying to figure out who runs...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>China hacking? Beijing is also a victim, foreign minister says in interview
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi
Attila Kisbenedek / AFP/Getty Images
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with the Los Angeles Times in Beijing ahead of talks between his country and the U.S.
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with the Los Angeles Times in Beijing ahead of talks between his country and the U.S.
(Attila Kisbenedek / AFP/Getty Images)
We are 'not competitors, much less adversaries,' Chinese foreign minister says of U.S.
China says it's also the victim of wide-scale computer hacking
Chinese foreign minister calls for new superpower model in the post-Cold War age
The worlds two biggest economies have been eyeing each other warily lately. Like two heavyweight contenders angling for a match, the U.S. and China have been managing a hugely productive economic relationship  two-way trade hit $590 billion last year  all the while trying to figure out who runs the world.
The two nations have forged common ground on big-ticket items such as climate change and concerns over nuclear proliferation in North Korea and Iran. But theres been tension over Chinas moves to secure disputed territory in the South China Sea, and accusations that recent large-scale hacking of U.S. government computers had a Chinese fingerprint.
Both nations are hurrying to lock in separate Pacific trade agreements that stand to give them a powerful foothold in commerce across Asia.
The investigation into the cyberattack on computers at the U.S. Office of Personnel Management is proceeding on the theory that the hack was directed by the Chinese government and aimed at uncovering sensitive, personal information that could have been used to blackmail or bribe government employees... ( Brian Bennett and Richard A. Serrano )
More than 400 Chinese officials are in Washington this week for talks aimed at making progress in a relationship regarded by almost everyone as vital. On the eve of the talks that began Tuesday, Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with the Los Angeles Times in Beijing as part of a delegation hosted by the New York-based Asia Society. The interview has been edited for length and clarity.
You have emphasized that China and the U.S. are not competitors, much less adversaries, but what about the allegations of computer hacking that the U.S. administration makes against China? Was China behind the hacking of the federal Office of Personnel Management computers?
The position of the Chinese government is very clear: The Chinese government opposes any hacking activities or the theft of commercial secrets. This is the set policy of the Chinese government, and we have very strict regulations.
8
I wonder if there is any foundation for the accusation. In this Internet age, it takes cooperation and mutual understanding to create healthy, stable, open and fair cyberspace in the world. We should not have irresponsible finger-pointing at each other.
As a matter of fact, China has suffered from hacking. Every day, China is subject to more than 300 large-scale hacking activities, and every month, more than 10,000 Chinese websites are changed by hackers, and 80% of the government websites are attacked. We have evidence to show that many of these hacking activities come from the U.S. We cannot say who inside the U.S., but these attacks come from U.S. soil.
So we think that China and the United States should have equal-footed and candid dialogue on this. The United States is a mature, major cyberpower, while China is also emerging fast as a major cybercountry. We hope that cyberspace will become an area of further cooperation between our two countries, instead of a source of friction.
What do you say to those voices in the U.S. who are saying that 40 years of efforts to engage China have not produced results, and it may be time to consider that confrontation makes more sense than engagement?
I dont think this is representative of mainstream public opinion in the United States. This only comes from a handful of people. I think the United States will stick to the path that it thinks is right, and also the path that enjoys the support and endorsement of the American people.
If the engagement policy of the United States is designed to turn China into another United States  I think that is impossible. Because our two countries have very different history, cultural backgrounds, and we are also at very different levels of development. But if this policy is designed for mutually beneficial and win-win outcomes, then we can choose to cooperate with each other; we can respect the differences and we can look for areas where our interests converge.
cComments
It might be the "stated" policy of the Chinese government to oppose hacking but who's to say their own equivalent to our NSA isn't doing so autonomously?(actually, this could very well be the case that the left hand doesn't know what the right hand is doing because...
Resident  Boomer
1
In the past 10 years, what do you think is the biggest mistake the U.S. has made in its relationship with China? And vice versa, what is the biggest single error your government has made in its relationship with the U.S.?
Im afraid you have too pessimistic a perception in raising this question. Instead of thinking of the mistakes and errors, why not think of the achievements?
An important agreement that we reached between our two countries in recent years is to work together to build a new model of a major-country relationship.
Some argue that it will mean a world of G2 [in which China and the U.S. jointly tackle the worlds problems], but China does not subscribe to this view  in the first place, because we do not believe that world affairs can be decided by one or two countries.
The second inaccurate contention we hear is that China is seeking parity with the United States. This is not true. Because the United States is the biggest developed country, and China is the biggest developing country. We still have a very big gap between us.
Our goal is that by the centenary of the founding of the People's Republic, that is, by 2049, China will become a medium-income developed country; and even by then, there will be a big gap between China and the United States.
Others argue that China is trying to keep a low profile in order to avoid conflicts with the United States, so that one day it can replace the status of the United States. This is totally groundless.
The original purpose of having this new model of major country relationship between us is really simple. That is to avoid a repeat of the historic pattern in which an emerging country is destined to have conflict with an established power.
To have this new model of a major country relationship, we need to have three things. The first element is nonconflict, nonconfrontation. Second, we need to have a win-win cooperation, and we need to reject the thinking that winner takes it all. And third, we need to have mutual respect. Some American friends may have misgivings about this mutual respect. They find it hard to accept, because they think it means the U.S. has to accept all demands from China. This is an inaccurate interpretation. Mutual respect means, in our view, not to impose ones will upon others.
China has drafted a law on regulating nongovernmental organizations. Some in the government warned that the spread of Western ideas could lead to instability. What are those ideas that you would prefer not be spread? And if the U.S. is behind this, whats its agenda?
China is an open society, and there are a large number of NGOs in China, but China is yet to have a dedicated law that can provide for rule-based regulation of NGOs. The development of this draft law is part of our effort to rule the country according to law, and also part of our effort to align China with the international community. So we think we deserve understanding and support for this.
I think for those NGOs who are dedicated to promoting exchanges and cooperation with the Chinese people in accordance with Chinese laws, this draft law will not bring about any obstacles to their activities, but rather it will only facilitate their work and give them better support and guarantees.
But indeed all countries have their different national conditions, so foreign NGOs need to respect the national conditions of those countries and also respect their local laws and regulations.
For instance, the constitution provides that China is a socialist country with the Communist Party of China as the ruling party. So if anyone wants to challenge this, if anyone calls on others to oust the Communist Party of China, then he has broken the law. Because this is so written in the Chinese Constitution.
8
As far as I know, many foreign NGOs have worked very hard to benefit peoples livelihood in China, and also work to promote social harmony, so we have a high degree of recognition of these things.
China has recently announced that it has halted some controversial construction work on one of several disputed islands in the South China Sea that have been the object of friction involving China, its neighbors and even the United States. Is this work stoppage a response to international criticism?
Yes, the ministry has just released this news because the relevant construction project is nearing completion. We have anticipated comments from the media saying that China had to stop the construction because of pressure from the U.S. Well, this is totally not true. But we cannot simply go on with construction work forever, simply because we are afraid of such comments from the media. At some point we have to stop because the construction plan is completed.
cComments
It might be the "stated" policy of the Chinese government to oppose hacking but who's to say their own equivalent to our NSA isn't doing so autonomously?(actually, this could very well be the case that the left hand doesn't know what the right hand is doing because...
Resident  Boomer
1
Incidentally, I want to tell you that construction on the islands and reefs in the South China Sea did not start yesterday, and it was not started first by China. We need to be very clear about this. Vietnam and the Philippines started large-scale construction work 20 or 30 years ago on islands they had illegally occupied. And China has all along exercised great restraint.
I think there is one basic fact that the international community has to learn, and that is that the islands and reefs of the Spratly Islands we are talking about are Chinese territory. I think the U.S. knows better than anyone else about this. Because at the end of the Second World War, China retook the sovereignty over these Spratly Islands from the Japanese troops which occupied these islands, and it was a joint operation between China and the United States. The Chinese retook the sovereignty with the support of U.S. military vessels.
Even into the late 1960s, there were never any objections from Vietnam and the Philippines about Chinas sovereignty over these islands.
But as you know that after that, there was a 10-year Cultural Revolution in China, a period of great turbulence here, so China was kept too busy here to look after those islands and reefs, and it gave other countries some opportunities. Another element was at play, in that there was some wild speculation about rich oil and gas reserves in that part of the world, so the neighboring countries started to occupy those islands and reefs one by one, and that is the source of the current status quo, the claims led by five countries or six parties. China has sovereignty over these islands and reefs, and our sovereignty has been seriously infringed upon. This is the basic reality.
But despite all this, China is still for a peaceful settlement to the disputes, through dialogue and consultation. We will remain committed to this, and there will not be any change to this position.
You mentioned that the world cant be ruled by a G2, but do you worry that Chinas actions in the South China Sea create a binary equation in the rest of the region  that youre either with China, or youre with the United States? It has been suggested that one of the reasons 20 countries in the region wanted to join the Trans-Pacific Partnership proposed by President Obama was that they wanted to be with America.
I dont think we should run the risk of oversimplifying this by interpreting the situation like this. As I mentioned earlier, China and the United States are having cooperation at various levels and in various fields. So if China and the United States are cooperating, then there is no question of asking those regional countries to take sides with one or the other.
President Xi said the Pacific Ocean is vast enough for both China and the United States. China is not only a major land country, but also a major maritime country, because we have a long coastline.
And as the Chinese economy continues to grow, and as China has closer economic interactions with other countries, it is only natural that China has closer links with the sea. So under this context, it is time for China and the United States to sit down and explore maritime cooperation.
Now, between China and the United States we have this military-to-military engagement. We are talking about a code of conduct for sea or air encounter. This is mainly a preventive act, but I think what is more important is that we sit down and explore cooperation.
As for TPP, I see it as an economic and trade treaty. We dont want to overpoliticize it. Rather, we hope that the TPP will not affect the free trade regime under the World Trade Organization mechanism. Now some American friends may think that now that there is a TPP, the U.S. can do without [the World Trade Organization]. So I think more thinking is needed on whether this kind of thinking is good for the U.S. or not.
On North Korea: A lot of people are puzzled as to why China, which is clearly the senior partner in that relationship, is unable to exert more control over the regime in North Korea.
Both China and the DPRK [Democratic People's Republic of Korea] are independent countries. So the relationship between us is a state-to-state relationship, not a relationship between a senior and a junior. Of course in dealing with the DPRK, China has to follow the norms of international relations, including noninterference in internal affairs. Of course, as the DPRKs neighbor, we want to see a DPRK that enjoys social stability, economic growth and better lives for their people.
We have been telling this to the DPRK that their pursuit of nuclear weapons will not bring safety or security, but rather it will bring a danger, and it does a disservice not only to the DPRK itself, but also to its neighbors and the entire region.
But what the DPRK has been telling us is that it is facing a real and immediate military threat from the U.S. So the DPRK has attributed the purpose of its nuclear program to one thing, and that is to counter the immediate military threat from the U.S.
I think you can perfectly understand this. China cannot settle or resolve this. So we hope that the U.S. and the DPRK can have face-to-face talks. We can provide whatever facilitation you need. If this problem is solved, and if you have normalization of the bilateral relationship, then China is more than ready to provide guarantee for the security and peace in the peninsula and also the region, because we count this as our obligation and our responsibility.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iranian leader's motives unclear as nuclear talks resume</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-iran-nuclear-2-20150628-story.html</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description>
	  It is 5 p.m., and the church bells in the center of the city begin to toll. Hundreds of commuters stream across the Praca da Se square, passing in front of the headquarters of the largest archdiocese in the nation with the most Catholics in the world.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Evangelicals take their fight with Satan to the streets of Sao Paulo
Brazilian street preacher
Vincent Bevins / For The Times
A street preacher spreads the word in Brazil in May.The evangelicals are foot soldiers on the front lines of a religious battle that their side seems to be winning.
A street preacher spreads the word in Brazil in May.The evangelicals are foot soldiers on the front lines of a religious battle that their side seems to be winning.
(Vincent Bevins / For The Times)
By Vincent Bevins
Pope Francis
It is 5 p.m., and the church bells in the center of the city begin to toll. Hundreds of commuters stream across the Praca da Se square, passing in front of the headquarters of the largest archdiocese in the nation with the most Catholics in the world.
But over the pealing sounds of the cathedral, many commuters are hearing a very different religious message.
"The world is dominated by sin! Only the Gospel can save you! Only evangelism can save you!" shouts a middle-aged man, gesticulating wildly and increasing volume as he utters each sentence. A rapt crowd of 30 or 40, mostly men, listens as the street preacher seeks to draw in additional passersby, warning them of danger to their souls.
I was born and raised Catholic like everyone else. But it's full of false doctrine and tradition which has nothing to do with the word. - Josemar Bento Mendes, Brazilian street preacher
"Satan is hidden everywhere! If you're with a religion, you're wrong! If you're Catholic, you're wrong! Put your hands together for Jesus!" The crowd obliges.
Nearby, homeless youths huddle together, passing a crack pipe back and forth. A young woman, apparently mentally ill, sits among the worshipers, playing with leaves and sticks on the ground.
Street preachers maintain a daily presence here and elsewhere around Brazil, calling upon believers to accept Jesus directly, rejecting the need for the Roman Catholic Church to serve as mediator.
Whereas some leaders behind Brazil's large evangelical churches have become famously wealthy and powerful, these men sweat on the street among Sao Paulo's downtrodden. They're foot soldiers on the front lines of a religious battle that their side seems to be winning.
8
When Josemar Bento Mendes was born, 50 years ago, more than 90% of Brazilians declared themselves Catholic. But by 2013, at the time that Pope Francis, the first pontiff from the Americas, visited, just 57% of Brazilians claimed allegiance to Rome. About 28% declared a commitment to some kind of evangelical Christian faith.
"I was born and raised Catholic like everyone else. But it's full of false doctrine and tradition which has nothing to do with the word," says Bento Mendes, who is preaching in the harsh cold of a wintry June day. "I come here because everyone in the city comes through the plaza. It's ground zero. It's a river with many fish, and many people suffering."
Mendes and others preach that the Bible is God's authoritative word, which should be spread evangelically, and that the Catholic Church is not necessary to interpret it.
Most of the fish in the river move along quickly, heading into the crowded metro station. But those loitering in the square tend to respect the seriousness of the gathering. After one young man, visibly high, spends a few minutes giggling, his perceived insolence is quickly singled out.
A tough-looking man in a hoodie and gold chains threatens him, instructing, "Respect the word of God!" The youth is soon clapping and praying along with the rest.
Preachers change off every hour or so and switch up styles. But they all rely on their intensity and passion, which could not contrast more sharply with the inside of the Catholic cathedral.
There, a priest's sermon is scarcely audible over the PA as he calmly explains the meaning of the church calendar. The audience for his Mass is barely larger than the circle formed around the preachers outside. Their slight presence in the pews is dwarfed by the ornate and grand structure built to hold thousands.
The world is full of crazy. Move along, nothing to see here...
Thinkandverify91
2
The format of the lessons outside is also looser, with the preachers reading select passages from the Bible, then expounding on their meaning. They may seem to be closer to adhering to Jesus' message of embracing the poor and sick, but these teachings  and indeed the Gospels themselves  are almost never the main point. Over the course of days and various preachers, a few dominant themes emerge: the imminent apocalypse, the influence of Satan and the evils of homosexuality.
"There are men sleeping with other men! We should see shame in your faces! You are worse than a dog or a pig. I have never seen a pig lie down with another pig," says one. Some in the crowd just listen intently, while others cry out spontaneously, or raise their eyes to the sky and tremble.
The preacher now turns his wrath on Edir Macedo, the media mogul billionaire leader of the evangelical Universal Church of the Kingdom of God, for airing sexually charged shows on his Record TV network. Bento Mendes and preacher Waldo Silvio Santos belong to the competing Assembly of God congregation. "Woe to you who pays his tithes to men who put naked women on TV to make millions. False prophets love money."
The evangelical movement has been criticized for profiting off Brazil's most destitute and sometimes offering a version of Christianity that they consider fundamentalist and reactionary, rejecting much of modern society. Within the complicated rules of Brazil's brutal class system, however, many middle-class liberals have also felt uncomfortable criticizing any movement that is largely working class.
But in the last few months, evangelical figures have risen to top positions of political power, causing liberals to panic. Eduardo Cunha, an evangelical who serves as president of the lower house of Congress, is considered a dangerous, cynical schemer by progressives, and he has said he will bar any vote on liberalizing abortion, which is illegal here.
After evangelical congressmen staged a protest against Sao Paulo's recent Gay Pride Parade, the major Folha de S.Paulo newspaper printed a scathing indictment: "A growing spirit of fundamentalism is manifesting itself ... and Congress seems committed to reflect this trend, intensify it, and use it to demagogic ends."
But the halls of the capitol in Brasilia are very far away from Praca da Se. As a Catholic priest and a Franciscan friar walk slowly, Bento Mendes has no time for focus on matters of politics.
"It is a thousand times better to trust in God than to trust in princes," he booms. "And I tell you this: Christ's return is coming sooner than we imagine. If it doesn't, I'll stop preaching. I'll rip up my Bible, if terrible things don't rain down upon us soon."
Bevins is a special correspondent.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Airstrikes hit two markets in Yemen; more than 100 people killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-yemen-market-explosion-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  More than 100 people were killed in airstrikes that hit two markets in Yemen on Monday, according to witnesses and officials, as a Saudi Arabian-led coalition continued aerial attacks against Houthi rebels for a fourth month.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>The second strike happened about 11 p.m. at a market in the area of Joub, north of Sana, and killed more than 60 people, according to the Houthi-run Defense Ministry.
Khalid Mahlah of Sana wondered when the world would call for an end to the airstrikes.
It is a shame on all the international [community] that they have given in and remain silent, Mahlah said in an interview.
More than 3,000 people, half of them civilians, have been killed and 14,000 more wounded since airstrikes began March 25, according to the United Nations, as the conflict has deepened into an alarming humanitarian crisis in the Arab worlds poorest country.
More than 1 million Yemenis have fled their homes, and 13 million have poor access to food, according to the United Nations. The organization has called the conflict a humanitarian catastrophe and is seeking a cease-fire until at least the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan in mid-July.
The Shiite Muslim rebels took over Sana in September, and the stated goal of the Saudi-led coalitions airstrikes has been to restore to power exiled President Abdu Rabu Mansour Hadi.
Previous air bombardments have struck Houthi positions and weapons caches but also residential areas and historic sites. The coalition has not acknowledged the killing of civilians and has accused the Houthis of using civilians as human shields.
Airstrikes on Monday also hit other parts of Yemen, including an area of Aden where seven people were killed, officials said. One strike hit a Houthi political office in a heavily populated area of Sana, injuring several people.
Special correspondent al-Alayaa reported from Sana, and staff writer Pearce from Los Angeles.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece seeks a bailout proposal that Eurozone nations could stomach</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-resignation-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Greece raced to come up with bailout proposals palatable to its international lenders Monday before its banks run out of money and the country slides closer to a chaotic default and exit from the Eurozone.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece seeks a bailout proposal that Eurozone nations could stomach
Yanis Varoufakis
Angelos Christofilopoulos / Associated Press
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis speaks Sunday in Athens after the results of the bailout referendum.
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis speaks Sunday in Athens after the results of the bailout referendum.
(Angelos Christofilopoulos / Associated Press)
European Debt Crisis
Greece raced to come up with bailout proposals palatable to its international lenders Monday before its banks run out of money and the country slides closer to a chaotic default and exit from the Eurozone.
At the same time, officials in various European capitals huddled in their own emergency meetings to forge a common response amid signs of rifts between, and within, countries over how hard a line to take with Athens.
Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras is expected to offer new proposals for funding his cash-starved government to the leaders of the other 18 nations that use the euro currency during a summit Tuesday evening in Brussels. Convincing the Eurozone leaders that there is a basis for an agreement is key to Greeces short- and long-term economic survival.
Greek voters' resounding rejection of international creditors demands may have strengthened the hand of their prime minister, Alexis Tsipras, who rose to power promising to halt painful austerity measures imposed in the bailout. But what options are open to the Greek leader when he meets with... ( Don Lee )
If they agree that a deal is possible, then the European Central Bank is likely to maintain the special lifeline it has extended to Greeces ailing banks to keep them functioning.
But if differences between Athens and its lenders appear irreconcilable, the European Central Bank could conclude that Greeces banks are insolvent and cut its emergency aid, and Greek banks would collapse within days, if not hours. Trade would seize up, residents would lose access to their savings and Greeces ability to continue using the euro would fall into serious doubt.
Under major pressure to reach an understanding with his Eurozone counterparts, Tsipras secured support from nearly all of Greeces political parties for his new offer, a show of unity meant to demonstrate his sincerity in negotiating in good faith on behalf of all Greeks. Trust between Tsipras and his European partners is at rock bottom since the previous round of talks broke down and Greek voters, in a referendum Sunday, heeded his call to reject creditor bailout proposals that were heavy on austerity.
8
On Monday, the European Central Bank avoided inflicting immediate catastrophe on Greece.
But as happened last week, the European Central Bank declined to increase the amount of emergency funds available, meaning that the banks cash supplies are continuing to dwindle. The European bank also upped the value of assets that the banks must provide as collateral to keep receiving aid, putting the banks in an even more precarious position.
The European bank has pumped $98 billion into the Greek financial system in recent months to prevent it from running out of money as depositors scrambled to withdraw their euros while they still could, for moving into accounts abroad or hiding under their mattresses. Greece's banks are reportedly down to their last $555 million  or about $50 per person in this country of 11 million.
Athens announced Monday that its weeklong closure of the banks and its cap on the amount customers can withdraw each day  about $66  would be extended through Wednesday. Officials had previously pledged to reopen the banks Tuesday.
Long lines at ATMs under the hot Aegean sun have been a common sight since capital controls were imposed. But Greeks have mostly taken the situation in stride, and some seem unfazed by the possibility of even worse restrictions if Greeces financial predicament worsens.
There is no fear in our hearts. We dont worship at ATMs, said Katerina Bakaliani, a 35-year-old film director. If I dont have enough to eat, I will pick an apple from a tree.
In Paris, the Eurozones two most important leaders, French President Francois Hollande and German Chancellor Angela Merkel, met to discuss the Greek crisis and to try to damp speculation of a split in attitude toward Greece between Northern and Southern European countries.
@penguinista No. They areI saying the cost out weigh the benefits.
harry.meantwell
91
Officials from Germany, Finland and the Netherlands spoke harshly of Athens on Monday, saying that the referendum result had set back relations with the Eurozone and that any bailout deal would now be harder to negotiate, not easier.
A German Finance Ministry spokesman poured cold water on the idea of any discussion of relief of Greeces colossal public debt, something that Greek negotiators insist must be on the table. A report by the International Monetary Fund released last week said that Athens needed loans of $55 billion and massive debt relief to survive through 2018.
Other European officials have been more conciliatory, including the French finance minister, Michel Sapin, who said discussions of Greeces debt were not taboo. Spanish and Italian officials also urged a fair settlement with Greece as soon as possible and expressed their desire to see Athens remain a member of the Eurozone.
There were reports that Hollande had encouraged Tsipras to get the backing of other Greek political parties for his new bailout offer, which would make it easier for France to broker a deal.
Speaking to reporters with Merkel, the French leader said it was incumbent upon Europe to resolve the crisis over one of its own.
Within this Europe, there is room for solidarity, Hollande said.
The door for talks remains open. Time is of the essence, and we hope that this week we will get these proposals, said Merkel, who spoke with Tsipras by phone Monday.
It was unclear what concessions either Greece or its lenders would be willing to make to break their previous impasse and clinch a deal. In fact, with the referendum result backing him, Tsipras might feel emboldened to press for an even greater reduction of austerity measures, whereas some creditor countries might feel inclined to dig in their heels.
The last offer we made was quite a generous one, Merkel said.
Tsipras plan is likely to involve tapping a bailout fund known as the European Stability Mechanism, which was set up after the euro debt crisis erupted in 2009, first in Greece and then in nations such as Ireland and Portugal.
Although Tsipras came to power in January pledging to end austerity, further spending cuts will probably be unavoidable in any deal. That will require the Greek leader to persuade members of his own left-wing Syriza party to stay on his side.
He chaired a six-hour meeting with leaders of the other political parties Monday to thrash out proposals that would garner their support.
Despite rejecting more Europe-ordered austerity in Sundays referendum, in a 61% to 39% vote, the vast majority of Greeks want their country to remain in the Eurozone. Tsipras insists that it will do so, and officials have let slip no indication of contingency plans to introduce a parallel currency or reprint drachmas in the event of a bank system failure or a default by Athens on its debts. Such talk would undoubtedly spook the markets.
Merkel, too, must worry about politics at home.
Any new bailout deal for Greece would need the Bundestags approval. Her grip on power is tight in Germany, Greeces biggest lender, but many of her backbenchers have openly expressed anger with Athens over its perceived irresponsibility and unwillingness to play by the rules.
To improve his chances of getting a deal, Tsipras named a new finance minister Monday, Euclid Tsakalotos, after the surprise resignation of the colorful but controversial Yanis Varoufakis.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks philosophical about uncertain future after rejecting bailout deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-react-20150707-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  In the end, Greek voters preferred ambiguity about their future to the certainty of more economic hardships.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Greeks philosophical about uncertain future after rejecting bailout deal
Yanis Varoufakis
Petros Karadjias / Associated Press
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis is surrounded as he tries to leave on his motorcycle after resigning in Athens. Greece and its membership in the Eurozone face an uncertain future after voters rejected a bailout plan that would have led to drastic austerity measures.
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis is surrounded as he tries to leave on his motorcycle after resigning in Athens. Greece and its membership in the Eurozone face an uncertain future after voters rejected a bailout plan that would have led to drastic austerity measures. (Petros Karadjias / Associated Press)
European Union
In the end, Greek voters preferred ambiguity about their future to the certainty of more economic hardships.
"We don't know what's going to happen now: Maybe it will be worse for a while, but maybe it will get better eventually," said Alexandra Tsalafouta, who, along with her husband and infant son, was among the multitudes strolling Monday along the picturesque harbor-front promenade of this northern port city. "But if we had voted 'yes,' for sure things would have been worse."
A lot of people felt it was all propaganda. It had the opposite effect, making a lot of people vote "no." - George Giorgos, Internet cafe employee
It was a sentiment often heard a day after Greeks overwhelmingly rejected an international bailout plan that would have imposed drastic new austerity measures on a nation where residents are plainly fed up with what many view as cutbacks imposed by a shadowy economic elite. More than 60% voted "no" to the rescue package, a landslide by any measure.
"I don't know who's behind it all: the Germans, the Russians, the Americans  who knows?" asked one pensioner seated with other elderly Greeks on a bench in Aristotle Square, where a bronze bust of the philosopher ponders the tranquil scene. "Someone is doing this to us."
Still, she said she was in the minority that voted "yes" in Sunday's referendum.
"For stability," explained the woman, who gave only her first name, Eugenia, for privacy reasons.
"We are worried; Greece needs stability," she said, as her bench mates nodded in agreement. "The banks? What is going to happen to them?"
8
It was a theme  vote "yes" for stability  that was often heard from "yes" proponents, especially in the media. But the campaign may have backfired: Many seemed to view the intensive pro-"yes" effort as a scare tactic meant to convince Greeks that voting "no" could have catastrophic consequences, especially for pensioners.
Closed banks and long lines at ATMs in recent days fanned the fears. Yet Greeks ultimately didn't buy the doomsday scenario.
"A lot of people felt it was all propaganda," said George Giorgos, 19, an Internet cafe employee studying computer science in Thessaloniki, Greece's second-largest city and home to a large student population. "It had the opposite effect, making a lot of people vote 'no.'"
He, like others, stressed that Greeks were determined to remain part of the European Union, a bond that many view as historic, cultural and unbreakable. Many seemed confident that a deal more favorable to Greeks will emerge from talks between European leaders, keeping Greece from defaulting on its debt and exiting the Eurozone.
"Of course we will stay with Europe," said Michael Michalis, 18, a physics student.
cComments
Greece is like the dysfunctional cousin that the family must support to keep off skid row. EU faces another problem though. Once Greece gets away with draining EU money, there are a couple additional countries that are waiting to follow whatever escape mechanism Greece negotiates. That's...
Future View
18
People in the city talked about a collective fatigue with years of dwindling incomes, vanishing job opportunities and a loss of a sense of security. Many who cast "no" votes Sunday did so as a collective rebuff of forced pauperization, a national declaration that enough is enough. They lamented the pejorative image of Greeks as people who don't want to work.
"We all work hard and want something better for our children," said Tsalafouta, glancing at her 18-month-old son, Gabriel, in the arms of her husband, Evangelous Siomas, whose pest-control business has endured cutbacks. "Everyone is working longer hours and earning less."
On a practical level, many business owners feared that new austerity measures and higher taxes would have been the death knell for already struggling enterprises.
"A 'yes' vote would have killed tourism here," said a hotel owner on the island of Lesbos, a popular vacation spot for European visitors. "Tourism is the best thing Greece has going for it now. Why make it harder for us?"
Among "no" voters, there was a distinct sense that Greece had finally fought back against the banks and oligarchs  and especially against Germany, the economic colossus of the European Union.
"I'm not frightened of Germany's junta," said Anthi Papadopoulou, 73, a pensioner with four grandchildren who was among the jubilant "no" backers celebrating into the early hours of Monday in Athens' Syntagma Square, in front of the Parliament building. "Right now we have a junta without tanks. It is economic war."
Despite the prevalent uncertainty about what will happen next, she said she was not frightened, even if she were to lose her pension of nearly $555 per month.
"Many are not afraid  we will survive," Papadopoulou proclaimed. "We'll live on lentils if we need to.... They can take my pension.... My pride, they will never take."
Others were more somber than exultant as European officials frantically tried to negotiate a solution to the crisis.
"Of course I'm still afraid and biting my nails expecting what's going to happen over the next five days," said Giorgos Kavasakalis, 38, an architect who voted "yes" in the referendum.
"Time is not on our side right now," added Kavasakalis, who has been considering immigrating to the United States. " We really have to hurry. Greece doesn't have time. Something has to happen, and it has to happen real fast."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 03:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After the Greek referendum: What will Merkel do?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-merkel-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  German Chancellor Angela Merkel has long said she wants to see Greece remain in the Eurozone, but "not at any price." And the Sunday vote by Greeks to reject their creditors' formula for repayment of $270 billion in bailout loans sent that price skyrocketing in both political and economic terms.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>61
However, in light of the decision by the Greek citizens, the conditions to start negotiations on a new aid program are not met yet, Seibert said, adding that Berlin would wait and see what the Greek government makes of it.
Seibert said the German government was stressing the principle that solidarity is inseparable from [a country's] own efforts, implying that the attempt by Athens to get a significant write-down on its debts was not in the offing.
Those in the Eurozone who support holding Greece to its previous commitments exuded frustration and showed signs of losing patience after the referendum.
Now [German Chancellor Angela] Merkel and the others must organize a Grexit, with all the cushions and upheavals that will result as a consequence. - Alexander Graf Lambsdorff of Germany's Free Democratic Party
Though Merkel may be reluctant to see the integrity of the Eurozone breached, her conservative colleagues in the grand coalition that governs Germany are of the view that the Greek no vote may well be a prelude to the country's exit from the Eurozone  a Grexit, as it has become known.
The referendum was a clear signal that Athens refuses to be beholden to its creditors, said Markus Ferber, who oversees euro policy for the Christian Social Union, the Bavarian sister party to Merkel's Christian Democratic Union.
The country and the government have knocked away the helping hand of their Eurozone colleagues, Ferber said. The only chance for Greece now is to leave the euro.
The Economist Intelligence Unit, an independent forecasting and advisory service of the Economist Group, put the chances of a Greek exit from the Eurozone at 60%.
Opposition political forces in Germany also signaled readiness to interpret the referendum result as a rejection of what is required to stay in the Eurozone, even if many Greeks voted no because their leaders suggested it would compel the creditors to offer a substantial debt write-off and more lenient plan for repaying the rest.
Now Merkel and the others [of the European creditors] must organize a Grexit, with all the cushions and upheavals that will result as a consequence, said Alexander Graf Lambsdorff of the Free Democratic Party, one of the German politicians willing to take no for an answer even if that wasnt what many Greeks meant.
Special correspondent Hassan reported from Berlin and Los Angeles Times staff writer Williams from Los Angeles.
Follow @cjwilliamslat on Twitter for the latest international news 24/7.
Copyright  2015, Los Angeles Times
UPDATE
5:25 p.m.: This article has been updated with developments from German Chancellor Angela Merkel's meeting with French President Francois Hollande.
It was first published at 11:20 a.m.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis' Mass in Ecuador focuses on family, draws multitudes</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-francis-family-ecuador-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Hundreds of thousands of cheering people welcomed Pope Francis to Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday for the first Mass on the Argentine-born pontiff's landmark pilgrimage to Spanish-speaking Latin America.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis' Mass in Ecuador focuses on family, draws multitudes
Pope Francis in Ecuador
Vincenzo Pinto / AFP/Getty Images
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate an open-air Mass at Parque Samanes in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday.
Pope Francis arrives to celebrate an open-air Mass at Parque Samanes in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday.
(Vincenzo Pinto / AFP/Getty Images)
Pope Francis
Hundreds of thousands of cheering people welcomed Pope Francis to Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday for the first Mass on the Argentine-born pontiffs landmark pilgrimage to Spanish-speaking Latin America.
Enthusiastic crowds thronged Francis as he walked from the airplane that took him from the Ecuadorean capital, Quito, to the coastal city of Guayaquil. Many tried to shake his hand and took selfies with the widely admired pope. Still more lined the route that the popemobile took to the site of the Mass.
Pope Francis in Ecuador
People wait for the arrival of Pope Francis in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday.
People wait for the arrival of Pope Francis in Guayaquil, Ecuador, on Monday.
(Vincenzo Pinto / AFP/Getty Images)
Preliminary estimates of attendance at the Mass, in Guayaquils sprawling Parque Samanes, topped half a million. The pope dedicated the service to the traditional family, the promotion of which he believes can stave off many of societys ills, especially in impoverished Latin America.
The family, he said, speaking in his native Spanish, is the nearest hospital ... the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly.
The family constitutes the best social capital, he continued. It cannot be replaced by other institutions. It needs to be helped and strengthened, lest we lose our proper sense of the services that society as a whole provides.
8
Those services should not be regarded as charity but as part of the social debt owed the institution of family, he said to sustained applause.
Illness, unemployment and other difficult situations can rob families of their warmth and sense of solidarity, he warned.
As expected, the pope departed from his prepared text on several occasions. At one point, as he spoke of how all members of a family are to be valued, he paused to recall an anecdote involving his mother. He said she was asked once which of her five children she loved the most. She responded that the five were like the five fingers on her hand; hurting any one of them would hurt her equally.
The family constitutes the best 'social capital.' It cannot be replaced by other institutions. It needs to be helped and strengthened.... - Pope Francis
The pope is on an eight-day visit to his native continent, deliberately choosing three of its poorest and most marginalized countries to drive home his belief in preaching from the periphery, or among the most disadvantaged. After Ecuador, he will travel to Bolivia and then Paraguay. In addition to meeting with clergy and national officials he will made a point of spending time at so-called places of pain  including a childrens hospital and a notorious prison.
The is Francis second trip to South America since becoming pope. His first, in 2013, was limited to Portuguese-speaking Brazil for World Youth Day.
cComments
Long-haired preachers come out every night To tell you what's wrong and what's right But when asked about something to eat They will answer in voices so sweet You will eat bye and bye, In that glorious land above the sky. Work and pray, live on hay, You'll get pie in the sky when...
LouAZ
2
Earlier Monday and shortly after his arrival in Guayaquil, the pope stopped to pray at the Divine Mercy shrine, where he blessed sick faithful and then chatted with the staff members who care for them. In his typical joviality, he said to the staff: I will bless you, and I wont charge.
Leaders of the Roman Catholic Church credit Francis popularity with stanching an exodus from the faith and attracting people back to the fold. It is too soon, however, to bear that out with numbers.
The countries the pope is visiting are among the most Catholic in South America.
Francis was scheduled to meet later Monday with Ecuadors leftist president, Rafael Correa, who also greeted the pontiff on the tarmac at his arrival in Quito on Sunday.
People began gathering at the Quito cathedral Monday afternoon to hear the pope speak that night.
It is a blessing that the pope has come, a signal of joy, said Angel Tapia, a 44-year-old IT engineer. I think the pope came because he wanted to, not because the president invited him. But political tension will return once the pope is gone.
Though most of the popes public comments at the Mass in Guayaquil were heavily religious and Bible-based, many in Ecuador hope he will stake out a more political position.
The visit of the pope comes at a critical moment for the country, because the division between those who support the government and those who criticize it is at its highest point, said architect Diego Moreano, 35, among those on the streets attempting to get a glimpse of the pope. The pope can serve as a point of balance, of social stability and peace. Lets hope his message lowers tensions.
Fabiola Cruz, a 50-year-old homemaker, said she hoped the pope could revive the spirituality of the people of Ecuador. Unfortunately we live in a moment of little reflection in our country.
Special correspondent Jaramillo Viteri reported from Quito and Times staff writer Wilkinson from Mexico City.
Follow @TracyKWilkinson on Twitter for more news from Latin America

Copyright  2015, Los Angeles Times
UPDATE
4:45 p.m.: This article has been updated to include the gathering at Quito cathedral before the popes Monday night address.
It was first published at 12:12 p.m.
Related Content
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama says anti-Islamic State strategy unchanged even as airstrikes increase</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-obama-islamic-state-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  President Obama acknowledged Monday that the Islamic State terrorists have been "particularly effective" at recruiting volunteers to fight in Iraq and Syria but pledged to stay on track with his current strategy even though it "will not be quick" in bringing about the group's defeat.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>22
But senior administration officials said Monday that the president is committed to his current strategy and that he was not going to the Pentagon to discuss possible changes in it.
There is no situationon the ground that has prompted this, White House Press Secretary Josh Earnest said Monday. The White House is mindful of the many risks in Iraq and Syria, Earnest said, adding that the fact is, our national security professionals are always vigilant.
As Obama prepared to visit the Pentagon on Monday, the White House complained publicly that Senate Republicans are dragging their feet in confirming his nominee to target terrorist funding in a sanctions drive at the Treasury Department.
In his daily briefing, Earnest called for the quick confirmation of of his pick, Adam Szubin, so that he begin efforts to cut off funding for Islamic State and its allies.
Obama described Szubins post as a vital position to our counter-terrorism efforts, adding that, if Congress wants to help, lawmakers will confirm him immediately.
As he spoke, Obama was joined onstage by commanders involved in the ISIL discussion, including Defense Secretary Ashton Carter, Joint Chiefs Chairman Gen. Martin Dempsey and Gen. Lloyd J. Austin III, head of U.S. Central Command, which oversees military operations in the Middle East.
The air war and the train-and-assist missions have been effective, Obama said.
We have taken out thousands of fighting positions, tanks, vehicles, bomb factories and training camps. We've eliminated thousands of fighters, including senior ISIL commanders, Obama said. And over the past year we've seen that, when we have an effective partner on the ground, ISIL can be pushed back, he added, ticking off Islamic State defeats across Iraq.
Obama, who was flanked by decorated generals, said it would take more than just military might to win the fight against Islamic State.
There's a cause, a coalition that's united countries across the globe, some 60 nations including Arab partners, Obama said. Our comprehensive strategy against ISIL is harnessing all elements of American power across our government -- military, intelligence, diplomatic, economic development and, perhaps most importantly, the power of our values.
For more White House coverage, follow @cparsons
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What are Greece's options now?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-options-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Greek voters' resounding rejection of international creditors' demands may have strengthened the hand of their prime minister, Alexis Tsipras, who rose to power promising to halt painful austerity measures imposed in the bailout. But what options are open to the Greek leader when he meets with...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>What are Greece's options now?
Greece Bailout
People line up to use ATM machines in Athens on Monday.
People line up to use ATM machines in Athens on Monday.
(Thanassis Stavrakis / Associated Press)
European Central Bank
Greek voters' resounding rejection of international creditors demands may have strengthened the hand of their prime minister, Alexis Tsipras, who rose to power promising to halt painful austerity measures imposed in the bailout. But what options are open to the Greek leader when he meets with European leaders at an emergency summit Tuesday?
Greek Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos handover ceremony
Alexandros Vlachos / European Pressphoto Agency
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis, left, hugs his successor, Euclides Tsakalotos, during the handover ceremony in the Ministry of Finance in Athens on Monday.
Outgoing Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis, left, hugs his successor, Euclides Tsakalotos, during the handover ceremony in the Ministry of Finance in Athens on Monday.
(Alexandros Vlachos / European Pressphoto Agency)
Despite the threat of Greece being forced to abandon the euro currency, Tsipras has said he considers that question to be off the table. And the abrupt departure of his confrontational finance minister, Yanis Varoufakis, a lightning rod in talks with European counterparts, suggests that Athens will tone down its rhetoric, if not demands, and may look for a compromise.
Analysts say European countries still have good reason to prevent an outright Greek collapse and departure from the euro area, even as the odds of a so-called Grexit, or Greek exit, rose sharply after Sundays vote.
cComments
Greece's problem is that there is no European legislature to tax Germsny and send the money to Greece. Where would Kentucky be without McConnell and all the Federal dollars sent there? No legislator in his right mind would advocate the Greek solution for the states of the United States-...
the_PB
11
Tomorrow night is going to be very critical to the medium and long-term future for Greece, says Jacob Funk Kirkegaard, a senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics. Tsipras needs to use his victory in a smart and deliberate manner  and not overreach.
 If Tsipras walks into Tuesdays summit insisting on debt relief but no pension cuts, tax increases or other reforms, it could be a short meeting. The international bailout for Greece was conditioned on Athens making structural reforms to get its finances in order, and Eurozone leaders arent willing to give Greece a pass on what many in Europe consider years of Athens profligate ways. Eurozone leaders see it as a dangerous precedent that could encourage other insurgent members to follow suit.
 Failure to present a credible bailout proposal, or something that offers hope of a deal, is likely to push the European Central Bank to reconsider whether to keep giving Greek banks emergency funds to stay afloat. Meeting Monday, the ECB board decided to leave the level of its support to Greek banks unchanged, waiting for clearer political signals from European leaders. But the ECB will certainly cut off Greeces life support if Athens misses a $3.46-billion bond payment due to the ECB on July 20.
 If Tsipras offers a proposal acceptable to Germany and other European leaders, Greece could work out a deal that will give it additional debt relief. With Greeces economy in tatters and the human suffering having reached epidemic proportions  unemployment has topped 25% and more than 50% for youth  France and Italy are among those who appear willing to give Athens at least more time to meet fiscal targets.
 Either way, Greek banks, which were closed last week except for limited withdrawals, arent likely to reopen this week. It may be months before they resume normal operations. But a compromise would help stabilize conditions fairly quickly as the ECB opens the emergency spigot and more calm returns to Greek financial markets.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New sticking point in nuclear talks: Iran wants arms embargo lifted</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-sticking-point-nuclear-talks-iran-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Iran's desire for a quick lifting of United Nations restrictions on its trade in missiles and other conventional arms has emerged as another potential sticking point in its nuclear negotiations with the United States and five other world powers.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>13
The Iranian official said the negotiators are still weighing the key issue of how they will set up a procedure providing for a snapback of sanctions on Iran if it is found to be breaking rules of the agreement. The official said Iran wants to find a way to restore its leverage over the world powers if they are found to be violating the deal.
Negotiators from the seven countries say they are closer to concluding a landmark deal than they have ever been. But issues remain, including how sanctions will be lifted, how closely U.N. inspectors willbe able to monitor Irans nuclear program, and what restrictions will remain on Irans nuclear research and development after the deals first 10 years. Also to be resolved is the U.N.s incomplete investigation into Irans suspected past research into nuclear weapons.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif and U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry have both warned in public comments since last weekend that the other sides intransigence was threatening completion of the deal.
Foreign ministers of all six countries were convening in Vienna on Monday and Tuesday in hopes of making tough policy decisions that their subordinates passed along to them. But some officials are saying that the deal making may not be completed by the latest deadline of midnight Tuesday and could spill over into Wednesday or Thursday.
The Obama administration is trying to complete the deal so that it can send its text, along withsupportingdocuments, to lawmakers by Thursday to meet a congressional deadline. If that deadline isnt met, Congress will extend the period it is taking to review the deal from 30 to 60 days, possibly opening the agreement to new risks.
A former Obama administration official, Ilan Goldenberg, said missing the Thursday congressional deadline might complicate things somewhat, but wont threaten the underlying agreement.
The conservative Fars news agency in Iran quoted Iranian officials saying that the bargaining could continue into Thursday.
Follow @RichtPau for more coverage of international affairs.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Critics of Iran nuclear talks see room for a tougher bargain</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-iran-bargain-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The Obama administration began its nuclear negotiations with Iran by insisting that Tehran halt production of all nuclear fuel, dismantle its nuclear infrastructure and roll back its missile program. In two years of bargaining, each of those demands has been dropped.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Critics of Iran nuclear talks see room for a tougher bargain
Iran nuclear talks
Carlos Barria / AFP / Getty Images
U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry, rear right, leaves his hotel for a meeting with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif in Vienna.
U.S. Secretary of State John F. Kerry, rear right, leaves his hotel for a meeting with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif in Vienna.
(Carlos Barria / AFP / Getty Images)
Iranian Nuclear Program
The Obama administration began its nuclear negotiations with Iran by insisting that Tehran halt production of all nuclear fuel, dismantle its nuclear infrastructure and roll back its missile program. In two years of bargaining, each of those demands has been dropped.
As the administration and its five major-power negotiating partners close in on a comprehensive nuclear deal with Iran  indications are that one could be announced as early as Tuesday, although some issues remain unresolved  they will have to answer a tough question: Did they drive a hard enough bargain?
President Obama and his top advisors contend the deal will achieve several major U.S. goals. Most important, they say, it will prevent Iran from getting a nuclear bomb for 10 to 15 years, and maybe longer  a big victory considering that Tehran has been on the threshold of being able to build a nuclear weapon.
The head of the United Nations nuclear watchdog agency said Saturday he hopes to complete his controversial investigation of Irans past nuclear activities by December, potentially removing a key obstacle to completion of world powers sweeping nuclear deal with the Islamic Republic. ( Paul Richter )
But critics, including some of Obama's former advisors, argue that the group could have gotten a tougher, longer-lasting deal, considering that they began negotiations two years ago, after they had put in place a powerful set of sanctions to squeeze the economically fragile, militarily weak, medium-sized country.
Secretary of State John F. Kerry and his team are "letting this deal erode away as they try to close it," Sen. Bob Corker (R-Tenn.), chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and sometimes an administration ally on Iran, said last month.
Administration officials counter that critics' demands for a better deal are unrealistic, given the advances that Iran has made over the last 20 years, its ideological commitment to resisting U.S. pressure, and its status as a sovereign state that has rights under international treaties.
8
The kind of deal critics are demanding is a "unicorn agreement," one that doesn't exist in the real world, Colin Kahl, national security advisor to Vice President Joe Biden, said recently.
On Sunday, as foreign ministers prepared to arrive in the Austrian capital for what seems likely to be the final days of talks, Kerry insisted that the administration was holding firm on its current demands.
U.S. negotiators would not "shave at the margins to get an agreement," Kerry said. Iran needs to compromise, he said in comments outside the hotel where the talks are underway, because "we are not yet where we need to be on several of the most difficult issues."
Negotiations could still "go either way despite recent progress," Kerry said, adding that President Obama is "prepared to walk" away from the talks if Iran does not agree to acceptable terms.
The debate about whether the final terms were acceptable will intensify in the days ahead if a final deal is reached, as the Obama administration mobilizes to win support. Both the administration and its critics see public opinion as key. Congress could vote to disapprove a deal, but Obama would veto any such resolution. The real test for an agreement, both sides believe, is whether it wins enough public acceptance to survive under the next president.
In one hint of the challenge, five former members of the administration's Iran team said in a letter last month that they wished the deal could have been stronger. The five didn't say they would oppose the emerging deal, but would not commit to supporting it until they see its final terms.
The United States and five other world powers  France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China  are seeking a deal with Tehran that would ease sanctions in exchange for Iran's acceptance of restrictions intended to prevent it from obtaining a nuclear bomb.
cComments
@Change Iran Now ++ "Iran has a deep and rich history of cheating and refusing to answer inspectors questions." Actually, you're describing Israel whose nuclear program has never been inspected by anyone. And, our Intelligence organizations have always stated that Iran does...
Brud01
32
The debate has at times taken a personal tone: Critics argue that the Obama administration is too eager for an agreement that could give the president a legacy-burnishing foreign-policy victory and possibly cap Kerry's career with a Nobel Peace Prize.
Opponents of the deal say it will give Iran a huge economic boost as sanctions are eased and its government reclaims up to $150 billion frozen in overseas accounts. A deal will restore Iran's ties to the world economy and give the former pariah state a new legitimacy, even as its military and proxy forces have been gaining influence in Yemen, Iraq, Syria, Lebanon and elsewhere in the region, the critics note.
Defenders of the negotiations say that Iran has also given up several major demands. The Iranians at one point insisted on a deal that would last no more than seven years and that would allow them to greatly increase the amount of commercial-grade nuclear fuel they could produce. The Iranians also vowed that they would never send their existing stockpile of nuclear fuel out of the country, which they are now poised to do, and that they would not allow international inspectors access to their nuclear sites.
Moreover, the Obama administration's defenders note, both the George W. Bush and Clinton administrations also backed off a series of "red line" demands on Iran, as its nuclear program advanced, beginning in the 1990s.
The U.S. and allies jettisoned eight such "red lines" between 1995 and 2013, the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs at Harvard's Kennedy School pointed out in a paper. Those included demands that Iran never acquire even a civilian nuclear power facility; enrich uranium above a low grade; accumulate enough low-enriched uranium to fuel a single bomb; or build secret nuclear facilities.
A key disagreement involves the deal's provision for international inspections.
Critics of the Obama administration say that because of Iran's history of lying about secret nuclear facilities, the world powers should have the right to conduct "anytime, anywhere" inspections, a concession the George H.W. Bush administration won from Iraq after the 1991 Persian Gulf War.
But that agreement came only after a military surrender, said Jofi Joseph, a former nonproliferation official in the Obama White House.
"What is forgotten is that Iraq was militarily defeated in a humiliating rout and had little choice but to accept such terms," he said.
Iran would never agree to any deal without three elements of the pending agreement, Joseph said: recognition of Iran's right to produce some amount of nuclear fuel, a lifting of the sanctions, and a time limit on the deal, after which Iran would be treated like any other signatory to the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty.
The current deal "stacks up pretty well" compared with other recent nonproliferation agreements, said Mark Fitzpatrick, a former State Department official now with the International Institute for Strategic Studies in London.
The Clinton administration got North Korea to freeze its plutonium program, but without strict verification requirements, he noted. President George W. Bush gave up nuclear trade restrictions on India without gaining much in the way of nonproliferation safeguards, Fitzpatrick said.
Negotiation with Iran is a special challenge because it has a proud, ideological government and a leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who believes his country can get by without a deal, said Cliff Kupchan, an Iran specialist and chairman of the Eurasia Group risk-assessment consulting firm.
In general, it is tough to bend other countries, including allies, to the American will, Kupchan said.
This agreement can't be fully judged until the details are clear about access to Iran's military sites and until it is known how the United Nations' nuclear watchdog agency has resolved its long dispute with Iran over suspected past research into nuclear weapons, Kupchan said. The IAEA investigation is aimed at finding out how much Iran knows about nuclear weapons, to make it easier to monitor its future activities.
He predicted that the agreement "will be good, not great."
"Great agreements don't happen," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 12:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Snoop Dogg music video sparks legal battle with India religious group</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-snoop-dogg-video-raises-ire-of-india-s-parsis-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  A music video featuring the rapper Snoop Dogg and an Iranian pop singer has become the subject of a legal battle in India, where members of the Parsi community say it should be banned because it demeans their Zoroastrian religion.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Snoop Dogg music video sparks legal battle with India religious group
Snoop Dogg
Ethan Miller / Getty Images
Snoop Dogg is interviewed at the XM Satellite Radio booth at the International Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas on Jan. 5, 2006.
Snoop Dogg is interviewed at the XM Satellite Radio booth at the International Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas on Jan. 5, 2006.
(Ethan Miller / Getty Images)
Snoop Dogg
A music video featuring the rapper Snoop Dogg and an Iranian pop singer has become the subject of a legal battle in India, where members of the Parsi community say it should be banned because it demeans their Zoroastrian religion.
The 3 1/2-minute video for the song King , released on YouTube last month, shows Snoop Dogg smoking weed while sitting on a throne topped by a giant gold Faravahar, the winged disc that is among the most revered symbols of Zoroastrianism.
Squatting on a low wooden stool, Sayed Mehboob adjusts his red turban, gently faded from countless hours in the afternoon sun. On this patch of sidewalk near the busy Grant Road train station in central Mumbai, modern India flies by in its customary hurry. ( Shashank Bengali )
The rest of the video features Iranian-born Amitis Moghaddam -- dressed as an ancient Persian queen, lying beneath a Faravahar and being fanned by two negligibly clothed men -- interspersed with scenes of women pole-dancing.
A Parsi civic organization has filed suit against Snoop Dogg, Moghaddam, YouTube and other defendants in the eastern city of Kolkata, saying the video is insensitive towards the religious beliefs of one of the oldest monotheistic religions in the world.
The public-interest lawsuit is also rooted in a sense of deep unease among the Parsi community, one of Indias smallest religious minorities, whose numbers have been declining for decades.
Descendants of Persians who fled religious persecution in Iran more than 1,000 years ago, Parsis have long held outsize influence in Indian cities such as Mumbai, the financial capital, where they built hospitals, universities and the citys first port.
India has the worlds largest population of Parsis, but while they numbered 115,000 in the 1940s, by 2001, the most recent year for which official statistics are available, the community had shrunk to 69,000.
Parsis prohibit conversion to Zoroastrianism, and due to their economic success, many are waiting longer to marry and have children, reducing their fertility rates. The Indian government started a campaign to encourage Parsis to procreate, including ads in Parsi publications with half-joking messages such as: Be responsible. Dont use a condom tonight.
@StJoseph wrote, "I respect your choice to be Atheist." Too bad the Christianists don't.
Carrot Cake Man
7
Parsis for the first time have started to feel insecure as none care for their religious beliefs due to their dwindling numbers, Phiroze Edulji, attorney for the plaintiffs in the music video case, wrote in the lawsuit.
The plaintiff, Darayas Jamshed Bapooji, president of the Parsi Zoroastrian Assn. of Kolkata, said in an interview that he was seeking for the video to be pulled from YouTube. The lawsuit also names the Indian government and the music video hosting companies Vevo and Vydia as respondents.
We being such a small community, our heritage should not be looked down upon, Bapooji said in an interview. We are very proud people, we take pride in our religion and we cannot afford for anyone to do such things.
Zoroastrians trace their faith to the Bronze Age prophet Zoroaster and worship fire as a symbol of God. The Faravahar represents the eternal spirit of the human being and features three layers of feathers, two streamers for the duality of good and evil, and the left-facing head of a man, Zoroaster.
Moghaddam, who performs under her first name, Amitis, lives in the Atlanta area but sings most of her songs in Farsi. As a native Iranian, she should have known the video would be offensive, Bapooji said.
It was done on purpose, we feel, Bapooji said. She should be very much aware of what is what, even if Snoop Dogg wasnt.
The video has hardly been a YouTube smash. Since being released June 1, it had less than 82,000 views as of Monday morning. The video for California Roll, by Snoop Dogg with Stevie Wonder and Pharrell Williams, published May 20, has been seen more than 7.3 million times.
A hearing in the case is scheduled for July 17.
For more news from South Asia, follow @SBengali on Twitter
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 10:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nigeria bomb attacks kill 44 at mosque, restaurant</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-nigeria-bombing-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  An Nigerian emergency agency official said Monday that 44 people were killed by two bombs that exploded at a crowded mosque and an elite Muslim restaurant in the central city of Jos.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Nigeria bomb attacks kill 44 at mosque, restaurant
By Associated Press
8
Abdussalam Mohammed of the National Emergency Management Agency said 67 other people were wounded in the Sunday attack and were being treated in hospitals.
Witnesses who requested anonymity for fear of reprisals said the explosion at the Yantaya mosque came as a leading cleric who preaches peaceful coexistence was addressing a crowd during the holy month of Ramadan.
When the delta smelt goes extinct, You begin to go extinct. You are totally dependent on a healthy, balanced environment, Ricardoh
Webster Maximus
158
Another bomb exploded at Shagalinku, a restaurant patronized by elite politicians.
Jos is located where Nigeria's majority Muslim north and mainly Christian south collide. The city has been targeted in the past by bomb blasts that have killed hundreds of people. Boko Haram Islamic extremists have claimed responsibility for the attacks.
The explosion at the Yantaya mosque came as leading cleric Sani Yahaya of the Jama'atu Izalatul Bidia organization, which preaches peaceful coexistence of all religions, was addressing a crowd during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, according to survivors who spoke on condition of anonymity.
They said they did not know how many worshipers were killed.
Sunday's attacks are the latest in a string blamed on Boko Haram that have killed more than 200 people over the past week in the group's northeastern stronghold.
The extremists returned Sunday to northeastern villages attacked three days earlier, killing nine villagers and burning down 32 churches and about 300 homes, said Stephen Apagu, chairman of a vigilante self-defense group in Borno state's Askira-Uba local government area.
He said the vigilantes killed three militants.
Boko Haram took over a large swath of northeastern Nigeria last year and stepped up cross-border raids. A multinational army from Nigeria and its neighbors forced the militants out of towns, but bombings and village attacks increased in recent weeks, apparently in response to an Islamic State group order for more mayhem during Ramadan.
Boko Haram became the Islamic State group's West Africa franchise earlier this year.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 10:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In the Persian world of 'ta'arof,' they make offers that will be refused</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-me-c1-tarof-20150706-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The Battle of the $18 Ice Cream Bill had a certain "Game of Thrones" quality to it.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>10
In Iranian culture, it is customary to offer guests a glass of water or a cup of tea; many Western cultures do the same. But an Iranian guest who's ta'arofing would refuse the beverage at first pass. The host would insist and offer again. Finally, on the third round, the guest would accept the drink. Any other scenario would be considered rude.
Ta'arof is about more than just offering and refusing things, Beeman said. It is about raising others and "self-lowering" oneself. It is often filled with self-deprecation  something he calls "getting the lower hand."
No matter what twist and turns ta'arof might take, the goal is to be respectful, Beeman said.
To that end, it is similar to the Chinese etiquette of fighting over who pays. People tug at the bill, trying to free it from the grips of someone else at the table. They shout. Faces turn crimson. People pretend to walk to the restroom to secretly pay the bill. It's over-the-top, but it's also considered polite.
The practice is much stronger in Iran and among immigrants from that country than it is among their offspring born in America  though younger Iranian Americans are still expected to ta'arof to some degree.
And then there's the matter of explaining the practice to non-Iranian Americans.
Papen, the ice cream shop owner, does his best to bridge cultural divides that might arise. When a Persian woman comes into the store with her parents and non-Persian boyfriend, for example, he makes sure to give the man a brief education on ta'arof.
A guest is not supposed to pay for a meal, he explains to the boyfriends. It's also considered rude if someone pays for his elder, but it's also rude not to offer.
"I tell them, 'Look, you're going to have to figure this out on your own, but you can't pay,'" Papen explained.
The cultural disconnect has led to a few awkward dates for Shams, who was just a toddler when her family moved to the United States.
And if the dates went well, she had to lay down the rules for how to interact with her Iranian family. Even the right way to say hello came up.
"It's a big ta'arof thing to acknowledge each person in the house," Shams said. "I think in a lot of American households you can get away with not saying hi to every person."
She added: "It's also important to be really thankful for food that you get and try to kind of figure out when people are offering something for real or not really."
The culture shock worked both ways, Shams said. She often found herself ta'arofing with Americans who had no idea that she was just trying to be respectful. Sometimes, it backfired.
"I would go to someone's house and they would ask, 'Would you like a glass of water?' And I would say no, no," she recalled. "But then everyone else had water and I was like, 'Well, now what do I do?'"
::
Masud Valipour, owner of Ketabsara bookstore in Westwood, said ta'arof can be strategic or genuine depending on who is offering.
"The heart of ta'arof is good," he said. "Sometimes people take advantage of it. It's just like anything else."
Down the street from his shop, two women sipped tea in a small cafe and caught up on the latest gossip. A round of ta'arof erupted when a waitress brought a slice of cake to their table.
"Here, please have some," one woman said in Farsi.
Americans get in trouble ... because they offer tea and the Iranian says no. Then the American says 'OK,' and they end up without tea when they wanted it. - William Beeman, author of "Language, Status, and Power in Iran"
"No, I already had one, I couldn't possibly," her friend replied.
At first blush, it seems like a universally feminine move. But in Iranian culture, it transcends gender  both men and women refuse food, not because of its effect on their waistlines but because accepting it on the first offer would be rude.
The back-and-forth continued for minutes, until one finally took a bite. Seconds later, the woman who said she was full stuck in her fork.
In less than five minutes, the pastry had vanished.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 05:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In landslide 61% to 39% vote, Greece says 'no' to bailout deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-referendum-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The resounding rejection of an international bailout deal by voters in Greece raised fears Sunday of the collapse of the country's banking system, a catastrophic government default, an eventual exit from the euro and potential social unrest.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>In landslide 61% to 39% vote, Greece says 'no' to bailout deal
Referendum in Greece
Kay Nietfeld / European Pressphoto Agency
Police stand guard at the Greek Parliament in Athens.
Police stand guard at the Greek Parliament in Athens.
(Kay Nietfeld / European Pressphoto Agency)
Angela Merkel
The resounding rejection of an international bailout deal by voters in Greece raised fears Sunday of the collapse of the countrys banking system, a catastrophic government default, an eventual exit from the euro and potential social unrest.
In a surprising 61% to 39% result, Greeks said no in a referendum on a rescue package that would have kept their debt-ridden country afloat but subjected it to additional austerity measures.
The landslide delivered a sharp rebuke to European Union leaders who had warned that the plebiscite was, in effect, a vote on whether Greece wanted to remain a member of the Eurozone, the group of 19 nations that share the euro currency.
The EU is now confronted with one of the gravest challenges to its mission of ever closer union between member states.
Greece's financial woes are mounting, and the country's current bailout program for repaying $270 billion in debt to major creditors is set to expire Tuesday. Greece and the Eurozone lenders cannot agree on the new bailout terms. The situation is so dire that the country's cash-strapped banks have... ( Kyle Kim )
Jubilant crowds of no voters thronged Athens main square into the early hours of Monday to celebrate what they said was a chance for Greece to reassert itself and achieve a better deal from creditors. Motorists honked their horns, and triumphant chants of Oxi! Oxi! Oxi!  No! No! No! in Greek  rose in the balmy Mediterranean air.
But there were already signs of a backlash from angry European officials that could make any new bailout agreement even more difficult. If a deal is not struck quickly, Athens could find itself broke, forcing it to default on its debts and triggering a slide out of the Eurozone.
The left-wing government of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, which campaigned for a no victory, had demolished the last bridge on which Europe and Greece could approach a compromise, Sigmar Gabriel, the German economy minister, told the Tagesspiegel newspaper.
Jeroen Dijsselbloem, the leader of the Eurozones finance ministers, described the poll result as very regrettable for the future of Greece. For recovery of the Greek economy, difficult measures and reforms are inevitable.
An emergency summit of Eurozone leaders is to be held Tuesday.
More urgently, officials at the European Central Bank are to meet Monday to review the emergency aid that has propped up Greeces nearly depleted financial system for the last few months.
If the European Central Bank decides to cut off that lifeline or make it costlier, Greek banks are likely to run out of cash within days. Business would grind to a halt, shops could run short of basic supplies and increasingly agitated residents could find it hard to buy fuel and medicine.
Greek banks have been closed since June 29 on order of the government, and customers limited to about $67 a day in ATM withdrawals. Officials insist that the banks will reopen Tuesday, but analysts doubt this can happen unless the European Central Bank maintains or increases its assistance.
Our immediate priority is the rapid restoration of the functioning of our banking system and the restoration of our economic stability, Tsipras said in a nationally televised address Sunday night. I am certain that the ECB fully understands not only the general economic situation but also the humanitarian dimension which the crisis has taken in the country.
Tsipras also said the referendum result had given him a mandate to press international lenders  mostly other Eurozone countries  for a sustainable bailout package for the Greek government that would address its staggering debt load and free the country from the vicious cycle of austerity.
Greece is the now shame of Europe and a rogue state. They are no longer the valiant Achaean warriors like those depicted by Homer; instead, the Greeks at present day are shameless cowards who try to renege on their loans.
JasonPan
311
The Greek economy has contracted by a breathtaking 25% since Athens began accepting emergency loans in exchange for brutal spending cuts in 2010. Tsipras radical-left Syriza party swept to power in January on an aggressive anti-austerity platform, setting up the current standoff with Greeces creditors.
He said Athens was prepared to return to the negotiating table immediately. But with relations at an all-time low, it was unclear whether any of Greeces European partners would show up and, even if so, whether an agreement could be hashed out before the Greek government runs out of money.
A major debt to the European Central Bank falls due July 20. If Athens fails to pay  as it already did with a loan from the International Monetary Fund last week  and bank coffers are empty, Greece could be forced to introduce a parallel currency and eventually quit the Eurozone.
Financial analysts say that this is not a threat in the next few days, but warn that the probability of a Grexit down the line has increased considerably because of Sundays vote.
Before the ballots were cast, a parade of European leaders, including German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande, said they would interpret a win for the no side as an expression of Greeces desire to quit using the euro.
But Tsipras insisted that the vote did not answer the question in or out of the euro. That question must be removed definitively from the discussion.
Polls consistently show that an overwhelming majority of Greeks want their country to remain in the Eurozone and, by extension, the 28-nation European Union.
Merkel and other European leaders must now ponder whether to let Greece go bust and drop out of the Eurozone or whether such a course would inflict irreparable damage to the credibility of the euro and to the project of greater European unity. The Greek debt crisis is the severest test the euro has faced since it was introduced more than a decade ago.
To try to entice his Eurozone partners back to the bargaining table, Tsipras is apparently considering shuffling his negotiating team to include a broader spectrum of members. Several European officials have said openly that they no longer trust Tsipras or his Syriza party; a Greek delegation with some members drawn from other parties could be more palatable.
That will show that Greece does not want a conflict, said political commentator George Papageorgiou. If there is a consensual approach from the Greek part, that could facilitate a consensual approach from the other part.
Dijsselbloem, the Eurozone finance ministers chief, said the first move was Athens. We will now wait for the initiatives of the Greek authorities, he said.
The size of the victory for the no campaign came as a surprise both inside and outside Greece after a flurry of opinion polls showed voters to be split down the middle. Bitter disagreement over the significance and possible effect of the plebiscite cleaved living rooms and workplaces across the country.
Just over 62% of the countrys 9.9 million voters cast a ballot, easily surpassing the mandatory threshold of 40% for a referendum to be considered valid.
Surveys suggested that young people voted no in droves. Many agreed with Tsipras contention that the bailout proposals on offer from Greeces lenders demanded too much austerity on top of years of brutal spending cuts and would hit the poor and elderly disproportionately hard.
These measures would worsen the situation, said teacher Paula Andriotaki, 33, after casting her vote in a local school on a bright and warm afternoon. We try to see light, but we get worse and worse.
Yes supporters had urged Greeks to join them in order to guarantee Athens continued place in the Eurozone. They said that membership in the wider European Union could also be at risk and that Greece could not afford to be isolated.
A 40-year-old man named Giorgos, who declined to give his surname, blamed Tsipras for passing the buck.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 23:25:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis lands in Ecuador, focusing on 'concern for the most vulnerable'</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-pope-francis-journey-americas-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Pope Francis launched the first of two summertime trips to the Americas on Sunday, arriving in Ecuador on a mission to reach and energize some of the hemisphere's poorest, most marginalized -- and most Catholic -- populations.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis lands in Ecuador, focusing on 'concern for the most vulnerable'
Pope Francis
Rodrigo Buendia / AFP/Getty Images
As wind whips his garments, Pope Francis alights from an airplane upon landing at the Mariscal Sucre International Airport in Quito, Ecuador, on Sunday.
As wind whips his garments, Pope Francis alights from an airplane upon landing at the Mariscal Sucre International Airport in Quito, Ecuador, on Sunday.
(Rodrigo Buendia / AFP/Getty Images)
Evo Morales
Pope Francis launched the first of two summertime trips to the Americas on Sunday, arriving in Ecuador on a mission to reach and energize some of the hemispheres poorest, most marginalized -- and most Catholic -- populations.
Francis, the first pope born in the Americas, intends for his now-familiar theme of expanding a church for the poor to be made real on his native continent.
I thank God for having allowed me to return to Latin America to be here with you today, Francis said after stepping off the Alitalia jet that brought him from Rome, becoming the first pope in 30 years to set foot in the dramatically beautiful but politically troubled Andean country of Ecuador.
Pope Francis
Rodrigo Buendia / AFP/Getty Images
Pope Francis waves to the crowd upon landing at the Mariscal Sucre International Airport in Quito, Ecuador, on Sunday.
Pope Francis waves to the crowd upon landing at the Mariscal Sucre International Airport in Quito, Ecuador, on Sunday.
(Rodrigo Buendia / AFP/Getty Images)
He said he hoped the gospel would lead the way to meeting contemporary challenges, while respecting differences, dialogue and broad participation, so that growth and progress can benefit everyone, with particular concern for the most vulnerable of our brothers and sisters.
Departing from his prepared remarks, he said that concern for the most vulnerable "is a debt that all of Latin America has."
Francis was greeted with a hug on the heavily guarded tarmac by Ecuadors leftist President Rafael Correa. A gust of wind knocked the white cap from his head as he walked off the plane.
The pope noted that Ecuador was home to the place on Earth closest to the sun, the peak of the Chimborazo volcano.
Francis sounded tired as he spoke, his voice somewhat strained.
In addition to Ecuador, he will travel to Bolivia and Paraguay over the next eight days.
By choosing impoverished and geopolitically insignificant countries, Francis drives home his belief in preaching from the periphery, as he and others have put it.
8
Similarly, he elected visits to Albania and Bosnia in Europe before larger, wealthier countries such as France and Germany, noted Austen Ivereigh, an expert on the church and author of a biography, "The Great Reformer: Francis and the Making of a Radical Pope."
The point he wants to make ... is his conviction that often those on the margins are the most receptive to the church, and he wants to give voice to those on the margins, Ivereigh, founder of the Catholic Voices website, said in a telephone interview from near Oxford.
It is an attitude Francis solidified when he cleared the way earlier this year for the beatification of slain archbishop Oscar Romero, of El Salvador, who was revered in much of Latin America and widely seen as a champion for the poor and downtrodden.
Expectations are high for this papal pilgrimage, with predictions that millions will turn out to see Francis, who is extremely popular, even among many non-Catholics.
The Argentine-born pontiff will also be in his element, speaking his native Spanish and evangelizing among people he knows well. As a Jesuit priest in Buenos Aires, he often preached in that citys shanty towns, which were heavily populated by Paraguayan, Ecuadoran and Bolivian immigrants.
As he did in his first trip to Latin America in Brazil in 2013, the pope also hopes to revitalize a church that has lost ground to Protestant groups, secularism and indigenous movements.
The big question is: Will the wild popularity of Pope Francis translate into numbers for the church? Andrew Chesnut, a church studies professor at Virginia Commonwealth University, said in a recent broadcast of Latin Pulse. If it doesnt, the Catholic Church will continue to be in trouble.
This is the same script that Obama uses. Find a poor, downtrodden audience, promise, them the world, and move on. Sadly the numbers in the US keep growing and the country continues to decline.
cantinflas
7
That question is less of an issue in the countries of this voyage, three of the most Catholic countries in South America, according to a recent survey by the Pew Research Center. In Paraguay, a full 89% of residents identify themselves as Roman Catholic, and attendance at Mass is particularly high.
The pope is also expected to make a special appeal to the indigenous, sprinkling his sermons with native languages such as Guarani, Aymara and Quechua -- in part to counter a movement in South America to recover pre-Columbian concepts, but that has sometimes taken on anti-colonial, and anti-clerical, tones, Ivereigh said.
Whether he gets mired in national politics or uses the themes he shares with leftist leaders to navigate the minefields will test Francis considerable diplomatic skills. He would find common cause, for example, on climate change and other environmental ills that he blames in part on Western consumerism, as outlined in the pope's recent historic encyclical on the subject.
In Bolivia, church-state relations were soured after the election in 2005 of leftist President Evo Morales and his push to change the constitution, declaring Bolivia a secular state.
The church had been a privileged institution and Bolivia opted to become a lay state, said Father Steve Judd, an American missionary priest in the Bolivian city of Cochabamba. That caused some mutual suspicion, where the church would go.
But Morales quickly embraced Francis and even traveled to Brazil and to Rome to meet with him.
Some people consider the pope coming to the country as perhaps a favor or a way to improve relations with the current government or because of the friendship [Morales] has with the pope, said Jose Luis Aguirre, spokesman for the papal trips organizing committee in La Paz, the Bolivian capital.
Francis plans to spend just four hours in La Paz and its sprawling neighbor El Alto, because of their altitude of nearly 12,000 feet -- potentially problematic for a pope with just one lung. He will move then to Santa Cruz, in Bolivias lowlands.
In Quito, meanwhile, in the days leading up to the popes arrival, thousands of anti-government demonstrators have taken to the streets to protest tax hikes, turning raucous at the end of last week and inviting an angry rebuke from Correa on Saturday. He accused his foes of attempting to politicize the popes visit.
Enough of so much violence, so much cowardice, Correa said in a weekly, four-hour television address. How sad we have to talk about this before the popes arrival.
In response, opposition leaders critcized Correas government for cherry-picking papal statements to support its own issues, such as the need for redistribution of wealth, and plastering them on fences across the capital.
The pope has scheduled two days of events in each country, including meetings with local bishops, officials, jailed inmates and people from slums.
In September, Francis heads for Cuba and the United States, where he will meet with President Obama, become the first pope to address a joint session of the U.S. Congress and elevate to sainthood Junipero Serra, the controversial Franciscan friar who founded Californias missions.
Special correspondent Jaramillo Viteri reported Bfrom Quito and staff writer Wilkinson from Mexico City. Special correspondent David Agren in Mexico City contributed to this report.
Follow @TracyKWilkinson on Twitter for more news from Latin America.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 20:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At WWII victory parade, Taiwan's Nationalists tout role fighting Japan</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-taiwan-japan-war-anniversary-201507-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Taiwan jabbed at mainland China this weekend with a two-hour military show aimed at asserting credit for defeating Japan in a key World War II theater, but Beijing is expected to absorb the barb as it seeks friendly relations with the island -- even though it credits its own Communist forces for...
	</Description>
        <MainBody>At WWII victory parade, Taiwan's Nationalists tout role fighting Japan
Taiwan marks 70th anniversary of end of WWII
Sam Yeh / AFP/Getty Images
Soldiers salute from M60A3 tanks during a parade in Taiwan marking 70 years since the end of World War II at a military base in Hsinchu, northern Taiwan, on July 4.
Soldiers salute from M60A3 tanks during a parade in Taiwan marking 70 years since the end of World War II at a military base in Hsinchu, northern Taiwan, on July 4.
(Sam Yeh / AFP/Getty Images)
Japan
Taiwan jabbed at mainlandChina this weekendwith a two-hour military show aimed at asserting credit for defeatingJapan in a key World War II theater, but Beijing is expected to absorb the barb as it seeks friendly relations with the island -- even though it credits its own Communist forcesfor the same victory.
APphoto_Taiwan WWII Parade
Wally Santana / AP
Taiwan's military special forces "frogmen" pass in front of thousands of spectators in a parade marking the 70th anniversary of the end of WWII, at the military base in Hsinchu, northern Taiwan, on Saturday.
Taiwan's military special forces "frogmen" pass in front of thousands of spectators in a parade marking the 70th anniversary of the end of WWII, at the military base in Hsinchu, northern Taiwan, on Saturday.
(Wally Santana / AP)
This year marks the 70th anniversary of the end of World War II, and nations across Asia are marking the event in a variety of ways. Mainland China is planning a massive military parade in early September to commemorate the event, but Taiwan has said it would not send any participantsto those events.
Taiwan staged V-shaped military aircraft flyovers and a first-ever display of homegrown missile systems at its headlineanniversary event Saturday at a military base in the north of the island. Taiwan has upgraded weaponry in recent years mainly to brace against any conflict with mainland China.
During Japans 1931-45 occupation of China, the Nationalist Party headed by Chiang Kai-shek resisted the Japanese and ruled most of the inland areas that did not fall to them. The Chinese Communist Party engaged in separate guerrilla warfare against the Japanese.
8
The Nationalist Party was forced to retreat to Taiwan after losing China'scivilwar to Mao Tse-tungs Communists in the late 1940s.
Since then, Taiwan and mainland China have been separately ruled, though Taiwan has never formally declared independence and Beijing continues to claim sovereignty over the island, straining relations for decades. Taiwan is formallyknown as the Republic of China.
The Chinese Communists will say they were the major force resisting Japan, but thats just a way of cheating public opinion, Taiwan Defense Ministry spokesman Lo Shao-he said. Over eight years of resistance, it was our Republic of China forces who led it.
In a speech after the Saturday show, Taiwanese President Ma Ying-jeou said fighting by Republic of China forces in World War II would not be forgotten, nor can the Republic of Chinas victory in the war be distorted.
Republic of China troops at times had to use simple knives against the militarily superior Japanese, recalled Tao Shih-chun, a 97-year-old veteran at the military show. At least 10 million Chinese people died during the resistance, with some estimates far higher.
cComments
Although I am pro-Taiwan, and my wife is Taiwanese, both Taiwan and China are completely wrong and should not be celebrating as the victors. If I recall correctly, the U.S. and two atomic bombs had a little bit to do with defeating Japan.
Doctor Oilcan
3
Japan formally surrendered in September 1945 after intensive American airstrikes including the dropping of atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
The Taiwan governments assertion of wartime leadership follows years of efforts to avoid being eclipsed internationally by the much larger mainland China as officials in Beijing try to diminishthe islands global profile.
It is of course a concern for the leadership here, said Raymond Wu, managing director of political risk consultancy e-telligence in Taipei. It goes back to the old angle between China and Taiwan about legitimacy.
After years of all but ignoring the Nationalists' contributions to wartime fighting, Beijing has begun to acknowledge their efforts -- but still maintains that Communist forces' contributions were decisive.
Mainland scholars now speak openly about the Republic of Chinas clout in World War II, said Kweibo Huang, associate diplomacy professor at National Chengchi University in Taipei.
At Saturdays military hardware parade, Taiwan brought out modern surface-to-air missiles and attack helicopters, some flying at steep angles above a crowd of thousands at a mountainous military base.
China is not expected to publicly challenge the narrativeTaiwan put on display Saturday. Since Ma, of the Nationalist Party, was elected in 2008, the two sides have set aside political disputes to pursuedialogue after decades of icy relations. 
Beijing prefers a Nationalist Party-ledgovernment in Taiwan, rather than one led by the islands chief opposition party, which advocates more distancefrom China. The island will hold elections next year, and Ma cannot seekoffice again. Early opinion polls show the opposition party with the lead.
China should be happy because the military parade will stimulate everyones understanding of the Republic of China, and its not for the promotion of a separate Taiwan identity, Huang said.
Jennings is a special correspondent
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 18:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan fighters accuse Kabul of neglect in deadly battle with Taliban</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-afghan-fighters-kabul-neglect-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  With his weapon in one hand, Ibrahim answered his cellphone with the other. He was hoping the call would bring news of reinforcements for his Afghan Local Police post, which was under siege from hundreds of Taliban insurgents.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan fighters accuse Kabul of neglect in deadly battle with Taliban
Ibrahim and Ali, who use no last name
Ali M. Latifi / Los Angeles Times
Ibrahim, left, and Ali, two members of the Afghan Local Police, seen in Kabul, Afghanistan, on Sunday.
Ibrahim, left, and Ali, two members of the Afghan Local Police, seen in Kabul, Afghanistan, on Sunday.
(Ali M. Latifi / Los Angeles Times)
By Ali M. Latifi
Taliban
With his weapon in one hand, Ibrahim answered his cellphone with the other. He was hoping the call would bring news of reinforcements for his Afghan Local Police post, which was under siege from hundreds of Taliban insurgents.
But the caller was his brother, and Ibrahim, a 20-year-old member of the U.S.-backed Afghan government militia, broke down in tears in the middle of an hours-long gun battle in the eastern province of Maidan Wardak.
When I heard his voice, I thought to myself, This is the end, Ibrahim said. I started to cry before telling him goodbye and that I was sorry for any wrong I ever did to him.
As soon as he sees the brightly colored storefronts of fruit sellers and general merchandisers on this small stretch of road, Gholam Karbalai knows he is safe. ( Ali M. Latifi )
At least 30 ALP members were killed in the fighting last week as Taliban insurgents launched a coordinated attack on a series of ALP checkpoints in Jalrez district, which lies on a strategically important highway about one hour west of Kabul.
Government forces said they had regained control of the checkpoints, but President Ashraf Ghani called for an investigation after surviving militiamen accused the Interior Ministry of failing to send army or police units to help the ALP, a mostly rural paramilitary force created with heavy U.S. support.
Ibrahim and another ALP member, Ali, 19, said they were outgunned and outnumbered during a 27-hour battle that began late Wednesday evening when Taliban forces rushed a nearby checkpoint. Both men  who like many Afghans have only one name  have refused orders to return to their posts and spoke to The Times on Sunday in Kabul.
Ali said he called the Interior Ministry  which oversees the ALP  several times during the battle to beg for air support and fresh weapons and ammunition. No help arrived.
Seven ALP checkpoints, all manned by members of the Hazara ethnic minority, were overrun by Taliban, raising charges of ethnic bias. All of the dead ALP fighters were Hazaras, and some were reportedly beheaded and dragged from the backs of moving cars. Some officials say the ALP death toll could be as high as 45.
We fought for two days without food, water or sleep and no one said so much as, 'Thank you for your service.' - Ali, a 19-year-old member of the Afghan Local Police
In the last three months, Afghan security forces in the northern provinces of Kunduz and Badakhshan have also accused Kabul of failing to help them in battles against Taliban insurgents who have been waging one of their deadliest offensives in years across parts of northern, eastern and southern Afghanistan.
The reports from Wardak were the first to involve the ALP and Hazaras, who have long felt targeted by the Pashtun-dominated Taliban and complained of discrimination from the central government.
They could be rescued easily but werent. Why? Because of their ethnicityit must become clear, said former Second Vice President Mohammad Karim Khalili.
0
Arif Rahmani, a lawmaker from the eastern province of Ghazni, said in parliament that three Afghan National Police checkpoints did not respond, despite being located within approximately 500 yards of ALP posts that were under attack.
By Thursday evening, a day after the fighting began, four ALP members at the Sar-e Tapa checkpoint were killed and another was severely injured, leaving Ibrahim and Ali as the only ones able to defend the position. They were stunned at the lack of support because they were less than 10 miles from the provincial capital and 30 miles from Kabul.
Each post had two, three, even four martyrs, Ali said.
When it became clear that Kabul was ignoring their pleas, Ali added, an ALP commander he identified only as Mohammad, who oversaw three of the checkpoints, called his two bodyguards into battle with him. All three were killed, Ali said.
Ali said that at the time of the attack, several of his colleagues had already gone five months without receiving their monthly salary of about $166.
We fought for two days without food, water or sleep and no one said so much as, Thank you for your service, Ali said.
Aref, a friend, said Ali is suffering from post-traumatic stress.
The other night he was talking in his sleep: Go, go, go! Get him, shoot the rocket now! Aref said. None of them have had the time to heal from the mental scars.
Ali said he and his comrades have all been told to return to their posts or risk losing their jobs, but he has refused, he said, until his superiors provide better weapons.
We cant go back if things are just going to continue as they were, he said.
An ALP commander named Zarif, who is based in Jalrez but was on leave last week, said in an interview that the paramilitary force had long felt ignored by the Interior Ministry. He said the areas in which they were stationed were among the most dangerous in the province and that officials have failed to recognize the forces sacrifices.
We still have martyrs there [in Jalrez], lying in the same spot where they were struck by the Taliban, he said.
He said the government cannot continue to ignore the risks the ALP face, especially in Jalrez.
We joined the ALP to be of service to the country, he said, not for the money.
Latifi is a special correspondent. Times staff writer Shashank Bengali contributed to this report from Mumbai, India.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 16:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China's move toward restricting foreign NGOs spurs anxiety in many organizations</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-china-ngos-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  When a massive earthquake struck Nepal in April, Chinese nongovernmental organizations rushed in to provide help, making camp on the grounds of the national palace museum and distributing water, food and tents.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>China's move toward restricting foreign NGOs spurs anxiety in many organizations
Nonprofits
Bikram Rai, AFP/Getty Images
Chinese actor Jackie Chan, center, walks with officials in Katmandu, Nepal, last month during a relief program with the Chinese Red Cross. Chinese nonprofits are expanding their reach just as the government is considering a law to restrict foreign nonprofits working in China.
Chinese actor Jackie Chan, center, walks with officials in Katmandu, Nepal, last month during a relief program with the Chinese Red Cross. Chinese nonprofits are expanding their reach just as the government is considering a law to restrict foreign nonprofits working in China. (Bikram Rai, AFP/Getty Images)
China
When a massive earthquake struck Nepal in April, Chinese nongovernmental organizations rushed in to provide help, making camp on the grounds of the national palace museum and distributing water, food and tents.
A Lions Club chapter in Guangdong province pitched in; so did the China Foundation for Poverty Alleviation, among others.
But Chinese nonprofits are not just engaging with neighbors during disasters: They have helped build hospitals in Sudan and organized educational exchanges with African lawyers.
The nascent coming-out reflects China's economic and social development, as well as a recognition that such activities are a means to enhance the country's image.
The law basically would prohibit any entity in China from receiving funding or doing partnerships with any non-approved foreign NGOs. - Huang Xuetao, a Chinese attorney who works with grass-roots organizations
But even as Chinese NGOs have started casting their gaze overseas, international nonprofits working in China are feeling a chill. Draft legislation under consideration could, for the first time, put foreign nonprofits under the direct supervision of China's security apparatus and impose a range of restrictions. Among the proposed rules: requiring half of all staff to be Chinese and forbidding direct recruitment of volunteers.
The legislation apparently would cover philanthropic groups such as the Gates Foundation and Doctors Without Borders, environmental organizations such as Greenpeace, educational entities and nonprofit trade associations such as the U.S. Meat Export Federation and the Motion Picture Assn. Overseas entities such as orchestras and museums that want to do tours or other short-term activities in China would need consent from security officials.
8
China says the aim of the legislation is to bring foreign nonprofits out of a legal gray area; many are now essentially registered as businesses on the mainland because China has lacked clear national regulations for foreign NGOs (aside from a few dozen overseas foundations registered with the Ministry of Civil Affairs). The draft law "is part of our effort to rule the country according to law, and also part of our effort to align China with the international community," Foreign Minister Wang Yi said in an interview.
Wang said the new law would not create obstacles to NGOs that are "dedicated to promoting exchanges and cooperation with the Chinese people in accordance with Chinese laws." But the proposed legislation comes in wake of the establishment of a new National Security Council, the drafting of a new national security law, and rising government rhetoric warning against the pernicious influence of "Western values."
The legislation says foreign NGOs must not endanger China's "national unity, security or ethnic unity" nor "harm China's national interests" nor "illegally engage in religious activities" and cannot raise money within China.
The proposal has inspired significant anxiety among foreign nonprofits  some of whom say they may be forced to curtail their activities or withdraw from China altogether  as well as many Chinese partner organizations, who worry that their overseas funding and professional support could be cut or criminalized.
Representatives of 10 major foreign nonprofits operating in China, contacted for comment, refused to be quoted by name or organization for fear of antagonizing Chinese authorities. "People are so skittish right now," said Anthony J. Spires, an associate professor of sociology at the Chinese University of Hong Kong whose research focuses on civil society and NGOs in China. "It's really a big deal."
3
But 45 foreign trade groups and professional organizations, including the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, the Recording Industry Assn. of America and the American Bar Assn., wrote an unusual letter last month to Chinese authorities, warning that unless revised, the legislation would have a "significant adverse impact on the future of U.S.-China relations."
Foreign industry associations, universities, environmental groups, science and technology groups and other NGOs, the 45 signees said, are key to businesses' research, market development, information sharing, innovation and corporate philanthropy activities. The legislation would even seem to limit Chinese engineers from participating in international professional societies, it said.
As drafted, the law would "negatively impact the ability of companies to do business in China, as well as U.S.-China commercial and people-to-people exchanges," said James Zimmerman, chairman of the American Chamber of Commerce in China. "This is increasingly important as China globalizes and its companies and NGOs expand overseas."
Exactly how many foreign NGOs operate in China is unclear; Spires put the number at 200 to 300, though some estimates range as high as 6,000. Fewer than 30 foreign foundations are registered with the Civil Affairs Ministry. China has more than 4,000 domestic foundations as well as 600,000 registered domestic NGOs, many of which have significant government participation, despite engaging in NGO-type activities.
The draft legislation calls for foreign entities in China with nonprofit parent organizations abroad to find a Chinese government agency to serve as their "sponsor"; the government is to publish a list of authorized sponsor agencies. But finding a sponsor may prove difficult, experts said, because government officials may be wary of vouching for a foreign entity.
"This would be a political risk, a personal risk" to one's career, Spires said.
But more concerning, Spires said, was the possible "ripple" damage to links between Chinese civil society groups and foreign nonprofits  cutting off funding, inhibiting mentoring and closing off the exchange of ideas.
"The law basically would prohibit any entity in China from receiving funding or doing partnerships with any non-approved foreign NGOs," said Huang Xuetao, a Chinese attorney who works with grass-roots organizations. Huang said she believes Communist Party authorities fear that foreign NGOs are promoting "Western values" and ideology.
"For Chinese authorities, this is a real threat; they view Western influence as undermining their role," she said. "But from a legal point of view, it's hard to regulate value systems. Laws can mostly only regulate actions. So they have drafted this law to take away as much freedom as possible and hand it to police."
A staff member of a foreign nonprofit who has 30 years of experience in China said she believed there were several triggers for the concern among Chinese authorities  including the U.S. surveillance activities revealed by Edward Snowden; the U.S. "pivot" to Asia; and last year's "Occupy Central" pro-democracy protests in Hong Kong, which some mainland Chinese authorities said were instigated or supported by foreign "black hands."
"All of this has fed a real worsening of bilateral [U.S.-China] relations that is about the worst I've ever seen," she said.
A monthlong comment period on the draft legislation ended in early June, but no Chinese or foreigners working in the sector expressed any optimism that major revisions would be made. Still, several said the real clarity will not come until Public Security authorities begin implementation and enforcement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 02:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For many Greeks, a 'no' vote on bailout deal doesn't mean no to the EU</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-europe-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  To the leaders of the European Union who warn that Greece might soon be expelled from their midst, Lydia Lenossi has an ancient reminder.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>For many Greeks, a 'no' vote on bailout deal doesn't mean no to the EU
Greek referendum
Louisa Gouliamaki / AFP/Getty Images
A news agent hangs newpapers bearing "no" and "yes" headlines in central Athenson the eve of the Greek referendum on bailout terms.
A news agent hangs newpapers bearing "no" and "yes" headlines in central Athenson the eve of the Greek referendum on bailout terms.
(Louisa Gouliamaki / AFP/Getty Images)
To the leaders of the European Union who warn that Greece might soon be expelled from their midst, Lydia Lenossi has an ancient reminder.
Remember where Europe got its name? From the beautiful princess Europa, a popular figure in Greek mythology.
"The god Zeus brought Europa on his back as a bull from Phoenicia to Crete," Lenossi said, adding tartly of EU officials: "They forgot about it. There is no Europe without Greece."
Conversely, Lenossi believes that her country needs, and deserves, to belong to a strong, united Europe. Yet the retired actress is still voting "no" Sunday on a painful cash-for-cuts bailout deal that European partners have offered debt-ridden Greece and that the government decided to put to a snap referendum.
Caption Debt crisis in Greece
Louisa Gouliamaki / AFP/Getty Images
Pensioners jam the sidewalk outside a national bank branch in Athens, opened Wednesday for seniors to withdraw up to 120 euros of their retirement benefits.
Pensioners jam the sidewalk outside a national bank branch in Athens, opened Wednesday for seniors to withdraw up to 120 euros of their retirement benefits.
(Louisa Gouliamaki / AFP/Getty Images)
Caption Greece bailout
Giannis Papanikos / Associated Press
Greeks line up for free sandwiches at a shop in the northern port city of Thessaloniki on July 2, offered as citizens struggle with closed banks and severe limits on their access to cash.
Greeks line up for free sandwiches at a shop in the northern port city of Thessaloniki on July 2, offered as citizens struggle with closed banks and severe limits on their access to cash.
(Giannis Papanikos / Associated Press)
See more galleries
The plebiscite has sown bitter divisions across this sunny, storied land, with surveys showing the race too close to call. The vote is being portrayed, by many news outlets here and abroad and by some EU officials, as a stark choice for or against Europe, pro-euro or anti-euro.
But the reality is more complicated than that. In some ways, many "yes" and "no" voters are closer than their binary election options imply, including in their attitudes toward the European Union.
Polls consistently show that, whatever they feel about the repeated bailouts and austerity cuts their country has suffered in the last five years, about 75% of Greeks want their country to remain one of the 19 nations using the euro and therefore, by extension, a full-fledged member of the European Union.
The single currency is the EU's most important project in promoting greater harmony and integration on a continent ripped apart by two world wars. EU rules dictate that all member states  except Britain and Denmark, which opted out from the start  must eventually adopt the euro to be considered in good standing.
8
Greece joined the EU in 1981, the 10th of 28 nations to sign up so far. To many Greeks reared in the aftermath of World War II, a bloody civil war and a military dictatorship that ruled from 1967 to 1974, admittance to the club was validation that their country  the cradle of democracy  had stabilized and matured and was no longer a Balkan basket case.
Membership gave the Greeks, still relatively poor, access to badly needed funds to build their laggard economy.
"Wherever you went at the time, there were signs of the European stars, the European flag, in the constructions of buildings, the constructions of roads," said Othon Anastasakis, an expert on Greek history at Oxford University and an advisor to the Greek Foreign Ministry on EU affairs during the 1990s.
"European money was very, very much improving the lives of the Greeks," Anastasakis said. "That was the thing that really defined the popularity of the European Union in the hearts and minds of the Greeks."
Adoption of the euro in 2001 brought in more investment and an even better standard of living, further cementing the perception of the EU as a key provider of prosperity.
But successive governments in Athens went on spending sprees they could not afford  and hid their excesses. The debt crisis that blew open in late 2009 has haunted this country since.
In five years of emergency loans and brutal spending cuts demanded by creditors such as Germany, Greeks have watched their once-growing economy tumble into free fall. Many residents speak incredulously of scenes they thought unimaginable in their proud country  hungry people picking through garbage, despairing pensioners committing suicide  and accuse Greece's lenders of plunging their society into an abyss.
cComments
@Bill Comment It's unfortunate that a number of them they allowed themselves to believe that their government would take care of them. But that's what a generation of them were promised and believed. It should be a lesson to all not to solely rely on the government for your well...
IELB91710
42
The left-wing government of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras contends that the new bailout package on the referendum ballot would bring yet more misery, especially for the poor and the elderly. Many Greeks who plan to join him in voting "no" hope to send a message to leaders of the EU: not that they want out, but that the EU should return to its original principles and stop riding roughshod over this nation of 11 million people.
"There were values  solidarity, democracy, freedom of the people.... There is nothing of that now," said Lenossi, the actress, who is 70. "They should not give precedence to money. Money is not the first issue. Humans are the first issue. We are not numbers; we are humans."
Nikos Aspradakis, 48, recalled the promises he felt were made.
"When I was voting in favor of the EU, I was told that my salary would slowly converge with French and German levels, that Greece wouldn't need to spend so much on its military anymore, that my democracy which has been shaken in the past would be secure, that there would be light at the end of the tunnel. I don't see any of that anymore," said Aspradakis, who works in the private sector.
"Now they are saying that I should have a salary like those in Bulgaria. Why? I want Bulgarians' salary to rise, not the opposite."
With his compatriots still heavily in favor of membership in the Eurozone and the EU, Tsipras has repeatedly sought to assure them that a "no" vote would not jeopardize either. That directly contradicts statements by the leaders of Germany, France and Spain, who warn that a win for the "no" camp will be taken as a desire to exit the euro. And quitting or being banished from the euro would mean giving up EU membership as well, the president of the European Parliament, Martin Schulz, has insisted.
Tsipras and his advisors have also tried to reinforce the idea that it is the EU that has let Greece down, with its "threats" and "blackmail," and not the other way around.
"It is a dark hour for Europe, as far as I'm concerned," the outspoken finance minister, Yanis Varoufakis, said in a recent radio interview. "We are looking upon these developments with a great deal of sadness on what has happened to the Europe we signed up to."
Many residents say that an EU without Greece is as unthinkable as Greece without the EU, for reasons of geopolitical stability and because of shared roots and culture stretching back millenniums.
"We are not guests in a system run by others. We are an integral part of it," said a 50-year-old bank worker named Giorgos, who declined to give his surname, at a massive "no" campaign rally Friday evening.
"Yes" supporters agree that Greece belongs at the heart of the Eurozone and the EU, but they insist that a victory for their side is the only way to guarantee it.
Anastasakis at Oxford said the anger fueling "no" voters is understandable, because European officials bear responsibility for some of the missteps that have turned Greece's debt crisis into such an intractable mess.
But in the end, even many "no" voters realize that their future is bound up with the EU.
"They are furious at Europe," Anastasakis said. "But there is no other game in town for them."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 21:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tunisia declares state of emergency, steps up its powers, after terror attacks</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-tunisia-president-emergency-20150704-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Tunisia declared a state of emergency Saturday, eight days after a gunman slaughtered dozens of foreign tourists at a Mediterranean beach resort.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunisia declares state of emergency, steps up its powers, after terror attacks
Tunisia tourists
WPA Pool / Getty Images
The coffin of Christopher Dyer is carried in Brize Norton, England, on Friday after arriving on a Royal Air Force plane that repatriated the bodies of five British nationals killed in a terrorist attack in Tunisia on June 26.
The coffin of Christopher Dyer is carried in Brize Norton, England, on Friday after arriving on a Royal Air Force plane that repatriated the bodies of five British nationals killed in a terrorist attack in Tunisia on June 26.
(WPA Pool / Getty Images)
8
The move, which gives the government stepped-up powers to deal with suspected terrorists but also curtails to a degree the rights of ordinary citizens, marks an unhappy juncture in what had perhaps been the only real success story to emerge from the 2011 uprisings that were collectively dubbed the Arab Spring.
Tunisia tourists
Handout / AFP/Getty Images
A handout picture released by the Tunisian Presidency Press Service shows Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi speaking during a news conference in Tunis on July 4, 2015. Essebsi declared a state of emergency following last week's beach massacre of tourists.
A handout picture released by the Tunisian Presidency Press Service shows Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi speaking during a news conference in Tunis on July 4, 2015. Essebsi declared a state of emergency following last week's beach massacre of tourists.
(Handout / AFP/Getty Images)
Tunisia, whose revolt against a longtime dictator set in motion similar pro-democracy movements across North Africa and the Middle East, had been making steady strides in its transition to democracy. But the June 26 attack on the idyllic seaside town of Sousse, which killed at least 38 people, most of them British vacationers, coupled with Islamic militants assault in March on a landmark museum in the capital, seemingly forced the governments hand.
Poor Tunisia. They were the successful "Arab Spring" country. Guess not.
TKLA-67
1
Emergency law strengthens executive powers, restricts rights such as freedom of assembly, and grants greater authority to the security forces. The declaration was announced by the office of President Beji Caid Essebsi, who later delivered a nationally televised speech.
In his address, Essebsi cited a state of war of a special kind that demanded the harnessing of the states powers.
A constitution agreed upon last year  and touted at the time as a token of Tunisias strengthening of its democratic institutions  does allow for an emergency declaration by the countrys leadership under exceptional circumstances. But for many, it harks back to days when authorities acted with impunity to quell any dissent.
Tunisian officials have been alarmed by evidence that two of the assailants in Marchs museum attack, and also the lone gunman in the Sousse massacre, had been provided with training at militant camps in next-door Libya. In the two attacks, officials see an intensifying bid by Islamist militants to destabilize Tunisia's still-fragile order.
The country's last state of emergency was in 2011, during the revolt against longtime ruler Zine el Abidine ben Ali, who was forced to step down.
In the immediate aftermath of the Sousse attack, the government announced measures including the deployment of troops at tourist sites and the closing of dozens of mosques deemed as wellsprings of hate rhetoric.
The most recent rampage, which targeted foreign tourists as they swam and sunbathed, is expected to cause more than $500 million in losses to Tunisias tourist sector, one of the mainstays of the economy.
The gunman in the resort attack was shot dead, but authorities have rounded up a number of suspected accomplices.
Special correspondent Amro Hassan contributed to this report.
Follow @laurakingLAT on Twitter for news out of North Africa

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 19:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Negotiators make headway on Iran sanctions, past nuclear activity</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-tentative-agreement-iran-sanctions-20150704-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  The head of the United Nations' nuclear watchdog agency said Saturday he hopes to complete his controversial investigation of Iran's past nuclear activities by December, potentially removing a key obstacle to completion of world powers' sweeping nuclear deal with the Islamic Republic.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Negotiators make headway on Iran sanctions, past nuclear activity
Iran talks
Carlos Barria / AFP/Getty Images
Secretary of State John F. Kerry, center, during nuclear talks with the Iranian foreign minister in Vienna on Friday.
Secretary of State John F. Kerry, center, during nuclear talks with the Iranian foreign minister in Vienna on Friday.
(Carlos Barria / AFP/Getty Images)
United Nations
The head of the United Nations nuclear watchdog agency said Saturday he hopes to complete his controversial investigation of Irans past nuclear activities by December, potentially removing a key obstacle to completion of world powers sweeping nuclear deal with the Islamic Republic.
As diplomats rush to reach an agreement to curb Iran's nuclear program, the U.S. military is stockpiling conventional bombs so powerful that strategists say they could cripple Tehran's most heavily fortified nuclear complexes, including one deep underground. ( W.J. Hennigan )
Meanwhile, diplomats said there has also been progress on another disputed issue in the negotiations, the sanctions relief that Iran will receive as part of the deal. Negotiators reached a tentative agreement on the structure and schedule for sanctions relief, though more work and a high-level blessing is needed, officials said.
If and when issues get resolved at an experts level, there will remain some open issues that can only be decided by ministers, a senior Obama administration official said. Negotiators still have a bunch of work to do on the sanctions issue, added the official, who would not be named while the discussions were still in progress.
8
Diplomats have also reached tentative agreement on a mechanism to restore suspended sanctions if Iran is found to be violating the agreement. U.S. officials consider this snapback essential and have pressed to avoid allowing a small number of countries to block it from happening.
Under the proposed arrangement, a panel made up of the six countries and Iran would examine any assertions that Iran is not living up to it obligations. The U.N.Security Council would periodically adopt a resolution rolling over suspension of the sanctions.
But if a council member believed Iran to be in violation of the rules, it could prevent the rollover and reinstate the sanctions, officials say.
@Skip Adam yes understand that bush grand father was doing that
Preci Gil
28
The United States and five other world powers -- France, Britain, Germany, Russia and China -- are seeking a deal that would ease sanctions on Iran if it agrees to steps intended to keep it from obtaining a bomb for 10 to 15 years. Negotiators for the group have been working in Vienna for the past week, toward a self-imposed deadline of Tuesday.
Yukiya Amano, director general of the International Atomic Energy Agency, told reporters he hopes to complete the IAEAs probe of Irans pastactivities if Iran cooperates in answering outstanding questions on past work, such as research on nuclear bomb related equipment.
With the cooperation from Iran, I think we can issue a report by the end of the year on the assessment of the clarification of the issues related to possible military dimensions, he said.
Amano visited Tehran on Thursday and held meetings that top Iranian officials said had yielded progress toward resolving the long-running investigation.
Kelsey Davenport, of the Arms Control Assn., said the comments were a very significant development for the IAEAs investigation and for completion of the nuclear deal, which may happen in days.
The nuclear agency has been seeking to establish the facts on avariety of suspected past nuclear activities, including experiments with bomb detonators. The IAEA considers the probecrucial because the information will help monitor Irans risky nuclear activities in the future, and to deter other countries from trying to break nuclear rules.
Iran insists that it has never sought a nuclear weapon. And it has been concerned that the agency would continue extending its investigation indefinitely.
Iran could still balk at providing all the information the IAEA is seeking.
But Davenport said Iran now has a strong incentive to cooperate. Doing so will ensure that it receives sanctions relief as part of the broader deal, she said. And since the deal is in view, Iranian officials can have confidence that the major powers wont penalize them in the agreement, she said.
Ray Takeyh, an Iran specialist at the Council on Foreign Relations, who has been skeptical about the negotiations, said Amanos plan may open the way for the agency to wrap up the investigation without getting all the answers it needs.
The issue will not be resolved, but it will be passed over, he predicted.
Special correspondent Ramin Mostaghim in Tehran contributed to thisreport.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 18:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dalai Lama's 80th birthday invites celebration and contemplation</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-tibet-future-20150705-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  To hear the Dalai Lama laugh, his face lighting up in a beatific smile, it is easy to forget the cascade of disasters endured by the Tibetan Buddhist movement over the course of his life.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>16
Tibet had been run as a de facto independent country in the chaotic early 20th century, but it had not been formally recognized. In 1949, Chinese Communists claimed power in distant Beijing and proved to be a force that the Himalayan mountain kingdom could not overcome.
For China, the 965,000-square-mile region known as the Tibetan plateau, spread over strategic high ground in the center of Asia, is a crucial buffer from India, Nepal and Bangladesh. Encompassing roughly one-quarter of China's landmass, it is the source of most of Asia's largest rivers, supplying water to nearly half the world's population. It also has the largest reserve of uranium in the world.
The struggle to subdue Tibet has shaped the character of modern China, forcing it to become the kind of brutal imperial power the early communist ideologues once deplored. Beijing devotes inordinate military and diplomatic effort to defend its claim to Tibet, which it calls "an integral part of China since antiquity."
"The Chinese know that historically their empire was weak when control over the western borders lapsed,'' said Sulmaan Wasif Khan, a specialist in Chinese foreign relations at Tufts University.
Tibetan resistance to Chinese rule has been relatively nonviolent compared with ethnic disputes elsewhere, such as those involving Kurds or Chechens.
Robert Barnett, a Tibet scholar at Columbia University in New York, counts only about 20 Han Chinese (the ethnic majority in China) who have been killed by political violence at the hands of Tibetans since the 1980s. The death toll among ethnic Tibetans is higher, in the hundreds including those who have self-immolated with calls for the Dalai Lama to return.
If he dies in exile, though, that could change. "People may feel the Chinese forced him to die outside his country and caused him grief, and they could reap a terrible harvest of suffering,'' Barnett said.
At the heart of the dilemma is the Dalai Lama. Although he abandoned calls for Tibetan independence in 1979, embracing instead a "middle way" in which Tibetans would enjoy autonomy and freedom of religion and speech under Chinese rule, the Chinese Communist Party reviles him as a separatist.
"The Dalai party has never abandoned the use of violence to achieve their ultimate goal of full independence,'' the State Council wrote in a "white paper" on Tibet released in mid-April.
So anathema is the Dalai Lama to the Communist Party that he is treated as the one whose name cannot be mentioned. Tibetans dare not speak of him in public. Walking down the street with a portrait of the Dalai Lama will get one immediately arrested in most parts of China. Tiny medallions are routinely confiscated and destroyed.
That causes a recurring cycle of ill will among Tibetans, whose reverence for their spiritual leader endures. People have crossed the Himalayas in flip-flops seeking a blessing from the Dalai Lama. Gonpo Tso, a 64-year-old Tibetan exile living in Dharamsala, says she could accept Chinese communist rule over Tibet if not for the slander of her spiritual leader.
"It gives such pain to my heart to hear the words they use about the Dalai Lama,'' she said.
+++
Tibetans remain deeply embittered about the horrors inflicted upon their society by the Communist Party from the 1950s through the 1970s: the mass starvation, the desecration of Buddhist monasteries, the arrests and executions. By the time of Mao Tse-tung's demise in 1976, hundreds of thousands of Tibetans had perished. Some exile sources estimate up to 1.2 million deaths.
Nevertheless, many Tibetans are quietly returning home, accepting that to live there they will lose many of the freedoms they enjoy in India.
Consider the case of Lobsang, a Tibetan (like many, he has only one name) who trekked across the Himalayas as a 16-year-old monk to follow the Dalai Lama.
Reincarnation is not the business of the communists. - The Dalai Lama
Last year, Lobsang found himself among the crowd of hundreds of Tibetans outside the barbed wire-topped concrete walls of the Chinese Embassy in New Delhi. It is a place that Tibetans used to go to protest; now they line up starting at 3 a.m for documents that permit them to go home.
"I felt such uneasiness being there,'' said Lobsang, 34, a slightly built man who works as a Tibetan-language teacher and editor. "Here I was, as a Tibetan, asking the Chinese for permission to go back to my own home."
Although the Tibetan exile community here reached a high of 118,000 in the mid-1990s, it dropped to 94,000 as of the most recent census, in 2009. Chinese state media say 80,000 Tibetan exiles have returned to visit or to live in Tibet since the 1980s.
The Chinese are quietly encouraging those who elect to return.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 13:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>India's traditional ear de-waxing business is waning</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-india-ear-cleaner-20150704-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Squatting on a low wooden stool, Sayed Mehboob adjusts his red turban, gently faded from countless hours in the afternoon sun. On this patch of sidewalk near the busy Grant Road train station in central Mumbai, modern India flies by in its customary hurry.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>8
A young man in an orange plaid shirt approaches Mehboob, who motions toward the empty stool. Gaurav, a 21-year-old housekeeper here for his occasional cleaning, sits down stiffly, like a boy in a dentist's chair.
Mehboob props his bag of tools on one leg. He pulls out a steel pin the length of a pencil, swathes the tip in a wad of cotton and guides it toward Gaurav's aural canal.
In Mumbai, a commercial hub of more than 12 million where seemingly no job is too small, many of the last remaining traditional ear cleaners hail from southern India. Some trace the profession to the 18th century, when India was under Mogul rule and much of the southern region belonged to the nizam or monarch, of Hyderabad.
Mehboob, who was born outside Hyderabad, learned the trade when he came to look for work in Mumbai 25 years ago, when it was still known as Bombay. After laboring in construction for a few years, a fellow southerner taught him how to clean ears.
"It was just something to do," he says. In the crowded city, with vehicles and construction sites fouling the air with fumes and dust, he describes getting one's ears professionally cleaned as "a normal practice."
Come on LA TIMES did you REALLY have to remind us of what a 3rd world sewer India is? And with PICTURES? EWWWWW
Another Fine Day in Compton
at 11:09 PM July 04, 2015
8
Mehboob charges 20 rupees, or about 30 cents, for a standard cleaning of both ears with cotton and hydrogen peroxide. It takes less time than a good shoeshine. The deluxe treatment can include daubs of lotion, coconut oil and a dark liquid that Mehboob described as an ayurvedic tonic, and costs 50 rupees, or 80 cents.
"That's if the ear is inflamed, or if it's really red," he says. "The lotions provide a soothing effect."
His method is to dip the cotton-tipped pin in hydrogen peroxide and scrape the outer ear canal before proceeding to the inner canal. An old pair of tweezers helps pick out stubborn bits of dirt and wax.
A routine day brings about a dozen customers, he says. For long stretches he sits alone in front of a former phone booth, its rusted doors padlocked shut. In the late afternoon, he moves farther down the road, hoping to catch commuters disembarking from a train on their way home.
It is unlikely that most young people who pass him on the street know what he does, or recognize the meaning of the red turban. Most of his regular customers are elderly, he says, although they are loyal, some even summoning him to their apartment for house calls.
"Rich people," he says proudly.
Mumbai's ear cleaners have a checkered reputation. Foreigners tell stories of being accosted along the promenade near the Gateway of India monument by red-turbaned men waving needles. With the advent of cotton swabs and obsessive hygiene, the trade seems destined for extinction.
In a decent month, Mehboob saves the equivalent of $80 after deducting the little he pays for rent. He shares a room nearby with 15 men  day laborers, taxi drivers, security guards  most of them migrants, all Muslims in a staunchly Hindu neighborhood.
They are the unsung of Mumbai, the people who run the basic machinery of the city, and then there is Mehboob, a fading relic in every way.
He owns nothing of value here, not even a cellphone. He deposits his earnings with a broker instead of in a bank, preferring to carry his savings back to his hometown when he returns every few months to visit his family and their tiny plot of farmland.
Yet Mehboob has trained his nephew, so there could be at least one more generation of ear cleaners in Mumbai. He dismisses the word of doctors who advise patients with earaches not to visit men like him, warning of infections and scrapes.
"Of course the doctors say that," he says. "It's good for their business."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 12:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Murder complaints filed over capsized Philippine ferry</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-murder-complaints-philippine-ferry-20150704-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Police in a central Philippine city said Saturday that they have filed murder complaints against the owner and the crew of a ferry that capsized shortly after pulling out of port, leaving more than 50 people dead.
	</Description>
        <MainBody>Murder complaints filed over capsized Philippine ferry
Ferry tips
Ignatius Martin / AFP/Getty Images
Rescuers battle rough seas Friday as they search for survivors after a ferry capsized off Ormoc City in the central Philippines.
Rescuers battle rough seas Friday as they search for survivors after a ferry capsized off Ormoc City in the central Philippines.
(Ignatius Martin / AFP/Getty Images)
By Associated Press
Police in a central Philippine city said Saturday that they have filed murder complaints against the owner and the crew of a ferry that capsized shortly after pulling out of port, leaving more than 50 people dead.
8
The complaints were filed with the local prosecutor late Friday as the 36-ton M/B Kim Nirvana was lifted from the water, said Senior Inspector Rio Tan of the Ormoc City police.
Regional coast guard commander Capt. Pedro Tinampay said at least 59 people died and 145 survived Thursday's disaster, including all 18 crew members.
Rescue workers are winding down the search for survivors and bodies aboard a ferry that capsized shortly after departing from a central Philippine port, leaving 45 people dead. ( Associated Press )
Tinampay said a maritime casualty investigation that has begun will determine how many people actually were aboard the vessel. The 204 so far known to have been on board are more than the 189 initially reported, Tinampay said, adding that authorities will reconcile different figures for survivors and casualties.
The ferry overturned minutes after pulling out of the port on its voyage to one of the Camotes Islands, about 30 kilometers (19 miles) to the south.
Tan said murder complaints were filed against ferry owner Joge Bung Zarco, boat captain Warren Oliverio and 17 other crew members.
0
The local prosecutor will review the complaints to determine whether there is enough evidence to file charges in court.
Tinampay said some passengers reported that the boat suddenly swerved to the right, possibly causing its cargo, including 80 sacks of cement, to shift to one side of the ferry.
It capsized and its right outrigger broke, Tinampay said. The captain suddenly turned the boat to the right, and we have people saying that.
Oliverio denied he made a sudden turn, blaming strong waves for flipping his boat. It was the waves, he told ABS-CBN television. He said that he could not have made any sudden turn because there was another vessel close to the ferry.
Tinampay said eight bodies were recovered from the boat after it was hoisted out of the water. City rescue group head Ciriaco Tolibao said three more bodies were recovered from the sea early Saturday.
The boat remains belly up on the Ormoc wharf and will be turned upright to allow investigators to get a closer look, Tinampay said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Sat Jul 04 04:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>In Athens district where the view is leftist, the word is 'no'</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-greece-exarchia-20150704-story.html</Link>
        <Description>
	  Radical ideas get passed around at the O Tseligkas cafe as easily as the plates of ruby-red tomatoes and wine-dark olives. White-haired leftists and tattooed rabble-rousers - sometimes one and the same - plot revolution, a better world or both as they sip ouzo and roll cheap cigarettes.
	</Description>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <MainBody>In Athens district where the view is leftist, the word is 'no'
Greece bailout referendum
Aris Messinis / AFP/Getty Images
A demonstrator flashes a no sticker at an Athens rally for the referendum Sunday on a financial bailout package for Greece.
A demonstrator flashes a no sticker at an Athens rally for the referendum Sunday on a financial bailout package for Greece. (Aris Messinis / AFP/Getty Images)
European Union
Radical ideas get passed around at the O Tseligkas cafe as easily as the plates of ruby-red tomatoes and wine-dark olives. White-haired leftists and tattooed rabble-rousers  sometimes one and the same  plot revolution, a better world or both as they sip ouzo and roll cheap cigarettes.
So it wasn't a surprise to see some of the Friday lunch crowd sporting bright orange stickers on their shirt fronts with the single word "oxi"  "no." That's how they'll vote in a pivotal referendum Sunday on a financial bailout package for Greece that would entail more of the austerity many people say has brought their economy to its knees.
Greece bailout referendum
Pro-Europe demonstrators attend a 'yes' rally in central Athens on July 3, 2015.
Pro-Europe demonstrators attend a 'yes' rally in central Athens on July 3, 2015.
(Iakovos Hatzistavrou / AFP/Getty Images)
"They gave us medicine that was worse than the illness," Popy Melliou, 57, said of the international creditors whose loans have kept the Greek government's lights on for the last five years. "It's a shame for them that they cannot save a small country."
She scoffed at warnings from the "yes" campaign  and from a passel of European leaders  that a "no" result could lead to Greece's banishment from the 19-nation Eurozone. And she laughed at the idea that anyone in the cafe might support the other side.
This is Exarchia, a neighborhood long renowned in Athens as a hotbed of radicalism and free thinking.
Anarchists, anti-fascists, environmentalists, feminists and immigrant-rights activists have all cut their teeth here. So did Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras, a left-wing firebrand who attended the National Technical University of Athens down the street, site of a famous uprising against Greece's military dictatorship in 1973, the year before he was born.
8
The political instincts Tsipras honed in Exarchia helped lead him to call Sunday's snap referendum, a bombshell announcement last weekend that blew up his negotiations with Greece's lenders. Tsipras said voters would have to pass judgment on the bailout offer, which he is campaigning against.
Other Eurozone countries have been urging Greeks to accept their proposals to extend the $270-billion package of loans the country received in the last five years, even though the offer technically expired Tuesday after the failure of talks between Athens and its creditors. Only a "yes" vote will open the way for negotiations to a new bailout, they say.
Polls suggest that the race is neck and neck. Beneath pink Athenian skies, both the "yes" and "no" sides held massive rallies Friday evening in a final push before a mandatory day free of campaigning on the eve of the vote.
"Today the whole of Europe has turned its eyes on the Greek people," Tsipras, wearing his trademark open-necked white shirt, told the boisterous "no" crowd in front of Parliament.
He urged them to stand up to threats and "blackmail" emanating from other European capitals and to reject their demand for "dead-end" austerity cuts. He repeated his contention that a victory for the "no" camp would improve his bargaining position.
Barely half a mile away, backers of a "yes" vote cheered speakers who said that the referendum posed a stark choice: Greece remaining a player in a united Europe or being sidelined and left to sink on its own.
They blamed Tsipras and his Syriza party for pushing Greece into a standoff with its lenders so damaging that the government had to order a weeklong bank shutdown to prevent a run on the financial system. The head of the banking association said Friday that Greece's banks had enough cash, about $1.1 billion, to last only until Monday.
Gosh, how terrible that there was a democratic vote and the people of Greece said No to more austerity! They should have left it to the politicians, who have done such a wonderful job! Whatever happens, the people have spoken.
Obtuse
8
"We have been dragged into a pointless referendum that is dividing the people and hurting the country," Athens Mayor George Kaminis said.
The nail-biting showdown Sunday has sharply divided a nation already reeling from five years of deep budget cuts in exchange for emergency loans. The Greek economy has fallen into a depression as severe as the one the United States experienced in the 1930s.
If the "no" campaign prevails in the end, it will be due in no small part to the anger and activism of left-wing enclaves like Exarchia.
Its cafes nestle between buildings splashed with graffiti like "No racism" and "Athens burns." Bookstores sell Marx; music stores sell vinyl.
There's little evidence of the long lines seen elsewhere in Athens at ATMs, perhaps because local anarchists tend to destroy them.
Conversations reflect the intellectual ferment of college campuses in the neighborhood. A site saved from development by community activists has been turned into a people's park where all types can meet.
"There are places in Exarchia where you can see the professor from Paris next to the anarchist who just got out of jail for armed robbery," said Melliou, the customer at the O Tseligkas cafe, which has been serving customers for at least 30 years.
It was already around when, in the 1990s, Tsipras distinguished himself as a gifted and charismatic student leader at the National Technical University of Athens, building on an activist temperament he had shown in high school during a campus revolt against education reforms.
His skills eventually propelled him to the leadership of Syriza, an acronym for "coalition of the radical left." The party's logo consists of three stacked flags in red, green and purple, signifying its commitment to labor unions, environmentalism, feminism and other social-activist groups.
Its ascent to power in elections in January on an aggressive anti-austerity platform set the stage for Greece's standoff with its international lenders.
From Syriza's stronghold in Exarchia, a main artery leads to the neighborhood of Kolonaki, an exclusive enclave that is almost Exarchia's polar opposite. There, the orange posters for the "no" campaign that are everywhere in Exarchia largely disappear among posh wine bars and boutique shops.
As he shared a cup of coffee with his cousin before attending Friday evening's "yes" rally, civil engineer Andreas Pierrakos said the choice in Sunday's plebiscite boiled down to whether Greece would remain a member in good standing of the group of 19 nations that share the euro currency and of the European Union.
"It's a matter of existence, of our future in the EU," said Pierrakos, 42. "There can be no Europe without Greece. But if Greece won't do what it takes to stay in, what do we do?"
Times staff writer Alexandra Zavis in Los Angeles contributed to this report.
=======
        <MainBody>Indians on social media mock Bobby Jindal candidacy
Bobby Jindal
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
Gov. Bobby Jindal announces his candidacy for the Republican presidential nomination in Kenner, La.
(Gerald Herbert / Associated Press)
As a rising power, India is obsessed with its image in the world, so the announcement of the first U.S. presidential candidate with Indian roots figured to create a stir.
It probably wasnt the kind Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal wanted.
Indians on Thursday roundly mocked Jindals campaign kickoff announcement, particularly for the 44-year-old Republicans line that he was tanned, rested and ready to run. It was widely seen as an attempt to play down his skin color to appeal to conservative voters, and fit with what Jindals critics say is a longstanding effort to disassociate himself from his Indian heritage.
The Twitter hashtag #BobbyJindalIsSoWhite trended in India for several hours.
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite that he couldn't win a spelling bee if he tried.
 VeeGee Narendra (@VeGeEn) June 25, 2015
#BobbyJindalIsSoWhite he's never been randomly selected at the airport
 Misha Choudhry (@MishaChoudhry) June 25, 2015
Some of Indias leading newspapers ran front-page mentions of Jindals announcement, although the coverage was less than effusive. Lalit K. Jha, longtime Washington correspondent for the Press Trust of India, wrote in a news report that Jindals announcement has failed to generate much enthusiasm among the Indian-Americans because of his recent statements in which he sought to distance himself from being an Indian-American.
Jindal was born in Louisiana in 1971 to Indian immigrants from the northern state of Punjab. As a child he changed his birth name, Piyush, to Bobby after the character from The Brady Bunch. Raised by devout Hindus, he converted to Catholicism as a teenager and says his faith inspires his conservative principles, including a staunch opposition to same-sex marriage.
Jindal invoked his parents at the start of his kickoff speech Wednesday but used the word India only once: in his oft-repeated accusation that Democrats were dividing the country along ethnic, gender and class lines.We are not Indian Americans, Irish Americans, African Americans, rich Americans or poor Americans, he said. We are all Americans.
Jindal enters the Republican presidential race near the bottom of the pack and has failed to inspire much support from U.S. voters of Indian origin, most of whom lean Democratic.
Bobby has never supported a single Indian issue, he refused to join the India Caucus when he was a congressman [on] Capitol Hill and is conspicuously absent from any event with a visiting Indian leader, Shashi Tharoor, an Indian politician and author, wrote in a recent book, India Shastra.
It is as if he wants to forget he is Indian, and would like voters to forget it too.
Jindal is an object of fascination for a rising Indian middle class that assiduously tracks their countrys stature in the world. When Prime Minister Narendra Modi led scores of countries in marking the first International Day of Yoga last weekend, many Indians beamed with pride.
But they are less charitable when it comes to Indians abroad who are seen to betray their heritage. Preet Bharara, the U.S. attorney in Manhattan, has received less than favorable press coverage for the perception that he has targeted Wall Street executives with South Asian roots, such as Sri Lankan-born hedge fund billionaire Raj Rajaratnam, for prosecution of financial crimes.
Young Indians flooded social media sites with sarcastic comments when Jindal unveiled his official governors portrait earlier this year because his skin looked shockingly white. A photo his office tweeted this week of his family playing Monopoly inspired mockery because his young children had their shoes on inside the house, a cultural no-no here.
 Gov. Bobby Jindal (@BobbyJindal) June 23, 2015
Mihir Sharma, a columnist for the Business Standard newspaper, accused Indian Americans of a tendency to turn viciously on those they see as less Indian. But even he balanced his words with a critique of the candidate.
Typical: smug Indians trying to shame Bobby Jindal for his choices on identity, and not his awful politics, Sharma tweeted.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
