<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Latimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wanderlust triathlon in Santa Monica to engage mind, body, spirit</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-he-wanderlust-20150502-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>If you haven't trained a whit, you still could finish a triathlon on May 2.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Wanderlust triathlon in Santa Monica to engage mind, body, spirit
Wanderlust triathlon
At a 2012 Wanderlust Festival in Lake Tahoe, it's yoga for everyone.
At a 2012 Wanderlust Festival in Lake Tahoe, it's yoga for everyone.
(5 Finger Photo)
Triathlon at Santa Monica Pier: 5K run, yoga, meditation
If you haven't trained a whit, you still could finish a triathlon on May 2.
0
The philosophy is a little different from many of the grueling races that usually include swimming, biking and running. "We place community above competition, inner peace above power, and self-awareness above strength," says the website for the event being put on by Wanderlust, which produces large-scale yoga events. It also includes live music and food and craft vendors.
A Wanderlust 108 mindful triathlon is scheduled in 15 cities in several countries this year. The 108, Wanderlust says, signifies the interconnection between body, mind and the universe in many Eastern traditions.
The entry fee is $60, and people can sign up at the pier starting at 9:30 a.m., with the first event starting at 11 a.m.
For more information, go to http://wanderlust.com/events .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florist to the mob had offers he couldn't refuse</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-na-mob-florist-20150501-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>When John Ferraro was a kid in the South Bronx, he thought arranging flowers was for girlie types.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Florist to the mob had offers he couldn't refuse
Florist to the mob
John M. Glionna / Los Angeles Times
Before moving to Nevada, florist John Ferraro worked for decades in the South Bronx, serving many customers who turned out to be wiseguys.
Before moving to Nevada, florist John Ferraro worked for decades in the South Bronx, serving many customers who turned out to be wiseguys. (John M. Glionna / Los Angeles Times)
Nation
Selling flowers is too girlie? Think again, says a florist who served tough guys and wiseguys
When John Ferraro was a kid in the South Bronx, he thought arranging flowers was for girlie types.
Boy, was he wrong.
Now 62, Ferraro is a slender man with a "New Yawka" accent who's been in the business for decades  the last 25 years in Las Vegas. He recently opened a shop in this bedroom community after a five-year hiatus from selling roses.
Ferraro works in an area known for its underworld roots, one that promotes its mob museum like Anaheim pitches Disneyland. But he was schooled in the world of organized crime long before he ever arranged a bouquet here.
He learned the trade in New York, where for 15 years he owned Bartel's flower shop in the South Bronx.
One lesson: Flower shops were often the domain of tough guys, or more specifically, wiseguys.
As a kid, I worked in a stable ripe with wiseguys. And I served coffee to clients of a basement bookie joint my friend's father used to run. - Florist John Ferraro
In the 1930s, Ferraro's Uncle Joe owned Marywell Florist, a suspected front for a racketeering operation run by mobster Dutch Schultz.
Over the years, guys got whacked  good customers Ferraro knew personally, such as Richard Costello, a union leader who patronized his shop for years. He and his son Richie were shot execution-style in the longshoreman's office, a crime police assumed was a hit by the Gambino crime family.
Those were the halcyon days in the old neighborhood, where guys in nice suits made deals you couldn't refuse. These days, Ferraro still flinches when he takes a call that begins, "Hey, Johnny, I got something for ya."
In the Bronx, his specialty was funerals. His shop was next door to a mortuary that funneled him clients.
Often, Ferraro didn't want to know any customer's back story. He never asked questions. But often he would read about a mob hit in the New York Daily News, and days later, he'd be fashioning wreaths for the grieving family.
Ferraro was an accidental florist.
One day, when he was 17, a guy in a bar offered him a job delivering roses. He refused: "I don't play with flowers."
Back then, Ferraro lived in tony Westchester County, N.Y., where his carpenter father had moved the family from the South Bronx.
But when it came to John, his father couldn't take the Bronx out of the boy.
"Tough guys seemed to pop up everywhere I went," he said, arranging flowers in his shop, Only Roses. "As a kid, I worked in a stable ripe with wiseguys. And I served coffee to clients of a basement bookie joint my friend's father used to run."
Flat broke, Ferraro took the job delivering flowers for an Italian widow and her daughter, who pressured him to start snipping petals. "I said, 'No. I don't touch flowers. I was hired as a driver.'"
Soon, the shop had a new owner named Victor, who couldn't tell a long-stemmed rose from a lead pipe. Victor, as they said in the neighborhood, was a piece of work, a scam artist looking for an easy score.
He once borrowed $700 from Ferraro for a can't-fail money-laundering scheme out of Switzerland that  you guessed it  failed. Victor had a rough side: Ferraro recalls him arguing at the shop with a brute called Charlie Big Bear, who soon turned up dead, shot seven times in a case that was never solved.
Victor eventually went to prison for tax evasion. Ferraro remembers the sheriff showing up at the shop, saying he had to padlock the place: government orders. The kid later slipped in through a side window and continued selling flowers.
One day, Victor called: "Hey, Johnny, I got something for ya."
He wanted to run a business from the joint, selling flowers to the wives and girlfriends of inmates. But Victor pocketed the money, often without ever even ordering the flowers.
In 1977, Ferraro quit flowers and moved to California.
But his wife, Cindy, got homesick and soon he was back in the Bronx, running Bartel's on Morris Park Avenue, angering his dad, who said he relocated the family for a reason.
Joe Ribustello, who ran the mortuary next door, was suspicious of the "snotty-nosed kid from Westchester," until he learned he was Joe's nephew.
He told Ferraro his Uncle Joe once saved his life from a mistaken mob hit.
The two forged a deal: Ferraro would get all the funeral work he could handle, "no kickback, no nothing," as long as he removed excess flowers and stands after every viewing.
At times, it seemed the wiseguys were everywhere.
Like the old man who passed the shop every day en route to his nearby coin store, which had no coins. His Aunt Mary, who worked in his store, would elbow Ferraro in the ribs.
"He's a big shot," she'd whisper.
Ferraro once saw mobster John Gotti emerge from his Lincoln and go into the mortuary  as surveillance photos were snapped from unmarked police cars across the street. Gotti bought his flowers from somebody else, Ferraro says.
Back then, the South Bronx was scene to so many burglaries that merchants barred their windows. But not Ferraro, who often forgot to lock his door.
But he was never hassled. He had a Godfather, perhaps: Richard Costello.
The union boss came in every holiday to order three $100 arrangements. Eventually, Ferraro had them ready when he walked in. Costello bought a gift for Ferraro's firstborn; he looked out for him.
And then he was dead.
In 1992, Ferraro sold his flower shop and moved to Las Vegas, seduced by the romance of the desert. Still, he misses his old haunts  all those characters and their inevitable funerals. It was good business.
Recently, a customer asked Ferraro whether he did burial flowers.
The florist smiled.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Julie Newmar invites you to dance into her private gardens</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-hm-newmar-garden-20150502-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>In a career that has stretched lithely across seven decades, Julie Newmar, the early blooming classical pianist and dancer who grew up to be TV's first feloniously feline Catwoman, has earned a Tony Award for her first speaking role on Broadway and received two U.S. patents for pantyhose and brassiere...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Julie Newmar invites you to dance into her private gardens
Caption Julie Newmar's garden
Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times
Julie Newmar stands beside the rose named for her. "It's like pale gold dipped in rubies," she says, "and the scent of it is an 11 out of 10."
Julie Newmar stands beside the rose named for her. "It's like pale gold dipped in rubies," she says, "and the scent of it is an 11 out of 10." (Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times)
Caption Julie Newmar's garden
Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times
A double-width chaise sits under a semi-fruitless olive tree. To the left, topiary boxwood and azaleas. At right, early summer blooming Peruvian daffodil and later summer blooming pink tropical Crinodonna lily.
A double-width chaise sits under a semi-fruitless olive tree. To the left, topiary boxwood and azaleas. At right, early summer blooming Peruvian daffodil and later summer blooming pink tropical Crinodonna lily. (Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times)
Caption Julie Newmar's garden
Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times
Outside the bay window of her living room, a seating area underneath a vine-covered pergola is surrounded by roses, pansies and a potted Eureka lemon tree.
Outside the bay window of her living room, a seating area underneath a vine-covered pergola is surrounded by roses, pansies and a potted Eureka lemon tree. (Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times)
Caption Julie Newmar's garden
Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times
"This is the plant hospital where begonias, herbal geraniums and orchids are recuperating," says landscape designer Bradley James Bontems. The sign is a gift from Newmar's mother-in-law.
"This is the plant hospital where begonias, herbal geraniums and orchids are recuperating," says landscape designer Bradley James Bontems. The sign is a gift from Newmar's mother-in-law. (Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times)
Caption Julie Newmar's garden
Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times
As seen from her front doorway, Newmar's porch and front garden are elevated above her driveway, providing a perch to look at her grounds.
As seen from her front doorway, Newmar's porch and front garden are elevated above her driveway, providing a perch to look at her grounds. (Francine Orr / Los Angeles Times)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>L.A.'s rich tradition of new music carries on</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-et-cm-lacma-mec-notebook-20150501-column.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Just as Hollywood stars are asked not to age, Los Angeles seems as though it will never lose its reputation as a town without a past. We came on the scene late culturally and believe ourselves always capable of reinvention. Tradition? That's so "Fiddler on the Roof."
  </Description>
        <MainBody>0
Curiously, the Monday concert was the least illuminating of the three events, but for all the right reasons. The series continues with its original exploratory mission. The program was devoted to Lewis Nielson, a composer who teaches at the Oberlin Conservatory of Music. His String Quartet No. 2: "Verge (remember)" received its first performance; "Herzplatten" for percussion, flute and voice and "Axis (sandman)" for string quintet and percussion were L.A. premieres.
Nielson has an ear for arresting sounds and he inspired terrific performances from the Formalist Quartet, percussionist Jonathan Hepfer and flutist-vocalist Alice Teyssier. But it was hard to know what Nielson was up to most of the time. His program notes read like attempts at obfuscation. At all times, there was the implication that something deep was happening but that is for academics, not an audience, to know.
Piano Spheres' program the next night at REDCAT introduced a young pianist, Nic Gerpe, who was, in contrast, wonderfully illuminating. His tone is crystalline. His technique is dazzlingly fluid. His program was starry and mystical, with Karol Szymanowski's dangerously sensual approach to Greek myth in "Mtopes" to the first astrological volume of George Crumb's "Makrokosmos" to the premiere of Juhi Bensal's shimmering "Land of Waking Dreams."
LACMA's Wednesday program only sideswiped the Monday Evening Concerts, but it usefully harked back to such overlooked aspects of the series as its investigation of little-known early music and its connection with film composers. Stravinsky's Septet, given a lively performance by Xtet, is based on Baroque forms. Schoenberg's Phantasy, played with engrossing expressivity by violinist Martin Chalifour and pianist Gavin Martin, has the dreamlike quality of a film montage.
That was also the likely motivation for including two of today's best-known L.A. composers, Morten Lauridsen and David Newman. The Angel City Choral offered warm performances of Lauridsen's "O Magnum Mysterium" and "Sure on This Shining Night," which have the essence of old music made shiningly new. Newman's "Renascence," sung by his daughter, Diana Newman, is the latest in a long line of concert works by Hollywood's best film composers  yet another Hollywood tradition.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Proposed bill on fighting wage theft is strong but needs more precision</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-ed-wage-theft-20150501-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>The California Legislature last year considered a bill that would have given workers a mechanism for collecting unpaid wages by filing a lien against their employer. It wasn't a perfect solution, but it would have made it harder for business owners to evade their obligations. The measure failed...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Proposed bill on fighting wage theft is strong but needs more precision
Higher wages and more protection for workers
Los Angeles Times
Labor groups and workers participate in a news conference on the steps of City Hall in October 2014. The demonstrators urged the City Council to raise the city's minimum wage.
Labor groups and workers participate in a news conference on the steps of City Hall in October 2014. The demonstrators urged the City Council to raise the city's minimum wage. (Los Angeles Times)
California workers lose up to $1.5 billion a year in unpaid wages, says U.S. Department of Labor
Only 17% of California workers who won back-wage judgments were able to collect, UCLA Labor Center says
The California Legislature last year considered a bill that would have given workers a mechanism for collecting unpaid wages by filing a lien against their employer. It wasn't a perfect solution, but it would have made it harder for business owners to evade their obligations. The measure failed to get enough traction for passage, though. Now Senate President Pro-Tem Kevin de Leon (D-Los Angeles) is revisiting the issue with an even better solution, putting the enforcement power in the hands of the state labor commissioner.
I purchased my first restaurant in 1985, and I am currently the managing partner of 11 restaurants in Los Angeles, including Bestia, Republique, Barrel and Ashes, Redbird and Pettycash. Like everyone in the service industry, I have a keen interest in the debate over whether and how to raise the... ( Bill Chait )
Workers in California lose up to $1.5 billion a year in unpaid wages, according to the federal Department of Labor. And a UCLA Labor Center study found that only 17% of workers who had won back-wage judgments were able to collect. In most cases, the offending employer simply closed up shop, often shifting operations to a new company.
0
SB 588 addresses the problem in two key ways. It would empower the labor commissioner to file claims directly against the business owner, rather than just the business, which means the obligation follows the offender. It also would allow the labor commissioner to seek payment from a new, related business if it does "substantially the same work in substantially the same working conditions under substantially the same supervisors" or if it engages in similar work with the original business' customer base. That wording gives us pause. It is intentionally vague in order to give the labor commissioner discretion in determining who is responsible for the owed wages. But vague wording can create unintended problems, and we believe the final measure should require a clearer link between the new business and the previous owner who failed to pay the wages, to preclude the innocent from being saddled with another person's debt.
The enforcement mechanism is strong. If, after appeals are exhausted, the employer still doesn't pay the back wages, the labor commissioner can file a lien or a stop-work order suspending business operations and demand a $150,000 bond to cover future wage-theft complaints.
Overall, this bill offers a reasonable recourse for workers who have been cheated out of their wages without burdening legitimate businesses.
Follow the Opinion section on Twitter @latimesopinion and Facebook
City Hall should hold the line on pay raises
After nearly a year of negotiations, Los Angeles city officials and the unions representing 20,000 city workers still haven't reached a deal on a new contract. One group of employees has even threatened to strike. The standoff is caused, in part, by the city's determination not to approve any raises...
Verizon picks a fight with ESPN over unbundled cable TV
Verizon isn't one of the biggest players in cable and satellite TV, but it picked what may be the most important fight in the industry this decade. Responding to consumers' demand for less expensive programming bundles, Verizon introduced a slimmed-down offering without the popular but costly ESPN...
What we pay for when we pay traffic tickets
About 80% of what you pay for a traffic ticket in California is not part of the base fine, but covers a variety of assessments and fees tacked on to pay for state and local programs. The State Penalty Assessment, for example, supports driver training, long-term care for those with traumatic brain...
Time to rein in California's traffic ticket surcharges
One reason you pay so much when you are ticketed for, say, driving with a broken taillight is that there's a surcharge added to your ticket to help victims of violent crimes. There's also an add-on that pays for training police officers, another to provide services to people with traumatic brain...
The problem with good guys vs. bad guys policing
No sentence gets spoken more at Homeboy Industries than this one: This is the longest I've ever been out. It is a refrain uttered by formerly gang-involved and serious and violent felons, in government parlance. These are not the nons, the nonviolent and nonserious offenders, but those who...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Billy Bob Thornton's Boxmasters wind up 'Somewhere Down the Road'</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-et-ms-boxmasters-billy-bob-thornton-20150501-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Given the band members' day jobs, it's a minor miracle that Billy Bob Thornton's band, the Boxmasters, ever finds time to record or tour.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Billy Bob Thornton's Boxmasters wind up 'Somewhere Down the Road'
Boxmasters
Christina House / For The Times
The Boxmasters: Brad Davis, left, Billy Bob "Bud" Thornton, J.D. Andrew and Teddy Andreadis in North Hollywood on March 31, 2015.
The Boxmasters: Brad Davis, left, Billy Bob "Bud" Thornton, J.D. Andrew and Teddy Andreadis in North Hollywood on March 31, 2015.
(Christina House / For The Times)
Billy Bob Thornton
Billy Bob Thornton's Boxmasters band has a new 2-CD set of roots-country/rock, 'Somewhere Down the Road'
Given the band members' day jobs, it's a minor miracle that Billy Bob Thornton's band, the Boxmasters, ever finds time to record or tour.
Not only does the quartet have a new studio album  "Somewhere Down the Road"  but it's a two-CD set comprising 22 original songs. One disc emphasizes the band's fascination with '60s L.A. rock and British Invasion music, and the other skews toward its penchant for roots-country music.
And that's not all.
I'll come into a session and these guys will be playing songs I've never even heard. I'll say, 'When did you guys write this? I haven't been gone that long!' - Teddy Andreadis, keyboardist
"We have five more albums in the can," said bassist-songwriter J.D. Andrew at a nondescript rehearsal space in North Hollywood just before the group was starting a monthlong run of shows through the Southwest, concluding with a Southern California stop Saturday in Temecula. Andrew co-produced the album with lead singer and drummer Bud Thornton, better known to most people as actor-writer-director Billy Bob Thornton when he's not busy with the Boxmasters.
"We record constantly," said Thornton, 59, after being the last to arrive for the rehearsal. He was all apologies  not a whiff of Hollywood ego in the air  explaining he'd gotten stuck in late-afternoon traffic trying to make his away across the L.A. Basin. While awaiting Thornton's arrival, lead guitarist Brad Davis sat on an equipment case in the hallway and picked a fleet acoustic rendition of the Stanley Brothers' bluegrass classic "A Man of Constant Sorrow."
8
"I'll come into a session and these guys will be playing songs I've never even heard," interjected keyboardist Teddy Andreadis, a busy session player in addition to his role in the Boxmasters. "I'll say, 'When did you guys write this? I haven't been gone that long!'"
If there were ever suspicions that the band was a vanity or novelty side project for Thornton, those suspicions have been dismissed after three solid studio albums  2008's "The Boxmasters"; a witty holiday album, "Christmas Cheer"; and "Modbilly" in 2009. The group gives Thornton a way to exercise the love for music that gripped him long before he ventured into acting, which he has said he fell into unintentionally.
Besides, there's a natural connection between the two avenues of creative exploration, one that's often evident in Thornton's evocative lyrics. There's a cinematic observer's eye at work in "Away, Away," which opens the album's atmospheric second disc, a song Thornton and Andrew wrote with steel guitarist Jon Rauhouse:
Wonder where that old smokin' truck is goin'
How much longer will that one taillight keep glowin'
How much pain has that tied-down mattress bedded
Where are that couple and those hollow-eyed children headed
The Boxmasters have little interest in songs about tailgate parties and leggy girls in cutoff jeans that often top the sales charts and commercial country radio playlists. Such songs, Andrew said, "are just denying what's going on in the world every chance they get."
0
Instead, they're working in the tradition of musical mavericks such as Waylon Jennings, Willie Nelson, Kris Kristofferson and Johnny Cash, surveying the world for stories of ordinary people. Sometimes, as in "Away, Away," it's to empathize with those who are struggling; in others, such as "What Did You Do Today," it's to challenge them to take responsibility for making a change:
Did you put all your thoughts together
And sit down and write a letter
Did you do anything tonight to make it better?
The latter, however, is not likely to be on the set list when the Boxmasters open for ZZ Top for a couple of dates. Thornton said they work from a variety of set lists depending on the size of the venue and the audience, which vary from rock clubs to venues such as the Monte de Oro Winery in Temecula.
This year, they said they plan to use the group's website to give their hardcore fans access to more of the still-unreleased material that's been piling up, as well as reissues of the four solo albums Thornton recorded from 2001 to 2007.
It's a balancing act, Thornton said, between wanting to share the multiple facets of the group's music with the public without oversaturating the market.
After releasing three albums on the folk-country Vanguard Records label, the Boxmasters recently signed with 101 Ranch Records. The Nashville-based boutique label is run by singer and songwriter Mark Collie, best known for his 1992 country hit "Even the Man in the Moon Is Crying," and his wife, Tammy, whom Thornton said have encouraged his group to follow their muse rather than chasing the latest trends.
"The thing about current Nashville ... is that it's a hit-making town," Thornton said. "Everybody goes in to write a hit. Well, how do you do that? You copy that guy's hit. As a result, for 20 years they've been doing the same song.
"There are a few people  Mark and Dwight [Yoakam] and two or three other guys maybe  Marty [Stuart], Steve Earle, Jim Lauderdale  that still do what they always did," he said. "There are some people that still write from their heart and soul and don't do it to make another Hula Hoop or tube of toothpaste or whatever it is they're manufacturing."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Verizon-ESPN dispute may pave way for a la carte pay-TV programming</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-fi-lazarus-20150501-column.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>There's a reason ESPN sicced its lawyers on Verizon this week, shattering any pretense of being part of a big, happy pay-TV family.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>0
At issue is the structure of the new package. Verizon is charging $55 a month for a base offering of 35 channels, including local stations and popular cable channels such as CNN, AMC and Food Network.
As part of the deal, subscribers can pick two of seven additional programming packs, depending on their viewing preferences, at no additional charge. These extra tiers include kid-friendly channels, news and, yes, sports.
"ESPN is disputing whether channels can be tiered," said Greenfield at BTIG. "Verizon is saying that it's just a customizable package."
Nuance is everything here.
If ESPN's contract requires that its channels be part of a pay-TV company's basic offering  that is, you have to get them no matter what  the network will argue in court that Verizon's customization violates that agreement.
Verizon will counter that because ESPN is still available to anyone who wants it at no additional charge, it's still technically part of the basic offering.
"We believe that we are allowed to offer these packages under our existing contracts," Verizon's chief financial officer, Fran Shammo, said in a conference call this week.
More to the point, she said: "Look, this is a product that the consumer wants. If you look at the TV bundles today, most people only on average watch 17 channels. So this is a way to give consumers what they want."
That's also an open question. Verizon's so-called skinny bundle could end up saving people a few bucks a month, but maybe not as much as the loss of dozens of channels might suggest.
The skinny bundle also remains a ways off from true a la carte programming that many consumers say they'd prefer  allowing them to pay only for the channels they want, picking each individually.
Analyst Michael Nathanson at media and telecom research firm MoffettNathanson wrote that it's unclear what Verizon hopes to gain "from going to war with their largest content providers."
He speculated that Verizon may be trying to light a fire under lawmakers and regulators to loosen pay-TV rules and move the entire industry closer to a la carte.
I'm not sure the deep thinkers at Verizon are that smart. I suspect they, like everyone else in the pay-TV business, know that the days of fat programming bundles are numbered.
My guess is they figured they had little to lose in pushing back against the old way of doing things. The cord-cutting will continue, and momentum will build for giving consumers more pay-TV choices. Verizon wants to appear that it's leading the trend.
Even so, you have to wonder about the company's chances in court. If ESPN's contract was as flexible as Verizon seems to think, other pay-TV companies would be running to Verizon's side, and they're not.
But Verizon nonetheless makes an important point: There are other, potentially better ways of offering pay-TV to consumers.
In that sense, Verizon can already score this as a win.
David Lazarus' column runs Tuesdays and Fridays. He also can be seen daily on KTLA-TV Channel 5 and followed on Twitter @Davidlaz. Send your tips or feedback to david.lazarus@latimes.com .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>When Manny Pacquiao fights, it's a Philippine holiday</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-me-beat-pacquiao-faithful-20150501-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Order $60 worth of Filipino favorites to go at Max's of Manila in Glendale on Saturday and you get to take home a special "knockout treat:" a free, family-size, deep-fried pork leg called a crispy pata. But make plans to sit down at Max's that night for sisig or kare kare and you're likely to find...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>When Manny Pacquiao fights, it's a Philippine holiday
Manny Pacquiao
Christina House / For The Times
Manny Pacquiao signs a poster for a fan as he leaves Wild Card Boxing Gym in Hollywood on April 27, before heading to Las Vegas.
Manny Pacquiao signs a poster for a fan as he leaves Wild Card Boxing Gym in Hollywood on April 27, before heading to Las Vegas. (Christina House / For The Times)
Blockbuster
In the Philippines, it's like a holiday when Manny Pacquiao fights. For Filipinos here, it's much the same
Order $60 worth of Filipino favorites to go at Max's of Manila in Glendale on Saturday and you get to take home a special "knockout treat:" a free, family-size, deep-fried pork leg called a crispy pata. But make plans to sit down at Max's that night for sisig or kare kare and you're likely to find the lights off and the front door locked.
It is like a holiday, even the president is going to watch. - Noly Bautista
There's really no point for a Filipino restaurant to stay open when Manny Pacquiao is fighting, says host Noly Bautista  unless it is planning to screen the pay-per-view fight in HD. When the pride of the Philippines faces Floyd Mayweather, well, forget about it. Closing time will be three or four hours earlier than usual.
In the Philippines, when Pacquiao enters the ring, "it is like a holiday, even the president is going to watch," Bautista said. For Filipinos here, it's not much different.
Pacquiao is his country's biggest star  not just a boxer but a basketball player, movie actor, congressman and good Samaritan.
"He's a Christian and he's a helping heart," said Bautista, who left Manila seven years ago to try his luck in the United States. He plans to gather with at least 20 friends and family members to feast and watch the fight Saturday night.
8
Most cable and satellite TV companies are charging customers who want to get the match at home about $100. If that sounds steep, it's really not if you use Filipino math, said one employee at Seafood City Supermarket in Eagle Rock Plaza who asked that his name not be used because he was on the clock.
"For Filipinos generally, it's not one household paying," he said. "Whoever has the biggest TV, the biggest kitchen, the biggest living room  everyone's going to converge there to watch."
It's also an excuse to gather and to cook and eat a lot, so Seafood City expects a run on such favorites as pork belly and spare ribs.
"It's going to be crazy here. Mangoes will be flying off the roof," he said.
Seafood City  which promises "True Filipino Goodness"  is a food emporium for the homesick. On display at the ends of the aisles near the cash registers this week were neat rows of bottled banana ketchup, cans of coconut milk and bags of noodles known as pancit bihon.
Some now call Eagle Rock Plaza the "mall of Manila" because of its many Filipino shops, including fast-food, a bakery and multiple companies offering flights and money services.
0
At the kiosks outside the supermarket, Pinoy Blockbuster pitched Filipino programming on DIRECTV. Go Phone-Card Outlet, which sells Philippines-focused SIM cards and phone packages, was hawking a T-shirt with a photo of a bare-chested, fierce-looking Pacquiao above the words Laban Para Sa Pinoy or, roughly, "fight for the Filipino people." The shirt was free with the purchase of a monthly calling plan.
We are praying for your victory, Manny! - An ad from a Panorama City doctor's office
While munching on Chickenjoy fried chicken at Jollibee or purple yam-filled pastries at Leelin Bakery &amp; Cafe, shoppers perused a variety of free Filipino American newspapers featuring plentiful Pacquiao news. In the Asian Journal's commemorative issue, "The Fight of the Century: Pacquiao vs. Mayweather," they could find an exclusive interview with the Filipino dentist who'd made Pacquiao a special mouth guard in the red, white, blue and yellow of the Philippine flag.
Many businesses had taken out ads in support of their champ: "All for His Glory, We are Praying for you!" from a Burbank real estate company; "We are praying for your victory, Manny!" from a Panorama City doctor's office; "Godspeed, Manny!" from Leelin, in a half-page tribute.
Leelin was the first of many stops Joey Nodalo planned to make to prepare for the fight.
He had driven from Visalia, where he runs a restaurant called BFF, as in "Best Filipino Food." He had so many orders for the big event, he said, that he had to come south for supplies.
At the bakery, Nodalo was getting rolls of embutido, a Filipino meatloaf. He had to fetch fish too, and many, many Manila mangoes.
All the trouble was worth it, he said, because whenever Pacquiao fights, "it's the one time we're doing good, we're earning."
There was another fight-night benefit: He had multiple viewing invitations from his customers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amid drought, the West is no place for a lawn, as Nevada has learned</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-na-vegas-lawns-20150501-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>When Gov. Jerry Brown ordered that California rip up 50 million square feet of lawns to conserve water amid the West's deadening drought, the Golden State gasped.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Amid drought, the West is no place for a lawn, as Nevada has learned
Las Vegas replaces lawns
David McNew / Getty Images
In Las Vegas, the traditional American front lawn has largely given way to desert-compatible landscaping, as seen here in 2004.
In Las Vegas, the traditional American front lawn has largely given way to desert-compatible landscaping, as seen here in 2004.
(David McNew / Getty Images)
California confronts what Nevada has learned: Drought and lawns are incompatible
In arid Western states, changing landscaping means changing mind-set
Las Vegas has ripped out 4,000 acres of lawn space, with plans to remove 3,000 more
When Gov. Jerry Brown ordered that California rip up 50 million square feet of lawns to conserve water amid the West's deadening drought, the Golden State gasped.
Meanwhile, the Silver State yawned.
Desert denizens have already been there and done that  since 1999, in fact.
A near-continuous population boom has long driven officials here to seek water-saving solutions to slake the region's thirst. Using community outreach and cash incentives, the area's Water Smart Landscaping Program has removed nearly 4,000 acres  173 million square feet  of lawn space.
That's enough to cover nearly 3,000 football fields, or stretch an 18-inch-wide strip of backyard sod almost entirely around the planet.
Caption California lawn, 1924
Women play mahjong on a California lawn.
Women play mahjong on a California lawn. (Underwood Archives / Getty Images)
Underwood Archives / Getty Images
Ballerina and actress Vera Zorina exercises on the lawn of her Beverly Hills home.
Ballerina and actress Vera Zorina exercises on the lawn of her Beverly Hills home. (Underwood Archives / Getty Images)
Caption California lawn, 1955
Gene Lester / Getty Images
Walt Disney sits on a lawn with his grandson in front of Disneyland's castle in 1955, the year the park opened in Anaheim.
Walt Disney sits on a lawn with his grandson in front of Disneyland's castle in 1955, the year the park opened in Anaheim. (Gene Lester / Getty Images)
Children play in a Studio City backyard.
Children play in a Studio City backyard. (Gene Lester / Getty Images)
Mel Melcon / Los Angeles Times
Walter Hill waters the lawn in front of his Newbury Park home.
Walter Hill waters the lawn in front of his Newbury Park home. (Mel Melcon / Los Angeles Times)
Across the West, a chronic water shortage may yield what was once unthinkable: The American lawn, that domestic decoration greening the nation's suburban tracts, could become an ornament of the past, at least this side of the Rockies.
But changing the landscaping means changing the mind-set.
"Looking at the lawn in the context of the drought, what was ridiculous has become indefensible," said author Michael Pollan, who has written about his boyhood experiences with the family lawn. "It's a wasteful way of treating the land."
He tore up the front lawn of his Berkeley home in 2006, replacing it with a vegetable garden.
"They're absolutely absurd, but we love them," Pollan said. "In the arid West, we will one day look back on lawns like we now do littering, smoking in bars and public urination."
In southern Nevada, this has been a hard sell. Many natives insisted they were entitled to their lawns, drought be damned. Transplants wanted to keep a grassy aesthetic they'd grown up with in Chicago or Charlottesville.
8
"We reminded everyone they live in the Mojave Desert," said Bronson Mack, a spokesman for the Southern Nevada Water Authority, an umbrella group comprising seven water agencies. "We had to find a way to make them rethink the best use of grass in an arid environment."
After years of gentle prodding that included common-sense community seminars on water-saving tips, many Las Vegas lawns have now morphed into environmentally sustainable spaces with desert landscaping. "In the long run, many homeowners realized they weren't really using the grass until they pushed a lawn mower across it," Mack said.
Even before Brown's order, some of California's 411 water districts offered rebates -- now as much as $3.75 per square foot -- to persuade homeowners to give up on grass.
The Southern Nevada Water Authority pays $1.50 per square foot of lawn replaced with desert landscaping, up to 5,000 square feet. After that, it's $1 per square foot. Arizona and Utah also have lawn rebate programs.
Looking at the lawn in the context of the drought, what was ridiculous has become indefensible. It's a wasteful way of treating the land. - Michael Pollan, author who has written about his boyhood experiences with the family lawn
The message: Don't "feed it!" as the TV lawn-care pitchman purrs in his Scottish brogue. Replace it. Or at least downsize it.
"You don't need wall-to-wall carpeting if an area rug will do," Mack said.
Las Vegas has become an unlikely water-saving mentor  visited by fact-finding groups from South Korea, Israel and neighboring California.
"We went to Las Vegas before we started our program," said Penny Falcon, water conservation policy manager at the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power, which has pushed lawn makeovers since 2009. "What they were doing just made sense."
In addition to paying rebates, the Southern Nevada Water Authority sponsors landscaping contests and offers homeowners free, downloadable designs, divvied into categories, such as "pool-friendly" and "child-friendly."
We removed out lawn about a year and a half ago. Great decision. Besides the water savings, no crabgrass, no mowing, no brown spots. So easy. We have a mix of desert rocks and drought tolerant plants. Very easy
TKLA-67
3
Las Vegas officials say they have removed nearly 4,000 acres of grass, with plans to rip up 3,000 more. In Los Angeles, officials want to take out 25 million square feet of grass by year's end.
But there's push-back from the $25-billion-a-year grass industry, which says lawns are good for the environment, producing oxygen, preventing soil erosion and dissipating heat.
"Kids play on lawns, dogs walk on them, you can lay down there in the summer and read a book," said Jim King, a spokesman for the Miracle-Gro company. "We believe there is a future for lawns in the western U.S. They're just going to look a little different."
Miracle-Gro officials and others met with Brown recently to discuss conservation steps, King said. Experts say too many homeowners wastefully over-water their grass. Still, there has been progress.
"A decade ago, it was all about having the best lawn on the block," King said. "Now people know a lawn doesn't have to be weed-free. It doesn't have to be the greenest or the thickest. People let their lawns go brown in the dormant season without worrying it's going to die."
Turf-grass sod has been around for eons: Grass allowed native hunters to stalk their prey on the African savannas. In medieval Europe, low-growing perennial turf grasses filled spaces around castles, helping watchmen scan the horizon.
Lawns appeared in European Renaissance paintings from the 15th century, before the concept was brought to North America by the first settlers. The poet William Wordsworth once called turf grass "a carpet all alive."
The mechanical first lawn mower was invented by Edwin Beard Budding in 1830. Decades later, mass production made mowers affordable to the masses, making grass an essential part of the American domestic landscape. Today, 80% of U.S. homes have lawns, industry officials say.
But they're not the right landscaping for all of America, critics say.
"Lawns should have never come west of the Rocky Mountains," said Diana Balmori, a New York-based landscape architect and author of "Redesigning the American Lawn."
The average rainfall in New York City, she said, is about 50 inches a year, compared with 15 inches in Los Angeles. Meanwhile, in places like Las Vegas, which receives less than 5 inches annually, a single square foot of lawn requires 55 gallons of water each year.
"We have to learn to fit into our place on Earth," Balmori said. "To take green grass and apply it worldwide does not work."
It didn't work for North Las Vegas homeowner Ron Newsome, so he installed what he calls "the carpet."
"No one can believe I could have grass like this in the middle of the desert," said the 53-year-old Chicago transplant. "You can't tell it's not real until you get real close."
Newsome did the work himself, spending $2,200. He soon received a $900 cash rebate. He now uses 8,000 gallons of water per month, rather than 26,000.
Best of all, he said, is foiling "the neighborhood Houdinis"  the unleashed dogs that used his lawn as a public toilet. They don't like the faux grass.
"They take a sniff and move on," he said. "They do their business elsewhere."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Verizon picks a fight with ESPN over unbundled cable TV</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-ed-verizon-espn-20150501-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Verizon isn't one of the biggest players in cable and satellite TV, but it picked what may be the most important fight in the industry this decade. Responding to consumers' demand for less expensive programming bundles, Verizon introduced a slimmed-down offering without the popular but costly ESPN...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Verizon picks a fight with ESPN over unbundled cable TV
Verizon
A Verizon technician installs fiber-optic lines in Somerville, N.J., in 2009.
A Verizon technician installs fiber-optic lines in Somerville, N.J., in 2009. (Mel Evans / Associated Press)
Pay-TV operators can't keep charging more for bundles filled with channels people don't watch
FiOS TV gives consumers the unusual ability to edit the once-inviolable basic programming tier
Verizon isn't one of the biggest players in cable and satellite TV, but it picked what may be the most important fight in the industry this decade. Responding to consumers' demand for less expensive programming bundles, Verizon introduced a slimmed-down offering without the popular but costly ESPN sports network, which was relegated to an optional sports package. The move drew a lawsuit from ESPN, which alleged that Verizon is violating its contract with the network.
There are many reasons Comcast came up empty in its bid to buy Time Warner Cable, including an administration that's hostile to telecommunications mergers, a nearly empty reservoir of goodwill among cable TV consumers and a howling mass of Internet users freaked out by the prospect of a single... ( Jon Healey )
In one sense, the battle is a simple dispute over the provisions of a contract. In another, however, it's part of a bigger struggle to change an aging business model in the face of the public's growing desire and ability to pay only for the entertainment it wants.
0
The new "Custom TV" offering by Verizon, whose FiOS TV service has 5.7 million subscribers isn't exactly cheap at $55 a month. But it does give consumers the unusual ability to edit the once-inviolable basic programming tier, cutting its cost by excluding groups of networks that they don't watch (for example, sports channels or kids programming). NBCUniversal and 21st Century Fox complained that this violated their contracts; ESPN not only complained, it sued.
The sad reality for Verizon and other pay-TV companies is that the handful of media conglomerates that own the vast majority of popular networks have enormous leverage when it comes to negotiating distribution deals. Those conglomerates are the driving force behind overstuffed and expensive programming tiers. Cable and satellite companies were happy to go along while their customer bases were growing, but the numbers are slowly heading in the opposite direction now as more consumers balk at paying cable bills that average more than $92 per month .
Comcast sought more leverage over the conglomerates by buying Time Warner Cable, only to have the deal collapse in the face of regulators' opposition. Now Verizon is trying a new tack. "Custom TV" may not survive, but smaller bundles are already popping up online from the likes of Sling TV, Sony and, soon, Apple. Cable and satellite seem sure to follow suit, although they're more likely to do it by pushing out networks less popular and powerful than ESPN. Pay-TV operators can't keep charging more for bundles filled with channels people don't watch, not when a growing number of creators and networks are making their work available online to those who'll accept fewer channels for a much lower price.
Follow the Opinion section on Twitter @latimesopinion and Facebook
With millennials gaining influence, surveillance reform is inevitable
About a year ago, a thirtysomething sculptor in Los Angeles began working on a bust of Edward Snowden. When he was done, he shipped the bust to his artist friends on the East Coast. Just before dawn April 6, the artists crept under cover of darkness into Brooklyn's Fort Greene Park and installed...
Proposed bill on fighting wage theft is strong but needs more precision
The California Legislature last year considered a bill that would have given workers a mechanism for collecting unpaid wages by filing a lien against their employer. It wasn't a perfect solution, but it would have made it harder for business owners to evade their obligations. The measure failed...
What we pay for when we pay traffic tickets
About 80% of what you pay for a traffic ticket in California is not part of the base fine, but covers a variety of assessments and fees tacked on to pay for state and local programs. The State Penalty Assessment, for example, supports driver training, long-term care for those with traumatic brain...
Time to rein in California's traffic ticket surcharges
One reason you pay so much when you are ticketed for, say, driving with a broken taillight is that there's a surcharge added to your ticket to help victims of violent crimes. There's also an add-on that pays for training police officers, another to provide services to people with traumatic brain...
The problem with good guys vs. bad guys policing
No sentence gets spoken more at Homeboy Industries than this one: This is the longest I've ever been out. It is a refrain uttered by formerly gang-involved and serious and violent felons, in government parlance. These are not the nons, the nonviolent and nonserious offenders, but those who...
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
