<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Latimes">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Frederik Andersen maintains his confidence, as do his Ducks teammates</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-sp-ducks-blackhawks-elliott-20150527-column.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Every good goaltender takes every goal scored against him as a personal insult. The best goalies learn to quickly forget the ones that got away, knowing they can't waste energy brooding over events they can't change.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>"I think there's things we can clean up, but they're here for a reason too. They're a great hockey team," Ducks defenseman Cam Fowler said. "You have to expect them to get their chances, as well."
For the Ducks, Andersen's numbers are less important than his composure and the confidence he gives them.
"When Freddie's at his best he seems to have this calmness about him," Fowler said. "He goes about his business. But the main thing that you get from him being back there is a sense of security. He seems to always be dialed in.
"I don't see any fatigue, really. There's going to be bounces that happen throughout a playoff series, there's going to be things that you don't want to happen, there's going to be mistakes that are made. That's us as a team. We go through those things as a team. It's not an individual thing. ... Freddie's our rock back there. He's a huge reason why we're here and why we're in this position."
Coach Bruce Boudreau acknowledged that of Chicago's goals in Game 5, "There's some that he'd like to have back, I think." But he, too, expressed trust in Andersen.
"Nobody's perfect," Boudreau said. "Freddie's really good. He's not perfect. None of our players are perfect. They make mistakes. We have the faith and confidence in him that he's going to be great again [Wednesday]."
It's significant that Boudreau, known for switching goalies in midstream in past playoffs, repeated his support for Andersen. "We're not changing anything. We're going with Freddie. He's our guy," Boudreau said.
Andersen wants to repay that faith. "I know how good I can be and I've showed that. Maybe last game wasn't my best but that stuff happens to any goalie," Andersen said. "It's about what you do next that matters."
What he does will go a long way toward determining if the Ducks seize this chance to advance or let it get away, like those goals in Games 4 and 5.
Follow Helene Elliott on Twitter @helenenothelen
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nuclear talks bogging down as Iran balks at key decisions, envoys say</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-fg-iran-talks-bog-down-20150526-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Talks over Iran’s nuclear program are bogging down because Tehran’s negotiators are reluctant to put in writing previous concessions that may be deeply unpopular at home, current and former diplomats said Tuesday.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Nuclear talks bogging down as Iran balks at key decisions, envoys say
Iranian supreme leader Ali Khamenei
Office of the Iranian supreme leader
Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has vowed that he will not allow international inspection of Iran's military sites or access to Iranian scientists under any nuclear agreement.
Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has vowed that he will not allow international inspection of Iran's military sites or access to Iranian scientists under any nuclear agreement.
(Office of the Iranian supreme leader)
With one month before deadline, negotiations over Iran's nuclear program are slowing
Iranian nuclear negotiators reluctant to commit in writing on issues that are politically explosive at home
Talks over Irans nuclear program are bogging down because Tehrans negotiators are reluctant to put in writing previous concessions that may be deeply unpopular at home, current and former diplomats said Tuesday.
With the negotiations June 30 deadline about a month away, the Iranian team is balking at important decisions, saying it wants to leave them for top officials who are to arrive just before the deadline, Gerard Araud, the French ambassador to the United States, said on a panel at the Atlantic Council think tank in Washington.
President Obama took his case for nuclear talks with Iran to a local synagogue Friday where he promised he would not make a bad deal with the Islamic Republic in part because he wouldnt want to bear the shame. ( Christi Parsons )
As a result, it is now very likely that deal won't be completed until early July, Araud said. If an agreement is reached, additional time may be required to put the general terms of the deal into specific technical language, he said.
It's going to be extremely complicated, he said. We could have a sort of fuzzy end to the negotiations.
8
The United States and five other world powers have been trying to negotiate a deal with Iran that would give the Middle East nation relief from economic sanctions if it agrees to restrictions aimed at preventing it from obtaining a nuclear weapon.
The negotiating group, which includes France, Germany, Britain, Russia and China, reached a preliminary agreement April 2.
Yet the slowdown is a sign of trouble, reflecting the fact that the Iranian elite remains deeply divided on key aspects of the deal.
Richard Nephew, a sanctions expert and a former member of the U.S. team of negotiators, said he believes the biggest potential stumbling block is whether international inspectors will have access to Iranian military bases. In Tehran, hard-liners and military officials  and at times Iran's supreme leader  have declared that such access would violate the Islamic Republics sovereignty and would never be acceptable.
But Western governments view access to the bases as an essential part of any deal because of the need for full transparency to ensure that Iran is not secretly working on a nuclear weapon, said Nephew, who is with Columbia University's Center on Global Energy Policy.
Just a dog and pony show, the republicans adopted president , Nut N U, will never allow it . And Obama is doing the Michel Jackson moon walk
Preci Gil
1
Until now, Iranian negotiators have been able to finesse several sticky issues because they haven't had to commit their verbal agreements in writing. But that's changing, as negotiators are required to fill in the technical language of an agreement, he said.
If the political environment in Tehran can't support agreement on this, things will fall apart, Nephew said.
He said he believed the Obama administration would not accept a deal without full transparency because such an agreement couldn't be sold in the United States or in European capitals.
This is nonnegotiable, from Washington's point of view, he said.
But the Iranians also feel strongly about it, Nephew said, because access to bases would mean that inspectors would be peering at Iran's defenses at a time when U.S. officials are saying publicly that they reserve the right to bomb the country if necessary to halt its nuclear program.
Peter Wittig, Germany's ambassador to the United States, who also appeared at the Atlantic Council, also noted the slowdown in the talks, saying they had been proceeding at a rather slow pace on the expert level.
The most difficult path may lie ahead of us, he said.
Another contentious issue that remains is the pace at which Iran would receive relief from sanctions. Iranian officials have demanded that sanctions relief come soon after the agreement is reached.
But Wittig said that sanctions might not be lifted at all this year because of the requirement that Iran first scale back its nuclear program and that United Nations inspectors then verify that it has done so.
Iran needs some time to start the implementation of the agreement, Wittig said. So in the best case, sanctions relief would not happen before the end of this year.
For more on the Iran talks and other foreign policy news, follow @richtpau
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Angels' Mike Trout says he'll never skip All-Star Game if selected</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-sp-sn-angels-mike-trout-all-star-game-20150526-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Whether Mike Trout truly succeeds Derek Jeter as the face of baseball remains to be seen. But Trout made a proclamation reminiscent of his childhood idol Tuesday, when he vowed never to skip the All-Star Game.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Milwaukee outfielder Khris Davis put his foot down directly in the middle of home plate after trotting around the bases following his third-inning home run Sunday against San Francisco pitcher Tim Lincecum. Too bad Davis wasn't that exact two innings earlier after his first home run of the day... ( Chuck Schilken )
"I'll never do that," Trout said. "You play baseball to win a championship, but there are things that come along with that. For me, it's a special honor."
Perhaps the most famous rhyme in All-Star history was uttered by St. Louis Cardinals shortstop Garry Templeton in 1979, selected as a reserve. "If I ain't startin', I ain't departin,' " Templeton said.
For some players fortunate enough to appear in multiple All-Star games, the novelty wears off and the four days off are preferred.
"You want to be there," Trout said. "It's a fun four days. It's great to be part of it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>L.A. County supervisors delay vote on water cuts after complaints</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-me-ln-county-water-restrictions-20150526-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Los Angeles County supervisors agreed Tuesday to postpone a vote on proposed water use restrictions for customers served by the county waterworks districts after residents expressed alarm at the reductions and questioned the method used to calculate target levels. 
  </Description>
        <MainBody>L.A. County supervisors delay vote on water cuts after complaints
Water Sprinkler
Rich Pedroncelli / Associated Press
Some L.A. County water customers who had been notified they would have to cut their usage by as much as 80% said the numbers had been miscalculated or that the formula was unfair to people with larger families.
Some L.A. County water customers who had been notified they would have to cut their usage by as much as 80% said the numbers had been miscalculated or that the formula was unfair to people with larger families.
(Rich Pedroncelli / Associated Press)
L.A. County residents contest calculations in proposed water conservation plan
L.A. County supervisors postpone vote on water restrictions after residents raise concerns
Los Angeles County supervisors agreed Tuesday to postpone a vote on proposedwater use restrictions for customersserved by the county waterworks districts after residents expressed alarm at the reductions and questioned the method used to calculate target levels.
Read more stories
Under the county's proposed plan, water customers in Marina del Rey, Kagel Canyon,Val Verde and Acton wouldhave to reduce their use 25%. Customers in the Antelope Valley would have to reduce their use 32% and those in Malibu and Topanga would be required to cut back 36% or pay significantly higher rates for any excess.
The restrictions would impact about 250,000peoplethroughout the system, the majority of them in the Antelope Valley and Malibu.
Users who do not reduce their water consumption would pay substantial penalties. The water use target for most residential users would be calculated based on the average usage for the area in 2013. Rates will double for water use above the target and triple if use exceeds 115% of the target.
The proposed conservation plan came in response to an emergency executive order issued by California Gov. Jerry Brown in April, requiring a 25% statewide reduction in urban water usebecause of the state's ongoing drought. The reduction required for individual cities and communities was calculated based on their 2013 use.
Some customers who had been notified they would have to cut their usage by as much as 80% said the numbers had been miscalculated or that the formula -- which is based on average water use in each district -- was unfair to people with larger families. Several also said that the notices they received of Tuesday's hearing incorrectly stated the timeof the meeting.
Andrew Chadd of Littlerock, an unincorporated area in Antelope Valley, said he had been notified his family would have to cut their use by 70%.Chadd said his family's bill could jump from$200 to $700 every two months.
"All my neighbors are single people and there are a couple [of] couples -- we have seven in the household," he said. "We were trying to figure out last night how we can do this and who's going to tell the kids that they can only use the bathroom on Monday and Friday."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Housing first' isn't a novel strategy on homelessness</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-le-0527-wednesday-housing-first-20150527-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>To the editor: The article about the tremendous success of "housing first" in Utah eloquently describes how that approach is the real solution to chronic homelessness. Utah's success is indeed noteworthy, but its effort is not truly novel.  ("Utah is winning the war on chronic homelessness with...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Immigration and the drought: How many newcomers can California tolerate?
To the editor: Apparently Stanford academic Victor Davis Hanson and his fellow travelers at Californians for Population Stabilization (CAPS) have stumbled onto the root cause of our drought: foreign-born immigrants. How foolish of the rest of us to think it was a lack of rain and snow. ("Group...
If Obama can't execute his strategy against Islamic State, what good is it?
To the editor: Doyle McManus quotes former U.S. Ambassador to Iraq Ryan C. Crocker as saying about the fight against Islamic State, "The administration's strategy is a good strategy  but it only gets done if you actually do it." ("Obama has a strategy for fighting ISIS -- one that isn't working,"...
'Buddhist Bin Laden': Myanmar's hate-mongering monk
To the editor: In the 1990s, more than 800,000 people were killed in Rwanda in a matter of months. This century now commences with probably the first Buddhist hate-monger in history. ("Monk dubbed 'Buddhist Bin Laden' targets Myanmar's persecuted Muslims," May 24)
The American spirit is alive -- in Ireland
To the editor: Ireland's minister for health called his country's referendum on same-sex marriage "a beacon, a light to the rest of the world, of liberty and equality." ("Ireland is first country to legalize same-sex marriage in popular vote," May 23)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Immigration and the drought: How many newcomers can California tolerate?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-le-0527-wednesday-immigration-drought-20150527-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>To the editor: Apparently Stanford academic Victor Davis Hanson and his fellow travelers at Californians for Population Stabilization (CAPS) have stumbled onto the root cause of our drought: foreign-born immigrants. How foolish of the rest of us to think it was a lack of rain and snow.  ("Group...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>'Housing first' isn't a novel strategy on homelessness
To the editor: The article about the tremendous success of "housing first" in Utah eloquently describes how that approach is the real solution to chronic homelessness. Utah's success is indeed noteworthy, but its effort is not truly novel. ("Utah is winning the war on chronic homelessness with...
If Obama can't execute his strategy against Islamic State, what good is it?
To the editor: Doyle McManus quotes former U.S. Ambassador to Iraq Ryan C. Crocker as saying about the fight against Islamic State, "The administration's strategy is a good strategy  but it only gets done if you actually do it." ("Obama has a strategy for fighting ISIS -- one that isn't working,"...
'Buddhist Bin Laden': Myanmar's hate-mongering monk
To the editor: In the 1990s, more than 800,000 people were killed in Rwanda in a matter of months. This century now commences with probably the first Buddhist hate-monger in history. ("Monk dubbed 'Buddhist Bin Laden' targets Myanmar's persecuted Muslims," May 24)
The American spirit is alive -- in Ireland
To the editor: Ireland's minister for health called his country's referendum on same-sex marriage "a beacon, a light to the rest of the world, of liberty and equality." ("Ireland is first country to legalize same-sex marriage in popular vote," May 23)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Buddhist Bin Laden': Myanmar's hate-mongering monk</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-le-0527-wednesday-myanmar-monk-20150527-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>To the editor: In the 1990s, more than 800,000 people were killed in Rwanda in a matter of months. This century now commences with probably the first Buddhist hate-monger in history.  ("Monk dubbed 'Buddhist Bin Laden' targets Myanmar's persecuted Muslims," May 24)
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Immigration and the drought: How many newcomers can California tolerate?
To the editor: Apparently Stanford academic Victor Davis Hanson and his fellow travelers at Californians for Population Stabilization (CAPS) have stumbled onto the root cause of our drought: foreign-born immigrants. How foolish of the rest of us to think it was a lack of rain and snow. ("Group...
'Housing first' isn't a novel strategy on homelessness
To the editor: The article about the tremendous success of "housing first" in Utah eloquently describes how that approach is the real solution to chronic homelessness. Utah's success is indeed noteworthy, but its effort is not truly novel. ("Utah is winning the war on chronic homelessness with...
If Obama can't execute his strategy against Islamic State, what good is it?
To the editor: Doyle McManus quotes former U.S. Ambassador to Iraq Ryan C. Crocker as saying about the fight against Islamic State, "The administration's strategy is a good strategy  but it only gets done if you actually do it." ("Obama has a strategy for fighting ISIS -- one that isn't working,"...
The American spirit is alive -- in Ireland
To the editor: Ireland's minister for health called his country's referendum on same-sex marriage "a beacon, a light to the rest of the world, of liberty and equality." ("Ireland is first country to legalize same-sex marriage in popular vote," May 23)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>If Obama can't execute his strategy against Islamic State, what good is it?</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-le-0527-wednesday-isis-strategy-20150527-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>To the editor: Doyle McManus quotes former U.S. Ambassador to Iraq Ryan C. Crocker as saying about the fight against Islamic State, "The administration's strategy is a good strategy — but it only gets done if you actually do it."  ("Obama has a strategy for fighting ISIS -- one that isn't working,"...
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Immigration and the drought: How many newcomers can California tolerate?
To the editor: Apparently Stanford academic Victor Davis Hanson and his fellow travelers at Californians for Population Stabilization (CAPS) have stumbled onto the root cause of our drought: foreign-born immigrants. How foolish of the rest of us to think it was a lack of rain and snow. ("Group...
'Housing first' isn't a novel strategy on homelessness
To the editor: The article about the tremendous success of "housing first" in Utah eloquently describes how that approach is the real solution to chronic homelessness. Utah's success is indeed noteworthy, but its effort is not truly novel. ("Utah is winning the war on chronic homelessness with...
'Buddhist Bin Laden': Myanmar's hate-mongering monk
To the editor: In the 1990s, more than 800,000 people were killed in Rwanda in a matter of months. This century now commences with probably the first Buddhist hate-monger in history. ("Monk dubbed 'Buddhist Bin Laden' targets Myanmar's persecuted Muslims," May 24)
The American spirit is alive -- in Ireland
To the editor: Ireland's minister for health called his country's referendum on same-sex marriage "a beacon, a light to the rest of the world, of liberty and equality." ("Ireland is first country to legalize same-sex marriage in popular vote," May 23)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The American spirit is alive -- in Ireland</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-le-0527-wednesday-ireland-marriage-20150527-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>To the editor: Ireland's minister for health called his country's referendum on same-sex marriage "a beacon, a light to the rest of the world, of liberty and equality."  ("Ireland is first country to legalize same-sex marriage in popular vote," May 23)
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Immigration and the drought: How many newcomers can California tolerate?
To the editor: Apparently Stanford academic Victor Davis Hanson and his fellow travelers at Californians for Population Stabilization (CAPS) have stumbled onto the root cause of our drought: foreign-born immigrants. How foolish of the rest of us to think it was a lack of rain and snow. ("Group...
'Housing first' isn't a novel strategy on homelessness
To the editor: The article about the tremendous success of "housing first" in Utah eloquently describes how that approach is the real solution to chronic homelessness. Utah's success is indeed noteworthy, but its effort is not truly novel. ("Utah is winning the war on chronic homelessness with...
If Obama can't execute his strategy against Islamic State, what good is it?
To the editor: Doyle McManus quotes former U.S. Ambassador to Iraq Ryan C. Crocker as saying about the fight against Islamic State, "The administration's strategy is a good strategy  but it only gets done if you actually do it." ("Obama has a strategy for fighting ISIS -- one that isn't working,"...
'Buddhist Bin Laden': Myanmar's hate-mongering monk
To the editor: In the 1990s, more than 800,000 people were killed in Rwanda in a matter of months. This century now commences with probably the first Buddhist hate-monger in history. ("Monk dubbed 'Buddhist Bin Laden' targets Myanmar's persecuted Muslims," May 24)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Wed May 27 03:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Marcus Belgrave dies at 78; jazz trumpeter backed Motown stars</title>
        <Link>http://www.latimes.com/la-me-0527-marcus-belgrave-20150526-story.html?track=rss</Link>
        <Description>Marcus Belgrave, a jazz trumpeter who shared the stage and recording studio with Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin, Dizzy Gillespie, Joe Cocker and a string of Motown artists, has died. He was 78.
  </Description>
        <MainBody>Marcus Belgrave dies at 78; jazz trumpeter backed Motown stars
Marcus Belgrave
Ricardo Thomas / Associated Press
Trumpeter Marcus Belgrave performs at the 33rd annual Detroit Jazz Festival in Detroit in 2012. He remained active on the Detroit and international jazz scenes up until his death.
Trumpeter Marcus Belgrave performs at the 33rd annual Detroit Jazz Festival in Detroit in 2012. He remained active on the Detroit and international jazz scenes up until his death.
(Ricardo Thomas / Associated Press)
Culture
Marcus Belgrave, a jazz trumpeter who backed Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin and Motown stars, dies at age 78
Marcus Belgrave, a jazz trumpeter who shared the stage and recording studio with Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin, Dizzy Gillespie, Joe Cocker and a string of Motown artists, has died. He was 78.
Belgrave died Sunday of heart failure at an Ann Arbor, Mich., care facility, said Hazelette Crosby-Robinson, a cousin of Belgrave's wife Joan. He was 78
Marcus Belgrave, jazz trumpter
Jazz trumpter Marcus Belgrave, who performed with Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin and Joe Cocker, died Sunday at the age of 78.
Jazz trumpter Marcus Belgrave, who performed with Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin and Joe Cocker, died Sunday at the age of 78.
See more videos
Belgrave remained active on the Detroit and international jazz scenes up until his death. Born into a family of musicians in Chester, Pa., he started playing professionally at 12 and joined the Ray Charles Band in the late 1950s  what he once described as "the beginning of my musical life."
He moved to Detroit in 1962 and became a studio musician for Motown Records, playing on hits including "My Girl," "The Way You Do the Things You Do" and "Dancing in the Street."
After Motown decamped to California in the early '70s, Belgrave stayed in Detroit and co-founded Tribe Records and recorded with a collective of jazz artists.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
