<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="metro">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:07:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Royal baby 2015: Someone left two giant teddy bears in the middle of a road</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/royal-baby-2015-someone-left-two-giant-teddy-bears-in-the-middle-of-a-road-5176473/</Link>
        <Description>We want one.</Description>
        <MainBody> Catherine Wylie (@wyliecatherine) May 1, 2015
The wait for the royal baby took an unusual turn today after two giant teddy bears randomly arrived at the hospital on the back of a truck.
The two 3-metre tall bears were delivered to the Lindo Wing at St Marys Hospital, Paddington,the hospital where the Duchess of Cambridge will give birth.
And as the nation excitedly waits to discover whether well have a new prince or princess, the two bears were wearing a crown and a tiara, to account for each possibility.
(Picture: Joe Pepler/REX Shutterstock)
But instead of being the work of a generous royalist, the gifts were part of a PR stunt by bookmaker William Hill.
(Picture: Joe Pepler/REX Shutterstock)
If its a girl, the bookies are offering odds of 2/1 on the new princess being named Charlotte.
And if its another prince, odds of 16/1 are being offered on James.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:58:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hundreds of strangers arrive at funeral to pay their respects to the baby boy with no name</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/hundreds-of-strangers-arrive-at-funeral-of-baby-boy-with-no-name-5176752/</Link>
        <Description>The abandoned child was simply known as 'Little Baby Boy'.</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow us
Hundreds of strangers arrive at funeral to pay their respects to the baby boy with noname
Amy Willis for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 1:58 pm
The coffin of an unidentified baby boy sits at his graveside(Picture:PA Wire)
Hundreds of mourners have paid tribute to a baby boy with no name and no clues to his identity.
The abandoned child simply known as Little Baby Boy was found dead on a footpath and wrapped in blankets by a dog walker almost two years ago in the Seafield area of Edinburgh.
After police failed to find his family, community leaders sent out an appealforstrangers to attend the littleboysfuneral to make sure he was not buried alone.
The response was overwhelming and today more than 250 people turned out at Seafield Crematorium to pay their respects to the child, thought to have been around six-weeks-old.
(Picture:PA Wire)
(Picture:PA Wire)
Mourners placed floral tributes and soft toys before a white coffin, which was carried through the grounds of the cemetery to the sound of a single piper playing Amazing Grace.
The service was conducted by Reverend Erica Wishart, a minister from Tranent Parish Church.
The remains of the child were found wrapped in a blanket on an old railway path in the Seafield area of Edinburgh in July 2013(Picture:PA Wire)
Minister Erica Wishart (left) from Tranent Parish church as the coffin is piped to the graveside for the funeral of theunidentified baby boy(Picture:PA Wire)
She said: Something like this touches everybodys hearts, in particularly when it is a child or a baby. Its one of these things that affects everybody.
This is a great community, Leith is a strong community and I know people were very moved when this first happened a couple of years ago and Im sure that everybody wanted to come and pay their respects.
It has been like a wave of compassion from everyone.
We had people here from other faiths so this has cut across all sections of the community.
I think it is wonderful the support people have shown today and giving freely of their time and resources.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:12:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man jailed after stabbing CBBC star to death</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/man-jailed-after-stabbing-cbbc-star-to-death-5176532/</Link>
        <Description>Carl Beatson-Asiedu was set upon and stabbed in the heart as he left a club with friends.</Description>
        <MainBody>Amy Willis for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 1:12 pm

Jeffrey Okafor (Picture: PA)
A man is facing a lengthy jail sentence after being found guilty of stabbing a CBBC star to death in south London.
Carl Beatson-Asiedu, who appeared in the BBC childrens series M.I. High, was set upon and stabbed in the heart as he left a club with friends in 2009.
His killer Jeffrey Okafor, 24, confessed to the murder to his girlfriend, but fled to Nigeria on his brothers passport  sparking a five year manhunt.
He was eventually extradited and was found guilty of murder after a trial at Londons Woolwich Crown Court.
VictimCarl Beatson-Asiedu (Picture: PA)
Mr Beatson-Asiedu, 19, was a university student and DJ who was well known in the club scene as DJ Charmz.
He had been playing a gig at Club Life near Vauxhall Station but was fatally attacked as he left the venue in the early hours of Saturday August 1 2009.
Mr Beatson-Asiedu and his friends were walking to their car when they were approached by a group of men.
An argument broke out and the TV star became separated from his pals and was stabbed by Okafor.
He collapsed on the street where his friends found him, bundled him into their car and set off towards the hospital.
Police officers saw them and tried to revive the CBBC star in the seat, but he died from a single stab wound.
Detective Inspector Alison Hepworth said: Jeffrey Okafor fled the UK to Nigeria illegally under a false identity in the hope of evading capture.
He lived a relatively comfortable life and even had the opportunity to study at university.
There is no doubt that he was supported by others both in the UK and in Nigeria.
In the five years he was on the run he was living a life that Carl should have been living but he was never afforded the opportunity to finish university.
Carls death has had a profound effect on his family and they have waited a very long time to see justice served.
Paying tribute to the victims family, he added: I can only commend them for their steadfastness and patience and I hope that seeing their sons killer finally behind bars brings some form of comfort to them.
Okafor will be sentenced at Woolwich Crown Court.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:35:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police use emergency lights and park on double yellow lines… so they can order a McDonald’s</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/police-use-emergency-lights-and-park-on-double-yellow-lines-so-they-can-order-a-mcdonalds-5176571/</Link>
        <Description>An officer was pictured clutching drinks as he returned to the car.</Description>
        <MainBody>Follow us
Police use emergency lights and park on double yellow lines so they can order a McDonalds
Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 12:35 pm
An officer clutching drinks from McDonalds was spotted getting into the car (Picture: LNP)
A police car was parked on a double yellow line with its emergency lights flashing soan officer couldget out and ordera McDonalds.
The Metropolitan Police car was seen pulling up to the curb with its emergency lights flashing and stopping on a set of double yellow lines, blocking one lane of the busy road leading from Westminster through central Victoria.
And an officerwas picturedleaving the McDonalds in Victoria holding three drinks andgetting into the car, which by that point had turned off its emergency lights.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:31:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Little girl, 2, ‘swears like a trooper thanks to Peppa Pig game’</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/little-girl-aged-two-swears-like-a-trooper-thanks-to-peppa-pig-game-5176468/</Link>
        <Description>'I was accusing her dad of teaching her to swear.'</Description>
        <MainBody>Matt Payton for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 12:31 pm
Lilly-May Barber, two, with the offending toy (Picture: Wales News Service)
A potty-mouthed Peppa Pig toy hastaught a littlegirl the F-word,according to her parents.
Lilly-May Barber, two, apparently started dropping the F-bomb after playing with thePeppa Pig Fun And Learn Tablet.
MORE: You and your child can star in Peppa Pig thanks to these books
Her mother LauraBurroughs, 23, said: She has been swearing ever since she started playing it  she has learned it off the toy and says it quite often.
I was accusing her dad of teaching her to swear but it was only when I tried out the tablet that I found one of the activities says find the odd one out  but it sounds like f*** you, odd one out.
MORE: 18 things only parents who have overdosed on Peppa Pig will understand
Here is the offending tablet in action:
Ms Burroughs, of Port Talbot, South Wales, bought the toy from Argosto helpteach her daughterabout letters and numbers before she started school.
However she claimstheonly thing that Lilly-May has learned is how to swear like a trooper.
MORE: One minute its Peppa Pig and Father Christmas and the next its an orgy train
A spokesman for Argos said: As a responsible family retailer we have robust processes in place to ensure that the toys we sell are safe and appropriate for children.
We take Miss Burroughs concerns regarding the Peppa Pig toy very seriously, and sincerely apologise for any distress this may have caused.
We are trying to make contact with the customer directly, and are working with the manufacturer to investigate as a matter of urgency.
Have any of yougot a potty-mouthed Peppa Pig toy? Share it with us on Twitter @MetroUK .
More
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:07:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rider pulls off first triple backflip on a motorcycle</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/rider-pulls-off-first-triple-backflip-on-a-motorcycle-5176257/</Link>
        <Description>'The slightest misstep may well have meant death.'
</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 12:07 pm
A motorbike rider just pulled off the first triple backflip in the sports history.
A 37-foot tall takeoff ramp was positioned at a ridiculous 81-degree angle in order to give Josh Sheehan as much time in the air as possible to complete the trick.
And gunning along the ramp at a speed of 60mph, Sheehan and his 200lb bike took off, reaching a height of over 80ft andturning over three times before landing.
It was an exhilarating ride and to be the first person to ever have done this was definitely a defining moment in my career and a dream come true, Sheehan said.
His teammate, Travis Pastrana, who was the first ever to land a double backflip, called the achievement so awesome.
The slightest misstep may well have meant death, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:51:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Calf born with two heads is ‘one in 400 million’</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/calf-born-with-two-heads-is-one-in-400-million-5176369/</Link>
        <Description>But two is not always better than one.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jimmy Nsubuga for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 11:51 am
Annabel, the two headed calf (Picture: First Coast News)
Two is not always better than one.
This calf shocked farmers when she was born with two headsin Baker County, Florida, on Monday.
Despite being a one in 400 million birth, Annabel is not likely to survive long.
But that hasnt stopped farmer Carolyn Crews from loving the animal and she has vowed to look after her until the end.
MORE: Four-month-old baby pulled from Nepalese wreckage
Shes not expected to live long (Picture: First Coast News)
I dont think it was meant to be for something like this to live, Crewstold First Coast News.
You know, I dont think shes going to make it.
A birth like this happens every one in 400 million times.
Vets think Annabel has polycephaly, which is when an embryo splits but doesnt fully form as twins.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:31:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Schoolboy took suspected cocaine wrap into school before ‘showing pupils how to snort it’</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/schoolboy-took-suspected-cocaine-wrap-into-school-before-showing-pupils-how-to-snort-it-5176432/</Link>
        <Description>The boy took the bag of white power to Our Lady and St Edward’s Catholic Primary School in Birkenhead.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nicholas Reilly for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 11:31 am
The incident occurred at Our Ladys and St Edwards Primary School in Birkenhead (Picture: Google Street View)
A young schoolboy took a suspected cocaine wrap into school, and allegedly showed other pupils how the drug could be snorted.
The boy took the bag of white power to Our Lady and St Edwards Catholic Primary School in Birkenhead, according to the Liverpool Echo.
He then reportedly showed off the substance to his classmates, and allegedly demonstrated how to take the drug. Concerns were only raised when pupils went home and told their parents what had happened.
While its believed that drugs werent taken by pupils, one parent, whose daughter attends the school, said that the incident was disgusting.
Its disgusting that a child would know what to do with drugs or even know what they are, she said.
Its worrying that there are kids that do.
The boy was showing other kids what it is and how to use it. Another parent made a complaint and thats when the police got involved.
A police spokesman confirmed that they were called to the school last Friday after the strange discovery was made.
Another pupil from the school found the bag near to a local shop a few days before passing it on to a friend, a spokesman said.
The pupil then told one of his parents about the item and they in turn reported the matter to the school who then informed the police.
The schoolboy in question, whose age is unknown, was spoken to by police but no formal action was taken.
The boy was accused of taking a cocaine wrap into School (Picture: AP)
This pupil did the right thing in the end and told an adult about what he had been given, Police inspector Georgina Minnery said.
These pupils were merely curious about the package that had been found.
MORE: Powerful 6.8 magnitude earthquake hits Papua New Guinea
We would always urge anyone who finds a suspicious item to report that matter to the police immediately.
The boys and their parents have been spoken to about the matter and there will be no further police action taken in relation to this incident.
In a 2010 OFSTED inspection, the primary school was rated outstanding, the highest ranking on offer.
More
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:24:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Four-month-old baby pulled from Nepalese wreckage</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/four-month-old-baby-pulled-from-nepalese-wreckage-5176239/</Link>
        <Description>'When I saw the baby alive all my sorrow went. Everyone was clapping.'</Description>
        <MainBody>Matt Payton for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 11:24 am
Four-month-old baby boy Sonit Awal is held up by Nepalese Army soldiers (Picture: Amul Thapa/AP)
A Nepalese photojournalist captured the moment army soldierssaved a four-month-old baby boy from the rubble of a house following the earthquake.
Sonit Awal miraculously survived 20 hours buried in the remnants of the familyhome with no injuries other than a small cutoverhis brow.
MORE: Amanda Holdens sister tells of terror after being caught in Nepal earthquake
Sonits nine-year-old sister was watching him when the earthquakestruck at midday on Saturday, collapsing a number ofhistoric buildings in the town.
Local photojournalist,Amul Thapa, caught this incredible scene inthe town of Bhaktapur, just east of Nepals capital.
Mr Thapa said: When I saw the baby alive all my sorrow went. Everyone was clapping.
It gave me energy and made me smile in spite of lots of pain hidden inside me.
These photos were taken by photojournalist Amul Thapa (Picture: Amul Thapa/AP)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:21:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baby born with organs on the outside</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/baby-born-with-organs-on-the-outside-5176309/</Link>
        <Description>Nell Marshall was born with exomphalos, a condition that means her abdomen did not fully develop in the womb.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 11:21 am
Nell had to undergo an operation to mend her heart (Picture: North News)
A baby girl needed an emergency life-saving operation after she was born with her stomach, bowel and liver outside her body in a bag of skin.
Nell Marshall, who was the only survivor of triplets, was born with exomphalos, a condition that means her abdomen did not fully develop in the womb.
This meansthat her stomach, bowel and liver were born outside her body and shenow faces a major operation to put them backinside her.
MORE: The 8 baby fears every first time dad will experience
Nell was born with a condition that means her organs are outside her body (Picture: North News)
But Nell also needed emergency surgery after it was discovered that she had a hole between the vessels coming out of her heart.
Shewas taken fromNewcastles Royal Victoria Infirmary to Freeman Hospital where she underwent a five-and-a-half hour operation.
The surgery to put her organs back inside her will take place in six weeks time when she has had some time to grow and develop.
Even though she has been through so much, shes never given up, her mother, 35-year-old Joanne Marshall, told the Chronicle .
MORE: New parents had to defend decision to have baby with same condition as dad
Nell will undergo surgery to put her organs inside her in six weeks (Picture: North News)
Shes still smiling. She is very placid and enjoys shuffling about on her bottom at the minute.
Joanne and father Andrew, 45, have spoken of their gratitude to staff at the Freeman Hospitals Childrens Heart Unit.
You can donate to CHUF here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:48:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Powerful 6.8 magnitude earthquake hits Papua New Guinea</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/powerful-6-8-magnitude-earthquake-hits-papua-new-guinea-5176389/</Link>
        <Description>The 6.8-magnitude quake struck about 66 miles south-west of the town of Kokopo.</Description>
        <MainBody>Amy Willis for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 10:48 am
Papua New Guinea 6.8 magnitude earthquake(Picture: EPA)
A powerful earthquake has rattled the South Pacific island nation of Papua New Guinea.
The 6.8-magnitude quake struck about 66 miles south-west of the town of Kokopo in north-eastern Papua New Guinea, the US Geological Survey reported.
It also said the quakes strength was lower than the initial measurement of 7.1.
The Pacific Tsunami Warning Centre said hazardous tsunami waves were possible within 186 miles of the epicentre, but the risk passed and the advisory was lifted.
There were no reports of damage or injuries, said Chris McKee, assistant director Geophysical Observatory in the capital, Port Moresby. The area closest to the epicentre is sparsely populated, and it was unlikely the quake caused any structural damage, he said.
There were also no reports of any tsunami sightings. Given the quakes depth of about 37 miles, officials believed the risk of a tsunami was slim, said observatory official Mathew Moihoi.
Shallower quakes tend to cause more damage, and have a higher potential for generating a tsunami.
Papua New Guinea sits on the Ring of Fire, the arc of seismic faults around the Pacific Ocean where earthquakes are common.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:31:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain’s fattest man is slowly gorging himself to death</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/britains-fattest-man-is-slowly-gorging-himself-to-death-5176261/</Link>
        <Description>If this 65 stone man doesn’t stop eating 10,000 calories a day he could be dead soon. </Description>
        <MainBody>Jimmy Nsubuga for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 10:31 am
Britains fattest man Carl Thompson (Picture: Stian Alexander)
If this 65 stone man doesnt stop eating 10,000 calories a day he could be dead soon.
You wont be surprised to hear that Carl Thompson is Britains fattest man, but he may not be around for much longer if he doesnt change his diet.
And what a diet that is.
MORE: Mum transforms children with special needs into superheroes for awesome photo project
He started gaining more weight when his mum died (Picture: Stian Alexander)
For breakfast, the 32-year-old tucks into a massive fry up of four sausages, a whole pan of butter-drenched mushrooms and five fried eggs and fried bread, as well as a huge bowl of cereal with full fat milk.
For lunch he will have pasta, chips, bacon, pork pies, crisps, pasties, sandwiches and chocolate.
He supplements these meals with five takeaways a week, which include curries, pizzas and Chinese.
Asked about his favourite food, he said he was hooked on puddings, including ice creams and magnum ice lollies, but admitted: I love all food and will eat anything.
Mr Thompson was taken to hospital five times last year after he slipped over and couldnt get back up at his home in Dover.
Its not just his health that has suffered, his love life has also taken a hit.
His last relationship was with a woman called Rachel 10 years ago.
They split up after he started getting too fat and he got even largerwhen his mum Elaine Hoyle, a cleaner, died of a brain tumour, in 2012.
Dont eat junk food all the time or youll end up like me, he added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:28:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Politician who voted against gay rights outed on Grindr</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/politician-who-voted-against-gay-rights-outed-on-grindr-5176213/</Link>
        <Description>Randy Boehning (yes, that's his real name) sent an explicit picture on the gay dating app.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 10:28 am
Randy Boehning sent an explicit picture to a man on Grindr
A politician who voted against gay rights was outed after he sent an explicit picture of himself to another man on Grindr.
Randy Boehning (yes, thats his real name) twice voted against a Senate bill that would makesexual discrimination part of the North Dakotasanti-discrimination law.
ButRepublicanMr. Boehning, who has served as part of the state assembly for 12 years, was outed when he sent an explicit picture to 21-year-old Dustin Smith on gay dating app Grindr.
MORE: Anti-gay bakers ordered to pay massive fine after refusing to make same-sex wedding cake
Dustin Smith recognised Mr. Boehnings face and looked for him on the app (Picture: Grindr)
Im sure Ive talked to this person before, Smith recalled thinking to himself when he saw the faces of the politicians who voted against the gay rights bill, he told the The Washington Post.
Suddenly it dawned on me: I think Ive seen this guy on Grindr!
Smith scrolled through the social network until he found the familiar bushy-eyebrowed, bespectacled face of Mr. Boehning and started up a conversation.
The small talk quickly escalated to sexually suggestive messages. Soon he found himself with a picture of the public servants private parts. It was then that he came forward to out the politician.
Mr. Boehning twice voted against gay rights legislation (Picture: Getty Images)
I just felt like this story had to get out, said Mr. Smith.
Mr. Boehning, from Fargo, Dakota, said he was relieved to finally come out.
A 1,000lb gorilla has been lifted, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:22:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Penguins ‘use their stinky poos to clear space to have sex’</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/penguins-use-their-stinky-poos-to-clear-space-to-have-sex-5176130/</Link>
        <Description>Where there's a will, there's a way. </Description>
        <MainBody>Jimmy Nsubuga for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 10:22 am
It seems that anything can be used for good in nature, even a stinky penguin poo.
The creatures apparently utilise their number twos to melt snow that covers their breeding grounds on Cuverville Island, near Antarctica.
Experts at Oxford University suggested the dark guano (faeces) worked by absorbing more heat, with the effects being shown in a time-lapse video.
MORE: Ed Miliband almost fell over during the BBC Question Time debate
Penguins apparently use poo to clear space to have sex (Picture: BBC)
In the clip the snow melts over a period of time after the Antarctic Gentoo penguins have seemingly spread their faeces over it.
The snow might also be melting because of mechanical erosion  because the penguins are walking around, Dr Tom Hart, from Oxford University, told The Verge .
The penguinologist analysed the footage along with the public as part of a university project called Penguin Watch.
The video was filmed by Oxford University experts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:18:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nasa has a ‘warp drive’ that could zip people to the moon in just hours</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/nasa-has-a-warp-drive-that-could-zip-people-to-the-moon-in-just-hours-5176138/</Link>
        <Description>Drive works using microwaves and solar energy.</Description>
        <MainBody>Amy Willis for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 10:18 am
(Picture: Universal)
Nasa has finally invented a warp drive that could take people to the moon in just a few hours.
Scientists have quietly been testing a new drive thatwould enable spacecrafts to travel faster than the speed of light.
The hope is that one day this will allow humans to reach the moon in just four hours.
(Picture: Star Trek)
The new warp drive works on an electromagnetic system, which creates thrust from electrical energy without rocket fuel.
The EmDrive engine bounces microwaves around in a closed container  providing thrust from nothing except solar energy to power the microwaves.
Technically  according to current understanding of physics  this should be impossible.
This should violate the laws of conservation of momentum, whereby the momentum of a system is constant if there are no external forces.
The implications for the new drive are huge  without needing fuel, satellites could be half the size.
Humans could also travel further into space than ever before.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:12:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pictured: Man killed by train at Stockwell station when he bent over to pick up bag</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/pictured-man-killed-by-train-at-stockwell-station-when-he-bent-over-to-pick-up-bag-5176108/</Link>
        <Description>Joe Burgess was called 'a lovely guy, a fantastic bloke'.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 9:12 am
Joe Burgess was described as a fantastic bloke (Picture: Facebook)
A man who was killed by a train when he bent over to pick up his bag has been pictured for the first time.
Joe Burgess, 27, died after beingstruck by an oncoming train while waiting at Stockwell station in south London.
The Dulwich man, who was called a lovely guy and a fantastic bloke by friends, battled in hospital for three days before succumbing to his injuries on 13 April.
Suddenly he bent as his lighter fell, and immediately his head hit the train so hard, designer Jean Charles Jeanneau, who saw the accident, told the Mirror .
I couldnt look at him. I just had to leave straight away. The girl next to me was crying. Station staff started pushing straight away to get through.
A page was set up in Joes memory (Picture: JustGiving)
Joes girlfriend Imogen was devastated by the death.
A friend told the Evening Standard:
He was a lovely guy, just a fantastic bloke with so many friends.
A JustGiving page has been set up where you can donate to Londons Air Ambulance in Joes memory.
More than 5,500 has been raised, three quarters of the 7,500 target. Donate here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:18:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>These rugby players got their teeth replaced with bottle openers</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/these-rugby-players-got-their-teeth-replaced-with-bottle-openers-5176076/</Link>
        <Description>This a great solution to missing teeth.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 8:18 am
A beer company hasrewarded rugby players who have lostteeth during games by filling the gaps  with bottle openers.
Atwo-minute advert from Salta Beer, who sponsor club rugby in Argentina, describeshow cuts mend, bruises disappear but teeth are lost forever.
So Salta commissioned a dental surgeon to design a special metal implant  emblazoned with the word Salta  which is fitted where the missing toothused to be.
And its a bottle opener.
Salta said they wanted to give back to the rugby players (Picture: YouTube)
We are incorporating a unique innovation here, said Dr. Sebastian Juri.
A new functionality is added to the chewing function of the premolars: a beer opener.
We think this is a great solution to missing teeth.
Good job, Salta.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:16:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ed Miliband almost fell over during the BBC Question Time debate</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/ed-miliband-almost-fell-over-during-the-bbc-question-time-debate-5176066/</Link>
        <Description>Bit of a wobble</Description>
        <MainBody> Aaron Boileau (@Boiler97) April 30, 2015
Except this guy, who used it as evidence to prove thatwere all doomed.
I'm so glad we live in a country where someone, somewhere will change their vote because Ed Miliband fell over
 Ron Walker (@ronnabe) April 30, 2015
During the 90-minute TV battle, Miliband was forced to explicitly rule out any deal with the nationalist party after SNP hotshot Jim Sillars claimedthe party would insist on a new independence referendum if they entered a coalition government with Labour.
If the price of a Labour government is a coalition or a deal with the SNP, it is not going to happen, Milibandtold the audience at Leeds Town Hall.
Milibandalso faced tough questions on immigration, public spending and the partys role in the credit crunch.
A snap poll put David Cameronas winner of the debates with 44 per cent of the public saying he had done best on the night.
Nick Clegg won 19 per cent of public opinion in the poll.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:43:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man wearing gift bag on his head falls asleep during alleged burglary</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/man-wearing-gift-bag-on-his-head-falls-asleep-during-alleged-burglary-5176045/</Link>
        <Description>Brandon Funkhouser was found slumped on a sofa, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Harry Readhead for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 7:43 am
Brandon Funkhouser was found slumped on a sofa, police said (Picture: Monroe County Sheriffs Office)
In the same week that a man wasarrested afterliking his own wanted post on Facebook , another man has been arrested after falling asleep during an alleged burglary.
With a gift bag on his head.
The brilliantly-named Brandon Funkhouser, 30, was detained by officers on Sunday after he reportedly entered a boat belonging to a 93-year-old and began sifting through the owners belongings.
According to Monroe County Sheriffs Office spokeswoman Becky Herrin, Funkhouser, from Marathon, Florida, then fell asleep. The owner called officers, who arrived to find Funkhouser slumped on a sofa with a gift bag on his head.
He now faces charges of burglary of an occupied dwelling and criminal mischief.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:34:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>General Election 2015: David Cameron crowned ‘winner’ of BBC Question Time debate</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/general-election-2015-david-cameron-crowned-winner-of-bbc-question-time-debate-5176044/</Link>
        <Description>In a 90-minute Question Time special, David Cameron, Ed Miliband and Nick Clegg faced a studio audience.</Description>
        <MainBody>Amy Willis for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 7:34 am
David Cameron (Picture:Reuters)
David Cameron was crowned the winner of the BBC Question Time special by a snap poll.
Labour leader Ed Miliband used his segment of the broadcast to make his strongest-worded declaration to date that he would not countenance any deal with the Scottish National Party in the event of a hung parliament after May 7.
If the price of a Labour government is a coalition or a deal with the SNP, it is not going to happen, he said.
In a 90-minute Question Time special, David Cameron, Ed Miliband and Nick Clegg faced a studio audience separately in Leeds Town Hall, in a format devised after Mr Cameron refused to take part in a head-to-head encounter with his Labour rival.
(Picture:Reuters)
GEd Miliband tackles Dimbleby (Picture:Reuters)
Mr Cameron rejected suggestions he was planning to slash 8 billion from child benefit after Liberal Democrats revealed details of proposals discussed by the coalition, including means-testing and restricting them to under-16s and two children per family.
I dont want to do that, he said  but asked if that amounted to an absolute guarantee not to cut child benefit or child tax credit, he said child benefit was not what we need to change.
Mr Miliband said he could give the guarantee and seized on Mr Camerons answer as evidence tax credits and child benefit are on the ballot paper at this election because millions of families risk losing thousands of pounds.
The Labour leader also resisted pressure to say the last Labour government overspent and said he was absolutely, deadly serious about balancing the books in the next parliament.
Ed Miliband (Picture:Getty Images)
Ed Miliband (Picture:Reuters)
An instant poll of Question Time viewers conducted by ICM for The Guardian found that 44 per cent thought Mr Cameron had done best on the night, against 38per centfor Mr Miliband and 19per centfor Mr Clegg.
But only 6 per cent of the viewers in a small sub-sample said they had their mind changed by the programme, while 87per centsaid it would make no difference to how they would vote.
Among this group Mr Clegg performed best, with 32per centof switchers saying they may now vote for the Lib Dems, compared with 25per centwho said they would switch to the Tories and 20 per cent to Labour.
Nick Clegg (Picture:Reuters)
Tory Leader of the Commons William Hague said that Mr Miliband had failed to rule out attempting to govern as a minority administration propped up by SNP votes.
Ed Miliband ruled out coalitions and deals with the SNP, but what he means of course is that every day there would have to be a vote, a negotiation, and everybody held to ransom by the Scottish National Party, he said.
(Picture:Reuters)
Mr Clegg  who did not rule out a coalition deal with whichever of the main parties won fewer seats if a deal could not be struck with the largest  pressed the Tories to come clean over welfare cuts.
Where they are going to take the equivalent of 1,500 off eight million of the most vulnerable families? We can only assume that they are looking at the kind of plans which they floated some years ago in government, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="20">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:00:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>You’re not dressed for May Day 2015 – this is how you should be dressed for May Day</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/05/01/youre-not-dressed-for-may-day-this-is-how-you-should-be-dressed-for-may-day-5172849/</Link>
        <Description>Summer Is A Coming In.</Description>
        <MainBody>Search Metro
Follow us
Youre not dressed for May Day 2015  this is how you should be dressed for MayDay
Yvette Caster for Metro.co.uk Friday 1 May 2015 7:00 am
Lets toast the nymphs of spring (Picture: Matt Cardy/Getty)
As any Wicker Man fan will know, Summer Is A Coming In (or Icumen In if were being pedantic).
May Day 2015 is here  the May 1 celebration of fertility and the start of spring.
Most of us are just concerned with the three-day weekend thanks to the Early May Bank Holiday on Monday, May 4.
But a rare few have got celebrating May Day down to a fine art, from head to toe.
Because youre not dressed for May Day  this is how you should be dressed for May Day.
1. Like a Blues Brother, but in green
(Picture: Matt Cardy/Getty)
2. In THIS  which everyone knows is a traditional Hobby Horse costume
(Picture: A2NYT2)
3. By getting the horn
What? Its traditional (Picture: Matt Cardy/Getty)
4. By dressing up so well people cant spot which one of yous the real Usain
(Picture: PA)
5. With a smile that belies the fact youre burning a virgin to appease the old gods after lunch
(Picture: Getty)
6. With a mask so none of your employees can identify you at the orgy later
(Picture: Getty)
7. With supplies stolen from the local primary school art cupboard
(Picture: Getty)
8. With an inexplicable paper mache bird
(Picture: PA)
9. With the entire contents of your front garden on your head and shoulders
Picture: Getty)
10. With a sensible coat and hat, because this is still England after all
(Picture: PA)
11. With a shrug that says I had this beard long before the hipsters
(Picture: Matt Dunham/AP)
12. With a dress that proves you can celebrate with pride
(Picture: Dan Kitwood/Getty)
13. With a mask Green Lantern would give his magic ring for
(Picture: Matt Cardy/Getty)
14. By tying ribbons round a large erection
(Picture: PA)
15. By getting the whole family involved
(Picture: Getty)
16. Like this, obviously
(Picture: PA)
17. By wearing all your clothes at once and not caring if you get beer on them all
(Picture: Getty)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="21">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:43:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Village of the Damned residents suffer from ‘sex cravings’ after waking up from sleep illness</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/04/30/village-of-the-damned-residents-suffer-from-sex-cravings-after-waking-up-from-sleep-illness-5176005/</Link>
        <Description>Men of the village are reportedly waking up for their unnaturally long slumber with excessive sex drives.</Description>
        <MainBody>Oliver Wheaton for Metro.co.uk Thursday 30 Apr 2015 10:43 pm
The village has been dubbed sleepy hollow (Picture: Vera Salnitskaya/Will Stewart)
The people living in a village in Kazakhstan have been suffering from a bizarre sleeping sickness which sees them fall unconscious for days.
However some of the side affects to this illness threaten to tear their community apart.
The men of Kalachi, labelled by media outlets as the Village of the Damned, are reportedly struggling with their uncontrollable sex drive after waking from their long bouts of sleep.
Pensioners suffering from the illness also use words previously unthinkable to the quite rural town, including the nuns looking after them whores and prostitutes, according the MailOnline .
MORE: Thief returns money to the 100-year-old tourist they pick-pocketed in Gloucester
(Picture: Will Stewart)
Roughly 160 people, about a quarter of the small town population, are thought to have been affected by the illness.
It was previously reported that sufferers, as well as sleeping for days at a time, experienced headaches and memory loss, however one woman told of other affects.
She said: Other women were saying the same. As soon as men were were recovering after waking, they needed sex right there and then, and this feeling lasted for at least a month.
Men even awake from their long slumberand immediatelygo searching nearby villages for their wives who have moved their families to protect them from the illness.
The village has now come to be known assleepy hollow in the local area due to the strange illness.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="22">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:25:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thief returns money to the 100-year-old tourist they pick-pocketed in Gloucester</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/04/30/thief-returns-money-to-the-100-year-old-tourist-they-pick-pocketed-in-gloucester-5175926/</Link>
        <Description>A crisis of conscience comes into play...</Description>
        <MainBody>Oliver Wheaton for Metro.co.uk Thursday 30 Apr 2015 9:25 pm
William White outside Gloucester Cathedral (Picture:SWNS)
An 100-year-oldtouristwho had 1,400 stolen from him while visiting Gloucester had the money returned to him by the thief.
CentenarianWilliam White, from Arizona, had his bum-bag snatched from him while exiting a bus in the Cathedral city recently.
However before he left to go home the thief had an apparent crisis of conscience and returned the money toMr White.
While the elderly tourist hasnt revealed who the thief was, he son Anthony who he was travelling with said: I believe whenever anything is taken and returned, that person should be completely anonymous.
MORE: Woman goes to the shops to buy milk  spots an emu running down the street
(Picture:SWNS)
Everything is fine. You dont want to punish a person. That would not be necessary. The nice thing was, dad ended up with his money back.
Mr White was born in Gloucester in 1914 and wanted to visit the city again before he died.
He moved to Canada in 1948 before finally settling in Arizona where he ran a successful aviation business, making him a very wealthy man.
William White pictured with his son Anthony(Picture: SWNS)
News of the theft made headlines throughout the South West, however now the tale of thievery has turned into one of redemption.
Gloucester Police say they will be talking to Mr White about how the money was returned.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="23">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:55:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Do you want to win a goat farm? Just write an essay</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/04/30/do-you-want-to-win-a-goat-farm-just-write-an-essay-5175917/</Link>
        <Description>If so, you will need to relocate to Elkmont in the Smoky Mountains in Tennessee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Matt Payton for Metro.co.uk Thursday 30 Apr 2015 8:55 pm
Lots of goats (Picture: Facebook)
The owners of a goat farm have set up an essay contest to see who will win their country holdings.
They are looking to relocate to Costa Rica for missionary work but want to pass the farm and creamery on asto someone.
Part of this prize will be60 goats and 30 sheep who live at the Tennessee propertyset in the Great Smoky Mountains.
To enter the GoatDairyEssay competition, you will have to pay an entrance fee of $150 and its owners hope to get as many as 2,500 applicants.
MORE: Vincent van Goat: This animal has become so good at painting people are buying his pictures
Paul Spell, who owns the farm with his wife, Leslie, said: Its for real. Weve had a pretty successful run here and I thought it was time for us to go help someone else.
By giving people the opportunity of winning the farm and creamery we will be able to help our missionary friends to become self-sufficient and have enough income for day to day expenses.
Heresanother (Picture: Facebook)
Mr Spell told Alabama.com : The winner will receive a debt free house and farm on 20 acres, dairy and cheese making building with animals and equipment along with recipes and training.
The winner will also receive $20,000 in operating expenses, enough to continue running a profitable goat dairy and cheese making operation.
And another (Picture: Facebook)
The results will be announced on October 15 and applicants will be disqualified if they contact the Spells directly.
So how about it, do you love goats, goats cheese and southern livin?
If so, this could be the lifestyle shake upfor you.
Wait, here another of the blighters (Picture: Facebook)
More
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="24">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:53:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thief stripped naked by locals and whipped with a belt</title>
        <Link>http://metro.co.uk/2015/04/30/thief-stripped-naked-by-locals-and-whipped-with-a-belt-5175866/</Link>
        <Description>'Officers arrived in time to save the man from further embarrassment and we are investigating,' said police.</Description>
        <MainBody>Metro News Reporter for Metro.co.uk Thursday 30 Apr 2015 8:53 pm
A thief was stripped naked and thrashed with a belt by two elderly women after being caught by locals nabbing a Toyotacar wing mirror.
The beaten and humiliated criminal isreported to beAlexis Rodriguez, 24,from thecity of Huancayo in central Peru.
MORE: Venezuelan TV presenter Yuvi Pallares strips naked during report on Real Madrid star Cristiano Ronaldo
After the video was uploaded to social media,one user, Hernando Calvo,posted This is just disgraceful.We live in the 21st century and yet these people behave like they are in the middle ages.
Another user, Enrique Benel wrote: for Christs sake, it was a wing mirror. JUST A WING MIRROR!!!
A police spokesman told reporters:Officers arrived in time to save the man from further embarrassment and we are investigating.
Rodriguez was arrested for theft and police are currently investigating his attackers.
Alexis Rodriguez during his naked thrashing (Picture: CEN)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
