<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:14:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gay-Marriage Study Author Admits to Lies, Mag Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bdf1d3/sc/32/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cscience0Cscience0Enews0Cgay0Emarriage0Estudy0Eauthor0Eadmits0Elies0Escience0Ejournal0Esays0En366266/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The journal Science has now formally retracted the study that said a person's view on gay-marriage could be changed by a short conversation.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
The journal Science has formally pulled a widely reported study on changing attitudes toward gay marriage, saying a lawyer for one of the co-authors, a UCLA grad student, had admitted it contained lies.
Michael LaCour, the political science PhD student accused of faking the data, did not agree to the retraction and said in an earlier statement that he stood by the results and would respond to the allegations by Friday.
 Solomon Messing (@SolomonMg) May 22, 2015
The study claimed that people's views on same-sex marriage could be changed by short one-on-one conversations with gay canvassers. It came under scrutiny after a Stanford University research team tried to replicate and expand on the findings and tipped off the lead author, Donald Green, to the irregularities.
advertisement
Green said LaCour refused to turn over contact information for the survey respondents and claimed the raw data had been accidentally deleted.
Science said that LaCour's lawyer has since confirmed that the original study's assertion that survey respondents were given cash incentives was false, and that organizations listed as sponsors provided no funding.
"In addition to these known problems, independent researchers have noted certain statistical irregularities in the responses," Science said . "LaCour has not produced the original survey data from which someone else could independently confirm the validity of the reported findings."
Tracy Connor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:17:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bowe Bergdahl Not Accused of Sexual Harassment: Officials</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bdc96d/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cbowe0Ebergdahl0Ereleased0Csexual0Eharassment0Eallegation0Eagainst0Ebowe0Ebergdahl0Eunfounded0Eofficials0En36630A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Army officials seek to tamp down "false reports" about Bergdahl, charged with desertion after he left his post and was held captive by the Taliban.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Army Sgt. Bowe Bergdahl, who's charged with desertion after he left his post in Afghanistan in 2009 and was held captive by the Taliban for five years, has not been accused of sexual harassment, according to Army officials seeking to tamp down "false reports."
The officials told NBC News on Thursday that while a female specialist at Fort Sam Houston in Texas made an unofficial complaint in February that Bergdahl had harassed and stalked her, she never accused Bergdahl specifically of sexual harassment.
In an informal inquiry, the two soldiers' commanding officer found that the allegations weren't true, the officials said. The female soldier accepted the informal findings and didn't file a formal complaint, they said.
The woman also accused Bergdahl of "unwanted contact and stalking, including leaving origami at her barracks door and showing up at her door in a gorilla suit and hanging around her while she was on staff duty."
The informal inquiry found that Bergdahl would often leave origami for his fellow soldiers and at times would don a gorilla suit in the barracks.
advertisement
In one instance, the Army specialist claimed Bergdahl was stalking her one evening and watching her through her office window at Fort Sam Houston. But the inquiry found that Bergdahl was actually at dinner off-base with soldiers who have been assigned as his escorts when he leaves the base.
Bergdahl had been assigned to administrative duties at Fort Sam Houston in, San Antonio, last summer after a reintegration process following his release by the Taliban.
A frame grab from the Taliban propaganda video released Dec. 25, 2009, purportedly showing U.S. soldier Bowe Bergdahl taken from a video made available by IntelCenter. IntelCenter via AP file
Bergdahl is scheduled to appear for an Article 32 hearing at the base on charges that he deserted his post in Afghanistan in June 2009. He was captured and held hostage by the Taliban and Haqqani terrorist network for five years before he was released in exchange for five high-ranking Taliban prisoners released from the U.S. detention center at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, in May 2014.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:39:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Heartbreaking': Search for Texas Flood Victims Goes On</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bae551/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ctexas0Efloods0Erivers0Erising0Emore0Erain0Eway0Esearch0Emissing0Egoes0En3660A56/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Rescue crews have already pulled more than 100 people from rushing floodwaters in Texas, some of them swept downstream more than 10 miles.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_fh_dpatricktxflooding_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The rushing waters swept people many miles away  one dead body was found at least 30 miles downstream, he said, and a person who survived was found 12 miles downstream.
And huge debris and heavy brush are making it hard for crews to know where to look, Perkins said.
"It's heartbreaking," he said.
Sarah Perez of Hays County posted dramatic video of Blanco River floodwaters rushing through her home and submerging the entire first floor. She and her family had to flee to the second floor, where rescuers found them late Wednesday.
advertisement
President Barack Obama offered thoughts and prayers to families in Texas and said the federal and state governments were working well together on disaster relief.
"They appear to have the assets they need at this stage," he said. "There's going to be a lot of rebuilding, and we as a nation are going to have to help, the same way we do any time that folks are affected by these natural disasters."
People were still cleaning up Thursday in Wimberley, where the Blanco left a landscape of tree limbs and shattered houses.
"I wake up in the morning sometimes and I'm thinking, no, this was all just a dream," Chuck Criswell told NBC News.
A restroom building was nearly submerged Thursday at Lake Somerville State Park near Brenham, Texas.Texas Parks and Wildlife
During the worst of the flood, on Saturday night and Sunday morning, "I shined my light out there and it looked like the water was going 500 miles an hour," he said. "The debris just flying by."
On Thursday, an estimated 14 million people in Nebraska, Kansas, Oklahoma and Texas were at risk of more severe weather, and flood watches were posted again for Texas and Oklahoma. A line of thunderstorms rumbled through Oklahoma City on Thursday morning.
5:07 PM: This storm is capable of quarter size hail and winds to 60 mph #txwx https://t.co/cXls60y6cF
 NWS Midland (@NWSMidland) May 28, 2015
A powerful tornado touched down Wednesday afternoon in the town of Canadian, in the Texas Panhandle, injuring three people, authorities said. One of them, a man who was impaled through the abdomen, remained in serious condition at University Medical Center in Lubbock, the hospital said Thursday.
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:37:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dog Walker Finds Body in Suitcase in Pennsylvania</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd3720/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcphiladelphia0N0Cnews0Clocal0CBody0ESuitcase0ETinicum0E30A53832510Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A dog walker discovered a suitcase with a human body inside Thursday not far from Philadelphia International Airport, authorities say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Updated 1 minute ago
A dog walker made a grisly discovery in Delaware County Thursday afternoon.
The person was walking in the area of the old Westinghouse plant near 2nd Street in Tinicum, Pennsylvania -- not far from Philadelphia International Airport -- when he saw the suitcase, said the Delaware County District Attorneys Office.
Psychiatrist: Colorado Theater Shooter "Knew What He Was Doing"
The man called police who came out and discovered the mans body stuffed inside the large brown case. The man appeared to be in his 20s, said investigators.
Jim Martin -- who walks his dog in the area called "Back Road" that sits just below flights paths -- said that he saw the case in the weeds a few days back and he noticed something strange about it.
"I smelled a smell -- you mentally think something, then you're like pause, pause it's my imagination," said Martin.
It wasn't. The investigation into the case continued late Thursday.
Published 5 hours ago
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:27:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Argentine Judge Orders Arrest of 3 Executives in FIFA Scandal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd7894/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cfifa0Ecorruption0Escandal0Cargentina0Ejudge0Eorders0Earrest0E30Eexecutives0Efifa0Escandal0En366296/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A judge in Argentina said Thursday that he had ordered the arrest of three businessmen named in a corruption scandal engulfing world soccer.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:27 pm ET
Argentine Judge Orders Arrest of 3 Executives in FIFA Scandal
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_30_nn_alexanderfifa_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
BUENOS AIRES  An Argentine judge said on Thursday he had ordered the arrest of three businessmen named in a corruption scandal engulfing world soccer and facing U.S. extradition requests, though he acknowledged he did not know if they were in the country.
Alejandro Burzaco, Hugo Jinkis and his son Mariano Jinkis, all Argentine citizens, are among five defendants who have apparently not been detained or arrested a day after the U.S. Department of Justice named them as among those facing corruption charges.
The U.S. Justice Department alleges that Burzaco, Hugo Jinkis and his son conspired to win and keep hold of lucrative media rights contracts from regional soccer federations through the payment of up to $110 million in bribes.
Related: FIFA Corruption Scandal: How Sepp Blatter Runs Soccer 'Like a Chicago Politician'
The three are among nine football officials and five sports media and promotions executives hit with U.S. corruption charges involving more than $150 million in bribes. Swiss police arrested seven of the senior soccer officials on Wednesday, plunging FIFA into its worst crisis in its 111-year history.
Of the remaining seven, two have been detained. Former FIFA vice-president Jack Warner surrendered to police in Trinidad and Tobago on Wednesday. Aaron Davidson, the U.S. head of Brazilian sports marketing firm Traffic Group, was arrested in Miami by the FBI on Wednesday.
U.S. officials are trying to extradite the defendants who remain outside the United States.
advertisement
In this May 14, 2015 photo, Conmebol delegate Roger Bello of Bolivia, left, talks with Boca Juniors goalkeeper Agustin Orion, center, and Alejandro Burzaco, right, president of Torneos y Competencias, moments before canceling the Copa Libertadores soccer match between Boca Juniors and River Plate in Buenos Aires, Argentina. A US Justice Department indictment was announced Wednesday, May 27, 2015, against nine FIFA officials and several corporate executives for racketeering, conspiracy and corruption. Burzaco is one of the sports marketing executives charged.Victor R. Caivano / AP
Burzaco is president of Argentine sports marketing firm Torneos y Competencias (Torneos), while Hugo and Mariano Jinkis are controlling principals of Full Play, another sports media and marketing business headquartered in Argentina.
The indictment states that Burzaco and the Jinkis' led their companies to form a new entity known as Datisa, which entered into a $317.5 million contract with CONMEBOL to obtain exclusive worldwide rights to the 2015, 2019 and 2023 Copa America tournaments.
Datisa later entered into a $35 million contract with the Confederation of North, Central America and Caribbean Association Football, CONCACAF, to acquire rights for another tournament, the Copa America Centenario.
Torneos on Wednesday denied any involvement in corrupt schemes to win contracts and said it was willing to work with judicial authorities.
Full Play did not immediately respond to an e-mailed request for comment on the U.S. allegations. Attempts to reach the three indicted men through the companies were unsuccessful.
Argentina's Cabinet Chief Anibal Fernandez said the country's tax authority would pursue any money owed to it.
"Illegal acts also pay taxes and in this case if it is proven that kickbacks were paid then they will have to pay an income tax of 35 percent," Fernandez said.
Contributor Reuters and Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:21:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>This May Explain Why DOD Accidentally Sent 'Live' Anthrax</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc4190/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Chealth0Ecare0Ctough0Espores0Emay0Eexplain0Eanthrax0Eblunder0Eexperts0Esay0En366151/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hard-to-kill anthrax spores may explain why the Department of Defense accidentally sent out "live" samples of the bacteria, experts say.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:21 pm ET
Tough Spores May Explain Anthrax Blunder, Experts Say
by Maggie Fox
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_snow_anthrax_scare_folo_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Hard-to-kill anthrax spores may explain why the Department of Defense accidentally sent out "live" samples of the bacteria, experts say.
The spores are so tough, and so tiny, that the irradiation procedure used to deactivate the spores might not have killed every single one.
John Peterson, a microbiology professor who works with anthrax at the University of Texas Medical Branch, says the X-rays or gamma rays used to kill anthrax spores might not get every little one.
"They were most likely inactivated but that the inactivation process may not have been complete," he told NBC News. Anthrax spores are only about 1 micron in diameter and a sample could contain 10 billion individual spores, he said.
"They are very difficult to kill."
advertisement
"If a procedure kills 99.999 percent of the bacteria, there would still be 100,000 spores left viable," he says. "They are very difficult to kill."
That's why, even though anthrax is not terribly infectious and is not fatal if it gets treated in time, is considered a potential biological weapon. The tough spores can be dispersed into the air and linger for months or even years, putting people at risk of infection.
The DoD is trying to explain how and why live anthrax spores were sent to labs in nine states and to an Air Force base in South Korea in recent months. At least 26 people who handled or were near the samples are taking antibiotics just in case they breathed in any of the spores.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_flashback_anthrax_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
Officials say the investigation is focusing on the irradiation process used to inactivate the spores.
Anthrax bacteria  the scientific name is Bacillus anthracis  live in the soil normally. They make spores when living conditions get tough, for instance, if it gets very dry. "When conditions improve, everything it needs to live again is there," Peterson said. "It can sense nutrients."
In nature, that would mean a rainfall, for instance. But if a spore landed in a lung, that could also signal for it to germinate and multiply.
"It only takes a very small number. A single spore will cause the culture to become positive."
A Maryland lab that received one of the shipments first notified DoD about the live spores. Peterson said the lab was almost certainly doing a validation test, which involves putting the spores into a nourishing broth that would encourage them to grow.
advertisement
"It only takes a very small number. A single spore will cause the culture to become positive," Peterson said.
But a single spore cannot cause an infection, Peterson said. "It is not the most virulent agent," he said. Studies of anthrax show it takes 2,500 to 50,000 spores to infect.
Even if lab workers thought the anthrax was completely dead, they would have handled it carefully and it would have been packaged in a way to fully contain the spores, Peterson and other experts agreed. Defense officials and the Centers for Disease control and Prevention say there is no risk to the public.
Officials said the government labs that received the potentially live anthrax samples were at the Army's Edgewood Proving Ground in Maryland and the Naval Surface Warfare Center in Virginia. The Pentagon has declined to identify the other labs.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:20:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to Surf the Web Safely at 30,000 Feet</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd3fd6/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Chow0Esurf0Eweb0Esafely0E30A0E0A0A0A0Efeet0En366226/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Unthinkable just a few years ago, Internet access is now widely available on planes in flight. But it carries the same risks as on the ground.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:20 pm ET
How to Surf the Web Safely at 30,000 Feet
by Tom Costello
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_cos_plane_wifi_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Chances are, you've already done what was unthinkable just a few years ago: Surfed the web from a plane.
But security experts warn that logging on to a plane's WiFi system carries the same risks as logging on to any public hotspot. The bottom line is that sophisticated hackers and crooks can intercept your internet activity and gain access to your digital life.
"It even doesn't matter if these networks are encrypted or not," said James Lyne, the head of security at Sophos Security. "When you connect to them, you're handing over your destiny of your internet connection to some unknown stranger."
To safeguard your digital privacy, Sophos Security suggests taking some basic precautions:
Treat every public WiFi as an open door to your computer.
Avoid accessing your bank account information via public WiFi. If someone is watching, they can quickly grab your username, password and account balances.
If you're concerned about email security, wait until you're on ground and using a trusted internet connection to check your inbox.
And depending on your level of paranoia, you may want to also avoid logging on to any social media websites where you keep personal information or photos.
Anytime you're using a public WiFi, even while flying across the country, there's a chance someone is watching.
The nation's largest provider of inflight WiFi access, Gogo, says its connection to access Wi-Fi is secure  but once users start surfing the web, the connection is not encrypted.
"The connection through which users purchase Gogo is an SSL-encrypted link and is secure. However, following the purchase, due to the many users of our Inflight Wi-Fi access point, Gogo does not provide an encrypted communication channel between our Inflight Wi-Fi access point and the user's computer."
advertisement
"Past the purchase point, GoGo operates similar to any public WiFi hotspot on the ground," the company said.
Gogo, along with many security experts, suggest customers use a Virtual Private Network (VPN) for the best security. A VPN takes your information, puts it into a bubble and encrypts it, protecting the data from being intercepted.
Another good security practice involves ensuring that file-sharing is not enabled while accessing the Internet from an un-encrypted public network and that laptops have firewall and other protection against malware.
"The reality is, cyber crime is entirely opportunistic and every time you connect to the internet, you are a target," Lyne said.
Tom Costello
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:12:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Speaker Hastert Indicted Over Alleged Hush Money Withdrawals</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc8ae7/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cformer0Espeaker0Eu0Es0Ehouse0Erepresentatives0Edennis0Ehastert0Eindicted0En366276/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Prosecutors say for the past four years the former Republican Speaker of the House has paid $1.7 million dollars in apparent hush money.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 7:12 pm ET
Former Speaker of U.S. House of Representatives Dennis Hastert Indicted
by Phil Helsel
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_wil_hastert_charged_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Former Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives J. Dennis Hastert was indicted on federal charges Thursday for allegedly structuring the withdrawal of over $950,000 in cash in a way to avoid reporting requirements, and then lying to the FBI about it.
Hastert allegedly took out the cash and handed it over to a Yorkville, Illinois, resident "in order to compensate and conceal his prior misconduct" against that person, according to the indictment.
Hastert, 73, of Plano, Illinois, is charged with one count each of structuring currency transactions to evade currency transaction reports and making a false statement to the FBI, the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Northern District of Illinois said.
Hastert, a Republican, served as speaker of the House of Representatives from 1999 to 2007. Hastert resigned in 2007, and has been working as a lobbyist since 2008, according to the government.
The indictment alleges that Hastert withdrew $1.7 million from 2010 to 2014 and gave it to the unidentified person, referred to in the indictment as "individual A."
advertisement
The indictment does not specify what the acts were or when they happened, only that they occurred "years earlier." The indictment says "individual A" has known Hastert for most of his or her life, but does not elaborate on the relationship. The indictment says Hastert was a high school teacher and coach in Yorkville from 1965 to 1981.
Hastert is accused of withdrawing $952,000 of that $1.7 million in increments of less than $10,000 so as to avoid regulations that require banks to report withdrawals over that amount.
Hastert agreed in 2010 to pay "individual A" a total of $3.5 million in compensation, according to the indictment.
Hastert at first made larger withdrawals, taking out $50,000 at a time on 15 occasions between June 2010 and April 2012, but scaled back the withdrawals to less than $10,000 at a time after bank officials questioned him about the larger amounts, according to the indictment.
When asked about the withdrawals by the FBI in December, Hastert allegedly told agents, "Yeah ... I kept the cash. That's what I'm doing," when he was actually giving the money to "individual A" as part of the agreement.
advertisement
Under the alleged agreement, Hastert handed over $50,000 cash payments to "individual A" every six weeks. In 2014, the former congressman began paying that person $100,000 every three months, according to the indictment.
The FBI began investigating Hastert in 2013, partly because investigators wanted to know if he was the victim of an extortion scheme, court documents said.
Each of the two criminal charges carries a maximum penalty of 5 years in prison and a $250,000 fine, the U.S. Attorney's Office said. A court date has not yet been set.
Hastert served as a U.S. Representative from 1987 until his resignation on Nov. 26, 2007.
Hastert spent 16 years as a teacher of history, economics and government at Yorkville High School, where he also coached football and wrestling, according to his biography on the Wheaton College website, where he earned a bachelor's degree in 1964.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosmetic Face 'Fillers' Can Go Tragically Wrong, FDA Warns</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bded28/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Chealth0Enews0Ccosmetic0Eface0Efillers0Ecan0Ego0Ewrong0Efda0Ewarns0En366261/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Cosmetic facial fillers, which can plump thin lips or erase wrinkles, can go badly and tragically wrong, the FDA warned Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 6:37 pm ET
Cosmetic Face 'Fillers' Can Go Wrong, FDA Warns
by Maggie Fox
Injecting Restylane. Dr. Paul Lorenc administers a Restylane treatment to patient Ania Dorfman in New York City on Monday, Feb. 23, 2004. Dorfman chose the treatment to reduce her 'naso-labial folds,' the lines from the nose to the sides of the mouth.(Photo by David Friedman / MSNBC.com)David Friedman / NBC News
Share
advertisement
Cosmetic facial fillers, which can plump thin lips or erase wrinkles, can go badly and tragically wrong, the Food and Drug Administration warned Thursday.
If the materials used to fill the skin get into a blood vessel, they can cause a stroke, blindness, or kill off big patches of skin, the FDA says in a new warning.
"Unintentional injection can block blood vessels and restrict blood supply to tissues," the FDA says in its warning to consumers and doctors.
"Unintentional injection can block blood vessels and restrict blood supply to tissues."
"Soft tissue fillers should be injected only by health care providers who have appropriate training and experience and who are knowledgeable about the anatomy at and around the injection site," it adds.
advertisement
The places most likely to cause trouble: the skin between the eyebrows and nose (called the glabella), in and around the nose, forehead, and around the eyes.
A team led by Cemile Nurdan Ozturk of the Cleveland Clinic found reports about 61 patients who had severe complications from facial filler procedures, including dead tissue in the nose.
Some of the materials in these fillers include hyaluronic acid, which is the main ingredient in products sold under brand names Restylane, Perlane and Juvederm. They're injected into wrinkles around the mouth, used to fill out deep scars and pock marks and to plump lips.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_cynthia_cosmetic_150303" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
A product called Radiesse is made using calcium hydroxyapatite and another called Sculptra uses poly-L-lactic acid, which are both designed to stimulate natural collagen production. Some providers use fat taken from elsewhere in the body.
One study published in the journal Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery found that these autologous fat injections were the most likely to cause permanent blindness. "Some cases of partial visual recovery have been reported with hyaluronic acid and calcium hydroxylapatite fillers," the researchers wrote.
FDA says patients need to take care to go to providers who know what they are doing.
"Before deciding to have soft tissue filler injections, talk with your health care provider about appropriate treatment injection sites and the risks associated with the procedure," the agency advises
"Ask your health care provider about their training and experience injecting soft tissue fillers in the face."
advertisement
"Be aware that FDA reviewed and approved different products for use in certain areas of the face. The FDA may not have reviewed the use of certain soft tissue fillers for all locations in the body. Ask your health care provider about their training and experience injecting soft tissue fillers in the face."
Many experts complain that non-specialists, even dentists, are starting to offer these procedures and products.
One product that doesn't have this particular problem is Botox, although fake Botox can cause its own problems. Injected incorrectly, Botox, which uses a natural toxin to freeze muscle temporarily, can cause permanent nerve damage.
Maggie Fox
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:49:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Former Michigan Cop to Stand Trial for Beating Unarmed Man</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bd085a/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cformer0Emichigan0Ecop0Ewilliam0Emelendez0Estand0Etrial0Ebeating0Eunarmed0Eman0En36620A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A former suburban Detroit police officer caught on camera beating an unarmed black man during a traffic stop will stand trial.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 5:49 pm ET
Former Michigan Cop William Melendez to Stand Trial for Beating of Unarmed Man, Floyd Dent
by Daniella Silva
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_dent_testifies_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A former suburban Detroit police officer caught on camera repeatedly punching, kicking and tasering an unarmed black man during a traffic stop will stand trial, a district court judge ruled Thursday afternoon.
Former Inkster, Michigan, officer William Melendez was charged with assault with intent to do great bodily harm and misconduct in office and fired after a January incident involving Floyd Dent, who was stopped after running a stop sign.
Wayne County District Court Judge Sabrina Johnson found there was enough evidence to put Melendez on trial Thursday afternoon, approving an additional charge of assault with strangulation after Dent testified in court and recounted the night he was arrested.
advertisement
Melendez's next court date is set for June 10.
Dash-cam video shows Melendez dragging Dent out of his vehicle, putting him in a choke hold and striking him repeatedly during a traffic stop on Jan. 28. The video was first obtained and released by NBC affiliate WDIV in March.
"Why you beating on me like this?" Dent can be heard asking after he was thrown onto the hood of a police cruiser.
A judge dismissed various charges against Dent following the video's release, including resisting arrest and assaulting a police office. Prosecutors also dropped drug charges against Dent, who claimed police planted a bag of crack cocaine in his car during the stop. He admitted to driving on a suspended license at the time.
In March, Dent passed a lie detector test where he was asked whether he verbally threatened the officers, if the police were correct about him having crack cocaine in his vehicle and if he was lying about the drugs. He answered "No," to each question and passed, NBC affiliate WDIV reported.
Judge Johnson's decision follows Dent settling his lawsuit with the city of Inkster for $1.4 million on Wednesday, according to WDIV .
"Money isn't everything," Dent, told the station. "You can't buy happiness."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:13:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Guitars, Rings and Cameras: Welcome to the Land of Lost Luggage</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc4cdb/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Cguitars0Erings0Ecameras0Ewelcome0Eland0Elost0Eluggage0En366251/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tucked away in rural northeastern Alabama, miles from any major airport, is the last stop for the nation's lost luggage.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_sha_lost_luggage_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Tucked away in rural northeastern Alabama, miles from any major airport, is the last stop for the nation's lost luggage.
If you've ever lost a suitcase on an airplane or left a cell phone in a seat-back pocket, chances are it could be here. Or, was here.
Janet Shamlian
advertisement
The Unclaimed Baggage Center in tiny Scottsboro, Alabama, buys left-behind bags from major airlines as well as bus and train companies and then sells what's inside them at a deep discount.
"We actually buy unclaimed baggage from planes, trains and automobiles, sight unseen," said Brenda Cantrell, brand ambassador for the Unclaimed Baggage Center. "We have no idea what's in the bags when we purchase them."
Visitors are drawn here from down the street  and all over the world.
Shopper Jerry Brown is a regular and has been visiting the store since 1972.
"There's a crew of us that's kind of like the Breakfast Club that meets down here every morning," Brown said. "We just enjoy doing this, it's fun."
advertisement
One walk through the aisles of the 40,000-square-foot store and you'll feel like you're in a well-stocked department store. The place features top brands, many items are new with the store tags still attached, and the electronics department could give an Apple store a run for its money. Last year, the Unclaimed Baggage Center sold 3400 iPads. They also cell iPhones, headphones, cameras, laptops and everything that goes with them: cases , covers, tripods and chargers. The center says it puts out more than 5,000 items a day, with discounts run from 20 to 80-percent less than you would pay for the item now.
So how good are the deals? Shopper Jeanne Hupfer walked away with an iPad for $164.
"It's a good deal," Hupfer said. "We're tickled."
So why aren't these items returned to the owner? The UCB says it has exclusive contracts (with carriers it won't name) to buy the items after the airlines and other companies have settled claims with customers. The items couldn't be returned because they had no identification. Airlines say only  of 1 percent of checked bags are lost, and of those, 98 percent are eventually returned.
advertisement
But with millions of people traveling every day, those bags that aren't reunited with their owner contain enough merchandise to fill a warehouse. If there's a take-away here, it's label everything!
It's not just clothes and cameras, from a fiberglass cast of a shark to a suit of armor, it's surprising what gets lost in transit. The most unusual items are on display in the Unclaimed Baggage Center.
Some suspect these bridesmaids dresses were left behind intentionally!Janet Shamlian
"This is absolutely an insight to people's traveling habits, people's packing habits, even their technology habits," Cantrell said. "You come across these gems where you have something amazing from a foreign country or an exquisite piece of jewelry, it's amazing."
Whether you're coming to shop or just to browse, one thing is for sure  you never know what you'll find in the land of lost luggage.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:10:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ten Youngsters Advance to Spelling Bee's Final Round</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc4cdc/sc/35/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cten0Eyoungsters0Eadvance0Efinal0Eround0Espelling0Ebee0En366146/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ten of the best spellers in the nation are one round closer to a big W-I-N in the 88th Scripps National Spelling Bee.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 4:10 pm ET
Ten Youngsters Advance to Final Round of the Spelling Bee
by Elizabeth Chuck
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_1to4spelling_bee_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Ten of the best spellers in the nation on Thursday moved one step closer to a big W-I-N in the 88th Scripps National Spelling Bee.
The ten finalists will compete Thursday night for more than $37,000 in cash and prizes. Dev Jaiswal, a 13-year-old from Louisville, Mississippi, had the No. 1 score coming out of the semifinals on Thursday afternoon.
Several of the finalists are spelling bee veterans: 13-year-old Vanya Shivashankar of Olathe, Kansas, is competing for the fifth time; 14-year-old Gokul Venkatachalam of Chesterfield, Missouri, came in third last year; and 12-year-old Tejas Muthusamy of Glen Allen, Virginia, was a finalist last year, too.
advertisement
Vanya's sister, Kavya, won the bee in 2009. If Vanya wins, they will be the first siblings to win the championship.
Ankita Vadiala of Manassas, Virginia, reacts after correctly spelling her word during the semifinal round of the 88th Annual Scripps National Spelling Bee at National Harbor in Oxon Hill, Maryland, May 28, 2015. SAUL LOEB / AFP - Getty Images
Before the competition, Vanya told NBC affiliate KSHB in Kansas, "I've studied a lot of words. The longest word in the dictionary is pneumonoultramicroscopicsilicovolcanoconiosis. That would have to be one of my favorites."
The word  which Vanya proceeded to spell correctly  refers to a lung disease caused by silica dust.
Nearly 300 contestants entered this year's Spelling Bee. Among them was a cast member of the Broadway musical "Annie," and a champion snowboarder, The Associated Press reported.
The finals air Thursday night on ESPN at 8 p.m. ET.
Elizabeth Chuck
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:39:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>It's Almost Summer, But There's Still Snow in Boston</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc41a7/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cits0Ealmost0Esummer0Etheres0Estill0Esnow0Eground0Eboston0En366161/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 75-foot-high snow mound has been reduced to a three-story pile of dirt and trash, encrusted in solid ice.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 3:39 pm ET
It's Almost Summer, But There's Still Snow on the Ground in Boston
by Associated Press
advertisement
Snow piles from the record-setting New England winter are lingering in the Boston area, even as the weather turns summer-like.
A 75-foot-high snow mound in Boston's Seaport District has been reduced to a three-story pile of dirt and trash  including bicycles, traffic cones and even half a $5 bill  that remains encrusted in solid ice.
A spring snow farm looks more like a dirt pile left over from a harsh winter on May 20. David L. Ryan           / Boston Globe
Department of Public Works Commissioner Michael Dennehy tells The Boston Globe the vile pile is "a science experiment waiting to happen."
Crews have been working for six weeks to clean away the trash as it breaks free from the mound. So far, they have pulled out 85 tons of debris.
Dennehy says the pile will be around for weeks, even as the air temperature hits 80.
Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:47:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>California City Cancels Fireworks Because of Drought</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bbf6f7/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcbayarea0N0Cnews0Clocal0CCupertino0EStrikes0EFireworks0EShow0EBecause0Eof0EDrought0E30A53365410Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>There won't be any July 4 pyrotechnics in Cupertino, home to Silicon Valley giant Apple, as a result of water-saving measures, officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cupertino Cancels Fireworks Because of Drought, Synthetic Grass Too Water-Intensive For Show Prep
The city could be the first in California to cancel fireworks because of drought
It takes 100,000 gallons of water to spray fields at Cupertino High School.
Updated 6 hours ago
The city of Cupertino won't be having a fireworks show on July 4 because of California's drought, and in an odd twist, the reason is because the Silicon Valley suburb was trying to be extra conscious of saving water.
People are very disappointed, said city spokesman Rick Kitson. Who doesnt love fireworks? But overall, I think they get it.
El Nio Could Bring Rain, Mudslides to Drought-Stricken California
And though no agency formally tracks fireworks cancellations related to drought, Cupertino  home to Apple Inc. headquarters  could be the first city in California to squash such a pyrotechnics display as the state enters its fourth year of drought.
Until this year, Cupertino was one of the rare spots in the Bay Area to still host city-funded firework shows while other cities, such as Livermore, Hercules, Oakland and San Leandro, cut such events during the recession. Kitson said the last time the city cancelled a show was about a decade ago, and that was for monetary reasons.
Dramatic Photos of California's Drought
The reason the community show was nixed this year is because of water conservation efforts, not finances.
Cupertino High School switched to artificial turf a while back, in part, Kitson said, to save money on watering the lawns.
Woman Bitten by Black Widow Spider Found in Grapes
And its those synthetic fields, where thousands of people congregate, that need 100,000 gallons of water to douse both before and after the fireworks display, according to the Fremont Unified School District. District officials said they reluctantly are shutting the show down because of the extreme water usage.
The water is needed to prevent any fireworks fallout on synthetic grass that would yield a mass of burning plastic, Kitson pointed out, adding that a little bit of sparks and ash on real grass isnt that big of a deal.
Extreme Weather 2015
Because weve done the right thing, the total use of water becomes more conspicuous, Kitson said. Youve got to hose down the plastic before and a lot afterward.
Cupertino is doing several things to counter the drought  not just saying no to fireworks. The city has turned off two fountains and is letting the grass turn brown on public land.
Lisa Lien-Mager, spokeswoman for the Association of California Water Agencies, said her agency is not tracking whether cities cancel fireworks shows because of the drought. But she did say that in past droughts, some communities have disbanded such events.
In 2012, three Chicago suburbs cancelled fireworks shows because of a persistent drought in the Midwest.
Woman Stabbed in Eye With Fork in Dispute Over Last Rib: Police
While the cherry bombs and Chinese crackers wont be popping off to celebrate Americas birthday, Kitson said the city of about 60,000 is going to play up other July 4 extravaganzas so that Cupertinos residents wont be gypped.
The city, he said, will give extra care to the morning parade, the community swim and the pancake breakfast.
Were going to make those activities a lot bigger, Kitson said. There will still be a lot to do."
Published at 8:53 AM PDT on May 28, 2015

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:24:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Comedy Central Sets Trevor Noah's 'Daily Show' Debut</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46baf1d2/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpop0Eculture0Ctv0Ctrevor0Enoah0Emake0Edaily0Eshow0Ehost0Edebut0Eseptember0E280En3660A86/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Trevor Noah is set to take over the anchor chair at "The Daily Show" with a September 28th debut this fall, Comedy Central announced Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 1:24 pm ET
Trevor Noah to Make Debut as Host of 'The Daily Show' on September 28
by Daniella Silva
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_tren_trevor_150330" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Trevor Noah, the South African comedian tapped to succeed Jon Stewart as host of "The Daily Show," will officially begin his duties on September 28, Comedy Central announced Thursday.
. @Trevornoah starts his new job September 28. Late night will NEVER BE THE SAME. Or maybe it will. Watch to find out. http://t.co/axWSKRD2U3
advertisement
A video on Comedy Central's website featured the new host "getting comfortable in Jon's chair."
Noah, 31, landed the hosting gig in March. He was first hired as an on-air contributor in December, and he had appeared on the show just three times before the network announced he would become its anchor.
Stewart, who has anchored the show since 1999, has said his final appearance on the satirical news program would be on August 6.
Less than a day after Comedy Central announced Noah's new role, he was criticized for old Twitter posts  some of which were interpreted as anti-Semitic or misogynistic .
Noah responded, saying his critics shouldn't judge him based on a few tweets alone.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:28:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Unarmed Man Beaten During Traffic Stop Settles for $1.4M</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46ba06d1/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cfloyd0Edent0Eman0Ebeaten0Emichigan0Ecops0Ecamera0Esettles0E10E4m0En365931/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dent was beaten and put in a choke hold during a January traffic stop in the Detroit suburb of Inkster.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 12:28 pm ET
Floyd Dent, Man Beaten by Michigan Cops on Camera, Settles for $1.4 Million
by Erik Ortiz
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_dent_testifies_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
An unarmed black man who was repeatedly punched, kicked and Tasered during a January traffic stop in the Detroit suburb of Inkster has agreed to a $1.4 million settlement with the city, NBC affiliate WDIV reported Wednesday.
"Money isn't everything," the man, Floyd Dent, told the station. "You can't buy happiness."
Dent's arrest on alleged assault and drug charges during a routine traffic stop continues to haunt him, he said. Dashcam video of the incident showed one Inkster officer, William Melendez, putting Dent, 57, in a chokehold and repeatedly punching him.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_settlement_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Prosecutors dropped the charges against Dent , who claimed police planted a bag of crack cocaine underneath his passenger seat during the stop. He did admit to driving on a suspended license at the time.
Amid public outcry over the case, Inkster's police chief resigned in April, two officers were suspended and Melendez was fired and charged with misconduct in office and assault with intent to do great bodily harm.
advertisement
A Wayne County district court judge was expected to decide Thursday if there's enough evidence to put Melendez on trial. Dent began testifying in the morning, and recounted the night that he was arrested.
Dent earlier told WDIV that he wishes the beating never happened, although he's pleased to see Melendez off the streets. He hopes to go back to work at Ford Motor Co., and get on with his life.
"I want people to remember me as an honest person  a person who told the truth, a person not scared to go against the officers that done this to me," Dent said. "I want people to know that I'm grateful."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:01:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA President: 'No Place for Corruption of Any Kind'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46ba61d6/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cfifa0Ecorruption0Escandal0Cfifa0Echief0Esepp0Eblatter0Esays0Ecorruption0Earrests0Ebring0Eshame0Ehumiliation0En3660A66/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>He stands for re-election on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 12:01 pm ET
FIFA Chief Sepp Blatter Says Corruption Arrests Bring 'Shame and Humiliation' to Soccer
by Erin McClam
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_blatterspeech_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Sepp Blatter, the president of FIFA and the most powerful man in world soccer, said Thursday that corrupt executives have brought "shame and humiliation" to the sport but are "in the thin minority."
"I will not allow the actions of a few to destroy the hard work and the integrity of the vast majority of those who work so hard for football," he said at the opening ceremony of the FIFA annual meeting in Zurich.
"There can be no place for corruption of any kind," he said. "The next few months will not be easy for FIFA. I am sure more bad news will follow, but it is necessary to begin to restore trust in our organization. Let this be the turning point."
Related: FIFA Executives Held Over Corruption
He said that he "cannot monitor everyone all of the time," but he said it will fall to him to be responsible for the well-being of the organization.
Seven current or former FIFA executives were arrested in Zurich on Wednesday as American prosecutors, working with the Swiss, cracked down on what they called rampant corruption in soccer.
In all, 14 people were indicted, and four others previously pleaded guilty. Prosecutors said the executives took bribes and kickbacks tied to lucrative marketing and television deals. Executives were also accused of rigging the bid process for the 2010 World Cup.
Blatter himself was not accused of wrongdoing, but corruption allegations have swirled around him for years. He is up for re-election on Friday, seeking a fifth four-year term as president.
FIFA President Sepp Blatter looks on during a press conference on March 20.Philipp Schmidli / Getty Images
Erin McClam
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:48:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran Group Stages Cartoon Contest to Ridicule ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bbf6f6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Ciran0Elaunches0Eanti0Eisis0Ecartoon0Ecompetition0En3660A31/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A cartoon competition aimed at ridiculing ISIS has been launched in Iran by the same organization that held another event on Holocaust denial.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 11:48 am ET
Iran Group Stages Cartoon Contest to Ridicule ISIS
by F. Brinley Bruton
advertisement
A cartoon competition aimed at ridiculing ISIS militants has been launched in Iran by the same organization that held similar events on the theme of Holocaust denial .
"Enthusiastic artists from over 43 countries have submitted their work" to the contest about ISIS' "crimes," semi-official Tehran-based House of Cartoons said on its website .
A total of 280 works were selected from 800 submissions and put on display in the exhibit, said the executive editor of the contest Mohammad Habibi, according to state-run news site IRNA.
The winners will be announced on Sunday.
Militias backed by majority Shiite Muslim Iran are battling extremist Sunni ISIS, which has overrun swathes of Iraq and Syria. While tensions between Shiite and Sunni Muslims have existed for centuries, they have worsened in recent years with largely Sunni Saudi Arabia competing with Iran for regional hegemony.
Related: Iran's Qasem Soleimani Is Guiding Iraqi Forces in Fight Against ISIS
Earlier this year, House of Cartoons held a competition where entrants artists had to address questions like: "If the West says that freedom of speech has no borders then why don't they let historians and experts properly research the Holocaust?" and "Why should the Palestinian people pay for the Holocaust?"
All had to be submitted by April Fools' Day because "April 1 is the day of big lies, and the Holocaust is a big lie that the Zionists invented to suppress the Palestinians," Masoud Shojaei-Tabatabaii, head of House of Cartoons and one of the competition's organizers, said at the time.
F. Brinley Bruton
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:41:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why Are So Many Republicans Running for President?</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46bc4cd5/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cmeet0Ethe0Epress0Cwhy0Eseven0Ereasons0Ewhy0Eso0Emany0Erepublicans0Eare0Erunning0Epresident0En3660A61/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Chuck's Take: History, money and media all play a role in explaining how the Republican presidential field grew to nearly 20 candidates.</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 11:41 am ET
7 Reasons Why So Many Republicans Are Running for President
by Perry Bacon Jr.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_chuck_field_150528" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The GOP presidential field for 2016 may be the largest-ever in either party, with eight formally-declared candidates and another eight widely expected to enter the race in the next few months. Here are seven reasons why there are so many Republicans seeking the White House:
1. The Fame Game
To put it simply, running for president can make a person famous, rich, deeply influential or all three, even if they lose. Former Arkansas Gov. Mike Huckabee was a serious candidate during his 2008 run, winning eight states. It's unlikely he entered the race simply to gain fame.
But his unsuccessful campaign helped him get a show on Fox News. It's hard to imagine he would have received such an opportunity without having run for president and become a favorite of the most conservative Republicans.
After his unsuccessful campaign in 2012, Rick Santorum was tapped to run a company that makes Christian-themed movies. Herman Cain was a virtually unknown former businessman who is now popular among conservative activists after his campaign four years ago.
advertisement
Sarah Palin didn't actually run for president, but she's perhaps the perfect example of how a national campaign can change a politician's life. Her vice-presidential run turned into a book deal, a tv show and both fame and money that she never could have achieved as governor of Alaska. (Test: Do you know the name of the current governor of Alaska?)
She also, at least for a time, gained major sway within the Republican Party. Candidates wanted her endorsement and for Palin to campaign with them.
It's hard to determine the motives of any individual politician. That said, Ben Carson fits the fame incentives perfectly. He's already drawn a huge amount of attention to himself through his candidacy that could help him sell books and appear on FOX News for years after his 2016 run.
Carly Fiorina and Donald Trump are both already famous and wealthy from their time in the business world. But presidential candidacies give them a chance for influence in a different realm. Fiorina in particular is increasing her chances of being appointed to the Cabinet of the next Republican president.
2. Redemption
advertisement
The national spotlight does sometimes hurt a politician. In 2011, Rick Perry was on his way to finishing what was considered a strong tenure as governor of Texas. Then, he opted to run for president and became a national laughingstock, unable in a debate to recall the three government agencies he was promising to close if elected president.
Perry though has a ready-made solution: a second campaign. Running for president can serve as a kind of redemption tour for politicians, even if they don't win.
Rick Santorum had been effectively forced out of politics, losing by more than 17 points during his 2006 reelection race in Pennsylvania. His long-shot presidential run in 2012 reinvigorated his political life.
Former New York Gov. George Pataki, who left that office in 2007, could be a more important figure in Republican politics through his presidential campaign, even though he is almost certain to lose. New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie could use his campaign to distance himself from the "Bridgegate" scandal.
3. Barack Obama
advertisement
For senators like Ted Cruz, Rand Paul and Marco Rubio in particular, the Obama example is hard to ignore. In the past, the presidential field was usually composed of sitting or former vice-presidents and then senators or governors who had already served at least one term in office. George W. Bush won reelection as governor of Texas in 1998, then started running for president. John Kerry had been a long-term senator from Massachusetts.
Obama had barely served two years in the Senate before opting to run for president in 2008. And he won. So Cruz, Paul and Rubio are in effect making the same case Obama did seven years ago: the time for my leadership and vision is now, and I can't lead from the Senate.
4. No Incumbent president
Obama is relevant in another way. In 2008, like in 2016, there is no incumbent president or sitting vice-president in the field. In 2012, even as Republicans dismissed Obama as a failed president, many potential candidates were wary of running against him, aware of the advantages incumbent presidents have.
Hillary Clinton is almost like a sitting vice-president, since the Democratic Party is mobilized around her and she is facing no strong challenger in the primary. But winning the third straight term for the same party is much harder than a president going for reelection.
advertisement
The Republican nominee will have a very strong chance of being elected president by simply running as a change candidate and arguing the country does not need a third term of Obama-like policies.
Rubio is young, so he could have waited to run for president. But what Obama showed in 2008 was that running at the right time can overcome a lack of experience. In 2020, a Republican could have won in 2016, so Rubio would have to wait out that person's tenure. Or Clinton or another Democrat would be president, forcing Rubio to face the power of incumbency.
5. No Strong Front-Runner
Hillary Clinton's strength is keeping other Democrats out of the race. On the Republican side, over the first five months of the campaign, a trio of front-runners have emerged: Jeb Bush, Marco Rubio and Scott Walker.
But they all have potential flaws. Bush is more moderate on issues like immigration than many GOP activists, and some conservatives were turned off by his father and brother's presidencies and are wary of a third Bush tenure. Rubio is a first-term senator and co-wrote a bill that would have granted citizenship to undocumented immigrants. Walker is untested on the national stage and made some mistakes early on, like non-answering when asked if Obama is a Christian.
The weakness of the front-runners is drawing into the race candidates, like Ohio Gov. John Kasich, who see a path to victory if those three flounder.
6. The Rise of Super PAC's
In the days when a candidate could only raise money in $2000 increments, it would have been hard for Rubio to run. He is not personally rich, and much of the GOP establishment who might have otherwise backed him instead went for Bush.
But with a few mega-donors bankrolling his super PAC, Rubio may be outspent by Bush, but the senator can raise enough to be a credible candidate.
Being able to raise money in unlimited amounts also helps someone like Kasich who has entered the race so late.
7. The Republican Party is Very Divided on Policy
Some of the Republican candidates have very strong, distinct views of policy that they feel uniquely qualified to advocate. Bush, Rubio and Kasich all want to create a kind of post-Tea Party GOP that is more focused on offering conservative policy solutions than shrinking the size of government.
Paul is pushing to reduce the size and scope of the U.S. government's footprint both at home and abroad. His policy views, from winding down the war on drugs to limiting national security surveillance programs, would be a sharp contrast to much of the Republican Party's current ideology. On some issues, if Paul were not running, no other candidate would be expressing these views.
Huckabee and Santorum want the Republican Party to shift away from its close alliance with big business. They are more skeptical about the benefits of immigration and free trade than the rest of the field.
Walker and Cruz are deeply conservative on nearly every issue and want to push the country in that direction. Their presidencies would likely include deep cuts to programs like Medicaid and food stamps, pushes to weaken the power of labor unions, more limits on abortion rights and the appointments of strong conservatives as federal judges.
Bush, Kasich and Rubio are pitching a more efficient and effective version of George W. Bush's conservatism. Electing Walker or Cruz would likely result in policies much closer to that of Tea Party activists and House Republicans.
Perry Bacon Jr.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:29:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Why It's a Big Deal That Nebraska Nixed Death Penalty</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/46b93ae3/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cmeet0Ethe0Epress0Cnebraska0Ejust0Enixed0Edeath0Epenalty0Eheres0Ewhy0Ethats0Ebig0Edeal0En365911/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>First Read is a morning briefing from Meet the Press and the NBC Political Unit on the day's most important political stories and why they matter</Description>
        <MainBody>May 28 2015, 11:29 am ET
Nebraska Just Nixed the Death Penalty. Here's Why That's a Big Deal
by Chuck Todd, Mark Murray and Carrie Dann
Restraints are shown on a table inside the death chamber of the new lethal injection facility at San Quentin State Prison in San Quentin, Calif., Sept. 21, 2010.Eric Risberg / AP file
Share
First Read is a morning briefing from Meet the Press and the NBC Political Unit on the day's most important political stories and why they matter
Why Nebraska eliminating the death penalty is a big deal
Maybe the most significant political story in the country over the past 24 hours didn't take place in Washington, DC, or on the 2016 campaign trail. Instead, it's what happened yesterday in Nebraska, which repealed the death penalty in the state after Republican and Democratic lawmakers overrode -- barely -- the GOP governor's veto. "In the most suspenseful decision to play out in Nebraska's one-house Legislature in years, lawmakers voted 30-19 to override Gov. Pete Ricketts' veto of Legislative Bill 268. Without a vote to spare, the override replaced lethal injection with life in prison," the Omaha World-Herald notes . This is a big deal for three reasons. One, Nebraska becomes the first red state in the country to repeal the death penalty in 40 years (after North Dakota did it in 1973 ). Two, it comes after at least one national poll ( Pew ) had found a drop in support of the death penalty. (If you don't think that public opinion on a social issue can change in a hurry, just look at gay marriage.) And three, it comes in the midst of a bipartisan effort -- even among Dem and GOP 2016ers -- to overhaul the nation's criminal-justice system.
advertisement
The '80s and '90s vs. now
Indeed, just compare the 1980s/1990s with now. Back in the '80s and '90s, the conversation was titled to "three strikes and you're out," stiff drug penalties, and the death penalty. Bill Clinton, in fact, used his support of the death penalty to prove his tough-on-crime credentials in 1992. But now? We're seeing a backlash to that era. For all the divide that we highlight on cultural issues in this country which usually gets amplified by partisan media, this shift on crime and punishment is even more remarkable. Is there a single moment that triggered this change in the American psyche? Hard to find one but between DNA testing raising doubts about some convictions which sparked the initial public questioning of the death penalty (see Illinois and George Ryan) to the fact that crime didn't rise but dropped during the last recession, there is simply a sea change in how society views these issues. And as for the implementation of the death penalty, as more doubts are raised about whether lethal injection is humane, and it's possible we are less than a generation away from the death penalty becoming nearly obsolete. As we noted above, cultural shifts on issues happen much faster in today's world.
Why are so many Republicans running for president?
Turning to the 2016 race, former New York Gov. George Pataki today becomes the latest GOP candidate to enter the presidential race . And it now looks like Ohio Gov. John Kasich is a sure bet to get in, too . So why are there so many Republicans -- as many as 18 (!!!) -- running in the 2016 race? Here are two obvious answers: 1) It's an open seat with history on the GOP's side (only once since Truman has a party held on to the White House for more than two terms), and 2) Jeb Bush isn't intimidating anyone. But it's more than that. Another answer is the Santorum Effect -- as 2012 proved, anyone has the ability to be the last man standing against the eventual nominee. There's also the Huckabee Effect -- a strong presidential performance can win you a TV contract. Then there is this fact: There are so many political reporters that almost ANY candidate can get some kind of coverage and find oxygen to justify an existence. And finally, in the Super PAC Era, all it takes is for one political sugar daddy/momma to keep you in the game.
advertisement
Jindal takes aim at Paul
Is it possible that the criteria for the first Republican debate in August -- taking the Top 10 from the national polls -- will force GOP candidates to begin fighting against each other a bit earlier than expected? Just look at what happened yesterday between Rand Paul and Bobby Jindal. The dispatch from NBC's Andrew Rafferty : "Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal went after Republican presidential candidate Rand Paul on Wednesday, releasing a statement saying Paul is "unsuited to be commander-in-chief" for saying foreign policy hawks in the GOP led to the rise of ISIS. 'This is a perfect example of why Senator Paul is unsuited to be commander-in-chief. We have men and women in the military who are in the field trying to fight ISIS right now, and Senator Paul is taking the weakest, most liberal Democrat position,' Jindal said in a statement." More: "Paul's chief strategist Doug Stafford responded Wednesday afternoon: 'It's ironic Gov. Jindal would level such a charge when he flip-flops on crucial issues like Common Core and national security, and he has cratered his own state's economy and budget."
The GOP's "Game of Thrones" is only going to help Hillary
advertisement
If the GOP contest turns into a survival-of-the-fittest competition to get on the debate stage, that's probably going to help Hillary Clinton. One, these candidates will seek to goose the conservative base as much as possible. And two, having the intramural attack season take place from June through April -- instead of the usual December through April -- will lengthen the amount of time we'll see Republicans attack each other instead of Obama or Clinton.
Your Top 10/11 Republicans, per a new poll
Speaking of the polls and that GOP debate criteria, here are the Top 10 (or 11, due to a tie) Republicans, according to a new national Quinnipiac poll :
Jeb Bush 10%
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
