<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:22:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Donald Trump Helps — and Also Hurts — Jeb Bush</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e86cb2/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cmeet0Ethe0Epress0Chow0Edonald0Etrump0Ehelps0Ealso0Ehurts0Ejeb0Ebush0En38790A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>First Read is a morning briefing from Meet the Press and the NBC Political Unit on the day's most important political stories and why they matter.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 9:22 am ET
How Donald Trump Helps  and Also Hurts  Jeb Bush
by Chuck Todd, Mark Murray and Carrie Dann
NEW YORK, NY - JULY 06:  Donald Trump attends the 2015 Hank's Yanks Golf Classic at Trump Golf Links Ferry Point on July 6, 2015 in New York City.  (Photo by Andrew H. Walker/Getty Images) Andrew H. Walker / Getty Images
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:32:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen Kill at Least 27 People in Attack on Tunisia Beach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479968de/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Ctunisia0Eattack0Egunmen0Ekill0Eleast0E190Epeople0Eattack0Esousse0Ebeach0En382346/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen opened fire on Western tourists on a beach in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 29 people, the country's interior ministry said.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Gunmen opened fire on a beach popular with tourists in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 27 people, the country's interior ministry said.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry told NBC News that at least six people were injured in the attack in the Mediterranean city of Sousse and that one attacker had been killed. The interior ministry said the operation was ongoing.
Gary Pine, a product manager from the U.K., told NBC News he was one of dozens of vacationers on the beach when the attack took place not far from his hotel, the El Mouradi Palm Marina.
He said he initially thought he was hearing firecrackers but that "it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire." His 22-year-old son saw one person get shot, Pine added.
He said guests started running off the beach and were told to go to their rooms by hotel staff, he said. Some guests ran back out onto the beach to get their room keys, he added.
The entertainment manager at the hotel, who only gave his first name, Hamouda, said guests had told him two gunmen "came from the sea" and attacked the beach. He confirmed that staff had told guests to hide in their rooms.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:22:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terror Probe Opened After Gruesome Attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4798e2b8/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cman0Edecapitated0Epossible0Eislamist0Eattack0Efrench0Efactory0Ereports0En38230A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>French authorities opened a terrorism investigation Friday after one person was beheaded in an apparent Islamist attack on a gas factory in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 8:22 am ET
Man Decapitated in Suspected Islamist Attack on Air Products Factory in France
by Alastair Jamieson, Cassandra Vinograd and Alexander Smith
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_kelly_terrorist_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
One person was decapitated and two others wounded in an apparent terror attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France, President Francois Hollande said Friday.
A car crashed through the gates of the Air Products plant in Saint-Quentin Fallavier. southeastern France, shortly after 10 a.m. local time (4 a.m. ET). It was followed by an explosion.
Hollande said a suspect had been arrested and there was "no doubt" that the attacker  possibly acting with an accomplice  intended to blow up the entire plant.
advertisement
The president  who told reporters that the decapitated body was found with "inscriptions" on it  said the attack bore the hallmarks of terrorism, adding that security has been stepped up at sensitive sites in France.
French interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve told reporters at the scene that the suspect was known to authorities and had previously been investigated for radicalization but surveillance ended in 2008.
An interior ministry official earlier told NBC News that an explosion occurred after a car drove onto the scene.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_hollande_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
The severed head was found hanging on a fence along a nearby road, according to local newspaper La Dauphine Libere, which said that an Islamist flag also was found nearby.
Air Products said the situation at the site had been "contained" and that all its employees had been evacuated from the site and accounted for.
"The site is secure," the Allentown, Pennsylvania-based company said in a statement. "Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
The beheaded person was not a worker at the factory, Le Monde reported, citing prosecutors .
France has been on high alert following the deadly January attacks on satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo and a kosher supermarket.
advertisement
Hollande, who announced he was returning early from a European summit in Brussels, spoke of "the necessity to protect our values and never give in to fear and not to create any unnecessary division and suspicions [which] would be intolerable and unacceptable."
Air Products supplies industrial gases to businesses and employs more than 20,000 people in 50 countries, according to its website.
 NBC News' Jake Cigainero contributed to this report
Alastair Jamieson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:31:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friday's Top 7 News Stories</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47996fb6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Efridays0Etop0E70Estories0Enbc0Enews0En382316/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From the funeral for the slain Charleston pastor to the Obamacare victory in the Supreme Court, see the stories we're following today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_mor_obamacare_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
3. Man Decapitated in French Terror Attack
advertisement
French authorities began a terror investigation Friday after one person was reportedly beheaded in an apparent Islamist attack at a gas factory in southeastern France. The country's BFM TV reported that an explosion was heard in the morning at the Air Products plant and a decapitated body was found near the scene. Read more in NEWS .
4. Arrested Prison Guard Paints Negative Atmosphere
Gene Palmer, the second New York prison employee arrested in the escape this month of two convicted killers , described the prison as a "negative environment" that could lead corrections workers to suicide in a radio interview from 2000. His arraignment Thursday was postponed until Monday because Palmer is hiring new lawyers. Read more in NEWS .
5. Putin Talks ISIS, Ukraine With Obama
Russian President Vladimir Putin called Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East. In a statement, the White House said the two leaders addressed continued bloodshed in Syria and agreed on the importance of unity among the six world powers that are negotiating to restrict Iran's nuclear capabilities. Read more in POLITICS .
advertisement
6. Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Kills Nine On Board
A sightseeing plane company boss told of his "pain and anguish" Friday after a pilot and all eight passengers were killed in a crash in southeastern Alaska. The plane was carrying cruise-ship passengers on a shore excursion when it crashed in the Misty Fjords area near Ketchikan. The NTSB has begun its investigation. Read more in NEWS .
7. Univision Dumps Trump Over Mexico Remarks
Univision announced Wednesday it is ending its relationship with the Miss Universe organization, which is partially owned by billionaire Donald Trump, following his remarks about Mexico sending its criminals and rapists to the U.S. Univision had acquired the rights to air the Miss Universe pageant in Spanish. Trump is running for the GOP presidential nomination, and made the controversial comment during his announcement. Read more in LATINO .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All 9 Aboard Cruise-Excursion Plane Die in Crash</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47960271/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ccruise0Eline0Eexcursion0Eplane0Ecrashes0Enine0Eaboard0Ealaska0En382166/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Alaska State Troopers said search and crews were able to reach the scene of the crash and confirmed the deaths, but bad weather hampered recovery.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 5:39 am ET
Alaska Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Killing All Nine Aboard
by Alastair Jamieson, M. Alex Johnson and Shamar Walters
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_blake_plane_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A sightseeing plane company boss told of his "pain and anguish" Friday after a pilot and all eight passengers were killed in a crash in southeastern Alaska.
The plane was carrying cruise-ship passengers on a shore excursion when it crashed in the Misty Fjords area near Ketchikan.
The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) has begun an investigation into the cause of the accident.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_alaskafaa_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Search and rescue teams reached the crash site near a granite rock face about 800 feet above Ella Lake.
However, the recovery of the bodies was postponed until Friday due to bad weather.
advertisement
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," said Marcus Sessoms, president of the plane operator, Promech Air. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
He added: "During this time of grief, our employees are working to do everything we can to extend support and assistance to the loved ones of those affected."
The passengers were from the Holland America Line ship the MS Westerdam, which set off to Alaska from Seattle on June 20, Holland America Line said in a statement.
The names of the deceased were not released pending notification of next of kin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>J.K. Rowling Announces New 'Harry Potter' Play</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479807d8/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Charry0Epotter0Ecursed0Echild0Eopen0Elondon0Estage0En382281/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Called Harry Potter and the Cursed Child, JK Rowling said it will tell the "untold part " of Potter's story.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 5:26 am ET
J.K. Rowling Announces 'Harry Potter and the Cursed Child' Will Hit London Stage
by Henry Austin
advertisement
Fans of "Harry Potter" are set for a magical 2016 after J.K. Rowling announced that a new stage play featuring the boy wizard will open next year in London.
"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part II" Harry, Hermione and Ron are spotted by Deatheaters. They hide and Harry sends Patronus. Hogsmeade. (SC210) Jaap Buitendijk / Warner Bros.
The Scottish author announced on Twitter that "Harry Potter and the Cursed Child" will tell an "untold part" of Potter's story, but insisted the play was "not a prequel."
It "is the result of a collaboration between writer Jack Thorne, director John Tiffany and myself" she said, adding that she was "confident" that when audiences see the play they'll understand why she chose the stage instead of printed word to tell the story.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:13:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Consoler-in-Chief: Obama to Again Comfort the Nation</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479829e6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ccharleston0Echurch0Eshooting0Cconsoler0Echief0Eobama0Eagain0Ecomforts0Enation0Eafter0Eshootings0En381956/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From Aurora, Colorado to most recently, Charleston, South Carolina, President Obama has had to comment numerous times on deadly gun violence in America.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_melvin_charleston_150622" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
His tone was strong while renewing questions about his failed push for tougher gun laws.
He sounded a similar note in his 2013 State of the Union address following a shooting massacre at Sandy Hook Elementary School in which 26 people, 20 of them young children, were killed by a gunman.
"Because in the two months since Newtown, more than a thousand birthdays, graduations, and anniversaries have been stolen from our lives by a bullet from a gun," the president said. "Gabby Giffords deserves a vote," he added of the former Arizona congresswoman, who was shot in the head by a gunman two years earlier. "The families of Newtown deserve a vote. The families of Aurora deserve a vote. The families of Oak Creek, and Tucson, and Blacksburg, and the countless other communities ripped open by gun violence  they deserve a simple vote."
So far, no legislative strategy has emerged to revive the issue of gun control in congress, where a vote on background checks for gun owners failed in the Senate in April of 2013.
As recently as a few days ago, White House officials were not sure if gun control would be a part of the president's remarks on Friday.
"There's obviously been a robust public debate on a variety of issues that have emerged in the aftermath of this terrible incident," Earnest told reporters. "At this point, again, it's hard for me to rule out the president mentioning some aspects of this debate at this point."
Related: Mourners Pay Respects to Rev. Clementa Pinckney at Charleston's Emanuel AME Church
The president's redirect to the gun control issue in the wake of the Charleston church shooting did not go over well with some segments of the black community, said Andra Gillespie, a political science professor at Emory University who has written extensively about racial politics.
"It was as if he was deflecting this away from being a hate crime," Gillespie said. "He has gotten some backlash within black communities for having pivoted to gun control."
According to a senior White House official, the president is not expected in his remarks to lay out policy or a slew of new gun reforms.
The president's remarks, the official said, are first and foremost, a eulogy.
And he will likely speak without a prompter.
Kristin Donnelly
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:02:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tit for Tat: China Slams U.S. Gun Culture, Race Relations</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47985602/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cchina0Eslams0Eu0Es0Ehuman0Erights0Erecord0Eannual0Ereport0En382296/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>China accused the U.S. of being "haunted by spreading guns" and racial bias, in its tit-for-tat rebuttal to U.S. criticism of China's human rights record.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
BEIJING  China accused the United States on Friday of being "haunted by spreading guns" and racial discrimination, in its annual tit-for-tat rebuttal to U.S. criticism of China's human rights record.
In a lengthy report carried by the official Xinhua news agency, the information office of the State Council, or cabinet, said the United States "violated human rights in other countries in a more brazen manner, and was given more 'red cards' in the international human rights field."
On Thursday, the U.S. State Department released its annual report on human rights conditions in the world. In the China section of the report, it said repression and coercion were routine against activists, ethnic minorities and law firms that took on sensitive cases.
China has long rejected criticism of its rights' record and has pointed to its success at lifting millions out of poverty.
The State Council report was "an equal and mutually beneficial way of reciprocating" the United States, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang said at a daily briefing.
advertisement
The Chinese report, which was mostly compiled from U.S. media articles, said "racial discrimination has been a chronic problem in the United States human rights record," adding that the U.S. suppressed the voting rights of minorities.
"In 2014, multiple cases of arbitrary police killing of African-Americans have sparked huge waves of protests, casting doubts on the racial 'equality' in the United States and giving rise to racial hatred factors," the report said.
The report also criticized the U.S. for conducting surveillance on world leaders and civilians and for allowing a few interest groups to influence the government's decision-making.
Human rights have long been a source of tension between the world's two largest economies.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:32:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teens Charged With Gang Raping Mentally-Disabled Girl</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479829fc/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcmiami0N0Cnews0Clocal0C40ETeens0ECharged0EWith0ERaping0EMentally0EDisabled0EGirl0Eat0ENorth0EMiami0ESenior0EHigh0ESchool0E30A99749810Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Derek Bynum and three under-18 students, are charged with the gang rape of a mentally-disabled girl at North Miami Senior High School.</Description>
        <MainBody>Updated 4 minutes ago
Disturbing allegations have surfaced about an alleged gang rape at a South Florida high school.
Derek Bynum, 18, along with three other underage students, are charged with the gang rape of a mentally handicapped girl at North Miami Senior High School back in January.
4-Year-Old Twins Rescued From House Fire
The teens allegedly took the girl into a janitor's closet near the end of the school day and forced her to perform oral, anal and vaginal sex acts.
Court records show Bynum and one of the other teens pleaded not guilty. The other two teens have not yet entered pleas.
Wilton Manors to Start Ticketing Jaywalkers
The discovery process is ongoing. Were trying to get to the bottom of what, if anything, happened  and all the clients remain and are presumed innocent, said Matthew Ladd, a lawyer representing one of the suspects. Lawyers for the other teens did not return requests for comment, according to the Miami-Herald .
The Miami-Dade County School District released a statement Thursday saying in part, "While we struggle to understand the senseless depravity of this isolated but disturbing student incident -- we commend the deliberate and swift actions of Miami-Dade Schools Police in apprehending the alleged perpetrators."
Published at 11:25 PM EDT on Jun 25, 2015
News breaks at inconvenient times. 
Download one of the NBC6 mobile apps and have the news come to you. Watch live streaming newscasts, receive  critical push notifications on the go and stay in touch with your city  around the clock.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:45:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Leaders Strike Deal to Relocate 40,000 Migrants</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4797ffec/sc/24/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ceuropes0Eborder0Ecrisis0Ceurope0Emigrant0Ecrisis0E40A0E0A0A0A0Ewill0Emove0Eitaly0Egreece0Ee0En382246/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>40,000 refugees are to be relocated from southern Europe under a deal reached by political leaders to tackle the continent's worsening migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_calais_150623" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
LONDON  Forty-thousand refugees will be relocated from southern Europe under a deal reached by political leaders to tackle the continent's worsening migrant crisis.
The migrants will be moved from Greece and Italy to other European Union countries over the next two years under the agreement, reached early Friday in Brussels by European leaders . A further 20,000 refugees will be resettled directly from overcrowded camps in Syria, Iraq or Afghanistan.
Friday's deal is a voluntary scheme, and exemptions were granted for Hungary, which is politically opposed to accepting migrants, and Bulgaria, one of the bloc's poorest countries. Britain is also opting out of the plan, which was discussed at acrimonious talks.
RELATED: Human Traffic: Migrants in Serbia Seek Gateway to Europe
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended, describing the migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor."
The deal comes as Mediterranean countries are struggling to cope with an unprecedented influx of desperate people fleeing conflicts in north Africa and the Middle East.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:53:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama to Talk ISIS, Iran</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47976802/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Crussia0Elove0Eputin0Ecalls0Eobama0Etalk0Eshop0En38220A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin called President Barack Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 2:53 am ET
Putin Calls Obama to Talk ISIS, Iran and Ukraine
Share
advertisement
Russian President Vladimir Putin called President Barack Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East.
In a statement, the White House said the two leaders addressed continued bloodshed in Syria and agreed on the importance of unity among the six world powers that are negotiating to restrict Iran's nuclear capabilities.
As for Ukraine, the White House said Obama told Putin Russia needs to meet commitments it made in Minsk, Belarus, earlier this year, including the removal of troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory.
A file picture dated 18 June 2012 shows US President Barack Obama (R) talking with Russian President Vladimir Putin (L) during their meeting at Esperansa hotel prior G20 summit in Los Cabos, Mexico. ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/RIA NOVOSTI/KREM / EPA
The call came on the same day NATO's supreme allied commander cited a continuous flow of ammunition and other military supplies from Russia across the border to Ukraine.
advertisement
According to a posting on the Kremlin's official English website , "significant attention" was given to the topic of ISIS and terrorism in the Middle East.
"Vladimir Putin and Barack Obama agreed to instruct Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov and U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry to hold a meeting to discuss this issue," the Kremlin said.
Contributors The Associated Press and Hasani Gittens
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:45:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>I Don't Want a Lecture: Bristol Palin Announces Pregnancy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479739bb/sc/17/l/0L0Stoday0N0Cparents0Cbristol0Epalin0Eannounces0Eshe0Epregnant0Esecond0Echild0Et28841/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Bristol Palin announced she is expecting her second child, in an emotional blog post on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paris taxi drivers stage violent protests against Uber
"Honestly, I've been trying my hardest to keep my chin up on this one," she wrote on the website Patheos. "At the end of the day there's nothing I can't do with God by my side, and I know I am fully capable of handling anything that is put in front of me with dignity and grace."
Until last month, Palin was engaged to Medal of Honor recipient Dakota Meyer, but the pair called off the wedding in May.
Reuters file
"Life moves on no matter what," she continued. "So no matter how you feel, you get up, get dressed, show up, and never give up. When life gets tough, there is no other option but to get tougher."
Bristol, the daughter of former Alaska governor Sarah Palin, said that the pregnancy "has been, and will be, a huge disappointment to my family, to my close friends, and to many of you." But she asked readers to respect the privacy of her and her 6-year-old son, Tripp.
The 24-year-old added, "I do not want any lectures and I do not want any sympathy. My little family always has, and always will come first. Tripp, this new baby, and I will all be fine, because God is merciful."
Sarah Palin first announced that Bristol's wedding to Meyer would be canceled in a Facebook post on May 18, less than a week before the ceremony was scheduled to take place.
Bristol broke her silence on the matter on May 26, writing, "I know God's plan is greater than anything else, and Tripp and I are in Alaska beginning to rebuild our lives under much different circumstances than we anticipated."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:42:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Six Die in Multi-Vehicle Wreck on Tennessee Interstate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795faff/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Csix0Ekilled0Emulti0Evehicle0Ewreck0Etennessee0Einterstat0En38220A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Six people were killed and at least nine others were injured in a nine-vehicle pileup Thursday night on Interstate 75 near Chattanooga, Tennessee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_tn_carax_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Six people were killed and at least nine others were injured in a fiery nine-vehicle pileup Thursday night on Interstate 75 in Tennessee, Chattanooga police said.
Few details were immediately available because emergency crews were still at work, Chattanooga police said. At 11 p.m., four hours after the wreck, state traffic cameras showed the scene still littered with vehicles as police and state troopers worked to remove victims from the scene.
None of the victims were identified because their families had yet to be notified.
Emergency cars littered Interstate 75 at Exit 11 for hours after the crash at 7 p.m. ET. Tennessee Transportation Department
The state Department of Transportation said the crash involved at least one cargo-carrying semi-trailer.
I-75 northbound north of Exit 11 to the town Ooltewah, east of Chattanooga, was expected to be shut down until at least dawn Friday after the crash, police said.
I-75 northbound north of Exit 11 to the town Ooltewah, east of Chattanooga, Tennessee, was expected to be shut down until at least dawn Friday. Chattanooga, Tennessee, Police Department via Twitter
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:41:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore County Police Fatally Shoot Unarmed Man</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47963c7b/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbaltimore0Ecounty0Epolice0Efatally0Eshoot0Eunarmed0Eman0En382171/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police said the officers fired on Spencer McCain after he acted like he was armed and was going to use a weapon, but no weapon was found.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 25 2015, 10:41 pm ET
Baltimore County Police Fatally Shoot Unarmed Man on Domestic Call
by Phil Helsel
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_balt_police_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Baltimore County Police officers fatally shot an unarmed man while responding to a call of a domestic disturbance early Thursday morning, authorities said.
Three officers opened fire on Spencer Lee McCain, 41, after being called to a home in Owings Mills just after 1 a.m., and forcing their way inside because the officers feared a person may be in danger, Baltimore County police said in a statement. Police said officers could hear a disturbance inside, but no one answered the door.
Police said the officers shot McCain after he allegedly made movements that the officers interpreted as indicating he was armed and ready to act, but no weapon was found, police said. McCain was taken to a hospital where he was later pronounced dead.
advertisement
"The police officers encountered a subject in a defensive position, making body movements and arm movements that placed the officers in fear of serious injury or death," Baltimore County Police Chief Jim Johnson told reporters.
Police said all three officers fired and the investigation has not determined how many shots were fired, but investigators recovered 19 shell casings at the scene.
Police said a woman inside the home had "visible injuries" but refused treatment; two children were also inside the home. The woman was not identified, but police said McCain was prohibited by a court protective order from having any contact with her, and police said they were called to the home around 17 times since 2012.
Johnson said the woman told investigators that McCain told her, "You're going to get the beating you deserve," NBC station WBAL reported.
A neighbor told the station he heard what sounded like a woman "begging, you know, like, 'Don't do that. Don't do this. Please stop."
advertisement
Owing Mills is about 20 miles northwest of Baltimore, which was roiled by protests and riots after a black man, Freddie Gray, died after suffering a spinal injury while in police custody. McCain's race was not released.
Police said the homicide unit will complete an investigation and forward the results to the state's attorney's office for review.
Phil Helsel
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:28:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Enormous Noah's Ark Replica Takes Shape in Kentucky Field</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795e2ff/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbible0Ebased0Eall0Ewood0Eark0Etakes0Eshape0Ekentucky0Efield0En382146/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Builders are betting big that millions of visitors will flood the Williamstown, Kentucky, attraction.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_noahsark_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A planned all-wood replica of Noah's ark got a step closer to its Old Testament ideal on Thursday, when workers lifted yet another rib of the would-be vessel into place in a Kentucky pasture.
The future tourist attraction is called Ark Encounter  centered around a 510-foot-long ark, which the builder, a Christian ministry called "Answers in Genesis," says "will be the largest timber-frame structure in the world" when it's completed next summer.
Builders are betting big that millions of visitors will flood the Williamstown, Kentucky, attraction. Ken Ham, president of Answers in Genesis, told WLWT he expects up to about 2 million visitors per year.
advertisement
"I believe it will be one of the biggest attractions outside of Disney, Universal, people like that  it's going to be one of the biggest attractions in this country."
Ham said the ark, which is being built according to dimensions provided in the Bible for the vessel that survived the worldwide flood, will house three stories of exhibits, while the fourth floor is planned to be a restaurant.
According to the project's website, "additional future phases for the attraction include a Walled City, the Tower of Babel, a first-century Middle Eastern village, a journey in history from Abraham to the parting of the Red Sea, a walk-through aviary, an expanded large petting zoo, and so on."
A wooden rib that is part of a ship based on the story of Noahs ark is raised into place in Williamstown, Ky., on Thursday, June 25, 2015. The Ark Encounter will be a religious tourist attraction when it opens next year. Dylan Lovan / AP
But  not unlike the ark in the Bible  this structure has attracted its own share of criticism. Last year, the state of Kentucky withdrew its offer of tax breaks for the attraction.
advertisement
"State tourism tax incentives cannot be used to fund religious indoctrination or otherwise be used to advance religion," Kentucky Tourism Secretary Bob Stewart wrote in a letter in December .
And Bill Nye "The Science Guy," who debated Ham about creationism last year, has argued the project would hurt science education.
Answers in Genesis sued Kentucky tourism officials in February, claiming the decision to deny the tax breaks violated the group's First Amendment rights. That suit is still pending, but the construction is moving forward, as organizes plan to open the attraction next summer.
Becky Bratu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cleveland Vigil Marks Tamir Rice's 13th Birthday</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795e731/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cvigil0Emarks0E13th0Ebirthday0Eslain0Ecleveland0Eboy0Etamir0Erice0En3820A96/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A candlelight vigil Thursday remembered the Ohio boy shot to death by police, on what would have been his 13th birthday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 25 2015, 9:42 pm ET
Vigil Marks 13th Birthday of Slain Cleveland Boy Tamir Rice
by M. Alex Johnson
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_tamir_rice_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A candlelight vigil was under way in Cleveland to remember Tamir Rice, the unarmed African-American boy shot to death by police last year, on what would have been his 13th birthday.
The vigil was held at Cudell Recreation Center, where Cleveland police Officer Timothy Loehmann killed Tamir on Nov. 22. Loehmann and his partner were responding to a report of a man with a gun, but Tamir had only a toy pellet gun.
"It's been eight months," Tamir's mother, Samira Rice, said in a statement . "While I am crushed, and I struggle daily with the loss of my son, I will not rest until those men who were responsible for taking my son's life are prosecuted."
advertisement
Cuyahoga County Prosecutor Timothy McGinty told reporters Wednesday that he expects to complete his investigation in "a matter of months."
Remember y'all, #TamirRice birthday is today. Find a way to honor his legacy, as today is birthday #13 #RestInPower pic.twitter.com/susVf605Uf
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Week in Pictures</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4796acea/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cweek0Ein0Epictures0Cweek0Epictures0Ejune0E180E250En382176/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tragedy strikes an historic church, mermaids parade through New York, lives saved at sea, and more.</Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
1. Rev. Norvel Goff prays at the empty seat of the Rev. Clementa Pinckney at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church four days after a mass shooting that claimed the lives of Pinckney and eight others on June 21 in Charleston, S.C. David Goldman / Pool via AP
2. Gary and Aurelia Washington, center left and right, the son and granddaughter of Ethel Lance, who died in a mass shooting earlier in the week, leave a sidewalk memorial in front of Emanuel AME Church comforted by fellow family members on June 18 in Charleston, S.C. Dylann Storm Roof was arrested in the slayings of nine people, including the pastor at a prayer meeting inside the historic church. David Goldman / AP
3. A Buddhist novice prays at a monastery affiliated with the MaBaTha organization on the outskirts of Yangon. The MaBaTha organization promotes hardline Buddhist nationalism in Myanmar. Christophe Archambault / AFP - Getty Images
advertisement
4. Flood water reflects damaged homes in Coal City, Illinois, a community of about 5,000 residents 60 miles southwest of Chicago, where the National Weather Service confirmed that a twister touched down on June 23.  A storm system flattened homes across the Midwest and slammed the Northeast on June 22 with heavy rain and strong winds, knocking out power for hundreds of thousands, snarling transportation and overturning semi-trucks on interstates. Jon Durr / Getty Images
5. Muslims attend Friday prayers during the second day of Ramadan, in the courtyard of a housing estate next to the small BBC community center and mosque in east London on June 19. Stefan Wermuth / Reuters
6. A stall holder covers over a carousel at the end of the day at The Hoppings fun fair, believed to be one of the largest travelling fairs in Europe, on its opening day in Newcastle upon Tyne, North East England on June 19. Oli Scarff / AFP - Getty Images
advertisement
7. Participants dance on Surf Avenue during the 33rd annual Mermaid Parade in New York's Coney Island on June 20. The parade began in 1983 and takes place on the Saturday closest to the first day of summer. Justin Lane / EPA
8. A man carries a box into the only shop open on an Athens street on June 25. Desperate Greeks expressed fears for their future Friday as more than $1.1 billion was withdrawn from banks in a single day, pushing the country closer towards a default. Daniel Ochoa De Olza / AP
9. Palestinians, not permitted by Israeli security forces to cross into Jerusalem from the West Bank due to an age limit, climb over a section of the controversial Israeli barrier as they try to make their way to attend the first Friday prayer of Ramadan in Jerusalem's al-Aqsa mosque, in the village of Al-Ram, near Ramallah on June 19. Mohamad Torokman / Reuters
advertisement
10. Dylann Roof appears via video before a judge in Charleston, S.C., on June 19. The 21-year-old accused of killing nine people inside he historic Mother Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church made his first court appearance, with the relatives of all the victims making tearful statements. Centralized Bond Hearing Court, of Charleston, S.C. via AP
11. Ash from Mount Sinabung volcano fills the sky over an abandoned church during another eruption in Karo, in Indonesia's North Sumatra province on June 19. Sinabung rumbled back to life in 2013 after a period of inactivity, since then around 10,000 people have had to evacuate their homes. Sutanta Aditya / AFP - Getty Images
12. Migrants sit on the deck of the Belgian Navy vessel Godetia after they were saved during a search and rescue mission in the Mediterranean Sea off the Libyan coasts on June 24. Hundreds of migrants were rescued by the Godetia, which is part of a fleet taking part in the Triton migrants rescue operation. Gregorio Borgia / AP
advertisement
13. A rider and his horse rear during the traditional Saint John festival in Ciutadella, on the Balearic Island of Minorca, Spain on June 24. During the festival, race horses gallop and prance on their hind legs through the streets to honor of the town's patron saint. As the "caixers" (horse riders) ride together in a parade, spectators attempt to pat the horses' chests to get good luck. Jaime Reina / AFP - Getty Images
14. The Crew onboard Australia's HMAS Canberra stand at attention as they honor the countrys oldest naval ship, the HMAS Tobruk (not pictured) as she arrives at Garden Island following a final voyage to Sydney on June 25. Tobruk, Australia's longest serving naval ship has been in service for 35 years and has sailed almost a million nautical miles around the world. Dean Lewins / EPA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:23:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Snooze-Deprived Couples Rest Easy After 'Sleep Divorce'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795b59d/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Csleep0Edivorce0En3820A46/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's estimated one in every four couples sleeps separately at night — twice as many as fifteen years ago, according to the Better Sleep Council and National Sleep Foundation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_hja_sleep_divorce_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Jack Mazewski snores so loudly that his children sleeping down the hall can hear it. The noise didn't bother his wife, Joanna, for the first few years of their marriage  until their kids were born.
"I became a light sleeper because you have a little more stress - two children, a mortgage, bills," said Joanna Mazewski.
Night after night, her husband's snoring kept her awake.
advertisement
"She would poke me a few times," Jack said. His wife quickly corrected him: "I would say kick, not poke."
"I would end up waking him up in the middle of the night," Joanna added. "And then two of us weren't sleeping."
It made mornings a nightmare for the otherwise happily-married couple.
"The arguing would happen when we're not sleeping well," said Joanna.
Jack and Joanna Mazewski Hallie Jackson / NBC News
advertisement
At the end of their rope, the Mazewskis finally found a solution, just like an increasing number of couples in the United States: separate beds.
It's estimated one in every four couples sleeps separately at night  twice as many as fifteen years ago, according to the Better Sleep Council and National Sleep Foundation. It's a phenomenon often called "sleep divorce."
"For some couples, it actually works," said Dr. Wendy Troxel, "particularly if they're both getting a better night of sleep and they're able to function better in the relationship during the day."
Many people prefer the comfort of sleeping next to a spouse, but Troxel  a behavioral and social scientist at the RAND Corporation, pointed to studies showing couples actually sleep worse together.
"This could be sort of a phenomenon of basic physics," she explained. "You have another person in bed with you, so there's more likelihood of more movement and that can be disruptive of sleep."
advertisement
Sleep deprivation can be a serious problem in romantic relationships.
"In a sleep deprived couple, they are more likely to engage in conflict and less likely to be able to resolve it effectively," said Troxel. Plus, a University of California-Berkeley study showed who slept poorly experienced less appreciation for their partners than people who got enough sleep.
For an increasing number of couples, "sleep divorce" is the clear solution - although it sometimes carries a stigma.
"We don't say anything because people think, 'oh, there's probably trouble in their marriage,'" said Joanna Mazewski. "But the fact of the matter is, we try to sleep in different beds so we avoid that trouble!"
Sleep experts recommend a few key tips for sleeping apart - and staying happy:
advertisement
Talk about it first. Pre-planning separate sleeping arrangements ensures one partner doesn't feel ditched when the other leaves the bedroom.
Schedule "together time" in the evenings. "That time before falling asleep is often the only time that couples have together to be away from these distractions," said Troxel. Creating space for intimacy doesn't have to mean just sex: cuddling and talking can help couples stay connected before they head to separate sleeping locations.
If snoring is the problem, schedule a doctor's visit. It can be a sign of a more serious sleep disorder, like sleep apnea.
For the Mazewskis, sleeping separately at night helps them feel better in the morning: "If it doesn't work out for one person or the other," Joanna asked, "why suffer through it?"
Hallie Jackson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:47:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State Department: 15 Emails Missing From Clinton Cache</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47955b7c/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0Cpolitics0Enews0Cstate0Edepartment0E150Eemails0Emissing0Ehillary0Eclinton0Ecache0En382151/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A report issued late Thursday says that all or part of 15 emails sent or received from Clinton's private server were missing from records turned over.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=mtp_daleyemail_150614" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
advertisement
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Clinton's responses are brief. In one from August 2011, she tells Blumenthal she will be in Paris the next day to meet rebel leaders and says she had "to resort to new iPad" because she didn't have electricity or Blackberry coverage after Hurricane Irene.
In another from March 2012, she passes on an adviser's skepticism regarding one of Blumenthal's reports about political intrigue in post-Gadhafi Libya, saying: "This strain credulity based on what I know. Any other info about it?"
And after a long August 2012 note from Blumenthal about Libya's new interim President Mohamed Yousef el-Magariaf, Clinton writes: "Another keeper  thanks and please keep 'em coming." Four days later, she responds to a follow-up reports about el-Magariaf, saying: "Fascinating. I had a very good call w him."
advertisement
Clinton's critics are likely to focus less on the substance of the emails than on the fact that they weren't shared with the State Department.
Gowdy, a South Carolina Republican, has pressed for an explanation of why Blumenthal gave the committee emails not previously shared by the State Department. The suggestion has been that either the department or Clinton was hiding something.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:23:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NBA Draft Tracker: Follow the Picks as They Unfold</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4794bfa9/sc/13/l/0L0Srotoworld0N0Carticles0Cnba0C548490C4750C20A150Enba0Edraft0Etracker0Dcid0Feref0Rnbcnews0Rtext/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Follow the NBA Draft as it unfolds on Thursday in Brooklyn, New York.</Description>
        <MainBody>31. Cleveland Cavaliers (from Minnesota Timberwolves) - Cedi Osman , SG/SF, Anadolu Efes
32. Houston Rockets (from New York Knicks) - Montrezl Harrell , PF, Louisville
33. Boston Celtics (from Philadelphia 76ers via Miami Heat) - Jordan Mickey , PF, LSU
34. Los Angeles Lakers - Anthony Brown , SF, Stanford
35. New York Knicks (from Philadelphia 76ers via Orlando Magic) - Guillermo Hernangomez , C, Baloncesto Sevilla (Spain)
36. Cleveland Cavaliers (from Minnesota Timberwolves via Sacramento Kings and Houston Rockets) - Rakeem Christmas , PF, Syracuse
37. Philadelphia 76ers (from Denver Nuggets, via Houston Rockets, Portland Trail Blazers and Minnesota Timberwolves) - Richaun Holmes , PF, Bowling Green
38. Detroit Pistons - Darrun Hilliard , SG, Villanova
39. Brooklyn Nets (from Charlotte Hornets) - Juan Vaulet , SF, Estudiantes Bahia Blanca (Argentina)
40. Miami Heat - Josh Richardson , SG, Tennessee
41. Portland Trail Blazers (from Brooklyn Nets) - Pat Connaughton , SG, Notre Dame
42. Utah Jazz - Olivier Hanlan , PG/SG, Boston College
43. Indiana Pacers - Joseph Young , SG/PG, Oregon
44. Phoenix Suns - Andrew Harrison , PG, Kentucky
45. Boston Celtics - Marcus Thornton , PG, William &amp; Mary
46. Toronto Raptors (from Milwaukee Bucks) - Norman Powell , SG, UCLA
47. Philadelphia 76ers (from New Orleans Pelicans via Washington Wizards and Los Angeles Clippers) - Arturas Gudaitis , C, Zalgiris Kaunas (Lithuania)
48. Oklahoma City Thunder - Dakari Johnson , C, Kentucky
49. Washington Wizards - Aaron White , PF, Iowa
50. Atlanta Hawks (from Toronto Raptors) - Marcus Eriksson , SG, FC Barcelona (Spain)
51. Orlando Magic (from Chicago Bulls) - Tyler Harvey , SG, Eastern Washington
52. Dallas Mavericks - Satnam Singh Bhamara , C, IMG Academy
53. Cleveland Cavaliers (From Portland Trail Blazers via Chicago Bulls and Denver Nuggets) - Sir'Dominic Pointer , SF, St. John's
54. Portland Trail Blazers (from Utah Jazz via Cleveland Cavaliers) - Daniel Diez , PF, San Sebastian (Spain)
55. San Antonio Spurs - Cady Lalanne , PF, Massachusetts
56. New Orleans Pelicans (from Memphis Grizzlies) - Branden Dawson , PF, Michigan State
57. Denver Nuggets (from Los Angeles Clippers) - Nikola Radicevic , PG, Baloncesto Sevilla (Spain)
58. Philadelphia 76ers (from Houston Rockets) - J.P. Tokoto , SG, North Carolina
59. Atlanta Hawks - Dimitrios Agravanis , PF, Olympiacos (Greece)
60. Philadelphia 76ers (from Golden State Warriors via Indiana Pacers) - Luka Mitrovic , PF, Red Star (Serbia)

Trades:
Brooklyn acquired the No. 23 pick (Rondae-Hollis-Jefferson) and G Steve Blake from Portland for the No. 41 pick (Pat Connaughton) and C Mason Plumlee .
Toronto acquired the No. 46 pick (Norman Powell) and a 2017 first-round pick from Milwaukee for PG Greivis Vasquez .
Brooklyn acquired the No. 39 pick (Juan Valet) from Charlotte for two future draft picks.
New York acquired the No. 35 pick (Guillermo Hernangomez) from Philadelphia for two future draft picks.
Portland acquired the No. 54 pick (Daniel Diez) from Utah for a future second-round pick.
Complete results from the 2015 NBA Draft are posted below. Scroll down to see the details of each in-draft trade. Click on each players name for full pick analysis.

For instant analysis on every player picked, refresh Rotoworld's NBA Player News page .

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:00:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Third Time's the Charm? SpaceX to Try to Land Rocket</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a34052/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cscience0Cspace0Cwatch0Espacex0Elaunch0Enasa0Ecargo0Etry0Eland0Efalcon0E90Erocket0En383166/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>After two oh-so-close attempts to land a rocket stage on a seagoing platform, SpaceX will try, try again during Sunday's launch of a Falcon 9 rocket.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 10:00 am ET
Watch SpaceX Launch NASA Cargo and Again Try to Land Falcon 9 Rocket
by Alan Boyle
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nbcnewslive_nyc1" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Will the third time be the charm? After two oh-so-close attempts to land a rocket stage on a seagoing platform, SpaceX will try, try again during Sunday's launch of a Falcon 9 rocket.
The primary objective of the mission , due for takeoff from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Florida at 10:21 a.m. ET, is to deliver a robotic Dragon capsule with more than two and a half tons of supplies, equipment and experiments  ranging from a new docking adapter for accommodating future U.S.-built spaceships to a virtual-reality headset for the space station's crew.
This will be the first robotic cargo delivery since a Russian Progress capsule went awry in April , resulting in the loss of the craft's 3-ton payload. The Dragon's payload includes food, oxygen and other much-needed basics  and that's putting extra pressure on SpaceX for a successful launch.
SpaceX's vice president of mission assurance, Hans Koenigsmann, told reporters on Friday that his company was up to the job. "Dragon has been super-reliable," he told reporters.
No technical problems were reported as the two-stage Falcon 9 rocket was fueled up, and the chances of acceptable weather were set at 90 percent. You can watch launch coverage on webcasts that are being streamed by NASA and SpaceX .
advertisement
The Dragon already has made six successful cargo runs under the terms of a $1.6 billion contract with NASA, plus an initial demonstration mission in 2012. But this time, SpaceX is hoping to pull off a trick that's never been done before: the safe landing of the Falcon's first stage on a drone ship stationed hundreds of miles out in the Atlantic.
The first stage's autonomous landing maneuver is due to unfold minutes after launch, while the second stage continues its rise to orbit with the Dragon capsule.
A completely successful landing at sea would mark a milestone in rocket reusability. SpaceX's billionaire founder, Elon Musk, says the technology would dramatically drive down launch costs and potentially pave the way for affordable trips to Mars.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:51:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armed Cops, Memorials Dot Bloodstained Beach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a43c27/sc/40/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cisis0Eterror0Ctunisia0Esteps0Esecurity0Esousse0Emourns0Eisis0Eattack0Evictims0En383271/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Makeshift memorials dotted this seaside resort town on Sunday as Tunisian officials deployed hundreds of extra police to guard tourist sites.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 9:51 am ET
Tunisia Steps Up Security as Sousse Mourns ISIS Attack Victims
by Chapman Bell, Kelly Cobiella and Charlene Gubash
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Share
advertisement
How Trump helps -- and also maybe hurts -- Jeb Bush
If you're Jeb Bush, the Republican presidential race becoming ALL ABOUT DONALD TRUMP has its positives. One, it freezes the rest of the field, sucking up oxygen from other candidates who might pop. Two, it provides him a foil to campaign against. Jeb can say, "I'm Mr. Responsible Republican, and we can't allow the irresponsible ones take over our party." And we saw Bush start to make this argument against Trump over the July 4 holiday weekend. But the rise of Trump has one big drawback for Jeb: It further exposes the party's wounds on immigration. Look no further than how Trump fired back at Bush's criticism. "[H]e doesn't understand anything about the border or border security. In fact, Jeb believes illegal immigrants who break our laws when they cross our border come out 'out of love.'" Indeed, Jeb's 2014 "act of love" comment is potentially radioactive in a GOP primary. It's one thing for a Republican to believe in immigration reform and a path to legal status; it's another to say that illegal immigration is an act of love. And as we've learned, Donald Trump isn't going to be shy at resurrecting those old quotes.
The immigration outrage doesn't match the data
Here's an additional point we want to make about Trump and the immigration debate: The outrage doesn't match the data. After all, illegal immigration from Mexico has declined . Deportations have gone up . And given the focus on the murder in San Francisco committed by an undocumented immigrant, the crime rate for first-generation immigrants is lower than the overall crime rate .
advertisement
Who makes the debate stage -- and who doesn't?
With the first GOP presidential debate now less than a month from now, one of your authors crunched the numbers from the last five national polls (two from Fox, one CNN, one NBC/WSJ, and one from Monmouth), and below are the polling averages. Remember, the first debate is restricted to the Top 10:
Bush - 15.4 %
advertisement
A reality check on the Hillary-vs.-Sanders horserace
Hillary Clinton today campaigns in Iowa, making stops in Iowa City and Ottumwa. She also sits down for the first national TV interview since becoming a presidential candidate, although she's conducted interviews with local political reporters in Iowa, New Hampshire, and Nevada. And we have a hunch that one question she gets is about Bernie Sanders' rise in the polls. Here's how the New York Times framed the Clinton-Sanders horserace : "Hillary Clinton's Team Is Wary as Bernie Sanders Finds Footing in Iowa." But as our sister publication The Lid noted yesterday , there are four things to keep in mind about Sanders' rise:
She's still ahead in Iowa by at least 19 points, a much wider margin than exists in the GOP race;
This kind of NYT story only helps the Clinton camp lower expectations;
Sanders' surge is being fueled by progressive whites -- the same folks who supported Bill Bradley in 2000 and Howard Dean in 2004. In fact, what Sanders has done is consolidate the 30% who were there for Elizabeth Warren. (What should concern Clinton Land is if he starts creeping up into the 40s;
And as the political scientists put it, the party (though its elected officials) ultimately decide the nomination. And so far, two-thirds of sitting Democratic senators have endorsed Hillary. That, to political scientists, matters more than the polls or crowd sizes.
In short, Sanders has consolidated the progressive wing of the party, and that is impressive. The question is: Can he grow it? And remember, a recent Gallup poll showed that a presidential candidate being labeled a socialist was the worst attribute -- lower than being a Muslim or an atheist. And for Sanders to TRULY take off, he needs to prove to Democratic elites that a socialist like him could win a general election.
***Get NBC News' 2016 newsletter "The Lid" straight to your inbox every afternoon -- click here to sign up. ***
Iran talks to extend -- again
Here's Andrea Mitchell on the latest in the Iran talks: "The State Department in Vienna announced it is taking steps to extend the agreement currently in place with Iran until July 10. Spokeswoman Marie Harf says they are more concerned about the quality of the deal than they are about the clock. Secretary of State Kerry plans to remain in Vienna to continue discussions."
advertisement
The fundraising rules? There really are no rules
Welcome to our brave new world in fundraising for the presidential contest. Exhibit A: The Super PAC backing Carly Fiorina reported raising twice as much ($3.4 million) as the Fiorina campaign raised for 2nd quarter ($1.4 million). Exhibit B: The 501c4 helping Marco Rubio -- which doesn't have to disclose its donors -- says it's raked in nearly $16 million, which could very well exceed the haul by Rubio's campaign. Exhibit C: As we reported yesterday, the Ted Cruz campaign issued a press release highlighting BOTH its campaign's 2nd-quarter numbers and the expected Super PAC cash. And we thought that campaigns weren't supposed to coordinate with the Super PACs!!! But as the Washington Post writes , the fundraising rules in the Super PAC Era are that there really are no rules. "Operatives on both sides can talk to one another directly, as long as they do not discuss candidate strategy. According to an FEC rule, an independent group also can confer with a campaign until this fall about 'issue ads' featuring a candidate. Some election-law lawyers think that a super PAC could share its entire paid media plan, as long as the candidate's team does not respond."
FEC hasn't opened an investigation into alleged illegal Super PAC coordination
Why are there no rules? Answer: The Federal Election Commission doesn't seem to care. "Since 2010, the FEC has yet to open an investigation into alleged illegal super PAC coordination, closing 29 such complaints. In 28 of those cases, the agency's general counsel did not recommend pursuing the matters, according to Goodman of the FEC," the Post adds . Wow.
Carly's unimpressive fundraising numbers
One more point about Fiorina's $1.4 million campaign haul and the $3.4 million for her Super PAC: For a candidate who got buzz over the last 60 days, those AREN'T impressive numbers. In fact, $1.4 million is a barely considered a decent quarterly haul for a Senate candidate these days.
Rubio: "The race for the future will never be won by going backward"
In Chicago at 10:00 am ET, Marco Rubio will deliver a domestic-policy speech, in which his argument will be -- again -- that he represents the future. "For the first fifteen and a half years of this century, Washington has looked to the past. Our economy has changed, but our economic policies have not," he is expected to say, according to advanced excerpts of his speech. "And we have learned, painfully, that the old ways no longer work - that Washington cannot pretend the world is the same as it was in the '80s, it cannot raise taxes like it did in the '90s, and it cannot grow government like it did in the 2000s. The race for the future will never be won by going backward." He will add, "We need a new president for a new age - one with original ideas to unlock the two great doors to the future: the doors of innovation and education." After his remarks in Chicago, Rubio heads to campaign in Iowa.
On the trail
Ben Carson is in New Hampshire Hillary Clinton stumps in Iowa, as does Ted Cruz and Bobby Jindal And Mike Huckabee is in South Carolina.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:50:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran Nuclear Talks to Continue Past 'Flexible' Deadline</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e85410/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0Cirans0Enuclear0Etalks0Econtinue0Epast0Eflexible0Edeadline0Ee0Eu0Eofficial0En387871/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Iran and major powers will continue negotiations on an historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term agreement.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_shorttake_arouzi_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
VIENNA  Iran and major powers will continue negotiations on an historic nuclear deal past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term agreement, European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," Mogherini told reporters.
The deal under discussion between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:46:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Remembering 7/7: Threat 'as Real as It Is Deadly'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e6f4ff/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Clondon0E70E70Ebombings0Ehow0Eworld0Eterrorism0Ethreat0Ehas0Eevolved0En387831/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>As Londoners paused to remember victims on the 10th anniversary of the 7/7 transit bombings, experts warned that terrorism remains a threat.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_stpauls_150707" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
LONDON  As Londoners paused to remember victims on the 10th anniversary of the 7/7 transit bombings on Tuesday, police and security experts warned that terrorism remains a threat due to the "wicked cult" of ISIS.
Many of the British capital's world-famous red buses pulled over as the city observed a minute's silence at 11:30am (6:30 a.m. ET)  one of a series of ceremonies marking the suicide bombings that killed 52 people and seriously wounded hundreds more during the morning rush hour.
Commuters were asked to make part of their journey on foot, recreating the defiance shown on July 7, 2005 when millions continued their daily routines to show they would not be cowed by the atrocity  the single worst on British soil.
advertisement
The Number 30 London bus which was bombed on July 7, 2005. DYLAN MARTINEZ / AFP - Getty Images
However, Prime Minister David Cameron warned: "Ten years on  the threat continues to be as real as it is deadly."
Experts agreed, saying the rise of individuals inspired by ISIS posed new issues for the security services.
"I think the threat has changed over the last 10 years and I think that this is more about lone actors now than it was," said Charlie Winter, researcher with the U.K.-based Quilliam Foundation.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:31:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tuesday's Top 7 News Stories</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e8018b/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Etuesdays0Etop0E70Estories0Enbc0Enews0En38760A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From World Cup wages to coffee cup price hikes, see the stories we're following today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=mtp_confederateflag_150630" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
4. London Remembers 7/7 Bombings as Terror Fears Persist
advertisement
As Londoners paused to remember victims on the 10th anniversary of the 7/7 transit bombings on Tuesday, police and security experts warned that terrorism remains a threat due to the "wicked cult" of ISIS. Prime Minister David Cameron warned: "Ten years on  the threat continues to be as real as it is deadly." Read more in NEWS.
 ITV News (@itvnews) July 7, 2015
5. Florida State QB Who Punched Woman Was Provoked: Lawyer
Video showing De'Andre Johnson, 19, apparently punching a woman in the face at a club got him booted from the Florida State University football team. He is charged with battery for the June 24 incident, but his lawyer says Johnson was provoked and did not start the altercation. Read more in NEWS.
advertisement
6. NATO Convoy in Afghanistan Hit by Suicide Bomb
The Taliban claimed responsibility for the suicide car bombing of a NATO military convoy in Kabul on Tuesday. Around three or four civilians were injured in the bombing, according to the Ministry of Public Health. NATO said that no coalition forces were killed in the explosion. Read more in NEWS.
7. Mexican Man Charged With Murder in SF Pier Death
Prosecutors charged a Mexican immigrant with murder on Monday in the seemingly random shooting death of a woman who was on a waterfront walk with her father last week in San Francisco. Authorities said Monday that Francisco Sanchez, 45, was expected to be arraigned Tuesday in the death of Kathryn Steinle, 32. Read more in NEWS.
Nightly Spotlight: Starbucks Hikes Prices
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:17:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Paranoid Farmers Almost Prevented This Monet Masterpiece</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e82b11/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cclaude0Emonets0Ewater0Elily0Epaintings0Ealmost0Enever0Eexisted0Edue0Efrench0En387856/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Claude Monet's iconic water lilies almost never existed after French farmers tried to block his plans to build a water garden, it has been revealed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 8:17 am ET
Claude Monet's Water Lily Paintings Almost Never Existed
by Alexander Smith
advertisement
Hundreds of the most famous paintings ever committed to canvas almost never came into being  all because of a group of paranoid French farmers, an exhibition curator has revealed.
Claude Monet completed around 250 paintings of his water lily garden in northern France, with the most valuable work selling for $80.4 million at a London auction in 2008.
But according to documents unearthed by Ann Dumas, co-curator of an upcoming exhibition on the subject in Cleveland, Ohio, and London, U.K., Monet's impressive water garden depicted in the images was not welcomed by his neighbors in 1893.
"There was a protest from local farmers who were very suspicious of these strange aquatic plants that Monet wanted to plant because they they would poison their water and kill their cattle," Dumas told a press briefing Monday attended by the BBC .
One of Claude Monet's series of "Nymphas," or "Water Lilies," purchased in 1930 in New York. Estate of Huguette M. Clark / Christie's
advertisement
As well as becoming one of the most iconic names in the art world, Monet was an avid gardener. The impressionist wanted to divert the river Epte into his property in Giverny, France, to create the soon-to-be-famous water garden.
But fearing the effect the water lilies might have on their livestock, the farmers wrote to local officials in 1893 in an attempt to block his plans.
Monet only gained permission to proceed "after a lot of difficulty," Dumas said, according to the BBC.
The exhibition "Painting the Modern Garden: Monet to Matisse Exhibition" will tell the story of how gardens featured in the work of Monet and his peers. It will run at the Cleveland Museum of Art from October 11 to January 5 next year, and then the Royal Academy of Arts, in London, from January 30 to April 20.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:10:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Officer Accused of Hiding Evidence Related to Cop Killing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e727f4/sc/33/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cdaryle0Eholloway0Einvestigation0Eleads0Earrest0Eofficer0Ewardell0Ejohnson0En387836/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Officer Wardell Johnson has been accused of withholding evidence related to the arrest of Travis Boys.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 8:10 am ET
Daryle Holloway Investigation Leads to Arrest of Officer Wardell Johnson
by Cassandra Vinograd
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_fh_nola_pd_150621" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A New Orleans cop has been arrested and suspended for allegedly withholding evidence involving the suspect charged in a fellow officer's shooting death, police said.
Officer Daryle Holloway was shot and killed while transporting aggravated assault suspect Travis Boys to jail .
The New Orleans Police Department has been investigating how Boys allegedly killed Holloway and escaped custody. It said in a statement Monday that an interview with the officer who initially arrested Boys for aggravated assault on June 20 revealed "sloppy police work"
advertisement
Detectives allege Johnson "deliberately attempted" to leave a .40 caliber casing at the scene and "not process it for evidence," the force said in a statement. "In addition, detectives learned that Officer Johnson recovered a box of unused .40 caliber bullets at the scene and did not process it as evidence."
While Johnson told detectives he did not remember where he had left the box of bullets, "shortly after the interview, detectives observed Johnson removing the box of bullets from his vehicle and throwing them out of the window while driving," the statement said. "Johnson admitted to throwing the box of bullets out of his window," it added.
"I am extremely disgusted and outraged by the lack of professionalism and integrity shown by this officer," NOPD Superintendent Michael Harrison said. "This is an example of sloppy police work with a clear intent to cover it up, and it will not stand."
Johnson has been arrested for obstruction of justice, theft and malfeasance in office.
New Orleans Police Officer Wardell Johnson was suspended on July 7 after he was accused of withholding evidence in an assault case involving a man who later killed an officer, police said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:05:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cosby Said He Gave Woman Drugs Before Sex: Court Docs</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e2a5b4/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbill0Ecosby0Esaid0Ehe0Egave0Esedative0Ewomen0Edocument0En387671/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Bill Cosby said in a 2005 legal deposition that he obtained prescriptions of a powerful sedative to give to women he wanted to have sex with, according to documents released Monday in a Pennsylvania court.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_snow_cosby_150707" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Bill Cosby said in a 2005 legal deposition that he obtained prescriptions of a powerful sedative to give to women he wanted to have sex with, according to documents released Monday in a Pennsylvania court.
The comedian's testimony was part of a civil suit involving a woman who accused him of drugging her and sexually assaulting her.
At one point, Cosby was asked by the woman's attorney about his use of prescriptions for the pills, known as Quaaludes.
"When you got the Quaaludes, was it in your mind that you were going to use these Quaaludes for young women that you wanted to have sex with?" the lawyer asked.
"Yes," Cosby said, according to the document, which was released after a request by The Associated Press.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:56:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One Killed, Four Injured in Washington Ice Cave Collapse</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e43d0b/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cthree0Einjure0Eafter0Ewashington0Estate0Eice0Ecaves0Ecollapse0Eagain0En387756/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>At least three people were injured when ice caves on a remote Washington state mountaintop partly collapsed for the second straight day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 7:56 am ET
One Killed, Four Injured as Washington State Ice Caves Collapse Again
by M. Alex Johnson and Shamar Walters
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_rascon_cave_150707" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A hiker was killed and four others injured when ice caves on a remote Washington state mountainside partly collapsed, authorities said Monday night.
Three of the injured were were airlifted to hospital with serious injuries after the accident at the Big Four Ice Caves in Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest.
The body of the hiker could not immediately be recovered because of the "fragile nature of the ice," Snohomish County spokeswoman Shari Ireton said.
advertisement
Survivor Chloe Jakubowski, 18, escaped from the cave and went to alert emergency services.
"There was a loud pop above us," she told NBC News. "Once I saw the ice chunks falling I ducked for cover and held my hands over my head."
A woman next to her was unconscious, she said.
It was the second straight day that part of the ice caves  which are accessible only by a 26-mile narrow, winding road  collapsed on Big Four Mountain, about 20 miles east of the town of Granite Falls. No one was injured in Sunday's collapse, which a visitor captured on video.
advertisement
The caves are formed when runoff from melting snow hollows out a tunnel in snow mounds that slide off the mountain and collect at the base of a cliff. The main cave, nearly 100 feet deep and 25 feet wide, is among the most popular hiking destinations in the Cascade Mountains.
But authorities have long warned that the caves are dangerous, because when temperatures rise, they can fall apart in giant ice mounds.
Susan Gregg, a spokeswoman for Harborview Medical Center in Seattle, said the hospital was treating two males for head lacerations and leg and pelvis fractures. A female patient arrived shortly afterward.
All the injured were conscious, but one man, 25, was in critical condition, Gregg said. A second man, 35, was in serious condition and the woman, 35, was in satisfactory condition.
A photo posted by NBC News (@nbcnews)
One girl who was not seriously injured in the collapse was transported by ground and being treated at Providence Medical Center in Everett.
Snohomish County emergency officials said the area around the Big Four ice caves would remain closed until search and rescue teams could assess the safety of the caves and recover the deceased victim of the collapse.
Temperatures reached 80 degrees in the area of the caves Monday as Washington swelters through a heat wave. The heat led the U.S. Forest Service to issue a special warning in May alerting hikers that the main cave was in a "dangerous state ... large, inviting and collapsing," and urging them to stay out of it. Several signs along the trail warn people to steer clear.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:36:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lennon's Reputation Is 'Revisionism,' McCartney Says</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e727f9/sc/14/l/0Ltime0N0C39468470Cpaul0Emccartney0Ejohn0Elennon0Emartyred0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>In a new interview with the U.K. edition of Esquire magazine, Paul McCartney has opened up on the subject of John Lennon.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ken IshiiGetty Images Paul McCartney performs live at the Budokan on April 28, 2015 in Tokyo.
The former Beatle opens up about his late bandmate
In a new interview with the U.K. edition of Esquire magazine, Paul McCartney has opened up on the subject of John Lennon, the Beatles bandmate whose posthumous reputation McCartney seems to find frustrating.
Describing his reaction to Lennons assassination in 1980, McCartney said, in part:
Yeah, John was the witty one, sure. John did a lot of great work, yeah. And post-Beatles he did more great work, but he also did a lot of not-great work. Now the fact that hes now martyred has elevated him to a James Dean, and beyond. So whilst I didnt mind thatI agreed with itI understood that now there was going to be revisionism. It was going to be: John was the one.
McCartney also expressed regret that a plan to alternate the Beatles songwriting credits between Lennon/McCartney and McCartney/Lennon did not come to pass, specifically citing the song Yesterday, written by McCartney solely.
I said, Could we have By Paul McCartney and John Lennon, wouldnt that be a good idea? [] Particularly on that particular song, because the original artwork had Yesterday by John Lennon and Paul McCartney and a photo of John above it. And I went, Argh! Come on, lads! Anyway they wouldnt do it.
Read the full interview at Esquires site.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:34:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Credit Card Interest-Rate Scam Refuses to Die</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e663bd/sc/24/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cbusiness0Cconsumer0Crobocall0Ecredit0Ecard0Einterest0Escam0Econtinues0Eplague0Econsumers0En387676/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Robocalls pitching interest rate reductions on credit card balances continue to plague consumers, despite federal efforts to stop the con artists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 5:34 am ET
Robocall Credit Card Interest Scam Continues to Plague Consumers
by Herb Weisbaum
advertisement
Has "Rachel from Card Services" called you?
Telephone fraudsters know that Americans are fed up with high interest rates on their credit card balances and have for years been trying to cash in on that frustration by tricking consumers into paying them as much as several thousand dollars for bogus rate reduction programs.
This con, often initiated by pre-recorded robocallers like "Rachel," has been going on for years. And despite numerous enforcement actions by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), it just won't go away.
'It's disheartening'
Bikram Bandy, coordinator of the FTC's Do Not Call Program, says he is concerned that many people are falling for the scam - and losing money - when offered the "too-good-to-be true" promise of unrealistically low interest rates.
advertisement
"It's disheartening that this scam continues, and it does continue because the scammers are still making money from it," Bandy told NBC News.
Like most telemarketing frauds these days, this scam typically starts with a recorded message from "credit services" or "card member services," often in the voice of "Rachel" but also from others, saying you qualify for a special interest rate reduction program that will help you pay off your balance sooner.
Related: Robocallers Are Coming After Your Cell Phone
Respond to the message and you'll be connected to a representative who falsely claims to work for your bank or credit card company.
Victims who take the bait either get nothing for their money or the scammer does something that they could have done on their own - for free - such as asking the credit card company for a hardship rate reduction.
advertisement
In recent years, the FTC has sued more than a dozen boiler-room operations making these bogus credit card rate reduction offers. And yet, the calls keep going out. In fact, when it comes to robocall complaints, these rate reduction calls top the list.
Several weeks ago, the FTC and Florida Attorney General sued an Orlando-based telemarketer that allegedly had been bombarding people across the country with rate reduction robocalls since 2011. A federal district court judge agreed to temporarily shut down the company.
"Too often the services promised were never provided, and the consumer faced even more credit card debt through charges made without their consent," Florida Attorney General Pam Bondi said in a statement.
They may say it's 'free,' but it's not
Rosa Pagan, who lives near Philadelphia, got one of these calls last year. She wound up talking to "Eugene," who claimed to be associated with her Sears MasterCard. He claimed that because of her good payment history, she was "pre-qualified" to have the interest rate on her card reduced from 24 percent to zero.
advertisement
"He had my complete credit card number and account information, so I really thought he was calling from Sears," Pagan told NBC News. "And he assured me there was no charge for this; it was free."
Once Eugene "verified" that she was qualified, he transferred Pagan to a "supervisor" who told her the service would cost $1,900, but he was willing to give her a special deal of $1,400. Pagan said "no," and told him she didn't want anything to do with the company.
Related: FCC Gives Phone Companies Power to Block Robocalls
When her next credit card statement arrived, Pagan found an unauthorized charge of $1,498 for the service she had declined. She complained to Sears, which reversed the fraudulent charge. Pagan told the FTC she did not give the company her card number and she does not know how they got it.
"It's terrible what they're doing to people," Pagan said. "You have a phone in your house and you can't pick it up because you never know what scam is going to come through the phone. We got caller ID and I will not answer the phone unless I am expecting the call or it's from someone I know."
advertisement
Dealing with robocalls
Robocalls continue to be a serious problem. These automated calls are the cheapest and easiest way for telemarketing scammers to find their victims.
Remember: If you get a robocall that's trying to sell you something, that call is illegal unless you have given that company specific permission to call you.
If you pick up the phone and it is a robocall - hang up. Don't press any keys to speak to an operator or to add your number to their do not call list. These crooks don't have a do not call list. And never call back. If you respond in any way, it will probably lead to more robocalls.
Never give personal information, such as credit card, checking account or Social Security number to an unknown caller, not even if the caller tries to "confirm" this information. That's just a trick, possibly aimed at getting you to reveal your personal details or getting you to supply missing information, like a PIN, for data obtained from a hacker or some other nefarious source.
If you are struggling to make payments on your credit card, contact a reputable credit counselor. You can find a nonprofit agency near you by going to the National Foundation for Credit Counseling website.
Herb Weisbaum is The ConsumerMan. Follow him on Facebook and Twitter or visit The ConsumerMan website.
Herb Weisbaum
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:16:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS' Destruction of History Is a War Crime: UNESCO</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e663bc/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cisis0Eterror0Cunesco0Eboss0Eirina0Ebokova0Elaments0Eisis0Ecultural0Ecleansing0Eantiquities0En386291/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The boss of UNESCO says that ISIS' rampant destruction and looting of millennia-old heritage sites amounts to a form of "cultural cleansing."</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 5:16 am ET
UNESCO's Irina Bokova Laments ISIS' 'Cultural Cleansing' of Antiquities
by Michele Neubert and Alexander Smith
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_unescobokova_150702" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
ISIS' rampant destruction and looting of millennia-old heritage sites amounts to a form of "cultural cleansing," according to the head of the United Nations' heritage body.
UNESCO Director-General Irina Bokova told NBC News that the extremists' campaign of wiping out antiquities in Iraq and Syria was unprecedented in contemporary history and classifiable as a war crime under international law.
"Cultural cleansing, in my view, is exactly what's happening in Iraq ," Bokova said in an interview. "These extremists want to impose a different vision on the world. They want to tell us that there is no memory [of these sites], that there is no culture, that there is no heritage."
advertisement
Since announcing the establishment of a caliphate in Iraq and Syria last year, ISIS has destroyed dozens of historically-significant sites, according to UNESCO.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_ots_isis_demolition_150412" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Heritage officials feared another irreplaceable loss in May after the Islamist group sized the ancient Syrian city of Palmyra , a UNESCO world heritage site and "one of the most important cultural centers of the ancient world," according to the U.N. body.
advertisement
Countless other places falling under ISIS' territory could be at risk. The group controls more than 20 percent of the 10,000 archaeological sites in Iraq alone, Bokova said at a discussion organized by the Royal United Services Institute (RUSI) in London.
As if to underline her concerns, security consultancy and NBC News partner Flashpoint Intelligence reported that ISIS released a statement the same day saying it had crushed a collection of statues that a suspected "smuggler" was attempting to remove from Palmyra.
ISIS militants in Syria entered the UNESCO World Heritage Site of Palmyra after seizing the town next to the ancient ruins. Travers Eric / Sipa USA File
Bokova explained that part of the problem was that there were "no inventories, no lists" of many relics.
"It's not like taking objects from the museum," she added.
advertisement
Bokova said the "enormous legacy" and "wonderful remnants of heritage" from the long-standing Christian, Jewish, Yazidi and Muslim communities in the region all were at risk.
"It is about destroying of cultural heritage, it is about looting, it is about uprooting people from their living communities and it is about destroying the incredible cultural diversity of the Middle East and Iraq," she said.
The key difference between the damage being done by ISIS and the losses seen in previous conflicts was that it was "not the collateral damage of a conflict, it is a systematic," Bokova said. "It is very deliberate destruction."
But UNESCO and other heritage groups say that as well as proudly destroying some antiquities, ISIS has been looting precious items from these sites and selling them on the black market to fund their operations.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_ots_isis_museum_150226" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Bokova said it was impossible to know exactly how much money the Islamists were making in this way because "there are so many illicit activities going on."
However, she told the RUSI discussion that it was "safe to assume the trade in conflict antiquities from Syria and Iraq represents millions of dollars for violent extremist groups."
She told NBC News that "every single day, at some customs [authority] somewhere in the world, we see artifacts appearing from Syria from Iraq."
A still from an ISIS video posted on April 11 purportedly shows militants with an Assyrian relief in the ancient city of Nimrud, Iraq. AFP via Getty Images
According to Chris Marinello, London-based lawyer specializing in looted art, ISIS represents the "gravest single threat to cultural heritage since the Second World War."
Marinello said there were reports the group was using eBay, Facebook and the instant messaging service WhatsApp to find buyers.
"A parallel can be drawn between the way [ISIS] is treating looted works of art and what the Nazis did it with so called 'degenerate art' looted from Jewish families 75 years ago," he said.
According to Marinello, both the Nazis and ISIS recognized the propaganda value in destroying some of the items they felt went against their beliefs, while simultaneously cashing in by selling others on the black market.
In an attempt to turn the tide, Bokova has brought together U.N. bodies, Interpol and the International Institute for the Unification of Private Law (Unidroit) to allow experts to share their knowledge and attempt to monitor the exchange of these artifacts on the black market.
"It is said, 'You can't fight an enemy you don't know,'" she told last Thursday's RUSI discussion. "This is why we need more research and better analysis."
A still from a video posted on April 3 shows an ISIS militant hammering away at a face on a wall in the Iraqi city of Hatra, which is recognized as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. AP
Michele Neubert
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:15:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Honoring the Dead Is a Delicate Business in Chicago Gangland</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e663a4/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cchicagos0Ecruel0Esummer0Cchicago0Efuneral0Ehomes0Eface0Echallenges0Egang0Eterritory0En38640A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Violence in Chicago presents challenges for the businesses that honor the dead.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 5:15 am ET
Chicago Funeral Homes Face Challenges in Gang Territory
by Tracy Jarrett
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=p_jb_chicago_funeral2_150630" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
There were more than 2,000 shootings in Chicago last year, and the city is on pace for more this year. The violence worsens in the summer months: over the holiday weekend , dozens of people were shot and nine died in the gunfire. Beneath the sobering figures are personal stories, both of fear and resilience. NBC News' Tracy Jarrett spent time in Chicago to hear them.
Part 2 in a series.
advertisement
CHICAGO  At A.A. Rayner &amp; Sons funeral home in Chicago, Charles Childs is used to planning celebrations of long lives. His biggest concern traditionally has been timing the stop lights as he leads grieving families in a procession to the cemetery.
These days, though, he has to worry about arranging a police presence to control the large, often emotional crowds that show up for the funerals of young people whose lives have been cut short by gun violence.
Rayner &amp; Sons is a predominantly black funeral home founded in 1947 on the city's South Side. It handled the funerals for Emmett Till, the 14-year-old slain in Mississippi in 1955 after reportedly flirting with a white woman, and Mayor Harold Washington, Chicago's first black mayor.
Childs is the president of the funeral home and has been in the business for 40 years. He used to see one or two violence-related funerals a year. Now, he says he directs one or two every month.
So he has to take into consideration all sorts of things that he otherwise wouldn't  avoiding certain gang colors, navigating a tricky route between the service and the cemetery and hiring cops to keep the peace.
advertisement
At these funerals for interrupted lives, the mood is as much tense as somber. Eulogies must be delicately written for "kids who may have been doing things they shouldn't have been doing," Childs said. The smallest thing can turn grief to violence.
"It could be something so minor, like somebody stepping on somebody's foot or not saying hello or being asked to take their hat off," Childs said.
In 2012, two men were shot outside a funeral that Childs was directing for a reputed gang member. One was critically injured, the other killed on the church steps. The family of the deceased had not told Childs about the gang association, so he hadn't arranged for police.
"I was standing over him when his eyes rolled in the back of his head," Childs recalled.
Behind the scenes, funeral directors in Chicago are dealing with demographic challenges  young mothers and grandparents, some of whom have wrenching questions about how and why death visited their young children. Others are all too aware.
advertisement
Pamela Rayner stands among caskets at A.A. Rayner &amp;amp; Sons Modern Funeral. (John Brecher / NBC News) John Brecher / NBC News
Pamela Rayner, one of the owners of the funeral home, remembers one mother who would not speak for 15 minutes when she came to arrange services for her son. At the funeral, she stood outside for 25 minutes before entering.
"It kind of got to me because I'm thinking to myself this is her only child," Rayner said. "Can you imagine not today, not tomorrow, but next week when everybody is gone and everybody is back to their old daily work, she has to go into their son's house, in their son's room, and start putting away his clothes."
She has seen mothers and grandmothers who have taken out life insurance on their own kids. She had to stop one funeral because of the threat of gang retaliation, and tell the mourners that for their own protection the service couldn't go on.
Cost is a concern, too, for families and the funeral home alike. Rayner &amp; Sons and other funeral homes often provide pro bono services or deep discounts.
advertisement
An average family who comes to Rayner &amp; Sons spends $6,000 to $7,000 on the funeral alone, plus $2,000 to $5,000 on cemetery and burial fees. Many families that have lost children to violence can only pay a fraction of the cost, Childs said.
"We try to make sure they get the kind of decent service they can afford or that we can afford to give them," said Marguerite Gatling of Gatling Chapel, a funeral home that she runs with her husband on the South Side.
The Gatlings say they have seen families sell shirts and pins with the name and face of their loved one to cover the costs. Others have asked for donations at the services.
Funeral director Lafayette Gatling, who works on the south side of Chicago, gives a bible like this one to each family he serves.(John Brecher / NBC News) John Brecher / NBC News
Still, Marguerite Gatling said, she and her husband try not to let money limit what they can provide for families who have lost a child to gun violence. Others who can pay full price keep the funeral home solvent.
Making sacrifices to honor the dead is important to the Gatlings. Lafayette Gatling Sr., Marguerite's husband, remembers his mother's funeral when he was five. He remembers a viewing at his home, and being ashamed at the simple casket.
He doesn't want anyone else to feel that way.
"Regardless of how this person lived or what he did or what crime he committed, it's not our personal business," he said. "Somebody loved this person. If nobody loved him, nobody would be here."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:54:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida State QB Who Punched Woman Was Provoked: Lawyer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e639bd/sc/13/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cfsu0Equarterback0Edeandre0Ejohnson0Ewas0Eonly0Efighting0Eback0Elawyer0Esays0En387816/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>De'Andre Johnson has been charged with battery following the incident at a Tallahassee Club. The freshman player also was kicked off FSU's team.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 4:54 am ET
FSU Quarterback De'Andre Johnson Was Provoked, Lawyer Says
by Cassandra Vinograd and Gabe Gutierrez
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_gabe_quarterback_150707" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The Florida State University quarterback seen on video punching a woman in the face was fighting back after being provoked, his lawyer told NBC News.
De'Andre Johnson, 19, has been charged with battery following the June 24 incident at a Tallahassee club. The freshman player was kicked off the FSU football team after surveillance video emerged which appeared to show the freshman quarterback taking a swing at the unidentified woman.
According to his lawyer, Johnson was not the initial aggressor  but is "owning this" and trying to learn from the experience.
advertisement
The woman raised her fist and shouted "racial epithets" at Johnson when the player accidentally made contact when he was walking up to the bar, lawyer Jose Baez told NBC News.
Johnson "tried to deescalate the situation" but the woman "kneed him in the groin area" and "took another swing before he retaliated," the attorney added.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_fsu_qbpunch_150706" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
"It wasn't until she struck him twice that he reacted," Baez said. "But he is very...He is very regretful that he didn't turn around and walk away immediately."
advertisement
"He makes no excuses for what happened," he added.
Baez called Johnson's dismissal from the football team "unfortunate" and said his client is now volunteering at a shelter for battered women.
"All he wants to do is learn from this experience and move on and get an education," Baez said. "We certainly don't want him to pay for the rest of his life for an incident that occurred in a bar."
Court documents said the victim was trying to defend herself after she was pushed and grabbed by Johnson. A witness heard the victim yell "no" at Johnson twice before he punched her in the face, according to an affidavit.
The victim  who has declined comment to NBC News  suffered bruising under her left eye, swelling to the left cheek and a small cut near the bridge of her nose in the incident.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:36:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Suicide Bomb Hits NATO Convoy in Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e67dd9/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cnato0Econvoy0Ekabul0Eafghanistan0Ehit0Esuicide0Eblast0En387811/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A NATO military convoy was attacked by a bomber in the Afghan capital on Tuesday, officials told NBC News.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_kabul_150707" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
KABUL, Afghanistan  A NATO military convoy was hit by a suicide car bomb in the Afghan capital on Tuesday, officials told NBC News.
The Taliban claimed subsequently claimed responsibility for the blast in the Shah Shaheed area of the city, but NATO said that no coalition forces were killed in the explosion.
Around three or four civilians were injured in the bombing, according to the Ministry of Public Health. Abdul Bashir, a local police officer at the scene, had told NBC News earlier that "many people have been injured and ambulances are rushing [them] to the hospitals."
advertisement
Smoke and flames rise from burning vehicles at the site of the bomb blast in Kabul, Afghanistan. AFP via Getty Images
U.S. Army Col. Brian Tribus, spokesman for the NATO mission in Afghanistan, confirmed there had been an "attack on coalition forces" at around 11:30 a.m. local time (3 a.m. ET).
He said the force was "gathering further information on this incident" but confirmed in a statement that no NATO personnel had been killed.
Fazul Rahim
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:08:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Eric Holder: Edward Snowden Might Return to U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e54cb0/sc/7/l/0Ltime0N0C39472360Ceric0Eholder0Eedward0Esnowden0C/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A deal returning NSA leaker Edward Snowden to the U.S. is not entirely out of the question, according to former Attorney General Eric Holder.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saul LoebAFP/Getty Images Attorney General Eric Holder walks from Air Force One after arriving with US President Barack Obama at Andrews Air Force Base in Maryland, March 6, 2015.
The former Attorney General said "the possibility exists"
A deal returning NSA leaker Edward Snowden to the U.S. is not entirely out of the question , according to Eric Holder.
The former U.S. Attorney General told Yahoo News, I certainly think there could be a basis for a resolution that everybody could ultimately be satisfied with to return Snowden from his current asylum in Moscow. I think the possibility exists, he said.
Holder, who is going back to work at the law firm Covington &amp; Burling, where he worked before serving as Attorney General, said that Snowdens actions spurred a necessary debate on surveillance in America.
We are in a different place as a result of the Snowden disclosures, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 07:02:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Victims Face Down 'Smug' Cancer Doc in Court</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e323f4/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Ccancer0Cvictims0Eface0Edown0Edr0Efarid0Efata0Ecancer0Efraud0Ecase0En387666/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Dr. Farid Fata could get as much as 175 years in prison when he is sentenced for misdiagnosing and over-treating patients.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Dozens of a disgraced cancer doctor's former patients  who say they were given false diagnoses or needless treatment  converged on a Detroit courthouse Monday for the start of a weeklong sentencing hearing.
Prosecutors are asking that Dr. Farid Fata, who pleaded guilty to fraud for bilking patients and insurance companies out of millions, get 175 years in prison.
About 35 of the victims took a bus to federal court for the chance to watch Fata as a government witness described his crimes.
"When he walked by me during one of the breaks, when they walked him out, I looked him square in the face. He had that 'Fata look'  smug," said Steven Skrzypczak.
advertisement
Steve Skrzypczak, 68, was told he had non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. Fata implanted a mediport in his chest and gave him 25 treatments with one chemo drug in six months, Skrzypczak said.
After Fata's arrest in 2013, Skrzypczak went to two other oncologists who told him that he'd never had cancer.
"I want him to get life," the ex-patient said of the doctor.
Dr. Farid Fata of Oakland County, Mich. The Oakland Press / ZUMAPRESS.com
In a pre-sentencing memo, prosecutors say 553 people allegedly got unnecessary treatment from Fata  amounting to 9,000 injections or infusions that cost insurance companies and patients millions. Some of the patients weren't even sick; others were so ill the treatments did more harm than good, prosecutors say.
advertisement
Fata's lawyer also filed a pre-sentencing memo, but it has been sealed. His attorneys have declined to comment on the allegations but they will get a chance to argue that he does not deserve a life sentence.
The hearing is expected to last at least four days. It opened with an expert witness for the government, Dr. Dan Longo, a Harvard oncologist who reviewed two dozen case files for prosecutors.
He said one patient identified only as C.C. received unnecessary chemotherapy for five years.
Fata's lawyer, Christopher Andreoff showed Longo evidence while he was on the stand that Longo had not previously seen that showed C.C. did in fact have cancer.
Longo said that while he would revise his testimony in light of that, he maintained, C.C. was treated with unnecessary chemotherapy.
"He's been treated continuously after going into remission," Longo said.
Fata's lawyer, Christopher Andreoff, retorted, "C.C. is alive after five years."
Longo said there was a common thread in the case files he examined.
"There is an aggressive approach to treating cancer  this was beyond aggressive. This was over the top."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:55:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Alabama Man Hunts Mystery Couple in Wedding Album</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e2803b/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Calabama0Eman0Ehunts0Emystery0Ecouple0Ewedding0Ealbum0En387636/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Randy Robinson bought an electronic photo frame and found it was already loaded with someone's wedding album.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 6 2015, 11:55 pm ET
Alabama Man Hunts Mystery Couple in Found Wedding Album
by Tracy Connor
advertisement
When Randy Robinson bought an electronic photo frame at a discount shop in Alabama a few months ago, he didn't bargain on the mystery it contained.
The frame contained a data card, and Robinson, a engineer, was surprised to find out it was loaded with wedding pictures from July 2012
"I wanted to find the couple," he told NBC News on Monday.
He started by following the visual clues.
There was a photo of a catering truck, but when he called the company, they were reluctant to help and said their records didn't go back that far. He managed to trace the limousine to Massachusetts, but hasn't heard back from the company that owns it.
advertisement
Next step: Facebook.
Robinson posted a picture of the bride and groom with a shot-in-the-dark plea. By Monday afternoon, it had gotten 153,000 shares and he was deluged with friend requests.
"It's crazy," he said.
Six days after Robinson first posted the photo, a couple who own an event-planning company in the Boston area said on their Facebook page that they are the mystery newlyweds.
"This is hilarious!" they said. "Thank you everyone for posting this photo. We never lost our wedding photos thankfully, this is actually from a returned item we thought was broken (a digital picture frame). So heartwarming to know that people care so much."
The couple could not be immediately reached for comment to verify that they were the same bride and groom in the picture.
Tracy Connor
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:07:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mexican Man Singled Out by Trump Charged With Murder</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e43d0a/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cprosecutors0Echarge0Eman0Emurder0Esan0Efrancisco0Epier0Edeath0En387746/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Prosecutors have charged a Mexican immigrant with murder in the killing of Kathryn Steinle, who was on a waterfront stroll with her father when she was shot.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 7 2015, 7:59 am ET
Prosecutors Charge Mexican Man With Murder in San Francisco Pier Death
by The Associated Press
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_peter_trump_150707" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Prosecutors have charged a Mexican immigrant with murder in the seemingly random shooting death of a woman who was on a waterfront stroll with her father last week in San Francisco.
Authorities said Monday that 45-year-old Francisco Sanchez is expected to be arraigned Tuesday in the death of 32-year-old Kathryn Steinle. Sanchez, a repeat drug offender and undocumented immigrant who has been deported five times, was released from jail on April 15 in San Francisco.
The killing vaulted into the presidential race over the weekend, with Republican candidate Donald Trump pointing to it as evidence of his widely criticized comments last month about Mexican immigrants.
advertisement
"This senseless and totally preventable act of violence committed by an illegal immigrant is yet another example of why we must secure our border immediately," Trump said in a statement. Trump's opponent Ted Cruz defended him on "Meet The Press," saying, "I salute Donald Trump for focusing on the need to fix illegal immigration."
Steinle's death has also brought criticism on San Francisco because it disregarded a request from immigration authorities to keep Sanchez locked up. The liberal city is one of dozens across the country that do not fully cooperate with federal immigration authorities. The city goes so far as to promote itself as a "sanctuary" for people in the country illegally.
In a jailhouse interview with a TV station, Francisco Sanchez, the 45-year-old repeat drug offender arrested in the shooting last Wednesday of Kathryn Steinle, appeared to confirm that he came to the city because of its status as a sanctuary.
"Most of the blame should fall squarely on the shoulders of the San Francisco sheriff, because his department had custody of him and made the choice to let him go without notifying [U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement]," said Jessica Vaughan, director of policy studies at the Washington-based Center for Immigration Studies, which wants tougher immigration enforcement.
Sheriff Ross Mirkarimi strongly defended his office's release of Sanchez and pointed the finger back at ICE, saying the federal agency should have issued an arrest warrant for Sanchez. Mayor Ed Lee issued a statement saying city policy was never intended to protect "repeat, serious and violent felons."
advertisement
Lee asked for federal and local agencies to review what happened.
Many other San Francisco politicians stayed quiet as mourners held a late Monday morning vigil on the downtown waterfront where Steinle was gunned down.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:58:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fake Security Guard Walks Out of Walmart With $75,000</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e54cc6/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cman0Edressed0Earmored0Etruck0Edriver0Ewalks0Eout0Ewalmart0E750E0A0A0A0En387751/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The suspect entered the Walmart store on the morning of July 4, walked to the cash office, signed for the deposit and walked right out.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 6 2015, 10:58 pm ET
Man Dressed as Armored Truck Driver Walks Out of Walmart With $75,000
by The Associated Press
advertisement
BRISTOW, Okla.  Investigators were working Monday to identify a man who took more than $75,000 from an Oklahoma Walmart after disguising himself as an armored truck driver.
Bristow Police Chief Wayne Williams said authorities in northeast Oklahoma have received some anonymous tips about the identity of the man whose image was captured by a video surveillance camera.
"We've got some calls out on it, but nothing yet," Williams said. He said officials do not believe the suspect lives in the area.
Authorities say the suspect entered the Walmart store in Bristow about 10:30 a.m. Saturday, walked to the cash office, signed for the deposit and walked out of the store. He drove away in a dark four-door Chevrolet.
"He came to the Walmart kind of dressed like a Loomis armored car driver," Williams said. Walmart employees called police after the real Loomis employee arrived about 45 minutes later. Bristow is about 35 miles southwest of Tulsa.
advertisement
In this July 4, 2015 frame from surveillance video provided by the Bristow Police Department, a man leaves with more than $75,000 from a Wal-Mart after disguising himself as an armored truck driver in Bristow, Okla. Authorities say the suspect walked to the cash office, signed for the deposit and walked out of the store. Bristow Police Department via AP
Williams said Walmart has alerted its other stores about the theft and his department has notified other law enforcement agencies.
Walmart Stores Inc. spokeswoman Betsy Harden said she wasn't aware of any similar incidents involving other Wal-Mart stores.
"Obviously, it's an ongoing investigation," Harden said. She declined to comment on whether the Bentonville, Arkansas-based company plans to alter its policy on verifying the identity of workers who transport its cash deposits.
Williams said investigators have no evidence the suspect may have once worked for an armored transportation service and was familiar with its procedures.
"It's not something we suspect. It's a possibility," Williams said.
Loomis spokesman Danny Pack declined to comment on the case.
The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 05:35:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Four Boys Face Charges in Huge Oregon Stadium Fire</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47e41484/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cfour0Eboys0Eages0E10A0E120Ebe0Echarged0Earson0Eoregon0Estadium0En387741/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The fire last week destroyed Civic Stadium in Eugene, a Depression-era landmark that had been on the National Register of Historic Places.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jul 6 2015, 10:35 pm ET
Four Boys to Be Charged With Arson in Massive Oregon Stadium Fire
by M. Alex Johnson
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_eugene_150630" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Four preteen boys will be charged with first-degree arson over a fire that destroyed a Oregon sports stadium on the National Register of Historic Places, authorities said Monday.
As weeping onlookers mournfully sang "Take Me Out to the Ballgame," Eugene's Civic Stadium  built in 1938 as part of the Depression-fighting Works Progress Administration  burned down June 29 just two months after a deal had been hammered out to give it new life as a facility for kids' sports.
Eugene police quickly zeroed in on five boys who had been seen near the stadium, and they were taken into custody last week.
advertisement
<<<<<<< HEAD
Four of the boys, who weren't identified because they're all 10 to 12 years old, face a variety of other charges, including multiple counts of criminal mischief, burglary, reckless burning and reckless endangering, NBC station KMTR of Eugene and the Oregonian newspaper of Portland reported, quoting police and prosecutors.
"I don't know if you've talked to a 10- or 12-year-old boy recently. You don't get a whole lot of rational information out of them."
The fifth boy, whose parents tipped off police, won't be charged because he left the area before the fire started, police said.
Eugene police Detective Steve Williams told reporters the boys didn't appear to have intended to set the blaze, which they then fled from in panic on their bicycles.
"They were messing around, and they were lighting some debris on fire and just being kids," Williams said last week. But he said there's still much to be learned because interviews haven't yielded a great deal.
advertisement
"I don't know if you've talked to a 10- or 12-year-old boy recently," he said. "You don't get a whole lot of rational information out of them."
Onlookers watch the Civic Stadium burn in Eugene, Ore., on June 29. The stadium was approved by voters in 1938 during the Great Depression and opened that same year. Andy Nelson / The Register-Guard via AP
M. Alex Johnson
=======
A company spokeswoman said Krill was a skilled and experienced pilot with a good safety record. He had flown for many years and had 4,300 hours of flight experience, including roughly 1,700 hours piloting single engine seaplanes. The airplane that crashed is one of five floatplanes operated by the company.
The Associated Press
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
