<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:32:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen Kill at Least 27 People in Attack on Tunisia Beach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479968de/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Ctunisia0Eattack0Egunmen0Ekill0Eleast0E190Epeople0Eattack0Esousse0Ebeach0En382346/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen opened fire on Western tourists on a beach in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 29 people, the country's interior ministry said.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Gunmen opened fire on a beach popular with tourists in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 27 people, the country's interior ministry said.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry told NBC News that at least six people were injured in the attack in the Mediterranean city of Sousse and that one attacker had been killed. The interior ministry said the operation was ongoing.
Gary Pine, a product manager from the U.K., told NBC News he was one of dozens of vacationers on the beach when the attack took place not far from his hotel, the El Mouradi Palm Marina.
He said he initially thought he was hearing firecrackers but that "it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire." His 22-year-old son saw one person get shot, Pine added.
He said guests started running off the beach and were told to go to their rooms by hotel staff, he said. Some guests ran back out onto the beach to get their room keys, he added.
The entertainment manager at the hotel, who only gave his first name, Hamouda, said guests had told him two gunmen "came from the sea" and attacked the beach. He confirmed that staff had told guests to hide in their rooms.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:22:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terror Probe Opened After Gruesome Attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4798e2b8/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cman0Edecapitated0Epossible0Eislamist0Eattack0Efrench0Efactory0Ereports0En38230A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>French authorities opened a terrorism investigation Friday after one person was beheaded in an apparent Islamist attack on a gas factory in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 8:22 am ET
Man Decapitated in Suspected Islamist Attack on Air Products Factory in France
by Alastair Jamieson, Cassandra Vinograd and Alexander Smith
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_kelly_terrorist_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
One person was decapitated and two others wounded in an apparent terror attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France, President Francois Hollande said Friday.
A car crashed through the gates of the Air Products plant in Saint-Quentin Fallavier. southeastern France, shortly after 10 a.m. local time (4 a.m. ET). It was followed by an explosion.
Hollande said a suspect had been arrested and there was "no doubt" that the attacker  possibly acting with an accomplice  intended to blow up the entire plant.
advertisement
The president  who told reporters that the decapitated body was found with "inscriptions" on it  said the attack bore the hallmarks of terrorism, adding that security has been stepped up at sensitive sites in France.
French interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve told reporters at the scene that the suspect was known to authorities and had previously been investigated for radicalization but surveillance ended in 2008.
An interior ministry official earlier told NBC News that an explosion occurred after a car drove onto the scene.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_hollande_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
The severed head was found hanging on a fence along a nearby road, according to local newspaper La Dauphine Libere, which said that an Islamist flag also was found nearby.
Air Products said the situation at the site had been "contained" and that all its employees had been evacuated from the site and accounted for.
"The site is secure," the Allentown, Pennsylvania-based company said in a statement. "Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
The beheaded person was not a worker at the factory, Le Monde reported, citing prosecutors .
France has been on high alert following the deadly January attacks on satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo and a kosher supermarket.
advertisement
Hollande, who announced he was returning early from a European summit in Brussels, spoke of "the necessity to protect our values and never give in to fear and not to create any unnecessary division and suspicions [which] would be intolerable and unacceptable."
Air Products supplies industrial gases to businesses and employs more than 20,000 people in 50 countries, according to its website.
 NBC News' Jake Cigainero contributed to this report
Alastair Jamieson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:31:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friday's Top 7 News Stories</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47996fb6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Efridays0Etop0E70Estories0Enbc0Enews0En382316/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From the funeral for the slain Charleston pastor to the Obamacare victory in the Supreme Court, see the stories we're following today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_mor_obamacare_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
3. Man Decapitated in French Terror Attack
advertisement
French authorities began a terror investigation Friday after one person was reportedly beheaded in an apparent Islamist attack at a gas factory in southeastern France. The country's BFM TV reported that an explosion was heard in the morning at the Air Products plant and a decapitated body was found near the scene. Read more in NEWS .
4. Arrested Prison Guard Paints Negative Atmosphere
Gene Palmer, the second New York prison employee arrested in the escape this month of two convicted killers , described the prison as a "negative environment" that could lead corrections workers to suicide in a radio interview from 2000. His arraignment Thursday was postponed until Monday because Palmer is hiring new lawyers. Read more in NEWS .
5. Putin Talks ISIS, Ukraine With Obama
Russian President Vladimir Putin called Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East. In a statement, the White House said the two leaders addressed continued bloodshed in Syria and agreed on the importance of unity among the six world powers that are negotiating to restrict Iran's nuclear capabilities. Read more in POLITICS .
advertisement
6. Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Kills Nine On Board
A sightseeing plane company boss told of his "pain and anguish" Friday after a pilot and all eight passengers were killed in a crash in southeastern Alaska. The plane was carrying cruise-ship passengers on a shore excursion when it crashed in the Misty Fjords area near Ketchikan. The NTSB has begun its investigation. Read more in NEWS .
7. Univision Dumps Trump Over Mexico Remarks
Univision announced Wednesday it is ending its relationship with the Miss Universe organization, which is partially owned by billionaire Donald Trump, following his remarks about Mexico sending its criminals and rapists to the U.S. Univision had acquired the rights to air the Miss Universe pageant in Spanish. Trump is running for the GOP presidential nomination, and made the controversial comment during his announcement. Read more in LATINO .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All 9 Aboard Cruise-Excursion Plane Die in Crash</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47960271/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ccruise0Eline0Eexcursion0Eplane0Ecrashes0Enine0Eaboard0Ealaska0En382166/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Alaska State Troopers said search and crews were able to reach the scene of the crash and confirmed the deaths, but bad weather hampered recovery.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 5:39 am ET
Alaska Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Killing All Nine Aboard
by Alastair Jamieson, M. Alex Johnson and Shamar Walters
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_blake_plane_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A sightseeing plane company boss told of his "pain and anguish" Friday after a pilot and all eight passengers were killed in a crash in southeastern Alaska.
The plane was carrying cruise-ship passengers on a shore excursion when it crashed in the Misty Fjords area near Ketchikan.
The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) has begun an investigation into the cause of the accident.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_alaskafaa_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Search and rescue teams reached the crash site near a granite rock face about 800 feet above Ella Lake.
However, the recovery of the bodies was postponed until Friday due to bad weather.
advertisement
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," said Marcus Sessoms, president of the plane operator, Promech Air. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
He added: "During this time of grief, our employees are working to do everything we can to extend support and assistance to the loved ones of those affected."
The passengers were from the Holland America Line ship the MS Westerdam, which set off to Alaska from Seattle on June 20, Holland America Line said in a statement.
The names of the deceased were not released pending notification of next of kin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>J.K. Rowling Announces New 'Harry Potter' Play</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479807d8/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Charry0Epotter0Ecursed0Echild0Eopen0Elondon0Estage0En382281/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Called Harry Potter and the Cursed Child, JK Rowling said it will tell the "untold part " of Potter's story.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 5:26 am ET
J.K. Rowling Announces 'Harry Potter and the Cursed Child' Will Hit London Stage
by Henry Austin
advertisement
Fans of "Harry Potter" are set for a magical 2016 after J.K. Rowling announced that a new stage play featuring the boy wizard will open next year in London.
"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part II" Harry, Hermione and Ron are spotted by Deatheaters. They hide and Harry sends Patronus. Hogsmeade. (SC210) Jaap Buitendijk / Warner Bros.
The Scottish author announced on Twitter that "Harry Potter and the Cursed Child" will tell an "untold part" of Potter's story, but insisted the play was "not a prequel."
It "is the result of a collaboration between writer Jack Thorne, director John Tiffany and myself" she said, adding that she was "confident" that when audiences see the play they'll understand why she chose the stage instead of printed word to tell the story.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:13:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Consoler-in-Chief: Obama to Again Comfort the Nation</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479829e6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ccharleston0Echurch0Eshooting0Cconsoler0Echief0Eobama0Eagain0Ecomforts0Enation0Eafter0Eshootings0En381956/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From Aurora, Colorado to most recently, Charleston, South Carolina, President Obama has had to comment numerous times on deadly gun violence in America.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_melvin_charleston_150622" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
His tone was strong while renewing questions about his failed push for tougher gun laws.
He sounded a similar note in his 2013 State of the Union address following a shooting massacre at Sandy Hook Elementary School in which 26 people, 20 of them young children, were killed by a gunman.
"Because in the two months since Newtown, more than a thousand birthdays, graduations, and anniversaries have been stolen from our lives by a bullet from a gun," the president said. "Gabby Giffords deserves a vote," he added of the former Arizona congresswoman, who was shot in the head by a gunman two years earlier. "The families of Newtown deserve a vote. The families of Aurora deserve a vote. The families of Oak Creek, and Tucson, and Blacksburg, and the countless other communities ripped open by gun violence  they deserve a simple vote."
So far, no legislative strategy has emerged to revive the issue of gun control in congress, where a vote on background checks for gun owners failed in the Senate in April of 2013.
As recently as a few days ago, White House officials were not sure if gun control would be a part of the president's remarks on Friday.
"There's obviously been a robust public debate on a variety of issues that have emerged in the aftermath of this terrible incident," Earnest told reporters. "At this point, again, it's hard for me to rule out the president mentioning some aspects of this debate at this point."
Related: Mourners Pay Respects to Rev. Clementa Pinckney at Charleston's Emanuel AME Church
The president's redirect to the gun control issue in the wake of the Charleston church shooting did not go over well with some segments of the black community, said Andra Gillespie, a political science professor at Emory University who has written extensively about racial politics.
"It was as if he was deflecting this away from being a hate crime," Gillespie said. "He has gotten some backlash within black communities for having pivoted to gun control."
According to a senior White House official, the president is not expected in his remarks to lay out policy or a slew of new gun reforms.
The president's remarks, the official said, are first and foremost, a eulogy.
And he will likely speak without a prompter.
Kristin Donnelly
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:02:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tit for Tat: China Slams U.S. Gun Culture, Race Relations</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47985602/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cchina0Eslams0Eu0Es0Ehuman0Erights0Erecord0Eannual0Ereport0En382296/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>China accused the U.S. of being "haunted by spreading guns" and racial bias, in its tit-for-tat rebuttal to U.S. criticism of China's human rights record.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
BEIJING  China accused the United States on Friday of being "haunted by spreading guns" and racial discrimination, in its annual tit-for-tat rebuttal to U.S. criticism of China's human rights record.
In a lengthy report carried by the official Xinhua news agency, the information office of the State Council, or cabinet, said the United States "violated human rights in other countries in a more brazen manner, and was given more 'red cards' in the international human rights field."
On Thursday, the U.S. State Department released its annual report on human rights conditions in the world. In the China section of the report, it said repression and coercion were routine against activists, ethnic minorities and law firms that took on sensitive cases.
China has long rejected criticism of its rights' record and has pointed to its success at lifting millions out of poverty.
The State Council report was "an equal and mutually beneficial way of reciprocating" the United States, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang said at a daily briefing.
advertisement
The Chinese report, which was mostly compiled from U.S. media articles, said "racial discrimination has been a chronic problem in the United States human rights record," adding that the U.S. suppressed the voting rights of minorities.
"In 2014, multiple cases of arbitrary police killing of African-Americans have sparked huge waves of protests, casting doubts on the racial 'equality' in the United States and giving rise to racial hatred factors," the report said.
The report also criticized the U.S. for conducting surveillance on world leaders and civilians and for allowing a few interest groups to influence the government's decision-making.
Human rights have long been a source of tension between the world's two largest economies.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:32:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teens Charged With Gang Raping Mentally-Disabled Girl</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479829fc/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcmiami0N0Cnews0Clocal0C40ETeens0ECharged0EWith0ERaping0EMentally0EDisabled0EGirl0Eat0ENorth0EMiami0ESenior0EHigh0ESchool0E30A99749810Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Derek Bynum and three under-18 students, are charged with the gang rape of a mentally-disabled girl at North Miami Senior High School.</Description>
        <MainBody>Updated 4 minutes ago
Disturbing allegations have surfaced about an alleged gang rape at a South Florida high school.
Derek Bynum, 18, along with three other underage students, are charged with the gang rape of a mentally handicapped girl at North Miami Senior High School back in January.
4-Year-Old Twins Rescued From House Fire
The teens allegedly took the girl into a janitor's closet near the end of the school day and forced her to perform oral, anal and vaginal sex acts.
Court records show Bynum and one of the other teens pleaded not guilty. The other two teens have not yet entered pleas.
Wilton Manors to Start Ticketing Jaywalkers
The discovery process is ongoing. Were trying to get to the bottom of what, if anything, happened  and all the clients remain and are presumed innocent, said Matthew Ladd, a lawyer representing one of the suspects. Lawyers for the other teens did not return requests for comment, according to the Miami-Herald .
The Miami-Dade County School District released a statement Thursday saying in part, "While we struggle to understand the senseless depravity of this isolated but disturbing student incident -- we commend the deliberate and swift actions of Miami-Dade Schools Police in apprehending the alleged perpetrators."
Published at 11:25 PM EDT on Jun 25, 2015
News breaks at inconvenient times. 
Download one of the NBC6 mobile apps and have the news come to you. Watch live streaming newscasts, receive  critical push notifications on the go and stay in touch with your city  around the clock.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:45:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Leaders Strike Deal to Relocate 40,000 Migrants</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4797ffec/sc/24/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ceuropes0Eborder0Ecrisis0Ceurope0Emigrant0Ecrisis0E40A0E0A0A0A0Ewill0Emove0Eitaly0Egreece0Ee0En382246/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>40,000 refugees are to be relocated from southern Europe under a deal reached by political leaders to tackle the continent's worsening migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_calais_150623" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
LONDON  Forty-thousand refugees will be relocated from southern Europe under a deal reached by political leaders to tackle the continent's worsening migrant crisis.
The migrants will be moved from Greece and Italy to other European Union countries over the next two years under the agreement, reached early Friday in Brussels by European leaders . A further 20,000 refugees will be resettled directly from overcrowded camps in Syria, Iraq or Afghanistan.
Friday's deal is a voluntary scheme, and exemptions were granted for Hungary, which is politically opposed to accepting migrants, and Bulgaria, one of the bloc's poorest countries. Britain is also opting out of the plan, which was discussed at acrimonious talks.
RELATED: Human Traffic: Migrants in Serbia Seek Gateway to Europe
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended, describing the migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor."
The deal comes as Mediterranean countries are struggling to cope with an unprecedented influx of desperate people fleeing conflicts in north Africa and the Middle East.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:53:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama to Talk ISIS, Iran</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47976802/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Crussia0Elove0Eputin0Ecalls0Eobama0Etalk0Eshop0En38220A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin called President Barack Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 2:53 am ET
Putin Calls Obama to Talk ISIS, Iran and Ukraine
Share
advertisement
Russian President Vladimir Putin called President Barack Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East.
In a statement, the White House said the two leaders addressed continued bloodshed in Syria and agreed on the importance of unity among the six world powers that are negotiating to restrict Iran's nuclear capabilities.
As for Ukraine, the White House said Obama told Putin Russia needs to meet commitments it made in Minsk, Belarus, earlier this year, including the removal of troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory.
A file picture dated 18 June 2012 shows US President Barack Obama (R) talking with Russian President Vladimir Putin (L) during their meeting at Esperansa hotel prior G20 summit in Los Cabos, Mexico. ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/RIA NOVOSTI/KREM / EPA
The call came on the same day NATO's supreme allied commander cited a continuous flow of ammunition and other military supplies from Russia across the border to Ukraine.
advertisement
According to a posting on the Kremlin's official English website , "significant attention" was given to the topic of ISIS and terrorism in the Middle East.
"Vladimir Putin and Barack Obama agreed to instruct Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov and U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry to hold a meeting to discuss this issue," the Kremlin said.
Contributors The Associated Press and Hasani Gittens
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:45:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>I Don't Want a Lecture: Bristol Palin Announces Pregnancy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479739bb/sc/17/l/0L0Stoday0N0Cparents0Cbristol0Epalin0Eannounces0Eshe0Epregnant0Esecond0Echild0Et28841/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Bristol Palin announced she is expecting her second child, in an emotional blog post on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paris taxi drivers stage violent protests against Uber
"Honestly, I've been trying my hardest to keep my chin up on this one," she wrote on the website Patheos. "At the end of the day there's nothing I can't do with God by my side, and I know I am fully capable of handling anything that is put in front of me with dignity and grace."
Until last month, Palin was engaged to Medal of Honor recipient Dakota Meyer, but the pair called off the wedding in May.
Reuters file
"Life moves on no matter what," she continued. "So no matter how you feel, you get up, get dressed, show up, and never give up. When life gets tough, there is no other option but to get tougher."
Bristol, the daughter of former Alaska governor Sarah Palin, said that the pregnancy "has been, and will be, a huge disappointment to my family, to my close friends, and to many of you." But she asked readers to respect the privacy of her and her 6-year-old son, Tripp.
The 24-year-old added, "I do not want any lectures and I do not want any sympathy. My little family always has, and always will come first. Tripp, this new baby, and I will all be fine, because God is merciful."
Sarah Palin first announced that Bristol's wedding to Meyer would be canceled in a Facebook post on May 18, less than a week before the ceremony was scheduled to take place.
Bristol broke her silence on the matter on May 26, writing, "I know God's plan is greater than anything else, and Tripp and I are in Alaska beginning to rebuild our lives under much different circumstances than we anticipated."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:42:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Six Die in Multi-Vehicle Wreck on Tennessee Interstate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795faff/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Csix0Ekilled0Emulti0Evehicle0Ewreck0Etennessee0Einterstat0En38220A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Six people were killed and at least nine others were injured in a nine-vehicle pileup Thursday night on Interstate 75 near Chattanooga, Tennessee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_tn_carax_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Six people were killed and at least nine others were injured in a fiery nine-vehicle pileup Thursday night on Interstate 75 in Tennessee, Chattanooga police said.
Few details were immediately available because emergency crews were still at work, Chattanooga police said. At 11 p.m., four hours after the wreck, state traffic cameras showed the scene still littered with vehicles as police and state troopers worked to remove victims from the scene.
None of the victims were identified because their families had yet to be notified.
Emergency cars littered Interstate 75 at Exit 11 for hours after the crash at 7 p.m. ET. Tennessee Transportation Department
The state Department of Transportation said the crash involved at least one cargo-carrying semi-trailer.
I-75 northbound north of Exit 11 to the town Ooltewah, east of Chattanooga, was expected to be shut down until at least dawn Friday after the crash, police said.
I-75 northbound north of Exit 11 to the town Ooltewah, east of Chattanooga, Tennessee, was expected to be shut down until at least dawn Friday. Chattanooga, Tennessee, Police Department via Twitter
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:41:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore County Police Fatally Shoot Unarmed Man</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47963c7b/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbaltimore0Ecounty0Epolice0Efatally0Eshoot0Eunarmed0Eman0En382171/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police said the officers fired on Spencer McCain after he acted like he was armed and was going to use a weapon, but no weapon was found.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 25 2015, 10:41 pm ET
Baltimore County Police Fatally Shoot Unarmed Man on Domestic Call
by Phil Helsel
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_balt_police_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Baltimore County Police officers fatally shot an unarmed man while responding to a call of a domestic disturbance early Thursday morning, authorities said.
Three officers opened fire on Spencer Lee McCain, 41, after being called to a home in Owings Mills just after 1 a.m., and forcing their way inside because the officers feared a person may be in danger, Baltimore County police said in a statement. Police said officers could hear a disturbance inside, but no one answered the door.
Police said the officers shot McCain after he allegedly made movements that the officers interpreted as indicating he was armed and ready to act, but no weapon was found, police said. McCain was taken to a hospital where he was later pronounced dead.
advertisement
"The police officers encountered a subject in a defensive position, making body movements and arm movements that placed the officers in fear of serious injury or death," Baltimore County Police Chief Jim Johnson told reporters.
Police said all three officers fired and the investigation has not determined how many shots were fired, but investigators recovered 19 shell casings at the scene.
Police said a woman inside the home had "visible injuries" but refused treatment; two children were also inside the home. The woman was not identified, but police said McCain was prohibited by a court protective order from having any contact with her, and police said they were called to the home around 17 times since 2012.
Johnson said the woman told investigators that McCain told her, "You're going to get the beating you deserve," NBC station WBAL reported.
A neighbor told the station he heard what sounded like a woman "begging, you know, like, 'Don't do that. Don't do this. Please stop."
advertisement
Owing Mills is about 20 miles northwest of Baltimore, which was roiled by protests and riots after a black man, Freddie Gray, died after suffering a spinal injury while in police custody. McCain's race was not released.
Police said the homicide unit will complete an investigation and forward the results to the state's attorney's office for review.
Phil Helsel
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:28:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Enormous Noah's Ark Replica Takes Shape in Kentucky Field</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795e2ff/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbible0Ebased0Eall0Ewood0Eark0Etakes0Eshape0Ekentucky0Efield0En382146/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Builders are betting big that millions of visitors will flood the Williamstown, Kentucky, attraction.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_noahsark_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A planned all-wood replica of Noah's ark got a step closer to its Old Testament ideal on Thursday, when workers lifted yet another rib of the would-be vessel into place in a Kentucky pasture.
The future tourist attraction is called Ark Encounter  centered around a 510-foot-long ark, which the builder, a Christian ministry called "Answers in Genesis," says "will be the largest timber-frame structure in the world" when it's completed next summer.
Builders are betting big that millions of visitors will flood the Williamstown, Kentucky, attraction. Ken Ham, president of Answers in Genesis, told WLWT he expects up to about 2 million visitors per year.
advertisement
"I believe it will be one of the biggest attractions outside of Disney, Universal, people like that  it's going to be one of the biggest attractions in this country."
Ham said the ark, which is being built according to dimensions provided in the Bible for the vessel that survived the worldwide flood, will house three stories of exhibits, while the fourth floor is planned to be a restaurant.
According to the project's website, "additional future phases for the attraction include a Walled City, the Tower of Babel, a first-century Middle Eastern village, a journey in history from Abraham to the parting of the Red Sea, a walk-through aviary, an expanded large petting zoo, and so on."
A wooden rib that is part of a ship based on the story of Noahs ark is raised into place in Williamstown, Ky., on Thursday, June 25, 2015. The Ark Encounter will be a religious tourist attraction when it opens next year. Dylan Lovan / AP
But  not unlike the ark in the Bible  this structure has attracted its own share of criticism. Last year, the state of Kentucky withdrew its offer of tax breaks for the attraction.
advertisement
"State tourism tax incentives cannot be used to fund religious indoctrination or otherwise be used to advance religion," Kentucky Tourism Secretary Bob Stewart wrote in a letter in December .
And Bill Nye "The Science Guy," who debated Ham about creationism last year, has argued the project would hurt science education.
Answers in Genesis sued Kentucky tourism officials in February, claiming the decision to deny the tax breaks violated the group's First Amendment rights. That suit is still pending, but the construction is moving forward, as organizes plan to open the attraction next summer.
Becky Bratu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cleveland Vigil Marks Tamir Rice's 13th Birthday</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795e731/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cvigil0Emarks0E13th0Ebirthday0Eslain0Ecleveland0Eboy0Etamir0Erice0En3820A96/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A candlelight vigil Thursday remembered the Ohio boy shot to death by police, on what would have been his 13th birthday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 25 2015, 9:42 pm ET
Vigil Marks 13th Birthday of Slain Cleveland Boy Tamir Rice
by M. Alex Johnson
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_tamir_rice_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A candlelight vigil was under way in Cleveland to remember Tamir Rice, the unarmed African-American boy shot to death by police last year, on what would have been his 13th birthday.
The vigil was held at Cudell Recreation Center, where Cleveland police Officer Timothy Loehmann killed Tamir on Nov. 22. Loehmann and his partner were responding to a report of a man with a gun, but Tamir had only a toy pellet gun.
"It's been eight months," Tamir's mother, Samira Rice, said in a statement . "While I am crushed, and I struggle daily with the loss of my son, I will not rest until those men who were responsible for taking my son's life are prosecuted."
advertisement
Cuyahoga County Prosecutor Timothy McGinty told reporters Wednesday that he expects to complete his investigation in "a matter of months."
Remember y'all, #TamirRice birthday is today. Find a way to honor his legacy, as today is birthday #13 #RestInPower pic.twitter.com/susVf605Uf
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Week in Pictures</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4796acea/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cweek0Ein0Epictures0Cweek0Epictures0Ejune0E180E250En382176/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tragedy strikes an historic church, mermaids parade through New York, lives saved at sea, and more.</Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
1. Rev. Norvel Goff prays at the empty seat of the Rev. Clementa Pinckney at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church four days after a mass shooting that claimed the lives of Pinckney and eight others on June 21 in Charleston, S.C. David Goldman / Pool via AP
2. Gary and Aurelia Washington, center left and right, the son and granddaughter of Ethel Lance, who died in a mass shooting earlier in the week, leave a sidewalk memorial in front of Emanuel AME Church comforted by fellow family members on June 18 in Charleston, S.C. Dylann Storm Roof was arrested in the slayings of nine people, including the pastor at a prayer meeting inside the historic church. David Goldman / AP
3. A Buddhist novice prays at a monastery affiliated with the MaBaTha organization on the outskirts of Yangon. The MaBaTha organization promotes hardline Buddhist nationalism in Myanmar. Christophe Archambault / AFP - Getty Images
advertisement
4. Flood water reflects damaged homes in Coal City, Illinois, a community of about 5,000 residents 60 miles southwest of Chicago, where the National Weather Service confirmed that a twister touched down on June 23.  A storm system flattened homes across the Midwest and slammed the Northeast on June 22 with heavy rain and strong winds, knocking out power for hundreds of thousands, snarling transportation and overturning semi-trucks on interstates. Jon Durr / Getty Images
5. Muslims attend Friday prayers during the second day of Ramadan, in the courtyard of a housing estate next to the small BBC community center and mosque in east London on June 19. Stefan Wermuth / Reuters
6. A stall holder covers over a carousel at the end of the day at The Hoppings fun fair, believed to be one of the largest travelling fairs in Europe, on its opening day in Newcastle upon Tyne, North East England on June 19. Oli Scarff / AFP - Getty Images
advertisement
7. Participants dance on Surf Avenue during the 33rd annual Mermaid Parade in New York's Coney Island on June 20. The parade began in 1983 and takes place on the Saturday closest to the first day of summer. Justin Lane / EPA
8. A man carries a box into the only shop open on an Athens street on June 25. Desperate Greeks expressed fears for their future Friday as more than $1.1 billion was withdrawn from banks in a single day, pushing the country closer towards a default. Daniel Ochoa De Olza / AP
9. Palestinians, not permitted by Israeli security forces to cross into Jerusalem from the West Bank due to an age limit, climb over a section of the controversial Israeli barrier as they try to make their way to attend the first Friday prayer of Ramadan in Jerusalem's al-Aqsa mosque, in the village of Al-Ram, near Ramallah on June 19. Mohamad Torokman / Reuters
advertisement
10. Dylann Roof appears via video before a judge in Charleston, S.C., on June 19. The 21-year-old accused of killing nine people inside he historic Mother Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church made his first court appearance, with the relatives of all the victims making tearful statements. Centralized Bond Hearing Court, of Charleston, S.C. via AP
11. Ash from Mount Sinabung volcano fills the sky over an abandoned church during another eruption in Karo, in Indonesia's North Sumatra province on June 19. Sinabung rumbled back to life in 2013 after a period of inactivity, since then around 10,000 people have had to evacuate their homes. Sutanta Aditya / AFP - Getty Images
12. Migrants sit on the deck of the Belgian Navy vessel Godetia after they were saved during a search and rescue mission in the Mediterranean Sea off the Libyan coasts on June 24. Hundreds of migrants were rescued by the Godetia, which is part of a fleet taking part in the Triton migrants rescue operation. Gregorio Borgia / AP
advertisement
13. A rider and his horse rear during the traditional Saint John festival in Ciutadella, on the Balearic Island of Minorca, Spain on June 24. During the festival, race horses gallop and prance on their hind legs through the streets to honor of the town's patron saint. As the "caixers" (horse riders) ride together in a parade, spectators attempt to pat the horses' chests to get good luck. Jaime Reina / AFP - Getty Images
14. The Crew onboard Australia's HMAS Canberra stand at attention as they honor the countrys oldest naval ship, the HMAS Tobruk (not pictured) as she arrives at Garden Island following a final voyage to Sydney on June 25. Tobruk, Australia's longest serving naval ship has been in service for 35 years and has sailed almost a million nautical miles around the world. Dean Lewins / EPA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:23:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Snooze-Deprived Couples Rest Easy After 'Sleep Divorce'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795b59d/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Csleep0Edivorce0En3820A46/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's estimated one in every four couples sleeps separately at night — twice as many as fifteen years ago, according to the Better Sleep Council and National Sleep Foundation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_hja_sleep_divorce_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Jack Mazewski snores so loudly that his children sleeping down the hall can hear it. The noise didn't bother his wife, Joanna, for the first few years of their marriage  until their kids were born.
"I became a light sleeper because you have a little more stress - two children, a mortgage, bills," said Joanna Mazewski.
Night after night, her husband's snoring kept her awake.
advertisement
"She would poke me a few times," Jack said. His wife quickly corrected him: "I would say kick, not poke."
"I would end up waking him up in the middle of the night," Joanna added. "And then two of us weren't sleeping."
It made mornings a nightmare for the otherwise happily-married couple.
"The arguing would happen when we're not sleeping well," said Joanna.
Jack and Joanna Mazewski Hallie Jackson / NBC News
advertisement
At the end of their rope, the Mazewskis finally found a solution, just like an increasing number of couples in the United States: separate beds.
It's estimated one in every four couples sleeps separately at night  twice as many as fifteen years ago, according to the Better Sleep Council and National Sleep Foundation. It's a phenomenon often called "sleep divorce."
"For some couples, it actually works," said Dr. Wendy Troxel, "particularly if they're both getting a better night of sleep and they're able to function better in the relationship during the day."
Many people prefer the comfort of sleeping next to a spouse, but Troxel  a behavioral and social scientist at the RAND Corporation, pointed to studies showing couples actually sleep worse together.
"This could be sort of a phenomenon of basic physics," she explained. "You have another person in bed with you, so there's more likelihood of more movement and that can be disruptive of sleep."
advertisement
Sleep deprivation can be a serious problem in romantic relationships.
"In a sleep deprived couple, they are more likely to engage in conflict and less likely to be able to resolve it effectively," said Troxel. Plus, a University of California-Berkeley study showed who slept poorly experienced less appreciation for their partners than people who got enough sleep.
For an increasing number of couples, "sleep divorce" is the clear solution - although it sometimes carries a stigma.
"We don't say anything because people think, 'oh, there's probably trouble in their marriage,'" said Joanna Mazewski. "But the fact of the matter is, we try to sleep in different beds so we avoid that trouble!"
Sleep experts recommend a few key tips for sleeping apart - and staying happy:
advertisement
Talk about it first. Pre-planning separate sleeping arrangements ensures one partner doesn't feel ditched when the other leaves the bedroom.
Schedule "together time" in the evenings. "That time before falling asleep is often the only time that couples have together to be away from these distractions," said Troxel. Creating space for intimacy doesn't have to mean just sex: cuddling and talking can help couples stay connected before they head to separate sleeping locations.
If snoring is the problem, schedule a doctor's visit. It can be a sign of a more serious sleep disorder, like sleep apnea.
For the Mazewskis, sleeping separately at night helps them feel better in the morning: "If it doesn't work out for one person or the other," Joanna asked, "why suffer through it?"
Hallie Jackson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:47:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State Department: 15 Emails Missing From Clinton Cache</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47955b7c/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0Cpolitics0Enews0Cstate0Edepartment0E150Eemails0Emissing0Ehillary0Eclinton0Ecache0En382151/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A report issued late Thursday says that all or part of 15 emails sent or received from Clinton's private server were missing from records turned over.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=mtp_daleyemail_150614" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
advertisement
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Clinton's responses are brief. In one from August 2011, she tells Blumenthal she will be in Paris the next day to meet rebel leaders and says she had "to resort to new iPad" because she didn't have electricity or Blackberry coverage after Hurricane Irene.
In another from March 2012, she passes on an adviser's skepticism regarding one of Blumenthal's reports about political intrigue in post-Gadhafi Libya, saying: "This strain credulity based on what I know. Any other info about it?"
And after a long August 2012 note from Blumenthal about Libya's new interim President Mohamed Yousef el-Magariaf, Clinton writes: "Another keeper  thanks and please keep 'em coming." Four days later, she responds to a follow-up reports about el-Magariaf, saying: "Fascinating. I had a very good call w him."
advertisement
Clinton's critics are likely to focus less on the substance of the emails than on the fact that they weren't shared with the State Department.
Gowdy, a South Carolina Republican, has pressed for an explanation of why Blumenthal gave the committee emails not previously shared by the State Department. The suggestion has been that either the department or Clinton was hiding something.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:23:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NBA Draft Tracker: Follow the Picks as They Unfold</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4794bfa9/sc/13/l/0L0Srotoworld0N0Carticles0Cnba0C548490C4750C20A150Enba0Edraft0Etracker0Dcid0Feref0Rnbcnews0Rtext/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Follow the NBA Draft as it unfolds on Thursday in Brooklyn, New York.</Description>
        <MainBody>31. Cleveland Cavaliers (from Minnesota Timberwolves) - Cedi Osman , SG/SF, Anadolu Efes
32. Houston Rockets (from New York Knicks) - Montrezl Harrell , PF, Louisville
33. Boston Celtics (from Philadelphia 76ers via Miami Heat) - Jordan Mickey , PF, LSU
34. Los Angeles Lakers - Anthony Brown , SF, Stanford
35. New York Knicks (from Philadelphia 76ers via Orlando Magic) - Guillermo Hernangomez , C, Baloncesto Sevilla (Spain)
36. Cleveland Cavaliers (from Minnesota Timberwolves via Sacramento Kings and Houston Rockets) - Rakeem Christmas , PF, Syracuse
37. Philadelphia 76ers (from Denver Nuggets, via Houston Rockets, Portland Trail Blazers and Minnesota Timberwolves) - Richaun Holmes , PF, Bowling Green
38. Detroit Pistons - Darrun Hilliard , SG, Villanova
39. Brooklyn Nets (from Charlotte Hornets) - Juan Vaulet , SF, Estudiantes Bahia Blanca (Argentina)
40. Miami Heat - Josh Richardson , SG, Tennessee
41. Portland Trail Blazers (from Brooklyn Nets) - Pat Connaughton , SG, Notre Dame
42. Utah Jazz - Olivier Hanlan , PG/SG, Boston College
43. Indiana Pacers - Joseph Young , SG/PG, Oregon
44. Phoenix Suns - Andrew Harrison , PG, Kentucky
45. Boston Celtics - Marcus Thornton , PG, William &amp; Mary
46. Toronto Raptors (from Milwaukee Bucks) - Norman Powell , SG, UCLA
47. Philadelphia 76ers (from New Orleans Pelicans via Washington Wizards and Los Angeles Clippers) - Arturas Gudaitis , C, Zalgiris Kaunas (Lithuania)
48. Oklahoma City Thunder - Dakari Johnson , C, Kentucky
49. Washington Wizards - Aaron White , PF, Iowa
50. Atlanta Hawks (from Toronto Raptors) - Marcus Eriksson , SG, FC Barcelona (Spain)
51. Orlando Magic (from Chicago Bulls) - Tyler Harvey , SG, Eastern Washington
52. Dallas Mavericks - Satnam Singh Bhamara , C, IMG Academy
53. Cleveland Cavaliers (From Portland Trail Blazers via Chicago Bulls and Denver Nuggets) - Sir'Dominic Pointer , SF, St. John's
54. Portland Trail Blazers (from Utah Jazz via Cleveland Cavaliers) - Daniel Diez , PF, San Sebastian (Spain)
55. San Antonio Spurs - Cady Lalanne , PF, Massachusetts
56. New Orleans Pelicans (from Memphis Grizzlies) - Branden Dawson , PF, Michigan State
57. Denver Nuggets (from Los Angeles Clippers) - Nikola Radicevic , PG, Baloncesto Sevilla (Spain)
58. Philadelphia 76ers (from Houston Rockets) - J.P. Tokoto , SG, North Carolina
59. Atlanta Hawks - Dimitrios Agravanis , PF, Olympiacos (Greece)
60. Philadelphia 76ers (from Golden State Warriors via Indiana Pacers) - Luka Mitrovic , PF, Red Star (Serbia)

Trades:
Brooklyn acquired the No. 23 pick (Rondae-Hollis-Jefferson) and G Steve Blake from Portland for the No. 41 pick (Pat Connaughton) and C Mason Plumlee .
Toronto acquired the No. 46 pick (Norman Powell) and a 2017 first-round pick from Milwaukee for PG Greivis Vasquez .
Brooklyn acquired the No. 39 pick (Juan Valet) from Charlotte for two future draft picks.
New York acquired the No. 35 pick (Guillermo Hernangomez) from Philadelphia for two future draft picks.
Portland acquired the No. 54 pick (Daniel Diez) from Utah for a future second-round pick.
Complete results from the 2015 NBA Draft are posted below. Scroll down to see the details of each in-draft trade. Click on each players name for full pick analysis.

For instant analysis on every player picked, refresh Rotoworld's NBA Player News page .

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:00:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Third Time's the Charm? SpaceX to Try to Land Rocket</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a34052/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cscience0Cspace0Cwatch0Espacex0Elaunch0Enasa0Ecargo0Etry0Eland0Efalcon0E90Erocket0En383166/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>After two oh-so-close attempts to land a rocket stage on a seagoing platform, SpaceX will try, try again during Sunday's launch of a Falcon 9 rocket.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 10:00 am ET
Watch SpaceX Launch NASA Cargo and Again Try to Land Falcon 9 Rocket
by Alan Boyle
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nbcnewslive_nyc1" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Will the third time be the charm? After two oh-so-close attempts to land a rocket stage on a seagoing platform, SpaceX will try, try again during Sunday's launch of a Falcon 9 rocket.
The primary objective of the mission , due for takeoff from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Florida at 10:21 a.m. ET, is to deliver a robotic Dragon capsule with more than two and a half tons of supplies, equipment and experiments  ranging from a new docking adapter for accommodating future U.S.-built spaceships to a virtual-reality headset for the space station's crew.
This will be the first robotic cargo delivery since a Russian Progress capsule went awry in April , resulting in the loss of the craft's 3-ton payload. The Dragon's payload includes food, oxygen and other much-needed basics  and that's putting extra pressure on SpaceX for a successful launch.
SpaceX's vice president of mission assurance, Hans Koenigsmann, told reporters on Friday that his company was up to the job. "Dragon has been super-reliable," he told reporters.
No technical problems were reported as the two-stage Falcon 9 rocket was fueled up, and the chances of acceptable weather were set at 90 percent. You can watch launch coverage on webcasts that are being streamed by NASA and SpaceX .
advertisement
The Dragon already has made six successful cargo runs under the terms of a $1.6 billion contract with NASA, plus an initial demonstration mission in 2012. But this time, SpaceX is hoping to pull off a trick that's never been done before: the safe landing of the Falcon's first stage on a drone ship stationed hundreds of miles out in the Atlantic.
The first stage's autonomous landing maneuver is due to unfold minutes after launch, while the second stage continues its rise to orbit with the Dragon capsule.
A completely successful landing at sea would mark a milestone in rocket reusability. SpaceX's billionaire founder, Elon Musk, says the technology would dramatically drive down launch costs and potentially pave the way for affordable trips to Mars.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:51:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armed Cops, Memorials Dot Bloodstained Beach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a43c27/sc/40/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cisis0Eterror0Ctunisia0Esteps0Esecurity0Esousse0Emourns0Eisis0Eattack0Evictims0En383271/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Makeshift memorials dotted this seaside resort town on Sunday as Tunisian officials deployed hundreds of extra police to guard tourist sites.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 9:51 am ET
Tunisia Steps Up Security as Sousse Mourns ISIS Attack Victims
by Chapman Bell, Kelly Cobiella and Charlene Gubash
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_kco_international_terror_150627" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
SOUSSE, Tunisia  Makeshift memorials dotted this seaside resort town on Sunday as Tunisian officials deployed hundreds of extra police to guard tourist sites following a massacre on the north African nation's beach.
At least 39 people  mostly British, German and Belgian vacationers  were killed when a gunman disguised as a tourist opened fire on beachgoers in Sousse on Friday.
Flowers and candles dotted the beach on Sunday, where two days earlier sun loungers were turned into makeshift stretchers for the wounded in the attack for which ISIS claimed responsibility.
advertisement
"We will never forget you," read one handwritten message placed in the sand, as armed police patrolled the beach on ATVs and boats offshore waved Tunisian flags.
Crowds gathered in front of the Imperial Marhaba Hotel  the site of the attack  chanting "with heart and blood we sacrifice for our flag." Below their feet, the sand was still bloodied.
As the community reeled, the imam of Sousse's second-largest mosque stressed how the attack ran counter to Islamic principles.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_tunisiaattack_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
"Islam is a religion of peace and these terrorists are destroying its image," the young imam, Juma Yassin Kidary, told NBC News ahead of the special Ramadan prayer.
Tunisia's Interior Minister Mohamed Najem Gharsalli said 1,000 extra police were being deployed at tourist sites and beaches in the North African nation.
"We don't want to make tourist establishments into barracks, that's not our goal. But we must act to guarantee the security of the tourist sector," he said late Saturday, according to The Associated Press.
Tunisia's tourism industry  already grappling with fallout from the deadly terror attack in March at the National Bardo Museum in Tunis  suffered a further blow from Friday's violence .
Sousse's tourism commissioner Saloua Kadri told Reuters that more than 3,000 foreigners had fled the town on Saturday  and many more were awaiting flights out.
advertisement
"We don't feel safe," Briton Sarah Maeson told Reuters at Ennfida airport.
Mahdin Zidani, 40, was on the beach when the attacker opened fire. He said he plans to see a therapist to help cope with the trauma of that day, but was certain he and his nation would heal.
"It is an accident, it can happen in any country, it happened in France and Kuwait," he told NBC News. "We will not give up, we will continue working and everything will come back to normal."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:57:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Boy Scout Dies in Flash Flood at Campsite</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a45ac6/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cboy0Escout0Edies0Eflash0Eflood0Enew0Emexicos0Ephilmont0Escout0Eranch0En383261/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The scouts were part of a group on a 12-day trek across Philmont Scout Ranch when a flash flood swept through their campsite.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 8:57 am ET
Boy Scout Dies in Flash Flood at New Mexico's Philmont Scout Ranch
by Cassandra Vinograd and Jacquellena Carrero
Share
advertisement
A young Boy Scout died when a flash flood swept through his campground in northern New Mexico, according to officials.
The victim was part of a group of scouts on a 12-day trek across Philmont Scout Ranch when a flash flood swept through their campsite before dawn on Saturday, according to NBC affiliate station KOB . Four boys were swept away but three were located immediately, KOB reported.
Philmont Scout Ranch  which has 214 square miles of wilderness  said its staff had "immediately" contacted crews and trekkers in the backcountry to check on safety and offer help after "significant" rainfall caused flooding in some areas of its property.
"During that process, our staff was unable to account for one youth participant, who we have since confirmed passed away," the ranch said in a statement offering thoughts and prayers to the affected family .
"All other participants have been accounted for and there are no additional injuries," it added.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pride parade made more significant after Supreme Court ruling</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a47198/sc/7/l/0L0Stoday0N0Cvideo0Cpride0Eparade0Emade0Emore0Esignificant0Eafter0Esupreme0Ecourt0Eruling0E472538179630A/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NBC's Frances Rivera visits New York's famed Stonewall Inn, moments before the parade kicked off. The Inn, now an official city landmark, was the scene of the historic Stonewall Riots 46 years ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>June 28th, 2015
Pride parade made more significant after Supreme Court ruling
NBC's Frances Rivera visits New York's famed Stonewall Inn, moments before the parade kicked off. The Inn, now an official city landmark, was the scene of the historic Stonewall Riots 46 years ago.
More video
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:14:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crunch Time in Iran's Nuclear Talks: Where Things Stand</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a30cc7/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0Ciran0Enuclear0Etalks0Ecrunch0Etime0Earrives0Eu0Es0Ep50E10En382286/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>After years of marathon negotiations, crunch time has finally arrived for Iran's nuclear talks with the United States and five other world powers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=a_shorttake_arouzi_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
TEHRAN  After years of marathon negotiations and several missed deadlines, crunch time has finally arrived for Iran's nuclear talks with the United States and five other world powers.
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry met Sunday in Vienna with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif, their third encounter since Saturday.
As gaps remained between all sides in the talks, Zarif planned to return to Tehran for 24 hours for consultations with Iran's leadership ahead of the June 30 deadline for a deal.
An enormous amount of ground already has been covered between Tehran and Washington , old foes who once referred to each other as "The Great Satan" and a member of "The Axis of Evil," respectively.
But despite this progress, there are still red lines to overcome before a deal can be struck.
America, Britain, Russia, France, China and Germany  known collectively as the P5+1 powers  want to ensure Iran cannot produce a nuclear weapon. They are asking for thorough inspections and written guarantees, resulting in harsh consequences if Iran does not hold up its side of the bargain.
In return, Iran wants an immediate end to the economic sanctions it says have crippled its economy. It also wants to rejoin the international community and lose its image as a global pariah.
In order to do this, however, Iran needs to prove its claim that its nuclear program is for energy alone and devoid of any military aspirations.
advertisement
Powerful elements on both sides remain deeply skeptical. Senior figures in Congress have warned they could trip up any pact that does not retain the power to carry out spot checks on Iranian facilities, or an agreement that lifts economic sanctions before Tehran begins to comply fully with its terms.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:05:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait ID's Mosque Bomber as Saudi Man, Detains Driver</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a38f85/sc/40/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cisis0Eterror0Ckuwait0Eids0Emosque0Ebomber0Esaudi0Enamed0Efahd0Esuliman0Eabdul0Emuhsen0En383256/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Kuwait on Sunday identified a suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst militant attack as a Saudi citizen</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_cob_terror_attacks_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
KUWAIT  Kuwait on Sunday identified a suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst militant attack as a Saudi citizen and said it had detained the driver of the vehicle that took him to a Shi'ite Muslim mosque where he killed 27 people.
The interior ministry named the bomber as Fahd Suliman Abdul-Muhsen al-Qabaa and said he flew into Kuwait's airport at dawn on Friday, only hours before he detonated explosives at Kuwait City's Imam al-Sadeq mosque.
ISIS claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing at the mosque, where 2,000 worshipers were praying at the time. It was one of three attacks on three continents that day apparently linked to hardline Islamists.
advertisement
"The interior ministry will continue its efforts to uncover the circumstances of this explosion," interior ministry spokesman Adel Hashash told Kuwait state television.
The ministry said the driver of the Japanese-made car, who left the mosque immediately after Friday's bombing, was an illegal resident named Abdul-Rahman Sabah Aidan.
The interior ministry, which had earlier reported the vehicle owner's arrest, said Aidan, 26, was found hiding in one of the houses in al-Riqqa residential area.
"Initial investigations showed that the owner of the house is a supporter of the deviant ideology," the ministry said, employing a term often used by authorities in the Gulf Arab region to refer to hardline Islamist militants. The owner of the house, a Kuwaiti citizen, was also detained, the ministry said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:21:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Slain Escapee's Ex-Accomplice: 'Nightmare' Is Finally Over</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a3e34f/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cnew0Eyork0Eprison0Eescape0Crichard0Ematts0Eformer0Eaccomplice0Ecalls0Ekiller0Epure0Eevil0En383241/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Lee Bates, who pleaded guilty and was imprisoned for his role in a 1997 murder carried out by Matt, described Matt as "the devil."</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_matt_accomp_150628" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
The former accomplice of slain escaped murderer Richard Matt told NBC News he is relieved that the "nightmare" is finally over.
Matt, 49, was fatally shot Friday by a U.S. Customs and Border Protection tactical team after three weeks on the run. Matt's fellow escapee, David Sweat, is still on the loose .
Lee Bates, who was convicted and served time for his role in a 1997 murder carried out by Matt, told NBC News that the he had "never met or seen anybody so vicious, so cruel and dangerous" in his life.
RELATED: A 'Desperate' David Sweat Poses Greater Threat After Death of Richard Matt
"If you really wanted to know what the devil looked like, take a picture of Richard Matt, look at a picture of Richard Matt," Bates told NBC News on Saturday. "That was the devil."
Bates, 38, testified against the Matt at his murder trial, describing how Matt had beaten, bound and eventually killed the boss who fired him. He was paroled in August, and told NBC News it had been "extremely difficult" living in Matt's shadow since then  even more so since Matt and Sweat used power tools to make a daring escape from New York's Clinton Correctional Facility on June 6.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:23:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teen Bitten by Shark in Second N.C. Attack in Two Days</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a20143/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ctwo0Epeople0Ebitten0Esharks0Etwo0Edays0Esame0Estretch0Enorth0Ecarolina0En383156/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A 17-year-old boy suffered injuries believed to have been caused by a shark Saturday, in an incident 14 miles away from another apparent attack.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 5:23 am ET
Teen Bitten by Shark on North Carolina Beach Near Scene of Earlier Attack
by Elisha Fieldstadt
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_shark_attack_150628" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A 17-year-old boy is in critical condition after he was apparently attacked by a shark in the ocean off North Carolina's Outer Banks Saturday, just 14 miles from the site of another suspected shark attack a day earlier, officials said.
The teen was swimming at a beach on the Cape Hatteras National Seashore near Waves at about 4 p.m. when he was apparently bitten by a shark and injured on his calf, buttocks and both hands, according to a statement from the National Park Service.
The victim was airlifted to Norfolk, Virginia. A spokesperson for Sentara Norfolk General Hospital said he is in critical condition.
advertisement
The 17-year-old was swimming with friends in about three feet of water about 20 feet offshore when the shark attack occurred, NBC affiliate WITN reported. He was the only person injured.
Shark attack took place at the beach at the KOA in Rodanthe, NC. First day of vacation...no beach for us this week. pic.twitter.com/9e6aVnoOpj
 David Marko (@DavidMarko1) June 27, 2015
On Friday, a 47-year-old man suffered injuries to his right leg and lower back believed to have been caused by a shark just 14 miles down the Cape Hatteras National Seashore, according to the National Park Service .
The last shark encounter at the Cape Hatteras National Seashore, before the two this weekend, was in 2011, the Park Service said. NBC affiliate WITN reported that there were seven reports of people being attacked by sharks off the Carolina coast in the past two weeks.
Last week, two teens lost arms after separate shark attacks in Oak Island , North Carolina, which is nearly 300 miles from the Cape Hatteras National Seashore.
Elisha Fieldstadt
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:05:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As U.S. Draws Back, Afghan Women's Future In Doubt</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a35dba/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cafghanistans0Ewomen0Efuture0Ethreatened0Eviolence0Econservatism0En377631/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Conservative forces are joining unabated poverty and growing violence to undermine huge gains women and girls have made since the U.S.-led invasion.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_afghan_150323" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Women's mortality rates are much higher than men's, even when factoring in male combatants who are fighting and dying on the battlefield, according to the United Nations.
Related: 'We Don't Eat, We Don't Sleep, We Cry': Farkhunda's Dad
In fact, the U.N. calls the rates of violence against women in Afghanistan "exceptionally high" with up to 87.2 per cent of women having experienced some form of violence.
The situation is getting worse, according to activists. There has been a 31 percent rise in the cases of violence against women so far this year compared to 2014, according to Soraya Sobhrang, deputy chair of Afghanistan's Independent Human Rights Commission.
"This is a worrisome development that should be addressed  all the gains women made could be lost," she said.
While President Ashraf Ghani is broadly believed to be a supporter of women's rights, critics say he is hamstrung by the presence of powerful figures who are hostile to them. A stark example of this is how conservative forces have blocked the Elimination of Violence Against Women (EVAW) law, which criminalized and set prison sentences for rape, domestic violence, and underage and forced marriage, among other things.
Former President Hamid Karzai passed the law in 2009 but it never got through the lower house of parliament, the Wolesi Jirga, where some parliamentarians said it ran counter to Islam and could tear apart Afghan society.
Related: Will Afghan Leader Ashraf Ghani Bow to Pressure to Hide His Wife?
Qazi Nazeer Ahmad Hanafi is one of the most prominent voices against the EVAW and has been especially rankled by the provision in the law to create women's shelters for victims of domestic violence. According to Hanafi, a parliamentarian from western Herat province, these shelters were actually "brothels" and could prompt a "revolution" that could kill millions.
The conservative forces resisting the full inclusion of women into society extend beyond Hanafi.
Afghanistan's Ulama Council  the highest religious authority in the country  recently fought to block the appointment of a woman to the Supreme Court.
"Life in general is very challenging and involves a lot of risk ... I have been the target of assassination attempts."
While a female judge, Anisa Rassoli, has been nominated by Ghani to the chamber on Tuesday, the council's spokesman Ataullah Ludin said the move ran against Sharia law. This will likely strengthen the position of many conservatives in parliament who are looking to prevent her from taking her post.
The council has also been quiet on the need to defend women, according to Fawzia Koofi , a prominent lawmaker and the head of the parliamentary committee on women's affairs and rights.
"They have been ineffective and silent about violence against women," she said. "They didn't even condemn the brutal murder of Farkhunda."
Familiar path to pain
Many women and rights activists say their fear isn't only that the Taliban will return to power in some form. They're also afraid the country is going down the same road that led to the 1992-1996 civil war which swept the fundamentalist fighters into power.
In this Monday, March 17, 2014 photo, Afghan lawmaker Fawzia Koofi from Kabul poses next to the picture wall showing Afghanistans 249 parliamentarians in the parliament in Kabul, Afghanistan. Anja Niedringhaus / AP
Now women who dare speak out, or even step outside their homes without the burqa, say they increasingly risk abuse  or worse.
Like other women in public life that NBC News interviewed, such as politicians, teachers and activists, Koofi said she felt her life was in danger.
WATCH: For Afghan Women, Home Isn't Where the Heart Is
"Life in general is very challenging and involves a lot of risk, but it's much harder to be a woman in the public sphere," Koofi said. "I have been the target of assassination attempts. [Recently] a well-placed security source told me that a suicide bomber came very close to target my vehicle in central Kabul, but lost me in the traffic."
And it isn't just legislators and activists who feel vulnerable.
Rangina Hamidi, who owns Kandahar Treasure  a successful business selling traditional Afghan pottery and textiles made by women  says she constantly worries about the future.
Hamidi is proud of her company, which employs around 400 women who mostly work from home including many secretly, in the heart of Kandahar, the Taliban's birthplace. The business has recently been hurt by the withdrawal of thousands of foreign troops, whom the company used to sell to.
"For a place like Kandahar, which is only known for war and destruction, it is a success for a group of women to generate over $300,000," Hamidi said. "The gains are certainly under threat of a civil war, should there not be peace."
Just 15 years ago, the Taliban imposed its strict interpretation of Islam combined with profoundly conservative tribal codes onto the Afghan people. Men and women were strictly segregated, the vast majority of the country's girls' schools were shuttered, women were barred from leaving their homes without an all-enveloping burka and a male chaperon. Those who broke the rules were beaten or executed.
The Taliban's rule, and the chaos that preceded it, are constantly on Hamidi's mind. As are the economic realities of Afghanistan, with foreign troops leaving and insecurity making it even harder for women as well as businesses like hers.
"We obviously fear that everything we have gained, not only as an entity here but as a country as a whole [will be reversed]. As women that fear is definitely in our minds," she said.
"My biggest fear is to tell all these women that we will not be able to support them any longer," Hamidi added.
Fazul Rahim
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:47:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Four People Shot Outside Connecticut Elementary School</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a36303/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcconnecticut0N0Cnews0Clocal0CAt0ELeast0ETwo0EPeople0EShot0Eat0EHartford0EElementary0ESchool0E310A3449210Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Hartford police received multiple 911 calls at about 4:30 p.m. about multiple shots fired near the Sarah J. Rawson Elementary School.</Description>
        <MainBody>Privacy Policy | More Newsletters
NBCConnecticut.com
Hartford police are investigating a shooting involving at least two victims at an elementary school in the capital city.
Updated 44 minutes ago
Police arrested one of four people shot during a basketball tournament outside a Hartford elementary school in a shooting that left one person dead and three injured Saturday afternoon.
Hartford police arrested Roosevelt Holmes, 23, of Windsor, Sunday morning in  connection with the shooting. Holmes was also injured, suffering a gunshot wound to  the leg. Police said that he may have shot himself but they are looking  into whether there is a second shooter.
Colorado Woman Finds 8.52 Carat Diamond at Arkansas State Park
Hartford police received 911 calls at about 4:30 p.m. Saturday reporting multiple shots fired and several victims at a city park adjacent to the Sarah J. Rawson Elementary School at 260 Holcomb Street.
James Headen, 41, of Hartford, was shot in the head. An ambulance transported him to St. Francis Hospital where he was later was pronounced dead.
The other three people shot, including Holmes, have non-life-threatening wounds to the hand, hip and leg, respectively. They were taken to the hospital in private vehicles.
Police say a weapon was located in one of the vehicles at the hospital.
Hartford police are conducting ballistics tests, though they say that there is no evidence as of right now that there is a second shooter.
Police are reviewing evidence and are working to obtain video surveillance from the school.
Bear Scares 'Living Daylights' Out of Pa. Partygoers
Hartford major crimes detectives and a shooting task force responded. The crime scene division is also investigating.
Police were unaware that the basketball tournament was taking place and said that typically the department likes to be made aware of events that size.
Updated 2 Arrested For Removing S.C. Confederate Flag
Hartford Mayor Pedro Segarra expressed outrage at the incident.
"I am not going to allow our children, our community to be threatened in this way," he said.
At Least 1 Injured in NYC High-Rise Fire
According to police, there were over 100 witnesses at the scene at the time of the shooting. Police ask anyone with information to call Hartford police, particularly if anyone has cellphone or camera video footage taken at the time of the shooting.
The incident does not appear to be targeted, police said.
NYC Teen With Cerebral Palsy Earns Valedictorian
Holmes was charged with criminal  possession of a firearm, assault, reckless endangerment and unlawful  discharge of a firearm. Police are holidng him in custody on a $1-million bond. Further charges  against Homes are possible pending lab results. Police also said that  others maybe charged in the investigation.
Published at 5:01 PM EDT on Jun 27, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:25:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bear Scares 'Living Daylights' Out of Lehigh Partiers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a2f202/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcphiladelphia0N0Cnews0Cweird0CBlack0EBear0ELehigh0EParty0E310A3427310Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A Pennsylvania college party got a little wild when a black bear showed up.</Description>
        <MainBody>Black Bear Scares 'Living Daylights' Out of Lehigh University Partygoers
Black bear crashes college party, gets collared
Black Bear Scares 'Living Daylights' Out of...
Link
Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=310395071&amp;videoID=XjkFurAGZMVx&amp;origin=nbcphiladelphia.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=weird&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
Crews in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania tranquilized a black bear after it was spotted by students at a party near Lehigh University. (Published Saturday, Jun 27, 2015)
Updated 5 hours ago
A Pennsylvania college party got a little wild when a black bear showed up.
The black bear, weighing between 300 and 400 pounds, crashed the party early Saturday near the campus of Lehigh University.
Deformed Mutt Crowned World's Ugliest Dog
Emergency officials received a flood of 911 calls after the bear was spotted around 2 a.m. in south Bethlehem, about 50 miles north of Philadelphia.
The bear "lumbered close to the party and scared the living daylights out of people," police Chief Mark DiLuzio said.
Adorable Zoo Babies: Baby Giraffe
Lehigh University said in a "Bear Update" on its website that the animal was captured, tranquilized and removed from the area a couple hours later.
DiLuzio said the same bear was seen Friday near an arena and the university's athletic facilities, but it ran away into a swampy area.
Sharks Attack for 6th Time in 2 Weeks in Carolinas
Tyler Krieder, district officer of the Pennsylvania Game Commission, said a tattoo on the bear's inner lip indicates that it was from New Jersey. Noting that bears are good swimmers, he theorized that the animal swam across the Delaware River to find a new home.
"The bear wasn't any threat to anybody," Krieder told LehighValleyLive.com . "It was just looking for somewhere to eat, take a break."
Probe, Remorse Over El Fare Arrest of Dad Holding Daughter
Encroaching development often prompts bears to leave their ranges, and it's not unusual for them to stray into populated areas on their way to a new home, Kreider said. And while young bears can wander into neighborhoods in the spring as they strike out on their own, adult bears also move around this time of year because it is mating season, he said.
The bear remains in the custody of the game commission and is doing fine, Krieder said. Pennsylvania and New Jersey authorities will discuss on which side of the river the animal will be released, he said.
Published at 4:45 PM EDT on Jun 27, 2015
Copyright Associated Press / NBC 10 Philadelphia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:58:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>More Than 500 Injured in Fire at Water Park</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a288a7/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Ctally0Einjured0Erises0Emore0E50A0A0Eafter0Etaiwan0Ewater0Epark0Efire0En383226/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>More than 180 are in intensive care after colored powder thrown on crowds at a water amusement park caught fire, badly burning revelers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_sanders_waterpark_150628" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
TAIPEI  The number of people injured in a fire at a Taiwan water amusement park rose to 516 on Sunday, government officials said, with more than 180 still in intensive care.
Media reported four mainland Chinese and two foreigners were among those injured after Saturday's fire, during a party where up to 1,000 revelers were sprayed with colored powder as they danced to music, seeking to escape the summer heat.
The blaze, which broke out around 8:30 p.m. at the Formosa Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
advertisement
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder explode," he added. Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters, adding that 410 people were still in hospital on Sunday, with 194 being treated for serious injuries.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, wearing wet swimsuits and lying on inflatable plastic doughnuts. Television showed images of people running from sky-high flames.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims of the incident suffered burns to the limbs, with some passing out from the pain while others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and pictures showed.
advertisement
"She is young. A student," sobbed the father of an 18-year-old girl with burns on 80 percent of her body, according to television footage.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
"We are very sorry about what happened and we will investigate the cause to find out who is responsible," Eric Chu, the mayor of New Taipei City, where the park is located, said on Saturday, adding that it had been ordered to shut down.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on its website on Sunday. Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in recent weeks.
A person helps an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015. STRINGER/TAIWAN / Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:45:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CEO Who Boosted Workers' Wages GIves Kids Big Surprise</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a30ccb/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Cstudents0Eget0Esurprise0Evisit0Eceo0Edan0Eprice0Ewho0Etook0Epay0En383116/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Seattle CEO Dan Price showed up to a sixth grade class in Irvine, California, after they wrote him letters.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 2:45 am ET
Students Get Surprise Visit From CEO Dan Price Who Took Pay Cut to Raise Salaries
by Joe Fryer
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_jfr_ceo_surprise_150627" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
When CEO Dan Price raised the minimum wage to $70,000 at his small business in April, the story went viral, and Gravity Payments, a Seattle company that processes credit card payments, became an overnight household name.
Price dropped his salary from about $1 million to $70,000 in order to increase pay for many of his employees.
In the weeks that have followed, Price has received hundreds of messages  some from CEOs who followed suit with similar moves and others from critics who feel the decision will destroy Price's company.
For more on this story, tune into Weekend Nightly News at 6:30 p.m. ET
Of all the notes that he has received, the most striking to Price was a stack of 33 letters  delivered by mail  from a class of sixth graders at Woodbury Elementary School in Irvine, California.
Gravity Payments CEO Dan Price visits a class of sixth graders at Woodbury Elementary School in Irvine, California. NBC News  / NBC News
Among their comments:
advertisement
"I honestly support your idea. Your kind heart will touch the lives of all your employees."
"I know some people might give you some criticism, but my class and I look up to you for all the sacrifices you've made."
Related: Seattle Business Owner Raises His Workers' Minimum Pay to $70,000
For the students, it was a chance to practice writing business letters. But teacher Hilary Dimitruk also saw a deeper lesson.
"This was a great example of all the values we try to instill in our students here," she said.
Gravity Payments CEO Dan Price visits with a group of sixth graders at Woodbury Elementary School in Irvine, California. NBC News / NBC News
The students were anxiously hoping Price would reply with a letter of his own.
The CEO had a better idea. Price showed up in person in their classroom last month, stunning the kids  and their teacher.
For about an hour, Price answered their questions about the business world and the reasons behind his wage hike. At the end, he asked the students to continue sending him notes and even added an incentive.
"If you write one letter every year, I am going to set aside a $1,000 scholarship for every single one of you," Price announced.
The kids and their teacher broke into applause. The exercise started as a lesson in business and resulted in an unexpected bonus.
Joe Fryer
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:20:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Huckabee: SCOTUS Tried to 'Unwrite Laws of Nature'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a288b8/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0C20A160Eelection0Chuckabee0Eother0Egop0Ehopefuls0Eslam0Egay0Emarriage0Eruling0En383111/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The Republican presidential candidate told conservatives that the Supreme Court tried to "unwrite the laws of nature and the laws of nature's God."</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 1:20 am ET
Huckabee, Other GOP Hopefuls Slam Gay Marriage Ruling
by Associated Press
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_welker_obama_150627" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
DENVER  Republican presidential candidate Mike Huckabee told conservatives Saturday that the Supreme Court tried to "unwrite the laws of nature and the laws of nature's God" when it legalized gay marriage across the nation.
The former Arkansas governor suggested that people in the United States flout the ruling, as President Abraham Lincoln did in the wake of the justices' 1857 decision that blacks could not be citizens. Huckabee also pointed out that President Barack Obama opposed gay marriage until 2012.
"He was either lying in 2008, or he's lying now, or God has rewritten the Bible and only Barack Obama has gotten the new edition," Huckabee told the crowd at the Western Conservative Summit.
Related: Suprem e Court Rules Same-Sex Marriage Legal Nationwide
Huckabee was among the GOP presidential hopefuls at the gathering, which followed a week in which the high court also upheld Obama's signature health care law. The Republicans offered few suggestions on what to do about the gay marriage ruling, highlighting the party's challenges on social issues ahead of the 2016 elections.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:21:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One Dead, Eight Rescued After Boat Goes Over Maryland Dam</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a22ca4/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cone0Edead0Eeight0Erescued0Eafter0Eboat0Egoes0Eover0Emaryland0Edam0En383216/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The body of the boat's driver, identified as a 62-year-old man, was recovered after a pontoon boat went over the Linganore Dam Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 28 2015, 12:21 am ET
One Dead, Eight Rescued After Boat Goes Over Maryland Dam
Share
advertisement
One man was killed and eight people were rescued after a pontoon boat with nine aboard was swept over a dam in Maryland, officials said.
The name of the deceased or those rescued was not released. The accident occurred just before 6:30 p.m. on Lake Linganore in Frederick County, west of Baltimore.
"Neighbors heard calls for help and saw people hanging over the dam," Frederick County Fire and Rescue Services Division Capt. Kevin Fox said.
A rescue basket lowered from Maryland State Police helicopter Trooper 3 nears three girls trapped on rocks in the swift current in the spillway of the Lake Linganore dam Saturday evening. Sam Yu / Frederick News Post
Four people hanging from the dam were rescued, three were pulled out of the spillway by a helicopter and another passenger was rescued by a boat, Fox said.
advertisement
Before the boat went over the spillway some aboard jumped overboard, and a few people were found clinging to a tree near the water's edge, Candy Thomson of the Maryland Department of Natural Resources Police Department said.
The cause of the accident was not released. The body of the boat's driver, only identified as a 62-year-old man, was trapped underwater by the force of the falling water but was recovered later Saturday, the Maryland Department of Natural Resources Police said.
It is unclear if weather played any role in the accident, Thomson said. Periods of heavy rain were reported shortly before 2 p.m. at Frederick Municipal Airport, just a few miles west of Lake Linganore, according to the National Weather Service.
Contributor Phil Helsel
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 06:23:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coast Guard Suspends Search for Missing Olympic Sailor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a26194/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ccoast0Eguard0Esuspends0Esearch0Emissing0Eolympic0Esailor0Etrevor0Emoore0En383211/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Moore's 16-foot boat was found with the engine running in a Miami marina Thursday and searchers covered over 510 square nautical miles.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 27 2015, 11:23 pm ET
Coast Guard Suspends Search for Missing Olympic Sailor Trevor Moore
by Phil Helsel
advertisement
The U.S. Coast Guard on Saturday suspended its three-day search for missing Olympic sailor Trevor Moore.
"Our thoughts and prayers go out to the loved ones affected," Coast Guard Capt. Michael Long said in a statement. "Despite the tireless search efforts by multiple agencies and good Samaritans, we were unable to find Mr. Moore."
Trevor Moore is shown in this January 2011 handout photo provided by USA Sailing June 26, 2015.  The search for the member of the 2012 U.S. Olympic sailing team was called off Saturday, the Coast Guard said. HANDOUT / Reuters
Moore, a member of the 2012 U.S. Olympic sailing team, was reported missing Thursday after his 16-foot boat was found in a Miami marina with the engine still running and his possessions on board, but the 30-year-old was nowhere to be seen.
The boat was found at Dinner Key Marina at around 6 p.m. Thursday, the Coast Guard said. The marina is near Biscayne Bay, where the United States Sailing Association said Moore was last seen. Moore was out on the boat alone, US Sailing said.
advertisement
The search was called off as night fell Saturday. The Coast Guard said searchers covered more than 510 square nautical miles during the massive three-day search, which included a Coast Guard helicopter and rescue boat as well as boats from Miami police, the Florida Fish and Wildlife Commission, the National Park Service and members of the public.
"At some point during his journey something must have happened because the boat came back to the marina, was found kind of tied up in some mooring lines without anyone on board," Liz Barraco of the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission told NBC Miami on Friday.
Moore finished 15th in the skiff event at the 2012 London Games.
Phil Helsel
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:26:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shots Fired Near San Francisco Pride</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a218a4/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcbayarea0N0Cnews0Clocal0CPolice0ERespond0Eto0EShots0EFired0EAt0ECivic0ECenter0EUN0EPlaza0ENear0EPride0EFestivities0E310A3829310Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>San Francisco police are responding to shots fired at Civic Center UN Plaza near Pride festivities in the city, police said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbcbayarea.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=310456941&amp;videoID=l4rmyGJbt2Qa&amp;origin=nbcbayarea.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=local&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
Police say a bystander was shot at a gay pride event in San Francisco's Civic Center when an argument between several men turned violent, but the argument was not tied to the event. Video courtesy of Sean-Franc Strang. (Published Sunday, Jun 28, 2015)
Updated 5 hours ago
A man was shot in the arm and several people detained after an argument broke out and shots were fired near the Civic Center/United Nations Plaza Saturday, just as San Francisco Pride celebrations were winding down nearby.
The shooting was "unrelated" to Pride events, police said, and stemmed from a dispute between several groups of young men. As the argument escalated, a suspect pulled out a gun and fired several shots.

A video posted by Doing It L I V E (@bonni300) on
Jun 27, 2015 at 6:37pm PDT
One of the bullets hit a 64-year-old Pride spectator in the arm, police said. He was transported to San Francisco General Hospital and was reported to be in stable condition.
As the shots rang out, people nearby screamed and fled while police officers responded to the scene, according to several cell phone videos apparently recorded near the scene of the shooting.
Police said they were called to the area on a report of shots fired   just after 6 p.m. Officers detained several possible suspects on Market   Street.
The Crime Scene Unit, Gang Task Force and Night Investigations Units were on scene, police said.
One Injured During Shooting Near UN Plaza Amid Pride Festivities
Some sort of police action at Civic Center BART. They went running and cordoned off large area. #SFPride2015 pic.twitter.com/EMRBuyrbU7
 Alexa Smith (@artfuture) June 28, 2015
Published at 6:50 PM PDT on Jun 27, 2015

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:52:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece Debt Crisis: Parliament Approves Referendum</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a25ace/sc/24/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cgreece0Edebt0Ecrisis0Eparliament0Eapproves0Ereferendum0Ecreditor0Ereforms0En383196/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The referendum took the country a step closer to falling out of the euro currency union after members refused to extend a bailout program.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_greece_150622" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Greece's parliament voted early Sunday in favor of Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras' motion to hold a July 5 referendum on creditor proposals for reforms in exchange for loans, with the country's future in the eurozone looking increasingly shaky.
Tsipras' surprise call stunned Greece's international debt negotiators, and the country took a big step closer to falling out of the euro currency union after fellow eurozone member states refused to extend its bailout program past its expiration date on Tuesday, leaving Greece on the brink of financial chaos.
In the streets of Greece, worried people queued outside banks for cash from dawn to dusk after Tsipras' announcement in the early hours of Saturday, after billions of euros had already been emptied in the preceding weeks.
RELATED: U.S. Warns Athens to Reach Deal or Face Decline
Greece has a 1.6 billion euro ($1.8 billion) debt due to the International Monetary Fund on Tuesday and its bailout program expires the same day, after which it is unclear how the country might survive financially.
The referendum is set for next Sunday with the question on whether to accept proposed reforms needed to get bailout loans from other eurozone countries and the IMF. The government is advocating a rejection of the proposals.
The radical left-wing leader accused the creditors of using blackmail and ultimatums against his proud but struggling people. European officials and all Greek opposition parties except the extremist far-right Golden Dawn party called his move for a vote a foolish and rash gambit that effectively ended negotiations to keep Greece financially afloat.
The sudden move comes after five months of stalemated negotiations, with Tsipras accusing creditors of trying to strong-arm his country into taking harsh austerity measures he says would hammer an economy already on its knees after months of creditor-demanded spending cuts and tax hikes.
The referendum move further crumbled already strained relations between Greece and its European partners.
Tsipras said the Greek people would vote against a deal next Sunday.
"This no will also be a big yes, a big yes to the decision of the Greek government to reject an ultimatum that insults the Greek people."
The Associated Press
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:57:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nearly 200 Injured in Fire Explosion During Concert</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a1c0fa/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cnearly0E20A0A0Einjured0Efire0Eexplosion0Eduring0Etaiwan0Econcert0Emedia0En3830A81/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The fire broke out at the center of the stage when up to 1,000 people were having a color play party.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_os_tawainfire_150627" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
TAIPEI  About 200 people were injured after a fire suspected to have stemmed from the explosion of an unknown flammable powder occurred in a recreational park in northern Taiwan, local media reported on Saturday.
The fire broke out at the center of the stage when up to 1,000 people were having a color play party  a festival of dance and music where revelers are sprayed with clouds of colored powder. Footage from television stations showed flames reaching into the sky with some people running to escape.
A person helps an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015. STRINGER/TAIWAN / Reuters
New Taipei City mayor Eric Chu told reporters that "178 people that have been injured have been sent to hospitals nearby. We are very sorry about what happened and we will investigate the cause to find out who is responsible."
"We have demanded the park shut down immediately for inspection," he said.
The number of injured could rise, local media said.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:27:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Investigators Probe Alaska Plane Crash That Killed Nine</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47a20b8a/sc/42/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cinvestigators0Eprobe0Ealaska0Eplane0Ecrash0Ekilled0Ecruise0Epassengers0En383151/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The team of aviation investigators is working at the remote site in southeastern Alaska where a plane crashed, killing all nine aboard.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 27 2015, 7:27 pm ET
Investigators Probe Alaska Plane Crash That Killed Cruise Passengers
by The Associated Press
advertisement
A team of aviation investigators is now working in a remote, mountainous site in southeast Alaska to determine what caused the crash of a sightseeing plane that killed eight cruise ship passengers and the aircraft's pilot.
The DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop  also known as a floatplane  went down Thursday. The excursion was sold through the cruise company Holland America.
Seven investigators with the National Transportation Safety Board made it to the crash site on Saturday morning and are spending the day scouring for clues to the disaster, said Clint Johnson, head of the board's Alaska office.
The plane was on its way back from the Misty Fjords National Monument, a wilderness area of lakes, snowcapped peaks and glacial valleys, Johnson said. The terrain where the plane crashed is steep, mountainous, and often sees strong winds and rain.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_jfr_alaska_plane_crash_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Johnson said the airplane's wings and tail broke off during impact, but the fuselage  the body of the plane  was largely intact. Officials said the plane crashed about 25 miles from Ketchikan on a cliff, 800 feet above Ella Lake in steep, muddy terrain. The cause of the crash isn't yet known.
"It's way too early to speculate," Johnson said. "We can't speculate out of respect to the families."
The eight passengers were on a cruise on the Holland America Line ship Westerdam. Their 7-day cruise had departed from Seattle on June 20.
Ketchikan-based airline Promech Air, operators of the airplane, said the pilot  64-year-old Bryan Krill, 64, of Hope, Idaho  had joined the company early this year as a summertime pilot.
advertisement
A company spokeswoman said Krill was a skilled and experienced pilot with a good safety record. He had flown for many years and had 4,300 hours of flight experience, including roughly 1,700 hours piloting single engine seaplanes. The airplane that crashed is one of five floatplanes operated by the company.
The Associated Press
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
