<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:32:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen Kill at Least 27 People in Attack on Tunisia Beach</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479968de/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Ctunisia0Eattack0Egunmen0Ekill0Eleast0E190Epeople0Eattack0Esousse0Ebeach0En382346/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gunmen opened fire on Western tourists on a beach in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 29 people, the country's interior ministry said.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
Gunmen opened fire on a beach popular with tourists in Tunisia on Friday, killing at least 27 people, the country's interior ministry said.
Tunisia's Interior Ministry told NBC News that at least six people were injured in the attack in the Mediterranean city of Sousse and that one attacker had been killed. The interior ministry said the operation was ongoing.
Gary Pine, a product manager from the U.K., told NBC News he was one of dozens of vacationers on the beach when the attack took place not far from his hotel, the El Mouradi Palm Marina.
He said he initially thought he was hearing firecrackers but that "it was only when you could hear the bullets whizzing through the air that we realized it was gunfire." His 22-year-old son saw one person get shot, Pine added.
He said guests started running off the beach and were told to go to their rooms by hotel staff, he said. Some guests ran back out onto the beach to get their room keys, he added.
The entertainment manager at the hotel, who only gave his first name, Hamouda, said guests had told him two gunmen "came from the sea" and attacked the beach. He confirmed that staff had told guests to hide in their rooms.
Sousse, some 150 kilometers from Tunis, is a popular resort for both Tunisians and Europeans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:22:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Terror Probe Opened After Gruesome Attack in France</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4798e2b8/sc/31/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cman0Edecapitated0Epossible0Eislamist0Eattack0Efrench0Efactory0Ereports0En38230A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>French authorities opened a terrorism investigation Friday after one person was beheaded in an apparent Islamist attack on a gas factory in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 8:22 am ET
Man Decapitated in Suspected Islamist Attack on Air Products Factory in France
by Alastair Jamieson, Cassandra Vinograd and Alexander Smith
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_kelly_terrorist_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
One person was decapitated and two others wounded in an apparent terror attack on a U.S.-owned factory in France, President Francois Hollande said Friday.
A car crashed through the gates of the Air Products plant in Saint-Quentin Fallavier. southeastern France, shortly after 10 a.m. local time (4 a.m. ET). It was followed by an explosion.
Hollande said a suspect had been arrested and there was "no doubt" that the attacker  possibly acting with an accomplice  intended to blow up the entire plant.
advertisement
The president  who told reporters that the decapitated body was found with "inscriptions" on it  said the attack bore the hallmarks of terrorism, adding that security has been stepped up at sensitive sites in France.
French interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve told reporters at the scene that the suspect was known to authorities and had previously been investigated for radicalization but surveillance ended in 2008.
An interior ministry official earlier told NBC News that an explosion occurred after a car drove onto the scene.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_hollande_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
advertisement
The severed head was found hanging on a fence along a nearby road, according to local newspaper La Dauphine Libere, which said that an Islamist flag also was found nearby.
Air Products said the situation at the site had been "contained" and that all its employees had been evacuated from the site and accounted for.
"The site is secure," the Allentown, Pennsylvania-based company said in a statement. "Our crisis and emergency response teams have been activated and are working closely with all relevant authorities."
The beheaded person was not a worker at the factory, Le Monde reported, citing prosecutors .
France has been on high alert following the deadly January attacks on satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo and a kosher supermarket.
advertisement
Hollande, who announced he was returning early from a European summit in Brussels, spoke of "the necessity to protect our values and never give in to fear and not to create any unnecessary division and suspicions [which] would be intolerable and unacceptable."
Air Products supplies industrial gases to businesses and employs more than 20,000 people in 50 countries, according to its website.
 NBC News' Jake Cigainero contributed to this report
Alastair Jamieson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:31:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friday's Top 7 News Stories</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47996fb6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Efridays0Etop0E70Estories0Enbc0Enews0En382316/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From the funeral for the slain Charleston pastor to the Obamacare victory in the Supreme Court, see the stories we're following today.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_mor_obamacare_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
3. Man Decapitated in French Terror Attack
advertisement
French authorities began a terror investigation Friday after one person was reportedly beheaded in an apparent Islamist attack at a gas factory in southeastern France. The country's BFM TV reported that an explosion was heard in the morning at the Air Products plant and a decapitated body was found near the scene. Read more in NEWS .
4. Arrested Prison Guard Paints Negative Atmosphere
Gene Palmer, the second New York prison employee arrested in the escape this month of two convicted killers , described the prison as a "negative environment" that could lead corrections workers to suicide in a radio interview from 2000. His arraignment Thursday was postponed until Monday because Palmer is hiring new lawyers. Read more in NEWS .
5. Putin Talks ISIS, Ukraine With Obama
Russian President Vladimir Putin called Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East. In a statement, the White House said the two leaders addressed continued bloodshed in Syria and agreed on the importance of unity among the six world powers that are negotiating to restrict Iran's nuclear capabilities. Read more in POLITICS .
advertisement
6. Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Kills Nine On Board
A sightseeing plane company boss told of his "pain and anguish" Friday after a pilot and all eight passengers were killed in a crash in southeastern Alaska. The plane was carrying cruise-ship passengers on a shore excursion when it crashed in the Misty Fjords area near Ketchikan. The NTSB has begun its investigation. Read more in NEWS .
7. Univision Dumps Trump Over Mexico Remarks
Univision announced Wednesday it is ending its relationship with the Miss Universe organization, which is partially owned by billionaire Donald Trump, following his remarks about Mexico sending its criminals and rapists to the U.S. Univision had acquired the rights to air the Miss Universe pageant in Spanish. Trump is running for the GOP presidential nomination, and made the controversial comment during his announcement. Read more in LATINO .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:39:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>All 9 Aboard Cruise-Excursion Plane Die in Crash</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47960271/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ccruise0Eline0Eexcursion0Eplane0Ecrashes0Enine0Eaboard0Ealaska0En382166/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Alaska State Troopers said search and crews were able to reach the scene of the crash and confirmed the deaths, but bad weather hampered recovery.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 5:39 am ET
Alaska Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Killing All Nine Aboard
by Alastair Jamieson, M. Alex Johnson and Shamar Walters
Share
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_blake_plane_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A sightseeing plane company boss told of his "pain and anguish" Friday after a pilot and all eight passengers were killed in a crash in southeastern Alaska.
The plane was carrying cruise-ship passengers on a shore excursion when it crashed in the Misty Fjords area near Ketchikan.
The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) has begun an investigation into the cause of the accident.
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_alaskafaa_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Search and rescue teams reached the crash site near a granite rock face about 800 feet above Ella Lake.
However, the recovery of the bodies was postponed until Friday due to bad weather.
advertisement
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," said Marcus Sessoms, president of the plane operator, Promech Air. "At this moment, all of us share the pain and anguish of this terrible event. Our thoughts and our prayers go out to everyone touched by this tragedy."
He added: "During this time of grief, our employees are working to do everything we can to extend support and assistance to the loved ones of those affected."
The passengers were from the Holland America Line ship the MS Westerdam, which set off to Alaska from Seattle on June 20, Holland America Line said in a statement.
The names of the deceased were not released pending notification of next of kin.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:26:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>J.K. Rowling Announces New 'Harry Potter' Play</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479807d8/sc/38/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Charry0Epotter0Ecursed0Echild0Eopen0Elondon0Estage0En382281/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Called Harry Potter and the Cursed Child, JK Rowling said it will tell the "untold part " of Potter's story.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 5:26 am ET
J.K. Rowling Announces 'Harry Potter and the Cursed Child' Will Hit London Stage
by Henry Austin
advertisement
Fans of "Harry Potter" are set for a magical 2016 after J.K. Rowling announced that a new stage play featuring the boy wizard will open next year in London.
"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part II" Harry, Hermione and Ron are spotted by Deatheaters. They hide and Harry sends Patronus. Hogsmeade. (SC210) Jaap Buitendijk / Warner Bros.
The Scottish author announced on Twitter that "Harry Potter and the Cursed Child" will tell an "untold part" of Potter's story, but insisted the play was "not a prequel."
It "is the result of a collaboration between writer Jack Thorne, director John Tiffany and myself" she said, adding that she was "confident" that when audiences see the play they'll understand why she chose the stage instead of printed word to tell the story.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:13:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Consoler-in-Chief: Obama to Again Comfort the Nation</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479829e6/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ccharleston0Echurch0Eshooting0Cconsoler0Echief0Eobama0Eagain0Ecomforts0Enation0Eafter0Eshootings0En381956/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From Aurora, Colorado to most recently, Charleston, South Carolina, President Obama has had to comment numerous times on deadly gun violence in America.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=tdy_melvin_charleston_150622" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
His tone was strong while renewing questions about his failed push for tougher gun laws.
He sounded a similar note in his 2013 State of the Union address following a shooting massacre at Sandy Hook Elementary School in which 26 people, 20 of them young children, were killed by a gunman.
"Because in the two months since Newtown, more than a thousand birthdays, graduations, and anniversaries have been stolen from our lives by a bullet from a gun," the president said. "Gabby Giffords deserves a vote," he added of the former Arizona congresswoman, who was shot in the head by a gunman two years earlier. "The families of Newtown deserve a vote. The families of Aurora deserve a vote. The families of Oak Creek, and Tucson, and Blacksburg, and the countless other communities ripped open by gun violence  they deserve a simple vote."
So far, no legislative strategy has emerged to revive the issue of gun control in congress, where a vote on background checks for gun owners failed in the Senate in April of 2013.
As recently as a few days ago, White House officials were not sure if gun control would be a part of the president's remarks on Friday.
"There's obviously been a robust public debate on a variety of issues that have emerged in the aftermath of this terrible incident," Earnest told reporters. "At this point, again, it's hard for me to rule out the president mentioning some aspects of this debate at this point."
Related: Mourners Pay Respects to Rev. Clementa Pinckney at Charleston's Emanuel AME Church
The president's redirect to the gun control issue in the wake of the Charleston church shooting did not go over well with some segments of the black community, said Andra Gillespie, a political science professor at Emory University who has written extensively about racial politics.
"It was as if he was deflecting this away from being a hate crime," Gillespie said. "He has gotten some backlash within black communities for having pivoted to gun control."
According to a senior White House official, the president is not expected in his remarks to lay out policy or a slew of new gun reforms.
The president's remarks, the official said, are first and foremost, a eulogy.
And he will likely speak without a prompter.
Kristin Donnelly
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:02:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tit for Tat: China Slams U.S. Gun Culture, Race Relations</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47985602/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cchina0Eslams0Eu0Es0Ehuman0Erights0Erecord0Eannual0Ereport0En382296/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>China accused the U.S. of being "haunted by spreading guns" and racial bias, in its tit-for-tat rebuttal to U.S. criticism of China's human rights record.</Description>
        <MainBody>advertisement
BEIJING  China accused the United States on Friday of being "haunted by spreading guns" and racial discrimination, in its annual tit-for-tat rebuttal to U.S. criticism of China's human rights record.
In a lengthy report carried by the official Xinhua news agency, the information office of the State Council, or cabinet, said the United States "violated human rights in other countries in a more brazen manner, and was given more 'red cards' in the international human rights field."
On Thursday, the U.S. State Department released its annual report on human rights conditions in the world. In the China section of the report, it said repression and coercion were routine against activists, ethnic minorities and law firms that took on sensitive cases.
China has long rejected criticism of its rights' record and has pointed to its success at lifting millions out of poverty.
The State Council report was "an equal and mutually beneficial way of reciprocating" the United States, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Lu Kang said at a daily briefing.
advertisement
The Chinese report, which was mostly compiled from U.S. media articles, said "racial discrimination has been a chronic problem in the United States human rights record," adding that the U.S. suppressed the voting rights of minorities.
"In 2014, multiple cases of arbitrary police killing of African-Americans have sparked huge waves of protests, casting doubts on the racial 'equality' in the United States and giving rise to racial hatred factors," the report said.
The report also criticized the U.S. for conducting surveillance on world leaders and civilians and for allowing a few interest groups to influence the government's decision-making.
Human rights have long been a source of tension between the world's two largest economies.
Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:32:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Teens Charged With Gang Raping Mentally-Disabled Girl</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479829fc/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcmiami0N0Cnews0Clocal0C40ETeens0ECharged0EWith0ERaping0EMentally0EDisabled0EGirl0Eat0ENorth0EMiami0ESenior0EHigh0ESchool0E30A99749810Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Derek Bynum and three under-18 students, are charged with the gang rape of a mentally-disabled girl at North Miami Senior High School.</Description>
        <MainBody>Updated 4 minutes ago
Disturbing allegations have surfaced about an alleged gang rape at a South Florida high school.
Derek Bynum, 18, along with three other underage students, are charged with the gang rape of a mentally handicapped girl at North Miami Senior High School back in January.
4-Year-Old Twins Rescued From House Fire
The teens allegedly took the girl into a janitor's closet near the end of the school day and forced her to perform oral, anal and vaginal sex acts.
Court records show Bynum and one of the other teens pleaded not guilty. The other two teens have not yet entered pleas.
Wilton Manors to Start Ticketing Jaywalkers
The discovery process is ongoing. Were trying to get to the bottom of what, if anything, happened  and all the clients remain and are presumed innocent, said Matthew Ladd, a lawyer representing one of the suspects. Lawyers for the other teens did not return requests for comment, according to the Miami-Herald .
The Miami-Dade County School District released a statement Thursday saying in part, "While we struggle to understand the senseless depravity of this isolated but disturbing student incident -- we commend the deliberate and swift actions of Miami-Dade Schools Police in apprehending the alleged perpetrators."
Published at 11:25 PM EDT on Jun 25, 2015
News breaks at inconvenient times. 
Download one of the NBC6 mobile apps and have the news come to you. Watch live streaming newscasts, receive  critical push notifications on the go and stay in touch with your city  around the clock.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:45:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>EU Leaders Strike Deal to Relocate 40,000 Migrants</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4797ffec/sc/24/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Ceuropes0Eborder0Ecrisis0Ceurope0Emigrant0Ecrisis0E40A0E0A0A0A0Ewill0Emove0Eitaly0Egreece0Ee0En382246/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>40,000 refugees are to be relocated from southern Europe under a deal reached by political leaders to tackle the continent's worsening migrant crisis.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=x_lon_calais_150623" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
LONDON  Forty-thousand refugees will be relocated from southern Europe under a deal reached by political leaders to tackle the continent's worsening migrant crisis.
The migrants will be moved from Greece and Italy to other European Union countries over the next two years under the agreement, reached early Friday in Brussels by European leaders . A further 20,000 refugees will be resettled directly from overcrowded camps in Syria, Iraq or Afghanistan.
Friday's deal is a voluntary scheme, and exemptions were granted for Hungary, which is politically opposed to accepting migrants, and Bulgaria, one of the bloc's poorest countries. Britain is also opting out of the plan, which was discussed at acrimonious talks.
RELATED: Human Traffic: Migrants in Serbia Seek Gateway to Europe
"It was a very intensive debate," German Chancellor Angela Merkel told reporters after the meeting ended, describing the migrant crisis "as the biggest challenge I have seen in European affairs in my time as chancellor."
The deal comes as Mediterranean countries are struggling to cope with an unprecedented influx of desperate people fleeing conflicts in north Africa and the Middle East.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:53:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin Calls Obama to Talk ISIS, Iran</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47976802/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Crussia0Elove0Eputin0Ecalls0Eobama0Etalk0Eshop0En38220A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin called President Barack Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 26 2015, 2:53 am ET
Putin Calls Obama to Talk ISIS, Iran and Ukraine
Share
advertisement
Russian President Vladimir Putin called President Barack Obama and discussed continued tensions in eastern Ukraine and the fight against ISIS in the Middle East.
In a statement, the White House said the two leaders addressed continued bloodshed in Syria and agreed on the importance of unity among the six world powers that are negotiating to restrict Iran's nuclear capabilities.
As for Ukraine, the White House said Obama told Putin Russia needs to meet commitments it made in Minsk, Belarus, earlier this year, including the removal of troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory.
A file picture dated 18 June 2012 shows US President Barack Obama (R) talking with Russian President Vladimir Putin (L) during their meeting at Esperansa hotel prior G20 summit in Los Cabos, Mexico. ALEXEI NIKOLSKY/RIA NOVOSTI/KREM / EPA
The call came on the same day NATO's supreme allied commander cited a continuous flow of ammunition and other military supplies from Russia across the border to Ukraine.
advertisement
According to a posting on the Kremlin's official English website , "significant attention" was given to the topic of ISIS and terrorism in the Middle East.
"Vladimir Putin and Barack Obama agreed to instruct Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov and U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry to hold a meeting to discuss this issue," the Kremlin said.
Contributors The Associated Press and Hasani Gittens
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:45:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>I Don't Want a Lecture: Bristol Palin Announces Pregnancy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/479739bb/sc/17/l/0L0Stoday0N0Cparents0Cbristol0Epalin0Eannounces0Eshe0Epregnant0Esecond0Echild0Et28841/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Bristol Palin announced she is expecting her second child, in an emotional blog post on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Paris taxi drivers stage violent protests against Uber
"Honestly, I've been trying my hardest to keep my chin up on this one," she wrote on the website Patheos. "At the end of the day there's nothing I can't do with God by my side, and I know I am fully capable of handling anything that is put in front of me with dignity and grace."
Until last month, Palin was engaged to Medal of Honor recipient Dakota Meyer, but the pair called off the wedding in May.
Reuters file
"Life moves on no matter what," she continued. "So no matter how you feel, you get up, get dressed, show up, and never give up. When life gets tough, there is no other option but to get tougher."
Bristol, the daughter of former Alaska governor Sarah Palin, said that the pregnancy "has been, and will be, a huge disappointment to my family, to my close friends, and to many of you." But she asked readers to respect the privacy of her and her 6-year-old son, Tripp.
The 24-year-old added, "I do not want any lectures and I do not want any sympathy. My little family always has, and always will come first. Tripp, this new baby, and I will all be fine, because God is merciful."
Sarah Palin first announced that Bristol's wedding to Meyer would be canceled in a Facebook post on May 18, less than a week before the ceremony was scheduled to take place.
Bristol broke her silence on the matter on May 26, writing, "I know God's plan is greater than anything else, and Tripp and I are in Alaska beginning to rebuild our lives under much different circumstances than we anticipated."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 06:42:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Six Die in Multi-Vehicle Wreck on Tennessee Interstate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795faff/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Csix0Ekilled0Emulti0Evehicle0Ewreck0Etennessee0Einterstat0En38220A6/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Six people were killed and at least nine others were injured in a nine-vehicle pileup Thursday night on Interstate 75 near Chattanooga, Tennessee.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_tn_carax_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Six people were killed and at least nine others were injured in a fiery nine-vehicle pileup Thursday night on Interstate 75 in Tennessee, Chattanooga police said.
Few details were immediately available because emergency crews were still at work, Chattanooga police said. At 11 p.m., four hours after the wreck, state traffic cameras showed the scene still littered with vehicles as police and state troopers worked to remove victims from the scene.
None of the victims were identified because their families had yet to be notified.
Emergency cars littered Interstate 75 at Exit 11 for hours after the crash at 7 p.m. ET. Tennessee Transportation Department
The state Department of Transportation said the crash involved at least one cargo-carrying semi-trailer.
I-75 northbound north of Exit 11 to the town Ooltewah, east of Chattanooga, was expected to be shut down until at least dawn Friday after the crash, police said.
I-75 northbound north of Exit 11 to the town Ooltewah, east of Chattanooga, Tennessee, was expected to be shut down until at least dawn Friday. Chattanooga, Tennessee, Police Department via Twitter
M. Alex Johnson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:41:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Baltimore County Police Fatally Shoot Unarmed Man</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47963c7b/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbaltimore0Ecounty0Epolice0Efatally0Eshoot0Eunarmed0Eman0En382171/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Police said the officers fired on Spencer McCain after he acted like he was armed and was going to use a weapon, but no weapon was found.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 25 2015, 10:41 pm ET
Baltimore County Police Fatally Shoot Unarmed Man on Domestic Call
by Phil Helsel
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_balt_police_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Baltimore County Police officers fatally shot an unarmed man while responding to a call of a domestic disturbance early Thursday morning, authorities said.
Three officers opened fire on Spencer Lee McCain, 41, after being called to a home in Owings Mills just after 1 a.m., and forcing their way inside because the officers feared a person may be in danger, Baltimore County police said in a statement. Police said officers could hear a disturbance inside, but no one answered the door.
Police said the officers shot McCain after he allegedly made movements that the officers interpreted as indicating he was armed and ready to act, but no weapon was found, police said. McCain was taken to a hospital where he was later pronounced dead.
advertisement
"The police officers encountered a subject in a defensive position, making body movements and arm movements that placed the officers in fear of serious injury or death," Baltimore County Police Chief Jim Johnson told reporters.
Police said all three officers fired and the investigation has not determined how many shots were fired, but investigators recovered 19 shell casings at the scene.
Police said a woman inside the home had "visible injuries" but refused treatment; two children were also inside the home. The woman was not identified, but police said McCain was prohibited by a court protective order from having any contact with her, and police said they were called to the home around 17 times since 2012.
Johnson said the woman told investigators that McCain told her, "You're going to get the beating you deserve," NBC station WBAL reported.
A neighbor told the station he heard what sounded like a woman "begging, you know, like, 'Don't do that. Don't do this. Please stop."
advertisement
Owing Mills is about 20 miles northwest of Baltimore, which was roiled by protests and riots after a black man, Freddie Gray, died after suffering a spinal injury while in police custody. McCain's race was not released.
Police said the homicide unit will complete an investigation and forward the results to the state's attorney's office for review.
Phil Helsel
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 05:28:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Enormous Noah's Ark Replica Takes Shape in Kentucky Field</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795e2ff/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbible0Ebased0Eall0Ewood0Eark0Etakes0Eshape0Ekentucky0Efield0En382146/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Builders are betting big that millions of visitors will flood the Williamstown, Kentucky, attraction.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nc_noahsark_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A planned all-wood replica of Noah's ark got a step closer to its Old Testament ideal on Thursday, when workers lifted yet another rib of the would-be vessel into place in a Kentucky pasture.
The future tourist attraction is called Ark Encounter  centered around a 510-foot-long ark, which the builder, a Christian ministry called "Answers in Genesis," says "will be the largest timber-frame structure in the world" when it's completed next summer.
Builders are betting big that millions of visitors will flood the Williamstown, Kentucky, attraction. Ken Ham, president of Answers in Genesis, told WLWT he expects up to about 2 million visitors per year.
advertisement
"I believe it will be one of the biggest attractions outside of Disney, Universal, people like that  it's going to be one of the biggest attractions in this country."
Ham said the ark, which is being built according to dimensions provided in the Bible for the vessel that survived the worldwide flood, will house three stories of exhibits, while the fourth floor is planned to be a restaurant.
According to the project's website, "additional future phases for the attraction include a Walled City, the Tower of Babel, a first-century Middle Eastern village, a journey in history from Abraham to the parting of the Red Sea, a walk-through aviary, an expanded large petting zoo, and so on."
A wooden rib that is part of a ship based on the story of Noahs ark is raised into place in Williamstown, Ky., on Thursday, June 25, 2015. The Ark Encounter will be a religious tourist attraction when it opens next year. Dylan Lovan / AP
But  not unlike the ark in the Bible  this structure has attracted its own share of criticism. Last year, the state of Kentucky withdrew its offer of tax breaks for the attraction.
advertisement
"State tourism tax incentives cannot be used to fund religious indoctrination or otherwise be used to advance religion," Kentucky Tourism Secretary Bob Stewart wrote in a letter in December .
And Bill Nye "The Science Guy," who debated Ham about creationism last year, has argued the project would hurt science education.
Answers in Genesis sued Kentucky tourism officials in February, claiming the decision to deny the tax breaks violated the group's First Amendment rights. That suit is still pending, but the construction is moving forward, as organizes plan to open the attraction next summer.
Becky Bratu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cleveland Vigil Marks Tamir Rice's 13th Birthday</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795e731/sc/3/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cvigil0Emarks0E13th0Ebirthday0Eslain0Ecleveland0Eboy0Etamir0Erice0En3820A96/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A candlelight vigil Thursday remembered the Ohio boy shot to death by police, on what would have been his 13th birthday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jun 25 2015, 9:42 pm ET
Vigil Marks 13th Birthday of Slain Cleveland Boy Tamir Rice
by M. Alex Johnson
Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=f_tamir_rice_150626" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
A candlelight vigil was under way in Cleveland to remember Tamir Rice, the unarmed African-American boy shot to death by police last year, on what would have been his 13th birthday.
The vigil was held at Cudell Recreation Center, where Cleveland police Officer Timothy Loehmann killed Tamir on Nov. 22. Loehmann and his partner were responding to a report of a man with a gun, but Tamir had only a toy pellet gun.
"It's been eight months," Tamir's mother, Samira Rice, said in a statement . "While I am crushed, and I struggle daily with the loss of my son, I will not rest until those men who were responsible for taking my son's life are prosecuted."
advertisement
Cuyahoga County Prosecutor Timothy McGinty told reporters Wednesday that he expects to complete his investigation in "a matter of months."
Remember y'all, #TamirRice birthday is today. Find a way to honor his legacy, as today is birthday #13 #RestInPower pic.twitter.com/susVf605Uf
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:37:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Week in Pictures</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4796acea/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cweek0Ein0Epictures0Cweek0Epictures0Ejune0E180E250En382176/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Tragedy strikes an historic church, mermaids parade through New York, lives saved at sea, and more.</Description>
        <MainBody>Comment
1. Rev. Norvel Goff prays at the empty seat of the Rev. Clementa Pinckney at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church four days after a mass shooting that claimed the lives of Pinckney and eight others on June 21 in Charleston, S.C. David Goldman / Pool via AP
2. Gary and Aurelia Washington, center left and right, the son and granddaughter of Ethel Lance, who died in a mass shooting earlier in the week, leave a sidewalk memorial in front of Emanuel AME Church comforted by fellow family members on June 18 in Charleston, S.C. Dylann Storm Roof was arrested in the slayings of nine people, including the pastor at a prayer meeting inside the historic church. David Goldman / AP
3. A Buddhist novice prays at a monastery affiliated with the MaBaTha organization on the outskirts of Yangon. The MaBaTha organization promotes hardline Buddhist nationalism in Myanmar. Christophe Archambault / AFP - Getty Images
advertisement
4. Flood water reflects damaged homes in Coal City, Illinois, a community of about 5,000 residents 60 miles southwest of Chicago, where the National Weather Service confirmed that a twister touched down on June 23.  A storm system flattened homes across the Midwest and slammed the Northeast on June 22 with heavy rain and strong winds, knocking out power for hundreds of thousands, snarling transportation and overturning semi-trucks on interstates. Jon Durr / Getty Images
5. Muslims attend Friday prayers during the second day of Ramadan, in the courtyard of a housing estate next to the small BBC community center and mosque in east London on June 19. Stefan Wermuth / Reuters
6. A stall holder covers over a carousel at the end of the day at The Hoppings fun fair, believed to be one of the largest travelling fairs in Europe, on its opening day in Newcastle upon Tyne, North East England on June 19. Oli Scarff / AFP - Getty Images
advertisement
7. Participants dance on Surf Avenue during the 33rd annual Mermaid Parade in New York's Coney Island on June 20. The parade began in 1983 and takes place on the Saturday closest to the first day of summer. Justin Lane / EPA
8. A man carries a box into the only shop open on an Athens street on June 25. Desperate Greeks expressed fears for their future Friday as more than $1.1 billion was withdrawn from banks in a single day, pushing the country closer towards a default. Daniel Ochoa De Olza / AP
9. Palestinians, not permitted by Israeli security forces to cross into Jerusalem from the West Bank due to an age limit, climb over a section of the controversial Israeli barrier as they try to make their way to attend the first Friday prayer of Ramadan in Jerusalem's al-Aqsa mosque, in the village of Al-Ram, near Ramallah on June 19. Mohamad Torokman / Reuters
advertisement
10. Dylann Roof appears via video before a judge in Charleston, S.C., on June 19. The 21-year-old accused of killing nine people inside he historic Mother Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church made his first court appearance, with the relatives of all the victims making tearful statements. Centralized Bond Hearing Court, of Charleston, S.C. via AP
11. Ash from Mount Sinabung volcano fills the sky over an abandoned church during another eruption in Karo, in Indonesia's North Sumatra province on June 19. Sinabung rumbled back to life in 2013 after a period of inactivity, since then around 10,000 people have had to evacuate their homes. Sutanta Aditya / AFP - Getty Images
12. Migrants sit on the deck of the Belgian Navy vessel Godetia after they were saved during a search and rescue mission in the Mediterranean Sea off the Libyan coasts on June 24. Hundreds of migrants were rescued by the Godetia, which is part of a fleet taking part in the Triton migrants rescue operation. Gregorio Borgia / AP
advertisement
13. A rider and his horse rear during the traditional Saint John festival in Ciutadella, on the Balearic Island of Minorca, Spain on June 24. During the festival, race horses gallop and prance on their hind legs through the streets to honor of the town's patron saint. As the "caixers" (horse riders) ride together in a parade, spectators attempt to pat the horses' chests to get good luck. Jaime Reina / AFP - Getty Images
14. The Crew onboard Australia's HMAS Canberra stand at attention as they honor the countrys oldest naval ship, the HMAS Tobruk (not pictured) as she arrives at Garden Island following a final voyage to Sydney on June 25. Tobruk, Australia's longest serving naval ship has been in service for 35 years and has sailed almost a million nautical miles around the world. Dean Lewins / EPA
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:23:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Snooze-Deprived Couples Rest Easy After 'Sleep Divorce'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4795b59d/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnightly0Enews0Csleep0Edivorce0En3820A46/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>It's estimated one in every four couples sleeps separately at night — twice as many as fifteen years ago, according to the Better Sleep Council and National Sleep Foundation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=nn_hja_sleep_divorce_150625" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
Jack Mazewski snores so loudly that his children sleeping down the hall can hear it. The noise didn't bother his wife, Joanna, for the first few years of their marriage  until their kids were born.
"I became a light sleeper because you have a little more stress - two children, a mortgage, bills," said Joanna Mazewski.
Night after night, her husband's snoring kept her awake.
advertisement
"She would poke me a few times," Jack said. His wife quickly corrected him: "I would say kick, not poke."
"I would end up waking him up in the middle of the night," Joanna added. "And then two of us weren't sleeping."
It made mornings a nightmare for the otherwise happily-married couple.
"The arguing would happen when we're not sleeping well," said Joanna.
Jack and Joanna Mazewski Hallie Jackson / NBC News
advertisement
At the end of their rope, the Mazewskis finally found a solution, just like an increasing number of couples in the United States: separate beds.
It's estimated one in every four couples sleeps separately at night  twice as many as fifteen years ago, according to the Better Sleep Council and National Sleep Foundation. It's a phenomenon often called "sleep divorce."
"For some couples, it actually works," said Dr. Wendy Troxel, "particularly if they're both getting a better night of sleep and they're able to function better in the relationship during the day."
Many people prefer the comfort of sleeping next to a spouse, but Troxel  a behavioral and social scientist at the RAND Corporation, pointed to studies showing couples actually sleep worse together.
"This could be sort of a phenomenon of basic physics," she explained. "You have another person in bed with you, so there's more likelihood of more movement and that can be disruptive of sleep."
advertisement
Sleep deprivation can be a serious problem in romantic relationships.
"In a sleep deprived couple, they are more likely to engage in conflict and less likely to be able to resolve it effectively," said Troxel. Plus, a University of California-Berkeley study showed who slept poorly experienced less appreciation for their partners than people who got enough sleep.
For an increasing number of couples, "sleep divorce" is the clear solution - although it sometimes carries a stigma.
"We don't say anything because people think, 'oh, there's probably trouble in their marriage,'" said Joanna Mazewski. "But the fact of the matter is, we try to sleep in different beds so we avoid that trouble!"
Sleep experts recommend a few key tips for sleeping apart - and staying happy:
advertisement
Talk about it first. Pre-planning separate sleeping arrangements ensures one partner doesn't feel ditched when the other leaves the bedroom.
Schedule "together time" in the evenings. "That time before falling asleep is often the only time that couples have together to be away from these distractions," said Troxel. Creating space for intimacy doesn't have to mean just sex: cuddling and talking can help couples stay connected before they head to separate sleeping locations.
If snoring is the problem, schedule a doctor's visit. It can be a sign of a more serious sleep disorder, like sleep apnea.
For the Mazewskis, sleeping separately at night helps them feel better in the morning: "If it doesn't work out for one person or the other," Joanna asked, "why suffer through it?"
Hallie Jackson
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:47:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State Department: 15 Emails Missing From Clinton Cache</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/47955b7c/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cpolitics0Cpolitics0Enews0Cstate0Edepartment0E150Eemails0Emissing0Ehillary0Eclinton0Ecache0En382151/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A report issued late Thursday says that all or part of 15 emails sent or received from Clinton's private server were missing from records turned over.</Description>
        <MainBody>Copy this code to your website or blog
&lt;iframe width="635" height="500" src="http://player.theplatform.com/p/2E2eJC/nbcNewsOffsite?guid=mtp_daleyemail_150614" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
When asked about the discrepancy, Nick Merrill, a Clinton campaign spokesman, said, "She has turned over 55,000 pages of materials to the State Department, including all emails in her possession from Mr. Blumenthal."
Clinton is running for the 2016 Democratic presidential nomination.
Clinton's use of the non-governmental email while in office was not publicly disclosed until earlier this year, after the committee sought her correspondence related to the Benghazi attack. She says the single account for personal and professional purposes was a matter of convenience, and says all her work emails were included in the 55,000 pages of documents she later handed over to the State Department. Emails of a personal nature were destroyed, she says.
The State Department informed the Select Benghazi Committee on Thursday that they are no longer certain that's the case, according to officials who spoke on condition of anonymity because they weren't authorized to speak publicly on the matter. The officials said Julia Frifield, the assistant secretary of state for legislative affairs, confirmed that nine emails and parts of six others that the committee made public Monday couldn't be located in the department's records.
advertisement
As for 46 other, previously unreleased Libya-related Blumenthal emails published by the committee, officials said all are in the department's records. They weren't handed over to congressional investigators because they had no relevance to events in Benghazi and did not correspond to the committee's request, the officials said. The officials added that they are willing to provide emails outside the committee's initial request, but warned that doing so would require more time.
The emails missing from the State Department's records include missives from Blumenthal in which he sends media accounts about the killing of one of Libyan dictator Moammar Gadhafi's sons, various reports on internal politics among Libya's rebels and news of the assassination of a former Gadhafi minister in Vienna. The last email was sent Aug. 28, 2012, two weeks before the Benghazi attack, and none focus particularly on the eastern Libyan city.
Clinton's responses are brief. In one from August 2011, she tells Blumenthal she will be in Paris the next day to meet rebel leaders and says she had "to resort to new iPad" because she didn't have electricity or Blackberry coverage after Hurricane Irene.
In another from March 2012, she passes on an adviser's skepticism regarding one of Blumenthal's reports about political intrigue in post-Gadhafi Libya, saying: "This strain credulity based on what I know. Any other info about it?"
And after a long August 2012 note from Blumenthal about Libya's new interim President Mohamed Yousef el-Magariaf, Clinton writes: "Another keeper  thanks and please keep 'em coming." Four days later, she responds to a follow-up reports about el-Magariaf, saying: "Fascinating. I had a very good call w him."
advertisement
Clinton's critics are likely to focus less on the substance of the emails than on the fact that they weren't shared with the State Department.
Gowdy, a South Carolina Republican, has pressed for an explanation of why Blumenthal gave the committee emails not previously shared by the State Department. The suggestion has been that either the department or Clinton was hiding something.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:23:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NBA Draft Tracker: Follow the Picks as They Unfold</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/4794bfa9/sc/13/l/0L0Srotoworld0N0Carticles0Cnba0C548490C4750C20A150Enba0Edraft0Etracker0Dcid0Feref0Rnbcnews0Rtext/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Follow the NBA Draft as it unfolds on Thursday in Brooklyn, New York.</Description>
        <MainBody>31. Cleveland Cavaliers (from Minnesota Timberwolves) - Cedi Osman , SG/SF, Anadolu Efes
32. Houston Rockets (from New York Knicks) - Montrezl Harrell , PF, Louisville
33. Boston Celtics (from Philadelphia 76ers via Miami Heat) - Jordan Mickey , PF, LSU
34. Los Angeles Lakers - Anthony Brown , SF, Stanford
35. New York Knicks (from Philadelphia 76ers via Orlando Magic) - Guillermo Hernangomez , C, Baloncesto Sevilla (Spain)
36. Cleveland Cavaliers (from Minnesota Timberwolves via Sacramento Kings and Houston Rockets) - Rakeem Christmas , PF, Syracuse
37. Philadelphia 76ers (from Denver Nuggets, via Houston Rockets, Portland Trail Blazers and Minnesota Timberwolves) - Richaun Holmes , PF, Bowling Green
38. Detroit Pistons - Darrun Hilliard , SG, Villanova
39. Brooklyn Nets (from Charlotte Hornets) - Juan Vaulet , SF, Estudiantes Bahia Blanca (Argentina)
40. Miami Heat - Josh Richardson , SG, Tennessee
41. Portland Trail Blazers (from Brooklyn Nets) - Pat Connaughton , SG, Notre Dame
42. Utah Jazz - Olivier Hanlan , PG/SG, Boston College
43. Indiana Pacers - Joseph Young , SG/PG, Oregon
44. Phoenix Suns - Andrew Harrison , PG, Kentucky
45. Boston Celtics - Marcus Thornton , PG, William &amp; Mary
46. Toronto Raptors (from Milwaukee Bucks) - Norman Powell , SG, UCLA
47. Philadelphia 76ers (from New Orleans Pelicans via Washington Wizards and Los Angeles Clippers) - Arturas Gudaitis , C, Zalgiris Kaunas (Lithuania)
48. Oklahoma City Thunder - Dakari Johnson , C, Kentucky
49. Washington Wizards - Aaron White , PF, Iowa
50. Atlanta Hawks (from Toronto Raptors) - Marcus Eriksson , SG, FC Barcelona (Spain)
51. Orlando Magic (from Chicago Bulls) - Tyler Harvey , SG, Eastern Washington
52. Dallas Mavericks - Satnam Singh Bhamara , C, IMG Academy
53. Cleveland Cavaliers (From Portland Trail Blazers via Chicago Bulls and Denver Nuggets) - Sir'Dominic Pointer , SF, St. John's
54. Portland Trail Blazers (from Utah Jazz via Cleveland Cavaliers) - Daniel Diez , PF, San Sebastian (Spain)
55. San Antonio Spurs - Cady Lalanne , PF, Massachusetts
56. New Orleans Pelicans (from Memphis Grizzlies) - Branden Dawson , PF, Michigan State
57. Denver Nuggets (from Los Angeles Clippers) - Nikola Radicevic , PG, Baloncesto Sevilla (Spain)
58. Philadelphia 76ers (from Houston Rockets) - J.P. Tokoto , SG, North Carolina
59. Atlanta Hawks - Dimitrios Agravanis , PF, Olympiacos (Greece)
60. Philadelphia 76ers (from Golden State Warriors via Indiana Pacers) - Luka Mitrovic , PF, Red Star (Serbia)

Trades:
Brooklyn acquired the No. 23 pick (Rondae-Hollis-Jefferson) and G Steve Blake from Portland for the No. 41 pick (Pat Connaughton) and C Mason Plumlee .
Toronto acquired the No. 46 pick (Norman Powell) and a 2017 first-round pick from Milwaukee for PG Greivis Vasquez .
Brooklyn acquired the No. 39 pick (Juan Valet) from Charlotte for two future draft picks.
New York acquired the No. 35 pick (Guillermo Hernangomez) from Philadelphia for two future draft picks.
Portland acquired the No. 54 pick (Daniel Diez) from Utah for a future second-round pick.
Complete results from the 2015 NBA Draft are posted below. Scroll down to see the details of each in-draft trade. Click on each players name for full pick analysis.

For instant analysis on every player picked, refresh Rotoworld's NBA Player News page .

</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
