<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nbcnews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:33:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Female Suspect Killed in Patrol Car After Shoot Out</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e7a693/sc/16/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cfemale0Esuspect0Ekilled0Eafter0Eexchanging0Egunfire0Eatlanta0Epolice0Epatrol0Ecar0En351561/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A female suspect was fatally shot by Atlanta police after exchanging gunfire with officers — from the back of their patrol car, police said Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:31:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>1,000 Europeans Still Missing in Nepal Quake</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45eafb75/sc/11/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cnepal0Eearthquake0Cnepal0Eearthquake0E10E0A0A0A0Eeuropeans0Estill0Emissing0Eeu0Eenvoy0Esays0En351791/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>One thousand people from the European Union are missing in Nepal and 12 are confirmed dead, nearly a week after the devastating earthquake.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:20:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Christie Ally Expected to Plead Guilty in 'Bridgegate': Sources</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45ea6dba/sc/16/l/0L0Snbcnewyork0N0Cinvestigations0CGeorge0EWashington0EBridge0ELane0EClosure0EScandal0EChris0EChristie0EDavid0EWildstein0E30A21212410Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>David Wildstein is expected to plead guilty to unspecified criminal charges</Description>
        <MainBody>NBC 4 New York
Updated 1 minute ago
The former Port Authority official who resigned amid the political uproar over the George Washington Bridge lane closures in September 2013 is due in federal court in Newark Friday, where he is expected to enter into a plea deal in the scandal, according to sources familiar with the matter.
David Wildstein, a former ally of Gov. Chris Christie and a Christie appointee to the Port Authority, is expected to plead guilty to unspecified criminal charges in connection with the lane closures at an 11 a.m. court appearance, sources familiar with the case said.
Baltimore Public Defender's Post About Jail Goes Viral
Authorities have also planned an afternoon news briefing for Friday, at which point they are expected to announce the names of other former Christie aides indicted in the scandal, which skewered the Republican's presidential ambitions and caused his popularity in the Garden State to tank.
Specific charges any former aides may face remain unclear. A federal grand jury has been hearing evidence for months in the case.
Top News Photos of the Week
The lane closings at the bridge, which links Fort Lee and New York City, caused massive traffic problems for days and investigators had been looking to see if the closure was retribution against Fort Lee's Democratic mayor for failing to endorse Christie's gubernatorial re-election bid.
Wildstein's lawyer Alan Zegas did not return calls and emails for comment Wednesday and Thursday. Spokesmen for U.S. Attorney Paul Fishman, the Justice Department and the FBI have all declined to comment.
Timeline: George Washington Bridge Scandal
Christie has denied knowing about any lane closure plans, saying he first learned of the controversy when stories appeared in the media.  Christie has said he believed his aides and their claims that the closure was part of a traffic study. But a lawyer for Wildstein alleged in February 2014 that the governor knew about them and that he had evidence tying the governor to it.
Officials familiar with the investigation have told NBC 4 New Yorkthat there is no evidence showing Christie had any advance knowledge of the lane closures.
In email exchanges obtained by news outlets last year, Wildstein and Bridget Anne Kelly, a Christie deputy chief of staff, wrote about shutting down the bridge.
"Time for some traffic problems in Fort Lee," Kelly wrote.
Youth Football Coach Who Fought to Prevent Violence Shot, Killed in Car: NYPD
A few weeks later, on the weekend before the lane closures, Wildstein wrote to her: "I will call you Monday AM to let you know how Fort Lee goes."
The unannounced closings caused traffic backups that lasted hours on streets in Fort Lee, where the mouth of the bridge is located.
Freddie Gray Investigation: What's Next?
Text messages also obtained by NBC 4 New York and other news outlets show an unidentified person texting Wildstein about the Fort Lee mayor, Mark Sokolich, asking for help on the second day of the closures: "Is it wrong that I am smiling?"
He texted back: "No."
The other person texted about feeling bad for children not being able to get to school because of the traffic.
Wildstein wrote back: "They are the children of Buono voters," referring to Christie's 2013 opponent for governor, Democrat Barbara Buono.
In December, a 136-page interim report by a joint legislative panel tasked with investigating the lane closures found no evidence Christie was involved in the scheme. The report echoed the findings of an independent investigation commissioned by Christie's administration that found no proof the governor was involved in the closures or subsequent cover-up, and the governor has consistently denied any advance knowledge of the traffic scheme.
Federal prosecutors issued a new subpoena to the Port Authority last month in connection with the case seeking evidence related to claims that members of the Christie administration may have engaged in retaliatory action against Jersey City's mayor for the non-endorsement. The request included records from former Port Authority officials who were appointed by or were allies of Christie.
The investigation has remained a point of frustration for many supporters of Christie, who has termed the lane closings "inexplicably stupid." Lawyers hired by the governor and a legislative committee investigating the circumstances of the lane closures have found no evidence to contradict his denials of any advance knowledge of them.
News of Wildsteins expected guilty plea was first reported by Bloomberg News.
Published 2 hours ago
Follow Jonathan Dienst on Twitter @jonathan4NY , Facebook or email him: jonathan.dienst@nbcuni.com

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:01:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Friday's Top 7 News Stories</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45ea6db4/sc/35/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Cknow0Eit0Eall0Efridays0Etop0E70Estories0Enbc0Enews0En351751/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>From the Freddie Gray-related protests to Jameis Winston being picked first in the NFL draft, see the stories we're following today.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:39:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Feds Charge New Moms as 'Birth Tourism' Fugitives</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e7bdf8/sc/11/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cfeds0Echarge0Enew0Echinese0Emoms0Ebirth0Etourism0Efugitives0En351616/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Ten Chinese nationals ordered to stay in the U.S. as witnesses have fled back to China, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:39:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How to See Everything This Weekend</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45ea6dbe/sc/14/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cbusiness0Cconsumer0Cguide0Eamazing0Eweekend0Esports0Eentertainment0En351761/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>This may be one of the greatest weekends in sports and entertainment in a long time.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:15:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Off-Color: Diplomat Hits Back Over 'Dumb Blonde' Taunt</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45ea1e3c/sc/11/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cu0Es0Ediplomat0Ehighlights0Eturkish0Edumb0Eblonde0Etaunt0Estates0Eharf0En351746/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A U.S. diplomat has altered his hair on Instagram in solidarity with State Department spokeswoman Marie Harf who was taunted as a "dumb blonde" by a Turkish politician.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:30:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two Dead as Havana Hit With Heavy Rain, Flooding</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45ea6555/sc/16/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cworld0Cheavy0Erains0Eslam0Ehavana0En351741/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Torrential rains Cuba's capital on Wednesday, flooding streets, stranding cars and killing two.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:07:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DOJ Unveils $20M Program to Expand Cop Body-Cam Use</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e996d2/sc/28/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cbaltimore0Eunrest0Cbody0Eworn0Ecameras0Eget0E20Am0Efederal0Epilot0Eamid0Ebaltimore0Eprotests0En351721/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A $20M federal program to extend the use of police body cameras was announced Friday, amid nationwide protests over the treatment of suspects by cops.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:36:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Elderly Woman Dies From Golf Club, Scissors Attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e993fc/sc/40/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Celderly0Ewoman0Efatally0Estabbed0Ewhile0Eworking0Egarden0Ecops0En351726/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Houston Police said that Su-Jung Teng was gardening when an "unknown" male suspect entered her property and attacked.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:04:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghans Find ISIS-Linked Fighters Worse Than Taliban</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e9b02d/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cisis0Eterror0Catmosphere0Eterror0Eisis0Elinked0Efighters0Etighten0Egrip0Eafghanistan0En34780A1/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Foreign militants fighting and recruiting under the ISIS flag have moved into towns and villages in northern Afghanistan and begun terrorizing locals.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:55:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mom Kept Alive Eight Weeks for Baby Angel's Delivery</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45ea6da7/sc/16/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Chealth0Cwomens0Ehealth0Cbrain0Edead0Enebraska0Emom0Ekarla0Eperez0Ekept0Ecoma0E20Emonths0En351716/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pregnant Nebraska women who became brain dead after suffering a hemorrhage was kept alive in coma for eight weeks so doctors could deliver her baby.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:55:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mom Kept Alive Eight Weeks for Baby Angel's Delivery</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e93066/sc/16/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Cbrain0Edead0Enebraska0Emom0Ekarla0Eperez0Ekept0Ecoma0E20Emonths0En351716/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>A pregnant Nebraska women who became brain dead after suffering a hemorrhage was kept alive in coma for eight weeks so doctors could deliver her baby.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 11:46:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Here's What We Know About the Freddie Gray Case</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e93061/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cbaltimore0Eunrest0Ctimeline0Efreddie0Egray0Ecase0Earrest0Eprotests0En351156/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Gray, 25, died about a week after he was arrested on April 12 in west Baltimore. He suffered a spinal injury while in police custody.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:41:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Freddie Gray Protesters Clash With Cops in Philly</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e9292f/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcphiladelphia0N0Cnews0Clocal0CProtest0ECity0EHall0EEvening0ETransit0E30A18532510Bhtml/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>The protest was one of many happening nationwide in response to the death of Freddie Gray.</Description>
        <MainBody>Close
Embed this video
&lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="UTF-8" src="http://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/portableplayer/?cmsID=302064521&amp;videoID=xMiYfM4oUkkr&amp;origin=nbcphiladelphia.com&amp;sec=news&amp;subsec=local&amp;width=600&amp;height=360"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
More videos (1 of 9)
 
Watch as a police line falls back as protesters push forward as the "Philly Is Baltimore" protest got physical. Most of the protest that marched around Center City on April 30, 2015 was peaceful. (Published Thursday, Apr 30, 2015)
Updated at 11:55 PM EDT on Thursday, Apr 30, 2015
A protest in response to recent events inBaltimore moved from Philadelphia's City Hall around Center City, causing traffic troubles along the way, and leading to confrontations with officers though most of the protest was peaceful.
Around 8 p.m., Philadelphia Police officers -- some on horseback -- and protesters pushed each on roads near the Vine Street Expressway (I-676) as the protest pushed toward the highway. The police line fell at one point and police could be seen cuffing at least one protester who broke through.
'Philly Is Baltimore' Protests Take Over Center City
About 75 minutes later, police blocked the entrance to the Four Seasons Hotel at 18th Street and the Benjamin Franklin Parkway as protesters approached.
The physical altercations came after the demonstration began peacefully at Dilworth Plaza. It wrapped up shortly before 6 p.m. as protesters headed onto city streets -- a large group marched on the streets around City Hall then down Broad Street in the other direction before turning onto Locust Street, winding around Rittenhouse Square and onto Walnut Street where they surrounded a police cruiser before moving along.
'Philly Is Baltimore' Protest Blocks Traffic in Center City, Turns Rowdy
A protest in Philadelphia, in response to the unrest in Baltimore, was mostly peaceful, but at one point turned into a brief clash with police. NBC10's George Spencer reports on the ground with protesters. (Published Thursday, Apr 30, 2015)
There were some verbal arguments during the march but nothing physical until nearly 8 p.m. when police could be seen removing some protesters who became rowdy after the group walked hand-in-hand down 16th Street toward the Vine Street Expressway.
Police then blocked the I-676 ramps to 15th Street as some protesters sat down in the intersection before the confrontations. Traffic continued to move on the highway as protesters eventually broke through the police line but didn't go onto the interstate.
Pa. State Troopers to Assist in Baltimore Amid Protests
After about 20 minutes the crowd began to scatter as police continued to block the ramps to the highway. Hundreds of demonstrators then headed toward Chinatown before moving to 8th and Market streets around 8:45 p.m.
Dozens of police vehicles trailed the protest down Market Street. After going down by the Gallery Mall (8th and Market) the protest cut back north and tried to enter the Four Season Hotel at 18th and Benjamin Franklin Parkway where police on bikes blocked their path.
'Philly Is Baltimore' Protest Told in Pictures
The protest, which appeared to slowly thin out, then meandered back over I-676 and down Vine Street before turning back onto N Broad Street where they approached the Philadelphia School District Building. The continued to become smaller as they demonstrated outside the 9th Police District on 21st Street shortly before 11 p.m.
Police arrested two protesters for disorderly conduct.
'Philly Is Baltimore' Protests Take Over Center City
A smaller group earlier walked up Broad Street toward North Philly.
The demonstration began with dozens of protesters marching along Chestnut Street in University City toward Center City shortly after 4 p.m. Philadelphia Police followed the peaceful protest as it marched.At the same time, the crowd began to grow at Dilworth Plaza -- near City Hall.
Mostly Peaceful Protest Marches Through Center City
A tense moment at Broad and Vine Streets between police and protesters marred a mostly peaceful demonstration around downtown Philadelphia. (Published Thursday, Apr 30, 2015)
As of 5 p.m. the majority of the rally remained at Dilworth Plaza with police estimating 600 to 800 demonstrators taking part.
The protest was one of many happening nationwide in response to the death of Freddie Gray , who suffered spinal injuries while in Baltimore Police custody following his April 12 arrest. Gray later died.
Freddie Gray Investigation Focusing on Transport Van: Source
Some officials warned commuters to plan their evening commute as the large crowd could mess with travel around City Hall and throughout Center City but for the most part things continued to move as normal.
SEPTA officials did not announce any planned detours due to the protest, but acknowledged that they would keep an eye on the proceedings and make adjustments to mass transit schedules if necessary. SEPTA reported several bus routes with delays in Center City.
Commuters planning on driving through Center City should avoid Market Street and Broad Street near City Hall and expect congestion on other nearby roadways. For commuters looking to avoid the crowds, staying completely clear of the area is likely the best option.
Police maintained mostly peaceful boundaries during the demonstration. At least one Philadelphia school announced an early dismissal so students could get home safely.
Published at 1:01 PM EDT on Apr 30, 2015
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:28:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mariota 'Trade That Wasn't' Defines 2015 First Round</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e993e2/sc/13/l/0L0Srotoworld0N0Carticles0Cnfl0C538580C3650Cnfl0Edraft0Eround0E10Erecap0Dcid0Feref0Rnbcnews0Rtext/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Under normal circumstances, mortgaging an entire team for one player is a horrible idea. Chip Kelly was not in a normal circumstance.</Description>
        <MainBody>NFL Draft: Round 1 Recap
Friday, May 01, 2015
Tweet
For the first time since 1965, the NFL draft was not held in New York City. And for the first time in recent memory, it also lacked any real drama.
There were no franchise-altering trades, no poor souls excruciatingly left in the green room to rot and no suspense in the top-two picks. What we did have was a lot of fantasy relevance as two running backs, six wideouts and two quarterbacks came off the board in Thursday nights Round 1. To the headlines:
THE TRADE THAT WASNT
Under normal circumstances, mortgaging an entire team for one player is a horrible idea. Chip Kelly was not in a normal circumstance. Its not often a QB-needy coach running a unique system has a chance to draft his prototypical quarterback. So its not a surprise Chip reportedly offered two first-round picks, a third-round pick, stud DT Fletcher Cox , two plus starters in CB Brandon Boykin /ILB Mychal Kendricks and more for the right to take Marcus Mariota at No. 2. It is a bit of a surprise that the Titans stood pat, declining that massive offer and installing Mariota  a questionable scheme fit for Ken Whisenhunt  as their starter. Mariota would have been a top-12 fantasy quarterback in Philly, but is a guy I wont want to touch in rancid Tennessee. 
MEET YOUR NO. 1 OVERALL PICK
The Bucs left no drama at the top, deciding on Florida States Jameis Winston a while back and never wavering. Hell step right in as a candidate for 4,000 passing yards thanks to Mike Evans , Vincent Jackson , Austin Seferian-Jenkins and OC Dirk Koetter s vertical passing scheme. Remarkably, Winston ate crab legs in a Bucs jersey after he was selected. If that rubs you the wrong way, you need more laughter in your life.
BIGGEST MISS BY MOCK DRAFTERS
I dont think anyone had the Redskins taking Iowa G/T Brandon Scherff at No. 5 overall in their mock. But thats what new GM Scot McCloughan did, living up to his reputation of ignoring group think. He passed on both DT Leonard Williams and OLB Vic Beasley in the process, leaving mock drafters ripping up their sheets. Scherff will play right tackle for Jay Gruden , forming an intimidating bookend with stud left tackle Trent Williams .
FREE FALL OF THE NIGHT
Speaking of USC DT Leonard Williams , he suffered a mini-freefall as he slipped to the Jets at No. 6 overall. Its nothing compared to a Warren Sapp , Aaron Rodgers or Teddy Bridgewater kind of debacle, but we didnt have any of those Thursday night. Williams, who was atop many analysts big boards as the top prospect in this draft, will serve as insurance in case Muhammad Wilkerson is traded or walks in free agency next year. And if Wilkerson stays put, talented defensive mind Todd Bowles will have some serious horses to work with up front in these two plus Sheldon Richardson . Running the football against the Jets is going to be a nightmare.
BY THE NUMBERS
The Eagles, rebuffed in their attempt to land Marcus Mariota , settled for versatile USC WR Nelson Agholor at No. 20 overall. Courtesy of our Evan Silva, heres how Agholor stacks up against ex-Eagle Jeremy Maclin :
Maclin  60/198, 4.48 forty, 10 broad jump, 35  vertical, 7.06 three cone.
Agholor  60/198, 4.42 forty, 105 broad jump, 36  vertical, 6.83 three cone.
As the featured receiver in Chip Kelly s scheme last year Maclin ripped off 85-1,318-10. Agholor wont get close to that as the roles of Jordan Matthews and Zach Ertz will expand, but hes landed in a great spot. Kelly offered Agholor a scholarship to Oregon and knows what hes getting.
HEAD SCRATCHER
In desperate need of toughness, beef up front and defensive players, the Colts used the No. 29 overall pick on 510/185 Miami speed WR Phillip Dorsett . It makes very little sense. Dorsett drew direct comps to T.Y. Hilton during the draft process, and the Colts already have Hilton, Andre Johnson and  Donte Moncrief as receivers. Yes, Hiltons rookie contract is up after this season. But the win-now Colts have such desperate needs elsewhere that going wideout in such a deep wideout class seems wasteful. GM Ryan Grigson continues to live off backing into Andrew Luck with the No. 1 pick in 2012.
BIGGEST EMBARRASSMENT
Roger Goodell took some well-deserved boos as he walked to the podium. Then he stumbled over and mispronounced Marcus Mariota s name, calling him Marioto. Later, Goodell botched Phillip Dorsett s last name. Rotogrinders Justin Van Zuiden wondered what would have happened If Goodell had tried to pronounce Giannis Antetokounmpo.
ALL THE LIES
Throughout the last few months, the Chargers brass insisted they were content with their running back stable of Branden Oliver , Danny Woodhead and Donald Brown . No one really believed them. Then they proved why listening to coach- and GM-speak is so pointless, trading up two spots to select Wisconsin RB Melvin Gordon at No. 15 overall. Gordon projects for a big Year 1 impact, even if Woodhead steals passing down work. Hes healthier than Todd Gurley and faces a far easier schedule.
BIGGEST SURPRISE OF TOP-10
I thought Tre Mason did enough as a rookie to knock running back off the Rams list of biggest needs. I was wrong. Not only did the Rams take a RB, but they took Todd Gurley (ACL) at No. 10 overall. Its high for a running back, even if Jeff Fisher insists Gurley is the best prospect at that position since Adrian Peterson . The Rams have arguably the least talent in the league along their offensive line and Gurleys durability is in doubt. He also plays in a division with two elite run defenses (SEA, ARZ). Meanwhile, fourth-stringer Zac Stacy wants out. Hed be able to run for 1,000 yards if given the chance for a team like the Cowboys.
REMODELED HOME
Its not easy to completely redo a position in one offseason and make it better. The Dolphins managed to do just that, unloading Mike Wallace , Charles Clay and Brian Hartline . They brought in Kenny Stills , Jordan Cameron and Greg Jennings  and then put a cherry on top Thursday night by taking Louisville WR DeVante Parker at No. 14 overall. Id give Parker a long look at 1.03 in Dynasty rookie drafts, behind only Kevin White and Amari Cooper .
DAY 2 PLAYER TO WATCH
Missouri WR Dorial Green-Beckham is 65/237 with 4.49 speed. He has warts both on the field and off, but Im always going to want shares of players with freakish physical gifts. The Titans hold the first pick of the second round and would do well to get Marcus Mariota an upgrade on Kendall Wright / Justin Hunter .
TWEETS OF THE NIGHT
1) Davis Mattek on the Bills decision to trade up for Sammy Watkins last year. Link .
2) The Fantasy Douche on the relative value and positional scarcity of running backs. Link . 
For the first time since 1965, the NFL draft was not held in New York City. And for the first time in recent memory, it also lacked any real drama.
There were no franchise-altering trades, no poor souls excruciatingly left in the green room to rot and no suspense in the top-two picks. What we did have was a lot of fantasy relevance as two running backs, six wideouts and two quarterbacks came off the board in Thursday nights Round 1. To the headlines:
THE TRADE THAT WASNT
Under normal circumstances, mortgaging an entire team for one player is a horrible idea. Chip Kelly was not in a normal circumstance. Its not often a QB-needy coach running a unique system has a chance to draft his prototypical quarterback. So its not a surprise Chip reportedly offered two first-round picks, a third-round pick, stud DT Fletcher Cox , two plus starters in CB Brandon Boykin /ILB Mychal Kendricks and more for the right to take Marcus Mariota at No. 2. It is a bit of a surprise that the Titans stood pat, declining that massive offer and installing Mariota  a questionable scheme fit for Ken Whisenhunt  as their starter. Mariota would have been a top-12 fantasy quarterback in Philly, but is a guy I wont want to touch in rancid Tennessee. 
MEET YOUR NO. 1 OVERALL PICK
The Bucs left no drama at the top, deciding on Florida States Jameis Winston a while back and never wavering. Hell step right in as a candidate for 4,000 passing yards thanks to Mike Evans , Vincent Jackson , Austin Seferian-Jenkins and OC Dirk Koetter s vertical passing scheme. Remarkably, Winston ate crab legs in a Bucs jersey after he was selected. If that rubs you the wrong way, you need more laughter in your life.
BIGGEST MISS BY MOCK DRAFTERS
I dont think anyone had the Redskins taking Iowa G/T Brandon Scherff at No. 5 overall in their mock. But thats what new GM Scot McCloughan did, living up to his reputation of ignoring group think. He passed on both DT Leonard Williams and OLB Vic Beasley in the process, leaving mock drafters ripping up their sheets. Scherff will play right tackle for Jay Gruden , forming an intimidating bookend with stud left tackle Trent Williams .
FREE FALL OF THE NIGHT
Speaking of USC DT Leonard Williams , he suffered a mini-freefall as he slipped to the Jets at No. 6 overall. Its nothing compared to a Warren Sapp , Aaron Rodgers or Teddy Bridgewater kind of debacle, but we didnt have any of those Thursday night. Williams, who was atop many analysts big boards as the top prospect in this draft, will serve as insurance in case Muhammad Wilkerson is traded or walks in free agency next year. And if Wilkerson stays put, talented defensive mind Todd Bowles will have some serious horses to work with up front in these two plus Sheldon Richardson . Running the football against the Jets is going to be a nightmare.
BY THE NUMBERS
The Eagles, rebuffed in their attempt to land Marcus Mariota , settled for versatile USC WR Nelson Agholor at No. 20 overall. Courtesy of our Evan Silva, heres how Agholor stacks up against ex-Eagle Jeremy Maclin :
Maclin  60/198, 4.48 forty, 10 broad jump, 35  vertical, 7.06 three cone.
Agholor  60/198, 4.42 forty, 105 broad jump, 36  vertical, 6.83 three cone.
As the featured receiver in Chip Kelly s scheme last year Maclin ripped off 85-1,318-10. Agholor wont get close to that as the roles of Jordan Matthews and Zach Ertz will expand, but hes landed in a great spot. Kelly offered Agholor a scholarship to Oregon and knows what hes getting.
HEAD SCRATCHER
In desperate need of toughness, beef up front and defensive players, the Colts used the No. 29 overall pick on 510/185 Miami speed WR Phillip Dorsett . It makes very little sense. Dorsett drew direct comps to T.Y. Hilton during the draft process, and the Colts already have Hilton, Andre Johnson and  Donte Moncrief as receivers. Yes, Hiltons rookie contract is up after this season. But the win-now Colts have such desperate needs elsewhere that going wideout in such a deep wideout class seems wasteful. GM Ryan Grigson continues to live off backing into Andrew Luck with the No. 1 pick in 2012.
BIGGEST EMBARRASSMENT
Roger Goodell took some well-deserved boos as he walked to the podium. Then he stumbled over and mispronounced Marcus Mariota s name, calling him Marioto. Later, Goodell botched Phillip Dorsett s last name. Rotogrinders Justin Van Zuiden wondered what would have happened If Goodell had tried to pronounce Giannis Antetokounmpo.
ALL THE LIES
Throughout the last few months, the Chargers brass insisted they were content with their running back stable of Branden Oliver , Danny Woodhead and Donald Brown . No one really believed them. Then they proved why listening to coach- and GM-speak is so pointless, trading up two spots to select Wisconsin RB Melvin Gordon at No. 15 overall. Gordon projects for a big Year 1 impact, even if Woodhead steals passing down work. Hes healthier than Todd Gurley and faces a far easier schedule.
BIGGEST SURPRISE OF TOP-10
I thought Tre Mason did enough as a rookie to knock running back off the Rams list of biggest needs. I was wrong. Not only did the Rams take a RB, but they took Todd Gurley (ACL) at No. 10 overall. Its high for a running back, even if Jeff Fisher insists Gurley is the best prospect at that position since Adrian Peterson . The Rams have arguably the least talent in the league along their offensive line and Gurleys durability is in doubt. He also plays in a division with two elite run defenses (SEA, ARZ). Meanwhile, fourth-stringer Zac Stacy wants out. Hed be able to run for 1,000 yards if given the chance for a team like the Cowboys.
REMODELED HOME
Its not easy to completely redo a position in one offseason and make it better. The Dolphins managed to do just that, unloading Mike Wallace , Charles Clay and Brian Hartline . They brought in Kenny Stills , Jordan Cameron and Greg Jennings  and then put a cherry on top Thursday night by taking Louisville WR DeVante Parker at No. 14 overall. Id give Parker a long look at 1.03 in Dynasty rookie drafts, behind only Kevin White and Amari Cooper .
DAY 2 PLAYER TO WATCH
Missouri WR Dorial Green-Beckham is 65/237 with 4.49 speed. He has warts both on the field and off, but Im always going to want shares of players with freakish physical gifts. The Titans hold the first pick of the second round and would do well to get Marcus Mariota an upgrade on Kendall Wright / Justin Hunter .
TWEETS OF THE NIGHT
1) Davis Mattek on the Bills decision to trade up for Sammy Watkins last year. Link .
2) The Fantasy Douche on the relative value and positional scarcity of running backs. Link . 
Adam Levitan is in his sixth season covering football and basketball for Rotoworld. He won the Fantasy Sports Writers Association award for Best Series in 2011 and 2009, and ESPN's overall fantasy football title in 2000. Find him on Twitter .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:26:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tom Brokaw Remembers the Fall of Saigon</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e92433/sc/7/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cnews0Cus0Enews0Ctom0Ebrokaw0Eremembers0Efall0Esaigon0En351696/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NBC's Tom Brokaw, who was covering the story that night, looks back on one of the most painful chapters in American history.</Description>
        <MainBody>Inspirational stories profiling people making a positive impact on communities around the country and world.
Play All
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:17:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Quake Toll May Climb Up to 15,000: Nepal Army Chief</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e3b71f/sc/11/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cnepal0Eearthquake0Cnepal0Earmy0Echief0En3510A71/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Up to 15,000 people may have died in Nepal's devastating earthquake, according to the official leading the relief effort.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 09:13:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal Offers $1,400 to Families of Quake Victims</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.nbcnews.com/c/35002/f/663303/s/45e88ef2/sc/11/l/0L0Snbcnews0N0Cstoryline0Cnepal0Eearthquake0Cnepal0Eoffering0E10E40A0A0Evictims0Efamilies0Edeath0Etoll0Etops0E60En351671/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Nepal announces that it will offer $1,400 to each family of the more than 6,200 people killed in last week's massive earthquake.</Description>
        <MainBody/>
    </Article>
</site>
