<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:57:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Expletive, threat cause chaos in National Assembly</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Expletive-threat-cause-chaos-in-National-Assembly-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Deputy Trade and Industry Deputy Minister Mzwandile Masina has been accused of threatening a DA MP with violence in the National Assembly.</Description>
        <MainBody>Expletive, threat cause chaos in National Assembly
2015-05-26 21:39
Alicestine October, Media24 Parliamentary Bureau
Mzwandile Masina. (GCIS)
When will you pay back the money? Zuma hears - again
Cape Town  The words I will fuck you up mouthed in the National Assembly on Tuesday threatened to derail the presidencys budget vote speech, Netwerk24 reported.
Deputy Trade and Industry Deputy Minister Mzwandile Masina was allegedly seen mouthing the words to a DA MP.
An expressionless President Jacob Zuma watched from his bench as all hell broke loose, giggling occasionally.
Presiding officer Thoko Didiza said she would have the matter investigated before making a ruling.
DA Chief Whip John Steenhuisen insisted on a ruling. He called Masina a "spineless coward" and his MPs said they were prepared to make sworn statements about his remark.
Masina denied making the threat.
EFF MP Mbuyiseni Ndlozi said Masina was "known to use vulgar language".
Deputy ANC Chief Whip Doris Dlakude called on Steenhuisen to withdraw the spineless coward remark, saying it was unparliamentary. He acknowledged he had said it and stood by it.
Somewhere from the opposition benches someone shouted that Steenhuisen was a real man and not a spineless coward.
IFP Chief Whip Narend Singh stressed the seriousness of the allegations and said they had to be investigated to protect the National Assemblys decorum.
When Masina stood up to resume his speech, he attacked DA parliamentary leader Mmusi Maimane .
A spineless coward is someone who quotes president Mbeki and president Mandela, but is too scared to quote Helen Suzman , who belongs to them, he said.
Earlier, a joke from Science and Technology Minister Naledi Pandor also threatened to derail the debate. She joked about an SMS that EFF leader Julius Malema had sent her, asking her to remind EFF MPs to hold their Marikana posters up high.
During the debate EFF MPs had held up posters with the words #releasemarikanareport.
Didiza reminded MPs to respect the debate.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:58:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Rhino horns seized in Mozambique's 'biggest bust' stolen</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/Green/News/Rhino-horns-seized-in-Mozambiques-biggest-bust-stolen-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Sixty-five rhino horns that were seized in an operation heralded as "Mozambique's biggest breakthrough in the war on illegal wildlife trafficking", have been stolen.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rhino horns seized in Mozambique's 'biggest bust' stolen
2015-05-26 22:45
Simon Bloch, News24 Correspondent
(File: AFP)
Poachers target rhino calves
Cape Town - Sixty-five rhino horns that were seized in an operation heralded as "Mozambique's biggest breakthrough in the war on illegal wildlife trafficking", have been stolen.
According to reports the horns were stolen from the strong-room at the premises of the Police Provincial Command in Mozambique, which was secured with just three padlocks, in the early hours of Friday morning.
Six people have since been arrested in connection with the stolen horns, with an estimated street value of R76m.
The horns were most likely hacked from animals slaughtered in the Kruger National Park.
The nationalities of those arrested are not known, and there is no indication if the horns were recovered.?
Shortly after the approximately 124kg horns were reported missing, newly-elected PresidentFelipe Nyusi, addressed a police parade to mark the 40th anniversary of the creation of the Mozambican police force. 
During his speech he said: "The news of policemen who join the ranks of the criminals, particularly when I am told that they have the necessary training so as not to commit the crimes they have embraced, deprives me of sleep.
"When policemen are caught in the gangs trafficking in rhinoceros horns, elephant tusks, and various drugs, or facilitate these same crimes, I am unable to sleep, Nyusi continued.
"I cannot sleep when the statistics show an increasing number of police involved in crime."
The rhino horns were seized along with 340 elephant tusks, weighing over 1000kg, in what was the countrys biggest find of illegal wildlife products.
In reaction to the operation prominent environmental activist Carlos Serra said: "It [the recovered horns] should be destroyed to send a message to the world that... we are shifting to another level of intervention in the fight against poaching."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:39:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Dept must take schools' policies into account - judge</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Dept-must-take-schools-policies-into-account-judge-20150526</Link>
        <Description>The High Court in Johannesburg has ordered that the Gauteng Department of Education must take into account schools' admission and language policies when dealing with admission of pupils for 2016.</Description>
        <MainBody>Dept must take schools' policies into account - judge
2015-05-26 21:39
Ahmed Areff, News24
Gauteng school wins language battle
Johannesburg - The High Court in Johannesburg on Tuesday ordered that the Gauteng Department of Education must take into account schools' admission and language policies when dealing with admission of pupils for 2016.
"Schools are entitled to prepare waiting lists A and B [for pupils]... In doing so, schools may take into account their admission and language policies," Judge Gregory Wright said.
"The district director and head of department [of education] must, when considering the lists, take into account, along with other relevant and lawful considerations, the schools' admission and language policies."
The Federation of Governing Bodies of SA Schools' (Fedsas) had applied for urgent application to halt the department's centralised admissions process and its plan to convert single-medium schools to parallel-medium schools.
Fedsas argues that these unlawfully interfere with the powers of schools' governing bodies in determining the language of teaching and the schools' admission policies.
Wright said his order would operate pending the final determination of "part B" of the application, which dealt with the plan to convert schools, which would be heard at a later stage.
"The question of costs is reserved for determination by the court hearing part B."
Gauteng Education MEC Panyaza Lesufi recently announced plans to convert 124 single-medium schools into parallel-medium schools.
It later emerged from a leaked list of the schools that the plan primarily involved Afrikaans single-medium schools.
After the order was handed down, Greta Engelbrecht, also for Fedsas, said that this basically ensured that the department had to consider schools' policies.
"They will also have to look at other considerations, such as the National Language Policy and the Constitution," she said.
"The court will hear in future whether the decision to turn single medium schools into parallel medium schools was lawful."
Gauteng education spokesperson Phumla Sekonyane said the department was unhappy with the order.
"This means that language and admission policies [of schools] supersedes the right to education," she said outside the court.
"We will be appealing."
The department told the court earlier that it had not yet implemented a plan to convert single-medium school into parallel-medium schools.
"We argue that there is no absolutely no decision that constitutes administrative action [on converting schools]," Muzi Sikhakhane SC for the department and Lesufi said.
Sikhakhane addressed the matter of the list.
"Let's put aside that it was leaked. We have said this repeatedly... it was a internal discussion document to discuss the problems in Gauteng," he said.
"We have been brought here on an urgent basis, on a fear that has no basis whatsoever. There has been no decision [on converting schools] yet.
"The applicants are only concerned with those students who speak Afrikaans. The department has to focus on everyone. The prescripts of the schools need to be in line with the distribution of resources."
He said that in terms of admissions, Fedsas made the mistake of not seeing the school, the department's district directors and the head of the department (HOD) as "part of the same chain".
"The Schools' Act is clear that that the function of admission... is a process of the HOD - anyone who does it, even up to the school principals, does it because they are an extension of that statutory function," Sikhakhane said.
Wright asked Johan Du Toit SC, for Fedsas, that if the department's policy was to "spread the resources from the privileged few in the past to everyone equally now", would that policy be in line with the Constitution.
"It is a laudable action... but the school's assets belong to the school. One cannot come from outside and take assets from one school and give it to another," Du Toit responded.
He gave the example of the department coming to school that had 10 computers, and giving five to a school that did not have anything.
Wright then asked: "You say it is laudable, does that mean you are saying it is Constitutional? It can't be laudable and not Constitutional.
"If the applicant's schools' policies have the effect - intended or otherwise - of retarding the rate at which resources are spread. Are they Constitutional?
"They are Constitutional," Du Toit responded.
Read more on:  fedsas | johannesburg | education
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:39:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Journalists manhandled, threatened by Joburg cops - Sanef</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Journalists-manhandled-threatened-by-Joburg-cops-Sanef-20150526</Link>
        <Description>A cameraman and a photographer have allegedly been manhandled by metro police officers in the Johannesburg city centre, the SA National Editors’ Forum says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Journalists manhandled, threatened by Joburg cops - Sanef
2015-05-26 21:39
Thomas Hartleb, News24
Johannesburg Metro Police. (File)
Sanef condemns continued harassment of journalists
Johannesburg  A cameraman and a photographer were allegedly manhandled by metro police officers in the Johannesburg city centre on Tuesday, the SA National Editors Forum (Sanef) said.
The officers manhandled and threatened eNCA cameraman Pierre le Roux and Beeld photographer Cornel van Heerden after they photographed and filmed the arrest of an alleged drunk driver outside the High Court in Johannesburg, Sanef media freedom sub-committee chairperson Adriaan Basson said in a statement.
Two JMPD [Johannesburg Metro Police Department] officers became aggressive and told the journalists they had no right to be there and should stop filming and taking pictures. A scuffle ensued during which one officer grabbed Le Rouxs camera.
The equipment was damaged during the scuffle. The officer threatened to arrest Le Roux and detain him in the JMPD vehicle with the alleged drunk driver. Van Heerden was also accosted by a JMPD officer, but managed to get away.
When a JMPD officer in civilian clothes arrived, his colleagues let the journalists go.
This behaviour is completely unacceptable and an infringement of the constitutional rights of journalist to do their work in a free and open society, Basson said.
JMPD spokesperson Wayne Minnaar said the two needed to provide statements detailing where and when it happened so the footage from CCTV cameras in the area could be reviewed.
Basson, who is also Beeld editor, said he would meet Le Roux on Wednesday to discuss what to do, adding that it would be a good idea to co-operate with the JMPD, in order to catch the culprits.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:31:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Stormers’ fierce scrap for semi</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Rugby/Super15/Stormers-fierce-scrap-for-semi-20150526</Link>
        <Description>The Waratahs may just nose out the Stormers to the crucial second home semi-final spot this season, feels </Description>
        <MainBody>Stormers fierce scrap for semi
2015-05-26 22:21
Cheetahs v Stormers (Gallo Images)
Related Links
Lions hooker cops 3-game ban
Rob Houwing, Sport24 chief writer
Cape Town  Its virtually certain the runaway Hurricanes will claim gold at the end of Super Rugbys ordinary season ... the battle for important silver looks hugely more exciting over the remaining three weekends.
Thats also where South African interest comes in, with the Stormers looking best shout from the domestic conference to grab the second home semi-final berth  even as they show a stubborn, mystifying lack of urgency over the accumulation of bonus points which could yet tilt the deal.
As much as anything, they are being a bit naive in historical terms if they continue to believe that just winning the conference, even if it means ending unfavourable third overall, gives them a rosy chance of advancing to the elusive title.
They would be defying the record books if they lift the overall silverware from that position; only sides finishing ordinary season first or second have gone on to achieve that.
Heres a quick reminder of how the title has been decided, since the advent of the three-group system in 2011:
First year: Reds champions, after topping ordinary-season table. Fate of third-placed team: Crusaders won two KO matches, but lost final.
2012: Chiefs champions, after ending second to Stormers in ordinary season. Fate of third-placed team: Reds knocked out in first KO round.
2013: Chiefs champions, after topping ordinary-season table. Fate of third-placed team: Brumbies won two KO matches, but lost final.
2014: Waratahs champions, after topping ordinary-season table. Fate of third-placed team: Sharks won first KO fixture, but beaten semi-finalists.
It must not be forgotten that both the Bulls (particularly) and Lions retain fighting chances of winning the SA conference, but with most experts acknowledging that the Stormers look healthiest prospects with three rounds to go, lets examine their chances of completing the task in coveted second place overall  thus handily bypassing a knockout round into a guaranteed home semi.
Given that the next best two New Zealand sides to the Hurricanes dubiously cant end in second or third by tournament stipulation, the Stormers appear to be engaged in a titanic battle with Australians the Waratahs and Brumbies for that runner-up spot to the Canes.
Sheer logic suggests the Tahs, the recently inconsistent but still strongly-staffed defending champions, are a whisker ahead in this likely three-way race: they are three points better off (41 from 13 games) than the other two. The Stormers and Brumbies have 38 apiece, also from 13.
Simply put, if the Waratahs keep winning over the next three weekends, they really ought to shut the others out and safely bank that Sydney semi  it is a fair old incentive to have.
Making that task reasonably tricky, however, is the fact not only that they have a mere one home game remaining (last round, against the Reds) but that the two away fixtures are on a South African mini-tour.
But they also sidestep the traditional three biggest SA franchises on the venture and, with the greatest of respect to the Lions (the opposition in a pivotal Johannesburg game for both sides this Saturday night) and Cheetahs, the Aussie outfit will not feel overawed either at Emirates Airline Park or the Free State Stadium and should believe they can prevail in both if they play to Wallaby-laden potential.
As for the Stormers, bracing themselves for Newlands games against the Cheetahs and Lions and then a dangerous last-day duel with the nothing-to-lose Sharks in Durban, they will have decidedly mixed emotions over Johan Ackermanns charges within the next fortnight or so.
First up, they will probably be praying the Lions can knock over the Waratahs, which would be a major boost to their Cape Town semi hopes ... but then their love affair with the red-and-whites will come to a very rapid end, when they tackle those very foes in the shadow of Table Mountain.
What about the Brumbies, though? These two-time champions of the competition, albeit the last time having been in 2004, share with the Stormers not only the same tally of points but knowledge that two of their last three fixtures are at home.
Theyll need a slip somewhere from the Waratahs to have a proper chance of seizing the Australian conference, but successive games against the Bulls, Force (the sole away one, in Perth) and fickle Crusaders arent ridiculously scary for them.
After all, when the Bulls visit Canberra this Friday (11:40 SA time) they do so having been infuriatingly inept and indecisive in two prior tour games in New Zealand and sitting on a swelling run of nine overseas losses on the trot.
Its a white-knuckle ride, you can be pretty sure, for that precious runner-up slot ahead of the knockout phase.
I hope for Allister Coetzees sake that his try-averse Stormers charges dont get nudged out by a single point or thereabouts, because that might open up a significant cry over spilled milk ... er, sorry, spilled bonus points.
*Follow our chief writer on Twitter: @RobHouwing
Follow Us:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:06:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Militants lay siege to guesthouse in Afghanistan capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Militants-lay-siege-to-guesthouse-in-Afghanistans-capital-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Heavy gunfire and explosions echoed through an upmarket  neighbourhood in Kabul,  as Afghan police surrounded a guesthouse popular with foreigners thought to be under attack by insurgents.</Description>
        <MainBody>Militants lay siege to guesthouse in Afghanistan capital
2015-05-26 22:54
Afghanistan-flag
SA doctor still in Afghanistan after family killed
Kabul - Heavy gunfire and explosions echoed through an upmarket neighbourhood in Afghanistan's capital late on Tuesday night, as police surrounded a guesthouse popular with foreigners thought to be under attack by insurgents.
The firefight in the Wazir Akbar Khan neighbourhood, which is home to several embassies, sounded to be focused on the Rabbani Guesthouse. It began just after 23:00, with heavy explosions accompanying sporadic automatic weapon fire.
Police could not be immediately reached for comment, though officers could be seen blocking off roads into the area. Police officers later smashed lights throughout the upscale neighbourhood to cover their movements.
Deputy Interior Minister Mohammad Aub Salangi said a guesthouse appeared to be the target of the attack, without specifically naming the Rabbani. He said two attackers had been killed and that authorities didn't know how many were involved in the assault.
The guesthouse, once known as the Heetal Hotel, was damaged in a December 2009 suicide car bomb attack near the home of former Afghan vice president Ahmad Zia Massoud - brother of legendary anti-Taliban fighter Ahmad Shah Massoud, who was killed in an al-Qaeda suicide bombing two days before the 9/11 attacks. That 2009 attack killed eight people and wounded nearly 40.
The hotel is owned by the Rabbani family, who include Burhanuddin Rabbani, who served as president of Afghanistan from 1992 until 1996, and current Foreign Minister Salahuddin Rabbani.
No one immediately claimed responsibility for the attack, which comes amid intensified fighting across many parts of Afghanistan since the Taliban launched their warm weather offensive a month ago.
Taliban militants attacked a guesthouse days earlier this month in Kabul, killing an American, a British citizen, an Italian, four Indian nationals, five Afghans and two Pakistanis. The United Nations already has documented a record high number of civilian casualties - 974 killed and 1 963 injured - in the first four months of 2015, a 16% increase over the same period last year.
Afghan security forces have been struggling to fend off Taliban attacks since US and Nato forces formally concluded their combat mission at the end of last year.
Read more on:  afghanistan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:59:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Channel24.co.za | Francois van Coke announces exciting shows as his video exceeds 500 000 views on YouTube</title>
        <Link>http://www.channel24.co.za/Music/News/Francois-van-Coke-announces-exciting-shows-as-his-video-exceeds-500-000-views-on-YouTube-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Francois van Coke's music video for </Description>
        <MainBody>Francois van Coke announces exciting shows as his video exceeds 500 000 views on YouTube
2015-05-26 21:59
Francois van Coke. (Photo: Jaco S Venter)
Related Links


Cape Town - Dominating the countrys national headlines on 8 April were grave reports of xenophobia, the Eskom power crisis and protesters chaining themselves to the Paul Kruger statue in Pretoria.
On 8 April Francois van Coke and Karen Zoid released arguably the most beautiful ballad of the year, Toe Vind Ek Jou. This song instantly captured thousands of hearts all over the country, switching on a light in the dark.
Last week the music video for Toe Vind Ek Jou reached well over 500 000 views in little over a month.
Francois believes that the success of this song lies in its openhearted honesty.
With the release of Francois self-titled debut solo album he bravely embarked on a new journey and its paying off. According to the Kia Top40 SA with iTunes show Saturdays on 947 and KFM, Toe Vind Ek Jou is the first South African release to hit the Number 1 spot this year and the first Afrikaans Number 1. This show is based solely on the live Top 40 songs chart on the South Africa iTunes Store.
A month after the release, the album and single was at the Number 2 position on 8 May and is still on the Top 10.
This single and album still dominates radio charts across the country and the SA Top 20 top sellers chart, where the album has been on the Top 10 for four weeks.
The Francois van Coke Live Experience
Francois shows with his live band, Jedd Kossew (Van Coke Kartel) on lead guitar, Richard Onraet (Jesse Clegg) on rhythm guitar, Rudolph Willemse on bass and keyboard and Sheldon Yoko (Die Heuwels Fantasties) on drums, have been a raging success. The last album launch show at Ridgeback in Centurion recently burst out of its seams with a double over-capacity attendance. Everybody wants to share a piece of the Francois van Coke live experience.
Francois van Coke and his live band have been confirmed to play at Oppikoppi later this year. Before then he is off to Amsterdam and then London for a couple of shows in June and will play some hot blooded rock n roll shows with Karen Zoid in July. Francois will undertake a tour in October with his full band again.
The first stop on Francois European trip will be at one of the most popular alternative music venues and nightclubs in Amsterdam, Paradiso, on 13 June. Click here for more info.
While in Amsterdam, Francois will shoot his second music video, Behoort Aan Niemand Nie, with his long-time friend, Johan Nel, who is responsible for several of Fokofpolisiekars music videos. Three more music videos will be released before the end of this year.
Francois and Jedd Kossew will play two shows in London. He will perform at Orange Bull on 19 June and at Zulu Bull on 20 June. Click here for more info.
The shows everyone has been waiting for:
Francois van Coke &amp; Karen Zoid  Toe Vind Ek Jou
This winning combination will perform together at Artscape, Cape Town on 12 July and at the Atterbury Theatre on 23, 24 and 25 July. The Atterbury shows were sold-out in record time and Artscape tickets will go on sale from Computicket on 1 June.
Details:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:26:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US airman shoots Wal-Mart workers, kills self</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/US-airman-shoots-Wal-Mart-workers-kills-self-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Police say a US airman opened fire on workers at Wal-Mart before turning the gun on himself.</Description>
        <MainBody>US airman shoots Wal-Mart workers, kills self
2015-05-26 23:26
College 'shooter' says he's neo-Nazi, hates gays
Grand Forks - A US airman walked into a Wal-Mart Supercenter in North Dakota early on Tuesday and opened fire with a handgun, killing one worker and injuring a second before turning the gun on himself, police said.
Grand Forks Police said the shooting that occurred a few minutes after 13:00 may have been random, with no link yet found between Marcell Willis, 21, and either the store or the employees.
"We've not been able to find any linkage to him and any of the victims. That's not to say that can't change," police Lt Derik Zimmel said during an afternoon news conference. "There's no apparent motive that jumps out at this time."
Authorities did not immediately identify the two workers who were shot or a third worker they say Willis shot at but missed. The injured person was hospitalised with a gunshot wound that was not believed to be life-threatening, Zimmel said. A hospital spokesperson said the person was listed in "satisfactory condition" on Tuesday afternoon.
Willis was given medical treatment at the scene and taken to the hospital, where he was pronounced dead, Zimmel said.
Willis was the only person with a gun and no police officers fired a weapon, according to Zimmel. A handgun was recovered near Willis' body, Zimmel said.
The Wal-Mart is one of two in the northeastern North Dakota city of about 55 000 people. The store is open 24 hours, though it was closed on Tuesday while authorities investigated the shooting. The company said it did not know when the store would reopen.
Read more on:  wal-mart | us
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:56:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | World must decarbonise - UN climate chief</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/Green/News/World-must-decarbonise-UN-climate-chief-20150526</Link>
        <Description>The UN climate chief says a decarbonised world is now irreversible, irrefutable.</Description>
        <MainBody>World must decarbonise - UN climate chief
2015-05-26 22:56
Megan Rowling
Christiana Figueres. (Woohae Cho, AFP)
UN climate chief hails US power plant plan
Barcelona - Responding to climate change in the next 15 years is the world's "mega development project", given the need to invest trillions of dollars in infrastructure, creating jobs and economic stability, the United Nations' top climate change official said on Tuesday.
"It makes fundamental economic sense" for countries to push forward on tackling climate change because of the benefits it will bring in terms of food, water and energy, as well as employment," Christiana Figueres told a carbon market conference in Barcelona.
This, together with the speed at which businesses are acting on climate change and efforts to put a price on carbon, mean "a decarbonised world is now irreversible, irrefutable," the head of the UN climate change secretariat told the conference.
"We are going to do it, because frankly we don't have any other option," she said.
Decarbonisation refers to shifting from fossil fuels to renewable energy sources, and improving energy efficiency, in order to cut planet-warming emissions to a net zero.
Rachel Kyte, the World Bank's special envoy for climate change, said to decarbonise economies, "we will need to begin with extraordinary ambition at the end of this year" in Paris where countries are due to agree a new global deal to tackle climate change.
Experts say the national plans countries are now compiling for that deal are unlikely to add up to the reductions in greenhouse gas emissions needed to keep global warming to an internationally agreed limit of 2 degrees Celsius.
Market mechanism needed
Market mechanisms, such as carbon taxes and emissions trading schemes, would be key in mobilising a global response on a big-enough scale, Kyte said.
"Every country will need to manage an orderly transition to low-carbon growth and resilient development," she said, adding that carbon pricing would be one necessary element of that transition.
On Tuesday, the World Bank said in a report that emission trading schemes were worth an estimated $34bn on April 1, up from $32bn in 2014, while the value of carbon taxes around the world amounted to about $14bn.
Countries introducing such initiatives include developing nations such as China, Mexico and South Africa.
Putting a price on carbon would be the foundation for unlocking investment in low-carbon economies "with hope for jobs and competitiveness - not a picture of sacrifice and of loss and giving things up", Kyte said.
The Paris agreement should send an "unequivocal signal" that markets will play a key role in tackling climate change and underscore the need to "get prices right", she said.
That would enable the current bottom-up patchwork of carbon pricing initiatives in some 40 nations and over 20 cities, states and regions to grow even faster, she added.
Carbon markets have struggled in recent years, with prices plummeting due to a lack of demand amid uncertainty over how the world planned to tackle climate change.
The UN's Figueres said constructing a new international framework to curb global warming was going to be more complex than earlier thought.
"We are currently in an era of transition - a construction site if you will," she said.
"By definition, transitions and construction sites are messy and that is a good thing, because everybody is trying to figure out how...they move forward."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:55:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Moroccan charity chief jailed for child trafficking</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/Africa/News/Moroccan-charity-chief-jailed-for-child-trafficking-20150526</Link>
        <Description>A Moroccan woman who used to head a charity has been jailed for two years for trafficking in abandoned children.</Description>
        <MainBody>Moroccan charity chief jailed for child trafficking
2015-05-26 22:55
(AP)
Abortion laws changed in Morocco
Rabat - A Moroccan woman who used to head a charity has been jailed for two years for trafficking in abandoned children, the national MAP news agency reported on Tuesday.
It said the woman in her 50s, who was not identified, was also fined about $500 by a court at Khenifra in the centre of the North African country.
She was sentenced for "her involvement in the trafficking of abandoned children" while "head of a local charity", MAP cited judicial sources as saying.
She had been in custody since March after being caught red-handed offering a woman "the adoption of a minor in exchange for money", it said.
The charity she headed has since been dissolved.
Moroccan courts in 2013 dealt with 5 377 cases of abandoned children, or nearly 15 per day, the justice ministry has said.
The government has introduced initiatives aimed at combating the problem, notably by encouraging families to adopt abandoned children.
According to a 2011 report, there are nearly 30 000 cases a year in Morocco of single women giving birth.
In seven out of 10 such cases the fathers are aware of the births, but most refuse to recognise the children as their own.
Read more on:  morocco
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:41:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US sends huge food aid shipment to Sudan</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/Africa/News/US-sends-huge-food-aid-shipment-to-Sudan-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Nearly 50 000 tons of US food aid bound for areas of Sudan affected by conflict has arrived in the country, the UN World Food Programme said.</Description>
        <MainBody>US sends huge food aid shipment to Sudan
2015-05-26 21:41
US gives $180m for food in South Sudan
Port Sudan - Nearly 50 000 tons of US food aid bound for areas of Sudan affected by conflict arrived in the country on Tuesday, the UN World Food Programme said.
"The US vessel Liberty Grace docked in Port Sudan carrying 47 500 tons of sorghum, a household food staple in Sudan," the WFP said in a statement.
The aid from the United States Agency for International Development would help "conflict-affected communities and other food insecure and vulnerable groups", the WFP said.
The huge tanker was moored in Port Sudan on the country's Red Sea coast on Tuesday as dozens of dockworkers unloaded sacks of the grain onto trucks.
Washington's charge d'affaires in Khartoum, Jerry Lanier, visited with a delegation from his embassy to see the shipment's arrival.
From Port Sudan, the WFP will distribute the sorghum around the country, particularly to the western region of Darfur.
President Omar al-Bashir has been battling insurgents in the western region of Darfur since 2003, as well as in Blue Nile and South Kordofan states since 2011.
Ethnic insurgents in Darfur launched an uprising against Bashir's Arab-dominated government in 2003, complaining their region was being economically and politically marginalised.
The conflict has killed 300 000 people and forced more than 2.5 million from their homes, according to the UN.
Some 4.4 million people across Darfur's five states require varying degrees of food assistance, the UN says.
Deadly tribal clashes, disputes over land and resources and rising criminality in parts of Darfur has further complicated the conflict.
Bashir, who was re-elected in April and will be inaugurated next week, is wanted by the International Criminal Court over war crimes charges in Darfur.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:15:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Health24.com | Noakes' 'real food' may not be kid friendly</title>
        <Link>http://www.health24.com/Parenting/Child/Nutrition/Noakes-real-food-may-not-be-kid-friendly-20150526</Link>
        <Description>A dietician tells </Description>
        <MainBody>26 May 2015
Noakes' 'real food' may not be kid friendly
A dietician tells Health24 why a low carbohydrate, high fat diet as promoted by Professor Tim Noakes may not be appropriate for infants and children.
Kerryn Gibson is a sports and paediatric dietician and Wonderbag Ambassador. (Image supplied)~
Related
Baby born as truck kills mother
Professor Tim Noakes , who encourages a low carbohydrate, high fat eating plan, also known as Banting, maintains that infants should be started on this diet as soon as they are weaned. However, a dietician specialising in paediatric nutrition says it is not as clear cut.
Noakes will be Tim -Noakes-to-face-inquiry-over-Banting-tweet-20150421"&gt;appearing before the Health Professions Council of South Africa (HPCSA) after advising a mother to wean her child on LCHF foods, which he calls "real foods".
Read: Tim -Noakes-to-face-inquiry-over-Banting-tweet-20150421"&gt; Tim Noakes to face inquiry over 'Banting' tweet
This was his recommendation to a mother over a year ago on Twitter, which resulted in a complaint being lodged with the HPCSA by the Association for Dietetics in South Africa's (ADSA) president Claire Julsing-Strydom. The two-day enquiry will take place in Cape Town on June 4 and 5 and Noakes is quite optimistic about it.
"A low carbohydrate, high fat diet as promoted by Professor Tim Noakes is not always easy to prepare in a way that is acceptable to infants and children," says Kerryn Gibson.
New tastes and textures
She told Health24 that the process of weaning involves the introduction of new tastes and textures to an infant's diet. "Weaning is also a way for infants to learn how to eat. The texture of weaning foods is extremely important to get right in order for the foods to be accepted and easily swallowed by infants. This factor often determines the type of food used."
According to Noakes, in order to maximise your infant's future prospects you need to maximise the brain growth during their first two years. "You cant do that with a high carbohydrate, cereal-based diet lacking in the real foods promoted by the LCHF/Banting diet promoted in the Real Meal Revolution," he told Health24.
Gibson concurs with Noakes that the nutritional value of real or natural foods is far superior compared to processed, convenience foods.
Stay away from processed foods
Preferably no processed or refined foods should be used to feed infants and children. Ideally only real or natural food stuffs that have not undergone any level of processing or refinement should be used," she said.
"All of the convenience baby cereals and foods on the market are processed and refined. There are better food options to feed an infant. However, preparing all of an infants meals and foods from scratch using natural, real and fresh ingredients involves a lot of time, planning and preparation."
Gibson pointed out that as much as a mother would like to do this for her child, it can sometimes be impossible. "A mother should not be made to feel inadequate or made to feel guilty for not preparing all of her babys foods from scratch."
She said store bought baby foods offer a convenient way to start introducing an infant to foods, especially with most mothers having to work as well.
Leaving out carbohydrates
"Carbohydrates must not be excluded from any infants or childs diet," recommended Gibson. "They provide valuable energy, vitamins and fibre."
She added that carbohydrates must, however, be from real, natural and unprocessed sources. Good examples of these include sweet potato, white potato, rolled oats, cooked porridge, legumes, fresh fruit and fresh vegetables.
Gibson explained that the fibre content of natural or real carbohydrate foods helps to maintain our gut flora, which maintains our gut integrity and overall health by strengthening our immune systems. "Refined carbohydrates will not offer this benefit."
Noakes also noted that although breast milk is important for infants, it is iron deficient. "Breast milk is a good source of many nutrients for the infant brain, but it is iron deficient and iron is a crucial brain specific nutrient," he said.
Sources of iron
He added: "Meat and liver are the best source of iron, much better than 'iron-fortified cereals' since iron absorption is poor from cereal-based foods, however much they are enriched." 
From 6 months of age breast milk becomes insufficient as a sole source of nutrition for infants, said Gibson. Breast milk will not provide an infant with the mineral iron and, therefore, iron rich foods must be introduced, especially if an infant is being exclusively breastfed. Liver, chickpeas and spinach are affordable and easily obtained real, natural food options high in iron."
Although, the bioavailability of iron is best from animal sources, she said plant-based sources should not be excluded.
"Apart from liver, other animal protein sources that will be high in iron are difficult to pure to the appropriate texture." She said infants will gag and regurgitate foods if they are the incorrect consistency.
Infants and children do have high protein requirements for growth, said Gibson. They must receive foods high in protein at least twice a day, she advised. "These foods should, however, not replace other foods like vegetables, fruit and starches.
Helping with brain development
Gibson added that omega 3 is extremely important for growing infants and children as it helps with brain development. She said the best source is from oily fish such as sardines or pilchards, mackerel, salmon and fresh tuna.
"These should be introduced as early as possible in an infants diet but at an appropriate age when an infant is ready to swallow the texture of these foods."
When Health24 asked Noakes if age is a factor in children eating LCHF foods, his answer was: "No, infants are designed to be more ketotic than adults. Ketosis is promoted by high fat low carbohydrate diets."
Ketosis is a state the body goes into if it needs to break down body fat for energy.
"Infants use ketones to build the substance of their brains. Without sufficient ketones, infant brains cannot develop to their optimum extent," said Noakes.
Each child is an individual
However, Gibson was a bit more cautious. "There are some situations where promoting ketosis is beneficial for some children; however, this should not be applied to all children," she said. "Each child is individual and their food intake should also be."
She advised parents against following a specific diet for their children and rather to encourage healthy eating habits.
"One of our jobs as parents is to teach our children how to eat and to establish healthy eating habits. We should not be encouraging them to follow any specific 'diet'.
"Children should not be taught that any food, especially foods that are real and natural, is either 'high carb' or 'high fat' and therefore good or bad. Rather we should teach our children which types of foods are beneficial to health and which types of foods are to be seen as normal to be eaten on a daily basis," Gibson concluded.
Also read:
Pro low carb diets:
Tim -Noakes-on-carbohydrates-20120721"&gt; Tim Noakes on how it works and why this is a lifestyle more than a diet
Tim -Noakes-diet-put-to-the-test-20130210"&gt; Tim Noakes diet is put to the test
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:09:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Houston submerged after wild weather</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Houston-submerged-after-wild-weather-20150526-2</Link>
        <Description>Torrential rain has left large parts of Houston submerged and trapped fans at an NBA basketball game.</Description>
        <MainBody>Houston submerged after wild weather
2015-05-26 21:09
Heavy rain overnight caused flooding and closure of sections of highways in the Houston area. (David J Phillip, AP)
Tornadoes kill at least 17 in US
Houston - Torrential rain left large parts of Houston submerged on Tuesday and trapped fans at an NBA basketball game, in savage weather that has killed nearly 20 people in the United States and Mexico.
The southern US states of Texas and Oklahoma, and far northern Mexico, have borne the brunt of several days of wild weather, including tornadoes, which have destroyed homes, seen rivers swell to record levels and left cars submerged on highways.
More than 250mm of heavy rain fell in just a few hours in the Texas city of Houston, triggering the worst flooding there in at least a decade and stranding at an arena spectators who had gone to watch a Houston Rockets basketball game on Monday night.
Images from a local CBS affiliate in Houston showed abandoned cars entirely submerged on roadways and flooded streets abandoned. Some people were trapped in their cars, other marooned in their homes.
One person died overnight in the flooding in the city, local media reported.
Downtown Houston, where the Toyota Center arena is located, was not under water, said Mayor Annise Parker, but some fans had been unable to get home from the NBA game after the deluge.
"We had a torrential downpour as the game was ending and a lot of folks were asked to stay until the rain let up and there was localised street flooding," Parker told CNN.
Fears were growing meanwhile for at least 12 people missing in Hays County, also in Texas, officials said.
One person was already confirmed dead there and two more died in Oklahoma, which is located to the north of Texas.
South of the border, Mexico has also felt Mother Nature's wrath.
A savage twister roared through the Mexican border town of Ciudad Acuna at dawn on Monday, killing at least 13 people and flattening hundreds of homes in a deadly six-second blast of carnage, officials said.
Images from the aftermath showed several crumpled vehicles resting against walls and roofs as shellshocked inhabitants of the town of 136 000 struggled to make sense of the devastation.
Read more on:  us | weather
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:00:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Channel24.co.za | If Chris Brown can't date Karrueche Tran then no one can!</title>
        <Link>http://www.channel24.co.za/Gossip/News/If-Chris-Brown-cant-date-Karrueche-Tran-then-no-one-can-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Chris Brown reportedly reacted badly to his ex-girlfriend Karrueche Tran's selfie with Tyson Beckford as he doesn't want her to date anyone else.</Description>
        <MainBody>If Chris Brown can't date Karrueche Tran then no one can!
2015-05-26 21:00

Chris Brown is not happy that Karrueche Tran is hanging out with other guys. (Greatstock/Splash and Instagram)
Related Links

Los Angeles - Chris Brown doesn't want Karrueche Tran to date anyone else.
The 27-year-old model got the attention of her ex-boyfriend after Tyson Beckford posted a selfie of the pair together.
A photo posted by Tyson C. Beckford (@tysoncbeckford) on
May 23, 2015 at 7:35pm PDT
A source shared: "He basically told Karrueche that it makes him look like a fool and less of a man when she's out partying with other men.
'He told her that 'ain't cool' and that he still loves her and wanted to express his love for her in his own way."
But the Loyal hitmaker is said to have angered Karrueche over the "crazy" feud.
Another insider added to HollywoodLife.com: 'This is one of those crazy and over-the-top incidents that Karrueche's shaking her head over. For starters, she's not with Chris. Secondly, she thinks he's doing way too much.
"It's cute ... if you're in high school. The only drama Karrueche wants in her life are the scripts she has to read for a role. Other than that, she hates all the drama.
"She's actually trying to establish a successful name for herself and launch a serious career in Hollywood and antics like this don't help.
"She doesn't want or need any of this nonsense from Chris and she's already told him that after this incident."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:03:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Chester: Write off Boks at own peril</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Rugby/Springboks/Chester-Write-off-Boks-at-own-peril-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Springbok legend Chester Williams has warned that teams write off South Africa at their own peril ahead of the RWC.</Description>
        <MainBody>Renewed depth for Stormers
Johannesburg - Springbok legend Chester Williams has warned that teams write off South Africa at their own peril ahead of the 2015 Rugby World Cup in England in September.
Williams, a member of South Africa's 1995 World Cup-winning rugby team, was speaking at a coaching clinic hosted by Emirates Airlines at Ellis Park for children of the John Mitchell Primary School on Tuesday.
"When they write us off - that is when we are at our most dangerous - and that is when South Africans get together and start working for each other," Williams said at the arrival of the Webb Ellis Cup in Johannesburg.
"We havent been good over the last year, but normally when that happens, we win the World Cup considering what happened with the team under Jake White.
"Before that, we had to build a team to be successful, Kitch Christie took over a team that lost against England in 1994, we went on tour in New Zealand where we could only draw against them in Auckland."
Williams was back at the venue where the Springboks famously beat the All Blacks 15-12 following a Joel Stransky drop goal in extra time 20 years ago.
The final is still fresh in his mind as people constantly asked him about his experience in the game while they recall where they were on that day.
"It feels like yesterday and it will probably be one of the World Cups people will always talk about because of the circumstances in the country at the time and Apartheid," he said
"The Springbok team and Nelson Mandela getting together to unite the country through a tournament.
"People think it happened in the final but it happened before that, with us going to coaching clinics in Khayelitsha and Soweto, and from there with Nelson Mandela supporting the team."
As the only non-white member of the team, Williams believed South African rugby had made good progress in terms of transformation of the sport but had more work to do.
"There is no way that we can say that weve done enough (in terms of transformation) because there is so much work to do and it is only 20 years after weve become a democratic country," Williams said.
"It is a work in progress and we need to work on it every day, every week, every month and every year."
He said there were real examples of transformation happening in rugby with black players not merely being selected on the wing but were given opportunities in other positions.
"There has been progress with regards to selection of teams, there arent just wings on the rugby field, but props, centres and flyhalves, so there is change," he said.
"If you look at the Stormers last week, 10 of the 23 players were so-called black players and nobody spoke about it.
"That is the nice thing because it means it is becoming natural to everyone and from now on people will select the team the way it is."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:58:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France suspends security co-operation with Burundi: diplomat</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/Africa/News/France-suspends-security-co-operation-with-Burundi-diplomat-20150526</Link>
        <Description>France has suspended its security co-operation with the crisis-hit central African nation of Burundi.</Description>
        <MainBody>Burundi slams foreign diplomatic pressure over political crisis
Bujumbura - France has suspended its security co-operation with the crisis-hit central African nation of Burundi, a French diplomat told AFP on Tuesday.
The source said aid to the country's police and defence establishment had been halted amid a crackdown on protests against President Pierre Nkurunziza's controversial bid to stand for a third consecutive term.
The decision throws even more pressure on Nkurunziza, who is facing international criticism, a refugee crisis and even survived a coup attempt earlier this month.
France currently helps the Burundian army with training for international peacekeeping missions - which are very lucrative for the impoverished country's armed forces.
France also helps train the Burundian police, who have been engaged in a violent crackdown against street demonstrations.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:58:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Cleveland announces overhaul of police dept</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Cleveland-announces-overhaul-of-police-dept-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Cleveland has agreed to overhaul its police department under the supervision of a federal monitor in a settlement with the US Justice Department over a pattern of excessive force and other abuses by officers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cleveland announces overhaul of police dept
2015-05-26 20:58
(John Minchillo, AP)
Baltimore rioting damage costs millions
Cleveland - Cleveland has agreed to overhaul its police department under the supervision of a federal monitor in a settlement with the US Justice Department over a pattern of excessive force and other abuses by officers.
The settlement was announced on Tuesday and comes three days after a white patrolman was acquitted of voluntary manslaughter charges in the shooting deaths of two unarmed black suspects in a 137-shot barrage of police gunfire.
The case helped prompt an 18-month investigation by the Justice Department.
The findings released in December required the city to work with community leaders and other officials to devise a plan to reform the police department.
Officials say the settlement calls for new use-of-force guidelines, a focus on community engagement, accountability reforms, training on bias-free policing and a mental health advisory committee.
Read more on:  us
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:56:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Ancestors delaying Medupi - CRL Commission</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Ancestors-delaying-Medupi-CRL-Commission-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Construction of the Medupi power station is being delayed as a result of graves being disturbed, which had upset the ancestors, the CRL Rights Commission says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ancestors delaying Medupi - CRL Commission
2015-05-26 20:56
Thomas Hartleb News24
Medupi power station. Picture: Lucky Nxumalo/City Press
Medupi struggles to come online
Johannesburg  The reason the Medupi power station is suffering delays is because graves were disturbed during construction, upsetting the ancestors, the CRL Rights Commission said on Tuesday.
How come this Medupi never comes together? asked commission chairperson Thoko Mkhwanazi in Johannesburg at the release of a report on the re-use of graves by local governments.
Its the bones underneath and in the vicinity. Some of the graves were destroyed there, she said of the power station near Lephalale, Limpopo.
The belief systems of some people will tell you that this Medupi dream of yours will never happen. It will be another 10 years.
Construction of the power station has been beset by delays and strikes by contractors.
She said the commission would send a report to Eskom on how to deal with the bones that were strewn around in a way that was culturally and religiously sustainable.
The report by the CRL Commission, a Chapter 9 institution that protects cultural and religious practices and linguistic communities, was compiled following complaints that several municipalities around the country were recycling graves.
Mkhwanazi said the ANC-run eThekwini municipality, the main culprit in grave recycling, was disrespecting cultural values.
For this to happen 21 years into democracy, for the ANC not to value the dead people, it tells you we are in a crisis. It tells us our values are not valued by those in power, she continued.
Ton of complaints
The commission had received a ton of complaints from residents in several municipalities around the country, mainly from eThekwini.
People were upset to find strangers buried in their relatives graves, and tombstones being removed and replaced with those of unrelated people.
She said it was hard to reverse the effects, in terms of spirituality and cultural beliefs, of having a Smith buried on top of a Naidoo on top of a Mkhwanazi.
If we allow the eThekwini municipality to continue, other municipalities are likely to gravitate towards doing this. The new struggle is to have access to our forefathers, she said.
According to African beliefs, the ancestor is believed to be living with God and playing a prominent, intercessory role in the life of a particular family, she explained.
This is your Jesus, it takes you to God, she said.
Recycling a grave was akin to bombing a mosque. When people spoke to their ancestors, I call them from the grave, not from some black plastic bag where they have been recycled, she said.
A grave is a place of communicating with those who have gone before, said the commissions deputy chairperson, Luka Mosoma.
Mkhwanazi said the practice was affecting the poor the worst, as they could not afford headstones and municipalities were re-using these graves.
The bigger the tombstone, the less likely you are to be recycled. This makes the poor people poorer, because if you dont have the ancestors backing you, you are more likely to be poor.
She said the eThekwini municipalitys procedure was to advertise its intention in the classified section of newspapers, but questioned if people saw these adverts.
Local governments position on the matter was that suitable land for cemeteries was fast becoming depleted, she said.
They are making it a land struggle. What local government is saying is very dangerous.
'One body, one grave'
The first prize, she said, was one body one grave. A weak second option was for municipalities to discuss recycling graves with affected relatives and communities before doing it.
Mkhwanazi said the commission had held talks with local government, Parliament, the SA Local Government Association (Salga), and others.
We are going to be much more aggressive. Weve tried being nice. We are going to let the Constitution speak.
She called for national legislation on the matter. If the practice continued, the commission would ask its lawyers to approach the courts for them to determine what now?.
We hope this thing can be solved over a cup of tea. We are willing to give it one more try within a couple of weeks, she added.
Salgas Mvuyisi April said municipalities were seriously running out of space, but that there was no room for municipalities to violate rights. Salga was looking at striking a balance between managing space and respecting peoples rights, he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:56:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Joburg pensioners to get massive rebates on property rates</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Joburg-pensioners-to-get-massive-rebates-on-property-rates-20150526</Link>
        <Description>Pensioners over 70 who own a house worth R2m or less will receive a 100% rebate on their property rates from the City of Johannesburg, financial mayoral committee member Geoffrey Makhubo says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Joburg pensioners to get massive rebates on property rates
2015-05-26 20:56
Mpho Raborife, News24
Rates change could cause rental chaos
Johannesburg - Pensioners over 70 who own a house worth R2m or less will receive a 100% rebate on their property rates from the City of Johannesburg, financial mayoral committee member Geoffrey Makhubo said on Tuesday.
The price of electricity would however increase by 12.19%, he said while delivering the city's budget speech in Sandton.
He said the rebates were designed to provide relief to residents.
Pensioners who earned less than R7 850 a month would also get a 100% rebate. Those earning more than R7 850, but less than R13 457, would qualify for a 50% rebate.
"Child-headed households with property value not exceeding R2m receive 100% rebate on properties," Makhubo said.
All households in the city were already receiving six kilolitres of water for free monthly. A subsidised water tariff was in place for those using prepaid meters, he said.
There would also be subsidies for sanitation and sewerage tariffs.
Makhuba announced increases in property, electricity and other essential services rates.
The electricity price increase was in line with the National Energy Regulator of SA and Eskom's proposed increases.
"The message we want to convey to our residents is: the less electricity consumers use, the less they pay."
The cost of waste removal services would increase by 8%, and that of water, sewerage and sanitation services by 14%.
Property rates would increase by 6%, he said.
Read more on:  johannesburg | rates
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue May 26 21:56:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Durban to host 2016 Aids conference</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Durban-to-host-2016-Aids-conference-20150526</Link>
        <Description>The eThekwini Municipality is set to host the International Aids Conference in 2016, it has been announced.</Description>
        <MainBody>Durban to host 2016 Aids conference
2015-05-26 20:56
Amanda Khoza, News24
(Duncan Alfreds, News24)
Motlanthe wants more in fight against HIV/Aids
2012-07-24 08:17
Deputy President Kgalema Motlanthe has touted South Africa's progress and Africa's collective resolve in tackling the HIV-AIDS pandemic but warned delegates attending the International AIDS Conference in Washington DC that now is not the time to lose the momentum. WATCH
Related Links
Crisis in funds lead to Aids innovation
Durban -The eThekwini Municipality will host the International Aids Conference in 2016, it was announced on Tuesday.
Head of the Aids 2016 Local Office, Dr Memory Muturiki, said more than 20000 delegates would descend on Durban to discuss the latest global responses to the epidemic, including scientific research, public health implementation, and human rights.
The International Aids Conference is a bridge between multiple health specialities and a crucial venue for civil rights engagement and government and government accountability, Muturiki said.
Sub-Saharan Africa has the most serious HIV/Aids epidemic in the world. In 2012, roughly 25 million people in Africa were living with HIV, accounting for nearly 70% of the global epidemic.
In the same year we had an estimated 1.6 million new infections and 1.2 million Aids-related deaths, she said.
Read more on:  durban | hiv/aids
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
