<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:28:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Workers cheer for Zuma at May Day rally</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Workers-cheer-for-Zuma-at-May-Day-rally-20150501</Link>
        <Description>President Jacob Zuma has received a warm welcome from workers attending a Cosatu May Day rally in Durban.</Description>
        <MainBody>Workers cheer for Zuma at May Day rally
2015-05-01 14:28
Amanda Khoza and Genevieve Quintal, News24
Gallery|click on thumbnail to view larger image
The Congress of SA Trade Unions (Cosatu) march through Durban city centre for the annual May Day rally. View all the pics here.
Related Links
- Are you there? Send us your eyewitness accounts and photos .
The crowd cheered when Cosatu's KwaZulu-Natal secretary Edwin Mkhize introduced Zuma.
Thousands of people, most of them dressed in red, marched from the Gugu Dlamini Amphitheatre at The Workshop in Durban to Curries Fountain earlier on Friday.
Guests at the event included Labour Minister Mildred Oliphant, Higher Education Minister Blade Nzimande , and ANC national executive committee members.
Numsa rally
"There are many unions that are here. What is interesting here is that there are people that were reported to be attending the other rally, but we see them here today," Mkhize said referring to a separate march by the National Union of Metalworkers of SA (Numsa).
The Numsa march, led by the union's general secretary Irvin Jim and expelled Cosatu general secretary Zwelinzima Vavi , was expected to start at Dinuzulu Park and end at City Hall.
Some Cosatu affiliate unions supporting Numsa and Vavi had said they would be attending the metalworkers' march.
Cosatu provincial chairperson Beauty Zibula told the crowd that despite Cosatu's problems, the trade union federation would not be deterred from achieving its goals.
"There are challenges in Cosatu, but we shall not be detracted or swayed from achieving our goal. We also said that we need to build a strong federation. We want to be the strongest federation in the world. We want to protect the workers' rights to strike.
"Workers, we need to be steadfast and fight for that right."
Zibula said unions' bargaining power needed to be strengthened.
"Let's go bargain at national level so that the impact can be felt by the employer. Wages should not be determined by our race."
Xenophobia
Speaking about the attacks in the province last month, Zibula said Cosatu was against xenophobia.
"Our African brothers are our brothers. As workers we need to educate one another about the black on black war."
eThekwini mayor and provincial SA Communist Party chairperson James Nxumalo welcomed the masses to the march.
"We have painted the whole of Curries Fountain red, thank you for coming out in your numbers," he said.
Nxumalo would on Saturday stand for the post of ANC eThekwini chairperson.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:40:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Bloem doctor searches for her grandmother in Nepal</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Bloem-doctor-searches-for-her-grandmother-in-Nepal-20150501</Link>
        <Description>A Bloemfontein doctor has told News24 she made the trip to earthquake-struck Nepal to check in on her grandmother, who had been unreachable in the days following the disaster.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bloem doctor searches for her grandmother in Nepal
2015-05-01 13:40
Jeff Wicks, News24, in Kathmandu
Dr Samita Pandey (Jeff Wicks, News24)
Kathmandu - A Bloemfontein doctor made the trip to earthquake-struck Nepal to check in on her grandmother, who had been unreachable in the days following the disaster last week.
After searching for several days, she was relieved to find her beloved grandmother safe and sound.
The death toll from the quake is thought to be over 6 000 and international aid missions have flooded into the country.
Nepal-born Dr Samita Pandey, an ENT (ear, nose and throat) registrar from Bloemfontein, travelled to Nepal in search of her elderly grandmother.
Pandey is one of a medical team of 37, dispatched to Nepal as part of a Gift of the Givers humanitarian mission.
Shaken
Speaking to News24, Pandey said that the realisation that her grandmother, who is in her 70s, was in one of the areas worst affected by the quake had left her shaken.
I dont quite have the words to describe how I felt when I heard about the earthquake because the first thought that popped into my mind was about my gran. She lives here and I was in a state of surreal shock, she said.
We desperately tried to get in touch with her and we couldn't for several days; it was horrible feeling that helpless, especially when I saw the images on the news about how bad it was. She is old and for a time I thought I wouldn't see her again, the doctor added.
We eventually reached her and luckily she was away from her house in Kathmandu and was near the south of the city. From what we hear from her she is fine and just a little bit shaken after all that has happened.
Pandey had moved to South Africa with her parents when she was 6-years-old and as a qualified doctor had decided to try and give back to the country of her birth.
Its part of what motivated me to volunteer for this mission. I want to give back to my country and just check in on my gran to make sure that she is okay. When I am with my family here this place feels like home, she said.
As the projected death toll continues to rise, the team consisting of specialist surgeons, anaesthetists and nurses will on Friday begin procedures at the Kirtipur Hospital on the outskirts of Kathmandu.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:56:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | EFF complains about ANC 'attack' on Madonsela</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/Politics/EFF-complains-about-ANC-attack-on-Madonsela-20150501</Link>
        <Description>The EFF says it will lodge a complaint over the way ANC MPs treated Public Protector Thuli Madonsela during a justice portfolio committee briefing.</Description>
        <MainBody>EFF complains about ANC 'attack' on Madonsela
2015-05-01 14:53
Thomas Hartleb, News24
Thuli Madonsela (Lerato Maduna, Netwerk24)
Madonsela, Malema dismiss 'rubbish' spy claims
Johannesburg  The EFF on Friday said it will lodge a complaint over the way Public Protector Thuli Madonsela was treated by ANC MPs during a briefing to a parliamentary committee this week.
During her appearance, the Public Protector was subject to personal, unprofessional and unparliamentary attacks by members of the justice portfolio committee, particularly its chairperson honourable Mathole Motshekga, the Economic Freedom Fighters Chief Whip Floyd Shivambu wrote in the complaint, addressed to National Assembly Speaker Baleka Mbete .
The EFF said MPs on Wednesday accused Madonsela of working with the Democratic Alliance, coerced her into apologising for making comments on a high court judgment, prevented her from conferring with her deputy, and rudely insisted that she finish answering questions.
Motshekga led the personal and unparliamentary attacks on her and she was subjected to a childish interrogation that undermined her office.
We therefore write to you to request that Parliament investigates the conduct of members of the justice portfolio committee, in particular its chairperson, with the view of determining whether this conduct falls within acceptable parliamentary rules and practices, Shivambu said.
Netwerk 24 reported on Wednesday that the DA, ACDP, and EFF came to her defence.
The ANC accused her of undermining the justice system, wasting tax money, submitting a flawed report to Parliament, and not having control over her office's finances.
In a statement the ANC Chief Whips office said: Our members are merely conducting oversight... .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:40:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Lawyer: Police not looking for Henri van Breda</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Lawyer-Police-not-looking-for-Henri-van-Breda-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Henri van Breda's lawyer Pieter van den Berg says he is not aware of claims that police are looking for him.</Description>
        <MainBody>Axe-murder kids to inherit R200m
Johannesburg  If police are looking for the survivor of the Stellenbosch family axe murders, Henri van Breda, they have only to contact his lawyers, Netwerk24 reported on Friday.
His lawyer Pieter Botha said he was not aware that police were looking for Henri and did not understand what was meant by claims that he had disappeared.
He could come and go as he pleased as he had not been charged with anything, Botha said.
Botha was reacting to rumours that the 20-year-old survivor had vanished and that police were looking for him, following the murders of his parents and older brother in January.
His father Martin, 54, mother Teresa, 55, and older brother Rudi, 22, were killed with an axe in their home on the De Zalze golf estate. Henris sister Marli, 16, sustained a severe head wound but survived. She was reportedly suffering from memory loss. Henri sustained a few scratches.
The Citizen reported that Henri had gone to Welkom to live with a family friend, when he had been obliged to be in Klerksdorp.
Weeks ago, Van Bredas lawyers had told police and prosecutors to contact them if they wanted to arrest him. He would then present himself, Botha said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:40:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Locals take relief work into own hands after Nepal quake</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Locals-take-relief-work-into-own-hands-after-Nepal-quake-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Villagers in quake-stricken Nepal áre distributing emergency provisions among themselves as official aid and rescue operations continue to be held up.</Description>
        <MainBody>Locals take relief work into own hands after Nepal quake
2015-05-01 14:40
Nepalese men look at buildings damaged in an earthquake at the Durbar Square in Kathmandu, Nepal. (Manish Swarup, AP)
SA medical team touches down in quake-hit Nepal
Kathmandu - Villagers in quake-stricken Nepal were distributing emergency provisions among themselves on Friday, as official aid and rescue operations continued to be held up.
"Sindupalchowk is the worst-hit district and the people in our neighbourhood decided to put things together," said a man calling himself Sagar in Kathmandu. He had travelled to the capital and was helping dispatch relief back to his home district, around 60 km north of the capital.
"We are so disappointed with the government efforts and the media is also not doing enough," he told dpa.
Anger at government
Local media reported cases of affected locals muscling out government officials and taking control of relief operations.
"People have been so angry with the government in different places because of lack of support, and have blocked relief and all that so we need to be careful," said Nayantara Gurung, an independent volunteer in Kathmandu.
"We haven't heard any such reports so far" about similar incidents, head of the government's disaster management department, Laxmi Prasad Dhakal said.
A group of Spanish tourists told dpa they were sending food supplies to Sindupalchowk, where over 2 000 people were killed.
Gurung said her group was focusing on basic shelter and medical supplies. "We have been able to send out supplies to outer Lalitpur's rural areas, at a distance of a day's walk" from Kathmandu.
The death toll reached 6 100 on Friday, six days after the 7.8-magnitude quake.
Also Friday, 20 foreigners were rescued from Dhunche of Rasuwa district, 50km due north of Kathmandu, police spokesperson Kamal Singh Bam said.
Local media reports said 43 foreigners had died in the earthquake and 41 were still missing.
Read more on:  nepal | nepal earthquake
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:25:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Wentzel: Hard to see any positives</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Rugby/Super15/Wentzel-Hard-to-see-any-positives-20150501</Link>
        <Description>The Highlanders demolished the Sharks 48-15 on Friday with a dominant seven-try performance.</Description>
        <MainBody>As it happened: Sharks thrashed by Highlanders
Buoyed by the return of All Black trio Ben Smith, Malakai Fekitoa and Aaron Smith, the Highlanders' slick passing game saw them run away with the game in the second half.
The bonus-point victory took the New Zealanders' record to seven wins from 10 matches, consolidating their spot in the top six as a clutch of rivals breathe down their neck.
It was the fourth straight defeat for the Sharks, leaving their finals hopes hanging after the first match of a tough five-week New Zealand-Australia road trip.
"It's quite hard to see any positives at this stage," captain Marco Wentzel said.
"We have to look at the negatives first and fix the problems then take it from there. It's a tough tour, it doesn't get any easier."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:38:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | NGO: Men are literally getting away with murder</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/NGO-Men-are-literally-getting-away-with-murder-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Violence against SA women remains a problem because of power imbalances and the perception that there will be no consequences for criminal behaviour, Sonke Gender Justice says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man arrested for stabbing girlfriend to death
Cape Town - Violence against South African women remains a problem because of power imbalances and the perception that there will be no consequences for criminal behaviour, Sonke Gender Justice said on Thursday.
There is an element of impunity because, in most cases, the perpetrators know they can literally get away with murder, spokesperson Mbuyiselo Botha told News24.
He said many male perpetrators perceived they would not be successfully prosecuted because witnesses would be afraid to speak up or they would be released because police had botched the investigation.
Power imbalances
A deep-seated issue is power imbalances, where it is still very prevalent around the world and here for women to be on the receiving end of violence. Women are still considered as not fully-fledged human beings.
Sonke Gender Justice is a non-governmental organisation focused on supporting men and boys in taking action to promote gender equality, prevent domestic and sexual violence, and reduce the spread and impact of HIV and Aids.
Botha said there was a perception that only certain races and classes committed crime, or were victims of crime.
 The assumption is that these murders and violence happen in other race groups and it does not happen in white areas and well-off communities, he said.
If we are to deal decisively with violence, it is very critical to say: how do we also work with class and race?
High profile cases
The country had seen a number of prominent cases of violence against women hit the headlines.
These included Paralympian Oscar Pistorius receiving five years in jail for culpable homicide after shooting his girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp dead, and the clearing of British businessman Shrien Dewani for the murder of his wife Anni while they were on honeymoon in Cape Town in 2010.
The latest murder to go viral was that of Eastern Cape teacher Jayde Panayiotou, who was abducted outside her home last week.
Police ruled out robbery as the motive and arrested two men, one of whom is said to be a close relative.
Economic impact
Last year, Sonke Gender Justice commissioned a KPMG report on the economic impact of gender-based violence in South Africa, looking at the cost suffered by female victims, the government, civil society and businesses.
Researchers could not fully assess the costs because the country lacked sufficient or adequate data, but came up with estimates based on prevalence rates of violence against women between 20 and 30 percent.
The report estimated that this type of violence cost between R28.4 billion and R35.4bn, representing up to 1.1% of the gross domestic product in 2012.
The majority of the cost was borne by the victim.
Many women never get their name published in stories and are simply referred to by their age and where they were killed or their body discovered.
Less prominent stories to hit the headlines this year include:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:25:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Van Persie in line for West Brom start</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Soccer/EnglishPremiership/Van-Persie-in-line-for-West-Brom-start-20150501-2</Link>
        <Description>Robin van Persie could make his first start since February against West Bromwich Albion on Saturday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Van Persie in line for West Brom start
2015-05-01 14:25
Manchester United's striker Robin van Persie. (Paul Ellis, AFP)
Related Links
Stamford Bridge ready to party
Manchester - Robin van Persie could make his first start since February against West Bromwich Albion on Saturday as Manchester United attempt to consolidate their place in the Premier League's top four.
Dutch striker van Persie came on as a substitute in United's 3-0 defeat by Everton last Sunday, his first appearance after suffering an ankle injury, and is in contention to face the Baggies at Old Trafford.
United could be without captain Wayne Rooney after he suffered a knee injury at Goodison Park, which would increase the prospects of Van Persie or Radamel Falcao playing in attack for United.
Van Persie, 31, has scored 10 goals in 25 league appearances this season but only two of those strikes have come in 2015.
As well as questions over Rooney's availability, United manager Louis van Gaal has concerns over the fitness of three defensive players. Holding midfielder Michael Carrick, and centre-backs Marcos Rojo and Phil Jones all missed the match against Everton and are doubts for the visit of West Brom.
United's defeat at Everton followed a 1-0 loss against champions-elect Chelsea at Stamford Bridge in their previous outing.
It was the first time they had suffered back-to-back defeats during van Gaal's tenure and gave fifth-place Liverpool the chance to close the gap.
Luckily for United, the Reds spurned that opportunity, losing 1-0 at Hull City on Tuesday, leaving van Gaal's fourth-placed side seven points clear of their bitter rivals.
United need six points from their final four matches to guarantee a top-four finish and defender Chris Smalling was confident the players would respond well after their two recent defeats.
"We've got four big games now in which we've got to make sure we were better than on Sunday," Smalling said.
"We'll be eager to put this right. I think we'll see a different Manchester United against West Brom."
West Brom left-back Chris Brunt was adamant the Baggies still had plenty to play for this term, despite virtually rubber-stamping their Premier League status with last weekend's 0-0 draw against Liverpool.
The Baggies head to Old Trafford seven points clear of the relegation zone in what looks set to be another successful escape act involving manager Tony Pulis.
The Welshman has turned around Albion's fortunes since his arrival in January, but Brunt said the Midlands club's players were now playing for their futures, with Pulis expected to carry out major surgery on his squad during the close season.
"With the new gaffer (manager) here I'm sure he will have a big say in what goes on over the summer," Brunt said.
"Regardless of what anybody thinks about whether we're safe or not, everybody has still got points to prove over the last few weeks of the season, whether they want to stay or want to leave."
Brunt, usually a winger, added he was relishing his new role on the left of the West Midlands side's defence.
"When you're part of the back four and you get a clean sheet it's enjoyable and over the last eight years it's not something I've been too concerned about.
"Obviously, it's always nice to get clean sheets but doing it as part of the back four is really enjoyable.
"I will do whatever I can to help out, and if the gaffer sees me as a left-back then I will get my head down and get on with it."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:01:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Workers: Cosatu internal battle having bad effect</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Workers-Cosatu-internal-battle-having-bad-effect-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Cosatu members attending a May Day rally in Durban say the internal battles in the trade union federation are not helping workers solve their problems.</Description>
        <MainBody>- Are you there? Send us your eyewitness accounts and photos .
Sabelo Mzimela, 29, a KwaDukuza Waste Management employee said: "There are so many issues affecting workers at the moment.
"There are hundreds of people on contract that have worked for many years. People are working without uniforms and some don't even have UIF, which makes working very difficult."
Gap
Mzimela felt that the internal fighting between leaders in Cosatu was having a negative effect.
"The faction fighting at top level is affecting us because the gap between management and the workers is too much.
"We are not happy with the federation."
He said those that are in charge should visit municipalities to check on the workers.
"We feel very neglected as the workers. There is so much infighting at top level but there are so many unemployed people sitting at home," said Mzimela.
Transformation
Beth Vickers, 55, from Pinetown, said she did not believe that there was enough transformation.
"I don't believe that business has transformed as much as they should have in implementing the laws. I see them as restricting and limiting the laws and change that should be taking place," she told News24.
"Instead of embracing them they complain about them. We just have to look at all the laws affecting labour.
"It's not just simply the basic employment labour relations but there are health and safety issues as well."
Sithembiso Dlomo, 43, from Clermont, said there were many issues facing unions at the moment.
"As you can see today, there are two separate marches. Numsa is holding its own march and Cosatu is holding its own march on the same day and to me this shows that there are people who think that they are above the union.
"This is causing factions in the unions because they are too focused on politics than dealing with issues affecting the workers," said Dlomo.
Back to basics
He said the unions needed to go back to the basics.
"They need to sit down and talk about the real issues affecting the workers," said Dlomo.
Thousands of Cosatu members marched from Gugu Dlamini Amphitheatre at The Workshop in Durban to Curries Fountain.
President Jacob Zuma was expected to address the crowd there.
He arrived at the rally just before 13:00.
The Numsa march, led by the union's general secretary Irvin Jim and expelled Cosatu general secretary Zwelinzima Vavi , was expected to start at 09:00 at Dinuzulu Park and end at the City Hall.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Waratahs sneak win over the Brumbies</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Rugby/Super15/Waratahs-sneak-win-over-the-Brumbies-20150501</Link>
        <Description>The Waratahs came from behind to edge past the Brumbies 15-13 away from home on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Waratahs sneak win over the Brumbies
2015-05-01 13:24
Sharks mauled in Dunedin
Cape Town - The Waratahs held on to beat the Brumbies 13-10 on Friday in a bruising encounter that kept their Super Rugby title defence alive and well.
The Brumbies still lead the Waratahs in the Australian conference after picking up a consolation bonus point for losing by less than seven.
But their advantage was slashed to single point with New South Wales still having a game in hand after a gripping battle at Canberra Stadium.
The Brumbies jumped out to a 7-0 lead after just eight minutes when wing Joe Tomane scored out wide and Christian Leali'ifano nailed the conversion.
The Waratahs hit back straight away with a try from centre Adam Ashley-Cooper but went to the break trailing 10-7.
Neither side managed a try in the second half as the two teams - who are likely to provide the bulk of players for the Australian squad at this year's World Cup - defended ferociously.
Kurtley Beale and Bernard Foley both kicked penalties to put the Waratahs ahead and the visitors held on to register their third win on the trot.
"It was classic Brumbies-Tahs," said NSW captain Dave Dennis.
"It was just a really tough physical match.
"We didn't get much flow and go-forward in attack but we defended really well, even with a man down."
The Waratahs were reduced to 14 men at the end when winger Rob Horne was given a yellow card for a professional foul and spent most of the last 10 minutes defending.
The Brumbies had a chance to get a draw when they were awarded a late penalty but opted to go for the win, kicking for the line and setting up a rolling maul.
"It's really disappointing, there wasn't much in it," Brumbies skipper Stephen Moore said.
"We had a lot of chances in the second half but weren't good enough to take them.
"It makes every game from now on really important if we want to make the top six."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:38:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Justice ministry considering assisted suicide appeal</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Justice-ministry-considering-assisted-suicide-appeal-20150501</Link>
        <Description>The justice ministry says it is considering whether it still wants to appeal a court ruling on the assisted suicide of Robin Stransham-Ford, after he died.</Description>
        <MainBody>Justice ministry considering assisted suicide appeal
2015-05-01 12:38
Thomas Hartleb, News24
Dignity SA member Patsy Schonegevel stands outside the North Gauteng High Court holding a picture of her son Craig. (Thomas Hartleb, News24)
Court grants man right to assisted death
Johannesburg  The justice ministry on Friday said it is considering whether it still wants to appeal the High Court in Pretorias ruling on the assisted suicide of Robin Stransham-Ford, after he died on Thursday .
In view of the latest developments we will reflect on the matter and also await written reasons for judgment and make a determination on the issue of appeal, spokesperson Mthunzi Mhaga said in a statement.
He said they had yet to verify reports that he died before the ruling was made. It was not clear if Stransham-Ford died before or after the ruling.
Judge Hans Fabricius ruled on Thursday that Stransham-Ford, 65, who was suffering from prostate cancer and was given weeks to live, could commit suicide with the help of a doctor. He ordered that the doctor who would help him should not be prosecuted or face disciplinary proceedings.
Immediately after the ruling, Mhaga told reporters they would appeal as soon as Fabricius handed down his reasons on Monday.
Mhaga said the ruling had far-reaching implications for the National Prosecuting Authoritys ability to decide what cases it could prosecute.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:30:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Pirates keen on clean sheet</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Soccer/PSL/Pirates-keen-on-clean-sheet-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Eric Tinkler is expecting nothing less than a clean sheet when CF Mounana face his side at the Orlando Stadium.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pirates keen on clean sheet
2015-05-01 12:30
Virus hits Pirates squad
Cape Town - Orlando Pirates coach Eric Tinkler is expecting nothing less than a clean sheet when his side face CF Mounana in the second leg of their CAF Confederations Cup second-round clash on Saturday.
The Buccaneers welcome their Gabonese opponents to the Orlando Stadium this weekend with the scores level at 2-2 from the reverse fixture, giving the Soweto giants the advantage on away goals.
That means Pirates need only a goalless draw to progress to the next round, and while Tinkler is determined to at least keep Mounana at bay over the 90 minutes, he still expects his side to find the back of the opposition net during the encounter.
"We need to take advantage of the fact that we scored those vital two away goals by not conceding at home," he told his club's official website.
"It is vital that we get ourselves an early goal because that will obviously put them under pressure which means they will have to go in search for a third goal and that is a scenario we will look to exploit.
"It is very important that we stay disciplined in defence, ensure we don't concede and when we do have possession of the ball we must make sure that we capitalise and score goals.
"If we can get two early goals it will make the match more comfortable and we can move into the next round of the competition."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:26:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Woman bitten to death by shark off Maui swam every day, brother says</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Woman-bitten-to-death-by-shark-off-Maui-swam-every-day-brother-says-20150501</Link>
        <Description>A 65-year-old woman bitten to death by a shark while snorkelling off the Hawaiian island of Maui loved the ocean and went swimming every day, her brother says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Woman bitten to death by shark off Maui swam every day, brother says
2015-05-01 12:26
(Picture: Supplied)
Man dies after shark bites off legs in Australia
Honolulu - A 65-year-old woman bitten to death by a shark while snorkelling off the Hawaiian island of Maui loved the ocean and went swimming every day, her brother said on Thursday.
Maui County police said in a statement Margaret Cruse of the local community of Kihei was found floating in the waters of Ahihi Kinau Bay on Wednesday morning and had injuries consistent with a shark attack.
It was the first fatal shark attack in Hawaii since 2013.
Cruse, who grew up in the San Francisco Bay Area, had lived for the past dozen years in Maui where she had many friends, her brother, Bill Cruse, said in a phone interview from Redding, California.
"She did what she wanted to do. She loved animals. Accidents happen, and I think she was aware that nature can be a hard thing sometimes," said Cruse, a retired police officer.
'She was never afraid'
He added that his sister loved the water and snorkelling.
"She went every morning ... she was never afraid of anything in the ocean because she did it so often," he said.
Deborah Ward, a spokesperson for the Hawaii Department of Land and Natural Resources, said officials closed a stretch of water along the shoreline in the area after the attack but re-opened it around noon on Thursday.
Authorities did not say what type of shark attacked Cruse.
The statement from police did not describe her injuries, but her brother said he was told she had bite marks on her face, upper torso and arm, which was nearly severed.
No one is known to have witnessed the attack.
'Freak accident'
Savitri Carlson, who is part of a swim group The Maui Mermaids that Cruse swam with, said in a phone interview she was in the water in the area when Cruse was bitten, but did not see the attack.
"She was a very experienced and cautious swimmer," Carlson said. "This was a freak accident, not a lack of caution."
An autopsy will be conducted to determine the official cause of death, police said.
The last two fatal shark attacks in Hawaii occurred in 2013 in the same area off the coast of Maui where Cruse died. That year, a man fishing from a kayak was bitten to death by a shark and a German tourist had her arm bitten off by a shark and later died in a hospital.
University of Florida researchers said shark attacks killed three people worldwide in 2014.
Read more on:  us | shark attacks
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:23:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Cosatu May Day rally off to a good start</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Cosatu-May-Day-rally-off-to-a-good-start-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Cosatu's main May Day rally has started on a high note in Durban, being led by top officials including Cosatu president Sdumo Dlamini and SACP general secretary Blade Nzimande.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cosatu May Day rally off to a good start
2015-05-01 12:23
Amanda Khoza and Genevieve Quintal, News24
(Amanda Khoza, News24)
Zwelinzima Vavi speaks ahead of Workers' Day
2015-04-30 18:44
Speaking to News24, expelled Cosatu general secretary Zwelinzima Vavi said much work must still be done for South Africa's workers. Watch. WATCH
Related Links
- Are you there? Send us your eyewitness accounts and photos .
More than 1 000 Cosatu members painted the streets of Durban red as they were led by police. Engines revved as bikers showed off while leading the march.
Cosatu president Sdumo Dlamini and SA Communist Party general secretary Blade Nzimande, KwaZulu-Natal Premier Senzo Mchunu, MEC Peggy Nkonyeni, Cosatu KwaZulu-Natal secretary Zet Luzipho and eThekwini Mayor James Nxumalo were leading the march.
The marchers arrived at Curries Fountain just before noon.
President Jacob Zuma is expected to address the masses there.
Numsa march
The National Union of Metalworkers (Numsa), which was expelled from Cosatu last year, is holding a separate May Day march, also in Durban.
It was not clear whether the two marches would bump into each other in the course of the day.
A police officer monitoring the Cosatu rally told News24 there were more than 2 000 people at the Numsa march and more buses were arriving.
The Numsa march, led by the union's general secretary Irvin Jim and expelled Cosatu general secretary Zwelinzima Vavi, was expected to start at 09:00 at Dinuzulu Park and end at the City Hall.
Some Cosatu affiliate unions, who are supporting Numsa and Vavi, have said they will be attending the metalworkers march.
Cosatu has warned its members not to attend events where Vavi was speaking to workers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:15:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Pitso okay with ugly wins</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Soccer/PSL/Pitso-okay-with-ugly-wins-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Mamelodi Sundowns coach Pitso Mosimane expressed the need for his team to be content with winning matches 'ugly'.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pitso okay with ugly wins
2015-05-01 12:15
Cape Town - Mamelodi Sundowns coach Pitso Mosimane expressed the need for his team to be content with winning ugly.
In their last five league games, Sundowns have lost twice, won one and drawn two.
Mosimane looked back to the draws against Platinum Stars and Mpumalanga Black Aces as games that could have gone the other way, had they been more focused on the win.
In their most recent league encounter, a 1-0 loss to Kaizer Chiefs, the performance was worthy of maximum points, according to Mosimane.
The Brazilians next take on bogey side Platinum Stars in Rustenburg on Sunday.
"If we played like we did against Chiefs we should be able to win the game, the only thing was that against them our best wasnt good enough," Mosimane toldFootball411.
"Against Platinum Stars we need to know that the performance is not the result."
The defeated former champions are still in the running for a second spot in the Premiership standings.
"There is still opportunity for the second position. We just need a consistency in how we manage the game," he added.
"We need to rise to the level of a championship side."
With two key defenders, Alje Schut and Siyanda Zwane, out through injury and suspension respectively, Mosimane said they had enough quality on the bench to make up for it.
Mosimane said: "We have enough defenders our defence is not an excuse we have Schut, Zwane suspended. We have Wayne Arendese and we have Ramahlwe Mphahlele, and Asavela Mbekile."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:06:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | FIVE super-fights of the past</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/OtherSport/International/FIVE-super-fights-of-the-past-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Before Manny Pacquiao and Floyd Mayweather enter the ring, look at five great bouts that captured the imagination.</Description>
        <MainBody>FIVE super-fights of the past
2015-05-01 12:06
Las Vegas - As Manny Pacquiao and Floyd Mayweather limber up for Saturday's welterweight "fight of the century," a look at five great bouts that captured the public imagination:
'THE FIGHT'
Joe Frazier-Muhammad Ali, March 8, 1971
Known simply as "The Fight," Ali-Frazier I pitted the two undefeated heavyweight champions in the famed Madison Square Garden, New York with seemingly the whole world watching and taking sides. Frazier absorbed tremendous punishment but relentlessly outworked Ali and dropped him in the 15th round to win by unanimous decision. The fight was the first in an epic trilogy capped by the "Thrilla in Manila" on October 1, 1975 -- a back-and-forth battle that tested both men to the limit. Ali called that bout the closest thing to dying but retained his heavyweight title with a 14th-round technical knockout.
'GREATEST SPORTING EVENT'
Joe Louis-Max Schmeling, June 22, 1938
Louis, who had been knocked out by Schmeling in their prior meeting two years earlier, destroyed his opponent in two minutes and four seconds, defending his heavyweight world title in a bout that played out against the backdrop of the rise of Nazi Germany. The cultural, racial and political ramifications led boxing historian Bert Sugar to call it "The greatest sporting event of the 20th Century" and Louis emerged as a rare African-American national hero with the win over a fighter rightly or wrongly regarded as the representative of Nazi values.
'THE WAR'
"Marvelous" Marvin Hagler-Thomas Hearns, April 15, 1985
Dubbed "The War," the middleweight world title contest outdoors at Caesars Palace in Las Vegas lived up to its super-fight billing. In a furious eight minutes Hagler and Hearns went toe-to-toe from the opening bell. Bleeding from a cut on his forehead, a desperate Hagler knocked Hearns out in the third round.
'RUMBLE IN THE JUNGLE'
Muhammad Ali-George Foreman, October 30, 1974
Undefeated heavyweight world champion George Foreman was widely expected to batter Ali in the "Rumble in the Jungle" in Kinshasa, in then Zaire. But the former champion's now famous "rope a dope" strategy of staying on the ropes, gloves up, saw Foreman punch out his energy. Ali pounced on his exhausted foe with a series of shuddering blows that sent Foreman crashing down for an eighth-round knockout, the first defeat of his career.
'FINALLY'
Evander Holyfield-Mike Tyson, November 9, 1996
Like Pacquiao-Mayweather, this heavyweight showdown dubbed "Finally" pitted two stars who should have clashed earlier, but James "Buster" Douglas's stunning knockout of Tyson in February of that year scuppered those plans. By the time they did meet, Holyfield was coming back from retirement and a heart scare while Tyson was regaining the mystique that surrounded him prior to serving a prison term for rape. In the MGM's Grand Garden Arena, Holyfield shocked the world when he stopped Tyson in the 11th round, becoming the first fighter since Ali to twice regain a heavyweight world title. The bout also set the stage for what became an infamous rematch. Holyfield-Tyson II seven months later generated a record-breaking 1.99 million pay-per-view buys, but ended with Tyson munching off a piece of Holyfield's ear.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:52:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Dying and the law: the Dignity SA case explained</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Dying-and-the-law-the-Dignity-SA-case-explained-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Even though Robin Stransham-Ford died before a court ruling on assisted dying, he may have started the process of SA law recognising the right to die with dignity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Everything you need to know about assisted dying watch
Pretoria - On Thursday Judge Hans Fabricius of the High Court in Pretoria handed down an order in the case of Robin Stransham-Ford.
Stransham-Ford was a 65-year-old man who was dying of prostate cancer. He had asked the court to determine whether a doctor could legally assist him to end his life.
Although, because of the urgency of the matter, a full written judgment will only be provided by Judge Fabricius in the weeks to come, the judges order indicates that Stransham-Ford had at most a few weeks to live and was suffering intractably and should therefore be permitted to end his life with the assistance of a doctor. This order which Stransham-Ford, supported by Dignity SA, asked Judge Fabricius to make, was opposed in court by the Department of Justice and Correctional Services, a Christian lobby called Doctors for Life and the Health Professions Council of South Africa.
Validating the urgency with which Judge Fabricius treated this matter, Stransham-Ford passed away peacefully , but unassisted while under the care of medical professionals and in the presence of his family in the early hours of Thursday morning. He never got to hear of or benefit from the Courts ruling.
Up until Judge Fabricius handed down this order on Thursday, it was clear that assisting a patient to take his or her own life was illegal in terms of South African law and could potentially open doctors up to civil claims, criminal prosecution and disciplinary action from within the medical profession.
'Dignity of the dying'
In 1999 President Nelson Mandela had tasked the South African Law Commission with investigating assisted dying. The Commission, which was chaired by former Chief Justice Ismael Mahomed, published its findings which included two different options of positions which would allow a terminally ill person to be assisted in the process of dying. These findings, which included draft law, were not seen as a priority and have not since been debated in Parliament. Recently former Archbishop Desmond Tutu has come out in support of assisted suicide and the dignity of the dying.
Stransham-Ford, a former advocate himself, had approached the High Court in Pretoria urgently, assisted by Dignity SA , an organisation which campaigns for the right of terminally ill, chronically suffering people to choose the time and place of their death. This right, Dignity SA argues is grounded in the constitutional rights to life, dignity, bodily and psychological integrity and to be free from cruel, inhuman and degrading treatment. Parliaments failure to pass a law to protect these rights is in Dignity SAs view a violation of its obligation to respect and protect the rights in the Bill of Rights and therefore in conflict with the Constitution.
The case appears to centre on Stransham-Fords right to have his inherent human dignity respected and protected. Human dignity is also a foundational value upon which the entire Constitution is built. The right to live with dignity, according to Dignity SA, includes the right to choose to die with dignity.
Judge Fabricius's order gives an indication that it is a combination of some of these rights and other provisions of the Constitution detailing the states obligations upon which his decision is based. He finds that the crimes of murder or culpable homicide in [the] context of assisted suicide by medical practitioners, insofar as they provide for an absolute prohibition, unjustifiably limit [Stransham-Fords] constitutional rights to dignity and bodily and psychological integrity. His judgment is therefore likely to acknowledge a right to choose to die with dignity and have professional medical assistance in doing so.
Filling a gap in the law
Although Judge Fabricius, according to news reports, appears to be attempting to limit the scope of the influence of this decision, it is a decision which will have far-reaching implications. In the order itself the judge notes that this decision is not to be interpreted as endorsing the proposals contained in the Law Commissions 1999 report or the draft law which accompanied it. The judge was also careful to include in his order a proviso that although, doctors may have in terms of the order, been legally permitted to either administer a lethal agent to Stransham-Fords or provide him with a lethal to administer himself, no doctor is obliged to accede to accede to [Stransham-Fords] request.
In making this order, Judge Fabricius is filling a gap which the law, in the absence of the finalisation of the Law Commissions 1999 process, has left open. Whether or not the expected judgment is appealed to a higher court, which seems likely, a ruling that our legal rules are unconstitutional and require development in terms of the Constitution will ultimately require the confirmation of the Constitutional Court.
The order, if confirmed, will provide some much needed clarity for both terminally ill patients about their options in ending their own lives and doctors in assisting them to do so.
Previously there have been many situations in which doctors have felt ethically obliged to assist suffering patients to end their lives despite the serious risk of criminal prosecution.
Suicide as an alternative
Unlike Stransham-Ford, other members of Dignity SA, short of legal options to acquire assistance in ending their suffering, have taken matters into their own hands. In August last year, Inkatha Freedom Party Member of Parliament, Mario Oriani-Ambrosini, a friend of Stransham-Fords, who was in the final stages of terminal lung cancer took the decision to shoot himself in his room in Cape Town.
Most recently , Avron Moss, a 49-year-old Capetonian paediatric neuropsychologist and patron of Dignity SA, went to the extraordinary length of illegally importing lethal drugs from Mexico and then ensuring their effectiveness by having them tested using a testing kit sourced in Australia to ensure that he could take his own life. His final statement to Dignity SA before taking the drugs and ending his life was:
That healthcare professionals cannot assist [terminally ill patients], and that these patients are forced to buy questionable medication to end their lives from unscrupulous websites, or suffer the terror of having to shoot or hang themselves, ought to be abhorrent to any caring professional ... The relevant law in South Africa actively perpetuates suffering, in conflict with our Constitution and with Human Rights, and is indefensibly unjust. All caring health care professionals ought to be actively involved in campaigning to change the law.
Judge Fabriciuss order, and the anticipated judgment, means that although Stransham-Ford died unassisted and before the order was handed down, he may have begun a process towards South African law's recognition of a right to die with dignity.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:51:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Murdered PE teacher's husband googled eulogy</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/SouthAfrica/News/Murdered-PE-teachers-husband-googled-eulogy-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Parts of the eulogy delivered by murdered teacher Jayde Panayiotou's husband at her funeral appear to rely heavily on another one available online.</Description>
        <MainBody>Murdered PE teacher's husband googled eulogy
2015-05-01 11:51
Genevieve Quintal, News24
Jayde Panayiotou (Facebook)
Hundreds gather for murdered PE teacher's funeral
Johannesburg  Parts of the eulogy the husband of murdered teacher Jayde Panayiotou delivered at her funeral appear to rely heavily on another one available online.
The eulogy, delivered by Christopher Panayiotou at his wife's funeral in Port Elizabeth on Tuesday, contains phrases used in a tribute written by Charles Atkins called "My Sweet Wife's Eulogy" and dated October 2010.
In his eulogy, Atkins said with "absolute confidence" that his wife Jennifer was not gone.
"She is everywhere: Jennifer rides the wind like an elemental force. She can be experienced in the blooming of the flowers of the field. She is the pink-white blossoms of the cherry tree. She is the crest and spindrift of breaking gulf waves. She is the fertile soil of the woods. She is the enduring ember of your fire on a cold winters night."
'Staggered'
Christopher Panayiotou said: "Jayde is not gone; she is everywhere. Jayde resides in the wind like an elemental force. She can be experienced in the blooming of flowers; she is the yellow in daffodils of her favourite flower. She is the crest in every breaking wave, she is the fertile soil; she is the enduring embers of the fire."
Panayiotou said he was honoured to have been her husband for 11 years and was "staggered by her sudden passing".
She was abducted outside her Kabega Park home on Tuesday, April 28, while waiting for her lift to the school where she worked. She was later found dead on the outskirts of a township in Uitenhage.
Atkins, who had been with his wife for 10 years, was also staggered by her sudden passing.
"She made me feel like the luckiest man on earth... Ive never quite figured out why she gave her heart to me, as Im not rich or handsome," said Atkins.
Panayiotou expressed similar sentiments: "She made me feel like the luckiest man alive and I never quite figured out why she gave her heart to me."
Love and respect
Atkins wife Jennifer was a qualified chef who taught culinary arts and a "master baker who was so good; she could have made Mahatma Gandhi break a fast".
He said she was as incredibly versatile, capable, and deep person.
Panayiotou, in turn, described his teacher wife as a master chef and master baker who could have made "Mahatma Gandhi break a fast". She was also incredibly versatile, capable, and deep.
Atkins said during his time with his wife that he witnessed a "profound transformation and deepening of love and respect" for Jennifer's father. Panayiotou said he "grew a profound and deep love and respect for her family, who became my own".
"Today should not be one of sadness - although her passing is truly tragic, it should be a celebration of life, for one of Gods finest creations," Atkins said.
Panayiotou said: Today should not be one of sadness, although her passing is truly tragic, it should be a celebration of life for one of Gods greatest creations."
Arrests
Two people have been arrested in connection with Jayde Panayiotou's abduction and murder, which appeared to have been deliberate.
One of them, Thando Siyoli, 31, appeared in the Port Elizabeth Magistrates Court on Thursday. Details had emerged that a substantial amount of money was paid to kill her.
The other arrested man, aged 28, is a close family member known to News24. He cannot be named until he appears in court on Monday.
Lawyer Alwyn Griebenow, who is representing the close family member, said he was not aware of the eulogy's origins.
"I can't comment on that... it's news to me," he told News24.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:50:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | Jailed rap mogul eyes Mayweather bail out</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/OtherSport/International/Jailed-rap-mogul-eyes-Mayweather-bail-out-20150501</Link>
        <Description>Fallen rap mogul Marion "Suge" Knight will be rooting for Mayweather from behind bars this weekend.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jailed rap mogul eyes Mayweather bail out
2015-05-01 11:50
Floyd plans to strike early
Los Angeles - Fallen rap mogul Marion "Suge" Knight will be rooting for Floyd Mayweather from behind bars this weekend - hoping his old friend can help pay his $10 million bail bill, his lawyer said Thursday.
Speaking shortly after his latest court hearing, attorney Matthew Fletcher said Knight - who denies murder, attempted murder and hit-and-run charges - is counting on the unbeaten Mayweather to beat Filipino great Manny Pacquiao in Las Vegas on Saturday night.
"I think we're going to have very good luck," Fletcher told reporters. "Hopefully next week... after Floyd Mayweather wins again, I think he's going to come riding to the rescue."
Knight, who remains in custody in Los Angeles over a hit-and-run incident earlier this year that left one man dead and another seriously injured, pleaded not guilty Thursday.
Los Angeles Superior Court judge Ronald Coen again refused a request to lower his $10 million bail.
Fletcher said Mayweather "and Suge are very close friends - have known each other for a while. Obviously he's been busy, they've both been busy, but I think we will be able to make bail."
The US boxer, who has a perfect 47-0 ring record and is the highest-paid sportsman on the planet, said this week he expects a payday of $200 million for this fight alone.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:38:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sport24.co.za | As it happened: Highlanders 48-15 Sharks</title>
        <Link>http://www.sport24.co.za/Rugby/Super15/LIVE-Highlanders-v-Sharks-20150430-2</Link>
        <Description>See how the action unfolded in the Super Rugby match between the Highlanders and Sharks from Dunedin.</Description>
        <MainBody>CONVERSION, HIGHLANDERS, SOPOAGA. 24-10. Another wonderful strike from a difficult position by fly-half Sopoaga.
38'
TRY, HIGHLANDERS, OSBORNE. 22-10. A double strike from the hosts as now Osborne is over to cap another flowing move.
36'
CONVERSION, HIGHLANDERS, SOPOAGA. 17-10. Superb.
35'
TRY, HIGHLANDERS, NAHOLO. 15-10. What a response. A break from Aaron Smith saw him find Ben in support and from the recycled ball Sopoaga chipped across to a scoring Naholo.
33'
CONVERSION, SHARKS, ZEILINGA. 10-10. We are level.
32'
TRY, SHARKS, MTAWARIRA. 10-8. There it is. Power from the Sharks and it's Tendai Mtawarira crashing over for them.
31'
Still they bang on the door, this time from just five metres out.
29'
The Sharks will have decent territory here after Mark Reddish collapses a maul in the visitors half. Now can they launch that dangerous set-piece with Coetzee at the tail off this line-out?
25'
PENALTY, SHARKS, ZEILINGA. 10-3. Tom Franklin is caught offside from a knock-on so here's Zeilinga from 40 metres out.
22'
PENALTY, HIGHLANDERS, SOPOAGA. 10-0. Hands on the ground from flanker Etienne Oosthuizen means it's a simple shot for Sopoaga, who makes no mistake from bang in front.
20'
Again Aaron Smith blows hot and cold as first his break off the scrum is good before a loose pass soon after allows the Sharks an easy out.
18'
They might not have to wait long after Lewies spills one in his own 22. Highlanders scrum then and they are ten metres out.
16'
First Aaron now Ben as the full-back now breaks through the Sharks defence. Fortunately for the visitors they recover and keep the Highlanders at bay - for how long is now the question.
15'
Good and bad from scrum-half Smith as his dummy sees him break over halfway. However, his pass to the right is collected by Mvovo so the chance is blown. Sharks ball now, 40 out.
11'
No joy for the Sharks as Fekitoa lines up Mvovo with the big hit in midfield. That leads to the South Africans being sent back to their own 22 before Zeilinga kicks clear to halfway.
9'
The Sharks have recovered well from that early setback and pack down about 40 metres out. Reinach waits at the base.
6'
CONVERSION, HIGHLANDERS, SOPOAGA. 7-0. Fine kick.
5'
TRY, HIGHLANDERS, EVANS. 5-0. There's the first try of the game as quickly recycled ball sees Nasi Manu find his back-row colleague Evans on the left. Worrying for the Sharks.
4'
Now the Sharks clear their lines after a decent spell from the hosts. It will be a Highlanders line-out on the Sharks 22 now.
2'
And we're off with Lima Sopoaga sending the ball down to lock Lewies. The Sharks threaten early as the powerful Alberts sets up scrum-half Cobus Reinach but he chips ahead instead of passing to his winger. Highlanders line-out on their own 22.
0'
Hello and welcome to our live coverage of the Highlanders vs Sharks fixture in Dunedin. The hosts are looking to close the gap on the Chiefs and Hurricanes which would also strengthen their grip on the top six places. Meanwhile their South African visitors are fast approaching a win or bust stage of the season. Team news is coming up ahead of kick-off at 19:35 local time.
0'
Highlanders head coach Jamie Joseph makes seven changes as prop Josh Hohneck, lock Mark Reddish, back-row duo Dan Pryor and Gareth Evans, scrum-half Aaron Smith, outside centre Malakai Fekitoa and full-back Ben Smith all come in.
0'
Marco Wentzel will continue as Sharks captain but Bismarck du Plessis returns at hooker. Lourens Adriaanse joins him in the front-row while Stephan Lewies gets the nod over Mouritz Botha at lock. In the backline, JP Pietersen starts at outside centre ahead of Waylon Murray who drops down to the bench.
Jump to
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
