<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:19:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 18 tourists hurt in Turkish hot air balloon accident</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/18-tourists-hurt-in-Turkish-hot-air-balloon-accident-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A Turkish medical official says that 18 tourists have been hospitalised after a hot air balloon accident in the Cappadocia area of central Turkey.</Description>
        <MainBody>18 tourists hurt in Turkish hot air balloon accident
2015-06-26 14:19
Chinese man crashes balloon near disputed isles
Istanbul - A Turkish medical official says that 18 tourists were hospitalised after a hot air balloon accident in the Cappadocia area of central Turkey.
District medical director Dr Rahim Unlubay says that none of the tourists is in a critical situation. Nine have already been released from the hospital and he expects the rest to be released soon.
He confirmed Turkish media reports that there were foreigners among the injured Friday.
Turkish news agency DHA say the hot air balloon went down after being buffeted by winds and hitting an electrical wire.
Anadolu news agency says that 14 of the tourists were Chinese, two were American, one was Brazilian, two were Greeks and one was Turkish. It is not immediately clear which among them was injured.
Read more on:  turkey
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:19:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Obama to deliver eulogy as Charleston mourns attack victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Obama-to-deliver-eulogy-as-Charleston-mourns-attack-victims-20150626</Link>
        <Description>President Barack Obama was on Friday set to deliver a eulogy for the chief pastor gunned down in an apparent racially-motivated attack that shocked the nation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama to deliver eulogy as Charleston mourns attack victims
2015-06-26 14:19
Barack Obama. (Saul Loeb, AFP)
Charleston shooting: 4 000 pay respects to slain pastor
Charleston - President Barack Obama was on Friday set to deliver a eulogy for the chief pastor gunned down in an apparent racially-motivated attack that shocked the nation.
Obama will deliver the remarks for pastor Clementa Pinckney, who was gunned down along with eight other African Americans during Bible study in a historic church nine days ago.
The shooting was allegedly carried out by Dylann Roof, aged 21, a white supremacist.
The carnage renewed discussions of racism and hate groups in America and led to a furor over the controversial Confederate flag, which is present throughout the south but that many see as a symbol of racism.
For Obama, the shooting touched a particular nerve because it overlapped with two thorny issues in his presidency: gun control, which he never managed to overhaul, and racial divides.
Soon after the killings, a frustrated and angry Obama condemned the country's lack of action over mass shootings.
Several thousand people, including Vice President Joe Biden, are expected at the ceremony at a university in Charleston near the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church where the shooting took place.
Mourners held the first funeral services Thursday for some of the nine African Americans killed.
Hundreds filed past the open coffin of Ethel Lance, aged 70, at a funeral home in North Charleston, ahead of an afternoon service for Sharonda Singleton, aged 45.
Emotions ran high at the Royal Missionary Baptist Church as friends and relatives bid a final farewell to Lance, a custodian at a Charleston arts center.
"I am here to tell you that we are stronger because we are together as a community," Reverend Norvel Goff told the mourners, the local Post and Courier newspaper reported.
Lance was later laid to rest at the Emanuel cemetery, where her children and grandchildren kissed her coffin and well-wishers threw roses into her grave.
Singleton, a speech pathologist, high school track coach and pastor at Emanuel, was remembered by a capacity crowd at the 2 000-seat Mount Moriah Missionary Baptist Church.
"She believed she could change every child," said South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, who attended both funeral services.
Seen in the pews were Jesse Jackson and Al Sharpton, two of the most recognizable civil rights activists in the United States today.
Thousands pay respects
On Wednesday, thousands filed past Pinckney's open coffin at the South Carolina legislature in the state capital Columbia, where he had served as a senator.
Services for the other victims are scheduled throughout the weekend and into next week.
Meanwhile, the campaign against the Confederate battle flag flying outside the South Carolina legislature picked up steam.
Adding his voice to the movement was College of Charleston president Glenn McConnell, a former Republican lieutenant governor and avid Civil War battle re-enactor.
As a state senator, McConnell favored positioning the flag alongside a Confederate memorial on the State House grounds 15 years ago.
"Today is a different time," he said, adding that the flag should come down as a "statement of courtesy and goodwill to all those who may be offended by it."
Some revere the Civil War-era flag as an emblem of Southern heritage, but others condemn it as a symbol of racial hatred and white supremacy.
Roof's getaway car, he was arrested a day after the shooting in North Carolina bore a Confederate license plate, and photos later emerged online of him brandishing the flag together with a handgun. He reportedly hoped to trigger a race war with the shooting.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, a Republican with Tea Party support, has come out in favor of removing the flag, but the final decision hinges on a vote by the state legislature.
Proliferation of petitions
MoveOn.org, a left-leaning campaign group, said more than 600 000 people have signed more than 50 petitions hosted on its website against the flag.
In Washington, US Attorney General Loretta Lynch said it was too early to say whether Roof will face federal civil rights charges.
A hate crimes investigation is unfolding, she said, but "it's simply premature at this point to be able to announce" how Roof might be charged.
South Carolina has charged Roof with nine counts of murder, one for each victim. He remains in solitary confinement at a North Charleston jail.
Haley has said that she favors the death penalty for Roof if he is convicted.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:13:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Kuwaiti-mosque-hit-by-suicide-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber has blown himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida says on social media.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack
2015-06-26 13:13
(Ibraheem Rahim, AFP)
Dubai - A suicide bomber blew himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said on social media.
The newspaper said the attack targeted Imam al-Sadeq Mosque in the Sawaber district.
"Eight casualties have been taken to the Emiri hospital, two in critical condition," al-Jarida said on its Twitter feed, without giving a source.
Arab television stations al-Arabiya and Al Jazeera earlier reported that an explosion hit the mosque and caused several casualties.
Read more on:  kuwait | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
24.com publishes all comments posted on articles provided that they adhere to our Comments Policy . Should you wish to report a comment for editorial review, please do so by clicking the 'Report Comment' button to the right of each comment.
Comment on this story
"It just looks generally awful and uncomfortable."

Western Cape
BRO Resourcing
Apartments / Flats R 1495000
Sponsored links
RSS feeds News delivered really simply.
Mobile News24 on your mobile or PDA
E-mail Newsletters You choose what you want
News24 on Android Get the latest from News24 on your Android device.
SMS Alerts Get breaking news stories via SMS.
Blogs Your opinion on you, me and everyone.
TV Get us in your home, on your television.

 2015 24.com. All rights reserved.
There arenew storieson the homepage. Click here to see them.

Hello
Create Profile
Creating your profile will enable you to submit photos and stories to get published on News24.
Please provide a username for your profile page:
This username must be unique, cannot be edited and will be used in the URL to your profile page across the entire 24.com network.
Hello
* You must provide a display name.
Edit your avatar:
Select an image file on your computer (max 4MB):
* The image you selected could not be uploaded.
Tell us a bit about yourself:
* Your profile could not be saved at the moment. Please try again later.

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:11:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | ISIS executes over 3 000 in Syria in year-long 'caliphate' - monitor</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/ISIS-executes-over-3-000-in-Syria-in-year-long-caliphate-monitor-20150628</Link>
        <Description>The Islamic State group has executed more than 3 000 people in Syria, including hundreds of civilians, in the year since it declared its self-described "caliphate", a monitor has reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS executes over 3 000 in Syria in year-long 'caliphate' - monitor
2015-06-28 16:11
(File, AP)
Kuwait arrests suspects in mosque attack, mourns dead
Beirut - The Islamic State group has executed more than 3 000 people in Syria, including hundreds of civilians, in the year since it declared its self-described "caliphate", a monitor said on Sunday.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based group monitoring Syria's conflict, said it had documented 3 027 executions by ISIS since June 29 2014.
Among those executed are 1 787 civilians, including 74 children, said the Observatory.
Members of Sunni Shaitat tribe account for around half of the civilians murdered.
ISIS killed 930 members of the clan in Deir Ezzor last year after they rose up against the extremist Sunni Muslim group.
The toll also includes recent mass killings by ISIS in the Syrian Kurdish town of Kobane, which the jihadist group re-entered briefly this week after being expelled in January.
The monitor said it had counted at least 223 executions in the border town this week.
The Observatory also documented 216 ISIS executions of rival rebel factions and Kurdish fighters, as well as the executions of nearly 900 regime forces.
ISIS has also executed 143 of its own members it accused of crimes including spying, many of them captured as they were trying to desert the group, the Observatory said.
And at least 8 000 ISIS militants have been killed in battles and US-led air strikes, added the monitor.
ISIS emerged in Syria in 2013, growing from al-Qaeda's one-time Iraq affiliate and initially seeking to merge with al-Qaeda's Syrian affiliate al-Nusra Front.
When al-Nusra refused the merger, the two groups become rivals, and ISIS went on to announce its "caliphate" in territory in Syria and Iraq last year, proclaiming its leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi "Caliph Ibrahim".
Read more on:  al-qaeda | isis | syria
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:14:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Flash floods, landslides kill 23 in Bangladesh</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Flash-floods-landslides-kill-23-in-Bangladesh-20150628</Link>
        <Description>At least 23 people have died in flash floods and landslides triggered by heavy rains that lashed southeastern Bangladesh, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Flash floods, landslides kill 23 in Bangladesh
2015-06-28 15:14
(File: AP)
Flash floods kill 41 in western India
Dhaka - At least 23 people have died in flash floods and landslides triggered by heavy rains that lashed southeastern Bangladesh, officials said on Sunday.
Tens of thousands of people were marooned on higher ground as flood waters submerged areas around Cox's Bazar and the hilly district of Bandarban.
Local police official Habibur Rahman confirmed the toll to reporters after four more bodies were recovered from a river on Sunday.
Bangladesh - one of the world's most densely populated countries - is highly vulnerable to natural disasters, including cyclones, droughts, floods and earthquakes.
India, Bangladesh and China are most at risk from river floods, with an increasing number of people threatened because of climate change and economic growth in low-lying regions, a study said in March.
Read more on:  bangladesh | weather | floods
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:10:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Assad confidante dies of illness</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Assad-confidante-dies-of-illness-20150628</Link>
        <Description>Mohammed Nasif Khayrbik, a senior Syrian government security official close to President Bashar al-Assad, has died after a long illness, state media says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Assad confidante dies of illness
2015-06-28 14:10
Assad says ISIS has expanded since US air strikes began
Damascus - Mohammed Nasif Khayrbik, a senior Syrian government security official close to President Bashar al-Assad, died on Sunday morning after a long illness, state media said.
Khayrbik was a key confidante of the Assad family and the target of EU and US sanctions for his alleged role in putting down anti-government demonstrations and interfering in neighbouring Lebanon.
"The presidency announces the death this morning of retired general Mohammed Nasif Khayrbik, deputy vice-president of the republic, after a long illness," Syrian state television said.
Khayrbik's ties to Syria's ruling family go back to the days of Hafez al-Assad, Bashar's father and predecessor as president.
Khayrbik was an advisor to him, and oversaw ties with Iran, and well as US-Syrian relations.
He remained close to the presidential palace after Bashar al-Assad succeeded his father, and in the 1990s served as chief of the country's internal security.
In 2005, he was named vice-president for security affairs.
In 2007, he was targeted by US sanctions for allegedly aiding efforts by Damascus "to undermine Lebanese democracy".
And in May 2011, after security forces moved to put down protests against Assad's regime, Khayrbik was among the officials added to an EU travel ban and asset freeze list.
Read more on:  bashar al-assad | syria
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:10:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Episcopal Church elects first black presiding bishop</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Episcopal-Church-elects-first-black-presiding-bishop-20150628</Link>
        <Description>US Episcopal Church elects 1st African-American presiding bishop</Description>
        <MainBody>Episcopal Church elects first black presiding bishop
2015-06-28 14:10
Salt Lake City - The Episcopal Church elected its first African-American presiding bishop, choosing Bishop Michael Curry of North Carolina during the denomination's national assembly on Saturday. He will now lead a nearly 1.9 million-member denomination known for its history as the faith home of many of the US presidents.
The New York-based Episcopal Church is the US body of the Anglican Communion, an 80-million member worldwide fellowship of churches with roots in the Church of England.
Curry was elected in a vote by bishops at the Episcopal General Convention, the top legislative body of the church. Curry won in a landslide, earning 121 votes. The other three candidates had 21 votes or less. The decision was affirmed on a vote of 800-12 by the House of Deputies.
Curry will succeed Presiding Bishop Katharine Jefferts Schori, who will complete her nine-year term on 1 November. She was the first female presiding bishop and the first woman to lead an Anglican national church.
Curry, 62, has been bishop of North Carolina since 2000. He is known for his emphasis on evangelism, public service and social justice.
"This is beautiful," said Norberto "Bert" Jones, 65, a lay deputy and African American. "God works awesome wonders, man. We're getting to that point of understanding that it's not about color and culture, but what you bring to the table. "
Curry takes charge at a time when fewer Americans are formally affiliating with a particular religious group, contributing to steady membership declines in the Episcopal Church and other liberal Protestant groups.
Membership in the Episcopal Church has dropped by 18% over the last decade.
Next week, the convention will vote on eliminating gender-specific language from church laws on marriage so religious weddings can also be performed for same-sex couples. Clergy could decline to perform the ceremonies.
Read more on:  us | religion
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:08:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Confession in French beheading attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Confession-in-French-beheading-attack-20150628</Link>
        <Description>The man suspected of decapitating his boss in an attack on a gas factory in France has confessed to the grisly crime, sources close to the investigation say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Confession in French beheading attack
2015-06-28 13:08
Police release 1 of 4 suspects held over France attack
Paris - The man suspected of decapitating his boss in an attack on a gas factory in France has confessed to the grisly crime, sources close to the investigation said on Sunday.
Yassin Salhi, 35, "has also given details about the circumstances" surrounding the killing, according to the sources, who said he would be transferred to Paris for further questioning later Sunday by anti-terrorist police.
Salhi's confession came after it emerged the married father-of-three sent a gruesome selfie photo of himself and the severed head to a WhatsApp number in Canada.
Investigators have warned however that it could be a relay number and the intended recipient could be anywhere in the world.
After several hours of silence, Salhi has begun to open up to investigators about the assault, which came six months after 17 were killed in Islamist attacks in Paris that began with the Charlie Hebdo massacre.
On Friday morning, Salhi rammed his van into the US-owned Air Products factory near France's second city of Lyon in what President Francois Hollande said was a "terrorist" attack designed to blow up the whole building.
He was overpowered by a firefighter as he was trying to prise open a bottle of acetone in an apparent suicidal bid to destroy the factory.
Police then made the grisly discovery of the severed head of Salhi's boss, 54-year-old Herve Cornara, lashed to the gates of the factory near two flags on which were written the Muslim profession of faith.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls repeated that the world was engaged in a "war against terrorism".
"We cannot lose this war because it's fundamentally a war of civilisation. It's our society, our civilisation that we are defending," Valls told iTELE rolling news channel.
France is facing "a major terrorist threat" which needs to be fought "over the long-term", warned the prime minister.
It's not a question of whether there will be another attack, but "when" and "where", stressed Valls.
Day of bloodshed
Friday's attack came on a day of bloodshed on three continents that saw 38 people mown down on a Tunisian beach and 26 killed in a suicide attack in Kuwait.
The Islamic State extremist group has claimed responsibility for those two attacks but no group has said it carried out the French operation.
Sources close to the investigation said Salhi was radicalised more than a decade ago after contact with Muslim convert Frederic Jean Salvi - known as "Ali" - who is suspected of preparing attacks in Indonesia with al-Qaeda militants.
An autopsy on the victim has proved inconclusive, with experts unable to determine whether he was killed before being beheaded or decapitated alive.
The French probe is naturally focusing on Syria, where hundreds of people from France have gone to wage jihad, officials said.
Anti-terrorist authorities have identified 473 people who have left France to fight in Iraq or Syria and Valls said 1,800 people in France were "linked" in some way to the jihadist cause.
'Being here, together'
Nearly six months after the Charlie Hebdo massacre, the attack raised painful memories for France, which is still on high alert for potential repeats.
Around 200 people in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier - where the attack took place - staged a minute's silence in the victim's honour followed by a rousing and spontaneous rendition of the French national anthem.
One man, Philippe Ouastani, said he came to show solidarity with the victim. "It's unheard of to decapitate someone in the 21st century. What weapons do we have to combat that? Being here, together."
Another woman, wearing the Muslim headscarf, said she was "unable to speak" when she heard the news.
"These acts have got nothing to do with religion. The Prophet never said to kill innocent people," raged the woman, who asked to remain anonymous.
Trying to find the words to explain the killing to her 4-year-old son, she said: "There are naughty people who have done bad things. The police will put them in prison to punish them for their silly, silly actions."
Like the Charlie Hebdo attackers and Islamist Mohamed Merah who gunned down soldiers and Jewish children in the southwest city of Toulouse in 2012, Salhi had been known to French security services for "radicalisation" but slipped through the net.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said Friday Salhi had been investigated for links to radical Salafists in Lyon, but was not known to have participated in terrorist activities and did not have a criminal record.
Europe has for months been bracing for so-called "lone wolf" attacks by supporters of Islamic State, which has urged its followers to strike wherever they can.
France, which has the highest Muslim population in Europe, last week passed a controversial new spying law granting sweeping powers to snoop on citizens.
Read more on:  france
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:00:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Bus carrying British children crashes in Belgium</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Bus-carrying-British-children-crashes-in-Belgium-20150628</Link>
        <Description>A British bus with 34 children aboard has overturned and crashed on a motorway in Belgium, killing at least one person, it has been reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus carrying British children crashes in Belgium
2015-06-28 12:00
Multimedia    User Galleries    News in Pictures Send us your pictures  Send us your stories
Brussels - A British bus with 34 children aboard overturned and crashed on a motorway in Belgium on Sunday morning, killing at least one person, Belgian media reported.
Photos show children were still trapped in the vehicle, which was lying on its side on the E40 motorway that runs to the Channel ferry ports and Channel Tunnel, public radio channel RTBF said.
Police were not available for immediate comment.
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Kuwait mosque bomber was Saudi national - ministry</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Kuwait-mosque-bomber-was-Saudi-national-ministry-20150628</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber who carried out a deadly attack claimed by the Islamic State group on a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait was a Saudi national, the interior ministry has said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait mosque bomber was Saudi national - ministry
2015-06-28 12:01
Kuwaiti emergency personnel pull a man on stretchers past security forces outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers in Kuwait City. (AFP)
Multimedia    User Galleries    News in Pictures Send us your pictures  Send us your stories
Kuwait City- A suicide bomber who carried out a deadly attack claimed by the Islamic State group on a Shi'ite mosque in Kuwait was a Saudi national, the interior ministry said Sunday.
In a statement carried by the official KUNA news agency, the ministry identified the attacker as Fahd Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Qaba'a.
IS claimed the Friday attack, which killed 26 and wounded 227 worshippers at the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:00:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Taiwan water park blast 'hell' - witness</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Taiwan-water-park-blast-hell-witness-20150628</Link>
        <Description>Witnesses have described the scene at a Taiwan water park as "hell" after a ball of fire ripped through a crowd, with authorities putting the number of injured at more than 500.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan water park blast 'hell' - witness
2015-06-28 12:00
Two men walk at the explosion site of the water park in Pali district, in New Taipei City. (Sam Yeh, AFP)
Nearly 200 injured amid fire explosion in Taiwan
Taipei - Witnesses described the scene at a Taiwan water park as "hell" after a ball of fire ripped through a crowd, with authorities putting the number of injured at more than 500 on Sunday, almost 200 of them seriously.
The number of those injured in the blast late Saturday, which came as coloured powder being sprayed on the partygoers ignited, more than doubled as authorities began to track down victims who had taken themselves to hospital or been ferried there by others.
Horrifying amateur video footage showed crowds of young revellers dancing in front of a stage and cheering as clouds of green and yellow powder covered them at the "colour party".
But their joy turned to terror when the powder suddenly erupted into flames engulfing them in an inferno as they ran screaming for their lives.
Some were dressed only in swimwear and images from the scene show many with severe burns being tended by those who escaped.
One male student who sustained minor injuries described the scene as "hell".
"There was blood everywhere, including in the pool where lots of the injured were soaking themselves for relief from the pain," he told reporters.
His visibly shaken girlfriend added: "I saw lots of people whose skin was gone."
Ambulances had struggled to reach the scene, and victims were carried away on rubber rings and inflatable dinghies as friends desperately tried to get them out.
Bystanders poured bottles of water on the scorched skin of the injured. Trails of bloody footprints leading away from the stage remained.
Around 1 000 spectators had been at the Color Play Asia event at the Formosa Fun Coast water park, just outside the capital Taipei, according to officials.
One male witness told local news channel CTI: "It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running."
Lee Lih-jong, deputy chief of the health bureau of the New Taipei City government, said 519 people had been injured with 190 of them seriously hurt.
The severely wounded are being treated in intensive care units at 37 different hospitals.
"The reason why the burns were so severe was that in addition to burns to the skin, there were also injuries caused by burns to the respiratory organs from the large amount of colour powder inhaled," Lee told AFP.
"The next 24 hours will be critical for those severely injured."
Young victims
One father broke down as he told how his daughter was in intensive care with third degree burns.
"She was attending a music concert... why would there be an explosion?" he wept bewildered.
"More than 80% of her body has been scorched," he told reporters.
The man, who was not named, lashed out at authorities saying they had not contacted him or offered any help.
The health bureau's Lee said details of the ages of the victims were not yet available, "but all looked very young, in their 20s or even younger".
Media reports said some victims had suffered burns to more than 40 percent of their bodies.
"Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage," said a spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department.
Deputy fire chief Chen Chung-yueh said Sunday the blast may have been caused by "sparks from machinery or lighting equipment".
Five people including event manager Lu Chung-chi were detained by police.
They are now being questioned by prosecutors on charges of offences against public safety and negligence of duties that caused severe injuries, a police spokesman said.
Color Play Asia has also run other "colour parties" in Taiwan in the past two years.
Taiwan's premier Mao Chih-kuo, who visited the injured Sunday, ordered that all such events be banned unless their safety could be assured.
Read more on:  taiwan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:44:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 1 dead, 8 rescued after boat goes over US dam</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/1-dead-8-rescued-after-boat-goes-over-US-dam-20150628</Link>
        <Description>One man has died and eight other people have been rescued after their boat went over a dam in the state of Maryland, it has been reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>1 dead, 8 rescued after boat goes over US dam
2015-06-28 10:44
Ambulance photo from Shutterstock
Multimedia    User Galleries    News in Pictures Send us your pictures  Send us your stories
Washington - One man died and eight other people were rescued on Saturday after their boat went over a dam in the state of Maryland, US media reported.
The incident on Lake Linganore left four people desperately hanging onto the dam for their lives, NBC news said, citing Frederick County Fire and Rescue Services Division Captain Kevin Fox.
The four were rescued, along with three more who were pulled from the dam's spillway by helicopter and another who was pulled out by boat.
Maryland Department of Natural Resources Police said the 62-year-old victim's body had been recovered after becoming trapped underwater by the force of the dam, according to NBC.
Fox told ABC News that residents heard people calling for help and reported the incident around 18:30 (22:30 GMT).
The cause of the accident was unknown but occurred amid heavy flooding.
Lake Linganore is located around 72km northwest of Washington.
Read more on:  us
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:55:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Cameron expresses sympathies to France over factory incident</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Cameron-expresses-sympathies-to-France-over-factory-incident-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Prime Minister David Cameron has spoken to President Francois Hollande to convey his sympathies over what a British government source said appeared to be an appalling incident at a gas factory in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cameron expresses sympathies to France over factory incident
2015-06-26 12:55
David Cameron. (File, AFP)
French police search for 2nd man in factory attack
Brussels - Prime Minister David Cameron spoke to President Francois Hollande on Friday to convey his sympathies over what a British government source said appeared to be an appalling incident at a gas factory in France.
"The Prime Minister has just spoken to President Hollande to express his sympathies for what looks like an appalling incident there," the source said.
"It clearly looks an extremely concerning situation and our thoughts are with all those affected by it."
#FRANCE #LIVE President #Hollande says- #Grenoble attack was carried out by one person, possibly aided by another. pic.twitter.com/Luw2U4kLO5
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:58:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Italy's Renzi slams EU leaders over migrant quotas</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Italys-Renzi-slams-EU-leaders-over-migrant-quotas-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi has launched a furious broadside at fellow EU leaders for failing to help deal with a tide of Mediterranean migrants, sources say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy's Renzi slams EU leaders over migrant quotas
2015-06-26 12:58
Matteo Renzi. (File: AFP)
Italy rescues 4 500 migrants, 10 die
Brussels - Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi launched a furious broadside at fellow EU leaders on Thursday for failing to help deal with a tide of Mediterranean migrants, sources said.
"If that's your idea of Europe, you can keep it," Renzi told his 27 counterparts at a European Union summit in Brussels, Italian sources told AFP.
"Either give us solidarity or don't waste our time," they quoted him as saying.
Renzi lashed out after the EU leaders at the summit failed to reach a consensus on mandatory quotas for migrants who land in frontline states like Italy, Greece and Malta.
They rejected European Commission proposals that 40 000 Syrian and Eritrean asylum-seekers who have already arrived in Europe should be redistributed according to a compulsory system.
"If you don't want to take the 40 000 you are not fit to be called Europe," added Renzi.
More than 100,000 migrants have crossed the Mediterranean so far this year, most of them landing in Italy, Greece and Malta who say their EU peers should share more of the burden.
The EU held an emergency summit on April 23 after around 800 migrants died when their boat sank in one of the worst disasters of its kind in the Mediterranean.
Renzi's comments came after an Italian mayor on the frontline of the crisis said failing to provide asylum seekers with safe passage to the EU was tantamount to genocide.
Tensions erupted between Italy and France recently over a crisis that saw hundreds of refugees blocked at the border between the two countries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:58:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Boston bomber Tsarnaev arrives at Colorado penitentiary</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Boston-bomber-Tsarnaev-arrives-at-Colorado-penitentiary-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev has arrived at the US Penitentiary in Florence, Colorado, a day after he was sentenced to death.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston bomber Tsarnaev arrives at Colorado penitentiary
2015-06-26 12:58
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev sits as survivors and victim's family members address the court before the US District Judge in Boston. (Jane Flavell Collins, AP)
Dozens to speak at Boston bomber's sentencing
Boston - Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev arrived at the US Penitentiary in Florence, Colorado, on Thursday, a day after he was sentenced to death.
A spokesperson for the US Department of Justice confirmed that Tsarnaev was being held at the high-security facility.
The penitentiary is in the same prison complex as the ADX, a Supermax prison, but is a different institution.
After a judge formally imposed a jury's recommendation of the death penalty on Wednesday, Assistant US Attorney William Weinreb said Tsarnaev is eventually expected to go to the death row unit at the US Penitentiary in Terre Haute, Indiana.
Oklahoma City bomber Timothy McVeigh was also put to death at the facility, and more than 50 other people are awaiting execution.
Tsarnaev could spend years or even decades there as his appeal makes its way through the court system.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:45:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | French police search for 2nd man in factory attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-police-search-for-second-man-in-factory-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French police are searching for a second man after arresting one man following a suspected Islamist attack on a chemical factory in the south-east of the country, a local newspaper reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>French police search for 2nd man in factory attack
2015-06-26 12:27
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon. (Philippe Desmazes, AFP)
France opens terrorism investigation after attack
Paris - French police are searching for a second man after arresting one man following a suspected Islamist attack on a chemical factory in the south-east of the country, a local newspaper reports.
A helicopter is sweeping the area around the Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier after the attackers drove a car onto the site, ramming gas tanks and causing an explosion and a fire, according to Le Dauphine Libere.
An emergency unit has been set up at a local hospital to treat the many injuries. A decapitated body was found at the scene, with the head placed on the factory's fence.
The Public Prosecutor in Paris has opened a terrorism investigation.
Read more on:  france | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:40:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Hollande returning to France from EU summit after terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Hollande-returning-to-France-from-EU-summit-after-terror-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French President Francois Hollande will return home early from an EU summit after a suspected Islamist attack on a factory in eastern France, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hollande returning to France from EU summit after terror attack
2015-06-26 12:40
French President Francois Hollande. (File, AFP)
At least 1 death reported in suspected Islamist attack in France
Brussels - French President Francois Hollande was to return home early from an EU summit on Friday after a suspected Islamist attack on a factory in eastern France, officials said.
"He will return early this afternoon and is in constant contact with Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve and the security services," the official said, adding that he would make a statement to the press in Brussels before 11:00.
Explosions at scene of decapitation in Grenoble, France: http://t.co/KQnHNj965V pic.twitter.com/r0fpxzNExP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:34:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France PM tightens security measures on 'sensitive' sites after attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/France-PM-tightens-security-measures-on-sensitive-sites-after-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French Prime Minister Manuel Valls has ordered heightened security measures at 'sensitive sites' near the gas factory that was attacked in eastern France.</Description>
        <MainBody>France PM tightens security measures on 'sensitive' sites after attack
2015-06-26 12:34
French prime minister Manuel Valls. (Christophe Ena, AP)
Man decapitated in attack on French gas factory
Paris - French Prime Minister Manuel Valls ordered heightened security measures on Friday at "sensitive sites" near the gas factory that was attacked in eastern France.
Valls, who is on an official trip to South America, asked Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve to head to Saint-Quentin Fallavier, the site of the attack, the premier's entourage said.
According to Reuters, the French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was heading to the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30km southeast of the city of Lyon.
Islamist flag found after man killed in attack in France ( http://t.co/Fyx3xnbL9p ) http://t.co/DYA1tkNumh pic.twitter.com/I44ReTTTv2
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:23:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France opens terrorism investigation after attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/France-open-terrorism-investigation-after-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>France opened a terrorism investigation after an attack at a gas factory left one person decapitated and multiple people wounded, officials say. One official says banners with Arabic writing were found near the body.</Description>
        <MainBody>France opens terrorism investigation after attack
2015-06-26 12:23
Hollande condemns violent French protests against Uber
Paris - France opened a terrorism investigation after an attack at a gas factory Friday left one person decapitated and multiple people wounded, officials said. One official said banners with Arabic writing were found near the body.
Two French officials said the attack began mid-morning when two men crashed a car into the entrance of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier in southeastern France, hitting gas canisters and touching off an explosion.
One of the attackers was arrested, they said. It was unclear what happened to the other attacker.
The decapitated body and banners with Arabic inscriptions were found near the factory entrance, one of the officials said.
Both officials spoke condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the news media.
In a statement, France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, which he said was carried out by "a terrorist group."
France went on high alert after an attack in January that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including the Islamic extremist attackers.
Police arrest 1 in apparent Islamist attack on factory near Grenoble, France http://t.co/DYHAuMaZjo (Illustration) pic.twitter.com/W2XzlQsQ3p
Read more on:  france | security
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:44:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Rockets from Yemen kill Saudi border guard</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Rockets-from-Yemen-kill-Saudi-border-guard-20150628</Link>
        <Description>A Saudi soldier has been killed in a rocket attack on the kingdom's border with Yemen, where Riyadh is leading an air war against Iran-backed rebels, the interior ministry says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rockets from Yemen kill Saudi border guard
2015-06-28 10:44
Saudi Arabia says it has shot down Scud missile
Riyadh - A Saudi soldier was killed in a rocket attack on the kingdom's border with Yemen, where Riyadh is leading an air war against Iran-backed rebels, the interior ministry said.
The rocket fire in the southern city of Jazan killed Faisal Mohammed Belqasem Maqaadi and wounded another soldier, an interior ministry spokesman said in a statement carried by the official SPA news agency late on Saturday.
It did not specify the source of the fire but cross-border shelling by Yemeni rebels has become common since Riyadh launched an air campaign against them in late March.
At least 44 people, civilians and troops, have now lost their lives in shelling and skirmishes along the Saudi side of the border since the campaign began.
Last week, three Saudi soldiers and an Emirati were killed in the border area.
Read more on:  saudi arabia | yemen
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:13:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France attack: Severed head covered in Arabic writing</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Arabic-writing-on-severed-head-pinned-to-factory-gates-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French authorities have found a man's decapitated head covered in Arabic writing attached to the gates of a gas factory, legal sources say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan president condemns Charlie Hedbo cartoon
Paris - French authorities found a man's decapitated head covered in Arabic writing attached to the gates of a gas factory that was attacked Friday, legal sources said.
The suspected attacker was arrested and was known to intelligence services, the sources said. Authorities are in the process of investigating whether he had an accomplice.
According to AFP, the suspect entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices.
Police said it was unclear whether the attacker was acting alone, or had accomplices.
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found at the scene."
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested, according to sources close to the enquiry, who said he was known to the security services.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
Charlie Hebdo
Prime Minister Manuel Valls ordered increased security measures at all sensitive sites in the area.
Two Islamist brothers attacked the satirical magazine, killing 12. A policewoman and four hostages in a Jewish supermarket were also killed during the three-day attacks.
The January attacks drew record crowds onto the streets of Paris in a historic "march against terrorism".
Nearly four million people marched through the streets of France and more than 1.5 million in the French capital along with dozens of world leaders to express defiance in the wake of the attacks.
France has a high proportion of people that have gone to fight alongside Islamists in Iraq and Syria and has been on alert for possible attacks on its soil since the Charlie Hebdo attacks.
Earlier this week, the country passed a controversial new spying law granting sweeping powers to snoop on citizens.
The new French law allows authorities to spy on the digital and mobile communications of anyone linked to a "terrorist" inquiry without prior authorisation from a judge, and forces Internet service providers and phone companies to give up data upon request.
Intelligence services will have the right to place cameras and recording devices in private dwellings and install "keylogger" devices that record every key stroke on a targeted computer in real time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:51:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Man decapitated in attack on French gas factory</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-gas-factory-attacked-by-Islamist-man-decapitated-20150626</Link>
        <Description>An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others Friday at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in attack on French gas factory
2015-06-26 11:48
(Shutterstock)
Charlie Hebdo says prize protest a 'misunderstanding'
Saint-Quentin-Fallavier - An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others on Friday at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source.
The suspected attacker entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said. A decapitated body was found nearby the factory, another source said.
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found on the scene".
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested, according to sources close to the enquiry.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack occurred around 10:00, according to local media.
The attack came nearly six months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January that started with a shooting at satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo.
Two Islamist brothers attacked the satirical magazine, killing 12. A policewoman and four hostages in a Jewish supermarket were also killed during the three-day attacks.
The attacks drew record crowds out on the streets of Paris days in a historic "march against terrorism".
Read more on:  france | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:52:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Jail time for those who break new S Korea MERS law</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Jail-time-for-those-who-break-new-S-Korea-MERS-law-20150626</Link>
        <Description>South Korea has introduced a new law designed to curb a MERS outbreak, imposing jail sentences on those who defy anti-infection measures in a crisis that has now left 31 dead.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jail time for those who break new S Korea MERS law
2015-06-26 11:52
Visitors wearing masks as a precaution against MERS. (Lee Jin-man. AP)
North Korea claims it has cure for MERS, Ebola, Aids
Seoul - South Korea has introduced a new law designed to curb a MERS outbreak, tightening quarantine restrictions and imposing jail sentences on those who defy anti-infection measures in a crisis that has now left 31 dead.
Under the new law, passed in parliament late on Thursday, people infected with the virus who lie to state investigators about how they came into contact with the disease will face a fine or a prison sentence.
"False testimony would entail up two years in prison or $18 000 in fines," said the new law, which replaces the fine that could be meted out to anyone who did not tell the truth under previous legislation.
"Interviewees will [now] feel compelled to provide honest answers."
The new law also strengthens officials' power to restrict the movement of infected people and close contaminated facilities, with offenders who refuse to follow their orders also facing two years in prison or a $18 000 fine.
The number of state health workers in charge of preventing outbreaks and tracing them will also be doubled to more than 60.
Government failure
The legislation comes as South Korea's government is facing criticism for failing to stop the MERS outbreak, which has now become the largest ever outside Saudi Arabia.
Two new fatalities were reported on Friday, the health ministry said - both women, aged 79 and 80, who had existing health conditions.
A doctor at Seoul's Samsung Medical Centre, the hospital to which nearly half of all infections have been traced, was also confirmed to have contracted the disease.
The hospital earlier this week decided to extend indefinitely a 12-day suspension of normal services as patients, doctors and visitors continued to be diagnosed with the disease.
The latest fatalities brought the total death toll to 31, the health ministry said, with 181 people diagnosed with the deadly virus since the first case emerged on May 20.
Of those diagnosed, aside from the number of dead, 81 have recovered and 69 are still being treated, including 13 listed in critical condition.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:53:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Politician sentenced in killing of Colombian journalist</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Politician-sentenced-in-killing-of-Colombian-journalist-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A Colombian court has sentenced a state legislator to 36 years and three months in prison as the mastermind behind the killing of a well-known journalist.</Description>
        <MainBody>Politician sentenced in killing of Colombian journalist
2015-06-26 11:53
Jail bars. (File photo, AP)
Journalist kidnapped, killed in India
Bogota - A Colombian court has sentenced a state legislator to 36 years and three months in prison as the mastermind behind the killing of a well-known journalist.
Ferney Tapasco was convicted in the 2002 shooting death of Orlando Sierra, the deputy editor of La Patria newspaper in Manizales, about 165 kms northeast of Bogota. The sentence was announced on Wednesday.
The Committee to Protect Journalists on Thursday praised the sentencing, which came after years of delays and a series of questioned rulings in the case.
Sierra had been a harsh critic of politicians in the region.
One of the witnesses in the case testified that Tapasco paid for Sierra to be killed.
Read more on:  columbia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US jury finds 'gay conversion' therapy fraudulent</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/US-jury-finds-gay-conversion-therapy-fraudulent-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A nonprofit organisation that claims it could turn gay men straight has violated the New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act, a jury concluds in a civil trial that an attorney for the plaintiffs called 'a momentous event' for LGBT rights.</Description>
        <MainBody>US jury finds 'gay conversion' therapy fraudulent
2015-06-26 11:00
(Peter Morrison, AP)
Moroccan men jailed for kissing in public: NGO
Jersey City - A nonprofit organisation that claimed it could turn gay men straight violated New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act, a jury concluded on Thursday in a civil trial that an attorney for the plaintiffs called "a momentous event" for LGBT rights.
The jury said that Jews Offering New Alternatives for Healing, co-founder Arthur Goldberg and counsellor Alan Downing made misrepresentations and engaged in unconscionable business practices.
Three men and two parents were awarded about $72 000 in damages. The judge will rule later on their request to revoke the company's license, plaintiffs' attorneys said.
"This is a momentous event in the history of LGBT rights," attorney David Dinielli said. "The same lies that motivate gay conversion therapy motivate homophobia, that gay people are broken and need to be fixed. The strength of our plaintiffs brought that to light."
Attorneys for the plaintiffs argued during the trial that the group, known by the acronym JONAH, claimed a success rate that wasn't backed up by actual statistics and used therapy methods that had no scientific basis, including having one client beat a pillow, meant to represent his mother, with a tennis racket.
In an emailed statement, defense attorney Charles LiMandri called the verdict "a sad day, not just for my clients, but for America."
LiMandri said he would "seek justice on appeal".
Read more on:  us | gay rights
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:01:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Erdogan denies ISIS launched attack on Kobane from Turkey</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Erdogan-denies-ISIS-launched-attack-on-Kobane-from-Turkey-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has dismissed as propaganda accusations that ISIS fighters had been allowed to cross from Turkey into Syria to launch a fresh assault on the symbolic battleground town of Kobane.</Description>
        <MainBody>Erdogan denies ISIS launched attack on Kobane from Turkey
2015-06-26 11:01
(File, AP)
ISIS video places UK hostage in Kobane
Ankara - Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on Thursday dismissed as "propaganda" accusations that Islamic State fighters had been allowed to cross from Turkey into Syria to launch a fresh assault on the symbolic battleground town of Kobane.
"We condemn the heinous attack by the terrorist ISIS organisation that targeted innocent civilians in the city of Kobane," Erdogan said in a speech.
Dozens of civilians and fighters on both sides were killed when the ISIS jihadists made a surprise return to Kobane on Thursday, detonating a suicide car bomb near the border and battling Kurdish fighters in the city. Two more bombs exploded later in the day.
Claims circulating on the Internet suggested several cars loaded with IS militants passed through the Mursitpinar border crossing in Turkey to make their way into Kobane.
Describing those allegations as "defamation and propaganda", Erdogan said: "No one has the right to link Turkey to terrorist organisations".
Trending topic on Twitter
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said at least 35 civilians and Kurdish fighters were killed in the car bomb and subsequent fighting in the centre and south of the town, along with 22 IS militants.
Turkish officials meanwhile said four victims had died in Turkish hospitals while 135 wounded received treatment on the Turkish side of the border.
The Turkish government said video footage taken from Turkish border security units and broadcast by the state-run Anatolia news agency showed a bomb-laden car did not pass through the Turkish border crossing.
But Kurdish activists accused Turkey on social media of assisting the ISIS group, with the hashtag #TerroristTurkey becoming a trending topic on Twitter.
Arin Shekhmos, a Syrian Kurdish activist, told AFP in Beirut earlier that ISIS had entered Syria from Turkey through the Mursitpinar border crossing.
He claimed the ISIS forces were wearing Kurdish People's Protection Units (YPG) uniforms as a disguise when they entered.
'Back and forth'
The accusations come amid growing tensions between Syrian Kurds and Turkey.
Turkey says Syrian Kurdish forces who recently made gains in Syria against IS are linked to the Kurdistan Workers' Party (PKK), which for decades has waged a deadly insurgency inside Turkey.
Western states have repeatedly accused Turkey of not doing enough to halt the flow of jihadists in both directions across its 911km border with Syria.
Turkey fiercely rejects the accusations, saying it is making every effort to secure a long border and in turn has accused the West of not playing its part to shoulder the burden of hosting refugees from Syria.
But Turkey's opposition pro-Kurdish Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP) accused the authorities of long allowing IS fighters back and forth across the border.
"IS has in every period being using the Turkish border. It's been going back and forth. There's lots of proof of this," HDP co-chair Figen Yuksekdag said.
"It's not logical to think that ISIS is no longer using the border when it has been doing so for so long before," she added.
Kurdish forces backed by US-led air strikes and peshmerga fighters from Iraq scored a major victory in January by winning a hugely symbolic battle for Kobane.
Months of fighting has prompted a mass exodus of local residents, with some 200 000 fleeing across the border into Turkey.
At least 35 000 Syrians returned home after Kobane's liberation, another Turkish official told AFP.
The official added that the border crossing of Mursitpinar that lies opposite Kobane has remained closed except for limited use by civilians returning after January.
He also said there was no sign of any new refugee influx so far.
Read more on:  isis | turkey | syria
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:56:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Putin calls Obama to discuss Ukraine, ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Putin-calls-Obama-to-discuss-Ukraine-ISIS-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has called his US counterpart Barack Obama to discuss the conflict in Ukraine, ISIS's advances and a deal on Iran's nuclear programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin calls Obama to discuss Ukraine, ISIS
2015-06-26 09:56
(Alexei Druzhinin, AFP)
Russia to boost nuclear arsenal - Putin
Washington - Russian President Vladimir Putin called his US counterpart Barack Obama on Thursday to discuss the conflict in Ukraine, the Islamic State group's advances and a deal on Iran's nuclear program.
The crisis in Ukraine has triggered the worst standoff between Russia and the West since the Cold War, and the US said earlier this week it would deploy heavy weapons in central and eastern Europe for the first time.
The US announcement followed promises by Nato on Monday to step up its military presence in eastern Europe, against the backdrop of the conflict in Ukraine.
Putin, who has consistently denied backing the pro-Russian rebels in Ukraine, initiated the phone call with Obama, according to the White House.
"President Obama reiterated the need for Russia to fulfill its commitments under the Minsk agreements, including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," it said in a statement.
The crisis in Ukraine has killed 6 500 people in a little over a year and a peace deal struck in Minsk, Belarus has unravelled.
Obama and Putin also discussed Syria, where the self-proclaimed Islamic State group has made rapid gains, as well as historic negotiations between world powers and Iran over its disputed nuclear program.
"The leaders discussed the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria, and underscored the importance of continued P5+1 unity in ongoing negotiations to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon," the White House said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:56:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | High emotions as Charleston bury massacre victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/High-emotions-as-Charleston-bury-massacre-victims-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Emotions ran high as defiant mourners held the first funeral services for nine African Americans shot dead by a white alleged supremacist in a Charleston church.</Description>
        <MainBody>High emotions as Charleston bury massacre victims
2015-06-26 09:56
Mourners leave the wake of Senator Clementa Pinckney, one of the nine killed in last week's shooting, at Emanuel AME Church. (David Goldman, AP)
Alabama lowers Confederate flag
Charleston - Emotions ran high as defiant mourners held the first funeral services on Thursday for nine African Americans shot dead by a white alleged supremacist in a Charleston church.
Hundreds filed past the open coffin of Ethel Lance, aged 70, at a funeral home in North Charleston, ahead of an afternoon service for Sharonda Singleton, aged 45.
The deceased were among the Bible study group that was targeted in the June 17 massacre at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church.
Dylann Roof, aged 21, is charged with murder in connection with the multiple killings, which he reportedly hoped would trigger a race war between blacks and whites.
President Barack Obama is scheduled to deliver the eulogy at Friday's funeral of another victim, Emanuel's chief pastor Clementa Pinckney, aged 41.
Obama will also meet the families of some of the other victims.
There was raw emotion at the Royal Missionary Baptist Church as friends and relatives bid a final farewell to Lance, a custodian at a Charleston arts centre.
"I am here to tell you that we are stronger because we are together as a community," Reverend Norvell Goff told the mourners, the local Post and Courier newspaper reported.
Lance was later laid to rest at the Emanuel cemetery, where her children and grandchildren kissed her coffin and well-wishers threw roses into her grave.
Singleton, a speech pathologist, high-school track coach and pastor at Emanuel, was remembered by a capacity crowd at the 2 000-seat Mount Moriah Missionary Baptist Church.
"She believed she could change every child," said South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, who attended both funeral services.
Seen in the pews were Jesse Jackson and Al Sharpton, two of the most recognizable civil rights activists in the United States today.
Obama "will be mindful of not just how sad it is that those individuals were taken from us, but also use the occasion to celebrate their lives," White House spokesman Josh Earnest said.
"Many of them, in the way that they went about their day-to-day lives, I do think serve as a genuine inspiration to others about the way that they lived their lives and about the values that they sought to embody."
Thousands pay respects
Thousands have visited Pinckney's open coffin at the South Carolina legislature in the state capital Columbia, where he had served as a senator.
Services for the other victims are scheduled throughout the weekend and into next week.
Meanwhile, the campaign against the Confederate battle flag flying outside the South Carolina legislature picked up steam.
Adding his voice to the movement was College of Charleston president Glenn McConnell, a former Republican lieutenant governor and avid Civil War battle re-enactor.
As a state senator, McConnell favoured the positioning of the flag alongside a Confederate memorial on the State House grounds 15 years ago.
"Today is a different time," he said, adding that the flag should come down as a "statement of courtesy and goodwill to all those who may be offended by it."
Some revere the Civil War-era banner as an emblem of Southern heritage, but others condemn it as a symbol of racial hatred and white supremacy.
Roof's getaway car, he was arrested in North Carolina one day after the shooting bore a Confederate license plate, and photos later emerged online of him brandishing the flag together with a handgun.
Haley, a Republican with Tea Party support, has come out in favour of removing the flag, but the final decision hinges on a vote by the state legislature.
'Truly sorry'
Roof's relatives said they had been asked many questions about the massacre.
"As more information becomes available, we will do our best to answer them," read a statement widely circulated in US media.
"We would like to take this time to reflect on the victims and give their families time to grieve. We feel it would be inappropriate to say anything at this time other than that we are truly sorry for their loss."
In Washington, US Attorney General Loretta Lynch said it was too early to say whether Roof is liable to face federal civil rights charges.
A hate crimes investigation is unfolding, she said, but "it's simply premature at this point to be able to announce" how the case will be handled.
Roof has been charged with nine counts of murder, one for each victim, and he is being held in solitary confinement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:59:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | EU leaders agree to relocate 40 000 migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/EU-leaders-agree-to-relocate-40-000-migrants-20150626</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders have agreed to the principle of redistributing 40 000 asylum seekers across their bloc, but left the details to be hashed out later, amid hefty disagreement on whether member states should be obliged to take in the migrants.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU leaders agree to relocate 40 000 migrants
2015-06-26 08:59
(File, AFP)
EU approves military to tackle migrant smugglers
Brussels - EU leaders agreed early Friday to the principle of redistributing 40 000 asylum seekers across their bloc, but left the details to be hashed out later, amid hefty disagreement on whether member states should be obliged to take in the migrants.
Conflicts and repression in Africa and the Middle East have driven thousands of people to travel to the European Union in search of protection or a better life.
Many have lost their lives during attempts to cross the Mediterranean Sea, while the bulk of arrivals to the bloc have been concentrated in a handful of member states, stretching resources there. Less affected EU countries have been under pressure to show solidarity.
"Leaders agreed that 40 000 persons in need will be relocated from Greece and Italy to other states over the next two years," said EU President Donald Tusk, following late-night talks in Brussels.
A further 20 000 refugees will be resettled from outside the EU, such as displaced Syrians, the leaders agreed. EU interior ministers will finalize the scheme by the end of July, Tusk said.
But the summit discussion was bogged down by a fierce debate, after it became clear that several member states would oppose a mandatory scheme for the relocation of the 40,000 asylum seekers.
Frustration
"Passions are inflamed," one EU source said, as the talks dragged on into the early hours of Friday.
"If you do not agree with the 40 000, you do not deserve to be called Europe," Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi told his counterparts, according to another source. "Either there is solidarity, or please don't waste our time," he added.
Sources said tensions were further exacerbated by a showdown between EU President Donald Tusk and European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker over the decision-making process.
But the two top officials later played down their differences, locking arms as they walked to a joint press conference. Frustration was still evident, however.
Juncker said the leaders had reached a "modest" decision. "That we take hours to agree on the system to apply proves that Europe is not up to the ambitions that it declaims on every occasion," he added.
It is now expected that interior ministers will proceed with a voluntary redistribution scheme.
"Every country must offer its own contribution, and then afterwards we will see whether the sum of contributions allows us to reach the objective, and if it is not the case, corrections will have to be made," said French President Francois Hollande.
Tusk singled out circumstances in Hungary and Bulgaria, noting that they are also affected by "strong migratory flows," and said they would probably "be treated by us as specific cases when the time comes to distribute the pledges."
While attention has focused on the plight of migrants crossing the Mediterranean, the two eastern European countries have faced an influx of people crossing their land borders to reach the EU.
Hungary has the bloc's highest number of asylum requests, relative to population size, and Prime Minister Viktor Orban has been one of the strongest opponents of the proposed relocation scheme.
Earlier this week, Hungary controversially announced that it has stopped accepting asylum seekers being sent back to its territory after moving on to other EU countries.
EU rules stipulate that asylum claims must be processed in the member state where migrants first set foot.
Following the summit debate, German Chancellor Angela Merkel described migration as the "biggest challenge" that the EU had faced during her time in office.
"I see a huge task approaching us, and here it will be decided whether Europe is up to the task," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:58:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Hollande condemns violent French protests against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Hollande-condemns-violent-French-protests-against-Uber-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French President Francois Hollande has condemned violent protests against ride-booking app Uber after taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked highways but he says the service should be taken off the road.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hollande condemns violent French protests against Uber
2015-06-26 08:58
Taxi drivers in France protest over Uber services. (Loic Venance, AFP)
US not spying on France's Hollande - Kerry
Paris - French President Francois Hollande on Friday condemned violent protests against ride-booking app Uber after taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked highways but he said the service should be taken off the road.
Hollande described the demonstrations, in which US rocker Courtney Love was caught up, as "unacceptable violence in a democracy, in a country like France."
But Hollande, attending an EU leaders summit in Brussels, added: "UberPOP should be dissolved and declared illegal".
The service has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and it continues to operate.
Around 3,000 cabbies took part in the strike Thursday, blocking access to the capital's Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports, and preventing cars reaching train stations around the country.
Ten people were arrested, seven police officers were injured and 70 vehicles were damaged in clashes between Uber drivers and taxi drivers.
Taxi drivers are furious at what they see as unfair competition from Uber, which puts customers in touch with private drivers at prices lower than those of traditional taxis.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said after meeting taxi drivers' unions following a fraught day: "UberPOP is an illegal service, it must be closed down".
Until that was done, "the vehicles of UberPOP drivers should be systematically impounded when they are openly breaking the law", the minister said.
"Governing the country will never be done by the law of the jungle," Cazeneuve added.
One of the taxi drivers' representatives, Ibrahima Sylla, described the minister's words as "promises, again" and said the drivers were considering continuing the demonstrations.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, was caught up in a confrontation near Charles de Gaulle airport.
She tweeted that protesters "ambushed" her vehicle and "were holding our driver hostage".
She appealed to the French president in another message, writing "Francois Hollande where are the fucking police???"
"This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad," she added.
Two vehicles torched
In the most serious incident in Paris, one private chauffeur, who said he did not work for Uber "or any other app" was dragged from his van when he reached a blockade in the west of Paris.
Angry taxi drivers slashed the tyres of his vehicle, smashed a window and then set it and a chauffeur-driven van on fire.
Police eventually fired teargas to break up the protest on the western stretch of the ring road around the capital and cleared burning tyres.
Licensed cabbies say Uber is endangering their jobs by flooding the market with low-cost drivers.
One driver said the strikers had been driven to desperation.
"Taxi drivers, alright, they've got big mouths but normally they're not aggressive," said Malia, aged 50, who has driven a taxi for three years.
"But these guys have families to feed, debts. They've been pushed to the brink."
More peaceful protests took place at transport hubs in other major cities including Bordeaux, Marseille and Toulouse.
Cabbies argued that the disruption was justified.
"UberPOP is banned, but it's still here," cabbie Stephane Molla said in Bordeaux, southwest France.
Taxi drivers in France, like their colleagues in several other countries, have held a number of protests against the app, some of which have turned violent.
On at least two occasions in Strasbourg in eastern France last week, taxi drivers posed as customers in order to lure Uber drivers to isolated spots where they were assaulted by cabbies and their vehicles damaged.
In Paris, the government tried to strengthen its hand on Wednesday by obtaining a court order banning Uber from operating in the capital, but the company dismissed the move.
"We will fight it [in the courts] and we'll see what happens on appeal. For the time being it changes nothing, UberPOP can continue to operate," the head of Uber France, Thibaud Simphal, told the BFM Business channel.
San Francisco-based Uber, which offers several types of ride-sharing services, claims to have 400,000 UberPOP users in France.
However, its drivers do not pay taxes, do not need to undergo the 250 hours of training mandatory for French cabbies and do not require the same insurance as taxis.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:01:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in mosque attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Kuwait-arrests-driver-of-bomber-in-mosque-attack-20150628</Link>
        <Description>Kuwaiti police have arrested the driver who transported a suicide bomber to a Shi'ite mosque where he blew himself up, killing 26 and injuring 227 in an attack claimed by the Islamic State group.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in mosque attack
2015-06-28 09:01
Kuwait says security raised to highest after attack
Kuwait City - Kuwaiti police have arrested the driver who transported a suicide bomber to a Shi'ite mosque where he blew himself up, killing 26 and injuring 227 in an attack claimed by the Islamic State group, official media reported.
Authorities have also detained the owner of the house where the bomber was staying, a Kuwaiti national who subscribes to "fundamentalist and deviant ideology", the KUNA news agency said, citing a statement from the Interior Ministry.
The driver, named as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, was described as an "illegal resident" born in 1989, who took the bomber to the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City on Friday, it said.
The arrest came after thousands of Kuwaitis braved scorching summer heat on Saturday to attend the funerals of 18 out of 26 victims of the bombing, claimed by the Islamic State group.
The bodies of the remaining eight victims were flown to Iraq's Shiite holy city of Najaf for burial, State Minister for Cabinet Affairs Sheikh Mohammad Abdullah Al-Sabah said.
Draped in Kuwaiti flags, the bodies were borne by mourners chanting religious slogans.
Mourners turned out in large numbers despite the Ramadan daylight fast and as temperatures hit 45 degrees Celsius.
"This crowd is the proof that the objectives of the criminal act have failed," parliament speaker Marzouk al-Ghanem told reporters.
The mourners, who included women clad in black Islamic dress, carried Kuwaiti flags and black and green banners bearing religious slogans.
The health ministry said that 40 wounded are still in hospital following the attack, one of the country's worst bombings and its first ever on a mosque.
The interior ministry said authorities will "continue efforts to uncover the conspirators in this criminal act and to reveal all of the information and circumstances behind it".
Sunni solidarity
Two of the dead were Iranian, the Shi'ite-dominated Islamic republic's foreign ministry said.
In Iraq, relatives wept as the eight coffins arrived and were taken inside the airport terminal at Najaf, an AFP journalist said.
"We want to deliver a message to Daesh (an Arabic acronym for IS) that we are united brothers among the Sunnis and Shiites, and they cannot divide us," Abdulfatah al-Mutawwia, a Kuwaiti who lost his brother in the bombing, said in Iraq.
Friday's attack targeted Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City during Friday noon prayers.
Mosque official Abdulnabi Mansur said the victims flown to Iraq were seven Kuwaitis and a Saudi, and that they would be buried in the Wadi al-Salam cemetery surrounding the shrine of Imam Ali in Najaf.
In Kuwait, condolences were being accepted for three days from Saturday at the Grand Mosque, the largest place of worship for Sunni Muslims, in a show of solidarity.
Kuwait's emir, the government, parliament and political groups and clerics have all said the attack aimed to stir up sectarian strife in the emirate.
The radical Sunni group Islamic State considers Shiites to be heretics.
Shi'ites comprise a third of Kuwait's 1.3 million native population. Sunni religious and political groups were quick to condemn the attack.
The emir, Sheikh Sabah al-Ahmad al-Sabah, who visited the site immediately after the bombing, said the "criminal attack is a desperate and evil attempt targeting Kuwait's national unity".
Countries and organisations including the United Nations and the United States deplored the bombing.
Eight Islamist, liberal and Shi'ite political groups condemned the attack in a joint statement and called on the government to confront extremists.
Security measures
The government had briefed MPs about measures it has taken since the bombing, Sheikh Mohammad told reporters.
An interior ministry statement said, without elaborating, that an unspecified number of suspects were held for questioning in connection with the attack.
The cabinet announced after an emergency meeting on Friday that all security agencies and police had been put on alert to confront what it called "black terror".
Justice and Islamic Affairs Minister Yacoub al-Sane said additional security measures will be taken around mosques and places of worship.
National oil conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) said on Saturday it had raised security at oil facilities to maximum level.
Oil is Kuwait's main source of income, accounting for around 90 percent of public revenues.
The OPEC member says it sits on around 10% of global reserves and pumps around 2.8 million barrels of oil per day.
Read more on:  isis | kuwait
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:01:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 500+ hurt in Taiwan water park fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/500-hurt-in-Taiwan-water-park-fire-20150628</Link>
        <Description>The number of people injured in a fire at a Taiwan water amusement park has risen to 516, with more than 180 still in intensive care.</Description>
        <MainBody>500+ hurt in Taiwan water park fire
2015-06-28 09:01
Two men walk at the explosion site of the water park in Pali district, in New Taipei City. (Sam Yeh, AFP)
Nearly 200 injured amid fire explosion in Taiwan
Taipei - The number of people injured in a fire at a Taiwan water amusement park rose to 516 on Sunday, government officials said, with more than 180 still in intensive care.
Media reported four mainland Chinese and two foreigners were among those injured after Saturday's fire, during a party where up to 1 000 revellers were sprayed with coloured powder as they danced to music, seeking to escape the summer heat.
The blaze, which broke out around 20:30 at the Formosa Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder explode," he added, however.
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters, adding that 410 people were still in hospital on Sunday, with 194 being treated for serious injuries.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, wearing wet swimsuits and lying on inflatable plastic doughnuts. Television showed images of people running from sky-high flames.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims of the incident suffered burns to the limbs, with some passing out from the pain while others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and pictures showed.
"She is young. A student," sobbed the father of an 18-year-old girl with burns on 80% of her body, according to television footage.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
"We are very sorry about what happened and we will investigate the cause to find out who is responsible," Eric Chu, the mayor of New Taipei City, where the park is located, said on Saturday, adding that it had been ordered to shut down.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on its website on Sunday.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees Celsius in recent weeks.
Read more on:  taiwan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 08:28:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | One wounded in shooting at US gay pride event</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/One-wounded-in-shooting-at-US-gay-pride-event-20150628</Link>
        <Description>A bystander was shot at a gay pride event in San Francisco when an argument between several young men turned violent, US police say.</Description>
        <MainBody>One wounded in shooting at US gay pride event
2015-06-28 07:28
(Darko Vojinovic, AP)
San Francisco - Police say a bystander has been shot at a gay pride event in San Francisco when an argument between several young men turned violent.
Officer Carlos Manfredi says several people were detained for questioning after the shooting on Saturday evening.
The shooting triggered a chaotic scene as dozens of people ran screaming as officers carrying handguns rushed to the scene.
Manfredi says a 64-year-old man who was caught in the crossfire got shot in the arm. He was hospitalised in a stable condition.
Four shots were heard in a witness video posted online.
Manfredi says the argument had nothing to do with the gay pride event.
A concert that was part of the weekend-long gay pride celebration across the city was ending around the time of the shooting.
Read more on:  us
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:54:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Funerals held for 3 more Charleston shooting victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Funerals-held-for-3-more-Charleston-shooting-victims-20150627</Link>
        <Description>Funerals for three more victims of a deadly shooting during a Bible study group in South Carolina have been held at the church where they were slain.</Description>
        <MainBody>Funerals held for 3 more Charleston shooting victims
2015-06-27 22:54
Mourners file into the funeral of Cynthia Hurd, 54, at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church where her and  eight others were killed in a mass shooting in Charleston, South Carolina. (Joe Raedle, AFP)
1st funerals set for Charleston church shooting victims
Charleston - Funerals for three more victims of a deadly shooting during a Bible study group in South Carolina were being held Saturday at the church where they were slain.
Services were first held for 54-year-old Cynthia Hurd at the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, 11 days after a gunman entered the church and killed her and eight other people - all African-Americans. Police contend the attack was racially motivated.
Hurd, a long-time Charleston librarian, will be remembered as a tireless public servant and loving family member, speakers at her funeral said. Attendees included South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, US Senator Tim Scott and the Reverend Jesse Jackson, a leading civil rights activist.
"Her death will lead to change and Cynthia Hurd will be helping millions," said Charleston Mayor Joseph Riley Jr during a eulogy.
Riley remembered Hurd as a young girl serving ice cream. She went from serving people ice cream, he said, "to leading them to knowledge," as a librarian for almost 30 years.
Funerals for Tywanza Sanders, 26, and Susie Jackson, 87, were to take place at the church later in the day.
Obama eulogy
The funerals follow one on Friday for another victim, the Reverend Clementa Pinckney, the church's pastor, whose eulogy was delivered in person by President Barack Obama.
Obama sang a hymn of hope and spoke with the fervour of a preacher as he eulogized Pinckney, and minced no words in calling for an end to racial injustice and gun violence in the United States. Obama suddenly began singing the hymn "Amazing Grace," quickly joined by ministers and some of the thousands who packed into the arena at the College of Charleston in South Carolina.
The nation's first black president called for gun control and efforts to eliminate poverty and job discrimination, and said the Confederate battle flag  long a symbol of Southern pride  must be removed from places of honour.
"For many  black and white  that flag was a reminder of systemic oppression and racial subjugation. We see that now," he said during Pinckney's funeral.
Hours later, a woman was arrested early on Saturday on the grounds of the South Carolina Capitol in Columbia after scaling a flagpole to rip down a Confederate flag that flew at the Statehouse. Bree Newsome, 30, was arrested immediately afterward.
She and James Ian Tyson, 30, also of Charlotte, face misdemeanour charges in the incident.
The Confederate flag was carried by forces supporting the secessionist, pro-slavery southern states during the American Civil War.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:54:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Nearly 200 injured amid fire explosion in Taiwan</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Nearly-200-injured-amid-fire-explosion-in-Taiwan-20150627</Link>
        <Description>About 200 people have been injured after a fire suspected to have stemmed from the explosion of an unknown flammable powder occurred in a recreational park in northern Taiwan.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nearly 200 injured amid fire explosion in Taiwan
2015-06-27 22:54
(Shutterstock)
Taiwan fishing boat missing with 49 on board
Taipei - About 200 people were injured after a fire suspected to have stemmed from the explosion of an unknown flammable powder occurred in a recreational park in northern Taiwan, local media reported on Saturday.
The fire broke out at the centre of the stage when up to 1 000 people were having a colour play party - a festival of dance and music where revellers are sprayed with clouds of coloured powder. Footage from TV stations showed flames reaching into the sky with some people running to escape.
"178 people that have been injured have been sent to hospitals nearby. We are very sorry about what happened and we will investigate the cause to find out who is responsible," New Taipei City mayor Eric Chu told reporters.
"We have demanded the park shut down immediately for inspection," he said.
The number of injured could rise, local media said.
Read more on:  taiwan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:28:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Authorities identify 9 victims in deadly Alaska plane crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Authorities-identify-9-victims-in-deadly-Alaska-plane-crash-20150627</Link>
        <Description>A recovery crew has reached a remote site in southeast Alaska where a sightseeing plane crashed, killing all nine people aboard.</Description>
        <MainBody>Authorities identify 9 victims in deadly Alaska plane crash
2015-06-27 21:28
The Holland America Line cruise ship Westerdam sits in dock in Ketchikan, Alaska. Officials say eight passengers on an excursion off the ship and a pilot were in a plane that was found crashed against the granite rock face of a cliff northeast of Ket
Last MH17 crash remains arrive in Netherlands
Juneau - A recovery crew reached a remote site in southeast Alaska where a sightseeing plane crashed, killing all nine people aboard.
Chris John of the Ketchikan Volunteer Rescue Squad said on Friday that the aircraft was sitting at a steep angle and three members from his organization had to secure it so they could safely work to recover the bodies.
Eight cruise ship passengers and the pilot died when the DeHavilland DHC-3 Otter turboprop went down on Thursday in Misty Fjords National Monument near Ketchikan.
The cause of the crash remained under investigation.
Authorities tentatively identified the victims as Hal Cheney, 71, and Mary Doucette, 59, of Lodi, California; Glenda Cambiaso, 31, and Hugo Cambiaso, 65, of North Potomac, Maryland; June Kranenburg, 73, and Leonard Kranenburg, 63, of Medford, Oregon; Margie Apodaca, 63, and Raymond Apodaca, 70, of Sparks, Nevada; and the pilot, Bryan Krill, 64 of Hope, Idaho.
The plane crashed on a cliff above a lake in steep, muddy and slippery terrain, John said. The fuselage was largely intact but the wings and tail were separated or heavily deformed, he said.
On Thursday, the Coast Guard received a report that the plane was overdue. An emergency locator transmitter activated and a helicopter pilot later spotted the downed aircraft.
Wind and rain prevented any recovery on Thursday. Winds were not a concern on Friday but there was cloud cover.
A National Transportation Safety Board team was assembled to investigate the crash. Plans were being made to take them to the site on Saturday, John said.
Ketchikan-based airline Promech Air operated the shore excursion offered through Holland America Line. The eight passengers were travelling on the Westerdam on a seven-day cruise that had departed Seattle last Saturday.
"We are incredibly distressed by this situation, and our thoughts and prayers are with those onboard the plane and their families," Holland America said in a statement.
The airline echoed those sentiments.
"There is nothing I can say that can alleviate the pain and overwhelming sense of loss that we and the loved ones of those affected are feeling," Marcus Sessoms, president of Promech Air, said in a statement.
The ship left Ketchikan on Thursday night and was expected back in Seattle on Saturday.
Promech's website advertises tours of the more than 7 770-square-kilometre Misty Fjord National Monument in its floatplanes.
"Towering granite cliffs, 1 000-foot waterfalls, lush and remote valleys and serene crystalline lakes make up this incredible landscape," it says.
Read more on:  alaska
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 22:28:35 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Kuwait conducts mass funeral for bombing victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Kuwait-conducts-mass-funeral-for-bombing-victims-20150627</Link>
        <Description>Thousands of people in Kuwait have taken part in a mass funeral procession for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing that targeted a Shi'ite mosque.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait conducts mass funeral for bombing victims
2015-06-27 21:28
(AP)
White House condemns France, Tunisia, Kuwait attacks
Kuwait - Thousands of people in Kuwait took part in a mass funeral procession on Saturday for 27 people killed in a suicide bombing that targeted a Shi'ite mosque a day earlier.
Police in Kuwait said they are interrogating a number of suspects with possible links to the suicide bombing, which was claimed by an affiliate of the Islamic State group.
An Interior Ministry statement on Saturday said police arrested the owner of the car that was used by the bomber to drive to the Imam Sadiq Mosque in Kuwait City, where he detonated his device inside among the worshippers. Police did not say how many suspects are being interrogated.
The bombing, which also wounded more than 200 male worshippers who were taking part in midday Friday prayers, was the first terrorist attack in Kuwait in more than two decades.
The government helped plan Saturday's mass funeral for those killed. Thousands of Sunnis and Shiites from across the country took part in the procession and prayer at Kuwait's Grand Mosque. Many carried the Kuwaiti flag; others a simple black flag to signify mourning. Some in the crowd chanted, "Sunnis and Shi'ites are brothers!"
Sunni groups in Kuwait and leaders from across the Middle East have strongly condemned the attack, which Gulf officials say is aimed at provoking a backlash from Shiites and sparking sectarian war. More than a third of Kuwait's 1.2 million citizens are believed to be Shi'ite. The majority of Kuwaitis are Sunni Muslims.
Kuwait's Deputy Prime Minister and Interior Minister Sheikh Mohammed Al-Hamad Al-Sabah was quoted in the official Kuwait News Agency describing the bombing as "grotesque" and vowing to "cut the evil hand" that tampers with the country's security.
The news agency also carried a statement from Iraq's top Shi'ite cleric, Grand Ayatollah Ali al-Sistani, extending his condolences to the families of the victims.
Read more on:  isis | kuwait
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:00:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-terror-suspect-took-selfie-with-beheaded-victim-20150627</Link>
        <Description>Officials say the top suspect in the beheading of a French businessman took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image to at least one recipient.</Description>
        <MainBody>French terror suspect took selfie with beheaded victim
2015-06-27 20:00
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon. (Philippe Desmazes, AFP)
French police quiz delivery man suspected in beheading
Fontaines-Sur-Saone - Officials say the top suspect in the beheading of a French businessman took a "selfie" photo with the slain victim and sent the image to at least one recipient.
Two French officials said authorities were working to confirm the identity of the recipient, but were not able to immediately confirm media reports that it was sent to an unspecified person in Syria.
On Friday, key suspect Yassine Salhi allegedly crashed a truck into an US-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employer's severed head on a factory gate in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier  in what authorities are calling a terror attack.
He was arrested and remained in police custody on Saturday.
Authorities noted the similarity to tactics used by the Islamic State group, though no group has claimed responsibility for the attack.
Read more on:  france
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 21:00:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Huge crowds for Berlin Gay Pride after historic ruling</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Huge-crowds-for-Berlin-Gay-Pride-after-historic-ruling-20150627</Link>
        <Description>Several hundred thousand people filled the streets of Berlin for the city's Gay Pride parade, a day after the US Supreme Court legalised same-sex marriage nationwide.</Description>
        <MainBody>Huge crowds for Berlin Gay Pride after historic ruling
2015-06-27 20:00
(Adam Berry, AFP)
Serbian church blasts gays over parade plan
Berlin - Several hundred thousand people filled the streets of Berlin for the city's Gay Pride parade on Saturday, a day after the US Supreme Court legalised same-sex marriage nationwide.
The crowds were a riot of colour under grey skies, with many demonstrators in costume - including US embassy staffer Tim Standaert, who painted his torso blue with an enormous red heart as he waved a rainbow-hued Stars and Stripes flag.
"We are all different, we are all the same," was the theme of this year's march, which comes a day after the landmark Supreme Court ruling that all 50 US states must carry out and recognise same-sex marriages.
Germany introduced civil unions for gay and lesbian couples in 2001, but they do not have the right to marry and are still also forbidden from jointly adopting children.
Earlier this month the upper house of the German parliament adopted a resolution calling for the legalisation of same-sex marriage, which is opposed by Chancellor Angela Merkel's conservatives.
Saturday's pride march was a typically festive affair, with lashings of sequins, fake eyelashes, wigs and feather boas, rainbow flags, and even one reveller who appeared to have dipped his penis in gold paint.
"A day without lesbians is like a day without sunshine," read one placard that seemed especially fitting for the miserable weather.
The parade came as tens of thousands of revellers also gathered in Dublin for the Irish capital's pride event, a month after that country became the first in the world to vote by referendum in favour of legalising gay marriage.
Read more on:  germany | gay rights
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:30:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | French police grill suspect after grisly beheading</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-police-grill-suspect-after-grisly-beheading-20150627</Link>
        <Description>French police are grilling a suspected Islamist about an attack in which the man displayed his boss's severed head, in what appeared to be the second jihadist attack in the country this year.</Description>
        <MainBody>French police grill suspect after grisly beheading
2015-06-27 18:30
French police officers. (Thomas Samson, AFP)
French PM warns of more attacks after man decapitated
Paris - French police were grilling a suspected Islamist Saturday about an attack in which the man displayed his boss's severed head, in what appeared to be the second jihadist attack in France this year.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls, who cut short an official trip to South America to rush home, warned France faced more attacks and that Friday's assault on a gas factory near the second city of Lyon would increase tensions in the country, putting citizens' resilience "to the test".
No jihadist group has claimed Friday's attack, which came on the same day as a massacre at a Tunisian beach resort in which 38 people were gunned down and a suicide bombing in Kuwait that killed 26.
The other two attacks have been claimed by the Islamic State group.
Suspect Yassin Salhi, a 35-year-old married father-of-three, was arrested after causing an explosion by driving a delivery van into a warehouse containing bottles of dangerous gas and chemicals at the US-owned Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, some 40km from Lyon.
The prosecutor in the case said firefighters overpowered Salhi as he was trying to open acetone bottles in what is believed to have been an attempt to cause a larger explosion.
The firefighters then discovered the decapitated body of his 54-year-old boss Herve Cornara - who ran a delivery firm - near the car, along with a knife.
Cornara's head was pinned to a nearby fence.
"The head was surrounded by two Islamic flags bearing the Shahada, the profession of [the Muslim] faith," said prosecutor Francois Molins.
'Unable to speak'
Authorities hope an autopsy, expected to be carried out later on Saturday, will offer more clues. A source close to the case said it would seek to determine if the victim was first killed before being decapitated.
Meanwhile, in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, shocked residents held a minute's silence, followed by a pulsating rendition of France's national anthem.
One man, Philippe Ouastani, said he turned out in solidarity with the victim. "It's unheard of to decapitate someone in the 21st century. What weapons do we have to combat that? Being here, together."
Another woman, wearing the Muslim headscarf, said she was "unable to speak" when she heard the news.
"These acts have got nothing to do with religion. The Prophet never said to kill innocent people," raged the woman, who requested to remain anonymous.
She tried to find words to explain the killing to her 4-year-old son.
"There are naughty people who have done bad things. The police will put them in prison to punish them for their silly, silly actions," she told him.
'Better armed'
The gory attack in France came nearly six months after a three-day Islamist killing spree in Paris left 17 people dead, most of them gunned down in the offices of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo.
Like the Charlie Hebdo attackers and Islamist Mohamed Merah who gunned down soldiers and Jewish children in the southwest city of Toulouse in 2012, Salhi had been known to security services for "radicalisation", but slipped through the cracks.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said on Friday that Salhi had been investigated for links to radical Salafists in Lyon, but was not identified as having participated in terrorist activities and did not have a criminal record.
Speaking after a ministerial meeting on Saturday with President Francois Hollande, Cazeneuve vowed the government would "continue to work relentlessly" against terrorism.
France is on high alert over hundreds of citizens who have gone to wage jihad in Iraq and Syria, as well as those involved in recruitment or radicalisation online.
Similarly, Europe has for months been bracing for so-called "lone wolf" attacks by supporters of Islamic State, which has urged its followers to strike wherever they can.
High threat
Cazeneuve outlined measures taken by the government in recent months to face "a threat which has never been as high" such as the creation of hundreds of new jobs for police, gendarmes and intelligence agents.
Some $256m will also go to modernising surveillance methods to keep track of jihadists online.
Earlier this week, France passed a controversial new spying law granting sweeping powers to snoop on citizens.
Cazeneuve said the law allowed security services to be "better armed" to fight the jihadist threat
Valls warned Friday's attack would fuel tensions in France - home to Western Europe's largest Muslim population - that "will be exploited".
"This macabre act of decapitation, staged with flags, is new in France" and aimed at "making an impact," Valls said.
"It's difficult for a society to live for years under the threat of attack," he told AFP on a flight back from Colombia.
"The question is not... if there will be another attack, but when."
Read more on:  france | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
