<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="NEWS">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The feet taking over social media</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/londoners-walk-together-on-10-year-anniversary-of-77-bombings/story-fndir2ev-1227432896470?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>IT WAS a tragic event that shook a city to its core. Ten years on, people have taken to social media with an inspiring symbol of defiance.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
People observe a nationwide minute's silence on the 10 year anniversary of the 7/7 London attacks which killed 52 people. Picture: AP/Matt Dunham. Source: AP
LONDONERS have poured onto the streets of the English capital to walk together as a symbol of solidarity on the ten-year anniversary of the 7/7 bombings.
This morning hundreds of people across the city were urged to get off their tube or bus a stop early to demonstrate they would not be cowed by terrorist brutality. Thousands took to social media to upload pictures of their journey.
 Jonathan Sothcott (@sothcott) July 7, 2015
I have my walking shoes on ready for #walktogether pic.twitter.com/U1DxtzTWjz
 Lauren O'Connor (@laurenoconnorPR) July 7, 2015
We will #WalkTogether tomorrow in solidarity with all those whose lives were affected by 7/7 ten years ago. pic.twitter.com/WrNNTR3BYj
 Faiths Forum London (@LondonFaiths) July 6, 2015
We may wear different #shoes but we always try to #walktogether especially during tougher times. pic.twitter.com/NAikkqtle7
 chingbee fernandez (@beeslist) April 2, 2015
Remembering 7/7: Community figures join #WalkTogether in Finchley Road http://t.co/ozNk3Kozce pic.twitter.com/afEkBSs3sa
 Ham and High (@HamandHigh) July 7, 2015
Ten years ago, 52 people lost their lives in London. Don't walk alone #walktogether on 7/7 to remember them! pic.twitter.com/vJru2d6NOI
 Richard Gough (@shotbyrichie) July 7, 2015
Still have the shoes I was wearing to walk 5 miles on 7/7. The blisters have gone, not the memories. #walktogether pic.twitter.com/Qg70sZuwte
 Andrew Dysch (@fing1992) July 7, 2015
The anniversary of the tragic bombings  in which separate bombs detonated by Islamic militants killed 52 people  comes 11 days after a terror attack in Tunisia claimed the lives of 38 people.
On 7 July 2005 three bombs went off at London Underground stops at Aldgate, Edgware Road and Russell Square stations. A fourth attack took place on a bus in Tavistock Square.
Prime Minister David Cameron laid a wreath at the Hyde Park memorial in honour of the victims, describing the attack as one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain.
Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly  the murder of 30 innocent Britons while holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism, he said.
We will keep on doing all that we can to keep the British public safe, protecting vulnerable young minds from others extremist beliefs and promoting the shared values of tolerance, love and respect that make Britain so great.
Commuters observe a minutes silence in Kings Cross. Picture: Niklas Hallen. Source: AFP
Faith leaders and Australian survivor Gill Hicks (in stripes) pose as a symbol of unity. Picture: NIKLAS HALLE'N Source: AFP
Survivors and relatives of the victims also attended a service at St Pauls Cathedral with HRH the Duke of York and Mayor of London Boris Johnson.
Australian Gill Hicks who lost her legs in the bombings met with the man who saved her and said it was a day full of mixed emotions.
Im feeling a lot of grief for those who didnt come out alive and feeling very fortunate that I survived, she said. Now living in Adelaide, she said she has a spiritual connection to the station where she was injured.
My spiritual connection to this place is very, very strong, she told AAP .
Its a lovely station. Its where my life was saved, so I cant hold any negative sense towards it.
Everyone did so much for me that day and that happened here. Its a special place.
A minutes silence was also observed across London at 11:30am.
An injured woman is helped out of a tube at Aldgate. Source: AFP
A bus exploded during the attack. Picture: CARL DE SOUZA/FILES. Source: AFP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Simple graph sums up Clinton campaign</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/what-this-graph-tells-us-about-democrat-candidates-in-the-race-for-the-white-house/story-fn5tas5k-1227432786983?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>IT MIGHT not look like exciting reading, but this simple graph that has been seen more than one million times shows the stark reality behind the US election.</Description>
        <MainBody>Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton spoke of her support for the removal of South Carolinas confederate flag during a campaign stop on Tuesday in Florissant, Mo. Photo: AP
WSJ Live
24 Jun 2015
News/USA
frontrunner for the Democratic presidential nomination Hillary Clinton. Picture: Darren McCollester / Getty Images / AFP Source: AFP
THE Democratic presidential nomination will come down to a man of the people and a corporate crony  at least thats what this viral graphic seems to suggest.
What appears to be a mind-numbingly boring graph in fact reveals whos been funding the federal political careers of Democratic presidential hopefuls Hillary Clinton and Bernie Sanders, and the contrast is striking.
The image, which has been shared more than one million times since it first surfaced on Imgur.com , may also suggest the former Secretary of States victory in the Democratic primaries is not such a sure thing.
This version of the graph shows the top 13 donors for each candidate. Source: Supplied
All but two of Clintons top 20 donors are large corporations, major banks or law firms, dominated by Citigroup, Goldman Sachs and DLA Piper.
Conversely, all but one of Sanders major donors are from labour unions, such as the Machinist/Aerospace Workers Union, Teamsters Union and United Auto Workers.
The donations, which date back to 1989, do not come directly from the organisations themselves but from individual employees or political action committees, or PACs, within the organisations.
News source Digg.com suggests the graphic represents exactly the type of comparison that Bernie Sanders wants voters to draw between him and Hillary Clinton  portraying him as a candidate backed by individuals and unions and her as a candidate backed by corporate interests.
Presidential hopeful Hillary Clinton at a Fourth of July parade in New Hampshire last weekend. Picture: AP / Robert F. Bukaty Source: AP
There is also a massive difference in how much each candidate raised: Clinton received more than $US8.39 million from her top 20 contributors alone, while Sanders fetched just $US1.13 million.
Sanders said last month average Americans families made up the backbone of his campaign donors , adding there was a need to transform our economics and politics so that millionaires and billionaires cant buy elections.
An independent Senator for Vermont and a self-professed socialist, the underdog is firming as a major challenger to Clinton and his surge in polls in New Hampshire and Iowa, which Clinton looks likely to lose , suggests he could be giving the Clinton camp a run for its money.
We are worried about him, sure. He will be a serious force for the campaign, and I dont think that will diminish, Jennifer Palmieri, the Clinton campaigns communications director, told MSNBC overnight.
Democratic presidential candidate Senator Bernie Sanders on the campaign trail. Picture: Michael P. King / AP Source: AP
The donations data has emerged as the disappearing middle class and concern over corporate influence in politics firm as key issues in the 2016 presidential election.
Clinton and Sanders have touted wealth equality as among their core campaign platforms, with both in strong favour of higher taxes for the wealthy and staunchly opposed to the privatisation of social security.
Never before in the modern history of our country have so few had so much and so many had so little, Sanders said before confirming his presidential bid last year. This incredible and obscene level of wealth and income inequality is a grave danger to our economy and our political system.
Clinton, too, has the rich and powerful in her sights: The deck is stacked in their favour, the Democratic frontrunner said in her first week on the campaign trail. My job is to reshuffle the cards.
Californian College Republicans protesting against Hillary Clinton's fundraising visit outside the Democratic Party offices in California, where Clinton regularly met with deep-pocketed supporters to amass funds needed to win the White House. Picture: AFP / Mark Ralston Source: AFP
However, while Sanders wants to break the power of the rich upper class , the New York Times reported last year that Clinton was determined to tackle income inequality without alienating businesses or castigating the wealthy.
Figures released last week revealed Clinton has raised $US45 million in political donations towards her primary campaign, which was partly drawn from paid public speeches. Recent figures puts Sanders haul at about $US15 million.
Leaked emails from University of Missouri officials, also released last week, revealed Clintons representatives were seeking a whopping US$275,000 for the former First Lady to speak at a gala luncheon in Kansas City in February.
Upon learning the fee, the university booked her daughter Chelsea Clinton instead for the bargain price of $US65,000.
Jerry Seib: Voters' Concerns Split Along Ideological Lines 1:15
The ideological void between Democratic and Republican voters is demonstrated in the issues most important to them. WSJs Jerry Seib explains what this means for the candidates. Photo: AP
WSJ Live
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks fear the worst is yet to come</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/finance/economy/euphoria-turns-to-fear-as-greeks-worry-about-what-will-happen-next/story-fnu2pycd-1227432635598?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>EUPHORIA has turned to fear as banks in Greece remain shut and panicked citizens worry about what will happen to their savings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek banks will remain closed until Wednesday with limits on daily withdrawals unchanged.
Sky News
07 Jul 2015
News
Down and out ... A homeless man sleeps on a bench in downtown Athens. Picture: AFP/ANDREAS SOLARO Source: AFP
THE steel shutters will remain down over all banks in Greece for a couple more days prompting panic in Athens with many now worried about the future of their savings.
After the euphoria of the referendum result where thousands celebrated in the central Athenian Syntagma Square for what they thought was the end of austerity, many woke to the realisation that nothing had changed.
In fact, many feared things had just got worse.
REFERENDUM: Aussies secure best seats in the house
Getting all they can ... People queue at a bank ATM in Athens. Picture: AFP/IAKOVOS HATZISTAVROU Source: AFP
Huge queues snaked from most ATMs from early yesterday after rumours began swirling that banks may not reopen on Tuesday or if they did it would only be to allow savers access to safety deposit boxes since there was not enough cash reserves in banks to meet an expected mass demand.
HITTING HARD: Broke Greeks desperate for a feed
Some ATMs were already out of cash yesterday while others where dispensing only 50 euros in a single note, below the 60 euro daily cap imposed more than a week ago, since they had run out of 20 euro notes.
Future uncertain ... A woman withdraws money from an ATM machine next to a beggar and a graffiti reading" No to fear" in Thessaloniki. Picture: AFP/SAKIS MITROLIDIS Source: AFP
Banks were to reopen today but it was announced they would not open till Thursday at best and caps on withdrawals would remain beyond this week.
Proliferation of street beggars, that many Greeks said was unheard off only a few months ago, was evident yesterday outside banks and at major intersections with some going into cafes and restaurants asking tourists for any money.
British treasurer George Osborne yesterday warned Westminster the financial situation in Greece could now deteriorate rapidly as he cautioned British tourists to not only take enough cash but also sufficient medicines, noting pharmacies in Greece were reporting shortages of prescription medicines.
Desperate for money ... As well as huge queues outside roller shuttered banks are beggars with cups in hand, a sight many Greeks said was unheard of even a few months ago. Picture: Charles Miranda Source: Supplied
He also said Britain was bolstering consular presence on popular tourist destinations Corfu and Crete and the Department for Work and Pensions had contacted 2000 expats living in Greece to offer them the chance to switch to a UK-based bank account to continue to receive their pensions.
Australian tourists Emma Yandle, 23, from Perth said she had been warned several times to bring enough cash to Greece during her two and a half week stay.
We were in Ios beforehand and there was enough money there to get out to here Athens but we had been warned by different family members back at home watching the news to take out enough cash, the hairdresser said.
Will be OK ... Australian tourists Emma Yandle, 23 and Danny Lent, 21, in Athens, both hairdressers from Perth, have enough cash to finish their trip. Picture: Charles Miranda Source: Supplied
Her friend and fellow hairdresser 20-year-old Danny Lent drew out money as soon as he heard things might change at short notice.
They were telling us in the hostels and places, letting us know to go to actual bank ATMs because they were more likely to refill those unlike others outside supermarkets or whatever, he said having flown in from Crete.
The Australian embassy in Greece was watching events closely but did not have a specific contingency plan should people get stranded. There are 90,000 dual Australian-Greek citizens in Greece. In these next three months of summer, as many as 200,000 Australian tourists will visit.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Europe’s stern warning to Greece</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/finance/economy/germany-and-france-open-to-discussions-with-greece-but-want-serious-credible-proposals/story-fnu2pycd-1227431501220?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>GREEK banks will stay closed amid fears ATMs are running out of cash. Meanwhile, France and Germany have one demand after crisis talks overnight.</Description>
        <MainBody>Moira Geddes provides a simple explanation
News Corp Australia
07 Jul 2015
News Business News/Politics Lifestyle/Money
Tensions mounting ... Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras (pictured) asked Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis to resign. Picture: AFP/Angelos Tzortzinis Source: AFP
GERMANY and France have called on Greece to make detailed proposals to revive bailout talks, a day after Greek voters defiantly rejected creditors demands for further austerity.
With Greeces economy gasping for air , the authorities have extended an eight-day bank closure amid fears cash machines in the country were running dry.
The European Central Bank, which has been keeping Greek lenders afloat, meanwhile announced it would maintain its liquidity lifeline to Greek banks, but made it harder for them to access the funds by tightening collateral terms.
The door is open to discussions, said French President Francois Hollande after crisis talks in Paris with German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
It is now up to the government of Alexis Tsipras to make serious, credible proposals so that this willingness to stay in the eurozone can translate into a lasting program.
Premier Tsipras is to unveil his governments proposals on Tuesday at a hastily-arranged emergency summit of the 19 eurozone countries in Brussels.
It is now up to Tsipras ... Francois Hollande and Angela Merkel say the door is open to discussions. Source: Getty Images
Merkel, speaking alongside Hollande, said the conditions for a new Greek rescue package have not yet been met.
And that is why we are now waiting for very precise proposals from the Greek prime minister, a programme that will allow Greece to return to prosperity, said Merkel, adding that eurozone countries had already shown a lot of solidarity with Greece.
As Athens awoke after a night of celebration after the No camp won a closely-watched referendum on bailout terms, Greeces firebrand finance minister, Yanis Varoufakis, announced he was stepping down to try to ease friction with creditors.
Resigned ... former Greek finance minister Yanis Varoufakis (pictured) quit at the request of PM Alexis Tsipras. Picture: Christopher Furlong/Getty Images Source: Getty Images
Varoufakis had infuriated European counterparts by lashing demands for economic reform and welfare cuts as terrorism and fiscal waterboarding.
He was replaced by Euclid Tsakalotos, a much more discreet junior foreign minister and economist who has been Greeces pointman in the negotiations with creditors.
We want to continue the discussion ... I believe something can change in Europe, said Tsakalotos, who admitted to having stage fright upon assuming the post not at the easiest moment in Greek history.
Protest ... a Bank of Greece sign is defaced with graffiti to read 'Banque de Merkel' in Athens, Greece. Picture: Christopher Furlong/Getty Images Source: Getty Images
Positions among Greeces 18 partners in the eurozone vary ahead of todays summit.
Germany, Finland, Slovakia and the Baltic states have taken a notably harder line, whereas France, Italy and Spain have adopted a more conciliatory tone.
Despite its tougher approach on debt relief, Germany said yesterday that eurozone leaders should discuss humanitarian aid for a country fatigued by years of belt-tightening and chronic unemployment.
Fiscal control ... a woman withdraws money from an ATM with the words No to fear freshly graffitied on the wall. Picture: AFP/Sakis Mitrolidis Source: AFP
Australian dollar down amid Grexit fears
The Australian dollar is lower amid uncertainty over Greeces future and concerns about Chinas equity markets.
At 0700 AEST on Tuesday, the local unit was trading at 75.00 US cents, down from 75.11 cents on Monday.
BK Asset Management FX Strategy managing director Kathy Lien said that although Greeces bailout rejection was the top story in financial markets, the volatility in Chinese equities should not be dismissed.
The vulnerability of Chinas economy, the drop in iron ore prices and the uncertainty created by Greece doesnt bode well for Australias economy, she said.
Investors will be watching Tuesdays Reserve Bank meeting, which is expected to keep the interest rate on hold at a record low of two per cent.
Ms Lien said that while the RBA may be happy with the decline in the local currency, there could be concern about the drop in manufacturing activity and flat consumer spending.
The only good news was from the labour market but job growth is expected to slow significantly in June after rising strongly in May, she said.
Westpac strategist Imre Speizer tipped the Aussie dollar to remain in a bearish mood on Tuesday, saying it could fall below 74.50 US cents during the next few days.
New World Economic Order 52:07
Robert Peston asks whether Greece and the EU are now in for decades, rather than years, of sluggish growth.
Oovvuu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:59:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Africa we don’t get to see</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/technology/online/theafricamedianevershowsyou-50000-photos-that-will-change-the-way-you-see-africa/story-fnjwnhzf-1227432245200?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>THE world&amp;#8217;s view of Africa is often a negative one, focused on violence, disease and poverty. This week a hashtag is telling a totally different story.</Description>
        <MainBody>NORTHERN Europes largest music festival just collected the urine from over 100,000 attendees to make recycled beer. Were serious.
Online
#TheAfricaMediaNeverShowsYou: 50,000 photos that will change the way you see Africa
by:
What are these?
Breaking down stereotypes ... #TheAfricaTheMediaNeverShowsYou is showing us a side of Africa we rarely see. Picture: Instagram. Source: Twitter
THE worlds view of Africa is often a negative one, focused on violence, disease, and poverty. This week a hashtag is telling a totally different story.
Africans in their thousands are sharing beautiful images of their lives to fight media stereotypes using the hashtag #TheAfricaTheMediaNeverShowsYou.
Yes, of course there is still suffering in Africa, but theres also plenty of happiness, thriving, vibrant culture and natural beauty.
Created by 22-year-old Somali Twitter user Diana Salah, the viral hashtag has generated close to 70,000 tweets.
Here are some of the most beautiful highlights from the eyes of the locals.
Check out the hashtag #TheAfricaTheMediaNeverShowsYou and get a glimpse of the world's most beautiful continent. pic.twitter.com/CUM5HcKRIh
 Yves Batoba (@Ybatoba) July 7, 2015
Kid fishing in the lake Mai Ndombe, Bandundu, DRC, Africa #TheAfricaTheMediaNeverShowsYou pic.twitter.com/QCWKNhq8dP
 Doudou Kalala (@kalala) July 6, 2015
#TheAfricaTheMediaNeverShowsYou Our little ones are happy &amp; not always bony starved kids with flies on their faces! pic.twitter.com/4vl8r7aHIi
 Martha Rose  (@DatAfricanGirl) July 3, 2015
My beautiful #senegal . Beauty is in the eyes of the viewer. #TheAfricaTheMediaNeverShowsYou . http://t.co/176FOVwiBk pic.twitter.com/M4LWOhVdhL
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Meet Fukushima’s latest robot hero</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/technology/innovation/scorpion-robot-hopes-to-succeed-where-the-snake-bots-failed-delving-into-fukushimas-dark-secrets/story-fnjwucti-1227431846282?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>IT&amp;#8217;S been four years since a 15-metre high tsunami shattered the Fukushima power plant. Only now do we have a hope of finding out what&amp;#8217;s going on inside &amp;#8212; via a robotic scorpion.</Description>
        <MainBody>A scorpion-like robot build by Toshiba is set to investigate Fukushima reactors in Japan. Courtesy: Toshiba
News Corp Australia
07 Jul 2015
Technology
Disaster zone ... Emergency services douse the flames which ripped through three of Fukushimas reactors after an earthquake and tsunami in 2011. Source: Japan Times Source: Supplied
A NEW robot that raises its tail like a scorpion is scheduled to look at melted nuclear fuel inside one of the three wrecked Fukushima reactors in Japan.
Toshiba Corp., co-developer of the scorpion crawler that was demonstrated today, said the robot will venture into the Unit 2 reactors primary containment vessel in August after a month of training for its handlers.
But even metal and silicon cannot hold up to the intensity of radiation within a nuclear reactor for long.
Mechanical hero ... The robot developed by Toshiba Corp to delve deep into Fukushimas damaged reactors is demonstrated its laboratory in Kawasaki, near Tokyo. Source: AP Source: AP
The robot has enough radiation tolerance to allowing it to stay about 10 hours inside the Unit 2 reactor.
Toshiba officials say they hope the robot can capture images of deeper areas of the vessel, though the primary focus is the platform area, so they can design a more suitable robot that can go deeper into the vessel.
Too hot to handle ... The conditions inside Fukushimas three damaged nuclear reactors remains unknown. Source: Japan Times Source: Supplied
INSIDER VIEW
Officials hope the robot can see the fuel in the pressure vessel in the middle of the reactor. The position of the toppled fuel rods hasnt been located exactly and studied because of the high radiation levels.
The scorpion robot is the second to enter a primary containment vessel, after snake robots were sent in April inside the worst-hit Unit 1. One of the two robots used in that reactor became stuck and had to be left behind, and neither was able to spot the melted fuel debris.
One for the camera ... Toshiba has developed the robot that raises its tail like a scorpion and collects data, and hopefully locate some of Fukushimas melted debris. Source: AP Source: AP
This time, the scorpion crawler, which is 54 centimetres long when extended, will enter through a duct designed as a passageway for fuel rods. Toshiba has no back up machine.
The robots entry is just the beginning of the reactor investigation required before the most challenging task of removing the melted fuel.
The difficult work of decommissioning the Fukushima plant damaged by the 2011 earthquake and tsunami will take decades.
Roving eye ... The 54-cm-long and 9-cm-hight and wide robot had developed to investigate the interior of the primary containment vessel (PCV) of Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Station Unit 2. Source: AFP Source: AFP
HIGH HOPES
During the demonstration at a Toshiba lab near Tokyo, the robot slid down a railing as it stretched out like a bar, with a head-mounted LED showing its way. After crawling over a slight gap and landing on a metal platform, the robot lifted its tail, as if looking up at the bottom of the control rod drive, a structure above the platform where some melted nuclear fuel might be left.
Celebrity ... Media take pictures of the robot designed to take pictures inside Fukushimas damaged reactors. Source: AP Source: AP
The scorpion also demonstrated it can roll back upright if it hits an obstacle and rolls over. The ability comes from a tail joint in the middle that bends.
One operator controls the robot with a joystick, and another monitors a video feed from the robot and other data. At the Fukushima plant, the robot will be operated remotely from a command centre in a separate building.
The work is planned for a full day.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>World’s fastest way to die</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/sport/motorsport/worlds-fastest-way-to-die-the-most-dangerous-race-on-the-planet/story-fne8930l-1227429467448?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>ON A tiny island in the Irish Sea, motorcyclists risk their lives hurtling around hairpin bends on narrow roads at more than 300km/h. This is the deadliest race on the planet.</Description>
        <MainBody>Visit the Isle of Man's motorcycle circuit, home to one of sport's most dangerous races
News Corp Australia
News
The crematorium graveyard behind the Isle of Man TT (Tourist Trophy) Race. Source: Getty Images
A TINY, independent island in the Irish Sea doesnt sound like the most likely location for the worlds deadliest race.
But the Isle of Man TT (Tourist Trophy) Race has seen more fatalities than any other motorcycle race  albeit in 100 years  with riders urging their bikes around narrow, winding roads and crumbling farmhouses at more than 300km/h.
Many of the 246 killed in the race were professionals taking part in the fastest division, the Senior TT. But others were amateurs, who compete on the 60km Snaefell Mountain Course on Mad Sunday, in the middle of the two-week event.
Attempts to protect riders at the most dangerous parts of the course have been made with safety bales wrapped around phone boxes and other obstacles.
A report by Jalopnik describes a Frenchman killed in practice this year , on a straight section of the infamous course. Another rider, Jamie Hamilton, was airlifted to hospital after he crashed during the Senior TT.
More than 240 riders have died over 100 years of the race. Source: News Limited
The deadly race is held on public roads, considered more dangerous than a closed circuit, particularly when the islands roads are old. Source: Getty Images
Last year, veteran Bob Price died on the third lap and 34-year-old Karl Bomber Harris was killed a day later. Another rider, Gary Johnson, broke his collarbone and cracked a vertebrae in his neck, but generally has escaped very lightly it seems, according to a cheerful tweet from his team.
In the TTs deadliest year, 1970, six competitors lost their lives, with another racer perishing during the islands Manx Grand Prix later the same year.
The crowds, standing just metres away from the speeding motorbikes, arent immune from the danger. In 2013, Jonathan Howarth ploughed into the crowd on his first lap, injuring 11 onlookers  10 days after Japanese rider Yoshinari Matsushita, 43, was killed in a qualifying session.
Australian spectators Dean Jacob, 33, and Gregory Kenzig, 52, and rider Marc Ramsbotham died in a 2007 collision.
Spectators lining the roads have been injured and killed by out-of-control bikes. Source: News Limited
The race shows no sign of slowing down. Source: Getty Images
The little islands pretty fields, ice cream vans and quaint grocery stores belie the risk of the course. The Isle of Man, 354 square kilometres in size and home to 85,000 people, is now one of the few places in the world where a motorcycle race is still held on public roads.
To outsiders, its record looks bad, but the race attracts 10,000 motorsport enthusiasts each year, who point out that more people are killed in road traffic accidents in every day life.
It was the islands autonomy that first saw the race held here in the 1900s, when speed limits in England were a pitiful 30km/h. And a world without rules and regulations, just a ferry ride away from the UK, still has massive appeal.
Death a high price to pay for the excitement of taking on these twisting, treacherous roads, but racers dont go there thinking that they are going to end up as another statistic, says marshall Suzanne Hitchinson.
For as long as they can, thrillseekers looking for that buzz will keep on coming.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Seized: 78-year-old’s Nazi arsenal</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/panther-tank-among-heavy-weaponry-seized-from-78-year-olds-basement/story-fndir2ev-1227431939606?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A 45-ton Panther tank, a flak cannon and other World War II weapons have been seized in a raid on a retiree&amp;#8217;s home in northern Germany.</Description>
        <MainBody>Panther tank among heavy weaponry seized from 78-year-olds basement
by:
What are these?
Hidden ... This tank and other heavy weaponry were seized in a raid on an elderly mans home. Source: AP
A 45-ton Panther tank, a flak cannon and other World War II weapons have been seized in a raid on a 78-year-old collectors home in northern Germany.
Kiel prosecutor Birgit Hess said the collector, whose name she would not release for privacy reasons, is being investigated for possibly violating German weapons laws but remains free while the probe is ongoing.
In the search, investigators also seized a torpedo and many other military items in addition to the Panzer V Panther tank and the 88mm flak gun, Hess told The Associated Press.
Lethal weapon ... A World War II-era Panther tank is prepared for transportation from a residential property in Heikendorf, northern Germany. Source: AP Source: AP
German military engineers were called in to haul the tank out of the underground garage of the house in Kitzeberg, near Kiel.
The collectors lawyer, Peter Gramsch, told the dpa news agency all the items were properly demilitarised and registered.
Hess said that she did not know whether the main gun on the tank could fire, but it didnt appear to be properly registered and an independent expert had ruled it wasnt properly demilitarised.
The collector came to authorities attention in an investigation into black market Nazi-era art that in May turned up two massive bronze horse statues that once stood in front of Adolf Hitlers chancellery. Those were in the possession of another man, who maintains he is the rightful owner.
Copping flak ... This anti-aircraft canon and multiple other World War II-era military weapons have been seized from 78-year-old Peter Gramsch. Source: AP Source: AP
The tank owner has made no secret of his collection, openly talking about the Panther and other items in media reports following the May revelation of the art investigation.
Neighbour Kristin Schroeder told the local Kieler Nachrichten newspaper that the man had even fired up the tank during the particularly bad winter of 1978-79 and helped plough others snow.
It was well known, at least to all the older Kitzebergers, that he had a tank, Schroeder said.
The Battle of Kursk: Southern Front 45:01
This is the story of the largest tank battle in military history, as elite SS troops face off against Russian defenders determined to stop them whatever the cost.
Oovvuu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man mocked alligator before attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/north-america/texas-alligator-attack-victim-tommie-woodward-mocked-animal-before-jumping-in-water/story-fnh81jut-1227431801162?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A MAN has been killed after he jumped into an alligator-infested marina, having screamed &amp;#8216;f*** that alligator&amp;#8217; only moments before his death.</Description>
        <MainBody>A man has died after an alligator attacked him during a late-night swim at a Southeast Texas marina. Courtesy: Fox News
news.com.au
05 Jul 2015
News/World
Killed ... Just moments after he mocked the animals for daring to interfere with his swim, Tommie Woodward was dead. Picture: Facebook Source: Facebook
A US MAN has been killed after he jumped into an alligator-infested marina, having screamed f*** that alligator only moments before his death.
Tommie Woodward suffered severe trauma injuries when he was attacked at a private marina in Southeast Texas.
The Huffington Post reports that Orange County sheriffs deputies and a Texas game warden found Woodwards body nearby about two hours later.
Wrong decision ... Woodward was swimming in a lake in Burkarts Marina in Louisiana Picture: KFDM Source: Supplied
Police said the local man, aged 33, was with a woman at the time of the attack and its believed she jumped into the water after hearing his screams for help.
He said, f**** the alligators and jumped into the water and almost immediately yelled for help, Orange County Justice of the Peace Rodney Price told KDFM.
Victim ... Woodward had recently moved to the area from St Louis, Missouri. Picture: Facebook Source: Supplied
Marina employee Michelle Wright said she pleaded with him not to go in the water and then witnessed his death.
Next thing I know this girl is screaming and an alligators got him, Wright told KDFM.
I saw his body floating face down and then hes up there for a couple seconds and then he gets dragged back down and pulled off.
Hes the first person to be killed by an alligator in Texas since 1836.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 02:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘Supermassive’ black holes discovered</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/technology/science/supermassive-black-holes-discovered-by-astronomers/story-fnjwlcze-1227431495823?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>FIVE monster black holes that were previously hidden by dust and gas have been uncovered by astronomers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Spotted ... NASA's Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array bags a supermassive black hole. Picture: NASA/JPL-Caltech Picture: Nasa/Instagram Source: Supplied
FIVE monster black holes that were previously hidden by dust and gas have been uncovered by astronomers.
The British-led discovery suggests there may be millions more supermassive black holes in the universe than were previously thought.
Supermassive black holes are powerful cosmic drains sucking material into a point of infinite density, which are formed from the compressed mass of hundreds of thousands to billions of suns.
Hidden monster ... an artists impression shows a vortex of debris obscuring a supermassive black hole. Picture: ESA/NASA Source: Supplied
High energy X-rays emitted from around the newly identified black holes revealed their presence at the centre of five galaxies.
They were detected by the American space agency NASAs Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array (NuSTAR) orbiting observatory, which was launched in 2012.
Black Hole 12 Billion Times Bigger Than Sun Found 1:54
Scientists have discovered a supermassive black hole from the dawn of time that is 12 billion times the size of our sun. WSJ's Monika Auger reports. Photo: Zhaoyu Li/NASA/JPL-Caltech/Misti Mountain Observatory
WSJ Live
Technology
The space telescope is designed to pick up extremely high energy X-rays from distant objects.
For a long time we have known about supermassive black holes that are not obscured by dust and gas, but we suspected that many more were hidden from our view, said lead scientist George Lansbury, from the Centre for Extragalactic Astronomy at the University of Durham.
Although we have only detected five of these hidden supermassive black holes, when we extrapolate our results across the whole universe then the predicted numbers are huge and in agreement with what we would expect to see.
Black-hole hunter ... an artists rendering of the NuStar orbiting observatory. Picture: NASA Source: AP
The scientists presented their findings at the Royal Astronomical Societys National Astronomy Meeting, in Llandudno, Wales.
High-energy X-rays are more penetrating than low-energy X-rays, so we can see deeper into the gas burying the black holes, said Dr Daniel Stern, NuSTAR project scientist at NASA.
NuSTAR allows us to see how big the hidden monsters are and is helping us learn why only some black holes appear obscured.
Who's Afraid of a Big Black Hole? 52:15
They're one of the most destructive entities in the universe. But despite their immense mass and powerful influence on stars and galaxies, no-one has ever seen a black hole.
Oovvuu
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
