<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:28:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | POTUS unscripted: Obama shows a softer side on Twitter</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/POTUS-unscripted-Obama-shows-a-softer-side-on-Twitter-20150707</Link>
        <Description>President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings, at all hours of the day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama to meet with gay rights activists
Washington - President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings, at all hours of the day.
The White House has used Twitter to promote the president's views for years, but with tweets composed by press aides and released at strategic times. Only occasionally would Obama post to Twitter himself, identifying a bona fide presidential tweet by appending his initials.
Now Obama is composing his own tweets almost daily, without the filter of his press office. His personal twitter account, @POTUS, launched earlier this summer.
"Hello, Twitter! It's Barack. Really!" Obama wrote in May. "Six years in, they're finally giving me my own account."
Obama, who has been known to use an iPad and a Blackberry, can send tweets from a variety of secure devices, according to the White House. Obama gives his team a heads up before he tweets, and his staff says he sometimes agrees to tweet about topics his aides suggest.
He's already amassed more than 3 million followers. He follows only 66 Twitter users, mostly sports teams, federal agencies and top government officials. He briefly set a record for attracting a million followers faster than any other Twitter user. But Obama's record was quickly broken by Caitlyn Jenner.
A look at some of Obama's recent tweets:
Gay marriage
Obama's first reaction to the Supreme Court's historic ruling legalising gay marriage nationwide came through his Twitter account.
"Today is a big step in our march toward equality," Obama tweeted on June 26. "Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else."
Bring in the band
After Obama tweeted that he'd spent his morning listening to the new album from The Black Keys, the rock band tweeted back asking if they could use Air Force One for their upcoming gigs. A few hours later, Obama tweeted his response: "It's not mine; just a loaner. Maybe you can come play at the White House sometime instead?"
No 1 fan
Obama congratulated the American team and midfielder Carli Lloyd for their victory Sunday night in the Women's World Cup.
"What a win for Team USA!" Obama wrote, adding: "Your country is so proud of all of you. Come visit the White House with the World Cup soon."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:30:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 3 men gored as Spain's bull-running week begins</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/3-men-gored-as-Spains-bull-running-week-begins-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Three men have been gored and 10 others taken to hospital on the first day of Pamplona's week-long San Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners in red scarves through the streets.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 men gored as Spain's bull-running week begins
2015-07-07 13:30
A steer, left, and a Jandilla fighting bull, centre right, run after revellers during the running of the bulls, at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona. (Andres Kudacki, AP)
Injured rodeo bull made to suffer
Pamplona - Three men were gored and 10 others taken to hospital on the first day of Pamplona's week-long San Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners in red scarves through the streets.
Tuesday's run included six bulls from the Jandilla ranch in the rural western region of Extremadura, known for the ferocity of its bulls.
The run lasted 2 minutes and 23 seconds. One man was gored in the chest and was in a stable condition, a doctor at the event said. The Red Cross said two other men were gored, one in the back, but gave no further details.
Many Spanish towns hold festivals involving bulls during the summer. San Fermin is the most famous internationally and attracts thousands of revellers, many from abroad.
San Fermin featured in Ernest Hemingway's novel "The Sun Also Rises". Its daily Bull Run starts at 08:00 and usually lasts between 3 and 5 minutes.
There are eight runs in total.
Read more on:  spain
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:33:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Chinese 'Walter White' nabbed for selling ecstasy substitute</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Chinese-Walter-White-nabbed-for-selling-ecstasy-substitute-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Police have arrested a Chinese university professor who allegedly sold "millions of US dollars" worth of psychoactive drugs over the internet to clients in the US, Britain, Canada and Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese 'Walter White' nabbed for selling ecstasy substitute
2015-07-07 12:33
Thailand battles to contain rising drug use
Beijing - Police have arrested a Chinese university professor who allegedly sold "millions of US dollars" worth of psychoactive drugs over the internet to clients in the US, Britain, Canada and Australia, state media reported on Tuesday.
The professor, surnamed Zhang, first learned about the popularity of such drugs while teaching as a visiting academic in Australia, the official Xinhua news agency reported.
He then started a chemical company in 2005 but had staff manufacture "hundreds of kilograms" of methylone, commonly used as a substitute for MDMA, or ecstasy, the report said.
Between March and November last year, the business sold at least 193kg of the substance to the overseas customers, Xinhua said.
The report did not provide a precise monetary figure, only quoting police as saying that Zhang earned "millions of US dollars" from the sales.
Xinhua dubbed Zhang "China's real-life Walter White" in reference to the fictional high school chemistry teacher and methamphetamine kingpin immortalised in the US hit cable TV series Breaking Bad.
The report did not identify his university, only describing it as "famous" and in the central city of Wuhan.
Last month, police raided Zhang's lab in the city, where they found 20kg of drugs and arrested eight people.
The report of Zhang's alleged dealings comes after police in May announced the arrest of a former chemistry professor on suspicion of selling a drug recipe to a gang which cooked up synthetic narcotics.
Chinese state media in May cited the government as saying the country has 14 million drug users, about 1% of the population, and their numbers have increased by an annual average of 36% in recent years.
Use of synthetic drugs, such as crystal meth and methcathinone, which can induce euphoric highs, are reported to be growing in rural areas of China.
Read more on:  china | narcotics
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:33:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Suicide car bomber targets Nato convoy in Afghan capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Suicide-car-bomber-targets-Nato-convoy-in-Afghan-capital-20150707</Link>
        <Description>A suicide car bomber has targeted a convoy of the Nato-led coalition forces in Kabul, police say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide car bomber targets Nato convoy in Afghan capital
2015-07-07 12:33
(Emad Matti, AP)
Bomb kills 3 in Pakistani tribal area
Kabul - A suicide car bomber targeted a convoy of the Nato-led coalition forces in Kabul on Tuesday, police said.
"We are confirming an explosion in the Shah Shahid area of Kabul," said Sediq Sediqqi, a spokesman for the Ministry of Interior.
"One civilian and the driver of an armoured vehicle with foreign troops in were injured," said Ebadullah Karimi, Kabul police spokesperson.
The bombing damaged both vehicles carrying foreign troops and the buildings around, he said.
The Taliban claimed responsibility for the attack.
Meanwhile, at least 49 rebels were killed in separate foreign drone strikes on Monday night in the eastern province of Nangarhar, said Ahmad Zai Abdulzai, the provincial governor's spokesperson.
He said the drone strikes targeted separate hideouts of the rebels in the villages of Achin district.
"No civilian casualties were reported," he said.
Read more on:  afghanistan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Spanish police arrest woman for recruiting young girls for ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Spanish-police-arrest-woman-for-recruiting-young-girls-for-ISIS-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Spanish police have arrested a woman suspected of recruiting pre-teen girls and teenagers of both sexes to send to areas controlled by ISIS in Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>Spanish police arrest woman for recruiting young girls for ISIS
2015-07-07 11:21
Spanish police. (Gerard Julien, AFP)
Women held over ISIS mosque attack in Kuwait
Madrid - Spanish police have arrested a woman suspected of recruiting pre-teen girls and teenagers of both sexes to send to areas controlled by ISIS in Syria.
An interior ministry statement said the woman, a Spaniard, was arrested Tuesday in the city of Arrecife on the Canary Island of Lanzarote.
The ministry says the woman maintained contact with ISIS in Syria.
It adds that the operation was being conducted by the National Court in Madrid.
Spain has arrested dozens of suspected jihadi militants and recruiters in recent years.
Read more on:  isis | spain
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:21:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Pope-puts-family-first-at-outdoor-Mass-in-Ecuador-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis has received a hero's welcome in Ecuador's biggest city as he celebrated the first public Mass of his South American tour, telling hundreds of thousands of families they are the bedrock of society.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in Ecuador
2015-07-07 11:21
Pope Francis talks to the people gathered in front of Quito's Cathedral, in Ecuador. (Ana Buitron, AP)
Pope Francis to touch on cherished issues
Guayaquil - Pope Francis received a hero's welcome in Ecuador's biggest city on Monday as he celebrated the first public Mass of his South American tour, telling hundreds of thousands of faithful their families are the bedrock of society but need to be supported better and strengthened.
In his homily, Francis praised families as the nucleus of society, calling them "the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly." He said miracles are performed every day inside a family out of love, but sometimes the love and happiness run out.
"How many women, sad and lonely, wonder when love left, when it slipped away from their lives?" he asked. "How many elderly people feel left out of family celebrations, cast aside and longing each day for a little love?"
Firefighters sprayed water from hoses on the crowd to provide relief from a searing sun and high humidity that made the 30C temperature in the Pacific port city of Guayaquil feel at least five degrees hotter.
Many pilgrims had spent the night outdoors, and some walked for miles to reach the park on Guayaquil's northern outskirts to catch a glimpse of history's first Latin American pope celebrating Mass on his home turf. They said it was well worth the discomfort.
"I'm tired, I'm hungry, I haven't slept, but I'm also full of emotion and joy in my heart," said Vicente Huilcatoma, a former police officer who walked 40km to reach Samanes Park.
One million people
The Vatican originally estimated more than 1 million people would turn out for the Mass, and government organisers put the crowd at above that figure in the hour before the service began. But Gabriel Almeida, the government spokesperson at the scene, rolled back the estimate to about 550 000 after officials viewed aerial images of the area.
Across the park, flags from Ecuador and more than a half dozen other countries waved above the enormous sea of people, who were divided into quadrants that Francis looped around slowly on his popemobile to cheers of "Francisco! Francisco!"
The pope's homily brought Janeth Valencia Bersosa to tears. The primary school teacher came to the Mass with her older sister Pilar from Cuenca, about 200km away, spending the night in the park and then baking under the heat of the noontime Mass. She said it was worth it.
"Francis has given us back hope in our families, in those we love the most, the nucleus of society," she said. "I wept at each phrase."
Francis has dedicated the first two years of his pontificate to family issues, giving weekly catechism lessons on different aspects of family life and inviting the entire church to study ways to provide better pastoral care for Catholic families facing difficulties today, including people who are divorced, gays and families in "non-traditional" situations.
Meetings on family life
A preliminary meeting of bishops on these issues ended last year in bitter divisions between liberals and conservatives, particularly over ministering to gays and to Catholics who divorce and remarry outside the church. Church teaching holds that Catholics who enter into a second marriage without having the first one annulled cannot receive Communion.
In his homily on Monday, Francis said he hoped the second meeting of bishops on family life, scheduled for October, would come up with "concrete solutions to the many difficult and significant challenges facing families in our time."
"I ask you to pray fervently for this intention, so that Christ can take even what might seem to us impure, scandalous or threatening, and turn it... into a miracle."
"Families today need miracles!" he added.
The Vatican spokesperson, the Reverend Federico Lombardi, said Francis wasn't referring to the gay or divorce issue specifically but was making a more general reference that he hoped the bishops would "help the church chart this path of leaving a situation of sin to one of grace."
Selfies
Upon his arrival in Guayaquil, the pontiff allowed several acolytes on the tarmac to take selfies with him. He then headed to the Shrine of the Divine Mercy, where 2 000 invitees gathered, including young cancer patients, residents of homes for the elderly abandoned by their families and some of Guayaquil's poorest people.
He told those gathered that he would pray for them "and I won't charge you a thing. All I ask, please, is that you pray for me."
After the open-air Mass, Francis had lunch with a group of Jesuits at a nearby high school.
A highlight was his reunion with the Reverend Francisco Cortes, a priest affectionately known as "Padre Paquito," to whom the Argentina-born pope, then the Reverend Jorge Mario Bergoglio, entrusted his seminarians on study trips to Ecuador years ago.
In a recent interview with The Associated Press, Cortes couldn't fathom that Bergoglio remembered him, much less made a point of coming to have lunch. "I don't know what to ask him," the soon-to-be 91-year-old Cortes said. "I'm really just a Mr Nobody."
Returning to the capital of Quito at dusk, Francis paid a 50-minute courtesy visit to Rafael Correa at the presidential palace. When it ended, Correa ushered him to reception line of dozens that took a quarter hour to negotiate.
The pope then prayed in Quito's cathedral and went out on the steps to address a crowd, many of whom had waited hours to see him and endured a deluge. But instead of giving the short speech that he had prepared, Francis offered a brief blessing.
Quito Mass
Tuesday brings another big public Mass, this time in Quito, as well as a meeting with the country's bishops, a speech at Ecuador's Catholic University and an evening gathering with civil society groups, including indigenous leaders.
Tens of thousands who lined up outside the Quito park where the Mass was to be held got soaked in a punishing rain and hail storm. People grabbed what they could to protect themselves. They tore vinyl advertising placards off the metal fences surrounding the park, which was the city's international airport until two years ago.
Some just shrugged it off. Although her clothes were soaked and she shivered in the cold of Quito's 9,000-foot altitude, 71-year-old Angelica Naranjo said: "This isn't a sacrifice. It's a demonstration of faith."
Quito security chief Juan Zapata said officials would distribute blankets from stocks kept by civil defence authorities.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:22:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Australian senator threatens to grab Abbott's testicles</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Australian-senator-threatens-to-grab-Abbotts-testicles-20150707</Link>
        <Description>An independent Australian senator has threatened to physically intimidate Prime Minister Tony Abbott, using illegal rugby tactics including grabbing his testicles, if he does not limit coal-seam gas exploration.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australian senator threatens to grab Abbott's testicles
2015-07-07 10:22
Senator Glenn Lazarus. (William West, AFP)
Australia tells Indonesia to fix its borders
Sydney - An independent Australian senator on Tuesday threatened to physically intimidate Prime Minister Tony Abbott, using illegal rugby tactics including grabbing his testicles, if he does not limit coal-seam gas exploration.
Glenn Lazarus, a former rugby league prop and a senator for the eastern state of Queensland, said he submitted a petition to Abbott calling for health impact assessments, exclusion zones and community consultations over mining developments near residential, agricultural and farming areas.
Lazarus, dubbed the "brick with eyes" in his rugby heyday, added to an anti-CSG protest in Sydney that he was prepared to use a range of tactics on the Australian leader if he does not respond to the community's concerns.
"I am prepared to go and squirrel grip, squirrel grip, the prime minister," Lazarus added, in apparently light-hearted comments.
"If that doesn't work I have got other things up my sleeve, like the grapple tackle, the chicken wing and even the crusher tackle, and if that doesn't work, I'm prepared to use the Hopoate tactics."
The "squirrel grip" is a testicle-grabbing tackle, the "chicken wing" involves twisting or bending an opponent's limbs and the "crusher" is pinning the head of a player against the tackler's chest.
"Hopoate tactics" is named after former Australian and Tongan rugby league player and serial offender John Hopoate, who in 2001 was banned for two weeks for inserting his finger in the anuses of several opposition players.
Lazarus, previously a member of flamboyant billionaire Clive Palmer's party in the upper house Senate before he quit to become independent, also said he had threatened to "shirtfront" Abbott over the coal-seam gas issue.
Abbott in October vowed to "shirtfront", an Australian Rules football term in which a player charges an opponent Russian president Vladimir Putin over the July 2014 crash of Malaysia Airlines MH17 in rebel-held eastern Ukraine.
Australia is one of the world's largest gas exporters and Lazarus said he was fired up about the issue as deposits and mines were causing "havoc to the residents that are living there".
Abbott had no immediate reaction.
Read more on:  tony abbott | australia
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:23:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Saudi Arabia arrests brothers linked to ISIS bombing in Kuwait</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Saudi-Arabia-arrests-brothers-linked-to-ISIS-bombing-in-Kuwait-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Saudi authorities have arrested three brothers linked to a suicide bombing by a Saudi man on a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in neighbouring Kuwait last month, a report says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saudi Arabia arrests brothers linked to ISIS bombing in Kuwait
2015-07-07 10:23
File: AFP
Biden calls Saudi Arabia after diplomatic gaffe
Dubai - Saudi authorities have arrested three brothers linked to a suicide bombing by a Saudi man on a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in neighbouring Kuwait last month, Saudi state news agency SPA reported on Tuesday.
The ultra-radical Sunni Islamic State group said it carried out the attack, which killed 27 people and appeared aimed at stoking sectarian hatred in the energy-rich Gulf.
The three Saudi brothers, who were not identified, were "parties to the crime of the sinful terrorist bombing that targeted the Imam al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait", SPA quoted a security spokesperson for the interior ministry as saying.
One was arrested in Kuwait and was extradited to the kingdom, another was arrested in the western city of Taif and a third was taken into custody after a shootout at a house near the Kuwaiti border that wounded two policemen.
A fourth brother lives in Syria and is a member of Islamic State, the security spokesperson added.
The bombing was Kuwait's deadliest militant attack, and the most lethal in any of the six hereditary-ruled Gulf Arab states since a campaign of al-Qaeda bombings was stamped out in Saudi Arabia a decade ago.
The attack has raised concerns about the number of young Saudi men willing to travel to attack Shi'ites in smaller Gulf Arab states and so make good on a threat by Islamic State to step up violence in the holy fasting month of Ramadan.
The group claimed two suicide bombings carried out on May 22 and May 29 on Shi'ite mosques in eastern Saudi Arabia, where the bulk of Saudi Arabia's Shi'ite minority lives.
The Saudi branch of the militant group has said it wants to clear the Arabian Peninsula of Shi'ites and urged young men in the kingdom to join its cause.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Thai military court releases 14 student protesters</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Thai-military-court-releases-14-student-protesters-20150707</Link>
        <Description>A Thai military court has released 14 students held for almost two weeks for holding anti-coup protests in defiance of a ban on public gathering, but the charges against them have not been dropped.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thai military court releases 14 student protesters
2015-07-07 09:13
Anti-government protesters have rallied in Bangkok in their biggest bid yet to topple Thai Prime Minister Abhisit Vejjajiva. The protests are the latest saga in Thailand's tug of war between recently ousted PM Thaksin Shinawatra's supporters and opponents.
Related Links
Renewed protests in Thailand view
Bangkok - A Thai military court on Tuesday released 14 students held for almost two weeks for holding anti-coup protests in defiance of a ban on public gatherings, but the charges against them have not been dropped.
There had been growing calls for their release, including from the United Nations and the European Union, and public shows of support for the 14 have taken place across Thailand and among the Thai diaspora over the past few days.
Thailand's military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
"Police asked to extend the students' detention but today the court threw out that request," said Kisadang Nutjarat, a lawyer for the students.
"They have released the kids from prison today. There are no conditions and there was no bail," he said, adding that charges against the students had not been dropped.
Street demonstrations
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations across Bangkok against the ruling junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
They were arrested last month and charged with sedition.
Scores gathered outside a military court in Bangkok on Tuesday, shouting slogans and holding signs, to show their support for the students as 150 police officers stood guard nearby.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand's first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Thailand has been bitterly divided for a decade between supporters of Yingluck and her brother, former Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, who was himself ousted by the army in 2006, and the traditional establishment in the capital and the south.
Read more on:  thailand
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:06:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Wealthy family 'knifed to death' in Vietnam</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Wealthy-family-knifed-to-death-in-Vietnam-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Six members of a wealthy family in southern Vietnam were found knifed to death in their home after an apparent break-in, news reports say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wealthy family 'knifed to death' in Vietnam
2015-07-07 09:06
Michael Brown's family to sue city of Ferguson
Hanoi - Six members of a wealthy family in southern Vietnam were found knifed to death in their home early Tuesday after an apparent break-in, news reports said.
Victims included the 47-year-old husband, his wife and two of their children, including a 10-year-old boy. A niece and a nephew of the couple were also killed. Their 2-year-old daughter was not harmed.
Police made one arrest and were searching for other suspects, Thanh Nien newspaper reported.
The murders were discovered at around 8:00 by a neighbour in Chon Thanh District of Binh Phuoc province, Tuoi Tre newspaper reported, around 90km north of Ho Chi Minh city.
Police told reporters that the family, which owns a woodworking factory with more than 100 workers, was apparently targeted for robbery.
Perpetrators broke into the house early on Tuesday and tied the six victims to three pillars, according to news reports.
Read more on:  vietnam
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:06:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Gay couple sue for recognition in South Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Gay-couple-sue-for-recognition-in-South-Korea-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Buoyed by a landmark US Supreme Court ruling, a prominent South Korean gay rights campaigner and movie director is suing officials for refusing to recognise his 2013 same-sex marriage.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gay couple sue for recognition in South Korea
2015-07-07 09:06
Kim Jho Gwang-Soo, a South Korean movie director who is gay, and his partner Kim Seung-Hwan. (Jung Yeon-Je, AFP)
Gay marriage pressure builds on Australian government
Seoul - Buoyed by a landmark US Supreme Court ruling, a prominent South Korean gay rights campaigner and movie director is suing officials for refusing to recognise his 2013 same-sex marriage.
Kim Jho Gwang-Soo, a rare openly gay celebrity in conservative South Korea and his partner Kim Seung-Hwan took their fight for legitimacy to a district court in western Seoul on Monday.
The couple held an outdoor wedding ceremony in Seoul in September 2013 and submitted their marriage registration form to their local authority, only for it to be rejected.
While homosexuality is not illegal in South Korea, same-sex marriage is not recognised.
Gay and transgender people live largely under the radar in a country that remains deeply conservative about matters of sexual identity and where many still regard homosexuality as a foreign phenomenon.
Monday's court hearing, held behind closed doors, marked the first effort by a same-sex couple in South Korea to acquire legal status for their marriage.
"If you are a Korean citizen, you are equal under Korean law," Kim, 50, told reporters outside the court.
"I hope through this trial we can uncover this constitutional principle," Kim said, adding that he had pleaded with the court to "acknowledge our marriage before I die."
The lawsuit has been given added prominence by the June 26 Supreme Court ruling that made same-sex marriage legal throughout the United States.
Celebrations of the landmark decision were at the heart of what organisers described as South Korea's biggest annual gay pride parade on June 28.
Concerns over potential clashes with Christian activists prompted police to ban the march a month before it was due to take place, but a Seoul court later overturned the ban.
Police estimated more than 6 000 people took part in the hour-long parade in Seoul, while organisers put the number at more than 20 000.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:05:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | World's oldest man dies at 112 in Japan</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Worlds-oldest-man-dies-at-112-in-Japan-20150707</Link>
        <Description>The world's oldest man, Sakari Momoi, has died in Japan at the ripe old age of 112.</Description>
        <MainBody>World's oldest man dies at 112 in Japan
2015-07-07 08:05
World's oldest man Sakari Momoi. (Japan Pool via Jiji Press, AFP)
Grandma, 92, sets record for oldest woman marathoner
Tokyo - The world's oldest man, Sakari Momoi, has died in Japan at the ripe old age of 112, an official said on Tuesday.
Momoi, born months before the Wright brothers made their first successful flight, passed away late on Sunday, said the official at Saitama City, north of Tokyo, where he had lived for many years.
The supercentenarian, recognised as the world's oldest male at the age of 111 last year, died of kidney failure in a care home in Tokyo.
"We heard from his family... that his health worsened one or two weeks ago," the official said.
Momoi, a former high school principal who was born on February 5, 1903, received a certificate from Guinness World Records confirming the achievement last year.
Two more years
Dressed in a black suit, white shirt and silver tie, Momoi told assembled media that he did not plan on going anywhere just yet.
"I want to live for about two more years," he said in soft voice at that time.
He was born in Minamisoma, Fukushima, an area badly hit by the deadly 9.0-magnitude earthquake and tsunami in 2011 that triggered the world worst nuclear crisis in a generation.
According to the US-based Gerontology Research Group, the title of world's oldest man now passes to Japan's Yasutaro Koide, also 112 years old and just over a month younger than Momoi.
On the opposite side of the Pacific, the world's oldest person celebrated her 116th birthday on Monday.
New Yorker Susannah Mushatt Jones, a former live-in housekeeper, known as "T" to her 100 nieces and nephews, was born on July 6, 1899.
Japan is known for the longevity of its people and around a quarter of its population of 128 million is aged 65 or older.
Read more on:  japan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:05:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UN goals helped lift 1 billion from extreme poverty – Ban</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UN-goals-helped-lift-1-billion-from-extreme-poverty-Ban-20150707</Link>
        <Description>A 15-year effort to implement eight goals adopted by world leaders at the start of the new millennium has helped lift more than one billion people out of extreme poverty, the UN chief says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Halving world hunger by 2015 possible: UN
New York - A 15-year effort to implement eight goals adopted by world leaders at the start of the new millennium has helped lift more than one billion people out of extreme poverty, enabled more girls to go to school than ever before, and brought unprecedented results in fighting diseases such as HIV/Aids, the UN chief said on Monday.
In the final report on the Millennium Development Goals released on Monday, Secretary General Ban Ki-moon said the global mobilisation to implement the goals by the end of 2015 has produced "the most successful anti-poverty movement in history".
But he said inequality persists, with 80% of the people living on less than $1.25 a day residing in two regions  southern Asia and sub-Saharan Africa, and 60% in just five countries, India, Nigeria, China, Bangladesh and Congo.
"Too many people have been left behind, particularly the poorest and those disadvantaged because of their sex, age, disability, ethnicity or geographic location," Ban said in a video conference launching the report from the Norwegian capital, Oslo. "Too many women and children continue to die during pregnancy or from childbirth-related complications. And too many people lack adequate sanitation facilities, especially in rural areas."
Ban said other dangers have intensified since 2000.
Human development
"Conflicts have forced almost 60 million people to abandon their homes  the highest level of displacement since the end of World War II, with staggering consequences for human development," he said. "Climate change has become an existential peril, environmental degradation is undermining development gains  and both are affecting poor people the most."
Ban said global efforts now have to focus on these gaps.
World leaders are set to adopt a new set of goals at a summit in September. But this time there will be 17 goals with 169 targets to be achieved by 2030.
While the goal of achieving universal primary education won't be met, the report said enrolment rose from 83% in 2000 to 91 percent this year, and the number of school-age children not getting an education fell from 100 million to 57 million over the last 15 years.
As for other goals, the report said, child mortality has declined by more than half and maternal mortality by 45% over the last 25 years, new HIV infections fell by approximately 40% between 2000 and 2015, and women have gained ground in parliament over the last 20 years in nearly 90% of the 174 countries with data.
The report also said ozone-depleting substances have been virtually eliminated since 1990 and the ozone layer is expected to recover by the middle of the century. And it said government aid to developing countries increased by 66 percent in real terms between 2000 and 2014, reaching $135.2 billion.
The report, compiled by over 28 UN and international agencies, was produced by the UN Department of Economic and Social Affairs.
Read more on:  un | ban ki-moon
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | HSBC fires staff for mock ISIS execution video</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/HSBC-fires-staff-for-mock-ISIS-execution-video-20150707</Link>
        <Description>British bank HSBC has fired six staff members after they filmed a mock ISIS-style execution video during a team-building day out and posted footage online, a spokesperson confirms.</Description>
        <MainBody>HSBC fires staff for mock ISIS execution video
2015-07-07 07:12
(Site Intelligence Group, HO, AFP)
ISIS video shows killing of 2 Syrian activists
London - British bank HSBC fired six staff after they filmed a mock ISIS-style execution video during a team-building day out and posted footage online, a spokesperson confirmed on Tuesday.
The bank described the video, showing staff members in balaclavas holding a fake knife over a kneeling man in an orange jumpsuit, as "abhorrent".
"We took the decision to sack the individuals involved," a spokesperson for the bank said.
"This is an abhorrent video and HSBC would like to apologise for any offence caused."
The employees filmed the video on an HSBC team-building day at a go-karting centre in Birmingham and posted it on Instagram before deleting it, according to newspaper The Sun, which published the video on its website.
In the eight-second clip, a kneeling man in a jumpsuit is held by the shoulders while a colleague wields a coat hanger like a knife above him, as though preparing to cut off his head.
One staff member shouts "Allahu Akbar" [God is greater in Arabic] during the clip.
The staging recalls gruesome beheading videos released by the ISIS, which has executed over 3 000 people in Syria in the year since it declared an Islamic "caliphate" in Syria and Iraq, according to the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
ISIS killed a series of international hostages dressed in orange jumpsuits, including British aid workers David Haines and Alan Henning, in videos that caused shock when they were released last year.
HSBC has recently weathered a string of bad publicity, including allegations its Swiss private banking arm helped wealthy clients dodge tax, and fines by regulators for attempting to rig foreign exchange markets.
In June it announced it would cut its global workforce by up to 50 000 as it exits Brazil and Turkey and mulls relocating its headquarters back to Asia from London.
Read more on:  isis | uk
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:50:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UK remembers 2005 London bombings under shadow of Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UK-remembers-2005-London-bombings-under-shadow-of-Tunisia-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Britain will mark 10 years since the London bombings with a minute's silence for the 52 victims, less than a fortnight after an attack in Tunisia highlighted the ongoing Islamist threat.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK remembers 2005 London bombings under shadow of Tunisia
2015-07-07 05:50
CCTV camera in London. (AP)
Britain mourns 15 dead in Tunisia attack
London - Britain will on Tuesday mark 10 years since the London bombings with a minute's silence for the 52 victims, less than a fortnight after an attack in Tunisia highlighted the ongoing Islamist threat.
Thirty Britons were among 38 people killed when a gunman went on the rampage at a popular Tunisian beach resort on June 26, Britain's worst terror incident since four suicide bombers attacked the London transport network on July 7, 2005.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly," Prime Minister David Cameron said.
"The murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
Radicalisation
In the past decade, successive governments have strengthened security powers and improved the way the emergency services respond to attacks.
But they are still struggling to address the problem of radicalisation exposed by the bombings, which were carried out not by foreign fighters but by four young men from Yorkshire in northern England who were inspired by Al-Qaeda.
Hundreds of British young people are now flocking to join the Islamic State group in Syria and Iraq, raising fears that they might return to attack their homeland.
"We will keep on doing all that we can to keep the British public safe, protecting vulnerable young minds from others' extremist beliefs and promoting the shared values of tolerance, love and respect that make Britain so great," Cameron said.
The commemorations begin with a wreath-laying at the national memorial in Hyde Park at 08:50 (07:50 GMT), marking the moment the first three bombs exploded on London Underground trains at Aldgate, Edgware Road and Russell Square stations.
An hour later, a fourth suicide bomber blew himself up on a double-decker bus in Tavistock Square near Russell Square, killing and injuring some of those who had been evacuated from the Underground.
'Body parts all over the place'
Relatives and survivors will gather at the Hyde Park memorial later in the day to lay flowers, while there will also be a service at St Paul's Cathedral.
A nationwide minute's silence will be held at 10:30 GMT, the second such gesture in four days after Britain fell silent on Friday for those killed in Tunisia.
For many of those directly affected by the London bombings, the anniversary has brought back painful memories.
David Boyce was a 25-year-old supervisor at Russell Square station and one of the first to witness the carnage.
"There was body parts all over the place and dead bodies lying all over the train," he told AFP in an interview.
He added: "The first person I came across, both his legs had got blown off.
"So using my own clothes I made a tourniquet, lifting his legs above his heart, made him more comfortable, let him know that help was on the way."
Counter-terrorism strategy
Many lives were saved by people such as Boyce, but the general emergency response was fractured, hampered by poor communications inside the tunnels and between controllers.
This has been overhauled, as has the government's counter-terrorism strategy, with new measures introduced to clamp down on radical preachers and give police and security services tougher powers to question and track suspects.
This year Cameron's government also moved to seize passports from Britons going to fight with the IS group, and it is working on highly controversial plans to increase the collection of mobile phone and Internet data.
The national terror threat remains severe, the second highest of five levels meaning an attack is highly likely.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:45:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | South Carolina Senate votes to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/South-Carolina-Senate-votes-to-remove-Confederate-flag-20150706</Link>
        <Description>The South Carolina Senate has voted to remove the Confederate flag from a pole on Statehouse grounds.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Carolina Senate votes to remove Confederate flag
2015-07-06 23:45
Jim Collins protests proposals to remove the Confederate flag from the grounds of the South Carolina Statehouse. (Jeffrey Collin, AP)
Protesters, politicians: Take down Confederate flag
Columbia - The South Carolina Senate has voted to remove the Confederate flag from a pole on Statehouse grounds.
Lawmakers had largely ignored the flag until the killing of nine black people during a Bible study at a historic African-American church on June 17.
The 37-3 vote on Monday allows the state to remove the flag and the flagpole where it flies as soon as it passes the state House of Representatives and is signed by Governor Nikki Haley.
The bill must pass a two-thirds vote, which is likely to be held on Tuesday.
The Confederate flag was raised atop the State House dome in 1961 as part of centennial commemorations of the Civil War.
Critics said that was a direct challenge to civil rights, voting rights and desegregation protests at the time.
Read more on:  us | charleston shooting
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:05:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 1000s evacuate as wildfires burn in Canada</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/1000s-evacuate-as-wildfires-burn-in-Canada-20150706</Link>
        <Description>More than 200 forest fires are burning across western Canada, causing a heavy grey haze to settle over the Pacific coast and forcing the evacuation of thousands of residents.</Description>
        <MainBody>1000s evacuate as wildfires burn in Canada
2015-07-06 23:05
A view of part of down town Vancouver covered with a smoky haze from the wildfires. (Franck Fife, AFP)
Mushers stand together as Alaska wildfire rages
Vancouver - More than 200 forest fires are burning across western Canada, causing a heavy grey haze to settle over the Pacific coast and forcing the evacuation of thousands of residents.
Authorities issued air quality advisories across British Columbia on Monday as an unrelenting heat wave that began in early June sent temperatures soaring to record highs. More than 20 fires were sparked on Sunday alone, according to officials.
People with medical conditions, as well as the elderly and the very young were urged to remain indoors and limit strenuous activity.
A 61-year-old logger died on Sunday while helping forestry crews battle a wildfire near Sechelt, north of Vancouver.
Local authorities have imposed a province-wide ban on open burning.
Read more on:  canada | weather
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:35:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Boston bomber demands new trial</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Boston-bomber-demands-new-trial-20150706</Link>
        <Description>Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev has filed a motion demanding a new trial, less than two weeks after he was sentenced to death for attacking the city's marathon in 2013.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston bomber demands new trial
2015-07-06 22:35
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev sits as survivors and victim's family members address the court before the US District Judge in Boston. (Jane Flavell Collins, AP)
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev sentenced to death
New York - Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev filed a motion on Monday demanding a new trial, less than two weeks after he was sentenced to death for attacking the city's marathon in 2013.
The preliminary motion did not stipulate grounds for a new trial, other than to say it was "required in the interests of justice."
His lawyers said it was a "placeholder" motion that would be expanded upon by August 17.
Tsarnaev, 21, apologized to his victims for the first time during a highly emotional court hearing in Boston on June 24 when he was sentenced to death on six counts for the April 15, 2013 bombings.
A US jury determined the sentence unanimously on May 15 after finding him guilty on all 30 counts related to the bombings, the murder of a police officer and other crimes carried out while on the run.
The bombings killed three people and wounded 264 others in one of the deadliest attacks on US soil since the September 11, 2001 attacks.
They were carried out by Tsarnaev and his older brother Tamerlan, who was shot dead by police while on the run.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:36:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US boy dies after being beaten for eating cake</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/US-boy-dies-after-being-beaten-for-eating-cake-20150706</Link>
        <Description>Police say a 9-year-old boy has died in the US after he allegedly was handcuffed and beaten for eating a piece of birthday cake without permission.</Description>
        <MainBody>US boy dies after being beaten for eating cake
2015-07-06 22:36
Kenya survivor: Sight of dead child made me want to kill
Hagerstown - Police say a 9-year-old boy has died after he was allegedly handcuffed and beaten for eating a piece of birthday cake without permission.
Hagerstown police Captain Paul Kifer says Jack Garcia died on Sunday at Children's National Medical Center in Washington.
Kifer says police will confer with Washington County prosecutors about bringing additional charges in the case.
The mother's boyfriend, 30-year-old Robert Wilson, was charged on Wednesday with first-degree assault and child abuse. His public defender hasn't returned calls from The Associated Press.
The mother's brother told police the boy was handcuffed on Tuesday as punishment for stealing the cake. He says Wilson hit the boy in stomach after the handcuffs were removed.
It's not clear whose cake it was. The boy had had a birthday three days earlier.
Read more on:  us
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:11:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Iran talks may fail - German source</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Iran-talks-may-fail-German-source-20150706</Link>
        <Description>Talks seeking a landmark nuclear deal between Iran and major powers may yet fail, a German diplomatic source says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran talks may fail - German source
2015-07-06 22:11
(AP)
Iran atomic bomb probe may be completed in 2015
Vienna - Talks seeking a landmark nuclear deal between Iran and major powers may yet fail, a German diplomatic source said on Monday during a break in negotiations in Vienna on the eve of a deadline.
"We are not there yet... We should not underestimate that important questions remain unresolved. There will not be an agreement at any price. If there is no movement in decisive areas a failure is not ruled out," the source said.
The comments came after a day of talks between the foreign ministers of Iran and six major powers - the United States, Russia, China, Britain, Germany and France - in the Austrian capital.
They are seeking an accord that ends a 13-year-old stand-off over Iran's nuclear programme by scaling down its activities in return for relief from painful sanctions.
Last week an earlier deadline was effectively extended by seven days to July 7 by extending the terms of an interim deal from November 2013.
But on Monday an Iranian official suggested that his delegation had never really considered Tuesday as a deadline.
"July 7, July 8, we do not consider these dates as those dates we have to finish our job," the official, who asked not to be named, told reporters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
