<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:17:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Syria rebels storm city, take province</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Syria-rebels-storm-city-take-province-20150528</Link>
        <Description>A rebel coalition led by al-Qaeda's Syrian affiliate has edged into the last remaining government-held city in the northwest province of Idlib.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria rebels storm city, take province
2015-05-28 21:17
An image grab taken from an undated video uploaded on YouTube allegedly shows a member of the jihadist group Al-Nusra Front shooting blindfolded supporters of the Syrian regime at an undisclosed location in eastern Syria. (YouTube/ AFP)
ISIS executes 200+ in ancient Syrian city - monitor
Beirut - A rebel coalition led by al-Qaeda's Syrian affiliate edged into the last remaining government-held city in the northwest province of Idlib on Thursday, a monitoring group said.
The lightning offensive saw the Army of Conquest, or Jaish al-Fatah in Arabic, enter outer districts of Ariha within a matter of hours, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights told AFP.
"There was heavy shelling and rocket fire, then they stormed the city," said Observatory director Rami Abdel Rahman.
"They have entered the city and are engaged in fierce clashes on its peripheries," he added.
Ariha, which was home to 40 000 people before the conflict began, is the last remaining government-held city in Idlib province which borders Turkey.
"The march of lions has begun... Let Allah liberate Ariha," the Army of Conquest's official Twitter account posted.
The coalition, which includes al-Qaeda branch Al-Nusra Front, has won a series of victories in Idlib, including the provincial capital on March 28 and the key town of Jisr al-Shughur on April 25.
Most recently, the rebels seized the massive Al-Mastumah military base and overran a hospital complex where regime soldiers were trapped.
Many government forces retreated from these areas to Ariha, which Abdel Rahman said was heavily defended by fighters from Iran and Lebanese Shi'ite movement Hezbollah.
The Army of Conquest vowed to consolidate its control of Idlib province, where the regime still holds Ariha, the Abu Duhur military airport and a sprinkling of minority villages and military posts.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:17:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Putin makes troop deaths a state secret</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Putin-makes-troop-deaths-a-state-secret-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has banned revealing information about troop deaths during peacetime, as the Kremlin continues to rebuff accusations its soldiers are fighting in Ukraine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin makes troop deaths a state secret
2015-05-28 21:17
Putin lauds Russian 'glory and power'
Moscow - Russian President Vladimir Putin on Thursday banned revealing information about troop deaths in "special operations" during peacetime, as the Kremlin continues to rebuff accusations its soldiers are fighting in Ukraine.
The strongman signed an amendment adding to what Russia classifies as "state secrets" any "information revealing losses of personnel... in peacetime during special operations."
The addition means that those who disclose details about the deaths of soldiers sent on operations during peacetime could be prosecuted.
The decree gives no details of what exactly is meant by a "special operation". Revealing state secrets, when it does not involve handing them to a foreign state, is a criminal offence that can be punished by up to four years in jail.
Analysts said the legal change was aimed at stamping out any leaks on Russian military losses in Ukraine after activists released a string of evidence pointing to the deaths of government soldiers across the border in the former Soviet state.
"The reason is not to reveal losses in Donbass," said military analyst Pavel Felgenhauer, referring to the war zone in eastern Ukraine, adding that the legal move was designed to "imprison or scare people".
"I've never heard a legal definition of the concept of a special operation," said Felgenhauer. "That means you could classify anything you like as this."
Troops mass on border
The Kremlin decree came as reports have pointed to a massing of Russian equipment close to the Ukraine border.
An AFP photographer in recent days saw Russian military vehicles loaded on a freight train in the southern Rostov region, around 20km from the Ukrainian border.
The photographer also saw Russian military vehicles at a training camp around 50km from the border.
The Kremlin has consistently denied government soldiers are fighting in Ukraine and claimed those fighting alongside rebels are there as volunteers.
Ukraine and the West insist Russia has not only armed and equipped the rebels but also sent in troops to spearhead fighting against Kiev's forces.
Nato has said rebels are using a lull in the fighting due to a shaky truce to bolster their forces ahead of possible new offensive.
The presence of Russian troops in east Ukraine has been backed up by reports from activists of hushed-up funerals, interviews with soldiers in the Russian media, and information gathered from relatives and social networking sites.
US-based think tank Atlantic Council released a report on Wednesday detailing "irrefutable evidence of direct Russian military involvement in eastern Ukraine" that researchers gathered from open sources.
Jail for espionage
The tightening of the state secrets act prompted an outraged reaction from Kremlin critics.
"Now the activity of looking for victims of 'special operations' in Ukraine will be a breach of state secrets," warned opposition leader and lawyer Alexei Navalny on his blog.
"Let the soldiers die and their relatives keep quiet. Those who don't agree, we'll jail for espionage."
Rights lawyer Nikolai Polozov wrote on Twitter: "If you want, you needn't bother giving relatives an insurance payout and a pension, and they won't tell anyone."
According to the latest survey by independent polling agency Levada published on May 5, only 20% of Russians believe government forces are fighting in Ukraine.
Forty-eight percent said they believed Russians were serving there as volunteers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 20:37:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Watchdog says 90% of declared chemical weapons destroyed</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Watchdog-says-90-of-global-stockpile-destroyed-20150528</Link>
        <Description>The chemical weapons watchdog has hailed a milestone in its mission to rid the world of poison gas and nerve agents, saying 90% of stocks declared has now been destroyed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Watchdog says 90% of declared chemical weapons destroyed
2015-05-28 18:54
Iraqi army retakes chemical weapons site from ISIS
The Hague - The Nobel Peace Prize-winning chemical weapons watchdog has hailed a milestone in its mission to rid the world of poison gas and nerve agents, saying 90% of stocks declared by its members worldwide has now been destroyed.
Ahmet Uzumcu, director-general of the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons, announced the milestone Thursday, saying it "shows we are well on the way to ridding the world of chemical weapons."
The organisation has been thrown into the spotlight over the last two years by its efforts to oversee the destruction of Syrian chemical weapons, but the majority of stocks are Cold War-era weapons held by the United States and Russia.
Russia is scheduled to complete destruction of its stockpile by 2020 and the United States three years later.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Texas cities worry about flooding</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Texas-cities-worry-about-flooding-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Texas cities worry that rivers swollen by heavy rains this week could lead to flooding.</Description>
        <MainBody>Texas cities worry about flooding
2015-05-28 17:18
The Blanco River flows past a road around Umphery Ranch located between Wimberley and San Marcos, Texas. (Gabe Hernandez, Corpus Christi Caller-Times via AP)
Twister kills 13 in Mexico; 12 missing in Texas
Houston - Many Texas cities remain in danger though a barrage of deadly thunderstorms has tapered, as officials warn about the possibility of more flooding from rain-swollen rivers.
The storms and floods in Texas and Oklahoma this week have left at least 21 people dead and about a dozen others missing.
In suburban Houston, the rains have pushed the San Jacinto River above flood stage, and its waters were expected to cover streets in subdivisions along the west fork of the river, possibly stranding people in their homes for days if they don't leave.
In Wharton, about 80km southwest of Houston, the mayor asked residents to voluntarily evacuate about 300 homes on the west side of the city due to the predicted rise of the Colorado River. In the Parker County town of Horseshoe Bend in North Texas, officials asked about 250 residents to leave their homes as the Brazos River was expected to rise above its flood stage of 6.4m on Thursday.
Meanwhile, in Central Texas, crews continued searching for nine people feared dead after the swollen Blanco River smashed through Wimberley, a small tourist town between San Antonio and Austin, over the Memorial Day weekend.
In Houston, residents whose homes were flooded by torrential rains on Monday and Tuesday also continued their clean-up efforts.
While the Houston area got a respite from rainy weather for most of Wednesday, the heavy rains from earlier in the week were still making their way downstream. By late Wednesday, the San Jacinto was at 15m, nearly one metre above its flood stage, said Kim Jackson, a spokesperson for the Harris County Flood Control District.
In Houston, between 800 and 1 400 homes have already been damaged by the flooding. Thousands of homes were also damaged or destroyed in the central Texas corridor that includes Wimberley  744 of them in San Marcos alone.
This has been the wettest month on record for Texas, even with several days left. The state climatologist's office said Wednesday that Texas has gotten an average of 19.15cm of rain in May, breaking the old record of 16.92cm, set in June 2004.
While rain is in the forecast the next couple of days for many of the affected areas, the chances for showers are greater during the weekend.
Read more on:  us | weather | flooding
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Yemen may never emerge intact from civil war</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Yemen-may-never-emerge-intact-from-civil-war-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Yemen may never emerge as a united country from a civil war pitting a northern Shi'ite Muslim militia and its allies in the army against fighters in the mostly Sunni south.</Description>
        <MainBody>Yemen may never emerge intact from civil war
2015-05-28 17:18
Yemeni supporters of the separatist Southern Movement, loyal to the government forces, hold a position on the western outskirts of Aden during reported clashes with Shi'ite rebels. (Saleh al-Obeidi, AFP)
ISIS claims Yemen mosque attack
Cairo - Yemen may never emerge as a united country from a civil war pitting a northern Shi'ite Muslim militia and its allies in the army against fighters in the mostly Sunni south.
The latest conflict, now in its third month, has exacerbated long-standing grievances that are regional but also increasingly religious in a country whose unity has always been brittle.
Secessionist sentiment in the south, stoked by what southerners see as decades of marginalization by the north, is deepening as result of the damage inflicted upon Aden and other southern cities in assaults by the northern Houthi militia.
Sunni Muslim Arab states have maintained an air bombing campaign against the Houthis, allied to archrival Shi'ite Iran, but the Houthis retain the upper hand in battles in the south.
Southern combatants fight under the flag of their formerly independent state, and residents spurn the idea of again joining those they see as northern invaders.
"What unity could there be after the destruction we see on our streets and wars of extermination against the south? Forget it," said Saleh Hashem, a resident of Aden, a port city whose historic commercial district lies in ruins.
Once a British protectorate turned satellite state of the Soviet Union, South Yemen joined North Yemen to form a united country in 1990 under then President Ali Abdullah Saleh, who took power in the north in 1978.
Many in the south, home to most Yemeni oil facilities, felt northerners had commandeered their resources and denied them their identity and political rights. The South then sought to break away in 1994, but Saleh re-united the country by force.
Resentment has festered since the unification and has grown with the ongoing war, taking on more religious overtones.
"We want there to be one people, but in two states with open borders between their citizens," Fuad Rashed, a leader of the southern secession movement, told Reuters.
"The ongoing war has bloodied and slaughtered what little remained of the national unity that has been bungled for over two decades," he said.
Despite Saleh's overthrow during the 2011 Arab Spring protests, he and loyalists in Yemen's army have made common cause with the Houthis, helping their drive from northern strongholds into the capital Sanaa in September and further south.
Northern entente
The Houthis say their advance is part of a revolution against Sunni Islamist militants and corrupt officials. Saleh says he seeks reconciliation and denies accusations that he wants to settle old scores.
The northerners' alliance against Yemen's government, whose base of support is in Aden, may reflect a new unity of purpose in the heavily tribal north, where Shi'ite Islam's Zaydi sect, to which the Houthis belong, prevails.
"A sectarian and regional polarization is under way. When the Houthis took over Sanaa and beyond, it showed that the Zaydi tribesmen were again vying for control)," a northern Yemeni politician, who requested anonymity for security reasons, told Reuters by telephone from Sanaa.
"The majority of the military command, being northerners, quickly fell in with this agenda," the politician said.
The northern advance is firing religious zeal in the south.
"The Houthis are a Shi'ite religious movement, and the whole south is Sunni. This has caused the religious to support the idea of secession more, so that the authority remains Sunni and they avoid living in a united state run by Shi'ites," said Mahmoud al-Salmi, a history professor at Aden University.
Unstable
While the idea of secession has gained ground, a security vacuum brought on by the split of Yemen's army into pro- and anti-Houthi factions may make a viable southern state harder.
Religious hardliners may be poised to make the most gains.
After pro-Saleh troops evacuated last month, a council of conservative Sunni tribesmen and clerics emerged to govern southeastern Hadramawt province, Yemen's largest and home to the modest oil reserves that keep its finances afloat.
Residents of Hadramawt's main city, Mukalla, say the council has made a pact with al Qaeda's Yemen branch, allowing it to hold recruitment rallies, set up informal Islamic courts and carry their weapons in public.
Southern activists worry that the new prominence of the group, whose goal of attacking the Yemeni state and Western targets, could turn the region into a hotbed of strife rather than the state they seek.
"The truth is that the situation has become like an Islamic Republic, where al Qaeda operates freely to impose its deviant version of hardline Islamic Law," activist Mohammed al-Sharqi said by telephone from Mukalla.
All this will only add to the worries of the United States, which poured aid and military assistance into Yemen, including drone strikes, to counter al-Qaeda's rise but has had to scale back due to this year's conflict.
Read more on:  al-qaeda | yemen
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Myanmar restricts journalists after photos of sleeping MPs go viral</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Myanmar-restricts-journalists-after-photos-of-sleeping-MPs-go-viral-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Journalists can no longer cover Myanmar's nascent Parliament from inside the media chamber because pictures of snoozing lawmakers have been published online.</Description>
        <MainBody>Myanmar restricts journalists after photos of sleeping MPs go viral
2015-05-28 17:18
An army representative dozes off at a parliament session in Naypyitaw, Myanmar. (Khin Maung Win, AP)
Myanmar acknowledges concern over migrant exodus
Yangon - Journalists can no longer cover Myanmar's nascent Parliament from inside the media chamber because pictures of snoozing lawmakers were published online.
Reporters in the capital, Naypyitaw, were told they would have to watch proceedings on TV from the corridor. The pictures of sleeping MPs were the main reason cited by Kyaw Soe, director general of the Union Parliament, which handles administrative duties.
Other embarrassing pictures have circulated showing lawmakers using iPad devices while in session. Another appeared to show an army representative leaning over to press a voting button for a missing lawmaker.
Journalists were negotiating with officials on Thursday to restore their access. In a minor victory, they were told they could occupy a row of far-away seats. But that would be sufficient only for text reporters, not visual journalists.
Read more on:  myanmar
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 18:18:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 5 Republicans tied atop 2016 presidential race</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/5-Republicans-tied-atop-2016-presidential-race-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Five White House hopefuls are tied atop the Republican nomination race, a national poll shows, making it anyone's guess who will battle likely Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton in 2016.</Description>
        <MainBody>5 Republicans tied atop 2016 presidential race
2015-05-28 17:18
Jeb Bush. (Pablo Martinez Monsivais, AP)
TV personality Huckabee running for US president
Washington - Five White House hopefuls are tied atop the Republican nomination race, a national poll released Thursday showed, making it anyone's guess who will battle likely Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton in 2016.
The group, which includes former Florida governor Jeb Bush, who has yet to declare his candidacy, and Senator Marco Rubio, was clustered at 10% support each, with none beating Clinton in head-to-head matchups.
Also bunched at the top, according to the Quinnipiac University poll, are three arch-conservatives: Wisconsin Governor Scott Walker; former Arkansas governor, onetime preacher and Fox television show host Mike Huckabee; and retired neurosurgeon Ben Carson, the only likely African-American in the crowded Republican field.
Libertarian-leaning Senator Rand Paul, in the spotlight recently for his opposition to the US government's controversial surveillance of millions of Americans, earned 7% while rival Senator Ted Cruz came in at 6% and business magnate Donald Trump received 5%.
In a sign of how large numbers of Americans have yet to begin processing the early stages of the presidential race, 20% of respondents said they did not yet have a favoured candidate.
"Safe to say, the 2016 Republican presidential primary is anyone's race," said Quinnipiac's assistant director Tim Malloy.
"With no front-runner and identical numbers for the top five contenders, it's a horserace which can only be described as a scrambled field, at least so far."
Highest executive office
With the GOP nomination contest wide open, the Democratic side was all about Clinton.
Clinton, aiming to become the nation's first-ever female president, earned 57% support, a three-point drop compared to an April 24 Quinnipiac poll, but still well ahead of socialist-leaning US Senator Bernie Sanders, with 15%.
Vice President Joe Biden, who has flirted with a run but has yet to take many of the steps seen as prerequisites to a campaign launch, was third at 9%.
Martin O'Malley, a recent two-term Maryland governor who is expected to launch his presidential bid Saturday, barely registered with 1% support.
In hypothetical matchups with her Republican rivals, only Paul and Rubio posed threats. Clinton came out on top 46% to 42% against Paul, and 45-41 versus Rubio.
Clinton cruised against the other Republicans, including a 47-37 advantage over Bush, the son and brother of two former presidents.
But on qualities seen as important for the highest executive office, it was a mixed bag for Clinton.
Voters by 53 to 39% said Clinton is not honest and trustworthy, but they responded 60-37% that she has strong leadership qualities.
They are split, 48-47, over whether Clinton cares about their needs and problems.
"Can you get low marks on honesty and still be a strong leader? Sure you can," Malloy said.
"Hillary Clinton crushes her democratic rivals and keeps the GOP hoard at arm's length."
The May 19-26 poll surveyed 1,711 registered voters nationwide, and it has a margin of error of plus or minus 2.4 percentage points.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:01:48 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Tikrit mass graves: More boddies found from the Speicher massacre</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Tikrit-mass-graves-More-boddies-found-from-the-Speicher-massacre-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Iraq has exhumed the remains of 470 people believed to have been executed by jihadists near Tikrit last year in what is known as the Speicher massacre, the health minister says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iraq forces uncover mass graves left by ISIS in Tikrit
Baghdad  Iraq has exhumed the remains of 470 people believed to have been executed by jihadists near Tikrit last year in what is known as the Speicher massacre, the health minister said on Thursday.
"We have exhumed the bodies of 470 Speicher martyrs from burial sites in Tikrit," Adila Hammoud said at a press conference in Baghdad, referring to the nearby military base that the massacre was named after.
In June 2014, armed men belonging or allied to ISIS abducted hundreds of young, mostly Shi'ite recruits from Speicher base, just outside the city of Tikrit.
They were then lined up in several locations and executed one by one, as shown in pictures and footage that has emerged since.
Some were pushed into the Tigris river, others hastily buried in locations that were discovered when government and allied forces retook Tikrit from the jihadists about two months ago.
The highest estimate for the number of people killed in one of the worst atrocities ever committed by ISIS stands at 1 700.
"These bodies come from four burial sites. One of them was bigger than the others and contained 400," said Ziad Ali Abbas, the chief doctor at Baghdad's main morgue.
He said forensic examination of the exhumed remains was conducted with foreign assistance, including from the International Committee of the Red Cross.
Hundreds of families whose sons, fathers and brothers went missing at the time of the ISIS-led offensive in Iraq have been waiting for confirmation that their loved ones were among the Speicher victims.
Officials at Thursday's press conference said the first list of names would be released next week.
Read more on:  iraq
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:01:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UK says EU must amend its treaties to help keep it in bloc</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UK-says-EU-must-amend-its-treaties-to-help-keep-it-in-bloc-20150528</Link>
        <Description>UK needs the EU to agree to amend its founding treaties as part of its renegotiation drive, British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond, adding London has to get a deal substantive deal to persuade voters to stay in the bloc.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK says EU must amend its treaties to help keep it in bloc
2015-05-28 15:01
Shutterstock
France says Britain EU referendum 'very risky'
London - Britain needs the European Union to agree to amend its founding treaties as part of its renegotiation drive, British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond said on Thursday, saying London had to get a substantive deal to persuade voters to stay in the bloc.
"If our partners do not agree with us, do not work with us to deliver that package then we rule nothing out," Hammond told BBC radio.
"The advice we're getting is that we will need Treaty change," he said.
Hammond spoke as Prime Minister David Cameron prepared to embark on a two-day tour of European capitals to try to charm other EU leaders into backing his reform plan.
He has pledged to reshape Britain's EU ties before giving voters an in-out EU membership referendum by the end of 2017.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:01:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Australia's search for MH370 under scrutiny</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Australias-search-for-MH370-under-scrutiny-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Nearly a year after embarking on a multi-million dollar quest to solve one of aviation's greatest unsolved mysteries, authorities and search teams are being criticised over their approach to finding Flight MH370 in the remote southern Indian Ocean.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australia's search for MH370 under scrutiny
2015-05-28 15:01
A shadow of a Royal New Zealand Air Force P-3 Orion aircraft is seen on low cloud cover while it searches for missing Malaysia Airlines Flight MH370 in the southern Indian Ocean. (File, AP)
No known link between found towelette and MH370
Sydney - Nearly a year after embarking on a multi-million dollar quest to solve one of aviation's greatest unsolved mysteries, authorities and search teams are being criticised over their approach to finding Flight MH370 in the remote southern Indian Ocean.
The Australian-led search, already the most expensive in aviation history, has found no trace of the Malaysia Airlines jet or its 239 passengers and crew, prompting calls for a rethink into the way the mission is conducted.
Experts involved in past deep water searches say the search to find MH370 could easily miss the plane as Dutch company Fugro NV, the firm at the forefront of the mission, is using inappropriate technology for some terrain and inexperienced personnel for the highly specialised task of hunting man-made objects.
Heightening concerns, Australian authorities said on Wednesday that another search vessel, the Go Phoenix, which is using the world's best deep sea search equipment and crew provided by US firm Phoenix International Holdings, would pull out within weeks. No reason was given for withdrawing the vessel from the quest.
"Fugro is a big company but they don't have any experience in this kind of search and it's really a very specialised job," said Paul-Henry Nargeolet, a former French naval officer who was hired by France's air accident investigation agency BEA to co-ordinate the search and recovery of Air France Flight AF447 in 2009.
"This is a big job," Nargeolet told Reuters. "I'm not an Australian taxpayer, but if I was, I would be very mad to see money being spent like that."
Fugro, which was contracted by the Australian government to operate three ships pulling sonar across the vast 60 000km search zone, has rejected claims it is using the wrong equipment, saying its gear is rigorously tested.
Still, Nargeolet's concerns are echoed by others in the tightly held deepsea search and rescue industry, who are worried that unless the search ships pass right over any wreckage the sonar scanning either side of the vessels won't pick it up.
Experts also question the lack of data released by the Australian Transport Safety Bureau (ATSB) on the activities of the Fugro ships.
Three of the bidders rejected for the MH370 contract, US firm Williamson &amp; Associates, France's ixBlue SAS and Mauritius-based Deep Ocean Search, have taken the unusual step of detailing their concerns, months down the track, directly to Australian authorities in correspondence viewed by Reuters.
Several other experts are also critical, including some who requested anonymity, citing the close knit nature of the industry which has just a few companies and militaries capable of conducting deepwater searches.
"I have serious concerns that the MH370 search operation may not be able to convincingly demonstrate that 100 percent seafloor coverage is being achieved," Mike Williamson, founder and president of Williamson &amp; Associates told Reuters.
Diving into the unknown
Australia took over the search for the missing plane from Malaysia in late March last year, three weeks after MH370 disappeared off the radar during a flight from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing.
The search area was determined by satellite data that revealed the plane turned back sharply over the Malaysian Peninsula and flew undetected for another six hours before crashing into the inhospitable southern Indian Ocean.
The unchartered waters, buffeted by the Roaring Forties winds, stretch as deep as 6km, hiding old volcanoes and cliffs in their depths. Australia, Malaysia and China earlier this month agreed to double the search area to 120 000 sq km.
Whether Phoenix International, which has US navy contracts and found the recorders of AF447, will be part of that extended search area is unclear after the ATSB said that Go Phoenix, owned by Australian firm Go Marine, will cease operating on June 19.
Phoenix International, which was contracted separately by the Malaysian government, did not immediately return calls about its position. The Malaysian government also did not reply to requests for comment.
Two of the Fugro ships traverse up and down 2.4 km-wide strips of the sea floor, pulling via a cable a "towfish" that contains sonar equipment, in a technique often called "mowing the lawn".
The towfish coasts around 100m above the sea floor, sending out sound waves diagonally across a swath, or broad strip, to produce a flattened image of the seabed.
The Fugro ships are using sonar provided by EdgeTech, the same US company whose sonar was used successfully to find Air France AF447 after it crashed in the Atlantic Ocean.
However, experts say while the type of sonar equipment being used by Fugro gives good results in flat surfaces, it is less well-suited to rugged underwater terrain, a world of confusing shadows.
The ATSB has routinely released detailed data from Go Phoenix, but has not done so for the Fugro ships. Experts have cobbled together an analysis from glimpses of the sonar use and data in videos and images posted to the ATSB website.
From that, they've gauged the EdgeTech sonars are operating at swathes beyond their optimum capabilities, resulting in poor quality images and leaving side gaps in coverage.
"It makes no sense to be using fine scale tools to cover a massive area; it is like mowing an entire wheat field with a household lawnmower," said Rob McCallum, a vice-president at Williamson &amp; Associates.
Fugro deputy managing director Paul Kennedy said the sonar is running within its capabilities, noting the system identified five "debris-like" objects in 700-metre deep water at a test range off the West Australian coast.
"The test range gives us full confidence the sonars will see the debris field when we cross it," he said.
Wild weather
Fugro is known for its expertise in high-quality low-resolution mapping of sea floors but has far less experience than some of the rejected bidders in deepwater aircraft searches. It has been involved in 17 search and recovery efforts for aircraft or ships over 15 years, compared with some of the bidders who search for 4-5 aircraft every year.
Kennedy pointed to the find earlier this month of a previously uncharted shipwreck as evidence Fugro was capable of finding the plane.
Concerning experts further is the fact that the third Fugro vessel, which was being used to scan the gaps between the other two ships with an autonomous underwater vehicle (AUV), was this month taken out of action because of encroaching wild winter weather.
That leaves the daily search without an AUV, a much more nimble piece of equipment that was vital in successful search for AF447.
"We are continuously reviewing the search data as it comes in and we are satisfied that the coverage and detection standards we have specified are being met or exceeded," ATSB Chief Commissioner Martin Dolan said in an email.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:08:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UK Church apologises for past sexual abuse cases</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UK-Church-apologises-for-past-sexual-abuse-cases-20150528-2</Link>
        <Description>Britain's Methodist Church says there were almost 2 000 reports of physical and sexual abuse within the institution over more than half a century, and has apologised for failing to protect the victims.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK Church apologises for past sexual abuse cases
2015-05-28 14:08
US Catholic brother convicted of sex abuse in Australia
London - Britain's Methodist Church says there were almost 2 000 reports of physical and sexual abuse within the institution over more than half a century, and has apologised for failing to protect the victims.
Martyn Atkins, general secretary of the Methodist Conference, made an "unreserved apology" on Thursday. He said the abuse "inflicted by some Methodists on children, young people and adults is and will remain a deep source of grief and shame to the church."
The report, published after three years of research, found 1 885 cases of sexual, physical, emotional and domestic abuse going back to 1950. In 26% of the cases, church ministers or lay employees were identified as the alleged perpetrators.
There are about 200 000 Methodist Church members in Britain, where Anglicanism is the major Protestant denomination.
Read more on:  uk | child abuse
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:07:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France wants Europe to do more to fight ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/France-wants-Europe-to-do-more-to-fight-ISIS-20150528</Link>
        <Description>France’s foreign minister wants European countries to do more to fight the ISIS group, and is seeking support from Russia in international talks about defeating the group.</Description>
        <MainBody>France wants Europe to do more to fight ISIS
2015-05-28 14:07
(File, AFP)
France: Assad talks would be scandalous gift to ISIS
Paris - France's foreign minister wants European countries to do more to fight the Islamic State group, and is seeking support from Russia in international talks about defeating the group.
France, which joined US-led airstrikes against Islamic State extremists in Iraq, is hosting a conference on Tuesday on the international efforts against ISIS.
Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said on France-Inter radio on Thursday that European countries "aren't doing many things" against the group, even as hundreds of European extremists have joined ISIS fighters.
He also said France is including Russia in the anti-ISIS discussions.
Fabius criticised the Iraqi government for "ostracising" Sunni communities who could help fight ISIS. Doubts have grown recently about whether the Shiite-dominated Iraqi government can overcome the sectarian divisions.
Read more on:  isis | eu | france
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 15:07:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Man arrested for massive LA blaze</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Man-arrested-for-massive-LA-blaze-20150528</Link>
        <Description>A man has been arrested on suspicion of starting a massive inferno that destroyed an unfinished apartment building and damaged adjacent office towers in downtown Los Angeles, authorities say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man arrested for massive LA blaze
2015-05-28 14:07
Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti, second from left, surrounded by city authorities, comments on the arrest by the Los Angeles Police Department's anti-terrorism division of a suspect on suspicion of arson, during a news conference in downtown Los Ange
US charges suspect over Chinese consulate attack
Los Angeles - A man has been arrested on suspicion of starting a massive inferno that destroyed an unfinished apartment building and damaged adjacent office towers in downtown Los Angeles, authorities said.
Dawud Abdulwali, aged 56, of Los Angeles, whose name may be an alias, was arrested on Tuesday on a traffic warrant and only later was booked on suspicion of aggravated arson and arson of a structure, fire officials said.
He was being held on more than $1m bail and was expected to be charged on Thursday.
Mayor Eric Garcetti said the fire caused $20m to $30m in damage to the building site and another $50m to $60m to a city-owned building nearby.
Abdulwali was renting a room in South Los Angeles last year, his landlord, Poleth Chavez, told the Los Angeles Times. In December, around the time of the fire, he paid two months' rent up front and left, saying he was heading to San Francisco.
The December 8 fire gutted the 121 000 square meters Da Vinci complex that was in the wood-framing stage, sending up flames that could be seen from miles away.
The fire's heat cracked or shattered hundreds of windows in neighboring buildings, ignited small fires in one, and damaged an adjacent freeway.
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:03:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Hospitals overwhelmed as India heatwave deaths continue</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Hospitals-overwhelmed-as-India-heatwave-deaths-continue-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Hospitals in India are struggling to cope with an influx of victims of a blistering heatwave that has claimed nearly 1 500 lives in just over a week.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hospitals overwhelmed as India heatwave deaths continue
2015-05-28 13:03
A mirage shimmers over Raphath leading to India Gate in New Delhi. (Chandan Khanna, AFP)
Soaring temperatures grip India
New Delhi - Hospitals in India were struggling on Thursday to cope with an influx of victims of a blistering heatwave that has claimed nearly 1 500 lives in just over a week.
Hundreds of people, mainly from the poorest sections of society die at the height of summer every year in India, but this year's figures are unusually high.
In southern Andhra Pradesh, by far the worst-hit state 1 020 people have died since May 18, more than double the number of heat-related deaths for the whole of last year.
In neighbouring Telangana, where temperatures hit 48 C over the weekend, 340 people have died from the heat recently compared to 31 in the whole of last year.
"Heatwave conditions in 2015 so far have been of a shorter duration, yet with a higher death toll," said Arjuna Srinidhi, programme manager for climate change at the Centre for Science and Environment (CSE) research group.
"This could be due to the sudden change in temperatures after a prolonged wet February and March that had kept the temperatures cool."
Hospitals in New Delhi, where top temperatures have soared to 45C, were struggling to cope with the fall-out.
"Hospitals are overflowing with heatstroke victims," said Ajay Lekhi, president of the Delhi Medical Association.
"Patients are complaining of severe headache and dizziness. They are also showing symptoms of delirium," he added, describing a common symptom of severe dehydration.
Queues outside hospitals
The surge in demand for electricity from air conditioners led to power cuts in parts of Delhi, exacerbating the misery for residents of the capital.
Large queues formed outside the All India Institute of Medical Sciences, one of Delhi's largest government-run hospitals, where women clutched plastic water bottles and packets of mango juice.
Others tried to console crying babies, their heads wrapped in handkerchiefs against the blistering sun.
"Last night there was no electricity for nearly five hours," 31-year-old housewife Seema Sharma told AFP outside the hospital as she waited in line for her four-year-old son to be seen.
"You can imagine what we must have gone through. He just couldn't sleep and kept on crying. Now he has fever as well," she said.
Unconfirmed reports said two people had died in Delhi, where tens of thousands sleep on the streets with little protection from the heat.
State authorities have ordered that air coolers be installed in shelters for homeless people, which are often windowless tin shacks.
Most are equipped only with small fans, meaning temperatures inside the shelters are often considerably higher than outdoors.
"When the temperature soars it becomes difficult to sleep inside the tin cabin," 54-year-old Delhi construction worker told the Hindustan Times daily.
"Sleeping on the road is a much better option."
Forecasters said there was little hope of any immediate respite from the soaring temperatures in northern India, which have been aggravated by hot, dry winds.
"We think that these heatwave conditions will take another four to five days to subside," said Brahma Prakash Yadav, director of the Indian Meteorological Department.
The Press Trust of India news agency reported 43 deaths from the heatwave in the eastern state of Orissa.
Another 13 succumbed to the heat in neighbouring West Bengal, where unions urged taxi drivers to stay off the roads during the day.
Two people died in western Maharashtra state, where authorities said they did not expect conditions to improve until the arrival of monsoon rains in June.
The monsoon is forecast to hit the southern state of Kerala towards the end of this month before sweeping across the country, but it will be weeks before the rains reach the arid plains.
Read more on:  india | natural disasters
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:03:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Syria's al-Qaeda chief says no plans to attack West</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Syrias-al-Qaeda-chief-says-no-plans-to-attack-West-20150528</Link>
        <Description>The leader of al-Qaeda’s branch in Syria says they have no plans to attack the West and denies that the so-called Khorasan group exists.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syria's al-Qaeda chief says no plans to attack West
2015-05-28 13:03
File: AFP
In the face of ISIS successes, al-Qaeda adapts
Beirut - The leader of al-Qaeda's branch in Syria says they have no plans to attack the West and denies that the so-called Khorasan group exists.
The Syrian known as Abu Muhammed al-Golani, who heads the Nusra Front, says the aim of his group is to march to the capital Damascus and bring down President Bashar Assad's government.
He said in an interview with the Al-Jazeera TV aired on Wednesday night that "there is nothing called Khorasan group. We heard this from the Americans only".
Washington says the Khorasan group is a special cell within Nusra focused on plotting attacks against Western interests.
Al-Golani said that the directions they have received from al-Qaeda's leadership are "not to use Syria for attacks against the West and Europe".
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:03:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Malaysia believes 139 bodies in migrant graves - minister</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Malaysia-believes-139-bodies-in-migrant-graves-minister-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Malaysia says it believes 139 people are buried in graves at remote detention camps used by people-smugglers on the Thai border which were discovered on the weekend.</Description>
        <MainBody>Malaysia believes 139 bodies in migrant graves - minister
2015-05-28 13:03
Malaysian minister to meet Indonesian, Thai counterparts on migrants
Wang Kelian - Malaysia said on Thursday it believes 139 people are buried in graves at remote detention camps used by people-smugglers on the Thai border which were discovered on the weekend.
"Based on the size of the graves, and after the area was cleared... we have a clearer indication - single grave, single person," Deputy Home Minister Wan Junaidi Tuanku Jaafar told reporters.
When asked by AFP if he believed that there are 139 bodies since Malaysia has previously said it had discovered 139 grave sites, Wan Junaidi said: "Yes".
Read more on:  malaysia | migrants
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:02:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Bangladesh to set up courts to try human traffickers</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Bangladesh-to-set-up-courts-to-try-human-traffickers-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Bangladesh is moving to set up seven special courts across the country to try people smugglers charged with trafficking desperate migrants to Southeast Asia on rickety boats, a minister says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bangladesh to set up courts to try human traffickers
2015-05-28 12:02
Malaysia finds graves of suspected trafficking victims
Dhaka - Bangladesh is moving to set up seven special courts across the country to try people smugglers charged with trafficking desperate migrants to Southeast Asia on rickety boats, a minister said on Thursday.
Law and justice minister Anisul Huq said a court would be established in each of the country's provinces following a recent spike in trafficking of Bangladeshis and Rohingya from neighbouring Myanmar.
"There will be seven tribunals to try traffickers," Huq told AFP by phone, without giving a timeline for them to start operating.
The move comes after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Sunday slammed the country's economic migrants, calling them "mentally sick" for fleeing in search of jobs, and accusing them of hurting the country's image.
Hasina called on authorities to halt the flow of migrants and take action against human traffickers.
An official also said Wednesday that Bangladesh planned to relocate thousands of Rohingya refugees, who are sheltering in two camps in the southeastern district of Cox's Bazar, to Hatiya island in the Bay of Bengal.
Bangladesh's police and border forces have launched a crackdown on the smugglers in recent weeks after the discovery of mass graves of migrants in Thailand.
Authorities have shot dead at least five suspected traffickers and arrested more than 100 others.
Hundreds of trafficking cases have also been piling up in the lower courts since Bangladesh enacted an anti-human trafficking law in 2012 which stipulates the death penalty for the worst offenders.
Southeast Asia is currently battling an exodus of boat people fleeing persecution and poverty.
A Thai crackdown on trafficking networks earlier this month left thousands of desperate people stranded at sea at the mercy of the smugglers.
More than 3 500 migrants have swum to shore or been rescued off the coasts of Malaysia, Indonesia, Thailand and Bangladesh since the crisis erupted.
Read more on:  bangladesh
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:01:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UN body says fewer are suffering from hunger in Asia-Pacific</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UN-body-says-fewer-are-suffering-from-hunger-in-Asia-Pacific-20150528</Link>
        <Description>The UN's food body says the proportion of people suffering from hunger in the Asia-Pacific region has fallen by half in the last 25 years.</Description>
        <MainBody>UN body says fewer are suffering from hunger in Asia-Pacific
2015-05-28 12:01
Africa takes the lead in fighting hunger and poverty
Bangkok - The UN's food body says the proportion of people suffering from hunger in the Asia-Pacific region has fallen by half in the last 25 years.
The Food and Agriculture Organisation said that using 1990 as a base year, when about 24% of the population in the region was undernourished, the percentage has been cut to 12%, enabling the region to meet the UN's Millennium Development Goals to halve undernourishment by 2015.
Some of biggest drops came in China, where it fell by 60.9%, and Thailand, where it dropped by 78.7%.
However, some parts of the region, such as South Asia, failed to reach the goal, and in total there are still 490 million people in Asia and the Pacific who suffer from chronic hunger.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 13:01:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 2 Saudi border guards die in Yemen shelling</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/2-Saudi-border-guards-die-in-Yemen-shelling-20150528</Link>
        <Description>Two Saudi border guards have been killed and five others wounded by shellfire on the frontier with Yemen, a report says.</Description>
        <MainBody>2 Saudi border guards die in Yemen shelling
2015-05-28 12:01
File: AP
Yemen-bound aid ship docks in Djibouti
Riyadh - Two Saudi border guards have been killed and five others wounded by shellfire on the frontier with Yemen, official media reported.
The deaths occurred when "military missiles from Yemen" struck their position at Zahran South in the Asir border region on Wednesday, Riyadh's interior ministry said in a statement carried by the official Saudi Press Agency.
The two dead guards bring to at least 30 the number of people, military and civilian, killed in the Saudi border area since a Riyadh-led coalition began air strikes against Iran-backed Shiite Huthi rebels in Yemen in late March.
Coalition warplanes have been bombing Huthis and their allies in support of pro-government forces in Yemen.
The air campaign led to deadly skirmishes between the rebels and Saudi forces along the border, but many of the recent Saudi casualties have been civilians killed by cross-border barrages.
Inside Yemen, weeks of fighting between pro- and anti-government forces have killed almost 2 000 people and displaced more than half a million, according to the United Nations.
Read more on:  saudi arabia | yemen
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:08:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | China detains artist who posted humorous photo of president</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/China-detains-artist-who-posted-humorous-photo-of-president-20150528-2</Link>
        <Description>The wife of a Chinese artist says authorities have detained him after he posted a humorous portrait of President Xi Jinping online.</Description>
        <MainBody>China detains artist who posted humorous photo of president
2015-05-28 11:08
(Dai Jianyong, Instagram)
China takes officials to prison as warning
Beijing - The wife of a Chinese artist says authorities have detained him after he posted a humorous portrait of President Xi Jinping online.
Judy Zhu said on Thursday that police are accusing artist Dai Jianyong of creating a disturbance after detaining him on Tuesday near their Shanghai home. Police there didn't answer phones on Thursday.
Dai is known for posting eclectic photos on social media , including some showing himself and others scrunching up their lips and eyes. Dai posted images of Xi with the same expression while wearing a moustache. He has also printed stickers with the Xi portrait.
Chinese authorities have tightened their grip on political dissent and have cracked down on Chinese artists who supported pro-democracy protesters in Hong Kong last year. Dai faces up to five years in prison.
View the some of the offending posts below
A photo posted by ??? (@coca96) on
May 24, 2015 at 7:37am PDT
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
