<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="NEWS">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gun terror erupts at gay pride festival</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/north-america/man-shot-near-san-francisco-gay-pride-event/story-fnh81jut-1227419266597?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>GUNFIRE has erupted at a gay pride event in San Francisco, wounding a bystander and sending dozens of marchers running for cover.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man shot near San Francisco gay pride event
by:
Play video
The shooting at San Francisco's gay pride festival which left one man injured was unrelated to the pride event, said Captain Caltagirone of the San Francisco Police Department whilst speaking to press shortly after the incident, Saturday. The shooting is believed to have taken place after several men got into an argument at a venue near to the gay pride event. As the situation intensified one man is thought to have pulled a gun and fired several shots, hitting a street vendor at the gay pride festival in the arm. At least two people have reportedly been arrested in connection with the shooting and the victim, a 64-year-old white man, was treated in hospital for his injuries.
Rightster
28 Jun 2015
News/World
Gun terror ... a police officer has his gun drawn after shots were fired at a gay pride event in San Francisco on June 27. Picture: Sean-Franc Strang via AP Source: AP
A 64-YEAR-OLD bystander has been shot at a gay pride event in San Francisco after an argument between several young men turned violent.
The incident was believed to have occurred when several groups of men unrelated to the pride event got in a verbal argument near or inside the venue, the San Francisco Police Department said in a statement.
The pride spectator who was shot was believed to be unrelated to the dispute, SFPD officer Carlos Manfredi told AFP.
Video posted by Instagram user "bonni300" purports to show shooting near San Francisco Pride event pic.twitter.com/mebROav2P9
 Matthew Keys (@MatthewKeysLive) June 28, 2015
Police said the incident escalated when one of the subjects pulled out a gun and fired several shots. One shot struck a pride spectator in the arm.
Several suspects have been detained, the statement added.
Police were alerted to the shooting, which occurred in the United Nations Plaza area, just after 6pm.
Shots fired at San Francisco Pride
(Frame content direct link: https://www.youtube.com/embed/CuFo4A0m5iY .)
The victim was transported to San Francisco General Hospital where he is in stable condition, police said.
A concert that was part of the weekend-long gay pride celebration across the city was ending around the time of the shooting.
Moving moment ... Lauren Robinson (left) and her girlfriend Kayla Weiss celebrate during a gay pride event in Dolores Park, San Francisco, on June 27. Picture: Elijah Nouvelage/Getty Images/AFP Source: AFP
Pride event ... gay rights supporters wave a rainbow pride flag and an American flag during a gay pride celebration in San Francisco on June 27. Picture: Elijah Nouvelage/Getty Images/AFP Source: AFP
The citys gang task force, crime scene unit and night investigations unit are investigating the incident.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Search for mum ends in tragedy</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/attack-on-hotels-in-tunisia-kills-dozens/story-fndir2ev-1227417128300?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>THE distraught son who took to Twitter to find his mother after she was caught up in the Tunisia terror attack has received the worst news. WARNING: Graphic content.</Description>
        <MainBody>Arrested Darwin teen had beheading hit list
THE distraught son  who took to Twitter to find his mother and her partner  after they were caught up in the Tunisia terror attack says his mum has tragically died.
Conor Fulford, from Tamworth in Englands Staffordshire, had pleaded for help to find his mother Sue Davy after seeing images of her being taken from the scene of the massacre on a stretcher,
In a series of heartbreaking tweets, Conor Fulford revealed his 44-year-old  mother, who had been  staying at the Imperial Hotel in Sousse with her partner Scott Chalkley, 42, had lost her life.
Hi Everyone, Sorry to tell you we lost my mother Sue Davey tonight but i want to thank everybody that tried to help me &amp; my family ...
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
My mom was a strong women who didn't take no crap from nobody so when you lie down tonight wish my mom goodnight as I know i sure will xxxxx
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
Love you always Mom, I've got my teddy bear you got me tonight, Rest easy xxxx
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
Earlier, Mr Fulford  told The Mirror of his frustration in his desperate search for his beloved mum.
The Foreign Office said 20 flights have left today to return to Britain but they are not on the planes, he said.
Im devastated, nobody is helping me, Ive rang up hospitals, Ive rang around hotels and I dont even know what to do anymore.
Gone ... Sue Davy had been  staying at the Imperial Hotel in Sousse with her partner Scott Chalkley when tragedy struck. Source: Twitter
Meanwhile, more chilling images have emerged of the Islamic State gunman, who heartlessly laughed as he murdered at least 38 sunbathing tourists.
Aby Yahya al-Qayrawani  the jihadi name for 23-year-old Seifeddine Rezgui, was seen walking down the beach with his Kalashnikov, a weapon which had been concealed inside a beach umbrella, before he opened fire.
He was walking away from the attack with a grenade in his other hand.
WARNING: Graphic images below may upset readers
Rifle in hand ... gunman Seifeddine Rezgui on the beach. Picture: Sky News Source: Supplied
The killer, a Tunisian engineering student  who was later shot dead police  had disguised himself as a tourist at the time of the massacre.
Tourists described him as very, very calm during the attack.
Tunisias Prime Minister, Habib Essid, said Rezgui had never travelled abroad, and was not known by the police to hold extremist views.
A Facebook page believed to belong to him depicts him as a young man who liked rap music, Real Madrid and contained numerous postings in support of ISIL, The Telegraph UK reports.
Gunman on the loose ... his casual stroll on the beach. Picture: Sky News Source: Supplied
His final entry is New Year 2015, and read: May God take me out of this unjust world and perish its people and make them suffer. They just remember you when they die.
In one post he wrote: If jihad is a crime, he wrote, the world shall know that Im a criminal.
Earlier, it was revealed he laughed and joked as he fired his assault rifle, slaughtering innocent tourists while they sunbathed on the beach outside the two resorts.
Smiling assassin ... Seifeddine Rezgui in a photo released by ISIL. Picture: Supplied Source: Supplied
Witnesses recalled the sound of the lone gunmans laughter as he pulled out the weapon and  targeted tourists, specifically the British, but also German, Belgian, Irish and French people.
He was laughing and joking around, like a normal guy, said one witness.
He was choosing who to shoot. Some people, he was saying to them you go away. He was choosing tourists, British, French.
Video of the attack has also emerged, showing panicked witnesses running through the streets and along the beach as gunshots echo in the background
Caught on camera ... the gunman slowly walks. Picture: Supplied Source: Supplied
.
Tunisian builders threw bags of cement and bricks at him from the top of buildings as he fired his weapon in nearby streets. After the attack, the lone wolf was later seen walking with his weapon by his side.
The Islamic State terror group released a picture of him on their social media accounts with a statement said: Our brother, the soldier of the Caliphate, Abu Yahya al Qayrawani, reached his target the Imperial hotel despite the security measures.
Most of those killed were subjects of states that make up the crusader alliance fighting the state of the caliphate, the group said in a statement released on Twitter, referring to the group of countries that have been bombarding its positions in the Middle East.
Video reveals successive gunshots in Tunisia 2:14
At least 39 people, mostly foreign tourists, were killed in a gun attack at a resort in Sousse, Tunisia, on June 26.
News Corp Australia
News
Loved ones missing as tourists flee
Britain said that at least 15 of its citizens were killed in Fridays gun assault in the popular resort of Port el Kantaoui and that the number may well rise.
Olivia Leathley, from Manchester in northwest England, said she and her boyfriend Mike Jones heard grenades and gunfire and saw hundreds of people running and screaming from the beach.
Somebody shouted, theyre inside, run!. We just ran as far away from the bullets as we could. It was all happening so quickly, it was deafening, she told the BBC.
The couple found shelter in a small security lodge, and later discovered that the gunman was killed about 400 yards from where they were hiding.
Feared for her life ... Rebecca Smith recalled the attack. Picture: Sky News Source: Supplied
Rebecca Smith, 22, from Coventry said she and her boyfriend Ross Thompson, 21, came face-to-face with the gunman who threw hand grenades, possibly homemade bombs at them.
The corridor just exploded ... we got separated ... I didnt know if he was dead or alive, she told Sky News.
I was in the staff toilets with another woman and her son, we just locked ourselves in and hoped for the best.
It was just a bloodbath in the corridor.
Shocked ... a woman grieves as she lay flowers at the beach next to the Imperial Marhaba Hotel. Picture: Getty Source: Getty Images
I was peppered with grenade shrapnel. With one hit, I thought my jaw had come off, Smith also told the Mail Online.
Please keep retweeting the images, thank you  pic.twitter.com/A31oqgzyzM
 A$AP ROSSI (@rossinaylor) June 27, 2015
He was told her phone was handed in to police at the beach and that she was there during the attack.  He has seen a picture of a woman on a stretcher he believes is his mum.
The Foreign office said 20 flights have left today to return to Britain but they are not on the planes, he told The Mirror . Im devastated, nobody is helping me, Ive rang up hospitals, Ive rang around hotels and I dont even know what to do anymore.
Weve watched the news and my two sisters were sure they had seen her on a stretcher and it looked like she had been shot in the leg, he said.
I believe this is my mom on @SkyNews can everybody please RT as we have no contact since ! Please Help #FindSueDavey pic.twitter.com/ZFvz90A1CE
 Conor Fulford (@ConorFulford) June 27, 2015
Scared ... Tourists react in the Imperial hotel at the resort town of Sousse, a popular tourist destination. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Planeloads of shocked foreign tourists flew home from Tunisia after the beachside massacre prompted a major security clampdown.
The North African nation, which relies heavily on tourism, announced plans to deploy troops at vulnerable sites and shut dozens of mosques accused of inciting extremism.
Going home ... British tourists leave Tunisia at the Enfidha International airport. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Tunisias health ministry said it had identified the bodies of 17 people from Britain, Germany, Ireland, Belgium and Portugal, as it tried to establish the identities of victims mown down in their beachwear.
British police have sent forensic experts and detectives to Tunisia to help identify victims and gather evidence.
Searching for evidence ... a Tunisian forensic expert inspects the beach in front of the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Victims identified
Ireland has confirmed Lorna Carty died after she went to the beach by herself.
She had gone on holiday with her husband, who was recovering from heart surgery.
Lorna rushed her husband to hospital about a fortnight ago after he was getting pains in his heart... He had to get stents in, a family friend said. They went out to Tunisia to have a bit of a holiday after the operation ... Apparently [her husband] Declan stayed back in the room and she went to the beach.
There are also one German and one Belgian among the dead.
Dead ... Lorna Carty was one of the 38 killed in Sousse, Tunisia.  Picture:  Supplied Source: Supplied
Thousands of scared foreign holiday-makers are being flown from Tunisia.
Carly Lovett, 24, was named as the first victim of the massacre.
The British beauty blogger had just finished university and was travelling with her fiance, Liam Moore, who is believed to have survived the attack.
Eyewitnesses told how Mr Moore cradled her in his arms after she had been shot.
Just two days before  as she prepared to go on holiday  Miss Lovett had excitedly tweeted: Definitely leaving in like three hours and definitely am not finished packing.
Shot dead ... Beauty blogger Carly Lovett has been named as a victim of the Tunisian massacre.  Picture:  Supplied Source: Supplied
Mr Moore, who survived the attack, was due to fly back to the UK yesterday. The couple had got engaged three months ago.
Tony Callaghan, said he saw Mr Moore holding Miss Lovett in the lobby of the Imperial Hotel. She appeared to have been shot in the chest and stomach.
Mr Callaghan, from Norfolk, said: I heard a sound of someone talking five yards down the corridor so I walked down there and there was a young guy holding a woman. She was on her back and had been shot in the chest and the stomach.
Distraught ... tourists react at the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
He looked up at me and said, What can I do? Its my fiancee and we are getting married.  Mr Callaghan said he checked Miss Lovetts pulse, and realised that she had died.
He said: I just said to him, sorry Liam I cant find her pulse. I didnt know what else to say. She was just a young girl. They looked a lovely couple and very happy. Its just heart-breaking.
Others killed include Adrian Evans, a local authority worker, and his nephew, student Joel Richards.
The aftermath ... a man uses a phone to take pictures of flowers at the site of a shooting attack on the beach in front of the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
More terror  attacks in France and Kuwait
The carnage at the popular Mediterranean resort of Port el Kantaoui on Friday came the same day as a suicide bomber killed 27 people at a Shiite mosque in Kuwait and a suspected Islamist attacked a factory in France .
In Kuwait, Health Minister Ali al-Obaidi told Kuwait Television the number of dead had risen to 27 in addition to 227 wounded in the first ever suicide attack on Shiite mosques in the oil-rich emirate.
The toll in the attack, carried out in the Muslim holy fasting month of Ramadan, is one of the largest in Kuwaits history.
Injured ... Kuwaiti emergency personnel pull stretchers past security forces outside the Shiite Al-Imam al-Sadeq mosque after it was targeted by a suicide bombing during Friday prayers. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
The IS-affiliated group in Saudi Arabia, calling itself Najd Province, said militant Abu Suleiman al-Muwahhid carried out the attack on the mosque, which it claimed was spreading Shiite teachings among Sunni Muslims.
IS, a radical Sunni Muslim group, considers Shiites to be heretic.
Meanwhile, in France, a man was decapitated and at least two more injured at a gas product factory in France by a man carrying an Islamic State banner.
The attack took place at the headquarters of American company Air Products, in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Grenoble, in the southeast of France, just after 10am (6pm AEST).
Forensics ... Investigating police officers work outside the plant where the alleged terror attack took place. Picture: Laurent Cipriani/AP Source: AP
Yassin Salhi, a 35-year-old truck driver, is suspected of decapitating his boss, before entering the factory grounds in a utility truck, then crashing the vehicle into a hangar at the site, prompting an explosion.
The head of his boss, who ran a delivery service, was found pinned to the gates at the factory, while his body was found inside the factory.
Australia responds
Speaking out against the attacks, Australian Prime Minister Tony Abbott said he was committed to tackling the threat of global terrorism, and was making a strong contribution at home and working closely with our partners abroad.
Australia stands in solidarity with all those affected by these atrocities, he said in a statement.
These attacks are yet another reminder that the terrorist threat is real. They strengthen our resolve to combat the threat and the evil it represents.
Searching ... Tunisian police patrol the beach in front of the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel in Port el Kantaoui. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
He later told reporters that the attack illustrates yet again that as far as the Daesh death cult is concerned, its coming after us.
We may not always feel that we are at war with them, but they certainly think that they are at war with us.
Foreign Minister Julie Bishop said she would contact her counterparts in France, Tunisia and Kuwait to express Australias support, AAP reported.
Mr Abbott said Australians should remain vigilant.
Our security agencies are assessing the situation for any implications for us but there is no information to suggest a higher threat to Australia as a result of these latest atrocities, he said.
How it unfolded
Earlier, witnesses described scenes of panic after the shooting at the Riu Imperial Marhaba Hotel on the outskirts of Sousse, about 140km south of Tunis.
Holiday nightmare ... Tunisian lifeguards and medics transport a covered body in the resort town of Sousse. Picture: Bechir Taieb/AFP Source: AFP
He had a parasol in his hand, aid Rafik Chelli, the secretary of state of the Interior Ministry.
He went down to put it in the sand and then he took out his Kalashnikov and began shooting wildly.
The gunman then entered the pool area of the Imperial Marhaba hotel before moving into the building, killing people as he went.
Tourists described hearing what sounded like fireworks and then running for their lives when they realised it was gunfire. Video of the aftermath showed medics using beach chairs as stretchers to carry away people in swimsuits.
Tragedy ... tourists console each other following a shooting in the resort town, Sousse. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Pictures posted on social media appeared to show the body of a man face down in the sand with empty sun loungers behind him. Elizabeth OBrien, an Irish woman on holiday with her two sons in the resort, described how she grabbed her children and ran for their lives when they heard gunfire erupting from one of the hotels.
Carnage ... In this screen grab taken from video provided by TNN, a body is covered on a Tunisian beach, in Sousse, Tunisia. Picture: TNN via AP Source: AP
The gunman was finally shot dead by Tunisian security forces. There were earlier reports that another attacker fled the scene but later reports said there was only one gunman.
Tunisian Interior Ministry spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui said: A terrorist infiltrated the buildings from the back before opening fire on the residents of the hotel, including foreigners and Tunisians.
Tunisian President Beji Caid Essebsi called for a unified global strategy.
We note that Tunisia faces an international movement. It cannot respond alone to this. On the same day at the same time France has been the target of such an operation, and Kuwait too, Mr Essebsi said.
Casualties ... A Tunisian medic stands next to the body of a tourist at the Imperial hotel in the resort town of Sousse. Picture: AFP Source: Supplied
This proves the need for a global strategy, and that all democratic countries must now join forces. This is worse than terrible.
I hope this is the last time, because we are determined to take the most painful measures to deal with an even more painful scourge, he said.
Tunisia, the birthplace of the Arab Spring, has seen a surge in radical Islam since veteran president Zine El Abidine Ben Ali was ousted in the 2011 revolution.
He said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms, and later to gather in the lobby.
Beach town ... The terrorist attack happened in the popular holiday destination of Sousse in the north of Tunisia. Picture: Google Maps Source: Supplied
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Batteries blamed for MH370 mystery</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/batteries-offer-best-explanation-for-mh370-crash-investigator/story-fnizu68q-1227419131035?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>AN independent MH370 investigator has come up with a simple, yet plausible explanation for the aircraft&amp;#8217;s baffling disappearance.</Description>
        <MainBody>The disappearance of Flight MH370 stunned the world. In an era of smart-phones and sat-nav, how could a passenger jet vanish into thin air?
Oovvuu
11 Jun 2015
TV/Science TV/Technology TV/Current Affairs
Seeking answers. Indian sand artist Sudarsan Pattnaik creating a sculpture of the missing Malaysian airliner MH370 on Puri beach in eastern Odisha state. Pic: AFP PHOTO/J. K. Jagdev Source: Supplied
A SIMPLE new theory for MH370s disappearance points the finger directly at the 221kg of lithium ion batteries on board.
US pilot and aviation engineer Bruce Robertson has outlined the theory on his website , based on known facts about the Malaysia Airlines flight and what it was carrying.
He suggests the lithium ion batteries caught fire sending a cloud of deadly carbon monoxide into the cabin.
Pilot Zaharie Ahmad Shah succumbed to the fumes, but co-pilot Fariq Abdul Hamid survived long enough to turn the plane around and place it into a descent.
Innocent victim .... US Aviation engineer Bruce Robertson insists Captain Zaharie was not to blame for MH370s disappearance. Source: Supplied
It then flew on in autopilot mode before crashing into the Southern Indian Ocean.
There you have it  no conspiracies, no evil intent, no fuzzy pictures, just a simple industrial accident that took a while to play out due to automation trying to save the situation, said Mr Robertson.
The wounded bird did its best to survive but it was not to be.
Mr Robertson believes the Boeing 777 came down west of Exmouth in Western Australia, much further north of the site where searchers are currently working.
Needle in a haystack ... Searchers are looking too far south, claims aviation engineer Bruce Robertson. Pic: Twitter Source: Twitter
Too much time and money has been wasted on a fruitless search in an area much further southwest, due west of Perth, he said.
The theory is the latest in a string of explanations put forward by experts to explain how a sophisticated aircraft carrying 239 people could simply disappear in the 21st century.
Others include pilot sabotage, hijacking, rapid cabin decompression and alien abduction.
No fun ...  Search crews have endured horrendous conditions in search for MH370. Picture: ABIS Chris Beerens, RAN. Source: Supplied
The carriage of lithium-ion batteries has now been banned by a number of airlines in the wake of research finding they can quite easily overheat and start fires.
BATTERIES BANNED:  Airlines take action over potentially flammable cargo
But Mr Robertsons simple theory has failed to convince other experts an industrial accident was to blame for MH370s demise.
Former pilot and author Peter Lee, who has written his own analysis MH370 by Accident or Design said it was unlikely the aircraft disappeared without deliberate human intervention.
Hope lives on ...  A tribute wall at Kuala Lumpur International Airport. Pic: AFP PHOTO/ Manan Vatsyayana Source: Supplied
If mechanical, electrical or electronic problems were encountered that were sufficient to sever all communication between the aircraft and ground control, it is extremely unlikely that the aircraft would have been in a fit state to remain in the air for as long as we know that it did, said Mr Lee.
The Boeing 777 has proven to be one of the worlds most reliable and trouble-free aircraft, and in order for there to be a sensible explanation involving system failures, an enormous number of different and duplicated components would have to fail almost simultaneously.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 07:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shark attacks boy’s leg, butt, hands</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/teen-attacked-by-shark-in-north-carolina-in-sixth-attack-in-two-weeks/story-fnizu68q-1227418711464?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A TEENAGE boy is in critical condition after another shark attack off the North Carolina coast, the sixth one to occur in two weeks in the area.</Description>
        <MainBody>A PLANE travelling from New York to Kuwait has declared a state of emergency and headed back to Londons Heathrow Airport.
Travel Updates
Teen attacked by shark in North Carolina in sixth attack in two weeks
by:
A US teen is in critical condition after a shark attack off the North Carolina coast, the sixth one in about two weeks. Courtesy FOX8
News Corp Australia
28 Jun 2015
News
Shark attack ... a teenage boy has been bitten by a shark in North Carolina. Source: Supplied
A TEENAGE boy is in critical condition after another shark attack off the North Carolina coast, the sixth one to occur in the area in two weeks.
The 17-year-old boy was attacked at about 4pm on a beach at the Cape Hatteras KOA campground in Rodanthe on Saturday, according to authorities.
His name has not been released but he was swimming with several others when the attack occurred.
According to a post on the National Park Service Facebook page, he reportedly sustained injuries to his right calf, buttocks and both hands.
He was treated at the scene before being flown to Sentara Norfolk General Hospital for treatment, MyFox8.com reports.
Visitor Injured from Shark EncounterWhile Swimming near Waves, NC Waves, NC  Around 4:00 p.m. on Saturday, June 27,...
Posted by Cape Hatteras National Seashore on Saturday, June 27, 2015
It is understood the boy may still be in a critical condition.
The latest attack is one of several that have occurred on the North Carolina coast in recent weeks.
This is the second incident in two days where a person was bitten by a shark in Dare County. On Friday, a 47-year-old man was bitten by a shark in Avon, North Carolina. His injuries were non-life threatening.
On Wednesday, an 8-year-old boy in Surf City suffered a minor shark bite.
On June 14, Kiersten Yow , 12, and Hunter Treschl, 16, both lost their arms in shark attacks at Oak Island.
Survivor ... Hunter Treschl, of Colorado Springs. Picture: AP Source: AP
Emergency responders ... assist Kiersten Yow. Picture: AP Source: AP
Yow lost her left arm below the elbow and suffered injuries to her left leg.
A 13-year-old girl was also bitten while boogie boarding off Ocean Isle Beach on June 11.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 05:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Khaled Sharrouf is still alive</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/terrorist-khaled-sharrouf-still-alive-after-drone-attack-that-killed-mohamed-elomar/story-fndir2ev-1227418515605?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>AUSTRALIAN terrorist Khaled Sharrouf is still alive after surviving the attack that killed Mohamed Elomar.</Description>
        <MainBody>Aust terrorist Khaled Sharrouf has reportedly survived the drone attack in Syria that killed Mohamed Elomar.
Sky News
28 Jun 2015
News
Khaled Sharrouf is still alive after surviving the drone attack that killed Mohamed Elomar. Source: Twitter
NOTORIOUS Australian terrorist Khaled Sharrouf is still alive after surviving the drone attack that killed Mohamed Elomar.
The Herald-Sun reports the US military in Al-Rawwah, Syria, have captured highly classified images that confirm the death of Sydney terrorist Elomar, 30, in the missile strike.
But authorities say none of the images prove Sharrouf was killed in the attack.
Hes got nine lives, a source who has seen the images told The Herald-Sun .
It was a split-second thing.
Three images reportedly show the moment Elomar, a former Sydney boxer, was killed by a predator drone in the attack last week.
Mohamed Elomar was killed in a missile attack last week in Syria. Source: News Corp Australia
In one image, he can be seen standing next to an SUV travelling with a tactical unit of foreign fighters.
The second shows an explosion after the group was hit by a missile. And the third captures the remaining debris after the explosion.
While authorities confirm Elomar is clearly identified in the images, they say there is no information to suggest Sharrouf was also killed.
Its suggested that while Sharrouf may have been with Elomar leading up to the attack, he was not in the car when the missile struck.
Prime Minister Tony Abbott has warned Elomar, who made international headlines after posing with severed heads, should not be treated as a martyr.
Mohamed Elomar was a terrorist. He was no hero in life and is no martyr in death, he said.
He served no god and advanced no religion.
He should not be mourned.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 04:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greeks drain ATMs in panic</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/greece-bailout-fears-spark-atm-panic-as-parts-of-country-run-out-of-money/story-fndir2ev-1227418477097?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>AS Greece hurtled closer to the catastrophic possibility of a euro exit, ATM queues are growing amid fears mount that banks will not open on Monday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece bailout fears spark ATM panic, as parts of country run out of money
by:
The Greek finance minister says the country is still fighting to reach a bailout deal with its EU creditors.
Sky News
28 Jun 2015
News
AS Greece hurtled closer to the catastrophic possibility of a euro exit, ATM queues are growing amid fears that banks will not open on Monday, and the government could impose capital controls to stop more deposits fleeing the country.
The most dramatic day in the five-month crisis saw long lines of people queuing at cash machines in Greece in fear of capital controls as Athens looked certain to default on a huge IMF payment on Tuesday.
Greeks queue in front of the National Bank to use ATM to withdraw cash in a panic. Picture: Getty Source: Getty Images
The queues have been growing in Athens while ATMs in the Greek parliament ran dry. In Greeces second city, Thessaloniki, some banks have run out of money, AFP reports.
Demand at petrol stations was also said to have heightened but there were no fuel shortage problems, according to state news agency ANA.
The European Central Bank will now play a crucial role in ensuring Greeces banks have the cash to open at the beginning of next week, as with the end of the bailout program Greece leaves behind billions of euros in profits on its government bonds.
People queue at a national Bank of Greece ATM in central Athens. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Two top Tsipras aides met ECB head Mario Draghi in Brussels. The governing council of the ECB was also reported to be meeting on Sunday, and was closely monitoring developments, the bank said.
Greece hurtled closer to the catastrophic possibility of a euro exit after Europe responded to the governments call for a referendum by refusing to extend Athenss desperately needed bailout.
Germany said the eurozone would do everything to protect contagion through the single currency.
Leftist Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras announced the referendum on bailout proposals by Greeces creditors via a televised speech in the small hours of Saturday, saying he had rejected a debt deal because it involved further austerity measures that would cause humiliation to the Greek people.
Greeks queue in front of the National Bank to use ATM to withdraw cash. Picture: Getty Source: Getty Images
Angry eurozone finance ministers accused Greece of unilaterally breaking off talks and said they would not extend Greeces bailout past June 30, the same day a 1.5 billion euro payment to the International Monetary Fund falls due.
It was not us who walked away from the talks, it was the Greek government that walked away, a grim-faced Eurogroup president Jeroen Dijsselbloem said after tense talks in Brussels.
But he added: Our door is always open. The Greek parliament was to vote on whether to go ahead with the referendum at midnight, after an address by Tsipras.
The news comes as Germany and France swiftly insisted that Greece would remain inside the 19-country eurozone, with European capitals increasingly nervous that the once irreversible single currency is itself at risk.
Greece remains a member of the eurozone and Greece remains part of Europe, said Germanys powerful Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble.
People stand in a queue to use the ATMs of a bank in the northern Greek city of Thessaloniki. Picture: AP Source: AP
His French counterpart Michel Sapin said that Greeces destiny was in the euro.
But with fears that the crisis could spread, the ministers later met without Greece to discuss the consequences and to insist they would preserve the integrity and stability of the euro area Dijsselbloem said.
We will do everything to fight against any possible danger of contagion, added Schaeuble in an attempt to calm global markets before they reopen on Monday.
Frozen out of the talks, Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis left saying: Its a sad day for Europe but we will overcome it. But he added that the refusal to grant his request to extend the bailout will certainly damage the credibility for the Eurogroup as a democratic union and I am very much afraid the damage will be permanent.
Greeks queue in front of the National Bank to use ATM to withdraw cash as Parliament holds an emergency session for the government's proposed referendum. Picture: Getty Source: Getty Images
Greeces negotiations with its international creditors that have dragged on since January, when Tsiprass Syriza party first took power on a promise of ending austerity after two EU-IMF bailout programs since 2010, worth 240 billion euros.
Syriza has repeatedly refused to make cuts to pensions and changes to the VAT system demanded by Greeces bailout monitors: the European Commission, European Central Bank and International Monetary Fund.
A week of intensive talks in Brussels ended with Greeces creditors on Friday offering Athens a five-month, 12-billion-euro ($13.4-billion) extension of its rescue program, on condition it committed to fresh reforms.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 03:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>CNN anchor’s ‘ISIS flag’ gaffe</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/cnn-on-air-gaffe-anchor-mistook-sex-toy-flag-for-isis-flag/story-e6frfmyi-1227418504649?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>A CNN anchor mistook a flag with sex toys on it for an ISIS flag from the terror group, in a live cross on the global news network.</Description>
        <MainBody>What are these?
Wrong flag ... CNN anchor mistakes a gay pride parade banner for the real ISIS flag. Source: Supplied
A CNN anchor mistook a flag with sex toys on it for an ISIS flag from the terror group, in a live cross on the global news network.
The report came in as breaking news on CNN after it was spotted at a parade in London.
Just in: ISIS flag spotted at gay pride parade, read a banner stretching across the bottom of the news channels TV feed as cameras repeatedly panned and zoomed in on it.
ISIS flag among a sea of rainbow colours was spotted by a CNN international assignment editor, CNNs anchor said.
Flag depicting dildos to mock ISIS used at London #pride parade. CNN thinks it's real and reports it as breaking news pic.twitter.com/F7v1oiInWn
 Nara Hodge (@NaraHodge) June 27, 2015
International assignment editor Lucy Pawle then called in to report on seeing the flag after she left work.
No one else seemed to have noticed the flag, she said.
She said it was an attempt to mimic an ISIS flag.
This man dressed in black and white was waving what appears to be a very bad mimicry, but a clear attempt to mimic, the ISIS flag, Pawle said.
The black and white flag with the distinctive lettering.
But it turned out to be a flag featuring crude drawings of sex toys.
While Pawle seemed to understand the flag was not real, she reported it to authorities.
If you look at the flag closely, its clearly not Arabic. In fact, it looks like it could be gobbledygook, she said,
The interview has sparked lots of laughs on social media and has been removed from CNNs site. But can still be seen on YouTube.
CNN's ISIS flag gaffe
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Top suspect took ‘beheading selfie’</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/france-attack-top-suspect-yassine-salhi-took-selfie-with-beheaded-boss-sent-it-via-whatsapp/story-fndir2ev-1227418461510?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>THE top suspect who beheaded his boss in an Islamic terrorist attack took a &amp;#8220;selfie&amp;#8221; photo with the slain victim, and sent it via WhatsApp after the brutal murder.</Description>
        <MainBody>Arrested Darwin teen had beheading hit list
THE top suspect who beheaded his boss in an Islamic terrorist attack took a selfie photo with the slain victim and sent the image via WhatsApp to a Canadian mobile phone number.
French investigators were working to confirm the identity of the recipient, but werent able to immediately confirm media reports that it was an unspecified person now in Syria, where the radical Islamic State group has seized territory, the security officials said.
They spoke on condition of anonymity because the investigation was ongoing.
Leading suspect Yassine Salhi, a truck driver with a history of radical Islamic ties, as well as his sister and wife remained in custody in the city of Lyon a day after he allegedly crashed a truck into an US-owned chemical warehouse and hung his employers severed head on a factory gate, officials have said.
Special forces of France's Research and Intervention Brigades escort an unidentified woman as they leave the apartment of a man suspected of carrying out an attack in Saint-Priest near Lyon. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
One of the security officials said the selfie was forwarded via WhatsApp, the globally popular instant messaging system owned by Facebook, to a phone number in Canada.
No group immediately claimed responsibility. The severed head appeared to mimic Islamic States practice of beheading prisoners and displaying their heads for all to see, and came days after the militants urged attacks during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. French authorities say Salhi had links to radical Salafists in the past.
Investigating police officers work outside the plant where an attack took place. Picture: AP Source: AP
Paris prosecutors office spokeswoman Agnes Thibault-Lecuivre said earlier Saturday that Salhi was refusing to speak to police investigators. She said that one of the other suspects initially arrested on Friday was released without being charged.
Investigators have not turned up any motive or possible foreign connection, Thibault-Lecuivre said. Under French anti-terrorism laws, Salhi and the women can be held up to four days before either being released or handed preliminary charges and locked up.
Special forces of France's Research and Intervention Brigades (BRI) cover a window with a sheet as they search the apartment of a man suspected of carrying out the attack. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Separately on Saturday, hundreds of people turned out in the region to honour slain businessman Herve Cornara and denounce the violence. Dozens turned out for a minute of silence in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, the town southeast of Lyon where Fridays attack took place at an Air Products chemicals warehouse.
Several hundred people also gathered outside a housing project in the town of Fontaines-sur-Saone to honour Cornara, 54, the manager of a transportation company that had employed Salhi since March. They recalled a kind, humble man who was active in the community of the Lyon suburb.
He lived on the fifth floor, me on the fourth. He spoke with all the young people in the neighbourhood. He didnt differentiate between (non-Muslim) French and Muslims, said Leila Bouri, a 24-year-old cafeteria cashier. If you ever had a problem, you would go see him.
When I heard this, I was shocked. Its shameful, she said. I am a Muslim, but you cant kill like this. Its not who we are. In Islam, were not told to slit throats. We only slit the throats of sheep. You dont slit the throats of people.
The suspected killer, she added, isnt a Muslim in my opinion.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Coloured spray burns waterpark crowd</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/asia/coloured-powder-spray-burns-crowd-in-explosion-at-formosa-fun-coast-waterpark-in-taiwan/story-fnh81fz8-1227418407741?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>MORE than 200 people were injured in an explosion at a waterpark in Taiwan after coloured powder being sprayed onto a crowd suddenly ignited. WARNING: Graphic images.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fire breaks out at Taiwan water park, injuring more than 200, many seriously burned. Sean Carberry reports.
Reuters
28 Jun 2015
News/World
Concert goers run as a fire starts at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan. Picture: AP Source: AP
MORE than 200 people were injured, over 90 of them seriously, in an explosion at a waterpark outside Taiwans capital Taipei after coloured powder being sprayed onto a crowd ignited, officials said.
Footage on the Apple Daily newspaper website showed crowds dancing as music played and clouds of powder being sprayed out which suddenly turned into a ball of fire that tore through the spectators.
Terrified partygoers were then shown running for their lives, screaming, as they were overtaken by flames.
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
As ambulance crews struggled to reach the site, victims were carried away on rubber rings and inflatable dinghies as friends desperately tried to get them out.
Bystanders poured bottles of water on the scorched skin of the victims still at the scene.
Around 1,000 spectators had been at the Color Play Asia event at the Formosa Fun Coast waterpark, just outside the capital Taipei, according to officials.
People tend to an injured woman at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
One male witness told local news channel CTI: It started on the left side of the stage. At the beginning I thought it was part of the special effects of the party but then I realised there was something wrong and people started screaming and running. Authorities said 229 had been hospitalised with 97 seriously hurt. Media reports said some victims had suffered burns to more than 40 per cent of their bodies.
A doctor treating 41 victims at one hospital in Taipei said 17 of them were seriously burned.
They all had respiratory system damage, he said.
A police officer walks past debris at the Formosa Fun Coast amusement park. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Our initial understanding is this explosion and fire ... was caused by the powder spray. It could have been due to the heat of the lights on the stage, said a spokesman for the New Taipei City fire department.
A man responsible for the event had been detained by police for investigation, the spokesman said.
Prosecutors were also looking into the incident, local media reported. Television images showed the stage on fire and crowds running away, some of them only dressed in swimwear and covered in coloured powder.
Items lie on the ground on the explosion site which was sealed off by police. Picture: AFP Source: AFP
Trails of bloody footprints leading away from the stage remained in the aftermath of the inferno, an AFP reporter at the scene said.
The fire was quickly extinguished, according to authorities. Officials said that ambulances had found it difficult to get near to the site and had to send in emergency workers with stretchers.
We feel sad and regretful about the accident, said New Taipei Mayor Eric Chu who was reported as saying it was the municipalitys worst ever incident of mass injury.
He said that extra doctors had been called in to help treat the victims. Ive ordered the park to shut down immediately and be placed under a rigorous investigation, Chu added.
Hundreds injured in Taiwan explosion 0:21
More than 200 people have been injured in an explosion at a water park outside Taiwan's capital Taipei.
Sky News
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sat Jun 27 23:54:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Inside escaped killers’ cabin hideout</title>
        <Link>http://www.news.com.au/world/north-america/escaped-murderer-richard-matt-shot-dead-by-police/story-fnh81jut-1227417345920?from=public_rss</Link>
        <Description>UPDATE: Police say they have escaped convicted killer David Sweat &amp;#8220;contained&amp;#8221; as images of his hideout surface online.</Description>
        <MainBody>Escaped murderer Richard Matt shot dead by police
by:
JOHN KEKIS and MICHAEL VIRTANEN
From:
One of two NY prison escapees Richard Matt has been shot and killed by police after three weeks on the run.
Sky News
27 Jun 2015
News
Richard Matt (right) was shot dead by police after staging a brazen escape from a New York State maximum security psion with David Sweat (pictured left), who is still on the run. Photo: New York State Police via AP, File. Source: AP
NEW York officials say they are closing in on David Sweat, one of two escaped convicted killers who staged a brazen escape from a northern New York State maximum-security prison.
Police who are on the ground hunting for the escapee, have him contained, CNN reports.
It only seems to have intensified overnight, said Correspondent Polo Sandoval.
We have no reason to believe David Sweat is not in this area, said Sandoval, before adding that there had not yet been an official sighting.
It comes after Richard Matt was shot and killed by police after an altercation in woodland yesterday.
A law enforcement official told @DebFeyerickCNN that they are closing in on #DavidSweat . http://t.co/zEpxEFLwsp pic.twitter.com/9RoEvSHXlN
 CNN (@CNN) June 26, 2015
Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a brick wall, squirmed through pipes and escaped early June 6 from Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, near the Canadian border.
After fleeing into the woods, The New York Post has obtained photos of a cabin the escaped killers used to hide out. The cabin is a 40-minute hike from the nearest dirt road and has a sign that says, Hey A**hole! This aint your f***ing land!
The rustic cabin is owned or leased by a group of correction officers who called their vacation spot, The Twisted Horn. according to neighbours.
The cabin where the pair hid out. Picture: William Farrington Source: New York Post
Picture: William Farrington Source: New York Post
Picture: William Farrington Source: New York Post
Picture: William Farrington Source: New York Post
Sweat was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriffs deputy in 2002. Matt was serving 25 years to life for the killing and dismembering of his former boss.
A civilian worker at the prison has been charged with helping the killers flee by giving them hacksaw blades, chisels and other tools.
Prosecutors said Joyce Mitchell, a prison tailoring shop instructor who got close to the men while working with them, had agreed to be their getaway driver but backed out because she felt guilty for participating. Mitchell pleaded not guilty June 15 to charges including felony promoting prison contraband.
I am at a road block outside where David Sweat is believed to be. Police bringing in flood lights. #PrisonBreakNY pic.twitter.com/g0Q4QQWZFk
 Susanne Craig (@susannecraig) June 26, 2015
Authorities said the men had filled their beds in their adjacent cells with clothes to make it appear they were sleeping when guards made overnight rounds. On a cut steam pipe, the prisoners left a taunting note containing a crude caricature of an Asian face and the words Have a nice day.
Clinton County chief prosecutor Andrew Wylie said they apparently used tools stored by prison contractors, taking care to return them to their toolboxes after each nights work.
Authorities also said Mitchell had discussed killing her husband, Lyle Mitchell, as part of the plot.
Joyce Mitchell tells us that was discussed between her and Matt and that upon their escape they were going to return back to Joyce Mitchells home at which time Matt and Sweat were going to kill her husband, Wylie said.
It's a beautiful morning to catch a murderer on the run! #PrisonBreakNY pic.twitter.com/r59y3f4sQ5
 Anne (@ONorthernOne) June 27, 2015
Lyle Mitchells lawyer, Peter Dumas, said June 18 that his client was shocked by word of the plot and that Joyce Mitchell had told her husband she couldnt go through with it and the inmates threatened to harm him.
On June 24, authorities charged Clinton correction officer Gene Palmer with promoting prison contraband, tampering with physical evidence and official misconduct. Officials said he gave the two prisoners the frozen hamburger meat Joyce Mitchell had used to hide the tools she smuggled to Sweat and Matt. Palmers lawyer said he had no knowledge that the meat contained hacksaw blades, a bit and a screwdriver.
Some businesses closed early in Malone due to the #PrisonBreakNY search pic.twitter.com/vzWx5uQLKO
 Jessica Layton (@JessicaLayton13) June 27, 2015
Dannemora, built in 1845, occupies just over 1 square mile (2.5 sq kilometres) within the northern reaches of the Adirondack Forest Preserve and is surrounded by forest and farmland. The stark white perimeter wall of the prison, topped with guard towers, borders a main street in the villages business district.
The escape was the first in history from Clinton Correctionals maximum-security portion. In July 2003, two convicted murderers used tools from a carpentry shop at Elmira Correctional Facility to dig a hole in the roof of their cell and a rope of bedsheets to go over the wall. They were captured within three days, and a subsequent state investigation cited lax inmate supervision, poor tool control and incomplete cell searches.
Governor Cuomo holds press conference with state police
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
