<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="news24">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:28:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | POTUS unscripted: Obama shows a softer side on Twitter</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/POTUS-unscripted-Obama-shows-a-softer-side-on-Twitter-20150707</Link>
        <Description>President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings, at all hours of the day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama to meet with gay rights activists
Washington - President Barack Obama is taking to Twitter to muse about sports, pop culture, even Supreme Court rulings, at all hours of the day.
The White House has used Twitter to promote the president's views for years, but with tweets composed by press aides and released at strategic times. Only occasionally would Obama post to Twitter himself, identifying a bona fide presidential tweet by appending his initials.
Now Obama is composing his own tweets almost daily, without the filter of his press office. His personal twitter account, @POTUS, launched earlier this summer.
"Hello, Twitter! It's Barack. Really!" Obama wrote in May. "Six years in, they're finally giving me my own account."
Obama, who has been known to use an iPad and a Blackberry, can send tweets from a variety of secure devices, according to the White House. Obama gives his team a heads up before he tweets, and his staff says he sometimes agrees to tweet about topics his aides suggest.
He's already amassed more than 3 million followers. He follows only 66 Twitter users, mostly sports teams, federal agencies and top government officials. He briefly set a record for attracting a million followers faster than any other Twitter user. But Obama's record was quickly broken by Caitlyn Jenner.
A look at some of Obama's recent tweets:
Gay marriage
Obama's first reaction to the Supreme Court's historic ruling legalising gay marriage nationwide came through his Twitter account.
"Today is a big step in our march toward equality," Obama tweeted on June 26. "Gay and lesbian couples now have the right to marry, just like anyone else."
Bring in the band
After Obama tweeted that he'd spent his morning listening to the new album from The Black Keys, the rock band tweeted back asking if they could use Air Force One for their upcoming gigs. A few hours later, Obama tweeted his response: "It's not mine; just a loaner. Maybe you can come play at the White House sometime instead?"
No 1 fan
Obama congratulated the American team and midfielder Carli Lloyd for their victory Sunday night in the Women's World Cup.
"What a win for Team USA!" Obama wrote, adding: "Your country is so proud of all of you. Come visit the White House with the World Cup soon."
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:19:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 18 tourists hurt in Turkish hot air balloon accident</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/18-tourists-hurt-in-Turkish-hot-air-balloon-accident-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A Turkish medical official says that 18 tourists have been hospitalised after a hot air balloon accident in the Cappadocia area of central Turkey.</Description>
        <MainBody>18 tourists hurt in Turkish hot air balloon accident
2015-06-26 14:19
Chinese man crashes balloon near disputed isles
Istanbul - A Turkish medical official says that 18 tourists were hospitalised after a hot air balloon accident in the Cappadocia area of central Turkey.
District medical director Dr Rahim Unlubay says that none of the tourists is in a critical situation. Nine have already been released from the hospital and he expects the rest to be released soon.
He confirmed Turkish media reports that there were foreigners among the injured Friday.
Turkish news agency DHA say the hot air balloon went down after being buffeted by winds and hitting an electrical wire.
Anadolu news agency says that 14 of the tourists were Chinese, two were American, one was Brazilian, two were Greeks and one was Turkish. It is not immediately clear which among them was injured.
Read more on:  turkey
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:19:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Obama to deliver eulogy as Charleston mourns attack victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Obama-to-deliver-eulogy-as-Charleston-mourns-attack-victims-20150626</Link>
        <Description>President Barack Obama was on Friday set to deliver a eulogy for the chief pastor gunned down in an apparent racially-motivated attack that shocked the nation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Obama to deliver eulogy as Charleston mourns attack victims
2015-06-26 14:19
Barack Obama. (Saul Loeb, AFP)
Charleston shooting: 4 000 pay respects to slain pastor
Charleston - President Barack Obama was on Friday set to deliver a eulogy for the chief pastor gunned down in an apparent racially-motivated attack that shocked the nation.
Obama will deliver the remarks for pastor Clementa Pinckney, who was gunned down along with eight other African Americans during Bible study in a historic church nine days ago.
The shooting was allegedly carried out by Dylann Roof, aged 21, a white supremacist.
The carnage renewed discussions of racism and hate groups in America and led to a furor over the controversial Confederate flag, which is present throughout the south but that many see as a symbol of racism.
For Obama, the shooting touched a particular nerve because it overlapped with two thorny issues in his presidency: gun control, which he never managed to overhaul, and racial divides.
Soon after the killings, a frustrated and angry Obama condemned the country's lack of action over mass shootings.
Several thousand people, including Vice President Joe Biden, are expected at the ceremony at a university in Charleston near the Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church where the shooting took place.
Mourners held the first funeral services Thursday for some of the nine African Americans killed.
Hundreds filed past the open coffin of Ethel Lance, aged 70, at a funeral home in North Charleston, ahead of an afternoon service for Sharonda Singleton, aged 45.
Emotions ran high at the Royal Missionary Baptist Church as friends and relatives bid a final farewell to Lance, a custodian at a Charleston arts center.
"I am here to tell you that we are stronger because we are together as a community," Reverend Norvel Goff told the mourners, the local Post and Courier newspaper reported.
Lance was later laid to rest at the Emanuel cemetery, where her children and grandchildren kissed her coffin and well-wishers threw roses into her grave.
Singleton, a speech pathologist, high school track coach and pastor at Emanuel, was remembered by a capacity crowd at the 2 000-seat Mount Moriah Missionary Baptist Church.
"She believed she could change every child," said South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, who attended both funeral services.
Seen in the pews were Jesse Jackson and Al Sharpton, two of the most recognizable civil rights activists in the United States today.
Thousands pay respects
On Wednesday, thousands filed past Pinckney's open coffin at the South Carolina legislature in the state capital Columbia, where he had served as a senator.
Services for the other victims are scheduled throughout the weekend and into next week.
Meanwhile, the campaign against the Confederate battle flag flying outside the South Carolina legislature picked up steam.
Adding his voice to the movement was College of Charleston president Glenn McConnell, a former Republican lieutenant governor and avid Civil War battle re-enactor.
As a state senator, McConnell favored positioning the flag alongside a Confederate memorial on the State House grounds 15 years ago.
"Today is a different time," he said, adding that the flag should come down as a "statement of courtesy and goodwill to all those who may be offended by it."
Some revere the Civil War-era flag as an emblem of Southern heritage, but others condemn it as a symbol of racial hatred and white supremacy.
Roof's getaway car, he was arrested a day after the shooting in North Carolina bore a Confederate license plate, and photos later emerged online of him brandishing the flag together with a handgun. He reportedly hoped to trigger a race war with the shooting.
South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, a Republican with Tea Party support, has come out in favor of removing the flag, but the final decision hinges on a vote by the state legislature.
Proliferation of petitions
MoveOn.org, a left-leaning campaign group, said more than 600 000 people have signed more than 50 petitions hosted on its website against the flag.
In Washington, US Attorney General Loretta Lynch said it was too early to say whether Roof will face federal civil rights charges.
A hate crimes investigation is unfolding, she said, but "it's simply premature at this point to be able to announce" how Roof might be charged.
South Carolina has charged Roof with nine counts of murder, one for each victim. He remains in solitary confinement at a North Charleston jail.
Haley has said that she favors the death penalty for Roof if he is convicted.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:13:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Kuwaiti-mosque-hit-by-suicide-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A suicide bomber has blown himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida says on social media.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack
2015-06-26 13:13
(Ibraheem Rahim, AFP)
Dubai - A suicide bomber blew himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said on social media.
The newspaper said the attack targeted Imam al-Sadeq Mosque in the Sawaber district.
"Eight casualties have been taken to the Emiri hospital, two in critical condition," al-Jarida said on its Twitter feed, without giving a source.
Arab television stations al-Arabiya and Al Jazeera earlier reported that an explosion hit the mosque and caused several casualties.
Read more on:  kuwait | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
24.com publishes all comments posted on articles provided that they adhere to our Comments Policy . Should you wish to report a comment for editorial review, please do so by clicking the 'Report Comment' button to the right of each comment.
Comment on this story
"It just looks generally awful and uncomfortable."

Western Cape
BRO Resourcing
Apartments / Flats R 1495000
Sponsored links
RSS feeds News delivered really simply.
Mobile News24 on your mobile or PDA
E-mail Newsletters You choose what you want
News24 on Android Get the latest from News24 on your Android device.
SMS Alerts Get breaking news stories via SMS.
Blogs Your opinion on you, me and everyone.
TV Get us in your home, on your television.

 2015 24.com. All rights reserved.
There arenew storieson the homepage. Click here to see them.

Hello
Create Profile
Creating your profile will enable you to submit photos and stories to get published on News24.
Please provide a username for your profile page:
This username must be unique, cannot be edited and will be used in the URL to your profile page across the entire 24.com network.
Hello
* You must provide a display name.
Edit your avatar:
Select an image file on your computer (max 4MB):
* The image you selected could not be uploaded.
Tell us a bit about yourself:
* Your profile could not be saved at the moment. Please try again later.

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 17:11:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | ISIS executes over 3 000 in Syria in year-long 'caliphate' - monitor</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/ISIS-executes-over-3-000-in-Syria-in-year-long-caliphate-monitor-20150628</Link>
        <Description>The Islamic State group has executed more than 3 000 people in Syria, including hundreds of civilians, in the year since it declared its self-described "caliphate", a monitor has reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS executes over 3 000 in Syria in year-long 'caliphate' - monitor
2015-06-28 16:11
(File, AP)
Kuwait arrests suspects in mosque attack, mourns dead
Beirut - The Islamic State group has executed more than 3 000 people in Syria, including hundreds of civilians, in the year since it declared its self-described "caliphate", a monitor said on Sunday.
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based group monitoring Syria's conflict, said it had documented 3 027 executions by ISIS since June 29 2014.
Among those executed are 1 787 civilians, including 74 children, said the Observatory.
Members of Sunni Shaitat tribe account for around half of the civilians murdered.
ISIS killed 930 members of the clan in Deir Ezzor last year after they rose up against the extremist Sunni Muslim group.
The toll also includes recent mass killings by ISIS in the Syrian Kurdish town of Kobane, which the jihadist group re-entered briefly this week after being expelled in January.
The monitor said it had counted at least 223 executions in the border town this week.
The Observatory also documented 216 ISIS executions of rival rebel factions and Kurdish fighters, as well as the executions of nearly 900 regime forces.
ISIS has also executed 143 of its own members it accused of crimes including spying, many of them captured as they were trying to desert the group, the Observatory said.
And at least 8 000 ISIS militants have been killed in battles and US-led air strikes, added the monitor.
ISIS emerged in Syria in 2013, growing from al-Qaeda's one-time Iraq affiliate and initially seeking to merge with al-Qaeda's Syrian affiliate al-Nusra Front.
When al-Nusra refused the merger, the two groups become rivals, and ISIS went on to announce its "caliphate" in territory in Syria and Iraq last year, proclaiming its leader Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi "Caliph Ibrahim".
Read more on:  al-qaeda | isis | syria
NEXT ON NEWS24X
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:30:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 3 men gored as Spain's bull-running week begins</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/3-men-gored-as-Spains-bull-running-week-begins-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Three men have been gored and 10 others taken to hospital on the first day of Pamplona's week-long San Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners in red scarves through the streets.</Description>
        <MainBody>3 men gored as Spain's bull-running week begins
2015-07-07 13:30
A steer, left, and a Jandilla fighting bull, centre right, run after revellers during the running of the bulls, at the San Fermin festival, in Pamplona. (Andres Kudacki, AP)
Injured rodeo bull made to suffer
Pamplona - Three men were gored and 10 others taken to hospital on the first day of Pamplona's week-long San Fermin festival in the northern Spanish city where bulls chase runners in red scarves through the streets.
Tuesday's run included six bulls from the Jandilla ranch in the rural western region of Extremadura, known for the ferocity of its bulls.
The run lasted 2 minutes and 23 seconds. One man was gored in the chest and was in a stable condition, a doctor at the event said. The Red Cross said two other men were gored, one in the back, but gave no further details.
Many Spanish towns hold festivals involving bulls during the summer. San Fermin is the most famous internationally and attracts thousands of revellers, many from abroad.
San Fermin featured in Ernest Hemingway's novel "The Sun Also Rises". Its daily Bull Run starts at 08:00 and usually lasts between 3 and 5 minutes.
There are eight runs in total.
Read more on:  spain
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:33:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Chinese 'Walter White' nabbed for selling ecstasy substitute</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Chinese-Walter-White-nabbed-for-selling-ecstasy-substitute-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Police have arrested a Chinese university professor who allegedly sold "millions of US dollars" worth of psychoactive drugs over the internet to clients in the US, Britain, Canada and Australia.</Description>
        <MainBody>Chinese 'Walter White' nabbed for selling ecstasy substitute
2015-07-07 12:33
Thailand battles to contain rising drug use
Beijing - Police have arrested a Chinese university professor who allegedly sold "millions of US dollars" worth of psychoactive drugs over the internet to clients in the US, Britain, Canada and Australia, state media reported on Tuesday.
The professor, surnamed Zhang, first learned about the popularity of such drugs while teaching as a visiting academic in Australia, the official Xinhua news agency reported.
He then started a chemical company in 2005 but had staff manufacture "hundreds of kilograms" of methylone, commonly used as a substitute for MDMA, or ecstasy, the report said.
Between March and November last year, the business sold at least 193kg of the substance to the overseas customers, Xinhua said.
The report did not provide a precise monetary figure, only quoting police as saying that Zhang earned "millions of US dollars" from the sales.
Xinhua dubbed Zhang "China's real-life Walter White" in reference to the fictional high school chemistry teacher and methamphetamine kingpin immortalised in the US hit cable TV series Breaking Bad.
The report did not identify his university, only describing it as "famous" and in the central city of Wuhan.
Last month, police raided Zhang's lab in the city, where they found 20kg of drugs and arrested eight people.
The report of Zhang's alleged dealings comes after police in May announced the arrest of a former chemistry professor on suspicion of selling a drug recipe to a gang which cooked up synthetic narcotics.
Chinese state media in May cited the government as saying the country has 14 million drug users, about 1% of the population, and their numbers have increased by an annual average of 36% in recent years.
Use of synthetic drugs, such as crystal meth and methcathinone, which can induce euphoric highs, are reported to be growing in rural areas of China.
Read more on:  china | narcotics
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:33:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Suicide car bomber targets Nato convoy in Afghan capital</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Suicide-car-bomber-targets-Nato-convoy-in-Afghan-capital-20150707</Link>
        <Description>A suicide car bomber has targeted a convoy of the Nato-led coalition forces in Kabul, police say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Suicide car bomber targets Nato convoy in Afghan capital
2015-07-07 12:33
(Emad Matti, AP)
Bomb kills 3 in Pakistani tribal area
Kabul - A suicide car bomber targeted a convoy of the Nato-led coalition forces in Kabul on Tuesday, police said.
"We are confirming an explosion in the Shah Shahid area of Kabul," said Sediq Sediqqi, a spokesman for the Ministry of Interior.
"One civilian and the driver of an armoured vehicle with foreign troops in were injured," said Ebadullah Karimi, Kabul police spokesperson.
The bombing damaged both vehicles carrying foreign troops and the buildings around, he said.
The Taliban claimed responsibility for the attack.
Meanwhile, at least 49 rebels were killed in separate foreign drone strikes on Monday night in the eastern province of Nangarhar, said Ahmad Zai Abdulzai, the provincial governor's spokesperson.
He said the drone strikes targeted separate hideouts of the rebels in the villages of Achin district.
"No civilian casualties were reported," he said.
Read more on:  afghanistan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Spanish police arrest woman for recruiting young girls for ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Spanish-police-arrest-woman-for-recruiting-young-girls-for-ISIS-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Spanish police have arrested a woman suspected of recruiting pre-teen girls and teenagers of both sexes to send to areas controlled by ISIS in Syria.</Description>
        <MainBody>Spanish police arrest woman for recruiting young girls for ISIS
2015-07-07 11:21
Spanish police. (Gerard Julien, AFP)
Women held over ISIS mosque attack in Kuwait
Madrid - Spanish police have arrested a woman suspected of recruiting pre-teen girls and teenagers of both sexes to send to areas controlled by ISIS in Syria.
An interior ministry statement said the woman, a Spaniard, was arrested Tuesday in the city of Arrecife on the Canary Island of Lanzarote.
The ministry says the woman maintained contact with ISIS in Syria.
It adds that the operation was being conducted by the National Court in Madrid.
Spain has arrested dozens of suspected jihadi militants and recruiters in recent years.
Read more on:  isis | spain
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:21:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Pope-puts-family-first-at-outdoor-Mass-in-Ecuador-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis has received a hero's welcome in Ecuador's biggest city as he celebrated the first public Mass of his South American tour, telling hundreds of thousands of families they are the bedrock of society.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope puts family first at outdoor Mass in Ecuador
2015-07-07 11:21
Pope Francis talks to the people gathered in front of Quito's Cathedral, in Ecuador. (Ana Buitron, AP)
Pope Francis to touch on cherished issues
Guayaquil - Pope Francis received a hero's welcome in Ecuador's biggest city on Monday as he celebrated the first public Mass of his South American tour, telling hundreds of thousands of faithful their families are the bedrock of society but need to be supported better and strengthened.
In his homily, Francis praised families as the nucleus of society, calling them "the nearest hospital, the first school for the young, the best home for the elderly." He said miracles are performed every day inside a family out of love, but sometimes the love and happiness run out.
"How many women, sad and lonely, wonder when love left, when it slipped away from their lives?" he asked. "How many elderly people feel left out of family celebrations, cast aside and longing each day for a little love?"
Firefighters sprayed water from hoses on the crowd to provide relief from a searing sun and high humidity that made the 30C temperature in the Pacific port city of Guayaquil feel at least five degrees hotter.
Many pilgrims had spent the night outdoors, and some walked for miles to reach the park on Guayaquil's northern outskirts to catch a glimpse of history's first Latin American pope celebrating Mass on his home turf. They said it was well worth the discomfort.
"I'm tired, I'm hungry, I haven't slept, but I'm also full of emotion and joy in my heart," said Vicente Huilcatoma, a former police officer who walked 40km to reach Samanes Park.
One million people
The Vatican originally estimated more than 1 million people would turn out for the Mass, and government organisers put the crowd at above that figure in the hour before the service began. But Gabriel Almeida, the government spokesperson at the scene, rolled back the estimate to about 550 000 after officials viewed aerial images of the area.
Across the park, flags from Ecuador and more than a half dozen other countries waved above the enormous sea of people, who were divided into quadrants that Francis looped around slowly on his popemobile to cheers of "Francisco! Francisco!"
The pope's homily brought Janeth Valencia Bersosa to tears. The primary school teacher came to the Mass with her older sister Pilar from Cuenca, about 200km away, spending the night in the park and then baking under the heat of the noontime Mass. She said it was worth it.
"Francis has given us back hope in our families, in those we love the most, the nucleus of society," she said. "I wept at each phrase."
Francis has dedicated the first two years of his pontificate to family issues, giving weekly catechism lessons on different aspects of family life and inviting the entire church to study ways to provide better pastoral care for Catholic families facing difficulties today, including people who are divorced, gays and families in "non-traditional" situations.
Meetings on family life
A preliminary meeting of bishops on these issues ended last year in bitter divisions between liberals and conservatives, particularly over ministering to gays and to Catholics who divorce and remarry outside the church. Church teaching holds that Catholics who enter into a second marriage without having the first one annulled cannot receive Communion.
In his homily on Monday, Francis said he hoped the second meeting of bishops on family life, scheduled for October, would come up with "concrete solutions to the many difficult and significant challenges facing families in our time."
"I ask you to pray fervently for this intention, so that Christ can take even what might seem to us impure, scandalous or threatening, and turn it... into a miracle."
"Families today need miracles!" he added.
The Vatican spokesperson, the Reverend Federico Lombardi, said Francis wasn't referring to the gay or divorce issue specifically but was making a more general reference that he hoped the bishops would "help the church chart this path of leaving a situation of sin to one of grace."
Selfies
Upon his arrival in Guayaquil, the pontiff allowed several acolytes on the tarmac to take selfies with him. He then headed to the Shrine of the Divine Mercy, where 2 000 invitees gathered, including young cancer patients, residents of homes for the elderly abandoned by their families and some of Guayaquil's poorest people.
He told those gathered that he would pray for them "and I won't charge you a thing. All I ask, please, is that you pray for me."
After the open-air Mass, Francis had lunch with a group of Jesuits at a nearby high school.
A highlight was his reunion with the Reverend Francisco Cortes, a priest affectionately known as "Padre Paquito," to whom the Argentina-born pope, then the Reverend Jorge Mario Bergoglio, entrusted his seminarians on study trips to Ecuador years ago.
In a recent interview with The Associated Press, Cortes couldn't fathom that Bergoglio remembered him, much less made a point of coming to have lunch. "I don't know what to ask him," the soon-to-be 91-year-old Cortes said. "I'm really just a Mr Nobody."
Returning to the capital of Quito at dusk, Francis paid a 50-minute courtesy visit to Rafael Correa at the presidential palace. When it ended, Correa ushered him to reception line of dozens that took a quarter hour to negotiate.
The pope then prayed in Quito's cathedral and went out on the steps to address a crowd, many of whom had waited hours to see him and endured a deluge. But instead of giving the short speech that he had prepared, Francis offered a brief blessing.
Quito Mass
Tuesday brings another big public Mass, this time in Quito, as well as a meeting with the country's bishops, a speech at Ecuador's Catholic University and an evening gathering with civil society groups, including indigenous leaders.
Tens of thousands who lined up outside the Quito park where the Mass was to be held got soaked in a punishing rain and hail storm. People grabbed what they could to protect themselves. They tore vinyl advertising placards off the metal fences surrounding the park, which was the city's international airport until two years ago.
Some just shrugged it off. Although her clothes were soaked and she shivered in the cold of Quito's 9,000-foot altitude, 71-year-old Angelica Naranjo said: "This isn't a sacrifice. It's a demonstration of faith."
Quito security chief Juan Zapata said officials would distribute blankets from stocks kept by civil defence authorities.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:22:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Australian senator threatens to grab Abbott's testicles</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Australian-senator-threatens-to-grab-Abbotts-testicles-20150707</Link>
        <Description>An independent Australian senator has threatened to physically intimidate Prime Minister Tony Abbott, using illegal rugby tactics including grabbing his testicles, if he does not limit coal-seam gas exploration.</Description>
        <MainBody>Australian senator threatens to grab Abbott's testicles
2015-07-07 10:22
Senator Glenn Lazarus. (William West, AFP)
Australia tells Indonesia to fix its borders
Sydney - An independent Australian senator on Tuesday threatened to physically intimidate Prime Minister Tony Abbott, using illegal rugby tactics including grabbing his testicles, if he does not limit coal-seam gas exploration.
Glenn Lazarus, a former rugby league prop and a senator for the eastern state of Queensland, said he submitted a petition to Abbott calling for health impact assessments, exclusion zones and community consultations over mining developments near residential, agricultural and farming areas.
Lazarus, dubbed the "brick with eyes" in his rugby heyday, added to an anti-CSG protest in Sydney that he was prepared to use a range of tactics on the Australian leader if he does not respond to the community's concerns.
"I am prepared to go and squirrel grip, squirrel grip, the prime minister," Lazarus added, in apparently light-hearted comments.
"If that doesn't work I have got other things up my sleeve, like the grapple tackle, the chicken wing and even the crusher tackle, and if that doesn't work, I'm prepared to use the Hopoate tactics."
The "squirrel grip" is a testicle-grabbing tackle, the "chicken wing" involves twisting or bending an opponent's limbs and the "crusher" is pinning the head of a player against the tackler's chest.
"Hopoate tactics" is named after former Australian and Tongan rugby league player and serial offender John Hopoate, who in 2001 was banned for two weeks for inserting his finger in the anuses of several opposition players.
Lazarus, previously a member of flamboyant billionaire Clive Palmer's party in the upper house Senate before he quit to become independent, also said he had threatened to "shirtfront" Abbott over the coal-seam gas issue.
Abbott in October vowed to "shirtfront", an Australian Rules football term in which a player charges an opponent Russian president Vladimir Putin over the July 2014 crash of Malaysia Airlines MH17 in rebel-held eastern Ukraine.
Australia is one of the world's largest gas exporters and Lazarus said he was fired up about the issue as deposits and mines were causing "havoc to the residents that are living there".
Abbott had no immediate reaction.
Read more on:  tony abbott | australia
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 11:23:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Saudi Arabia arrests brothers linked to ISIS bombing in Kuwait</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Saudi-Arabia-arrests-brothers-linked-to-ISIS-bombing-in-Kuwait-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Saudi authorities have arrested three brothers linked to a suicide bombing by a Saudi man on a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in neighbouring Kuwait last month, a report says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saudi Arabia arrests brothers linked to ISIS bombing in Kuwait
2015-07-07 10:23
File: AFP
Biden calls Saudi Arabia after diplomatic gaffe
Dubai - Saudi authorities have arrested three brothers linked to a suicide bombing by a Saudi man on a Shi'ite Muslim mosque in neighbouring Kuwait last month, Saudi state news agency SPA reported on Tuesday.
The ultra-radical Sunni Islamic State group said it carried out the attack, which killed 27 people and appeared aimed at stoking sectarian hatred in the energy-rich Gulf.
The three Saudi brothers, who were not identified, were "parties to the crime of the sinful terrorist bombing that targeted the Imam al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait", SPA quoted a security spokesperson for the interior ministry as saying.
One was arrested in Kuwait and was extradited to the kingdom, another was arrested in the western city of Taif and a third was taken into custody after a shootout at a house near the Kuwaiti border that wounded two policemen.
A fourth brother lives in Syria and is a member of Islamic State, the security spokesperson added.
The bombing was Kuwait's deadliest militant attack, and the most lethal in any of the six hereditary-ruled Gulf Arab states since a campaign of al-Qaeda bombings was stamped out in Saudi Arabia a decade ago.
The attack has raised concerns about the number of young Saudi men willing to travel to attack Shi'ites in smaller Gulf Arab states and so make good on a threat by Islamic State to step up violence in the holy fasting month of Ramadan.
The group claimed two suicide bombings carried out on May 22 and May 29 on Shi'ite mosques in eastern Saudi Arabia, where the bulk of Saudi Arabia's Shi'ite minority lives.
The Saudi branch of the militant group has said it wants to clear the Arabian Peninsula of Shi'ites and urged young men in the kingdom to join its cause.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Thai military court releases 14 student protesters</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Thai-military-court-releases-14-student-protesters-20150707</Link>
        <Description>A Thai military court has released 14 students held for almost two weeks for holding anti-coup protests in defiance of a ban on public gathering, but the charges against them have not been dropped.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thai military court releases 14 student protesters
2015-07-07 09:13
Anti-government protesters have rallied in Bangkok in their biggest bid yet to topple Thai Prime Minister Abhisit Vejjajiva. The protests are the latest saga in Thailand's tug of war between recently ousted PM Thaksin Shinawatra's supporters and opponents.
Related Links
Renewed protests in Thailand view
Bangkok - A Thai military court on Tuesday released 14 students held for almost two weeks for holding anti-coup protests in defiance of a ban on public gatherings, but the charges against them have not been dropped.
There had been growing calls for their release, including from the United Nations and the European Union, and public shows of support for the 14 have taken place across Thailand and among the Thai diaspora over the past few days.
Thailand's military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
"Police asked to extend the students' detention but today the court threw out that request," said Kisadang Nutjarat, a lawyer for the students.
"They have released the kids from prison today. There are no conditions and there was no bail," he said, adding that charges against the students had not been dropped.
Street demonstrations
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations across Bangkok against the ruling junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
They were arrested last month and charged with sedition.
Scores gathered outside a military court in Bangkok on Tuesday, shouting slogans and holding signs, to show their support for the students as 150 police officers stood guard nearby.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand's first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Thailand has been bitterly divided for a decade between supporters of Yingluck and her brother, former Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, who was himself ousted by the army in 2006, and the traditional establishment in the capital and the south.
Read more on:  thailand
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:06:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Wealthy family 'knifed to death' in Vietnam</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Wealthy-family-knifed-to-death-in-Vietnam-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Six members of a wealthy family in southern Vietnam were found knifed to death in their home after an apparent break-in, news reports say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Wealthy family 'knifed to death' in Vietnam
2015-07-07 09:06
Michael Brown's family to sue city of Ferguson
Hanoi - Six members of a wealthy family in southern Vietnam were found knifed to death in their home early Tuesday after an apparent break-in, news reports said.
Victims included the 47-year-old husband, his wife and two of their children, including a 10-year-old boy. A niece and a nephew of the couple were also killed. Their 2-year-old daughter was not harmed.
Police made one arrest and were searching for other suspects, Thanh Nien newspaper reported.
The murders were discovered at around 8:00 by a neighbour in Chon Thanh District of Binh Phuoc province, Tuoi Tre newspaper reported, around 90km north of Ho Chi Minh city.
Police told reporters that the family, which owns a woodworking factory with more than 100 workers, was apparently targeted for robbery.
Perpetrators broke into the house early on Tuesday and tied the six victims to three pillars, according to news reports.
Read more on:  vietnam
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 10:06:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Gay couple sue for recognition in South Korea</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Gay-couple-sue-for-recognition-in-South-Korea-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Buoyed by a landmark US Supreme Court ruling, a prominent South Korean gay rights campaigner and movie director is suing officials for refusing to recognise his 2013 same-sex marriage.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gay couple sue for recognition in South Korea
2015-07-07 09:06
Kim Jho Gwang-Soo, a South Korean movie director who is gay, and his partner Kim Seung-Hwan. (Jung Yeon-Je, AFP)
Gay marriage pressure builds on Australian government
Seoul - Buoyed by a landmark US Supreme Court ruling, a prominent South Korean gay rights campaigner and movie director is suing officials for refusing to recognise his 2013 same-sex marriage.
Kim Jho Gwang-Soo, a rare openly gay celebrity in conservative South Korea and his partner Kim Seung-Hwan took their fight for legitimacy to a district court in western Seoul on Monday.
The couple held an outdoor wedding ceremony in Seoul in September 2013 and submitted their marriage registration form to their local authority, only for it to be rejected.
While homosexuality is not illegal in South Korea, same-sex marriage is not recognised.
Gay and transgender people live largely under the radar in a country that remains deeply conservative about matters of sexual identity and where many still regard homosexuality as a foreign phenomenon.
Monday's court hearing, held behind closed doors, marked the first effort by a same-sex couple in South Korea to acquire legal status for their marriage.
"If you are a Korean citizen, you are equal under Korean law," Kim, 50, told reporters outside the court.
"I hope through this trial we can uncover this constitutional principle," Kim said, adding that he had pleaded with the court to "acknowledge our marriage before I die."
The lawsuit has been given added prominence by the June 26 Supreme Court ruling that made same-sex marriage legal throughout the United States.
Celebrations of the landmark decision were at the heart of what organisers described as South Korea's biggest annual gay pride parade on June 28.
Concerns over potential clashes with Christian activists prompted police to ban the march a month before it was due to take place, but a Seoul court later overturned the ban.
Police estimated more than 6 000 people took part in the hour-long parade in Seoul, while organisers put the number at more than 20 000.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:44:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 1 dead, 8 rescued after boat goes over US dam</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/1-dead-8-rescued-after-boat-goes-over-US-dam-20150628</Link>
        <Description>One man has died and eight other people have been rescued after their boat went over a dam in the state of Maryland, it has been reported.</Description>
        <MainBody>1 dead, 8 rescued after boat goes over US dam
2015-06-28 10:44
Ambulance photo from Shutterstock
Multimedia    User Galleries    News in Pictures Send us your pictures  Send us your stories
Washington - One man died and eight other people were rescued on Saturday after their boat went over a dam in the state of Maryland, US media reported.
The incident on Lake Linganore left four people desperately hanging onto the dam for their lives, NBC news said, citing Frederick County Fire and Rescue Services Division Captain Kevin Fox.
The four were rescued, along with three more who were pulled from the dam's spillway by helicopter and another who was pulled out by boat.
Maryland Department of Natural Resources Police said the 62-year-old victim's body had been recovered after becoming trapped underwater by the force of the dam, according to NBC.
Fox told ABC News that residents heard people calling for help and reported the incident around 18:30 (22:30 GMT).
The cause of the accident was unknown but occurred amid heavy flooding.
Lake Linganore is located around 72km northwest of Washington.
Read more on:  us
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:55:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Cameron expresses sympathies to France over factory incident</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Cameron-expresses-sympathies-to-France-over-factory-incident-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Prime Minister David Cameron has spoken to President Francois Hollande to convey his sympathies over what a British government source said appeared to be an appalling incident at a gas factory in France.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cameron expresses sympathies to France over factory incident
2015-06-26 12:55
David Cameron. (File, AFP)
French police search for 2nd man in factory attack
Brussels - Prime Minister David Cameron spoke to President Francois Hollande on Friday to convey his sympathies over what a British government source said appeared to be an appalling incident at a gas factory in France.
"The Prime Minister has just spoken to President Hollande to express his sympathies for what looks like an appalling incident there," the source said.
"It clearly looks an extremely concerning situation and our thoughts are with all those affected by it."
#FRANCE #LIVE President #Hollande says- #Grenoble attack was carried out by one person, possibly aided by another. pic.twitter.com/Luw2U4kLO5
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:58:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Italy's Renzi slams EU leaders over migrant quotas</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Italys-Renzi-slams-EU-leaders-over-migrant-quotas-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi has launched a furious broadside at fellow EU leaders for failing to help deal with a tide of Mediterranean migrants, sources say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Italy's Renzi slams EU leaders over migrant quotas
2015-06-26 12:58
Matteo Renzi. (File: AFP)
Italy rescues 4 500 migrants, 10 die
Brussels - Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi launched a furious broadside at fellow EU leaders on Thursday for failing to help deal with a tide of Mediterranean migrants, sources said.
"If that's your idea of Europe, you can keep it," Renzi told his 27 counterparts at a European Union summit in Brussels, Italian sources told AFP.
"Either give us solidarity or don't waste our time," they quoted him as saying.
Renzi lashed out after the EU leaders at the summit failed to reach a consensus on mandatory quotas for migrants who land in frontline states like Italy, Greece and Malta.
They rejected European Commission proposals that 40 000 Syrian and Eritrean asylum-seekers who have already arrived in Europe should be redistributed according to a compulsory system.
"If you don't want to take the 40 000 you are not fit to be called Europe," added Renzi.
More than 100,000 migrants have crossed the Mediterranean so far this year, most of them landing in Italy, Greece and Malta who say their EU peers should share more of the burden.
The EU held an emergency summit on April 23 after around 800 migrants died when their boat sank in one of the worst disasters of its kind in the Mediterranean.
Renzi's comments came after an Italian mayor on the frontline of the crisis said failing to provide asylum seekers with safe passage to the EU was tantamount to genocide.
Tensions erupted between Italy and France recently over a crisis that saw hundreds of refugees blocked at the border between the two countries.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:58:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Boston bomber Tsarnaev arrives at Colorado penitentiary</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Boston-bomber-Tsarnaev-arrives-at-Colorado-penitentiary-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev has arrived at the US Penitentiary in Florence, Colorado, a day after he was sentenced to death.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston bomber Tsarnaev arrives at Colorado penitentiary
2015-06-26 12:58
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev sits as survivors and victim's family members address the court before the US District Judge in Boston. (Jane Flavell Collins, AP)
Dozens to speak at Boston bomber's sentencing
Boston - Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev arrived at the US Penitentiary in Florence, Colorado, on Thursday, a day after he was sentenced to death.
A spokesperson for the US Department of Justice confirmed that Tsarnaev was being held at the high-security facility.
The penitentiary is in the same prison complex as the ADX, a Supermax prison, but is a different institution.
After a judge formally imposed a jury's recommendation of the death penalty on Wednesday, Assistant US Attorney William Weinreb said Tsarnaev is eventually expected to go to the death row unit at the US Penitentiary in Terre Haute, Indiana.
Oklahoma City bomber Timothy McVeigh was also put to death at the facility, and more than 50 other people are awaiting execution.
Tsarnaev could spend years or even decades there as his appeal makes its way through the court system.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:45:28 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | French police search for 2nd man in factory attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-police-search-for-second-man-in-factory-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French police are searching for a second man after arresting one man following a suspected Islamist attack on a chemical factory in the south-east of the country, a local newspaper reports.</Description>
        <MainBody>French police search for 2nd man in factory attack
2015-06-26 12:27
French police secure the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon. (Philippe Desmazes, AFP)
France opens terrorism investigation after attack
Paris - French police are searching for a second man after arresting one man following a suspected Islamist attack on a chemical factory in the south-east of the country, a local newspaper reports.
A helicopter is sweeping the area around the Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier after the attackers drove a car onto the site, ramming gas tanks and causing an explosion and a fire, according to Le Dauphine Libere.
An emergency unit has been set up at a local hospital to treat the many injuries. A decapitated body was found at the scene, with the head placed on the factory's fence.
The Public Prosecutor in Paris has opened a terrorism investigation.
Read more on:  france | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:40:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Hollande returning to France from EU summit after terror attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Hollande-returning-to-France-from-EU-summit-after-terror-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French President Francois Hollande will return home early from an EU summit after a suspected Islamist attack on a factory in eastern France, officials say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hollande returning to France from EU summit after terror attack
2015-06-26 12:40
French President Francois Hollande. (File, AFP)
At least 1 death reported in suspected Islamist attack in France
Brussels - French President Francois Hollande was to return home early from an EU summit on Friday after a suspected Islamist attack on a factory in eastern France, officials said.
"He will return early this afternoon and is in constant contact with Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve and the security services," the official said, adding that he would make a statement to the press in Brussels before 11:00.
Explosions at scene of decapitation in Grenoble, France: http://t.co/KQnHNj965V pic.twitter.com/r0fpxzNExP
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:34:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France PM tightens security measures on 'sensitive' sites after attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/France-PM-tightens-security-measures-on-sensitive-sites-after-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French Prime Minister Manuel Valls has ordered heightened security measures at 'sensitive sites' near the gas factory that was attacked in eastern France.</Description>
        <MainBody>France PM tightens security measures on 'sensitive' sites after attack
2015-06-26 12:34
French prime minister Manuel Valls. (Christophe Ena, AP)
Man decapitated in attack on French gas factory
Paris - French Prime Minister Manuel Valls ordered heightened security measures on Friday at "sensitive sites" near the gas factory that was attacked in eastern France.
Valls, who is on an official trip to South America, asked Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve to head to Saint-Quentin Fallavier, the site of the attack, the premier's entourage said.
According to Reuters, the French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was heading to the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30km southeast of the city of Lyon.
Islamist flag found after man killed in attack in France ( http://t.co/Fyx3xnbL9p ) http://t.co/DYA1tkNumh pic.twitter.com/I44ReTTTv2
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:23:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France opens terrorism investigation after attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/France-open-terrorism-investigation-after-attack-20150626</Link>
        <Description>France opened a terrorism investigation after an attack at a gas factory left one person decapitated and multiple people wounded, officials say. One official says banners with Arabic writing were found near the body.</Description>
        <MainBody>France opens terrorism investigation after attack
2015-06-26 12:23
Hollande condemns violent French protests against Uber
Paris - France opened a terrorism investigation after an attack at a gas factory Friday left one person decapitated and multiple people wounded, officials said. One official said banners with Arabic writing were found near the body.
Two French officials said the attack began mid-morning when two men crashed a car into the entrance of a gas factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier in southeastern France, hitting gas canisters and touching off an explosion.
One of the attackers was arrested, they said. It was unclear what happened to the other attacker.
The decapitated body and banners with Arabic inscriptions were found near the factory entrance, one of the officials said.
Both officials spoke condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the news media.
In a statement, France's anti-terror prosecutor said an investigation was opened into the attack, which he said was carried out by "a terrorist group."
France went on high alert after an attack in January that left 20 people dead in the Paris region, including the Islamic extremist attackers.
Police arrest 1 in apparent Islamist attack on factory near Grenoble, France http://t.co/DYHAuMaZjo (Illustration) pic.twitter.com/W2XzlQsQ3p
Read more on:  france | security
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:44:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Rockets from Yemen kill Saudi border guard</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Rockets-from-Yemen-kill-Saudi-border-guard-20150628</Link>
        <Description>A Saudi soldier has been killed in a rocket attack on the kingdom's border with Yemen, where Riyadh is leading an air war against Iran-backed rebels, the interior ministry says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rockets from Yemen kill Saudi border guard
2015-06-28 10:44
Saudi Arabia says it has shot down Scud missile
Riyadh - A Saudi soldier was killed in a rocket attack on the kingdom's border with Yemen, where Riyadh is leading an air war against Iran-backed rebels, the interior ministry said.
The rocket fire in the southern city of Jazan killed Faisal Mohammed Belqasem Maqaadi and wounded another soldier, an interior ministry spokesman said in a statement carried by the official SPA news agency late on Saturday.
It did not specify the source of the fire but cross-border shelling by Yemeni rebels has become common since Riyadh launched an air campaign against them in late March.
At least 44 people, civilians and troops, have now lost their lives in shelling and skirmishes along the Saudi side of the border since the campaign began.
Last week, three Saudi soldiers and an Emirati were killed in the border area.
Read more on:  saudi arabia | yemen
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:13:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | France attack: Severed head covered in Arabic writing</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Arabic-writing-on-severed-head-pinned-to-factory-gates-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French authorities have found a man's decapitated head covered in Arabic writing attached to the gates of a gas factory, legal sources say.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan president condemns Charlie Hedbo cartoon
Paris - French authorities found a man's decapitated head covered in Arabic writing attached to the gates of a gas factory that was attacked Friday, legal sources said.
The suspected attacker was arrested and was known to intelligence services, the sources said. Authorities are in the process of investigating whether he had an accomplice.
According to AFP, the suspect entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices.
Police said it was unclear whether the attacker was acting alone, or had accomplices.
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found at the scene."
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested, according to sources close to the enquiry, who said he was known to the security services.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
Charlie Hebdo
Prime Minister Manuel Valls ordered increased security measures at all sensitive sites in the area.
Two Islamist brothers attacked the satirical magazine, killing 12. A policewoman and four hostages in a Jewish supermarket were also killed during the three-day attacks.
The January attacks drew record crowds onto the streets of Paris in a historic "march against terrorism".
Nearly four million people marched through the streets of France and more than 1.5 million in the French capital along with dozens of world leaders to express defiance in the wake of the attacks.
France has a high proportion of people that have gone to fight alongside Islamists in Iraq and Syria and has been on alert for possible attacks on its soil since the Charlie Hebdo attacks.
Earlier this week, the country passed a controversial new spying law granting sweeping powers to snoop on citizens.
The new French law allows authorities to spy on the digital and mobile communications of anyone linked to a "terrorist" inquiry without prior authorisation from a judge, and forces Internet service providers and phone companies to give up data upon request.
Intelligence services will have the right to place cameras and recording devices in private dwellings and install "keylogger" devices that record every key stroke on a targeted computer in real time.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:51:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Man decapitated in attack on French gas factory</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-gas-factory-attacked-by-Islamist-man-decapitated-20150626</Link>
        <Description>An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others Friday at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man decapitated in attack on French gas factory
2015-06-26 11:48
(Shutterstock)
Charlie Hebdo says prize protest a 'misunderstanding'
Saint-Quentin-Fallavier - An attacker carrying an Islamist flag killed one person and injured several others on Friday at a gas factory in eastern France, according to a legal source.
The suspected attacker entered the factory and set off several small explosive devices, the source said. A decapitated body was found nearby the factory, another source said.
"According to the initial findings of the enquiry, one or several individuals on board a vehicle, drove into the factory. An explosion then took place," said one of the sources.
"The decapitated body of a person was found nearby the factory but we do not yet know whether the body was transported to the place or not," added this source, adding that a "flag with Arabic writing on it was found on the scene".
A man thought to be the person who carried out the attack has been arrested, according to sources close to the enquiry.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said he would go "immediately" to the scene, his office said.
The attack occurred around 10:00, according to local media.
The attack came nearly six months after the Islamist attacks in and around Paris that killed 17 people in January that started with a shooting at satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo.
Two Islamist brothers attacked the satirical magazine, killing 12. A policewoman and four hostages in a Jewish supermarket were also killed during the three-day attacks.
The attacks drew record crowds out on the streets of Paris days in a historic "march against terrorism".
Read more on:  france | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:52:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Jail time for those who break new S Korea MERS law</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Jail-time-for-those-who-break-new-S-Korea-MERS-law-20150626</Link>
        <Description>South Korea has introduced a new law designed to curb a MERS outbreak, imposing jail sentences on those who defy anti-infection measures in a crisis that has now left 31 dead.</Description>
        <MainBody>Jail time for those who break new S Korea MERS law
2015-06-26 11:52
Visitors wearing masks as a precaution against MERS. (Lee Jin-man. AP)
North Korea claims it has cure for MERS, Ebola, Aids
Seoul - South Korea has introduced a new law designed to curb a MERS outbreak, tightening quarantine restrictions and imposing jail sentences on those who defy anti-infection measures in a crisis that has now left 31 dead.
Under the new law, passed in parliament late on Thursday, people infected with the virus who lie to state investigators about how they came into contact with the disease will face a fine or a prison sentence.
"False testimony would entail up two years in prison or $18 000 in fines," said the new law, which replaces the fine that could be meted out to anyone who did not tell the truth under previous legislation.
"Interviewees will [now] feel compelled to provide honest answers."
The new law also strengthens officials' power to restrict the movement of infected people and close contaminated facilities, with offenders who refuse to follow their orders also facing two years in prison or a $18 000 fine.
The number of state health workers in charge of preventing outbreaks and tracing them will also be doubled to more than 60.
Government failure
The legislation comes as South Korea's government is facing criticism for failing to stop the MERS outbreak, which has now become the largest ever outside Saudi Arabia.
Two new fatalities were reported on Friday, the health ministry said - both women, aged 79 and 80, who had existing health conditions.
A doctor at Seoul's Samsung Medical Centre, the hospital to which nearly half of all infections have been traced, was also confirmed to have contracted the disease.
The hospital earlier this week decided to extend indefinitely a 12-day suspension of normal services as patients, doctors and visitors continued to be diagnosed with the disease.
The latest fatalities brought the total death toll to 31, the health ministry said, with 181 people diagnosed with the deadly virus since the first case emerged on May 20.
Of those diagnosed, aside from the number of dead, 81 have recovered and 69 are still being treated, including 13 listed in critical condition.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:53:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Politician sentenced in killing of Colombian journalist</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Politician-sentenced-in-killing-of-Colombian-journalist-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A Colombian court has sentenced a state legislator to 36 years and three months in prison as the mastermind behind the killing of a well-known journalist.</Description>
        <MainBody>Politician sentenced in killing of Colombian journalist
2015-06-26 11:53
Jail bars. (File photo, AP)
Journalist kidnapped, killed in India
Bogota - A Colombian court has sentenced a state legislator to 36 years and three months in prison as the mastermind behind the killing of a well-known journalist.
Ferney Tapasco was convicted in the 2002 shooting death of Orlando Sierra, the deputy editor of La Patria newspaper in Manizales, about 165 kms northeast of Bogota. The sentence was announced on Wednesday.
The Committee to Protect Journalists on Thursday praised the sentencing, which came after years of delays and a series of questioned rulings in the case.
Sierra had been a harsh critic of politicians in the region.
One of the witnesses in the case testified that Tapasco paid for Sierra to be killed.
Read more on:  columbia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US jury finds 'gay conversion' therapy fraudulent</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/US-jury-finds-gay-conversion-therapy-fraudulent-20150626</Link>
        <Description>A nonprofit organisation that claims it could turn gay men straight has violated the New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act, a jury concluds in a civil trial that an attorney for the plaintiffs called 'a momentous event' for LGBT rights.</Description>
        <MainBody>US jury finds 'gay conversion' therapy fraudulent
2015-06-26 11:00
(Peter Morrison, AP)
Moroccan men jailed for kissing in public: NGO
Jersey City - A nonprofit organisation that claimed it could turn gay men straight violated New Jersey's Consumer Fraud Act, a jury concluded on Thursday in a civil trial that an attorney for the plaintiffs called "a momentous event" for LGBT rights.
The jury said that Jews Offering New Alternatives for Healing, co-founder Arthur Goldberg and counsellor Alan Downing made misrepresentations and engaged in unconscionable business practices.
Three men and two parents were awarded about $72 000 in damages. The judge will rule later on their request to revoke the company's license, plaintiffs' attorneys said.
"This is a momentous event in the history of LGBT rights," attorney David Dinielli said. "The same lies that motivate gay conversion therapy motivate homophobia, that gay people are broken and need to be fixed. The strength of our plaintiffs brought that to light."
Attorneys for the plaintiffs argued during the trial that the group, known by the acronym JONAH, claimed a success rate that wasn't backed up by actual statistics and used therapy methods that had no scientific basis, including having one client beat a pillow, meant to represent his mother, with a tennis racket.
In an emailed statement, defense attorney Charles LiMandri called the verdict "a sad day, not just for my clients, but for America."
LiMandri said he would "seek justice on appeal".
Read more on:  us | gay rights
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:01:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Erdogan denies ISIS launched attack on Kobane from Turkey</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Erdogan-denies-ISIS-launched-attack-on-Kobane-from-Turkey-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has dismissed as propaganda accusations that ISIS fighters had been allowed to cross from Turkey into Syria to launch a fresh assault on the symbolic battleground town of Kobane.</Description>
        <MainBody>Erdogan denies ISIS launched attack on Kobane from Turkey
2015-06-26 11:01
(File, AP)
ISIS video places UK hostage in Kobane
Ankara - Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on Thursday dismissed as "propaganda" accusations that Islamic State fighters had been allowed to cross from Turkey into Syria to launch a fresh assault on the symbolic battleground town of Kobane.
"We condemn the heinous attack by the terrorist ISIS organisation that targeted innocent civilians in the city of Kobane," Erdogan said in a speech.
Dozens of civilians and fighters on both sides were killed when the ISIS jihadists made a surprise return to Kobane on Thursday, detonating a suicide car bomb near the border and battling Kurdish fighters in the city. Two more bombs exploded later in the day.
Claims circulating on the Internet suggested several cars loaded with IS militants passed through the Mursitpinar border crossing in Turkey to make their way into Kobane.
Describing those allegations as "defamation and propaganda", Erdogan said: "No one has the right to link Turkey to terrorist organisations".
Trending topic on Twitter
The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said at least 35 civilians and Kurdish fighters were killed in the car bomb and subsequent fighting in the centre and south of the town, along with 22 IS militants.
Turkish officials meanwhile said four victims had died in Turkish hospitals while 135 wounded received treatment on the Turkish side of the border.
The Turkish government said video footage taken from Turkish border security units and broadcast by the state-run Anatolia news agency showed a bomb-laden car did not pass through the Turkish border crossing.
But Kurdish activists accused Turkey on social media of assisting the ISIS group, with the hashtag #TerroristTurkey becoming a trending topic on Twitter.
Arin Shekhmos, a Syrian Kurdish activist, told AFP in Beirut earlier that ISIS had entered Syria from Turkey through the Mursitpinar border crossing.
He claimed the ISIS forces were wearing Kurdish People's Protection Units (YPG) uniforms as a disguise when they entered.
'Back and forth'
The accusations come amid growing tensions between Syrian Kurds and Turkey.
Turkey says Syrian Kurdish forces who recently made gains in Syria against IS are linked to the Kurdistan Workers' Party (PKK), which for decades has waged a deadly insurgency inside Turkey.
Western states have repeatedly accused Turkey of not doing enough to halt the flow of jihadists in both directions across its 911km border with Syria.
Turkey fiercely rejects the accusations, saying it is making every effort to secure a long border and in turn has accused the West of not playing its part to shoulder the burden of hosting refugees from Syria.
But Turkey's opposition pro-Kurdish Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP) accused the authorities of long allowing IS fighters back and forth across the border.
"IS has in every period being using the Turkish border. It's been going back and forth. There's lots of proof of this," HDP co-chair Figen Yuksekdag said.
"It's not logical to think that ISIS is no longer using the border when it has been doing so for so long before," she added.
Kurdish forces backed by US-led air strikes and peshmerga fighters from Iraq scored a major victory in January by winning a hugely symbolic battle for Kobane.
Months of fighting has prompted a mass exodus of local residents, with some 200 000 fleeing across the border into Turkey.
At least 35 000 Syrians returned home after Kobane's liberation, another Turkish official told AFP.
The official added that the border crossing of Mursitpinar that lies opposite Kobane has remained closed except for limited use by civilians returning after January.
He also said there was no sign of any new refugee influx so far.
Read more on:  isis | turkey | syria
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:56:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Putin calls Obama to discuss Ukraine, ISIS</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Putin-calls-Obama-to-discuss-Ukraine-ISIS-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has called his US counterpart Barack Obama to discuss the conflict in Ukraine, ISIS's advances and a deal on Iran's nuclear programme.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin calls Obama to discuss Ukraine, ISIS
2015-06-26 09:56
(Alexei Druzhinin, AFP)
Russia to boost nuclear arsenal - Putin
Washington - Russian President Vladimir Putin called his US counterpart Barack Obama on Thursday to discuss the conflict in Ukraine, the Islamic State group's advances and a deal on Iran's nuclear program.
The crisis in Ukraine has triggered the worst standoff between Russia and the West since the Cold War, and the US said earlier this week it would deploy heavy weapons in central and eastern Europe for the first time.
The US announcement followed promises by Nato on Monday to step up its military presence in eastern Europe, against the backdrop of the conflict in Ukraine.
Putin, who has consistently denied backing the pro-Russian rebels in Ukraine, initiated the phone call with Obama, according to the White House.
"President Obama reiterated the need for Russia to fulfill its commitments under the Minsk agreements, including the removal of all Russian troops and equipment from Ukrainian territory," it said in a statement.
The crisis in Ukraine has killed 6 500 people in a little over a year and a peace deal struck in Minsk, Belarus has unravelled.
Obama and Putin also discussed Syria, where the self-proclaimed Islamic State group has made rapid gains, as well as historic negotiations between world powers and Iran over its disputed nuclear program.
"The leaders discussed the increasingly dangerous situation in Syria, and underscored the importance of continued P5+1 unity in ongoing negotiations to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon," the White House said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 10:56:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | High emotions as Charleston bury massacre victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/High-emotions-as-Charleston-bury-massacre-victims-20150626</Link>
        <Description>Emotions ran high as defiant mourners held the first funeral services for nine African Americans shot dead by a white alleged supremacist in a Charleston church.</Description>
        <MainBody>High emotions as Charleston bury massacre victims
2015-06-26 09:56
Mourners leave the wake of Senator Clementa Pinckney, one of the nine killed in last week's shooting, at Emanuel AME Church. (David Goldman, AP)
Alabama lowers Confederate flag
Charleston - Emotions ran high as defiant mourners held the first funeral services on Thursday for nine African Americans shot dead by a white alleged supremacist in a Charleston church.
Hundreds filed past the open coffin of Ethel Lance, aged 70, at a funeral home in North Charleston, ahead of an afternoon service for Sharonda Singleton, aged 45.
The deceased were among the Bible study group that was targeted in the June 17 massacre at the historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church.
Dylann Roof, aged 21, is charged with murder in connection with the multiple killings, which he reportedly hoped would trigger a race war between blacks and whites.
President Barack Obama is scheduled to deliver the eulogy at Friday's funeral of another victim, Emanuel's chief pastor Clementa Pinckney, aged 41.
Obama will also meet the families of some of the other victims.
There was raw emotion at the Royal Missionary Baptist Church as friends and relatives bid a final farewell to Lance, a custodian at a Charleston arts centre.
"I am here to tell you that we are stronger because we are together as a community," Reverend Norvell Goff told the mourners, the local Post and Courier newspaper reported.
Lance was later laid to rest at the Emanuel cemetery, where her children and grandchildren kissed her coffin and well-wishers threw roses into her grave.
Singleton, a speech pathologist, high-school track coach and pastor at Emanuel, was remembered by a capacity crowd at the 2 000-seat Mount Moriah Missionary Baptist Church.
"She believed she could change every child," said South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley, who attended both funeral services.
Seen in the pews were Jesse Jackson and Al Sharpton, two of the most recognizable civil rights activists in the United States today.
Obama "will be mindful of not just how sad it is that those individuals were taken from us, but also use the occasion to celebrate their lives," White House spokesman Josh Earnest said.
"Many of them, in the way that they went about their day-to-day lives, I do think serve as a genuine inspiration to others about the way that they lived their lives and about the values that they sought to embody."
Thousands pay respects
Thousands have visited Pinckney's open coffin at the South Carolina legislature in the state capital Columbia, where he had served as a senator.
Services for the other victims are scheduled throughout the weekend and into next week.
Meanwhile, the campaign against the Confederate battle flag flying outside the South Carolina legislature picked up steam.
Adding his voice to the movement was College of Charleston president Glenn McConnell, a former Republican lieutenant governor and avid Civil War battle re-enactor.
As a state senator, McConnell favoured the positioning of the flag alongside a Confederate memorial on the State House grounds 15 years ago.
"Today is a different time," he said, adding that the flag should come down as a "statement of courtesy and goodwill to all those who may be offended by it."
Some revere the Civil War-era banner as an emblem of Southern heritage, but others condemn it as a symbol of racial hatred and white supremacy.
Roof's getaway car, he was arrested in North Carolina one day after the shooting bore a Confederate license plate, and photos later emerged online of him brandishing the flag together with a handgun.
Haley, a Republican with Tea Party support, has come out in favour of removing the flag, but the final decision hinges on a vote by the state legislature.
'Truly sorry'
Roof's relatives said they had been asked many questions about the massacre.
"As more information becomes available, we will do our best to answer them," read a statement widely circulated in US media.
"We would like to take this time to reflect on the victims and give their families time to grieve. We feel it would be inappropriate to say anything at this time other than that we are truly sorry for their loss."
In Washington, US Attorney General Loretta Lynch said it was too early to say whether Roof is liable to face federal civil rights charges.
A hate crimes investigation is unfolding, she said, but "it's simply premature at this point to be able to announce" how the case will be handled.
Roof has been charged with nine counts of murder, one for each victim, and he is being held in solitary confinement.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:59:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | EU leaders agree to relocate 40 000 migrants</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/EU-leaders-agree-to-relocate-40-000-migrants-20150626</Link>
        <Description>EU leaders have agreed to the principle of redistributing 40 000 asylum seekers across their bloc, but left the details to be hashed out later, amid hefty disagreement on whether member states should be obliged to take in the migrants.</Description>
        <MainBody>EU leaders agree to relocate 40 000 migrants
2015-06-26 08:59
(File, AFP)
EU approves military to tackle migrant smugglers
Brussels - EU leaders agreed early Friday to the principle of redistributing 40 000 asylum seekers across their bloc, but left the details to be hashed out later, amid hefty disagreement on whether member states should be obliged to take in the migrants.
Conflicts and repression in Africa and the Middle East have driven thousands of people to travel to the European Union in search of protection or a better life.
Many have lost their lives during attempts to cross the Mediterranean Sea, while the bulk of arrivals to the bloc have been concentrated in a handful of member states, stretching resources there. Less affected EU countries have been under pressure to show solidarity.
"Leaders agreed that 40 000 persons in need will be relocated from Greece and Italy to other states over the next two years," said EU President Donald Tusk, following late-night talks in Brussels.
A further 20 000 refugees will be resettled from outside the EU, such as displaced Syrians, the leaders agreed. EU interior ministers will finalize the scheme by the end of July, Tusk said.
But the summit discussion was bogged down by a fierce debate, after it became clear that several member states would oppose a mandatory scheme for the relocation of the 40,000 asylum seekers.
Frustration
"Passions are inflamed," one EU source said, as the talks dragged on into the early hours of Friday.
"If you do not agree with the 40 000, you do not deserve to be called Europe," Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi told his counterparts, according to another source. "Either there is solidarity, or please don't waste our time," he added.
Sources said tensions were further exacerbated by a showdown between EU President Donald Tusk and European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker over the decision-making process.
But the two top officials later played down their differences, locking arms as they walked to a joint press conference. Frustration was still evident, however.
Juncker said the leaders had reached a "modest" decision. "That we take hours to agree on the system to apply proves that Europe is not up to the ambitions that it declaims on every occasion," he added.
It is now expected that interior ministers will proceed with a voluntary redistribution scheme.
"Every country must offer its own contribution, and then afterwards we will see whether the sum of contributions allows us to reach the objective, and if it is not the case, corrections will have to be made," said French President Francois Hollande.
Tusk singled out circumstances in Hungary and Bulgaria, noting that they are also affected by "strong migratory flows," and said they would probably "be treated by us as specific cases when the time comes to distribute the pledges."
While attention has focused on the plight of migrants crossing the Mediterranean, the two eastern European countries have faced an influx of people crossing their land borders to reach the EU.
Hungary has the bloc's highest number of asylum requests, relative to population size, and Prime Minister Viktor Orban has been one of the strongest opponents of the proposed relocation scheme.
Earlier this week, Hungary controversially announced that it has stopped accepting asylum seekers being sent back to its territory after moving on to other EU countries.
EU rules stipulate that asylum claims must be processed in the member state where migrants first set foot.
Following the summit debate, German Chancellor Angela Merkel described migration as the "biggest challenge" that the EU had faced during her time in office.
"I see a huge task approaching us, and here it will be decided whether Europe is up to the task," she said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 09:58:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Hollande condemns violent French protests against Uber</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Hollande-condemns-violent-French-protests-against-Uber-20150626</Link>
        <Description>French President Francois Hollande has condemned violent protests against ride-booking app Uber after taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked highways but he says the service should be taken off the road.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hollande condemns violent French protests against Uber
2015-06-26 08:58
Taxi drivers in France protest over Uber services. (Loic Venance, AFP)
US not spying on France's Hollande - Kerry
Paris - French President Francois Hollande on Friday condemned violent protests against ride-booking app Uber after taxi drivers set fire to vehicles and blocked highways but he said the service should be taken off the road.
Hollande described the demonstrations, in which US rocker Courtney Love was caught up, as "unacceptable violence in a democracy, in a country like France."
But Hollande, attending an EU leaders summit in Brussels, added: "UberPOP should be dissolved and declared illegal".
The service has been illegal in France since January, but the law has proved difficult to enforce and it continues to operate.
Around 3,000 cabbies took part in the strike Thursday, blocking access to the capital's Charles de Gaulle and Orly airports, and preventing cars reaching train stations around the country.
Ten people were arrested, seven police officers were injured and 70 vehicles were damaged in clashes between Uber drivers and taxi drivers.
Taxi drivers are furious at what they see as unfair competition from Uber, which puts customers in touch with private drivers at prices lower than those of traditional taxis.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said after meeting taxi drivers' unions following a fraught day: "UberPOP is an illegal service, it must be closed down".
Until that was done, "the vehicles of UberPOP drivers should be systematically impounded when they are openly breaking the law", the minister said.
"Governing the country will never be done by the law of the jungle," Cazeneuve added.
One of the taxi drivers' representatives, Ibrahima Sylla, described the minister's words as "promises, again" and said the drivers were considering continuing the demonstrations.
Love, Kurt Cobain's widow, was caught up in a confrontation near Charles de Gaulle airport.
She tweeted that protesters "ambushed" her vehicle and "were holding our driver hostage".
She appealed to the French president in another message, writing "Francois Hollande where are the fucking police???"
"This is France?? I'm safer in Baghdad," she added.
Two vehicles torched
In the most serious incident in Paris, one private chauffeur, who said he did not work for Uber "or any other app" was dragged from his van when he reached a blockade in the west of Paris.
Angry taxi drivers slashed the tyres of his vehicle, smashed a window and then set it and a chauffeur-driven van on fire.
Police eventually fired teargas to break up the protest on the western stretch of the ring road around the capital and cleared burning tyres.
Licensed cabbies say Uber is endangering their jobs by flooding the market with low-cost drivers.
One driver said the strikers had been driven to desperation.
"Taxi drivers, alright, they've got big mouths but normally they're not aggressive," said Malia, aged 50, who has driven a taxi for three years.
"But these guys have families to feed, debts. They've been pushed to the brink."
More peaceful protests took place at transport hubs in other major cities including Bordeaux, Marseille and Toulouse.
Cabbies argued that the disruption was justified.
"UberPOP is banned, but it's still here," cabbie Stephane Molla said in Bordeaux, southwest France.
Taxi drivers in France, like their colleagues in several other countries, have held a number of protests against the app, some of which have turned violent.
On at least two occasions in Strasbourg in eastern France last week, taxi drivers posed as customers in order to lure Uber drivers to isolated spots where they were assaulted by cabbies and their vehicles damaged.
In Paris, the government tried to strengthen its hand on Wednesday by obtaining a court order banning Uber from operating in the capital, but the company dismissed the move.
"We will fight it [in the courts] and we'll see what happens on appeal. For the time being it changes nothing, UberPOP can continue to operate," the head of Uber France, Thibaud Simphal, told the BFM Business channel.
San Francisco-based Uber, which offers several types of ride-sharing services, claims to have 400,000 UberPOP users in France.
However, its drivers do not pay taxes, do not need to undergo the 250 hours of training mandatory for French cabbies and do not require the same insurance as taxis.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:01:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in mosque attack</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Kuwait-arrests-driver-of-bomber-in-mosque-attack-20150628</Link>
        <Description>Kuwaiti police have arrested the driver who transported a suicide bomber to a Shi'ite mosque where he blew himself up, killing 26 and injuring 227 in an attack claimed by the Islamic State group.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait arrests driver of bomber in mosque attack
2015-06-28 09:01
Kuwait says security raised to highest after attack
Kuwait City - Kuwaiti police have arrested the driver who transported a suicide bomber to a Shi'ite mosque where he blew himself up, killing 26 and injuring 227 in an attack claimed by the Islamic State group, official media reported.
Authorities have also detained the owner of the house where the bomber was staying, a Kuwaiti national who subscribes to "fundamentalist and deviant ideology", the KUNA news agency said, citing a statement from the Interior Ministry.
The driver, named as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, was described as an "illegal resident" born in 1989, who took the bomber to the Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City on Friday, it said.
The arrest came after thousands of Kuwaitis braved scorching summer heat on Saturday to attend the funerals of 18 out of 26 victims of the bombing, claimed by the Islamic State group.
The bodies of the remaining eight victims were flown to Iraq's Shiite holy city of Najaf for burial, State Minister for Cabinet Affairs Sheikh Mohammad Abdullah Al-Sabah said.
Draped in Kuwaiti flags, the bodies were borne by mourners chanting religious slogans.
Mourners turned out in large numbers despite the Ramadan daylight fast and as temperatures hit 45 degrees Celsius.
"This crowd is the proof that the objectives of the criminal act have failed," parliament speaker Marzouk al-Ghanem told reporters.
The mourners, who included women clad in black Islamic dress, carried Kuwaiti flags and black and green banners bearing religious slogans.
The health ministry said that 40 wounded are still in hospital following the attack, one of the country's worst bombings and its first ever on a mosque.
The interior ministry said authorities will "continue efforts to uncover the conspirators in this criminal act and to reveal all of the information and circumstances behind it".
Sunni solidarity
Two of the dead were Iranian, the Shi'ite-dominated Islamic republic's foreign ministry said.
In Iraq, relatives wept as the eight coffins arrived and were taken inside the airport terminal at Najaf, an AFP journalist said.
"We want to deliver a message to Daesh (an Arabic acronym for IS) that we are united brothers among the Sunnis and Shiites, and they cannot divide us," Abdulfatah al-Mutawwia, a Kuwaiti who lost his brother in the bombing, said in Iraq.
Friday's attack targeted Al-Imam Al-Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City during Friday noon prayers.
Mosque official Abdulnabi Mansur said the victims flown to Iraq were seven Kuwaitis and a Saudi, and that they would be buried in the Wadi al-Salam cemetery surrounding the shrine of Imam Ali in Najaf.
In Kuwait, condolences were being accepted for three days from Saturday at the Grand Mosque, the largest place of worship for Sunni Muslims, in a show of solidarity.
Kuwait's emir, the government, parliament and political groups and clerics have all said the attack aimed to stir up sectarian strife in the emirate.
The radical Sunni group Islamic State considers Shiites to be heretics.
Shi'ites comprise a third of Kuwait's 1.3 million native population. Sunni religious and political groups were quick to condemn the attack.
The emir, Sheikh Sabah al-Ahmad al-Sabah, who visited the site immediately after the bombing, said the "criminal attack is a desperate and evil attempt targeting Kuwait's national unity".
Countries and organisations including the United Nations and the United States deplored the bombing.
Eight Islamist, liberal and Shi'ite political groups condemned the attack in a joint statement and called on the government to confront extremists.
Security measures
The government had briefed MPs about measures it has taken since the bombing, Sheikh Mohammad told reporters.
An interior ministry statement said, without elaborating, that an unspecified number of suspects were held for questioning in connection with the attack.
The cabinet announced after an emergency meeting on Friday that all security agencies and police had been put on alert to confront what it called "black terror".
Justice and Islamic Affairs Minister Yacoub al-Sane said additional security measures will be taken around mosques and places of worship.
National oil conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) said on Saturday it had raised security at oil facilities to maximum level.
Oil is Kuwait's main source of income, accounting for around 90 percent of public revenues.
The OPEC member says it sits on around 10% of global reserves and pumps around 2.8 million barrels of oil per day.
Read more on:  isis | kuwait
NEXT ON NEWS24X
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:05:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | World's oldest man dies at 112 in Japan</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Worlds-oldest-man-dies-at-112-in-Japan-20150707</Link>
        <Description>The world's oldest man, Sakari Momoi, has died in Japan at the ripe old age of 112.</Description>
        <MainBody>World's oldest man dies at 112 in Japan
2015-07-07 08:05
World's oldest man Sakari Momoi. (Japan Pool via Jiji Press, AFP)
Grandma, 92, sets record for oldest woman marathoner
Tokyo - The world's oldest man, Sakari Momoi, has died in Japan at the ripe old age of 112, an official said on Tuesday.
Momoi, born months before the Wright brothers made their first successful flight, passed away late on Sunday, said the official at Saitama City, north of Tokyo, where he had lived for many years.
The supercentenarian, recognised as the world's oldest male at the age of 111 last year, died of kidney failure in a care home in Tokyo.
"We heard from his family... that his health worsened one or two weeks ago," the official said.
Momoi, a former high school principal who was born on February 5, 1903, received a certificate from Guinness World Records confirming the achievement last year.
Two more years
Dressed in a black suit, white shirt and silver tie, Momoi told assembled media that he did not plan on going anywhere just yet.
"I want to live for about two more years," he said in soft voice at that time.
He was born in Minamisoma, Fukushima, an area badly hit by the deadly 9.0-magnitude earthquake and tsunami in 2011 that triggered the world worst nuclear crisis in a generation.
According to the US-based Gerontology Research Group, the title of world's oldest man now passes to Japan's Yasutaro Koide, also 112 years old and just over a month younger than Momoi.
On the opposite side of the Pacific, the world's oldest person celebrated her 116th birthday on Monday.
New Yorker Susannah Mushatt Jones, a former live-in housekeeper, known as "T" to her 100 nieces and nephews, was born on July 6, 1899.
Japan is known for the longevity of its people and around a quarter of its population of 128 million is aged 65 or older.
Read more on:  japan
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 09:05:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UN goals helped lift 1 billion from extreme poverty  Ban</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UN-goals-helped-lift-1-billion-from-extreme-poverty-Ban-20150707</Link>
        <Description>A 15-year effort to implement eight goals adopted by world leaders at the start of the new millennium has helped lift more than one billion people out of extreme poverty, the UN chief says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Halving world hunger by 2015 possible: UN
New York - A 15-year effort to implement eight goals adopted by world leaders at the start of the new millennium has helped lift more than one billion people out of extreme poverty, enabled more girls to go to school than ever before, and brought unprecedented results in fighting diseases such as HIV/Aids, the UN chief said on Monday.
In the final report on the Millennium Development Goals released on Monday, Secretary General Ban Ki-moon said the global mobilisation to implement the goals by the end of 2015 has produced "the most successful anti-poverty movement in history".
But he said inequality persists, with 80% of the people living on less than $1.25 a day residing in two regions  southern Asia and sub-Saharan Africa, and 60% in just five countries, India, Nigeria, China, Bangladesh and Congo.
"Too many people have been left behind, particularly the poorest and those disadvantaged because of their sex, age, disability, ethnicity or geographic location," Ban said in a video conference launching the report from the Norwegian capital, Oslo. "Too many women and children continue to die during pregnancy or from childbirth-related complications. And too many people lack adequate sanitation facilities, especially in rural areas."
Ban said other dangers have intensified since 2000.
Human development
"Conflicts have forced almost 60 million people to abandon their homes  the highest level of displacement since the end of World War II, with staggering consequences for human development," he said. "Climate change has become an existential peril, environmental degradation is undermining development gains  and both are affecting poor people the most."
Ban said global efforts now have to focus on these gaps.
World leaders are set to adopt a new set of goals at a summit in September. But this time there will be 17 goals with 169 targets to be achieved by 2030.
While the goal of achieving universal primary education won't be met, the report said enrolment rose from 83% in 2000 to 91 percent this year, and the number of school-age children not getting an education fell from 100 million to 57 million over the last 15 years.
As for other goals, the report said, child mortality has declined by more than half and maternal mortality by 45% over the last 25 years, new HIV infections fell by approximately 40% between 2000 and 2015, and women have gained ground in parliament over the last 20 years in nearly 90% of the 174 countries with data.
The report also said ozone-depleting substances have been virtually eliminated since 1990 and the ozone layer is expected to recover by the middle of the century. And it said government aid to developing countries increased by 66 percent in real terms between 2000 and 2014, reaching $135.2 billion.
The report, compiled by over 28 UN and international agencies, was produced by the UN Department of Economic and Social Affairs.
Read more on:  un | ban ki-moon
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 08:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | HSBC fires staff for mock ISIS execution video</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/HSBC-fires-staff-for-mock-ISIS-execution-video-20150707</Link>
        <Description>British bank HSBC has fired six staff members after they filmed a mock ISIS-style execution video during a team-building day out and posted footage online, a spokesperson confirms.</Description>
        <MainBody>HSBC fires staff for mock ISIS execution video
2015-07-07 07:12
(Site Intelligence Group, HO, AFP)
ISIS video shows killing of 2 Syrian activists
London - British bank HSBC fired six staff after they filmed a mock ISIS-style execution video during a team-building day out and posted footage online, a spokesperson confirmed on Tuesday.
The bank described the video, showing staff members in balaclavas holding a fake knife over a kneeling man in an orange jumpsuit, as "abhorrent".
"We took the decision to sack the individuals involved," a spokesperson for the bank said.
"This is an abhorrent video and HSBC would like to apologise for any offence caused."
The employees filmed the video on an HSBC team-building day at a go-karting centre in Birmingham and posted it on Instagram before deleting it, according to newspaper The Sun, which published the video on its website.
In the eight-second clip, a kneeling man in a jumpsuit is held by the shoulders while a colleague wields a coat hanger like a knife above him, as though preparing to cut off his head.
One staff member shouts "Allahu Akbar" [God is greater in Arabic] during the clip.
The staging recalls gruesome beheading videos released by the ISIS, which has executed over 3 000 people in Syria in the year since it declared an Islamic "caliphate" in Syria and Iraq, according to the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
ISIS killed a series of international hostages dressed in orange jumpsuits, including British aid workers David Haines and Alan Henning, in videos that caused shock when they were released last year.
HSBC has recently weathered a string of bad publicity, including allegations its Swiss private banking arm helped wealthy clients dodge tax, and fines by regulators for attempting to rig foreign exchange markets.
In June it announced it would cut its global workforce by up to 50 000 as it exits Brazil and Turkey and mulls relocating its headquarters back to Asia from London.
Read more on:  isis | uk
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 06:50:26 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | UK remembers 2005 London bombings under shadow of Tunisia</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/UK-remembers-2005-London-bombings-under-shadow-of-Tunisia-20150707</Link>
        <Description>Britain will mark 10 years since the London bombings with a minute's silence for the 52 victims, less than a fortnight after an attack in Tunisia highlighted the ongoing Islamist threat.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK remembers 2005 London bombings under shadow of Tunisia
2015-07-07 05:50
CCTV camera in London. (AP)
Britain mourns 15 dead in Tunisia attack
London - Britain will on Tuesday mark 10 years since the London bombings with a minute's silence for the 52 victims, less than a fortnight after an attack in Tunisia highlighted the ongoing Islamist threat.
Thirty Britons were among 38 people killed when a gunman went on the rampage at a popular Tunisian beach resort on June 26, Britain's worst terror incident since four suicide bombers attacked the London transport network on July 7, 2005.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly," Prime Minister David Cameron said.
"The murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact. But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
Radicalisation
In the past decade, successive governments have strengthened security powers and improved the way the emergency services respond to attacks.
But they are still struggling to address the problem of radicalisation exposed by the bombings, which were carried out not by foreign fighters but by four young men from Yorkshire in northern England who were inspired by Al-Qaeda.
Hundreds of British young people are now flocking to join the Islamic State group in Syria and Iraq, raising fears that they might return to attack their homeland.
"We will keep on doing all that we can to keep the British public safe, protecting vulnerable young minds from others' extremist beliefs and promoting the shared values of tolerance, love and respect that make Britain so great," Cameron said.
The commemorations begin with a wreath-laying at the national memorial in Hyde Park at 08:50 (07:50 GMT), marking the moment the first three bombs exploded on London Underground trains at Aldgate, Edgware Road and Russell Square stations.
An hour later, a fourth suicide bomber blew himself up on a double-decker bus in Tavistock Square near Russell Square, killing and injuring some of those who had been evacuated from the Underground.
'Body parts all over the place'
Relatives and survivors will gather at the Hyde Park memorial later in the day to lay flowers, while there will also be a service at St Paul's Cathedral.
A nationwide minute's silence will be held at 10:30 GMT, the second such gesture in four days after Britain fell silent on Friday for those killed in Tunisia.
For many of those directly affected by the London bombings, the anniversary has brought back painful memories.
David Boyce was a 25-year-old supervisor at Russell Square station and one of the first to witness the carnage.
"There was body parts all over the place and dead bodies lying all over the train," he told AFP in an interview.
He added: "The first person I came across, both his legs had got blown off.
"So using my own clothes I made a tourniquet, lifting his legs above his heart, made him more comfortable, let him know that help was on the way."
Counter-terrorism strategy
Many lives were saved by people such as Boyce, but the general emergency response was fractured, hampered by poor communications inside the tunnels and between controllers.
This has been overhauled, as has the government's counter-terrorism strategy, with new measures introduced to clamp down on radical preachers and give police and security services tougher powers to question and track suspects.
This year Cameron's government also moved to seize passports from Britons going to fight with the IS group, and it is working on highly controversial plans to increase the collection of mobile phone and Internet data.
The national terror threat remains severe, the second highest of five levels meaning an attack is highly likely.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:45:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | South Carolina Senate votes to remove Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/South-Carolina-Senate-votes-to-remove-Confederate-flag-20150706</Link>
        <Description>The South Carolina Senate has voted to remove the Confederate flag from a pole on Statehouse grounds.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Carolina Senate votes to remove Confederate flag
2015-07-06 23:45
Jim Collins protests proposals to remove the Confederate flag from the grounds of the South Carolina Statehouse. (Jeffrey Collin, AP)
Protesters, politicians: Take down Confederate flag
Columbia - The South Carolina Senate has voted to remove the Confederate flag from a pole on Statehouse grounds.
Lawmakers had largely ignored the flag until the killing of nine black people during a Bible study at a historic African-American church on June 17.
The 37-3 vote on Monday allows the state to remove the flag and the flagpole where it flies as soon as it passes the state House of Representatives and is signed by Governor Nikki Haley.
The bill must pass a two-thirds vote, which is likely to be held on Tuesday.
The Confederate flag was raised atop the State House dome in 1961 as part of centennial commemorations of the Civil War.
Critics said that was a direct challenge to civil rights, voting rights and desegregation protests at the time.
Read more on:  us | charleston shooting
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:05:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | 1000s evacuate as wildfires burn in Canada</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/1000s-evacuate-as-wildfires-burn-in-Canada-20150706</Link>
        <Description>More than 200 forest fires are burning across western Canada, causing a heavy grey haze to settle over the Pacific coast and forcing the evacuation of thousands of residents.</Description>
        <MainBody>1000s evacuate as wildfires burn in Canada
2015-07-06 23:05
A view of part of down town Vancouver covered with a smoky haze from the wildfires. (Franck Fife, AFP)
Mushers stand together as Alaska wildfire rages
Vancouver - More than 200 forest fires are burning across western Canada, causing a heavy grey haze to settle over the Pacific coast and forcing the evacuation of thousands of residents.
Authorities issued air quality advisories across British Columbia on Monday as an unrelenting heat wave that began in early June sent temperatures soaring to record highs. More than 20 fires were sparked on Sunday alone, according to officials.
People with medical conditions, as well as the elderly and the very young were urged to remain indoors and limit strenuous activity.
A 61-year-old logger died on Sunday while helping forestry crews battle a wildfire near Sechelt, north of Vancouver.
Local authorities have imposed a province-wide ban on open burning.
Read more on:  canada | weather
NEXT ON NEWS24X
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:35:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Boston bomber demands new trial</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Boston-bomber-demands-new-trial-20150706</Link>
        <Description>Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev has filed a motion demanding a new trial, less than two weeks after he was sentenced to death for attacking the city's marathon in 2013.</Description>
        <MainBody>Boston bomber demands new trial
2015-07-06 22:35
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev sits as survivors and victim's family members address the court before the US District Judge in Boston. (Jane Flavell Collins, AP)
Boston Marathon bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev sentenced to death
New York - Boston bomber Dzhokhar Tsarnaev filed a motion on Monday demanding a new trial, less than two weeks after he was sentenced to death for attacking the city's marathon in 2013.
The preliminary motion did not stipulate grounds for a new trial, other than to say it was "required in the interests of justice."
His lawyers said it was a "placeholder" motion that would be expanded upon by August 17.
Tsarnaev, 21, apologized to his victims for the first time during a highly emotional court hearing in Boston on June 24 when he was sentenced to death on six counts for the April 15, 2013 bombings.
A US jury determined the sentence unanimously on May 15 after finding him guilty on all 30 counts related to the bombings, the murder of a police officer and other crimes carried out while on the run.
The bombings killed three people and wounded 264 others in one of the deadliest attacks on US soil since the September 11, 2001 attacks.
They were carried out by Tsarnaev and his older brother Tamerlan, who was shot dead by police while on the run.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:36:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | US boy dies after being beaten for eating cake</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/US-boy-dies-after-being-beaten-for-eating-cake-20150706</Link>
        <Description>Police say a 9-year-old boy has died in the US after he allegedly was handcuffed and beaten for eating a piece of birthday cake without permission.</Description>
        <MainBody>US boy dies after being beaten for eating cake
2015-07-06 22:36
Kenya survivor: Sight of dead child made me want to kill
Hagerstown - Police say a 9-year-old boy has died after he was allegedly handcuffed and beaten for eating a piece of birthday cake without permission.
Hagerstown police Captain Paul Kifer says Jack Garcia died on Sunday at Children's National Medical Center in Washington.
Kifer says police will confer with Washington County prosecutors about bringing additional charges in the case.
The mother's boyfriend, 30-year-old Robert Wilson, was charged on Wednesday with first-degree assault and child abuse. His public defender hasn't returned calls from The Associated Press.
The mother's brother told police the boy was handcuffed on Tuesday as punishment for stealing the cake. He says Wilson hit the boy in stomach after the handcuffs were removed.
It's not clear whose cake it was. The boy had had a birthday three days earlier.
Read more on:  us
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:11:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | Iran talks may fail - German source</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/Iran-talks-may-fail-German-source-20150706</Link>
        <Description>Talks seeking a landmark nuclear deal between Iran and major powers may yet fail, a German diplomatic source says.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran talks may fail - German source
2015-07-06 22:11
(AP)
Iran atomic bomb probe may be completed in 2015
Vienna - Talks seeking a landmark nuclear deal between Iran and major powers may yet fail, a German diplomatic source said on Monday during a break in negotiations in Vienna on the eve of a deadline.
"We are not there yet... We should not underestimate that important questions remain unresolved. There will not be an agreement at any price. If there is no movement in decisive areas a failure is not ruled out," the source said.
The comments came after a day of talks between the foreign ministers of Iran and six major powers - the United States, Russia, China, Britain, Germany and France - in the Austrian capital.
They are seeking an accord that ends a 13-year-old stand-off over Iran's nuclear programme by scaling down its activities in return for relief from painful sanctions.
Last week an earlier deadline was effectively extended by seven days to July 7 by extending the terms of an interim deal from November 2013.
But on Monday an Iranian official suggested that his delegation had never really considered Tuesday as a deadline.
"July 7, July 8, we do not consider these dates as those dates we have to finish our job," the official, who asked not to be named, told reporters.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 19:30:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>News24.com | French police grill suspect after grisly beheading</title>
        <Link>http://www.news24.com/World/News/French-police-grill-suspect-after-grisly-beheading-20150627</Link>
        <Description>French police are grilling a suspected Islamist about an attack in which the man displayed his boss's severed head, in what appeared to be the second jihadist attack in the country this year.</Description>
        <MainBody>French police grill suspect after grisly beheading
2015-06-27 18:30
French police officers. (Thomas Samson, AFP)
French PM warns of more attacks after man decapitated
Paris - French police were grilling a suspected Islamist Saturday about an attack in which the man displayed his boss's severed head, in what appeared to be the second jihadist attack in France this year.
Prime Minister Manuel Valls, who cut short an official trip to South America to rush home, warned France faced more attacks and that Friday's assault on a gas factory near the second city of Lyon would increase tensions in the country, putting citizens' resilience "to the test".
No jihadist group has claimed Friday's attack, which came on the same day as a massacre at a Tunisian beach resort in which 38 people were gunned down and a suicide bombing in Kuwait that killed 26.
The other two attacks have been claimed by the Islamic State group.
Suspect Yassin Salhi, a 35-year-old married father-of-three, was arrested after causing an explosion by driving a delivery van into a warehouse containing bottles of dangerous gas and chemicals at the US-owned Air Products factory in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, some 40km from Lyon.
The prosecutor in the case said firefighters overpowered Salhi as he was trying to open acetone bottles in what is believed to have been an attempt to cause a larger explosion.
The firefighters then discovered the decapitated body of his 54-year-old boss Herve Cornara - who ran a delivery firm - near the car, along with a knife.
Cornara's head was pinned to a nearby fence.
"The head was surrounded by two Islamic flags bearing the Shahada, the profession of [the Muslim] faith," said prosecutor Francois Molins.
'Unable to speak'
Authorities hope an autopsy, expected to be carried out later on Saturday, will offer more clues. A source close to the case said it would seek to determine if the victim was first killed before being decapitated.
Meanwhile, in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, shocked residents held a minute's silence, followed by a pulsating rendition of France's national anthem.
One man, Philippe Ouastani, said he turned out in solidarity with the victim. "It's unheard of to decapitate someone in the 21st century. What weapons do we have to combat that? Being here, together."
Another woman, wearing the Muslim headscarf, said she was "unable to speak" when she heard the news.
"These acts have got nothing to do with religion. The Prophet never said to kill innocent people," raged the woman, who requested to remain anonymous.
She tried to find words to explain the killing to her 4-year-old son.
"There are naughty people who have done bad things. The police will put them in prison to punish them for their silly, silly actions," she told him.
'Better armed'
The gory attack in France came nearly six months after a three-day Islamist killing spree in Paris left 17 people dead, most of them gunned down in the offices of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo.
Like the Charlie Hebdo attackers and Islamist Mohamed Merah who gunned down soldiers and Jewish children in the southwest city of Toulouse in 2012, Salhi had been known to security services for "radicalisation", but slipped through the cracks.
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said on Friday that Salhi had been investigated for links to radical Salafists in Lyon, but was not identified as having participated in terrorist activities and did not have a criminal record.
Speaking after a ministerial meeting on Saturday with President Francois Hollande, Cazeneuve vowed the government would "continue to work relentlessly" against terrorism.
France is on high alert over hundreds of citizens who have gone to wage jihad in Iraq and Syria, as well as those involved in recruitment or radicalisation online.
Similarly, Europe has for months been bracing for so-called "lone wolf" attacks by supporters of Islamic State, which has urged its followers to strike wherever they can.
High threat
Cazeneuve outlined measures taken by the government in recent months to face "a threat which has never been as high" such as the creation of hundreds of new jobs for police, gendarmes and intelligence agents.
Some $256m will also go to modernising surveillance methods to keep track of jihadists online.
Earlier this week, France passed a controversial new spying law granting sweeping powers to snoop on citizens.
Cazeneuve said the law allowed security services to be "better armed" to fight the jihadist threat
Valls warned Friday's attack would fuel tensions in France - home to Western Europe's largest Muslim population - that "will be exploited".
"This macabre act of decapitation, staged with flags, is new in France" and aimed at "making an impact," Valls said.
"It's difficult for a society to live for years under the threat of attack," he told AFP on a flight back from Colombia.
"The question is not... if there will be another attack, but when."
Read more on:  france | security
NEXT ON NEWS24X
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
