<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nebraska Governor Vetoes Bill That Repealed Death Penalty</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/26/409859650/nebraska-governor-vetoes-bill-that-repealed-death-penalty?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The move sets up a showdown Wednesday with lawmakers in the state's unicameral legislature. A close vote is expected as lawmakers try to override the veto.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nebraska Governor Vetoes Bill That Repealed Death Penalty
May 26, 2015 7:44 PM ET
Twitter
Nebraska Gov. Pete Ricketts vetoed legislation passed last week that repealed the state's death penalty.
"Please sustain my veto. Please stand with the citizens of Nebraska and law enforcement for public safety," he said, flanked by law enforcement personnel, murder victims' family members and state lawmakers who support capital punishment.
As we reported last week , "opposition to the death penalty came from Republican lawmakers who are against it for fiscal or religious reasons, as well as Democrats and independents.
"Nebraska has not executed a prisoner in nearly 20 years  something Ricketts, a Tea Party Republican who strongly supports capital punishment, wants to change. He said this week that Nebraska had bought new lethal injections to resume the practice."
Last week's vote was 32-15. The state has a unicameral Legislature where all bills go through three votes. The vote in the previous rounds were 30-16 and 30-13.
It would take 30 votes to override a veto from Ricketts.
Fred Knapp of member station NET News tells our Newscast unit that one supporter of repeal "has already announced he'll switch and side with the governor. A close vote is expected Wednesday afternoon."
If lawmakers succeed in overriding the veto, Nebraska will become the first Republican-controlled state in the U.S. to repeal the death penalty since North Dakota in 1973.
The previous attempt in 1979 to repeal capital punishment in the state failed when the measure was vetoed by then-Gov. Charles Thone.
The death penalty is legal in 32 states ; the 18 states that have banned recently it include Maryland (2013), Connecticut (2012), Illinois (2011) and New Mexico (2009).
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 02:28:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heat Wave Claims More Than 750 Lives In India </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/26/409856461/heat-wave-claims-more-than-750-lives-in-india?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Most of the deaths have occurred in southern Andhra Pradesh and Telangana states. But high temperatures persist across much of the country of 1 billion people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Heat Wave Claims More Than 750 Lives In India
May 26, 2015 7:28 PM ET
An Indian farmer sits today in his dried up land in Gauribidanur village, in southern India's Karnataka state. More than 750 people are died in a heat wave that has swept across the country. Jagadeesh NV/EPA /Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Jagadeesh NV/EPA /Landov
An Indian farmer sits today in his dried up land in Gauribidanur village, in southern India's Karnataka state. More than 750 people are died in a heat wave that has swept across the country.
Jagadeesh NV/EPA /Landov
More than 750 people are dead in India in a heat wave that has seen temperatures in some parts of the country touching 118 degrees.
Most of the deaths have occurred in southern Andhra Pradesh and Telangana states. The Associated Press reports that more than 550 people have died in Andhra Pradesh since May 13; the number is 215 in Telangana since April 15. Indian news sites say the toll has exceeded 1,000.
Officials have urged people to stay indoors and remain hydrated. Temperatures in both states are expected to start falling by the end of the week.
But high temperatures persist across much of the country of 1 billion people. In New Delhi, NPR's Julie McCarthy reports , the temperature on Monday was 114 degrees. She notes that it's "so hot in the capital ... that the roads are warping. Zebra-striped crosswalks are mere smudges on melted blacktop in this sizzling sun."
The high temperatures are not unusual. Temperatures in parts of the country typically exceed 100 degrees before the monsoons begin. Those who die are usually poor.
Here's more from Julie's story that aired on today's All Things Considered:
"India's Meteorological Department says the current choking weather pattern is caused by missing pre-monsoons showers and an undisturbed high pressure system. It has issued so-called 'red box' warnings for three states  meaning a high chance of sunstroke, dehydration and fatality as temperatures creep up to 113 degrees and higher."
The annual monsoons, set to begin in the first week of June, are likely to lower temperatures. The season runs through September.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Test Of '1 Person, 1 Vote' Heads To The Supreme Court</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/itsallpolitics/2015/05/26/409836615/test-of-1-person-1-vote-heads-to-the-supreme-court?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Analysts have noted that dividing districts based on eligible voters rather than total population would tend to shift representative power to localities with fewer children and fewer immigrants.</Description>
        <MainBody>Test Of '1 Person, 1 Vote' Heads To The Supreme Court
May 26, 2015 6:51 PM ET
i
Part of Texas' congressional redistricting map from 2003. The lead plaintiffs in Evenwel v. Abbott are residents of a state Senate district in Texas who say their equal rights to representation are diluted because Texas equalized the districts in population terms and not in terms of eligible voters. Harry Cabluck/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Harry Cabluck/AP
Part of Texas' congressional redistricting map from 2003. The lead plaintiffs in Evenwel v. Abbott are residents of a state Senate district in Texas who say their equal rights to representation are diluted because Texas equalized the districts in population terms and not in terms of eligible voters.
Harry Cabluck/AP
When the Supreme Court returns for its next term in October, among the cases it has agreed to hear is a challenge to a fundamental practice that has governed American elections for generations.
When public-policy makers talk about a state's population, they generally mean the number of human beings living in that state  as counted or estimated by the U.S. Census Bureau.
That applies to a host of political actions, including the apportionment of seats in Congress and the Electoral College votes that choose the president.
At the federal level, seats in Congress have been assigned to the states based on their total population, regardless of age or voting status. At the state level, lawmakers and others who draw election maps have generally drawn districts for various offices on that same basis.
In a landmark case decided by the U.S. Supreme Court in 1964 (Reynolds v. Sims), states were ordered to make such districts "as near equal in population as practicable." This was referred to as the one-man-one-vote decision, more recently referred to as one-person-one-vote. States were no longer allowed to apportion their state senates, for example, with a single senator to represent each county  regardless of population.
But the court in Sims did not specify a precise definition of the word population. In the half-century that has passed, the court has also passed on several other opportunities to do so. The prevailing interpretation has been that the population meant all the people. But critics have long maintained that the court might as well have meant eligible voters, as the power to vote and be equally represented was what was at stake. Conservative jurists have raised the question, at least for the sake of argument, and Supreme Court Associate Justice Clarence Thomas did so in an opinion as far back as 2001.
The current case is Evenwel v. Abbott and the lead plaintiffs are two residents of a state Senate district in Texas who say their equal rights to representation are diluted, because Texas equalized the districts in population terms  not in terms of eligible voters. So, they argue, the eligible voters in some districts are more powerful than in others, because it takes fewer of them to elect a state senator.
The discrepancy is particularly pronounced in Texas because the state has so many residents who are not citizens. These include many longtime legal residents and also more recent arrivals who may not be eligible to apply for citizenship.
Analysts have noted that dividing districts based on eligible voters only would tend to shift the balance of representative power to localities with fewer children and fewer immigrants. The state of Texas has opposed the lawsuit in filings with a lower federal court, which ruled in 2014 that the plaintiffs' challenge was a political issue that was not judicially reviewable.
The case was filed by the Project on Fair Representation and its president, Edward Blum. Blum is former resident of Houston but has lived in Washington, D.C., for more than a decade.
Among his other efforts that reached the U.S. Supreme Court are the Fisher v. University of Texas case, which limited affirmative action in public college admissions, and Shelby County v. Holder, which eliminated a key section of the Voting Rights Act of 1965. Shelby released certain states and localities from the "pre-clearance requirement" by which the federal Department of Justice had to approve any chances to laws or rules affecting elections.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Dorothea Lange Taught Us To See Hunger And Humanity</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2015/05/26/409738018/hunger-and-humanity-how-dorothea-lange-taught-us-to-see?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Perhaps no one did more to show us the human toll of the Great Depression than Lange, who was born on this day in 1895. Her photos of farm workers and others have become iconic of the era.</Description>
        <MainBody>How Dorothea Lange Taught Us To See Hunger And Humanity
May 26, 2015 6:08 PM ET
i
Carrot pullers from Texas, Oklahoma, Missouri, Arkansas and Mexico. "We come from all states and we can't make a dollar in this field noways. [sic] Working from seven in the morning until twelve noon, we earn an average of thirty-five cents." California, February 1937 Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress hide caption
itoggle caption Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
Carrot pullers from Texas, Oklahoma, Missouri, Arkansas and Mexico. "We come from all states and we can't make a dollar in this field noways. [sic] Working from seven in the morning until twelve noon, we earn an average of thirty-five cents." California, February 1937
Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
Documentary photographer Dorothea Lange had a favorite saying: "A camera is a tool for learning how to see without a camera."
Lange's iconic photograph of Florence Owens Thompson, often referred to as "Migrant Mother." It was taken at a camp full of destitute pea pickers in Nipomo, Calif., in 1936. Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress hide caption
itoggle caption Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
And perhaps no one did more to reveal the human toll of the Great Depression than Lange, who was born on this day in 1895. Her photographs gave us an unflinching  but also deeply humanizing  look at the struggles of displaced farmers, migrant laborers, sharecroppers and others at the bottom of the American farm economy as it reeled through the 1930s.
Lange worked for the Farm Security Administration in the 1930s, chronicling rural poverty across America and the agency's efforts to provide relief.
Her most famous photo is often referred to as "Migrant Mother." Shot in 1936 at a campsite full of unemployed pea pickers in Nipomo, Calif., the image features Florence Owen Thompson , a poor farmworker flanked by two of her seven children, while a third, a baby wrapped in burlap, rests on her lap.
Freezing rain had destroyed the pea crop. Thompson and her kids "had been living on frozen vegetables from the surrounding fields, and birds that the children killed," Lange wrote in her notes. "She had just sold the tires from her car to buy food."
A man waits in a bread line in San Francisco during the winter of 1933. Dorothea Lange/National Archive/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Dorothea Lange/National Archive/Getty Images
But you don't need to read Lange's notes to sense this desperation. So much is conveyed in the worry etched on Thompson's face, worn far beyond her 32 years at the time the photo was taken.
Before she began documenting the travails of the poor, Lange was a portrait photographer for the well-to-do in San Francisco. So she knew that images of individuals would have far more emotional impact than those showing barren landscapes, her biographer, Linda Gordon, told NPR in 2010. Some of Lange's early photos of the downtrodden include images of hungry, unemployed men in San Francisco's bread lines.
As Anne Whiston Spirn recounts in Daring To Look, her book about Lange's Depression-era work, Lange turned her lens to agricultural workers in early 1935, traveling to California's Imperial Valley.
"Off for the melon fields (Mexican labor)." Imperial Valley, Calif. 1935 Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress hide caption
itoggle caption Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
"Off for the melon fields (Mexican labor)." Imperial Valley, Calif. 1935
Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
There, Spirn writes, Lange documented the situation of Mexican, Filipino and "white American" farm workers "living in hovels made of cartons, branches, and scraps of wood and cloth, with primitive privies, no waste disposal, no potable water." One of Lange's captions noted: "On these workers the crops of California depend."
Later that year, Spirn says, Lange's images and field notes from the Imperial Valley helped sway officials to fund a camp for migrants in California.
A sharecropper plants sweet potatoes with his 13-year-old daughter near Olive Hill, N.C., July 1939. "Her father hopes to send her to school," Lange noted. Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress hide caption
itoggle caption Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
Throughout her career documenting the Great Depression, Lange took great pains to include detailed captions with her photographs. In her daybook, she jotted down facts about the people she captured on film, like how much they earned and paid for food, and the number and ages of their children, Spirn says. Lange also made it a point to engage her subjects in conversation, and her notes included direct quotes from these chats.
i
A family traveling between Dallas and Austin, Texas. "The people have left their home and connections in South Texas, and hope to reach the Arkansas Delta for work in the cotton fields," Lang wrote in her notes. "Penniless people. No food and three gallons of gas in the tank. The father is trying to repair a tire. Three children. Father says, 'It's tough but life's tough anyway you take it.' " Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress hide caption
itoggle caption Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
A family traveling between Dallas and Austin, Texas. "The people have left their home and connections in South Texas, and hope to reach the Arkansas Delta for work in the cotton fields," Lang wrote in her notes. "Penniless people. No food and three gallons of gas in the tank. The father is trying to repair a tire. Three children. Father says, 'It's tough but life's tough anyway you take it.' "
Dorothea Lange/Library of Congress
Lange once wrote that "half the value" of her fieldwork was in these captions. Yet as her images became more widely distributed, they were often published without these notes  a situation that made Lange "furious all of her life," according to Gordon.
Even so, Lange well understood that photographs can speak a powerful visual language of their own. As she once said: "No country has ever closely scrutinized itself visually ... I know what we could make of it if people only thought we could dare look at ourselves."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Out Of The Classroom And Into The Woods</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/ed/2015/05/26/407762253/out-of-the-classroom-and-into-the-woods?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>In this Vermont kindergarten, every Monday is "Forest Monday" a day that gets students out of the classroom and into nature.</Description>
        <MainBody>Out Of The Classroom And Into The Woods
May 26, 2015 5:53 PM ET
Partner content from American Public Media
Emily Hanford
Philby Illustration/Corbis
Philby Illustration/Corbis
Kids in the U.S. are spending less time outside. Even in kindergarten, recess is being cut back. But in the small town of Quechee, Vt., a teacher is bucking that trend: One day a week, she takes her students outside  for the entire school day.
It's called Forest Monday.
Eliza Minnucci got the idea after watching a documentary about a forest school in Switzerland where kids spend all day, every day, out in the woods.
"I would do that in a heartbeat," she thought to herself. Then reality hit. "We're in a public school in America. That's not going to happen."
But her principal at the Ottauquechee School in central Vermont surprised her by saying: Try it.
Every Monday morning, the kids suit up for a day outdoors. Rain or shine  even in the bitter cold  they go out. They head to the woods next to their school where they've built a home site with forts and a fire pit.
First thing, the kids go to their "sit spots." These are designated places  under a tree, on a log  where each kid sits quietly, alone, for 10 minutes. Their task is to notice what's changed in nature since last week.
"There's more moisture in the air," a boy named Orion Bee tells me. An astute observation: It's early April on the day I visit, and the snow is starting to melt, making the air feel slightly soggy.
Playtime is next. Kids run around and do all kinds of things they're not allowed to do inside, like yell and throw things. Down by the stream, two boys are working together to build a dam.
"We can't roll it," says one boy, pushing with all his might to try to move a downed tree onto the dam.
More About Forest Schools
Set Up A Forest Kindergarten
"We can roll it!" insists the other boy. They push and push, to no avail. Eventually, one of the boys realizes he can get leverage using the tree's branches. Teacher Eliza Minnucci is standing about 20 feet away, watching.
"We're supposed to study force and motion in kindergarten," she says  and these boys just got a real-world lesson. "Outside offers so much," she says. "It is sort of the deepest and widest environment for learning that we have."
There are formal lessons in the forest, too. After playtime, the kids visit learning stations. At one, they paint using natural materials. At another, they make letters out of sticks. One girl struggles to make an "S."
"I'm going to get some curvy sticks!" she declares. Realizing that curvy sticks are hard to come by, she soon comes up with the idea of making a backwards "Z" instead.
"Kids are so resourceful out here," says Minnucci. "In the classroom, we chunk everything into small pieces. We teach them discrete skills and facts and they put it together later. That's a good way to learn, but it's not the way the world works," she says. "I like giving them the opportunity to be in a really complex place where they need to think about how to build a dam with a peer and at the same time, think about staying dry and staying warm."
There are very few rules in the woods. Take care of yourself, take care of others, don't wander too far away; that's pretty much it. The goal is to let kids experience independence and help them learn the self-regulation skills that are so important to becoming a successful adult. Minnucci points to a kid sitting in the stream.
"It's 33 degrees out. He's sitting in water. And he's going to figure out whether that becomes uncomfortable or not," she says. "I don't need to make a rule for him. He's going to figure that out. This is a place where he can learn to take care of himself."
Minnucci worries that U.S. schools have become too focused on academics and test scores and not enough on "noncognitive" skills such as persistence and self-control. There is growing attention on the importance of these skills, but Minnucci doesn't think traditional school is set up to teach them very well.
Forest Mondays, however, provide lots of opportunities.
"I see some amazing grit," she says with a smile, looking over at the boys who have successfully moved the downed tree onto their dam.
At Ottauquechee School, taking children into the woods requires more adult supervision. Grants pay for an additional forest day teacher. And most Mondays, there's at least one parent volunteer. Chris Cooper comes often.
"I like spending time with my son," he says. "I think it's a really great idea that they get the kids out. They're able to just kind of explore and figure things out on their own."
And what do the students think?
"We get to play and we don't have to stay seated forever," says kindergartner Jacob Tyburski.
When Minnucci started this experiment two years ago, she knew it would be good for the rowdy boys, who clearly need to run around more than the typical school day offers.
What she didn't foresee was how good it would be for the children who can sit still and "do" school when they're 5 years old.
Kids who are good at school need to understand there's more to life than acing academics, says Minnucci. And students who aren't excelling at the academic stuff need to know there's value in the things they are good at.
Clearly there's a lot students are learning in the forest. But what about standardized test scores?
Minnucci says scores went up more last year than any other year she's been teaching. She's quick to point out there could be lots of reasons for that.
What her students gain from the experience might not be measurable, she says, but that doesn't mean it's not worth doing.
Her principal, Amos Kornfeld, agrees. He says schools are being forced to think about everything in terms of data and measurable outcomes, but he doesn't need test scores to tell him forest kindergarten is working.
When the kids come back from the woods, they look happy and healthy, he says. "Schools need to be focusing on that, too."
Emily Hanford is an education correspondent for American Radio Works .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers Stole Data From More Than 100,000 Taxpayers, IRS Says</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/26/409829693/hackers-stole-data-from-more-than-100-000-taxpayers-irs-says?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The thieves used the data to file fraudulent tax returns. The IRS commissioner said less than $50 million had been successfully claimed from the agency.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hackers Stole Data From More Than 100,000 Taxpayers, IRS Says
May 26, 2015 5:48 PM ET
Twitter
The IRS says criminals gained access to the accounts of more than 100,000 taxpayers through its online service Get Transcript. The data stolen included taxpayers' Social Security information, when they were born and their street addresses.
At a news conference, IRS Commissioner John Koskinen said criminals made about 200,000 attempts to access tax information; 100,000 of those attempts, made from February to mid-May, were successful.
The IRS became aware of the breach when workers noticed a larger than usual number of people seeking transcripts through the online service. The thieves used the data to file fake tax returns. Koskinen said less than $50 million had been successfully claimed from the agency.
"We're confident these are not amateurs [but are] actually organized crime syndicates that not only we but everyone in the financial industry are dealing with," Koskinen said.
The IRS, in a statement, said the criminals "gained sufficient information from an outside source before trying to access the IRS site, which allowed them to clear a multi-step authentication process, including several personal verification questions that typically are only known by the taxpayer."
The agency said the Treasury inspector general for tax administration and the IRS's Criminal Investigation unit are reviewing the breach; the Get Transcript application has been shut down temporarily.
"The IRS will provide free credit monitoring services for the approximately 100,000 taxpayers whose accounts were accessed," the IRS said. "In total, the IRS has identified 200,000 total attempts to access data and will be notifying all of these taxpayers about the incident."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:40:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sip It Slowly, And Other Lessons From The Oldest Tea Book In The World</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2015/05/26/409746944/sip-it-slow-and-other-lessons-from-the-oldest-tea-book-in-the-world?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Over 800 years before tea was known in the West, a Chinese master penned the </Description>
        <MainBody>Sip It Slowly, And Other Lessons From The Oldest Tea Book In The World
May 26, 2015 5:40 PM ET
Jeff Koehler
itoggle caption via Wikimedia
A copy of the first page of The Classic of Tea. Containing just over 7,000 classic Chinese characters, the work is brief but comprehensive.
via Wikimedia
At least 2,500 years ago, tea, as we know it, was born.
Back then, it was a medicinal concoction blended with herbs, seeds and forest leaves in the mountains of southwest China. Gradually, as manners of processing and drinking tea were refined, it became imbued with artistic, religious, and cultural notes. Under the Tang Dynasty (AD 618907), the apogee of ancient Chinese prosperity, the drink involved ritual, etiquette and specific utensils. During this period of splendor, the first book dedicated solely to tea was written by Lu Y.
Ch'a Ching, or The Classic of Tea, remains the definitive work on the origins and culture, cultivation, processing and ways of preparing and drinking tea in ancient Asia  an Aristotle's Poetics of tea.
Tea had harmony and order, Lu Y wrote. And he stressed the need to slow down when making and drinking it, to pay strict attention to each step and utensil in the process, and infuse the entire undertaking with beauty. It's salient wisdom even  or especially  in the fast-moving world of today.
The author's life story has a Moses-like beginning. Sometime around 733, in the mountains of Hubei in central China, the abbot of a Zen monastery, out for a morning stroll, found an abandoned infant in a basket beside the river. He brought the boy back and raised him as a novice, according to The Way of Tea by Aaron Fisher, an American writer living in Taiwan.
A range of Darjeeling tea at Goomtee Tea Estate in Darjeeling, India. Jeff Koehler for NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Jeff Koehler for NPR
A range of Darjeeling tea at Goomtee Tea Estate in Darjeeling, India.
Jeff Koehler for NPR
Lu Y was a mischievous child. He rebelled against the monastic life and left before being ordained to join a theatrical troupe, becoming a popular circus clown and playwright. He later worked as a government official before settling into life as a scholar, poet, and expert in tea. Sometime between 760 and 780 over 800 years before the drink was even known in the west  he penned the The Classic of Tea.
Weeks into one of my visits to the Darjeeling hills in northern India, while researching my book on the region and its tea, I stayed in the planter's bungalow on Goomtee Tea Estate . Inside a dozen glass-fronted barrister bookcases of the library, I found the written treasures of the tea world: works by mid-century British academics and Indian agronomists, 1970s Tea Board of India pamphlets with rusted staples, atlas-sized folios on camellias. Copies were well read, often annotated, and frequently inscribed to Goomtee's owner.
Tea Tuesdays: The Evolution Of Tea Sets From Ancient Legend To Modern Biometrics
Secreted inside one case was Francis Ross Carpenter's magisterial but out-of-print translation of The Classic of Tea. As the first complete translation of the work into English, Goomtee's copy, published in 1974, had coppery brown spots on the edges and foxing on the inside from four decades of monsoon dampness.
Containing just over 7,000 classic Chinese characters, the work is brief but comprehensive and detailed enough that the British drew upon it when they started producing tea themselves in the 19th century in India. It's not a technical manual, but it's thick with a poet's imagery and inventive use of metaphor:
"Tea has a myriad of shapes. If I may speak vulgarly and rashly, tea may shrink and crinkle like a Mongol's boots. Or it may look like the dewlap of a wild ox, some sharp, some curling as the eaves of a house. It can look like a mushroom in whirling flight just as clouds do when they float out from behind a mountain peak. ..."
Or this, on the frothiness of a well-poured cup:
"They should suggest eddying pools, twisting islets or floating duckweed at the time of the world's creation. They should be like scudding clouds in a clear blue sky and should occasionally overlap like scales on fish. They should be like copper cash, green with age, churched by the rapids of a river, or dispose themselves as chrysanthemum petals would, promiscuously cast on a goblet's stand."
Pluckers on Jungpana Tea Estate during the monsoon, Darjeeling, India. Jeff Koehler for NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Jeff Koehler for NPR
Pluckers on Jungpana Tea Estate during the monsoon, Darjeeling, India.
Jeff Koehler for NPR
Throughout The Classic of Tea, Lu Y instills the practical with the spiritual and emphasizes the ritualized details paid to each step from cultivation to drinking.
Sitting in one of the wicker chairs on the glassed-walled verandah of Goomtee with a cup of tea, as rain streamed off the gutters, I was able to read The Classic of Tea with the patience necessary to fully gather in its cadence and reflections.
At such moments, glancing up from the page to catch the quiet green hills covered with knitted rows of tea bushes through rain-streaked windows, I felt the proper tempo and authentic, unhurried spirit of the drink. For Lu Y, tea must not only be treated with reverence, but, as his translator notes, "attended by beauty."
While the book brought Lu Y great fame, he withdrew from society to live as a hermit. Upon his death in 804, the sage of tea became its patron saint. Images of him appeared in tea establishments and tea merchants hoping for better sales worshipped statues of him, according to noted American tea authority James Norwood Pratt . And when their tea didn't sell well? They would pour boiling water over the statues.
The goal of the merchants who commissioned the work was, as William Ukers wrote is his hefty All About Tea, "to emancipate tea from its crude commercialism and lead it to its final idealization." Lu Y succeeded in offering them a Code of Tea. His lessons on appreciating the drink should be required reading today. Especially for those getting a cinnamon chai tea latte in a to-go cup and drinking it on the rush hour commute to work.
Tea Tuesdays is an occasional series exploring the science, history, culture and economics of this ancient brewed beverage.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>How Worried Should We Be About Lassa Fever?</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/05/26/409769488/how-worried-should-we-be-about-lassa-fever?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The tropical virus has killed a man who returned to New Jersey from Liberia this month. But chances that he could have spread the disease are remote.</Description>
        <MainBody>How Worried Should We Be About Lassa Fever?
May 26, 2015 5:27 PM ET
A single Lassa fever virus particle, stained to show surface spikes  they're yellow  that help the virus infect its host cells. London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine hide caption
itoggle caption London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine
A single Lassa fever virus particle, stained to show surface spikes  they're yellow  that help the virus infect its host cells.
London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine
An unidentified New Jersey man died after returning home from West Africa, where he had contracted Lassa fever, a virus that has symptoms similar to those of Ebola. Federal health officials are treating the case with caution because the virus, which commonly is spread by rodents, can occasionally spread from person to person.
Lassa fever can cause internal bleeding. Other symptoms include respiratory distress, vomiting, facial swelling, and back and abdominal pain. Dr. Tom Frieden , who heads the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, says the virus is not nearly as deadly as Ebola. Ninety-nine percent of people with Lassa fever survive.
"It's not that rare a disease in West Africa," says Frieden. "One in six hospitalized patients may have Lassa."
The virus hardly ever makes its way to the United States. But it did on May 17, when a man returning from Liberia by way of Morocco landed at John F. Kennedy International Airport in New York. He fell ill a few days later and went to a hospital in New Jersey.
Frieden says the patient was sent home. A few days later he returned to the hospital feeling worse. Initially, Frieden says, the patient was asked if he'd been to West Africa and he said no.
Doctors later learned the man had traveled to Liberia. According to Frieden, he was a frequent visitor because he worked in the mining industry. So they suspected he might have Lassa fever and sent him to an isolation facility that had been equipped to assess patients who might have Ebola.
By Monday morning, the CDC had run tests that confirmed that the man had Lassa fever, not Ebola. That night he died of the disease.
The CDC is now helping state and local health officials track people who may have come into contact with the man's blood or secretions and keep an eye on them for 21 days as a precaution. The likelihood that he spread Lassa fever is "low at this point," says Frieden, "but it's not zero."
Yet in this age of global travel, there are no sure things. "That's why it's so important to strengthen our infection control in this country," says Frieden, "and our efforts around the world to find, stop and prevent health threats from spreading."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What Will The Next President Face On #Day1?</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/itsallpolitics/2015/05/26/408553045/what-will-the-next-president-face-on-day1?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>This week, NPR looks at four seemingly intractable problems that await the 45th president: stagnant wages, violent extremism, cybersecurity and the federal debt.</Description>
        <MainBody>What Will The Next President Face On #Day1?
May 26, 2015 4:35 PM ET
The next president to occupy the Oval Office will confront four seemingly intractable problems: stagnant wages, cybersecurity, violent extremism and federal debt. Jewel Samad/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Jewel Samad/AFP/Getty Images
The next president to occupy the Oval Office will confront four seemingly intractable problems: stagnant wages, cybersecurity, violent extremism and federal debt.
Jewel Samad/AFP/Getty Images
Presidential candidates are doing what they have to do at this point in the campaign season  they're raising money and strutting their biographies and electoral viability to voters. We haven't heard much yet about policy papers or what they would actually do if they win. But those policy issues will matter  as the campaign picks up steam and especially once the next president steps into the Oval Office on Day 1.
This week, NPR looks at four seemingly intractable problems that await the 45th president on Day 1, and the policy options that might be available to him or her. The issues we're focusing on are:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>NYU Changes Its Policy On Reviewing Applicants' Criminal Background</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/ed/2015/05/26/409722773/nyu-changes-its-policy-on-reviewing-applicants-criminal-background?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>NYU has announced that when looking at applications, it will initially overlook the criminal record of prospective students.</Description>
        <MainBody>NYU Changes Its Policy On Reviewing Applicants' Criminal Background
May 26, 2015 4:27 PM ET
New York University announced it will not require the criminal record of prospective students in the first round of the admissions process. Jpellgen/Flickr hide caption
itoggle caption Jpellgen/Flickr
New York University announced it will not require the criminal record of prospective students in the first round of the admissions process.
Jpellgen/Flickr
Students applying for college supply all sorts of information  financial records, letters of recommendation, the personal essay  to name just a few.
One big question they face: Do you have a criminal record?
The question appears on the Common Application  the website that prospective students use to apply to more than 500 schools across the U.S. and abroad.
Most students don't even think about it. But for some applicants, it's a reason not to apply.
Over the weekend, New York University announced a change in how it handles the answer to that question. Students will still have to check that box, but admissions officers won't see it right away.
Applicants to the school will initially be reviewed without any knowledge of criminal records, explains MJ Knoll-Finn, the vice president for enrollment management at NYU.
Admissions officers are trained to be unbiased, Knoll-Finn says, but not knowing the criminal history in that first round of selection will be an added help. After that, a special committee will determine whether there's anything of concern. The process aims to allow NYU a chance to preserve safety on campus, while not ruling out applicants for youthful mistakes.
"We believe in second chances," says Knoll-Finn.
A majority of colleges do ask about criminal histories  some 20 percent don't, according to the Center for Community Alternatives , an organization that advocates for alternatives to incarceration.
Asking about criminal backgrounds has little to do with actual safety concerns, says Marsha Weissman, the group's executive director.
"People of color are much more likely to be arrested, convicted," she says. "What this is really doing is undermining campus diversity goals."
Weissman co-authored a report, released earlier this year, that surveyed screening policies in the State University of New York system  which is separate from NYU. The report found nearly two-thirds who had a felony conviction were discouraged by that one question. "When they see the question, they say  'I'm not gonna get in.' "
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Higher-Tech Fake Eggs Offer Better Clues To Wild-Bird Behavior</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2015/05/26/409730987/higher-tech-fake-eggs-offer-better-clues-to-wild-bird-behavior?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Faux eggs made with 3-D printers are better than sculpted versions, researchers say, because it's easier to systematically vary their size, weight and other features. Next goal: 3-D fragile shells.</Description>
        <MainBody>Higher-Tech Fake Eggs Offer Better Clues To Wild-Bird Behavior
May 26, 2015 4:23 PM ET
One of these things is not like the other: A 3-D printed model of a beige cowbird egg stands out from its robin's egg nest mates, though their shape and heft are similar. Ana Lopez/Courtesy of Mark Hauber hide caption
itoggle caption Ana Lopez/Courtesy of Mark Hauber
One of these things is not like the other: A 3-D printed model of a beige cowbird egg stands out from its robin's egg nest mates, though their shape and heft are similar.
Ana Lopez/Courtesy of Mark Hauber
Since the 1960s, biologists have made fake eggs for some studies of bird behavior. But Mark Hauber of Hunter College in New York says this kind of scientific handicraft is not exactly his forte.
"With 3-D printing, it's the possibility of being able to make exactly what you want. And not only that, but you can share those designs with other researchers, so they can replicate your results with exactly the same methods."
- Christie Riehl, biologist, Princeton University
"I'm a terrible craftsperson," he admits.
That's why Hauber is pioneering the use of 3-D printing technology to quickly produce made-to-order fake eggs, taking a bit of old-school science into the 21st century.
Researchers traditionally have made artificial eggs for experiments out of wood or clay or plaster, and then painstakingly painted them. But Hauber says his plaster of Paris eggs look awful. "They look like pears instead of eggs."
The particular eggs that interest him are the speckled eggs of cowbirds. Like cuckoos, these birds lay their eggs in the nests of other species. Sometimes the eggs get accepted, but sometimes they get tossed out of the nest. Scientists want to understand how birds perceive the eggs and what characteristics make the difference.
"It could be the size, it could be speckling itself or the lack thereof, and it could be the color  beige versus robin blue," Hauber explains.
All of this and more can be tested with fake eggs, he says. "Instead of using natural eggs, it's best to use fake eggs, because you can control the size, and shape and the color much more accurately."
i
A 3-D printer can turn out any number of identical faux eggs of nearly any shape or size. Such uniformity is crucial in replicating science studies and is tough to achieve when each of the fakes is handcrafted, the old-fashioned way. Courtesy of Mark Hauber hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Mark Hauber
A 3-D printer can turn out any number of identical faux eggs of nearly any shape or size. Such uniformity is crucial in replicating science studies and is tough to achieve when each of the fakes is handcrafted, the old-fashioned way.
Courtesy of Mark Hauber
Hauber remembers his first fake egg.
"In 1997, I went into a craft store and bought a beige speckled egg, which looks very much like a cowbird egg," he says, recalling that it was actually an Easter decoration. He put it in the nest of a gray catbird, which promptly tossed it out.
But usually, the right egg for a particular experiment can't be found in a store, and researchers have to make it themselves.
So when affordable 3-D printers became available, Hauber was intrigued. These machines generally create objects in plastic that are based on computer models of the object. Hauber bought a 3-D printer and tested its ability to make a fake egg.
"I loved it," he says. "It had the shape of a cowbird egg, because we designed it as such. It had the weight of a cowbird egg." Plus, he adds, the process was standardized, so they could print as many identical eggs as they wanted. His lab has now made hundreds of fake eggs in the printer.
Hauber and his colleagues published a study in the current issue of the journal PeerJ showing that robins, at least, treat the printed eggs like real cowbird eggs  at least when the shells aren't painted robin's egg blue.
Christie Riehl , a biologist at Princeton University, was impressed by this study because it used a whole range of fake cowbird eggs  from small round ones to long skinny ones.
"You can imagine, it would be really labor-intensive and time-intensive to individually handcraft eggs that exploit that whole range of variation," Riehl says, "and it would be very difficult to find commercially available eggs  like even wooden eggs or something  that would have the properties of size and shape that you're trying to test."
She speaks from experience; Riehl has personally made dozens of eggs the old-fashioned way. She's excited by the potential of this technology, not just for fake eggs, but for all sorts of knickknacks needed in experiments.
"With 3-D printing, it's the possibility of being able to make exactly what you want," Riehl says. "And not only that, but you can share those designs with other researchers so they can replicate your results with exactly the same methods."
The printed eggs aren't perfect yet. The colors aren't great  scientists still have to paint them.
And while Hauber has been able to print hollow eggs, the plastic shells are currently too strong to be pierced by a bird's beak. That's important, because piercing an egg is how some species get rid of it.
Hauber is now dreaming of somehow creating an egg that can be punctured. He's noticed some sugar-shelled treats that chefs make, shaped like eggs and filled with ice cream.
Those fake eggs have "a very fragile shell," he says, "so I might try that technique."
But he's also still trying to do it with his 3-D printer.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blind Waiters Give Diners A Taste Of 'Dinner In The Dark' In Kenya</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/05/26/408796172/blind-waiters-give-diners-a-taste-of-dinner-in-the-dark-in-kenya?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>It's a worldwide chain that lets "the blind become our eyes." But there's a difference in the new Nairobi branch: The servers themselves had never eaten in a restaurant before.</Description>
        <MainBody>Blind Waiters Give Diners A Taste Of 'Dinner In The Dark' In Kenya
May 26, 2015 4:22 PM ET
At the "Dinner in the Dark" restaurant that's just opened in Nairobi, a blind waiter leads guests to their table. The photo was taken during a training session  that's why the lights are on. Courtesy of is Eatout.co.ke hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of is Eatout.co.ke
At the "Dinner in the Dark" restaurant that's just opened in Nairobi, a blind waiter leads guests to their table. The photo was taken during a training session  that's why the lights are on.
Courtesy of is Eatout.co.ke
Ignatius Agon practices his greeting: "OK, good evening ladies and gentlemen. My name is Ignatius and I am going to guide you into the dark."
It's Monday, and the first day of training for a new restaurant opening this month in Kenya. Diners will be served in the dark. They'll have to find their food with their forks and eat it in a pitch black room.
And the waiters are blind.
Welcome to Dinner in the Dark , a franchise founded in Paris in 2004. The chain says it wants to help people "re-evaluate [their] sense of taste and smell" and let "the blind become our eyes." It's served more than 1 million customers around the world. Now it's opening its first restaurant in Africa.
Close embed modal
&lt;iframe src="http://www.npr.org/player/embed/4529325/4529326" width="100%" height="290" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;
The new eatery is called Gizani  that's Swahili for "in the dark." It served its first meals last weekend in Kenya's capital city of Nairobi.
At this training session, Agon, who is blind, has to lead six people in a conga line into the dining room, find their table and seat them. "Just come with me," he says. "And I promise you're going to enjoy your dinner in the dark."
But Agon is about to get lost.
For training purposes, the lights are on so I can see him losing his way and bumping into walls.
"Please, I'm sorry for the inconvenience," he says, right before he bumps into a speaker.
A thud rings across the room.
"Yeah, we're now at the table," he says.
"No," says Ghow Ratnarajah, who flew in from London to train the new staff. "You're at the wrong table apparently."
Ratnarajah, who's also blind, is less critical of Agon for getting lost than he is for his social faux pas  calling customers "my friend" instead of "sir" or "ma'am," touching them anywhere except their arm and shoulder.
"Why are you touching my tummy?" Ratnarajah asks.
This exercise is challenging for Agon in a way that I can't see. Agon, who lost his sight to meningitis at age 10, has almost never been to a restaurant himself. It's too expensive. So he doesn't have that waiterly spiel running in his head. But he's not intimidated.
"Let me tell you, if someone comes, I serve him so well, I talk to him good," he says. "He will say ... 'Today I have been served by a blind man! Yeah. In a very big restaurant.' "
On Day 2 of training, Jennifer Wanjira is learning to keep track of the orders coming in and the plates going out.
"Jennifer, copy," she says into a walkie-talkie, which the servers need to take orders in the blackness.
Wanjira gets instructions from Fabrice Roszczka, who has flown in from Paris to help with training.
"Four surprise on top, round plate, OK," he says to her.
Meat dishes are served on round plates; vegetarian, on square ones.
"Hello, sir, how are you?" she says as she brings out the dishes. But Wanjira gets so nervous keeping track of it all that she serves a round plate directly into the back of someone's skull.
She gasps: "Oh my God! Sorry."
"OK, OK," Roszczka says. "You know you're here to learn, you know?"
Yes, she responds.
The Nairobi franchise is run by Abdul Kamara, a 35-year-old blind lawyer from Sierra Leone and the U.S. "We're training 12 blind individuals to be professionals in the hospitality industry," he says. "That will get them far."
Twelve jobs mean something in a country where unemployment among the blind is officially 98 percent. In the U.S., it's around 75 percent. And in Kenya there's neither social security nor income help for people with disabilities.
So blindness in Kenya often means total dependence on your family. Wanjira lost her sight seven years ago from untreated Type I diabetes. She lost her job, and her husband left her. Since then she's always had to beg for help.
But now it's different. "Now I'm helping another person," she beams. "I'm guiding somebody else. I've never guided anybody!"
She'll earn her first paycheck since going blind. When I ask what she'll spend it on, she says she'd like to pay it forward and cover someone else's school fees. Or perhaps she'll pay the hospital bill for someone.
"Wait," I respond. "That's what you want to spend your salary on?"
She cuts me off. "Yeah! Or even buy someone a blanket," she says. "For me that has been my dream."
Despite the accident with the plate, she doesn't worry. She's used to learning her way in the dark. The greater challenge is learning all the etiquette of eating out. The customers Gizani expects to attract are embassy staff and U.N. workers, expats and Kenyan professionals.
"People in high places," she says with a laugh. "They're not poor."
At the last training day, there's a dress rehearsal with real customers. After all this training, the careful orchestration of the meal, there's a final serenade by all the waiters in the dark.
First someone starts off. Then the chorus follows: "Malaika, nakupenda Malaika."
"Angel, I love you, Angel."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Photographer Mary Ellen Mark Dies At 75</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/26/409806219/photographer-mary-ellen-mark-dies-at-75?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The influential photographer was known mostly for her humanist work.</Description>
        <MainBody>Photographer Mary Ellen Mark Dies At 75
May 26, 2015 4:10 PM ET
Photographer Mary Ellen Mark attends the Leica Los Angeles grand opening on June 20, 2013. Mark died Monday. She was 75. Todd Williamson/Invision for Leica hide caption
itoggle caption Todd Williamson/Invision for Leica
Photographer Mary Ellen Mark attends the Leica Los Angeles grand opening on June 20, 2013. Mark died Monday. She was 75.
Todd Williamson/Invision for Leica
Mary Ellen Mark, the influential photographer known mostly for her humanist work, has died. She was 75.
Mark died Monday, a representative said Tuesday. The Philadelphia Inquirer reported that she died in New York.
Mark's work appeared in Life, New York Times Magazine, Rolling Stone and Vanity Fair. Her photo essay on runaway children in Seattle became the basis of Streetwise, an Academy Award-nominated film that was directed by her husband, Martin Bell.
Courtesy of Mary Ellen Mark Studio and Library
1 of 6
View slideshow i
In a 1988 interview with the Philadelphia Inquirer , Mark said she got her break while working for a Penn alumni magazine. On assignment, she met Pat Carbine, who then was managing editor of Look. Carbine later took Mark's pitch to photograph London drug clinics.
"From the very first moment I took pictures [on the streets of Philadelphia], I loved it," she told the Inquirer. "The thrill was the idea of just being on a street, turning a corner and looking for something to see. It was just an amazing feeling. ... Photography became my obsession. ... In a way it's not so different when I go out to work now. It's just that now I have years of experience in knowing how to use that little machine in front of me  at least better than I used it then. When it's good and interesting it's still that feeling of being on the street and wondering  God, I love this!  what's going to happen next?"
NPR, in a 2005 review of her work , called her "a brilliant and fearless artist," adding: "Mark's highly celebrated work is sad, spectacular, desperate, disturbing and so much who we are."
In 2012, Mark spoke to NPR about her book Prom, a collection of 127 portraits from 13 schools across the country, shot between 2006 and 2009. You can listen to that interview here :
NPR's Neda Ulaby is reporting on Mark's legacy on Wednesday's Morning Edition . Please tune in to your local public radio station to listen.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Prolific Fantasy And Science-Fiction Writer Tanith Lee Has Died</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/26/409726390/prolific-fantasy-and-science-fiction-writer-tanith-lee-has-died?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Lee wrote dozens of books, including </Description>
        <MainBody>Prolific Fantasy And Science-Fiction Writer Tanith Lee Has Died
May 26, 2015 4:00 PM ET
Twitter
British science-fiction and fantasy writer Tanith Lee has died, according to her publisher. Lee, 67, was a prolific author who also worked in radio and television; her dozens of books include Don't Bite The Sun and Death's Master  the latter of which was part of her popular Flat Earth series.
The writer's death was reported early Tuesday by the website Sci-Fi Bulletin and Tor.com , a website run by the publishing house. Her official website was updated Tuesday to show only the dates of her birth and death and a passage of text that includes the line, "Till the sky falls, and all things are flawless and need no words at all."
Lee "died peacefully in her sleep May 24, 2015 after a long illness," according to Locus magazine .
More details have not emerged; in 2010, Lee revealed she had been treated for breast cancer on at least two occasions.
At the time, she wrote , "So far though, I am clear, if losing lots of time back on the hospital-test-X ray carousel. I may, and could, flourish for years to come. But once more, I don't know how long I've got. As it says in the wonderful Blade Runner, 'Who does?' "
A highly decorated writer, Lee was nominated for two Nebula Awards, and many of her short stories, novels and anthologies were nominated for and/or won the World Fantasy Award. In 1980, Death's Master won the British Fantasy Society's August Derleth Award as the best novel of the genre.
Lee also wrote several children's books, including Piratica, and wrote two episodes of the British sci-fi TV series Blake's 7. Her book Don't Bite The Sun was nominated as a finalist for NPR's list of the 100 best science-fiction and fantasy books .
Lee's work ranged from tales set in historic Venice to vampire stories and re-imagined folklore. In other stories, she blended modern life with elements of horror and magic. Her books, and hundreds of short stories, came despite dyslexia, which delayed her reading. She told Locus magazine in 1998:
"When I started as a writer, I knew nothing about publishing  nothing about anything! I didn't learn to read until I was nearly eight. My father had to teach me. My mother used to tell me fairy stories, most of which she made up herself, which were wonderful  and many of which I've ripped off for things, subsequently! When I was nine, about a year after I learned how to read, I started to write."
Lee also told Locus about her unique handwriting style:
"I have to write longhand, and no one can read my writing, I have to type my own manuscripts, because I'm going almost in a zigzag, across and then down. (I don't write backwards, I've never been able to do that!) Fortunately, it's not like a circus trick where, when they try to work out how they did it, they're unable to do it. If I can't see something enough, I shut my eyes and look at it, and I don't feel I am writing  I'm there.
"I used to throw away my holograph manuscripts after I'd typed them, but I'm keeping a lot of them now, because obviously, at 50, I'm starting to think, if anyone ever is interested in me after I'm dead, they can look and see, 'My god, this woman was a maniac!' "
Lee is survived by her husband, John Kaiine, an artist and writer whose previous jobs included gravedigger.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Despite An Economy On The Rise, American Paychecks Remain Stuck </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/itsallpolitics/2015/05/26/408555544/despite-economic-climb-american-paychecks-remain-stuck?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>NPR's "Day 1" series looks at major issues the next president will face in office. One issue is that Americans still aren't seeing big raises, even though the job market is slowly recovering.</Description>
        <MainBody>Despite An Economy On The Rise, American Paychecks Remain Stuck
May 26, 2015 3:53 PM ET
Seattle Space Needle elevator operator Michael Hall says despite the success of the attraction, his pay hasn't budged in four years. Ted S. Warren/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Ted S. Warren/AP
Seattle Space Needle elevator operator Michael Hall says despite the success of the attraction, his pay hasn't budged in four years.
Ted S. Warren/AP
As candidates hit the campaign trail, NPR looks at four major issues the next president will face from Day 1 in office.
Hall holding a sign that reads "I deserve a raise" as part of a petition drive organized by his union. Courtesy Michael Hall hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy Michael Hall
Hall holding a sign that reads "I deserve a raise" as part of a petition drive organized by his union.
Courtesy Michael Hall
For seven years, Michael Hall has been guiding tourists to the top of Seattle's Space Needle and back. It's a unique vantage point from which to watch the ups and downs of Americans' paychecks.
At first, the 30-year-old elevator operator shared in the success of the popular attraction. He got regular raises, thanks to a union contract. Then the contract ran out. Hall's pay hasn't budged in the past four years.
At first, Hall said, "I could put some money into savings every check. Still go out, grab a beer. But after about two or three years, suddenly it was like there's seven of us in a house. And then finally I started to find myself, about a year ago, living paycheck to paycheck."
It's a familiar story. Most Americans still aren't seeing big raises, even though the job market is slowly recovering.
In April, the official unemployment rate dropped below 5.5 percent for the first time in seven years. But the problem of stagnant wages goes back a lot further. Since 1979, average wages have barely kept pace with inflation.
John Pallaoro, a self-employed truck driver, says his paychecks stretched further four decades ago.
"I was able to purchase a suburban house in the mid-'70s for the price of barely one year of wages, two years at the most," Pallaoro recalled. "My standard of living is probably reduced by 50 percent from 40 years ago."
Stagnant wages aren't just a problem for individuals. When workers like Hall and Pallaoro don't have money to spend, it's a drag on the whole economy.
Experts point to a variety of causes for wage stagnation, including sluggish productivity growth. In the first decades after World War II, Americans' productivity climbed steadily, nearly 3 percent every year. But in the mid-'70s, that growth downshifted to less than 2 percent.
"One obvious lesson is it's better to be growing fast than to be growing slow," said James Pethokoukis, an economic policy scholar at the conservative American Enterprise Institute.
"The default Republican position would be you need to reduce taxes, you need to reduce spending so more of America's economic resources are being run by the private sector," he said. "And that would boost economic growth."
Other proposals such as education reform and increased investment in public works are also intended to boost productivity. But that's not the only challenge.
Since the 1970s, there's been a disconnect between productivity and wages, so even as workers produce more, they don't necessarily see the benefits.
"We have created lots of income, lots of output, lots of wealth over the last three decades," said Larry Mishel, president of the left-of-center Economic Policy Institute. "The problem is it has not accrued to the vast majority."
Virtually all of the gains have gone to those at the top of the income scale. In the past, politicians have sometimes tried to address that through the tax code: taking a slightly larger cut from the wealthy and using tax credits to pad the pockets of the poor. But there are political limits to that approach. Some people consider such government redistribution akin to adding or taking away points after the whistle has blown. Mishel and others argue that policymakers need to focus more on shaping the rules of the economic game, so average workers can command higher pretax wages.
"The problems with people's paychecks is not what the federal government is taking out in taxes. It's what employers are not putting in," Mishel said.
Elevator operator Hall agrees. He complains that while his paycheck has flat-lined for the past four years, business at the Space Needle has been up, up, up.
"We're busier than we ever were," Hall said. "One full elevator, that pays most of us working for the day. And we'll do that 100 times. It's sort of insulting that they can't afford to keep paying us enough to live in the city."
There is one stretch in the past 35 years that offers a glimmer of hope for struggling workers. That's the late 1990s  a period when not only was the economy growing fast but the gains were widely shared, so workers on every rung of the economic ladder were climbing together.
What Will The Next President Face On #Day1?
"What was distinct about that period can be summarized in two words: full employment," said economist Jared Bernstein of the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. "Or maybe three words: very full employment."
Unemployment in the late '90s was below 5 percent. Some months it fell below 4 percent. That gave workers everywhere lots of leverage to demand higher wages.
Short of full employment, Bernstein says, there are other policies that could boost workers' bargaining power, including a higher minimum wage, steps to make it easier for unions to organize, and immigration policies that limit the growth of a shadow workforce.
Many of those policies will be debated over the next year and a half by those who seek to occupy the White House. As the U.S. economic elevator starts to climb again, a central challenge for the next president will be making sure more American families aren't stuck on the bottom floor.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
