<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At Least 27 Dead After Attack On Hotel At Tunisian Beach Resort</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/26/417704593/19-dead-after-gunman-attacks-hotel-at-tunisian-beach-resort?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Interior Ministry officials report that at least one assailant opened fire on a hotel in the popular resort of Sousse.</Description>
        <MainBody>At Least 27 Dead After Attack On Hotel At Tunisian Beach Resort
June 26, 2015 8:29 AM ET
Twitter
A pair of gunmen attacked a tourist hotel on the popular Tunisian beachfront resort of Sousse, killing at least 27 people, including foreigners, according to the North African country's interior ministry.
The Associated Press quotes Interior Ministry spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui as saying Tunisian security forces had killed one of the attackers and that the other had fled the scene.
The AP said there were no details of the nationalities of those killed, but noted that during the holy month of Ramadan, beach-goers tend to be tourists, not locals.
British tourist Gary Pine tells Sky News that he was on the beach when he heard what he and others thought was firecrackers going off nearby.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he said, as reported by the AP.
Pine said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms and later, to gather in the lobby.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:16:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Report: ISIS Goes Door-To-Door Killing Scores Of Civilians In Kobani</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/26/417702031/report-isis-goes-door-to-door-killing-scores-of-civilians-in-kobani?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights calls the killing a massacre and says it is the worst such incident carried out by ISIS fighters since last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>i
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey on Friday. An attack by Islamic State fighters on the Syrian town of Kobani and a nearby village has so far killed at least 146 civilians, the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday. Murad Sezer/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Murad Sezer/Reuters/Landov
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey on Friday. An attack by Islamic State fighters on the Syrian town of Kobani and a nearby village has so far killed at least 146 civilians, the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Murad Sezer/Reuters/Landov
Fighters of the self-declared Islamic State have killed some 146 people in a house-to-house massacre of civilians in the Syrian border town of Kobani, a conflict monitoring group says, calling it the second-worse such mass killing by the Islamist extremists since last year.
NPR's Deborah Amos, reporting from southern Turkey, says the Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights has spoken to witnesses who reported the shooting spree.
Citing medical sources in Kobani, the Syrian Observatory said the civilians "were executed by [the Islamic State] in their homes or killed by the group's rockets or snipers," Rami Abdel Rahman, the Observatory's director said. The group said that militants "fired at everything that moved."
The Associated Press quotes Kobani-based Kurdish activist Mustafa Bali as saying "that small groups of jihadis are still in the town and have taken civilians hostage in at least three locations." At a restaurant where hostages had been taken, Kurdish fighters stormed the building and freed the captives, Bali told the AP.
"The militants launched twin attacks on Thursday, in Kobani, also farther east in one of the last government held areas in northern Syria," Deborah says. "More than 60,000 people are now displaced, according to the United Nations [and] another 200,000 may yet flee as ISIS fights take over areas formerly held by the regime" of Bashar al-Assad.
The reported massacre comes a day after the Islamic State launched an attack to recapture the city after being forced out in January after fierce battles with Kurdish fighters.
Kurdish officials say ISIS militants secretly infiltrated the town by wearing Syrian rebel uniforms and carrying flags of the Free Syrian Army.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man Beheaded In Terrorist Attack On French Factory</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/26/417696368/man-beheaded-at-french-factory-in-apparent-isis-attack?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Police have arrested one suspect over the attack, which also included an explosion at the facility operated by Air Products, an American company.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man Beheaded In Terrorist Attack On French Factory
June 26, 2015 6:41 AM ET
French security and emergency services gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, the scene of an attack on an industrial gas factory Friday. Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
French security and emergency services gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, the scene of an attack on an industrial gas factory Friday.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
One person has been killed and at least 12 others injured in an attack on a gas factory in a small town in southeastern France. Officials say it was a terrorist attack: a flag of the self-declared Islamic State was reportedly found at the factory southeast of Lyon.
One suspect has been arrested over the attack, which also included an explosion at the facility operated by Air Products, an American company whose headquarters are in Pennsylvania. It's not yet certain whether he was acting alone.
"The terrorist nature of this act are without doubt," says French President Francois Hollande, who will return home today from a European Union economic summit in Brussels.
Update at 8:25 p.m. ET: Details On Victim, Vehicle
The person who was killed was the manager of a transport company who was making a delivery, according to local newspaper Dauphine Libere . The newspaper adds that the prefect of Isere, John Paul Bonnetain, says the attacking vehicle was authorized to enter the factory  giving support to the theory that the vehicle belonged to a contractor or supplier.
Dauphine Libere also reports that a second arrest has been made  of a person whose vehicle was seen repeatedly passing in front of the factory Friday morning  but that no direct link has been established between the events.
Update at 7:25 p.m. ET: Suspect Had Been Monitored
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve says the suspect in the case, who is believed to have lived near Lyon, had no prior criminal record. He also said that the man had been monitored by authorities as far back as 2006, but he was found not to be in communication with terrorist groups.
Cazeneuve also stated that the suspect had been detained by a local firefighter who was among the first responders at the scene.
"I salute this courage," he said.
Our original post continues:
From Calais, NPR's Eleanor Beardsley reports:
"One or maybe two men rammed the gates of a gas factory in the small industrial town. An explosion followed. The man killed was beheaded, and his head was placed at the front of the factory along with a flag of the so-called Islamic State.
"Residents of the small town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier interviewed on television expressed shock that such an attack could take place in their tiny town."
According to its website, Air Products specializes in producing industrial and medical gases, listing oxygen, nitrogen, argon, helium and hydrogen as its chief products.
France's interior minister has ordered increased security at other potential targets around the country.
Speaking about the attack, Hollande said, "Our answer is prevention, deterrence and thus the necessity of embracing values and not giving in to fear, ever."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:04:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrants In French Camp Near English Channel Attempt To Get Into Britain</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/26/417675817/migrants-in-french-camp-near-english-channel-attempt-to-get-into-britain?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>European leaders are meeting in Brussels Friday to deal with the migrant crisis. At a squalid camp in northern France, migrants plot to stow away on trucks to cross the English Channel into Britain.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrants In French Camp Near English Channel Attempt To Get Into Britain
June 26, 2015 5:04 AM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:04:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kosovo: The Pros And Cons Of Being Europe's Newest Country</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/26/417675810/kosovo-the-pros-and-cons-of-being-europe-s-newest-country?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>America played a major role in Kosovo's fight for independence. Now, seven years after its emergence as a country, Kosovo suffers growing pains with more than half the young people unemployed.</Description>
        <MainBody>
You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Showdown Looms At South Korea's Gay Pride Parade</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/06/26/417310709/a-showdown-looms-at-south-koreas-gay-pride-parade?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In Seoul, a parade that has gone on for 15 years is at the heart of a bitter standoff between organizers and Christian activists. Church groups threaten to stop the parade — in the name of God.</Description>
        <MainBody>A Showdown Looms At South Korea's Gay Pride Parade
June 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET
A religious activist is carried away by police after he tried to stop a gay pride parade in Seoul last year. Christian activists are planning to disrupt the parade again this year. Ed Jones/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Ed Jones/AFP/Getty Images
A religious activist is carried away by police after he tried to stop a gay pride parade in Seoul last year. Christian activists are planning to disrupt the parade again this year.
Ed Jones/AFP/Getty Images
In Seoul, a gay pride parade 15 years in the running is at the center of heated controversy between LGBT groups and Christian activists, who threaten to do what it takes to stop the marchers.
The growing visibility of South Korea's gays and lesbians has led to louder opposition from church groups in recent years, and this weekend's event has organizers preparing for confrontation.
"In the Bible, homosexuality is sin. And to publicize your personal, private identity like that is a problem," says Pastor Jonah Lee of Calvary Church in Seoul. He is part of the religious opposition to gay culture, and calls himself formerly gay  cured of 43 years of homosexuality.
Gay rights in South Korea have become so contentious that at a pride month kickoff event earlier in June, more anti-gay protesters showed up than LGBT participants.
The Christian groups blared a Korean version of the Battle Hymn of the Republic to try and drown out pride event speakers. They also handed out leaflets, shouted into megaphones, and held up signs with messages like "Homosexuality will destroy humanity."
"Churches oppose the festival and parade because it's too decadent," says Lee. "Korea is not as open and free so as you could walk around with your bottom hanging out like that."
Public polls seem to back up the pastor. A Pew Research Center survey on moral issues found that 57 percent of South Koreans thought that homosexuality was unacceptable, while 18 percent said it was acceptable.
Disruptions Last Year
At last year's parade, Christian protesters laid down in the streets, singing songs and stalling LGBT marchers for hours. This year, religious groups tried to stop the parade from happening at all. They flooded the police with permit applications to rally on the same day as the pride parade. It jammed up the permitting process, leading the Seoul Police to ban the parade altogether , citing safety reasons.
But a court last week overturned the ban  upholding the LGBT group's right to assemble.
"Everybody has a right to protest, including the religious groups. What they don't have the right to do is to stop other people gathering in the way that they express themselves," says Graeme Reid. He's the LGBT rights director for Human Rights Watch.
"As there's progress on one level, and in this instance, internationally, we see an overall trend toward more inclusive policies. But then, we often see a reaction to those gains. And I think that's what we're seeing in South Korea," Reid says.
Now, all eyes turn to Sunday, when as many as 20,000 are expected to turn out for the parade and festivities around it. Organizers  like Kang Myeong-jin  say they have to prepare for confrontation.
"There's the possibility of unpredicted behaviors from the haters. And their sole purpose is to stop the parade, but it's a matter of how they're going to stop it, what they're going to do, so we need to prepare against that," Kang says.
Organizers have warned participants to be ready for flying objects, long stalls along the route and other potential safety hazards. For his part, the pastor says he doesn't condone physical or violent confrontations.
"Extreme measures to LGBT parades will only breed social conflict. I try to convince the church on this matter, but I get a lot of contempt from them," Lee says.
HaeRyun Kang contributed to this story. For behind-the-scenes photos and observations from our Seoul bureau, check out our East Asia Tumblr, Elise Goes East .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Polio Is Active In Only 3 Countries. Soon It Could Be Down To 2</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/06/26/417113319/polio-is-active-in-only-3-countries-soon-it-could-be-down-to-2?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Nigeria is one of three places where polio is still a problem. But there hasn't been a case in almost a year. So Africa is on the verge of being polio-free.</Description>
        <MainBody>Polio Is Active In Only 3 Countries. Soon It Could Be Down To 2
June 26, 2015 4:58 AM ET
At the health clinic in Minjibir, Nigeria, a child is immunized for polio. David Gilkey/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption David Gilkey/NPR
At the health clinic in Minjibir, Nigeria, a child is immunized for polio.
David Gilkey/NPR
Nigeria is on the verge of being polio-free. And that would mean that for the first time ever there's no ongoing polio transmission on the African continent.
Nigeria is one of just three countries in the world, along with Pakistan and Afghanistan, where polio transmission has never been fully stopped. But no trace of the virus has been found in Nigeria since a child was paralyzed with the disease on July 24, 2014. If the West African nation reaches a full year with no new cases, the World Health Organization will strike Nigeria off the list of countries with active polio transmission.
"It would be a major milestone in the global polio eradication initiative," says Hamid Jafari, the head of polio eradication at WHO in Geneva.
Over the last 20 years Nigeria has been the primary obstacle to eradicating polio on the African continent. Every other African nation managed to extinguish polio at one point or another, but many of those countries were hit with new outbreaks linked to polio from Nigeria.
Nigeria didn't just fail to vaccinate children. At times communities actively fought polio immunization campaigns. Religious leaders denounced the vaccination drops as part of a Western plot to sterilize Muslim children. Vaccinators were shot and killed.
"They [Nigerian health officials] did not have the political commitment," says Jon Andrus, the executive vice president of the Sabin Vaccine Institute. Andrus spent 30 years working on polio eradication for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the World Health Organization, including in Nigeria.
"They did not have good supervision and management of field staff," he says. "They did not have the engagement of the community probably the most important factor in making sure all children get vaccinated."
He says 15 years ago Nigeria was an incredibly frustrating place to work. Andrus remembers meeting with politicians in Northern Nigeria back in 2001 and finally getting the governor to agree to launch a polio vaccination campaign.
"Sure enough a month later the government refused to do the campaign and then Nigeria started exporting the viruses to the rest of Africa so it was quite a setback,"
Nigeria came under huge international pressure to get polio under control. Aid agencies used carrots and sticks and shame to try to get the West African nation to contain the virus. They promised additional international funds for other pressing health needs. but the additional assistance was contingent on Nigeria tackling polio. Local religious leaders were courted, wooed and cajoled in to supporting the vaccination campaigns.
Then the public had to be brought on board too. At one point the Emir of Kano publicly immunized his own children and drank a vial of polio vaccine to prove it was safe.
Hamid Jafari, the polio chief at the WHO, doesn't want to declare victory too quickly. He speaks like a man afraid he might jinx this whole thing. Nigeria's come close to wiping out polio before. In 2010 the West African nation had just 21 cases only to see the virus come roaring back.
"We are not yet certain that the wild polio virus is gone from the African continent," he says. "We have not yet completed the full surveillance time of 12 months in Nigeria. And there are areas in the African region in the northeast of Nigeria, Lake Chad, the north of Cameroon where the situation is uncertain security-wise. We may have undetected transmission of polio virus there."
In parts of northern Nigeria controlled by Boko Haram it's impossible for health officials to vaccinate children or monitor for new cases of polio. Jafari says polio could possibly be spreading undetected in some pockets.
Even if the last reservoirs of polio on the African continent have been wiped out, Jafari says mass polio vaccination campaigns will have to continue globally until the virus is stopped completely in Afghanistan and Pakistan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Army Begins Training Ukrainian Soldiers</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/06/25/417511636/u-s-army-begins-training-ukrainian-soldiers?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The U.S. won't give the Ukrainian army lethal weapons to fight separatists and their Russian allies, but it has sent 300 trainers to help the beleaguered, bedraggled Ukrainian military.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. Army Begins Training Ukrainian Soldiers
June 25, 2015 5:50 PM ET
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice protecting and recovering wounded comrades as American military trainers watch. Corey Flintoff/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Corey Flintoff/NPR
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice protecting and recovering wounded comrades as American military trainers watch.
Corey Flintoff/NPR
Fighting surged again this week in eastern Ukraine, where government troops are battling separatist militias and their Russian allies.
NATO is responding by sending troops and equipment to eastern Europe, and it's also giving defensive training to Ukraine's beleaguered army.
First, you need to know how bad things were for the Ukrainian army when separatist militias and their Russian allies began the fight in eastern Ukraine in April 2014.
Miroslav Gai volunteered for the army last winter.
I met him in Kiev, and this is how he described its state of readiness: "The army gave me just my weapon and uniform, and bring me with my friends to Slovyansk and say, 'OK, fight.' "
Gai saw many of his friends killed around the eastern city of Slovyansk in the winter and spring of 2014. He says he wouldn't have survived without food and warm clothing provided by volunteers from Kiev.
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice skills shared by U.S. trainers. A U.S. brigade commander says the mission is as much a learning experience for the Americans as it is for the Ukrainians. Corey Flintoff/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Corey Flintoff/NPR
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice skills shared by U.S. trainers. A U.S. brigade commander says the mission is as much a learning experience for the Americans as it is for the Ukrainians.
Corey Flintoff/NPR
He now runs a volunteer foundation that helps supply Ukrainian soldiers with body armor and clothing.
The Ukrainian military says it's doing everything it can to make its army combat-ready.
That's happening on a sprawling base and firing range near the Polish border.
I'm here to watch about 300 American paratroopers from the U.S. Army's 173rd Airborne Brigade, who've arrived to work with about 750 Ukrainian national guardsmen.
Practice ranges on all sides of us are crackling with weapons fire, everything from hand grenades to heavy machine guns.
"Part of what we really want to do here is just to help these guys in terms of survivability, in terms of flexibility," says Army Capt. Steven Modugno.
He says the Americans were surprised to find that most of their initial trainees already had combat experience in the war in eastern Ukraine.
Two Ukrainian soldiers in the first group, he says, were actually decorated war heroes from their service in the east.
Modugno says what started as basic infantry training quickly grew more complex, when the trainees started asking questions like, "When we know that there's a potentially hostile drone monitoring us, how do we react?"
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For Poland's Gay Community, A Shift In Public Attitudes, If Not Laws</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/06/25/417446107/for-polands-gay-community-a-shift-in-public-attitudes-if-not-laws?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Poland does not allow gay marriage or same-sex unions, and is unlikely to amend these laws anytime soon. But the city of Gdansk elected an openly gay mayor and has hosted its first gay pride march.</Description>
        <MainBody>For Poland's Gay Community, A Shift In Public Attitudes, If Not Laws
June 25, 2015 5:09 PM ET
Marchers carried a multicolor flag during Warsaw's annual gay pride parade earlier this month. Poland prohibits gay marriage but activists say attitudes toward gays have improved in recent years. Alik Keplicz/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Alik Keplicz/AP
Marchers carried a multicolor flag during Warsaw's annual gay pride parade earlier this month. Poland prohibits gay marriage but activists say attitudes toward gays have improved in recent years.
Alik Keplicz/AP
Around the world, gay marriage is allowed in more than 20 countries. Many European Union nations are enhancing rights for their gay, bisexual and transgender citizens. But Catholic Poland isn't one of them.
This former Soviet satellite constitutionally restricts marriage to a man and a woman. Recent efforts to pass laws to protect the LGBT community in Poland from discrimination and violence have gone nowhere.
But there is one notable change these days  in Polish attitudes.
Ireland Votes Overwhelmingly To Approve Same-Sex Marriage
The Polish city of Gdansk, on the country's Pomeranian coast, is famous for being first. World War II is widely regarded as having started here in 1939. So did the Solidarity workers' movement of the 1980s, which helped precipitate the demise of the Soviet Union.
Last month, Gdansk celebrated another first  a gay rights march that attracted about 1,000 participants.
"Gdansk is a symbol of freedom," says psychologist Marta Kosinska, who helped organize the event. "And we are fighting for freedom, too."
Yet even two years ago, a gay rights march in this city would have been unthinkable.
At that time, its most famous native  Polish democracy icon Lech Walesa, founder of the Solidarity movement  said on TV that gays had no right to impose their will on the Polish majority. Nor should they play a prominent role in Polish politics, he added.
Homophobic attitudes were prevalent among Polish lawmakers when Robert Biedron was elected as a member of parliament back in 2011.
i
Slupsk Mayor Robert Biedron (from left) and LGBT activists Marta Abramowicz and Marta Kosinska stand next to a symbolic Gdansk lion statue painted in rainbow colors in honor of the city's first gay rights march, held in May. Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson/NPR
Slupsk Mayor Robert Biedron (from left) and LGBT activists Marta Abramowicz and Marta Kosinska stand next to a symbolic Gdansk lion statue painted in rainbow colors in honor of the city's first gay rights march, held in May.
Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson/NPR
"I was the first member of the Polish parliament who was openly gay," Biedron says, "and they would not be brave enough to shake hands publicly because somebody would think they're gay."
Nor did his colleagues take him seriously.
"I remember when I went to the parliament and had my first speech," he says. "I was defending one issue and I said, 'Your arguments are below the belt.' They all started to laugh. ... They thought I'm talking about sexuality. And when they asked them why they are laughing, they said, 'What else can a gay guy talk about?' "
But Biedron, 39, says attitudes toward gays are improving, in part because the Catholic Church's influence is shrinking in Poland and because more Poles are coming out of the closet.
Take, for example, Biedron's own successful run last year for mayor of the northern city of Slupsk. Biedron was one of about 30 gay candidates who ran in local races across Poland. He says his opponents never made his sexual orientation a campaign issue.
His partner of 12 years attended Biedron's swearing-in ceremony  the first time he's done so.
"To go finally with my partner for the public ceremony was one of the greatest things, and I had my mother with me," Biedron says.
Polish gay rights activists say there are other changes, too, including the opening of central Europe's first homeless shelter for LGBT teens earlier this year in Warsaw.
Marianna Szczygielska, the project coordinator for the Warsaw-based Campaign against Homophobia, says attitudes toward gays here began to change when Poland joined the European Union in 2004.
"Also with [the] opening of borders after joining the European Union, things have changed, especially for queer youth," she says. "Even LGBT characters being featured in popular TV series, that already makes a difference in social acceptance towards LGBT."
But the group's vice president, Miroslawa Makuchowska, fears that progress could be short-lived, as happened in Ukraine following the annexation of Crimea and the lingering war in the east.
"The public discourse [in Ukraine] has said, 'Look, you are not important right now. We cannot discuss gay issues right now. Stop talking about it.' It's all about the war."
She predicts that real equality for Poland's LGBT community could be generations away.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:37:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Cycling World May Soon Bow Down Before Nairo Quintana</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/06/25/417115274/the-cycling-world-may-soon-bow-down-before-nairo-quintana?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In 2013, a newcomer from Colombia passed almost everyone else and came in second in the Tour de France. This year, many think he'll take home the winning yellow jersey.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Cycling World May Soon Bow Down Before Nairo Quintana
June 25, 2015 4:37 PM ET
John Otis
Colombian cyclist Nairo Quintana poses for a snapshot during a training session this month in Colombia. LUIS ACOSTA/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption LUIS ACOSTA/AFP/Getty Images
Colombian cyclist Nairo Quintana poses for a snapshot during a training session this month in Colombia.
LUIS ACOSTA/AFP/Getty Images
He began biking to get to high school. The return trip was a 10-mile uphill slog. That didn't deter Nairo Quintana. Sometimes he'd even attach a cable to his sister's bike and haul her up the mountain with him.
And now some pundits think that the 25-year-old Colombian athlete could win the grueling, three-week Tour de France, which kicks off on July 4.
When Quintana was growing up, there were few signs he would become an elite athlete. He was raised on a farm 10,000 feet high in the Andes near the village of Combita. As a toddler he nearly died from a bad case of diarrhea. Rather than sports, he used his free time he helped his father, Luis, who raised cows and sold fruit and vegetables.
A Tour De France First: An African Team Will Compete This Year
His school bicycle commutes led him to competitive cycling. Soon, Nairo was winning local races on a second-hand clunker.
"You could earn up to $50 per race," he says. "There were two races per week. So that's $100. I would use the money to buy new parts for my bike."
The pint-sized Quintana weighs just 130 pounds but has a monster cardiovascular system. Jenaro Leguizamo, a Colombian sports trainer, once tested Quintana's VO2 max, which shows how efficiently athletes use oxygen and is a key performance indicator. He says the level was better than any of today's top cyclists.
As Nairo Quintana trains on a twisting mountain road, Colombian children cheer him on. When he stops to drink water, he's surrounded by fans who take souvenir photos.
Quintana first pedaled to glory in 2013. Riding in his first Tour de France when he was just 23, he came in second.
It was the highest-ever finish for a Latin American. Addressing Quintana, an ecstatic Colombian race announcer shouted: "The whole world bows down before you!"
Last year, Quintana became the first Latin American to win the Giro D'Italia, cycling's second most important road race.
It helps that Quintana grew up in a country with a strong network of cycling clubs and teams. In addition, Colombia is home to Latin America's oldest multistage bike race with mountain passes far higher than those in the Tour de France.
Colombia is the only Latin American nation that consistently produces world-class bike racers. One of the most famous  and gutsiest  was Luis Herrera.
In 1985, Herrera crashed on a descent. A TV announced reporter: "His eye is absolutely streaming with blood." But he hung on to win this mountain stage of the Tour de France, inspiring a generation of Colombian cyclists.
That's a role Quintana now fills. While following him in a taxi, we pull up beside a junior cyclist, 16-year-old Danilo Ardila. He's pedaling hard to catch up to Quintana.
"He's an example," Ardila says. "Everyone who rides a bike wants to be like him."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French Taxi Drivers Launch Nationwide Uber Protest</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/25/417516427/french-taxi-drivers-launch-nationwide-uber-protest?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>French taxi drivers stage a nationwide strike to protest UberPop's encroachment on their market.  It turned nasty after an Uber driver and passenger were beaten up.</Description>
        <MainBody>French Taxi Drivers Launch Nationwide Uber Protest
June 25, 2015 4:37 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tama, The Cat That Saved A Japanese Train Station, Dies</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417440765/tama-the-cat-that-saved-a-japanese-train-station-dies?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Tourists would come to the Kishi train station near Wakayama City to see the feline hanging out in her office — a converted ticket booth — wearing a railway hat and collar.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tama, The Cat That Saved A Japanese Train Station, Dies
June 25, 2015 2:55 PM ET
Tama had held sway as stationmaster of the Kishi train station since 2007. Toru Yamanaka/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Toru Yamanaka/AFP/Getty Images
Tama had held sway as stationmaster of the Kishi train station since 2007.
Toru Yamanaka/AFP/Getty Images
A calico cat in southeastern Japan has left some big paw prints to fill. Tama, who served as "stationmaster" of the Kishi train station near Wakayama City, died Monday from acute heart failure, according to CNN. She was 16 (about 80 in cat years), the network reports.
Tama is credited with saving the train station from financial ruin. Tourists would come to the station to see her hanging out in her office  a converted ticket booth  wearing a railway hat and collar. (A stationmaster is, generally, the human in charge of running the facility.)
@airlineflyer Hmm. You need to ride on Tama the cat train. #StationCat http://t.co/Vps0D6MEET pic.twitter.com/mn7XWJ3TNi
 Kevin-Economy&amp;Beyond (@EconomyBeyond) April 29, 2015
The railway system's president, Mitsonubu Kojima, said he visited Tama the day before she died and that she "stood up and let out a strong meow."
Tama's station is on the outskirts of Wakayama City, according to a CNN report in 2013. Aside from local residents, not many people traveled through the station. The current railway operator selected Tama, who was owned by a local family, as stationmaster in 2007 to try to bring in more travelers.
She had a noticeable impact, according to Kyodo News :
"The number of passengers on the line jumped to 2.27 million in fiscal 2014 from 1.92 million in fiscal 2005. Photos of Tama and other merchandise also sold well, leading to her appointment to acting president of Wakayama Electric Railway in January 2013."
Here's more from CNN's 2013 story:
"Kishi station currently houses a Tama-themed cafe, as well as a souvenir shop with items ranging from the usual array of pens, staplers and other supplies, to Kishi Station uniforms.
"Tama's cuteness is exploited wherever possible  from the chairs to the cakes in the cafe to the cat-shaped station building itself.
"There's also a cat stationmaster apprentice, Nitama, who shoulders some responsibilities for Tama. Sleeping and doing nothing is hard work, you know?"
A memorial service reportedly is set for Sunday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope: Sometimes Marital Separation 'Morally Necessary'</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417459458/pope-sometimes-marital-separation-morally-necessary?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Francis, speaking during his weekly general audience, said couples splitting may be needed to protect "the weaker spouse" and children.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nuns greet Pope Francis as he arrives to lead the weekly audience in Saint Peter's Square at the Vatican on Thursday. The pope, speaking at his weekly general audience, said sometimes separation is "morally necessary." Tony Gentile/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Tony Gentile/Reuters/Landov
Nuns greet Pope Francis as he arrives to lead the weekly audience in Saint Peter's Square at the Vatican on Thursday. The pope, speaking at his weekly general audience, said sometimes separation is "morally necessary."
Tony Gentile/Reuters/Landov
Pope Francis, speaking on family issues, says that sometimes marriages are so damaged that it is "morally necessary" for a husband and wife to separate.
"There are cases in which separation is inevitable," the pontiff said at his weekly general audience. "Sometimes it can become even morally necessary, precisely when it comes to subtracting the weaker spouse, or small children, from more serious injuries caused by arrogance and violence, by humiliation and exploitation ... and by indifference."
Sometimes parents need to separate for the sake of their children, @Pontifex says. http://t.co/jDIKc24yGr pic.twitter.com/5mWZKMbyyz
 NCR (@NCRonline) June 24, 2015
"Let us ask the Lord for a strong faith to see with his eyes the reality of family life, and for a deep love to approach all families with his merciful heart," he said.
The Associated Press notes: "Francis has been making a series of statements about family issues ahead of a much-anticipated October synod, or meeting, of bishops to address the topic. The bishops will take up many issues, including how the church can be more welcoming to divorced Catholics who remarry without going through the church process that declares their first marriage null."
The church has long said that divorced members cannot participate in communion. Time magazine writes: "There's no precise estimate worldwide, but according to Georgetown University's Center for Applied Research in the Apostolate, some 4.5 million Catholics in the United States (alone) are divorced and remarried without an 'annulment,' a declaration from a church court that the first marriage was invalid."
In December, speaking in an interview with the Argentine newspaper La Nacion, Francis said the church must consider ways to integrate divorced and civilly remarried people."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Stealthy' Giant Rhea Eludes Police In U.K.</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417426469/stealthy-giant-rhea-eludes-police-in-u-k?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The ostrich-like bird, native to South America, escaped from a farm in Nottinghamshire last week.</Description>
        <MainBody>'Stealthy' Giant Rhea Eludes Police In U.K.
June 25, 201510:33 AM ET
The female partner of the missing rhea bird that has been on the loose from a private collection in Carlton-in-Lindrick near Worksop, Nottinghamshire, U.K. Joe Giddens/PA Photos/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Joe Giddens/PA Photos/Landov
The female partner of the missing rhea bird that has been on the loose from a private collection in Carlton-in-Lindrick near Worksop, Nottinghamshire, U.K.
Joe Giddens/PA Photos/Landov
The giant ostrich-like rhea, despite its largely useless vestigial wings, seems to be something of a flight risk.
Last year , we brought you the story of one of the birds  native to South America  that escaped from a farm in the U.K., startling cyclists and otherwise wreaking mayhem in the English countryside.
Well, here we go again. The Daily Mail reports that another rhea is on the lam in rural Nottinghamshire after escaping last week.
The mate of a rhea bird missing in Nottinghamshire is said to be pacing their field by herself http://t.co/a1hbLF2D2C pic.twitter.com/ySMwBOaZJM
 Sky News (@SkyNews) June 25, 2015
As we mentioned last year, the rhea can sprint at 40 mph and, if provoked, deliver a nasty kick capable of seriously injuring a human.
"We are warning local people and particularly those with small children to be on their guard and not to approach the bird, which poses a very real threat to the public due to its size, aggressive nature and the unfamiliar surroundings it could find itself in," Inspector Paul Peatfield of the Nottinghamshire Police was quoted by the Mail as saying.
"Officers are working with the owner to trace the bird as we look to bring his incident to a safe conclusion," he said.
David Lindo, described as a bird expert by the BBC , says rheas are "quite stealthy and they'll be running off, hiding into the bushes ... they can melt into the countryside quite easily."
However, he said that the danger the birds pose has been "overrated."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS Launches Push To Retake Border Town Of Kobani</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417415672/isis-launches-push-to-re-take-border-town-of-kobani?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The battle began with one or more car bombs set off inside the Syrian city. There are unconfirmed reports that Islamic State fighters hid themselves among refugees flooding into Kobani.</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS Launches Push To Retake Border Town Of Kobani
June 25, 2015 9:04 AM ET
Civilians, reportedly wounded by fighting in Kobani, wait with their relatives to cross into Turkey at the Syrian-Turkish border crossing of Tel Abyad, Syria, on Thursday. Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Reuters/Landov
Civilians, reportedly wounded by fighting in Kobani, wait with their relatives to cross into Turkey at the Syrian-Turkish border crossing of Tel Abyad, Syria, on Thursday.
Reuters/Landov
Islamic State fighters, who were ousted from the Kurdish border town of Kobani in January, have launched an offensive to recapture the Syrian city  setting off car bombs as a prelude to an attack, NPR's Deborah Amos reports.
Deborah, reporting from southern Turkey near the Syrian border, says thousands of Kurdish civilians have been coming to Kobani from Ar Raqqa, the de facto capital of the self-declared Islamic State, after being forced out of the city by the Islamist extremists. Deborah says there are unconfirmed reports that Islamic State militants hid themselves among the returning refugees.
Al-Jazeera says its sources report that Islamic State fighters "were wearing Kurdish and Free Syrian Army uniforms ... as they attacked from three sides and took several positions inside the battleground town."
This latest attack comes as ISIS had lost ground due to the Kurdish militia backed by the U.S.
The Associated Press says that "in Kobani ... an activist group said 10 people died in fighting Thursday  the first time in six months the [Islamic State] had managed to enter the town along the Syria-Turkey border." The BBC put the number of dead at 30 and says that ISIS militants killed another 20 in a nearby village.
Meanwhile, "in the city of Hassakeh, Redur Khalil, a spokesman for the Kurdish People's Protection Units, or YPG, said [ISIS] militants attacked government-held neighborhoods on the southern edge of the city, and captured some areas. Hassakeh is divided between Syrian President Bashar Assad's forces and Kurdish fighters," the AP says.
According to the BBC: "The apparent two-pronged IS offensive came as Kurdish fighters from the Popular Protection Units (YPG) cut a major supply line for IS near [Ar] Raqqa."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
