<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cholera Surges In Haiti As Rain Arrives Early</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/05/28/410242929/cholera-surges-in-haiti-as-rain-arrives-early?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Cholera has been spreading in Haiti for over four years. But this year looks especially bleak. In the first four months, there were nearly four times the number of cases as in the same period in 2014.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cholera Surges In Haiti As Rain Arrives Early
May 28, 2015 6:39 PM ET
Peter Granitz
Health workers collect the body of a cholera victim in Petionville, Haiti, February 2011. The cholera outbreak in Haiti began in October 2010. Nearly 9,000 people have died. David Gilkey/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption David Gilkey/NPR
Health workers collect the body of a cholera victim in Petionville, Haiti, February 2011. The cholera outbreak in Haiti began in October 2010. Nearly 9,000 people have died.
David Gilkey/NPR
At a government-run clinic in Diquini, near Port-au-Prince, doctors are treating a handful of cholera patients.
One of them is Givenchi Predelus. For five days, the high school sophomore has been lying on a cot with a towel over his midsection and an IV in his arm, listening to tinny music on his bare-bones cellphone.
Why Cholera Persists In Haiti Despite An Abundance Of Aid
Predelus speaks in a whisper, a sign of what cholera has done to his strength. "Only one other person in my area has cholera," he says, through an interrupter. "She sells patties on the side of the road. I'm the second victim."
Cholera causes profuse diarrhea and vomiting, which can lead to death by dehydration, sometimes within a matter of hours.
An unusually early start to the rainy season has brought a spike in the waterborne bacteria  and thus the number of infections. In the first four months of this year, the number of reported cholera cases was nearly 400 percent higher than that reported in the same period in 2014.
This outbreak in Haiti has been ongoing since October 2010  10 months after the catastrophic earthquake . So far, nearly 9,000 people have died, and more than 730,000 have been infected.
After Bringing Cholera To Haiti, U.N. Plans To Get Rid Of It
Scientific studies show that U.N. peacekeepers from Nepal likely imported the bacteria causing the outbreak in 2010. The U.N. says it's committed to eradicating cholera from Haiti, but it hasn't accepted responsibility for inadvertently introducing the disease.
An unprecedented surge in cholera cases at the end of the last year and a harsh, early start to the rains mean this year will be bleak, says Oliver Schulz, who, until last week, led Doctors Without Borders' mission in Haiti.
Some illegal behavior could be contributing to the spread of the disease, Schulz says. "People [are] breaking the official water pipes to illegally take the water," he says. "There's the risk of contamination. If you have an open water pipe on the ground, and there's a heavy rain, perhaps there's a latrine nearby that floods into the pipe, and it contaminates the whole system."
5 Years After Haiti's Earthquake, Where Did The $13.5 Billion Go?
More than 15,000 people have been infected and another 126 have died this year, says Haiti's health ministry.
But despite the grim totals, the number are slowing. The health ministry says 2,400 cases were reported last month, which is down from 4,000 in January.
Back at the cholera treatment center, a man rushes in with his 1-year-old daughter. She already has an IV in her arm. She is vomiting, and workers rush to surround her metal cot with buckets.
Workers at a clinic near the man's home sent him and his daughter by motorcycle taxi here because the clinic is better equipped than the one nearby.
Across the room, Rinel Mathurin holds her 3-year old daughter, Williana, who after three days of treatment can finally sit up.
Rinel says the center staff told her to watch Williana's interactions with other kids to avoid spreading infections  and to purify the home's water to keep other kids safe.
"We need to treat the water we drink with chlorine tabs," Rinel says through an interrupter. "We need to clean the house with Clorox. We need to buy chlorine tabs."
But chlorine tabs at the market cost money, she says. And she's not sure she can afford them.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:10:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cod Comeback: How The North Sea Fishery Bounced Back From The Brink </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2015/05/28/410319950/cod-comeback-how-the-north-sea-fishery-bounced-back-from-the-brink?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>A decade ago, fishermen trying to catch North Sea cod were coming up empty. Now, thanks to strict fishing rules put in place to halt the decline, this fish tale looks headed for a happy ending.</Description>
        <MainBody>Fish for sale in the fish market in Fraserburgh, Scotland. Ari Shapiro/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Ari Shapiro/NPR
Fish for sale in the fish market in Fraserburgh, Scotland.
Ari Shapiro/NPR
Cod love the icy cold waters of the North Sea  and British people love eating cod.
But a decade ago, it looked like people were eating the fish to the brink of collapse. Now the trend has turned around, and the cod are coming back.
We pick up this fish tale, which seems to be on its way to a happy ending, at an early morning fish auction in Fraserburgh, Scotland, where buyers and sellers are lined up alongside hundreds of boxes containing cod, hake, monkfish, sole and every other kind of fish you can imagine from the North Sea.
This auction is not a place for fancy chefs and home cooks. The sales are in bulk, and most of the buyers and sellers here come from generations of fishermen. Like market superintendent Ian Buchan  he spent most of his life at sea, until it became just too hard to catch fish.
"People were saying there was no cod. Ten years before I stopped, at least 150 miles to get fish. Now, 20 miles. Fish is everywhere," Buchan says.
Everywhere.
A view of the fishing port in Fraserburgh, Scotland. A decade ago, fishermen trying to catch cod were coming up empty. Now the cod and hake catch is rebounding. Ari Shapiro/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Ari Shapiro/NPR
A view of the fishing port in Fraserburgh, Scotland. A decade ago, fishermen trying to catch cod were coming up empty. Now the cod and hake catch is rebounding.
Ari Shapiro/NPR
"We've seen a big explosion in the cod and hake," says Alan Mutch, who runs the fish salesmen's association here. "We're definitely seeing an upsurge in that. And in fact, now vessels  because of the restrictions on the amount they're allowed to land  vessels now have to steam to other areas to get away from cod."
This is a huge turnaround from just a decade ago, says Robin Cook , a scientist who used to run the region's fisheries research center. He's now with Strathclyde University in Glasgow.
"Through much of my career, many of the stocks in European waters were in decline. And things were getting worse and worse and worse," Cook says.
Back then, Cook was the go-to expert for stories on fishery collapse. He was quoted in programs with titles like Goodbye Fish and Chips and Costing the earth  In Cod We Trust.
Whereas today?
"It's interesting, you get a lot more interviews when things are bad than when things are getting better. So this is certainly quite a change," Cook says of our conversation.
In the late '90s, scientists say fishermen were pulling about 60 percent of the cod out of the water each year in the North Sea. It doesn't take an advanced math degree to calculate that that is unsustainable.
So about 10 years ago, the government bought about half of the fishing boats in Scotland and destroyed them. The boats that kept working were put under strict regulations  the number of days they could spend at sea, the number of cod they could catch.
And to Cook, it looks like the program is working. "I certainly in the past would've avoided buying cod, whereas I wouldn't now," he says.
Most of the buyers and sellers at the Fraserburgh fish auction come from generations of fishermen. Ari Shapiro/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Ari Shapiro/NPR
Most of the buyers and sellers at the Fraserburgh fish auction come from generations of fishermen.
Ari Shapiro/NPR
It's not a perfect system.
Fishermen tell me they sometimes throw dead cod back in the water when they scoop them up with other fish. Otherwise, they'll be penalized for violating quotas.
In Fraserburgh, Mutch tells me he thinks this community can regulate itself. I note that some critics say that, if the industry is allowed to self-regulate, then every ship will be in a race to empty out the oceans. What does he think?
"I would've said 20 years ago, 15 years ago, possibly. But you've now got a breed of young fishermen who have gone through all the trauma that we've gone through. They realize that we can't do what we were doing before."
He says the new crop of fishermen has seen what their parents went through and realize they can't return to the old ways. And there is a new generation coming on board.
Xander West gave up fishing almost 20 years ago when the fishery started collapsing. But his son, he says, has now taken up trawling.
He says his son doesn't make a great living, but it's good enough. And he's just glad that his son can continue in the family business.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Foreign Policy Experts Weigh In On U.S. Strategy Against The Islamic State</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410340217/foreign-policy-experts-weigh-in-on-u-s-strategy-against-the-islamic-state?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>NPR's Robert Siegel speaks with White House spokesman Josh Earnest about the current U.S. strategy in Iraq and Syria. He also interviews foreign policy experts who say that policy needs review.</Description>
        <MainBody>Foreign Policy Experts Weigh In On U.S. Strategy Against The Islamic State
May 28, 2015 5:23 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 00:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>As Publishing Industry Courts China, Authors Speak Out Against Censorship</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410332552/as-publishing-industry-courts-china-authors-speak-out-against-censorship?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Chinese writers and publishers are being celebrated this week at BookExpo America — the industry's largest trade event in North America. Free speech advocates are supporting silenced Chinese writers.</Description>
        <MainBody>As Publishing Industry Courts China, Authors Speak Out Against Censorship
May 28, 2015 5:23 PM ET
Protesters gathered on the steps of the New York Public Library on Wednesday to show support for silenced Chinese writers. Frank Franklin II/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Frank Franklin II/AP
Protesters gathered on the steps of the New York Public Library on Wednesday to show support for silenced Chinese writers.
Frank Franklin II/AP
Chinese writers and publishers are being celebrated this week in New York at BookExpo America  the industry's largest trade event in North America. Organizers of the event say China deserves a seat at the table because it is such a big and potentially lucrative market. But some authors and free speech advocates have seen this as an opportunity to shine light on censorship in China.
Most of the books in the exhibition area are in Chinese, but Paul Myatovich presides over a display of books in translation. Myatovich is sales and marketing manager for CN Times Books, which is the U.S. publishing arm of Beijing Media Times. He says being invited to BookExpo is a great opportunity for Chinese publishers:
"To give Americans and Westerners who are coming to the show a chance to see the breadth of Chinese publishing  that it's not all the little red book of Mao," Myatovich says.
BookExpo invited China to exhibit this year because organizers say China represents a market that could be crucial to Western publishers. But critics say in its eagerness to please the Chinese, the book industry is ignoring the dark side of publishing in China: censorship. Xiaolu Guo is a Chinese writer who now lives in the U.K. She left China because she felt she had to censor herself to stay out of trouble.
"You have to protect yourself," she says. "... If you can't leave China, most of the writers, artists and filmmakers they have to play the game. You know  use lots of metaphors to write a story or don't touch certain subjects."
Western writers who publish in China are also subject to censorship and sometimes they don't even know how their work has been altered. In his novel Sunset Park, Paul Auster included a mention of the imprisoned Chinese poet Liu Xiaobo. His Chinese publisher indicated some changes might be necessary but Auster says it wasn't until he got a copy of the Chinese translation of his book that he understood that all mention of the dissident poet had been eliminated.
Auster and Xiaolu Guo were in Manhattan on Wednesday to take part in a protest organized by the PEN American Center on the steps of the New York Public Library. They were joined by both Chinese and American writers including Jonathan Franzen, Ha Jin, Francine Prose and A.M. Homes, who all read from the work of dissident Chinese writers. Auster read a poem by Liu Xiaobo.
Yes, it's vibrant, yes it dynamic, yes there are some great Chinese writers who can get published and whose books can be sold. But there are also others who are completely muzzled and jailed and that piece of the story at least seems to be missing.
- Suzanne Nozzel, executive director of PEN American Center
China may deserve a seat at the international publishing table, but PEN American Executive Director Suzanne Nossel says that doesn't mean the rest of the world should overlook the fact that there are two very different sides to Chinese publishing.
"Yes, it's vibrant, yes it dynamic, yes there are some great Chinese writers who can get published and whose books can be sold. But there are also others who are completely muzzled and jailed and that piece of the story at least seems to be missing, so we think it's important to show the part of the story that is not being told."
As the protest ended, Nossel led the demonstrators in signing a petition demanding freedom for imprisoned Chinese writers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:47:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>What Are $26 Million In American Express Rewards Points Worth?</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410340176/what-are-26-million-in-american-express-rewards-points-worth?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>While he was a FIFA executive, Chuck Blazer charged $26 million in business expenses to a personal American Express card. Brian Kelly of thepointsguy.com explains the value of those rewards points.</Description>
        <MainBody>What Are $26 Million In American Express Rewards Points Worth?
May 28, 2015 4:47 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:47:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA Delegate: Indictment 'Brought A Cloud' On Upcoming Presidential Vote</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410340159/fifa-delegate-indictment-brought-a-cloud-on-upcoming-presidential-vote?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>NPR's Robert Siegel speaks with Randolph Harris, president of the Barbados Football Association, about the latest on the FIFA indictments and the soccer organization's upcoming presidential vote.</Description>
        <MainBody>
You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Does Less Latin Mean Dumbing Down? France Debates School Reform</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/05/28/410017058/does-less-latin-mean-dumbing-down-france-debates-school-reform?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>France has one of the world's highest dropout rates, and the reforms are meant to make the middle school curriculum more interesting. But critics say the changes amount to a "dumbing down."</Description>
        <MainBody>Does Less Latin Mean Dumbing Down? France Debates School Reform
May 28, 2015 4:06 PM ET
i
Striking French teachers hold a German flag as they take part in a nationwide protest against new measures aimed at revamping the country's school system, in Marseille, France, on May 19. France's 840,000 teachers are largely opposed to the reform, their unions say, fearing it will increase competition between schools and exacerbate inequalities. Jean-Paul Pelissier /Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Jean-Paul Pelissier /Reuters/Landov
Striking French teachers hold a German flag as they take part in a nationwide protest against new measures aimed at revamping the country's school system, in Marseille, France, on May 19. France's 840,000 teachers are largely opposed to the reform, their unions say, fearing it will increase competition between schools and exacerbate inequalities.
Jean-Paul Pelissier /Reuters/Landov
Reforming the education system in any country can be tricky. But in France, where learning is highly centralized and public school (l'ecole de la Republique) a symbol of French greatness, it's all but impossible.
Several French presidents have tried and failed. President Francois Hollande's second attempt has traditionalists up in arms and critics on the right and left screaming that French schools are being dumbed down.
Teachers, students and some parents took to the streets of cities across the country recently to denounce the government's project.
One of the most contentious elements is the plan to cut back on Greek and Latin, focusing instead on teaching a more lively history of ancient civilizations. In Paris, Latin and Greek teachers waved signs of protest as they marched through the streets, some of them dressed in togas.
Former journalist Peter Gumbel, who is writing his second book on the French education system, says the middle school reform has touched a nerve.
"The fuss has come about because there are certain very elitist things that are being scratched at," he says. "Anyone who thinks of himself as an intellectual is saying, this is the end of civilization as we know it! But of course it's not."
Conservatives are also up in arms about proposed changes to teaching history. Slavery and colonialism are to be emphasized, while the study of the Enlightenment will be optional.
Luc Ferry, education minister under former President Jacques Chirac, denounced what he called an "apologist curriculum."
"Presenting European civilization through the lens of the slave trade and colonialism is scandalous," said Ferry. "What about Voltaire and Diderot, not to mention the invention of science, the encyclopedia and the museum, and of course the ideals of the French revolution  these aren't important?"
The aim of the reform is to make the heavy, French middle school curriculum more interesting and lively for students. International studies show France has one of the highest dropout rates, with one in five kids leaving school with no qualifications at all.
Author Gumbel says the French public school system is also one of the world's most unequal, with success often linked to where a student lives and the income level of his family.
"And for a country where the words liberte, fraternite and egalite are carved on the front of school buildings, that's very shocking for the French," says Gumbel.
"They have this meritocratic belief in the vision that anybody by sheer dint of their intellectual prowess can rise to the top of French society," he continues." And of course it basically doesn't work like that. And the real problem is it's getting worse."
At the protest, 65-year-old Odile Nicolas says she's demonstrating for her granddaughter, who will start middle school next year.
"Dumbing down school is not the way to go," she says. "Children from disadvantaged families should be pulled up to succeed in their lives and not the other way around."
Related NPR Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:35:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Smartphones Are So Smart They Can Now Test Your Vision</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/05/28/409731415/smart-phones-are-so-smart-they-can-now-test-your-vision?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In a new study, an easy-to-use app did just as good a job as the machines in an eye doctor's office. That's a boon for people in low-income countries — and really for anyone with vision issues.</Description>
        <MainBody>Smartphones Are So Smart They Can Now Test Your Vision
May 28, 2015 3:35 PM ET
Emily Sohn
A new smartphone app gives a close-up view of a patient's eye. Screengrab from video by Peek Vision, produced in collaboration with Sony Mobile. hide caption
itoggle caption Screengrab from video by Peek Vision, produced in collaboration with Sony Mobile.
A new smartphone app gives a close-up view of a patient's eye.
Screengrab from video by Peek Vision, produced in collaboration with Sony Mobile.
The creators of a new smart phone app say that portable testing will help prevent blindness in the developing world.
British ophthalmologist Andrew Bastawrous moved his family from London to Kenya in 2013 with $150,000 of equipment, a team of 15 people and an ambitious goal: to understand the causes of blindness in rural Africa. It didn't take long before he encountered all sorts of obstacles, including unpredictable power supplies and the regular need to run a gas-fueled generator to keep the equipment going. Many of the villages he was trying to reach had no roads and no electricity.
There had to be a better way, Bastawrous thought as he set about developing a smartphone app to help conduct high-quality eye exams without the need for heavy or expensive equipment. In the first published study on the app, called Peek , he and colleagues report that, for a group of older Kenyans, the phone-based vision test worked just as well as the gold-standard methods used in a doctor's office.
Of the 285 million people in the world with vision impairment, 80 percent live in low-income countries. The vast majority have preventable or treatable conditions, like glaucoma or cataracts. By increasing access to simple and affordable eye tests, Bastawrous hopes to create awareness about eye conditions and, in turn, connect patients with vision-saving treatments.
People In Poor Communities Are More Likely To Lose Eyesight
"For most people, it's an accepted consequence of old age that as you get older, you lose your sight," he says. "If we can create a freely downloadable app with high-quality results, it means that hopefully more people with vision problems can be identified, particularly the most vulnerable groups."
There are two standard ways to test vision. One is with a traditional letter chart that shows progressively smaller letters as patients read down each line. A newer, more accurate method uses an electronically powered box that illuminates letters of various sizes.
The Peek vision test looks a little different. On the phone's screen, patients see just one letter: an "E" that can be displayed with the prongs facing up, down, to the left or to the right. Patients don't need to be able to read or to know the English alphabet. They just point a finger in the direction they see the E facing. If it looks like a "W," for example, when pointing up.
The test-giver, who does not need to be a trained health care worker, stands 6 feet away and simply swipes the phone to indicate the way the patient thinks the E is positioned. If the patient shakes his head because the letter is too blurry, the test-giver shakes the phone. That's the "don't know" response.
At the end of the test, which takes a little over a minute, the phone vibrates and dings. Results appear immediately on the screen and can be translated to the 20/20 scale. The app can also show the patient's level of blurriness compared to normal vision.
For the latest trial, Bastawrous' team evaluated 233 Kenyans who were 55 or older. At home, patients took two eye exams: one with the Peek app and one with a standard paper chart. The next day, the same people went to a temporary clinic, where they completed the same two tests as well as one with the newer electronic technology.
Results, which appeared Thursday in the journal JAMA Ophthalmology , showed that the Peek test was as accurate as the other two methods for testing vision. The app's test, Bastawrous adds, was as quick if not quicker than the paper chart.
The phone method has other advantages, he says, including more objectivity. While paper charts require an examiner to look frequently back and forth from the patient to the chart to check for accuracy, a test-giver holding a phone never has to make any assessments at all. The phone does all the work. And once the results are on a smartphone, they can be shared remotely with doctors who are not in the field. The app also performs retina scans and other kinds of vision tests that are undergoing their own trials.
In a follow-up study that has not yet been published, the team found that people were very accepting of phone-based vision tests, possibly because the technology is so familiar. In sub-Saharan Africa, according to the United Nations, more people have cellphones than have clean, running water.
A portable, easy-to-use vision app could be useful in settings where ophthalmologists might be scarce, like developing countries, or even for patients who want to monitor their eyesight at home, says Jeremy Keenan, an ocular infectious disease expert at the University of California, San Francisco.
"This could greatly expand the ability of public health agencies to include vision screening in their outreach programs," Keenan says. "The hope would be that this type of tool could help identify people with eye disease before they have lost too much vision and at a time when treatments are still available, though whether this will be the case needs to be studied further."
One important step that needs to be worked out: how to translate vision test results into action.
"No matter how good the technology is, it's just a test," Bastawrous says. "You have to link people to very dedicated health workers and good quality services."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 19:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Not Your Mother's Catholic Frescoes: Radiant Portraits Of Queer People Of Color </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/2015/05/28/409770203/not-your-mothers-catholic-frescoes-radiant-portraits-of-queer-people-of-color?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Inspired by Mexican religious art, photographer Gabriel Garcia Roman portrays queer people of color as saints and warriors.</Description>
        <MainBody>Photographer Gabriel Garcia Roman's "Queer Icons" series portrays queer people of color as saints and warriors. Jahmal Golden is a poet and a student at The New School. Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Photographer Gabriel Garcia Roman's "Queer Icons" series portrays queer people of color as saints and warriors. Jahmal Golden is a poet and a student at The New School.
Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Photographer Gabriel Garcia Roman's portraits feature friends and acquaintances, activists and poets, Americans and immigrants  some naturalized, some undocumented.
All of them are queer people of color.
"I wanted to specifically focus on this community because queer and trans people of color are so rarely represented in the art world," says Roman , who is Mexican-American and also identifies as queer.
Kathy Rodriguez lives in Brooklyn and works for the educational organization New Visions for Public Schools. Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Kathy Rodriguez lives in Brooklyn and works for the educational organization New Visions for Public Schools.
Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
The photo series, called " Queer Icons ," evokes the colorful, religious artwork that Roman grew up with. "Because I grew up Catholic in a Mexican community in Chicago, my first introduction to art was religious art," he says.
He was particularly inspired by the fresco paintings of haloed saints that decorated the walls of his neighborhood church. "I've always thought of the halo as something very powerful  it's like a badge of nobility," he says.
And because Roman's subjects are activists and artists who do good for the community, "I wanted to represent them as saints," he says.
He also wanted to capture their pride and their strength. "I wanted them to be warriors  that's why a lot of them are looking straight at the camera, saying 'Here I am, and I'm not going to hide.'"
Some of the images feature poems or prose, written by the subject of the portraits. Roman uses the silkscreen printing method to layer text and photograph with color and pattern.
He has shown this work at several exhibits around the country. As of now, he works on the project in his free time  he works at a market research firm by day.
Like many of the people he has photographed, Roman, 41, says he often grapples with his identity. He moved with his family from Zacatecas, Mexico to the US when he was two years old, and they were undocumented until he was 15. "I grew up in the states always being reminded that I was Mexican," he says. "When I finally went to Mexico for the first time, when I was 31, everyone there was like 'You're not Mexican  you're American.'"
These images play with feelings of not belonging, and, above all, being seen.
Sonia Guiansaca Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Sonia Guiansaca
Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Sonia Guiansaca is an undocumented poet and community organizer who was born in Ecuador and has been raised in Harlem since age five. She is a board member at NYSYLC , a non-profit organization that advocates for the rights of undocumented youth.
Today you were reminded that you are not "queer" enough, not "artistic" enough, not "migrant" enough...
Today you cry. Today you write. Today you make love to your queer partner.
Emanuel Xavier Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Emanuel Xavier
Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Today, all femmed out you disrupt the gaze. Today you love and not just survive!
Emanuel Xavier is an award-winning poet and LGBT rights activist of Ecuadorian and Puerto Rican heritage, based in New York. He's also chair of the Penguin Random House LGBT Network.
There is a world out there where I belong: loved by a mother and father who understand my dreams who listen to my fears of my older cousin, his touch, or how boys make fun of me in school. There is a world out there where I can grow up to love myself and others like me, where soft spoken boys can speak boldly. I will call it poetry, each memory an inspiration. All this pain, these dismembered &amp; abandoned cars, these empty lots left behind where I knew deep in my heart there is innocence in playing with dolls, reaching for rainbows, book, even mami's pretty dresses. I will not be alone in this world. I have somewhere to run. I do not know exactly where.
Julissa Rodriguez Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Julissa Rodriguez
Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
I have no maps or stars to guide me through the night. If it turns out this is my world, maybe I should simply learn to laugh and love and let the others catch up to me instead.  "Runaway"
Bakar Wilson Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Bakar Wilson
Courtesy of Gabriel Garcia Roman
Julissa Rodriguez is a poet and tattoo artist from the Bronx, NY. Her family is from the Dominican Republic.
Bakar Wilson is a poet and an adjunct professor of English at the Borough of Manhattan Community College.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 16:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FIFA Update: Europe's UEFA Backs Blatter's Opponent; Raids In Brazil</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/28/410243946/fifa-update-europes-uefa-backs-blatter-s-opponent-raids-in-brazil?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Accusations of rampant corruption at FIFA came just days before Sepp Blatter is set to stand for re-election Friday. Europe's UEFA says it will back Blatter's lone opponent.</Description>
        <MainBody>UEFA President Michel Platini says his organization is backing FIFA President Sepp Blatter's opponent in Friday's presidential election. When asked if UEFA might consider leaving FIFA, Platini said, "Of course." FABRICE COFFRINI/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption FABRICE COFFRINI/AFP/Getty Images
UEFA President Michel Platini says his organization is backing FIFA President Sepp Blatter's opponent in Friday's presidential election. When asked if UEFA might consider leaving FIFA, Platini said, "Of course."
FABRICE COFFRINI/AFP/Getty Images
One day after a string of bribery arrests and indictments was revealed to center on FIFA, the soccer organization's president, Sepp Blatter, says he will not resign. Accusations of rampant corruption at FIFA came just days before Blatter stands for reelection in Switzerland Friday.
The dozens of criminal charges have stoked long-simmering suspicions about corruption in soccer's governing body. In response, Europe's umbrella organization, UEFA, has called for postponing Friday's vote  and today, its leader announced that many of its member associations will support Jordan's PrinceAli Bin Al Hussein, the lone challenger to Blatter.
"Enough is enough," UEFA President Michel Platini said. He added, "I am disgusted."
Describing a talk he had with Blatter, Platini said, "He already lost. FIFA already lost."
In a news conference held Thursday, Platini described how Blatter was "affected" by their talk, in which Platini says he spoke to the embattled FIFA leader as an old friend.
It's a startling turnabout for both Blatter and FIFA, which earlier this year announced that in the years from 2011 to 2014, it brought in revenue of $5.7 billion against expenses of $5.38 billion.
As of Thursday, Blatter "says he has no intention of resigning," the BBC reports.
On Wednesday, U.S. and Swiss authorities announced arrests, indictments and investigations into bribery and kickbacks, with the U.S. inquiry naming nine senior FIFA officials and several sports marketing executives. The Swiss investigation includes the process of choosing host cities for two upcoming World Cup tournaments, in Russia and Qatar.
The arrests took place at a Lake Zurich hotel where FIFA members had gathered ahead of the organization's elections. Later, the U.S. released a lengthy indictment that detailed money changing hands over marketing and media rights to prestigious tournaments run by FIFA.
The criminal charges against senior FIFA leaders in the U.S. and South America have had wide effects, prompting federal police in Brazil to raid a sports marketing firm in Rio de Janeiro.
From Rio, NPR's Lourdes Garcia-Navarro reports:
"It's called Klefer Sports Marketing and it's owned by the former head of renowned Brazilian soccer club Flamengo. The company negotiates TV rights for sporting events and had a close relationship with Traffic, the Brazilian firm implicated in bribery scheme.
"Separately, the former footballer and current senator known simply here as Romario has asked the Senate to open an investigation into the Brazilian football confederation. The former president and current vice president of the Brazilian confederation, Jose Maria Marin, is under indictment by US. .authorities for his involvement in the alleged massive kickback scheme."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 14:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Live Anthrax Was Mistakenly Sent To 9 States And A U.S. Military Base</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/05/28/410220914/live-anthrax-was-mistakenly-sent-to-9-states-and-a-u-s-military-base?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The Pentagon says an attempt to ship inactive anthrax samples resulted in live samples being sent to labs in nine U.S. states and to a U.S. Air Force base in South Korea.</Description>
        <MainBody>Live Anthrax Was Mistakenly Sent To 9 States And A U.S. Military Base
May 28, 2015 7:12 AM ET
Dugway Proving Ground military base, seen here in 2010, was the source of several anthrax shipments that are suspected of containing live samples of the disease. Jim Urquhart/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Jim Urquhart/AP
Dugway Proving Ground military base, seen here in 2010, was the source of several anthrax shipments that are suspected of containing live samples of the disease.
Jim Urquhart/AP
The Department of Defense says an attempt to ship inactive anthrax samples resulted in live samples being sent to labs in nine U.S. states and to a U.S. Air Force base in South Korea.
Fears of exposure to the potentially deadly disease prompted officials to advise four civilian workers to get preventive care; more than 20 military personnel are also being monitored. The samples were sent via commercial shipping companies, but the Pentagon says there is "no known risk to the general public."
The spores were supposed to have been killed by being irradiated. But at least one lab, in Maryland, reported receiving spores that were still alive. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is investigating the accidental shipment.
From NPR's Science Desk, Geoff Brumfiel reports:
"The anthrax came from the Army's Dugway Proving Ground in Utah, which conducts biosecurity research. The samples were apparently sent to labs in nine states as part of ongoing efforts to develop field tests for anthrax.
"Tests are usually conducted with dead samples of anthrax, and an investigation is now under way to learn why live samples were sent instead. Anthrax are highly infectious bacteria that can travel through the air and infect people.
"So far, the Pentagon says it appears nobody has become sick from the mistake. It has suspended all shipments of biological agents from its labs until an investigation is completed."
The military says 22 personnel were potentially exposed to the live sample at a U.S. base in South Korea.
From Seoul, NPR's Elise Hu reports:
"The military destroyed the anthrax on Wednesday after the sample, which was thought to be inactive, was suspected of being live. None of the personnel in contact showed signs of exposure. But they were given exams, antibiotics, and in some cases, vaccinations.
"The military stresses there was no risk to the public. The exposure happened in a contained lab environment on the Osan Air Base, which is 65 miles south of Seoul. It's one of a number of bases that houses the estimated 28,000 American military personnel based in South Korea."
According to the CDC's fact page on anthrax, it's caused by "rod-shaped bacteria known as Bacillus anthracis," is found naturally in soil, and affects domestic and wild animals around the world.
Anthrax can cause severe illness, the CDC says  the agency adds that while the disease can spread through spores, "anthrax is not contagious, which means you can't catch it like the cold or flu."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Soccer Indictments Outline Schemes Involving Sports Marking Firms</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410204978/soccer-indictments-outline-schemes-involving-sports-marking-firms?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Most of the charges relate to bribes paid by sports marketing executives to secure lucrative marketing and media rights. One of the companies named has its North American headquarters in Miami.</Description>
        <MainBody>Soccer Indictments Outline Schemes Involving Sports Marking Firms
May 28, 2015 5:01 AM ET
Most of the charges relate to bribes paid by sports marketing executives to secure lucrative marketing and media rights. One of the companies named has its North American headquarters in Miami.
DAVID GREENE, HOST:
And there are other companies with a lot on their minds right now - FIFA's big sponsors, which tie their brands to the sport and its organizers. With more on the potential fallout they face, here's NPR's Jason Margolis.
JASON MARGOLIS, BYLINE: Coca-Cola, Adidas, Visa and Hyundai are FIFA's main long-term sponsors. They're not saying much about yesterday's corruption charges. None agreed to an interview. Visa did release a brief statement expressing disappointment in FIFA. The company said it will, quote, "reassess our sponsorship" if FIFA doesn't take immediate steps to address issues within its organization. An Adidas spokesperson sent a brief email saying Adidas is committed to creating a culture that promotes the highest standards of ethics and compliance, and we expect the same from our partners. They wouldn't comment further.
MIKE LEWIS: I actually think it's probably enough in this day and age - I mean, the expression of concern that they're monitoring the situation.
MARGOLIS: Mike Lewis specializes in sports marketing at Emory University. He says sponsors need to emphasize that they're supporting the game itself.
LEWIS: And so I think for the vast majority of fans, you know, Coca-Cola is connected to the stars on the field, not the administrators in the back office.
MARGOLIS: Political scientist Andrei Markovits takes things a step further. He teaches a class about sports, politics and society at the University of Michigan.
ANDREI MARKOVITS: If FIFA were run by child molesters, mass murderers and - I don't know - some other heinous folks, it would have zero effect on my soccer watching - zero - and I'm not the exception.
MARGOLIS: He says Coke and Adidas know what fans are like, and they know what FIFA is like, too.
MARKOVITS: Everyone knows these organizations are crooked. This is known. This is how you procure votes. This is totally not news.
MARGOLIS: Still, there is some pressure on sponsors to disassociate from FIFA. Activists are calling on them to challenge FIFA's decision to hold the 2022 World Cup in Qatar and are sharply critical of alleged human rights abuses at construction sites in that country. Hundreds of guest workers have died there in the past five years. Three sponsors did walk away from the FIFA earlier this year - Johnson &amp; Johnson, Castrol and Continental Tires. I contacted all three. They sent brief emails basically saying it was a business decision. Andrei Markovits says sponsors like Coke will distance themselves from FIFA soccer when fans distance themselves.
MARKOVITS: If in fact Coke actually realizes that, boy, this is bad enough and we're really worried that somehow people will not watch the World Cup then yes, but...
MARGOLIS: No way that's happening. More than 900 million people watched the World Cup final. That's nearly eight times as many as the Super Bowl. Jason Margolis, NPR News.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sponsors Monitor Corruption Charges Against Soccer Officials</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410204971/sponsors-monitor-corruption-charges-against-soccer-officials?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The arrest of 7 FIFA officials in Zurich is raising questions for corporations that underwrite soccer's main event, the World Cup. Coca-Cola, Adidas and others are withholding public comment for now.</Description>
        <MainBody>Sponsors Monitor Corruption Charges Against Soccer Officials
May 28, 2015 5:01 AM ET
Jason Margolis
The arrest of 7 FIFA officials in Zurich is raising questions for corporations that underwrite soccer's main event, the World Cup. Coca-Cola, Adidas and others are withholding public comment for now.
DAVID GREENE, HOST:
Soccer is the world's most popular sport. It is also a massive global business, and judging by yesterday's news, it is an organized crime ring. That's at least how the world's governing body for the sport, FIFA, is being portrayed. Officials were rounded up at a hotel; charged with corruption on a massive scale. And now we're going to dig into exactly what these officials are accused of. Most of the alleged schemes outlined by the Justice Department involve sports marketing companies. One of them is Traffic Sports USA. They're based in Miami. So is NPR's Greg Allen, and he's on the line. Hey, Greg.
GREG ALLEN, BYLINE: Good morning, David.
GREENE: OK, so some of the basics here - the Justice Department says well over $150 million in bribes paid by these sports marketing companies to officials in FIFA. What are these marketing companies, and what were they hoping to get?
ALLEN: Well, in the indictment there was three marketing companies - Traffic USA, which is part of a larger company based in Brazil, and there are two Argentinean sports marketing firms involved. And what they are charged with is paying bribes to get these media and marketing rights. Media, of course, is things like TV, radio and the Internet. And they resell those rights to media companies that then, you know, broadcast. Marketing, of course, is to allow companies like Traffic and others to sell sponsorships on and off the field for things like Coca-Cola, Adidas, etcetera. So Traffic, which has that parent company in Brazil, and the Argentinean companies, they're charged with paying these big bribes to international soccer officials to get those big contracts.
GREENE: And, you know, there are individuals named in this indictment, including Traffic's U.S. president, Aaron Davidson. I mean, could he be in serious trouble here?
ALLEN: Yes. I mean, the racketeering is the biggest charge and that carries a 20-year prison sentence. But that's just one of a - there's a dozen charges against him, including conspiracy and wire fraud charges. The Justice Department says that its big indictment - it's 164 pages - took years to put together, and there's a dozen different schemes - fraud schemes - detailed in there that Traffic was involved in. It doesn't help Davidson that his boss, the Brazilian owner of Traffic - a man named Jose Hawilla - has already pleaded guilty. He agreed to pay a $150 million fine for his part in the schemes. And also in the indictment, several other Traffic employees are listed as unindicted co-conspirators, but it does seem like Davidson knew what he was doing. In one of the schemes, he allegedly agreed to pay more than $3 million in bribes to one of the officials to secure rights to a tournament. And I'll read you something - it's in the indictment here. It's a quote from Davidson when he was asked about it. In the indictment he says (reading) is it illegal? It is illegal. Within the big picture of things, a company that has worked in the industry for 30 years, is it bad? It is bad.
GREENE: So is the U.S. president of Traffic actually just admitting guilt there?
ALLEN: Well, I don't think he thought he was doing it to prosecutors, and we'll see what comes out at trial, but it certainly seems like he knew what was going on.
GREENE: But, Greg, I guess, you know, just listening to a line like that, I wonder if this kind of behavior has just become really commonplace almost because this is an environment where a company just feels like if all my competitors are doing this, well, I guess I have to, too.
ALLEN: Right. I'll give you an example. There's a tournament in South America called Copa America, which Traffic held rights to for some 30 years. More than 20 years ago, the tournament officials told them that they wanted a bribe for them to get the media and marketing rights. So they agreed to pay it, and the bribes increased over the years. Eventually, Traffic lost the rights, though, to another sports marketing company, Full Play, which is also charged in the indictment, and they paid a larger bribe. But then later, Traffic teamed up with some of its competitors to form a new company that got back the media and marketing rights to that tournament - the Copa America soccer tournament - and they ended up paying some $40 million in bribes for that.
GREENE: Well, that's just stunning. These allegations have just a lot of money being thrown around everywhere. NPR's Greg Allen joining us from Miami. Greg, thanks.
ALLEN: You're welcome.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Illegal Migration From Africa Is Now An Industry, Ethnographer Says</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410204957/illegal-migration-from-africa-is-now-an-industry-ethnographer-says?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Renee Montagne talks to Ruben Andersson, who studies West African migrants trying to reach Europe. He says most efforts to control clandestine migration will only make the situation worse.</Description>
        <MainBody>Illegal Migration From Africa Is Now An Industry, Ethnographer Says
May 28, 2015 5:01 AM ET
Renee Montagne talks to Ruben Andersson, who studies West African migrants trying to reach Europe. He says most efforts to control clandestine migration will only make the situation worse.
DAVID GREENE, HOST:
And now, let's turn to an urgent migrant crisis on the other side of the globe. Thousands of people from Africa are trying to reach European shores. And we're about to hear from a man with some deep insight into this. For seven years, ethnographer Ruben Andersson has been studying West African migrants. He's interviewed migrants as well as aid workers, border security guards, smugglers and journalists. Andersson told my colleague Renee Montagne that research has led him to this conclusion - clandestine migration has become an industry and efforts to control it only make it worse.
RENEE MONTAGNE, BYLINE: As an example, Ruben Andersson pointed to two Spanish enclaves on the coast of North Africa. Over the years, security there has expanded and fences have gotten higher.
RUBEN ANDERSSON: We have 6-meter tall fences equipped with razor wire, sensors, cameras, bright lights, pepper spray mechanisms. You have very militarized policing on both the Moroccan and Spanish side of the border. But even so, the people have kept coming in recent years in more and more distressing circumstances, getting badly wounded on the fences. And the problem is simply not going away.
MONTAGNE: Last year, you published a book on your work. It's been widely praised. The title is "Illegality, Inc." Talk to us about the Inc. part. How do you think illegal migration from Africa to Europe has become an industry?
ANDERSSON: Well, we've seen more and more over the past two decades how a larger and larger range of sectors have become involved, in one way or another, in managing migration into Europe by land and sea and in border controls at Europe's external borders in the Mediterranean and the Atlantic. And we also have the various sectors that are involved in the more humanitarian side of things, and often they are collaborating with the security force. I'm thinking here of the assistance in deportation facilities, detention facilities and on the journey south as people get expelled back into Africa. And crucially, we have the - also the defense sector and the private companies involved in creating new border technologies, fences, radars. And we also see how it's not really working, how it's counterproductive in generating evermore risks for migrants and feeding also stronger smuggling business as border controls get strengthened.
MONTAGNE: One thing about the coverage of the desperation that we see in people crossing the Mediterranean - mostly people think of them as the poorest of the poor, but I gather you found that's not the case?
ANDERSSON: Yeah, we often think of these migrants and refugees reaching Europe as the most desperate of all. But, in fact, most migrants stay within their home region in West Africa at any rate. And the poorest of the poor move very little at all, or if anything to the next village. And they certainly don't set out on these very long, dangerous journeys towards Europe, which involve monies. Well, you do need to have some funds to move north, often family connections, family funds and often some level of education to embark on these very long and dangerous journeys.
MONTAGNE: What thoughts have your work given you as to what an alternative might be, a good alternative to what is being proposed, which is cracking down on the smugglers?
ANDERSSON: I think first of all, we need to start de-escalating the rhetoric. Of course this is a crisis right now in the Mediterranean in terms of the numbers of people dying. But at the same time, we can manage this. We shouldn't forget here that many parts of Europe are aging very rapidly and we'll need labor migrants in coming years. So we should really - also for our own sake - try to tap into migration as an opportunity rather than seeing it simply as a threat. And part of that involves re-establishing some form of legal pathways into the continent. We should remember that a few decades ago, we did have these roots. We had circular migration - countries such as France from West Africa. And we didn't have this type of boat migration back then. We need to leave an alternative to the smuggling business. We need to start undercutting the smuggling business or otherwise it's just going to keep getting strong and stronger.
MONTAGNE: Thank you very much for joining us.
ANDERSSON: Thank you.
MONTAGNE: Ruben Andersson is an anthropologist at the London School of Economics and Political Science.
GREENE: Andersson was speaking there with my colleague Renee Montagne.
(SOUNDBITE OF MUSIC)
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 12:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Southeast Asia Nations To Meet To Discuss Migrant Crisis</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/28/410204950/southeast-asia-nations-to-meet-to-discuss-migrant-crisis?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Representatives will meet in Bangkok on Friday to discuss the refugee crisis. The migrants are mainly members of Myanmar's Muslim minority Rohingya community and economic migrants from Bangladesh.</Description>
        <MainBody>Southeast Asia Nations To Meet To Discuss Migrant Crisis
May 28, 2015 5:01 AM ET
Michael Sullivan
Representatives will meet in Bangkok on Friday to discuss the refugee crisis. The migrants are mainly members of Myanmar's Muslim minority Rohingya community and economic migrants from Bangladesh.
DAVID GREENE, HOST:
Next, we're going to talk about the refugee crisis in two parts of the world, and we begin in Southeast Asia. Let's remember about a month ago, Thailand began cracking down on human trafficking. That prompted many traffickers to abandon their human cargo on boats at sea. These migrants are mainly members of Myanmar's Muslim minority, the Rohingya community, and also economic migrants from neighboring Bangladesh. Several thousand of these migrants remain at sea. Several thousand others have now landed on the shores of Thailand, Malaysia and Indonesia. Their future is the subject of a meeting taking place tomorrow in Bangkok that involves representatives from nearly two dozen nations and also the United Nations. Joining me on the line is reporter Michael Sullivan, who's been covering this story for NPR. Michael, good morning.
MICHAEL SULLIVAN, BYLINE: Good morning, David.
GREENE: So what exactly is this meeting, and what do people there hope to accomplish tomorrow?
SULLIVAN: Well, Thailand has called this meeting to try to figure out a way to stop this exodus from Myanmar's Rakhine State. And it's invited the neighbors to attend and anyone else with a stake. So the U.N. will be there and the U.S., which has offered to help with the search effort for those still at sea. And even Myanmar has agreed to attend, though it won't abide by the term Rohingya being used at the conference. It doesn't acknowledge that the Rohingya exist, even though there's more than a million of them in western Myanmar and have been there for centuries. Myanmar continues to insist that these people are Bengalis, meaning from Bangladesh. And they're not considered citizens. They're stateless people. And the way they get treated is wretched, and that's why they get on these boats in the first place. So there's going to be some efforts to get Myanmar to try to address this issue at the conference because human rights groups and some governments, like the U.S. government, say this is key. Myanmar is the root of the problem, and it has to take steps to address it.
GREENE: OK. Stopping the problem at its source, putting pressure on Myanmar - is Myanmar likely to listen?
SULLIVAN: Good luck with that. I mean, not unless the neighbors gang up on Myanmar. And that's not likely to happen because the first rule of ASEAN, the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, is non-interference in other country's internal affairs. But that's just it, David, because this isn't internal anymore. It's affecting everyone. And we've seen some impatience with Myanmar from the neighbors recently. Malaysia, last week, basically told Myanmar to get its house in order. They're tired of taking care of these refugees. They've got about 40,000 of them already, and they don't want anymore. And if Malaysia and Thailand and Indonesia got together and really leaned on Myanmar, we might see some action, but that's a big if.
GREENE: And, well, now, Michael, your reporting has now taken you to another Southeast Asian country - a poor one we should say - Cambodia. Why are you there?
SULLIVAN: I'm waiting for some refugees to arrive here, too, David. Cambodia has agreed to take a whole bunch of migrants who were trying to reach Australia but were caught and detained offshore. Australia is now outsourcing those refugees to Cambodia for a pile of cash. Human rights groups are crying foul, but the arrival of the first four is imminent, and one of them is a Muslim minority Rohingya from western Myanmar.
GREENE: All right, that's Michael Sullivan speaking to us from the city of Phnom Penh in Cambodia. Michael, thanks very much.
SULLIVAN: You're welcome, David.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
