<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man Re-Enacts Scene From Pixar's 'Up'</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/07/420769466/man-re-enacts-famous-scene-from-pixars-up?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>A Canadian man attached giant helium-filled balloons to a lawn chair -– and soared for miles over Calgary during a promotional stunt. But things went wrong, and he had to skydive back to land.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man Re-Enacts Scene From Pixar's 'Up'
July 07, 2015 7:33 AM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At Least 27 Dead After Attack On Hotel At Tunisian Beach Resort</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/26/417704593/19-dead-after-gunman-attacks-hotel-at-tunisian-beach-resort?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Interior Ministry officials report that at least one assailant opened fire on a hotel in the popular resort of Sousse.</Description>
        <MainBody>At Least 27 Dead After Attack On Hotel At Tunisian Beach Resort
June 26, 2015 8:29 AM ET
Twitter
A pair of gunmen attacked a tourist hotel on the popular Tunisian beachfront resort of Sousse, killing at least 27 people, including foreigners, according to the North African country's interior ministry.
The Associated Press quotes Interior Ministry spokesman Mohammed Ali Aroui as saying Tunisian security forces had killed one of the attackers and that the other had fled the scene.
The AP said there were no details of the nationalities of those killed, but noted that during the holy month of Ramadan, beach-goers tend to be tourists, not locals.
British tourist Gary Pine tells Sky News that he was on the beach when he heard what he and others thought was firecrackers going off nearby.
"There was a mass exodus off the beach," he said, as reported by the AP.
Pine said guests at his hotel were first told to lock themselves in their rooms and later, to gather in the lobby.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:16:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Report: ISIS Goes Door-To-Door Killing Scores Of Civilians In Kobani</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/26/417702031/report-isis-goes-door-to-door-killing-scores-of-civilians-in-kobani?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights calls the killing a massacre and says it is the worst such incident carried out by ISIS fighters since last year.</Description>
        <MainBody>i
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey on Friday. An attack by Islamic State fighters on the Syrian town of Kobani and a nearby village has so far killed at least 146 civilians, the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday. Murad Sezer/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Murad Sezer/Reuters/Landov
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey on Friday. An attack by Islamic State fighters on the Syrian town of Kobani and a nearby village has so far killed at least 146 civilians, the second-biggest massacre by the hardline group in the country, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Murad Sezer/Reuters/Landov
Fighters of the self-declared Islamic State have killed some 146 people in a house-to-house massacre of civilians in the Syrian border town of Kobani, a conflict monitoring group says, calling it the second-worse such mass killing by the Islamist extremists since last year.
NPR's Deborah Amos, reporting from southern Turkey, says the Britain-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights has spoken to witnesses who reported the shooting spree.
Citing medical sources in Kobani, the Syrian Observatory said the civilians "were executed by [the Islamic State] in their homes or killed by the group's rockets or snipers," Rami Abdel Rahman, the Observatory's director said. The group said that militants "fired at everything that moved."
The Associated Press quotes Kobani-based Kurdish activist Mustafa Bali as saying "that small groups of jihadis are still in the town and have taken civilians hostage in at least three locations." At a restaurant where hostages had been taken, Kurdish fighters stormed the building and freed the captives, Bali told the AP.
"The militants launched twin attacks on Thursday, in Kobani, also farther east in one of the last government held areas in northern Syria," Deborah says. "More than 60,000 people are now displaced, according to the United Nations [and] another 200,000 may yet flee as ISIS fights take over areas formerly held by the regime" of Bashar al-Assad.
The reported massacre comes a day after the Islamic State launched an attack to recapture the city after being forced out in January after fierce battles with Kurdish fighters.
Kurdish officials say ISIS militants secretly infiltrated the town by wearing Syrian rebel uniforms and carrying flags of the Free Syrian Army.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man Beheaded In Terrorist Attack On French Factory</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/26/417696368/man-beheaded-at-french-factory-in-apparent-isis-attack?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Police have arrested one suspect over the attack, which also included an explosion at the facility operated by Air Products, an American company.</Description>
        <MainBody>Man Beheaded In Terrorist Attack On French Factory
June 26, 2015 6:41 AM ET
French security and emergency services gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, the scene of an attack on an industrial gas factory Friday. Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
French security and emergency services gather at the entrance of the Air Products company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, the scene of an attack on an industrial gas factory Friday.
Philippe Desmazes/AFP/Getty Images
One person has been killed and at least 12 others injured in an attack on a gas factory in a small town in southeastern France. Officials say it was a terrorist attack: a flag of the self-declared Islamic State was reportedly found at the factory southeast of Lyon.
One suspect has been arrested over the attack, which also included an explosion at the facility operated by Air Products, an American company whose headquarters are in Pennsylvania. It's not yet certain whether he was acting alone.
"The terrorist nature of this act are without doubt," says French President Francois Hollande, who will return home today from a European Union economic summit in Brussels.
Update at 8:25 p.m. ET: Details On Victim, Vehicle
The person who was killed was the manager of a transport company who was making a delivery, according to local newspaper Dauphine Libere . The newspaper adds that the prefect of Isere, John Paul Bonnetain, says the attacking vehicle was authorized to enter the factory  giving support to the theory that the vehicle belonged to a contractor or supplier.
Dauphine Libere also reports that a second arrest has been made  of a person whose vehicle was seen repeatedly passing in front of the factory Friday morning  but that no direct link has been established between the events.
Update at 7:25 p.m. ET: Suspect Had Been Monitored
Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve says the suspect in the case, who is believed to have lived near Lyon, had no prior criminal record. He also said that the man had been monitored by authorities as far back as 2006, but he was found not to be in communication with terrorist groups.
Cazeneuve also stated that the suspect had been detained by a local firefighter who was among the first responders at the scene.
"I salute this courage," he said.
Our original post continues:
From Calais, NPR's Eleanor Beardsley reports:
"One or maybe two men rammed the gates of a gas factory in the small industrial town. An explosion followed. The man killed was beheaded, and his head was placed at the front of the factory along with a flag of the so-called Islamic State.
"Residents of the small town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier interviewed on television expressed shock that such an attack could take place in their tiny town."
According to its website, Air Products specializes in producing industrial and medical gases, listing oxygen, nitrogen, argon, helium and hydrogen as its chief products.
France's interior minister has ordered increased security at other potential targets around the country.
Speaking about the attack, Hollande said, "Our answer is prevention, deterrence and thus the necessity of embracing values and not giving in to fear, ever."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:04:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrants In French Camp Near English Channel Attempt To Get Into Britain</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/26/417675817/migrants-in-french-camp-near-english-channel-attempt-to-get-into-britain?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>European leaders are meeting in Brussels Friday to deal with the migrant crisis. At a squalid camp in northern France, migrants plot to stow away on trucks to cross the English Channel into Britain.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrants In French Camp Near English Channel Attempt To Get Into Britain
June 26, 2015 5:04 AM ET

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:22:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait Says Saudi Responsible For Mosque Suicide Bombing</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/28/418279847/kuwait-fingers-saudi-in-mosque-suicide-bombing?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Officials say the Saudi national flew into the neighboring Gulf nation hours before launching the attack that killed 27 worshipers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait Says Saudi Responsible For Mosque Suicide Bombing
June 28, 2015 9:22 AM ET
People gather near flag-draped coffins of Kuwaiti Shiite victims from Friday's suicide bombing at a mosque in the capital. Khider Abbas/EPA/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Khider Abbas/EPA/Landov
People gather near flag-draped coffins of Kuwaiti Shiite victims from Friday's suicide bombing at a mosque in the capital.
Khider Abbas/EPA/Landov
The suicide bomber who attacked a Shiite mosque in Kuwait last week , killing 27 people, was a Saudi national who flew into the neighboring Gulf nation hours before carrying out his deadly mission, Kuwaiti officials say. The self-declared Islamic State later claimed responsibility for the attack.
The Associated Press reports that Kuwait police have started making arrests in connection with the bombing during Friday midday prayers at the Imam Sadiq Mosque in Kuwait City.
The AP reports:
"The Interior Ministry named the bomber as Fahad Suleiman Abdulmohsen al-Gabbaa and said he was born in 1992, making him 22 or 23 years old. It said in a statement carried by the official Kuwait News Agency that he arrived on a flight to Kuwait International Airport at dawn Friday.
"Authorities also said they arrested a 25-year-old from Kuwait's 'bidoon'  or desert nomad  community, identified as Abdulrahman Sabah Eidan Saud, who they say drove the car that brought the bomber to the mosque."
The Interior Ministry described Abdulrahman as a follower of "fundamentalist and deviant ideology."
Reuters says:
"Officials said the bombing was clearly meant to stir enmity between majority Sunnis and minority Shiites and harm the comparatively harmonious ties between the sects in Kuwait.
"Shiites are between 15 and 30 percent of the population of Kuwait, a mostly Sunni country where members of both communities live side by side with little apparent friction."
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:53:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran, World Powers Will Work Past Deadline Toward Nuclear Deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/07/420776190/as-another-deadline-looms-theres-still-no-sign-of-nuclear-deal-with-iran?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Western powers and Iran said they will not be pressured into accepting a bad deal by a deadline. The two sides had already extended a previous deadline for a final deal in June.</Description>
        <MainBody>Iran, World Powers Will Work Past Deadline Toward Nuclear Deal
July 07, 2015 6:53 AM ET
Secretary of State John Kerry meets with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif in Vienna, Austria, on Friday. Carlos Barria  /AP hide caption
itoggle caption Carlos Barria  /AP
Secretary of State John Kerry meets with Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif in Vienna, Austria, on Friday.
Carlos Barria  /AP
Just hours before a self imposed deadline, Iran and six world powers said they would not extend a deadline but they would keep working toward a deal over Iran's nuclear program for the next few days.
Reporting from Vienna, where the talks are taking place, NPR's Peter Kenyon says both sides are saying they will not be pressured into accepting a bad deal. Peter filed this report for our Newscast unit:
"EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini says Iran and six world powers are not extending the July 7 deadline, just interpreting it with a certain flexibility. Both iran and the U.S. have said getting the right nuclear agreement is more important than any single deadline.
"If they do manage to finish by early Thursday, negotiators could still deliver a deal to congress by their July 9 deadline. If they don't, Congress gets an extra 30 days to weigh in on the agreement. Many members of Congress describe the accord as not strong enough."
Al Jazeera reports that Iranian officials say the two sides are divided by a few thorny issues. Chief among them is whether U.N. sanctions on Iran's ballistic missile program should be lifted.
"The Iranians want the ballistic missile sanctions lifted. They say there is no reason to connect it with the nuclear issue, a view that is difficult to accept," an unnamed Western official told Reuters . "There's no appetite for that on our part."
Of course, this cuts to the heart of what's at stake in these negotiations: Western powers are trying to keep Iran from developing a nuclear weapon, while Iran has always insisted that its nuclear program has been used only for peaceful purposes.
The two sides agreed to an interim deal that curbed some parts of Iran's nuclear programs in November 2013. That deal set a July 2014 deadline for a broader deal. That deadline was extended to November. After that deadline was missed, Iran and six world powers announced that they had reached a framework agreement in April.
They then set a June 30 deadline for coming up with a finalized deal. That deadline was extended to July 7.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:11:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hackers Target Controversial Italian Cyber Espionage Company</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/07/420769459/hackers-target-controversial-italian-cyber-espionage-company?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Spyware belonging to the security firm Hacking Team has been detected in many countries with repressive regimes. The firm's client list is secret, but a hack has made thousands of documents public.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hackers Target Controversial Italian Cyber Espionage Company
July 07, 2015 5:11 AM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>With Greece Facing Economic Abyss, What Will EU Leaders Do?</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/07/420769508/with-greece-facing-economic-abyss-what-will-eu-leaders-do?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The result of Sunday's Greek referendum was a resounding "no" to plans for more austerity as a way out of the country's debt crisis. European leaders meet Tuesday to resume talks on a rescue package.</Description>
        <MainBody>With Greece Facing Economic Abyss, What Will EU Leaders Do?
July 07, 2015 5:11 AM ET

=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ukraine's Double Woes: War And Runaway Inflation</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/28/418262045/ukraines-double-woes-war-and-runaway-inflation?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Beyond the battlefront in the east, the Ukrainian government is fighting a war to reform a monumentally corrupt, dysfunctional economy. For now, Ukrainians seem willing to weather 60 percent inflation.</Description>
        <MainBody>
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Memories Of London's 2005 Terrorist Attack Live On As If It Were Yesterday</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/07/420769480/10-years-on-2-people-remember-the-july-terror-attacks-in-london?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>On July 7, 2005, terrorists hit public transportation networks across London in a series of suicide bombings. Ten years later, we hear the personal stories of two people remembering that day.</Description>
        <MainBody>Memories Of London's 2005 Terrorist Attack Live On As If It Were Yesterday
July 07, 2015 5:11 AM ET
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:04:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kosovo: The Pros And Cons Of Being Europe's Newest Country</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/26/417675810/kosovo-the-pros-and-cons-of-being-europe-s-newest-country?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>America played a major role in Kosovo's fight for independence. Now, seven years after its emergence as a country, Kosovo suffers growing pains with more than half the young people unemployed.</Description>
        <MainBody>
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>7 Years After Kosovo's Independence, A Border Still Fraught With Tension</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/28/418261966/7-years-after-kosovos-independence-a-border-still-fraught-with-tension?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Kosovo gained independence from Serbia less than a decade ago. The two have not yet reconciled, which is apparent when crossing the border between the countries.</Description>
        <MainBody>7 Years After Kosovo's Independence, A Border Still Fraught With Tension
June 28, 2015 7:48 AM ET
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Global Financial Crisis Did A Real Number On Greece's Economy</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/07/420769445/the-global-financial-crisis-really-did-a-number-on-greece-s-economy?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Greece and its European creditors remain at a stalemate. European leaders say without changes, they won't provide any more aid.  Greek banks are closed - unable to get the cash they need to operate.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Global Financial Crisis Did A Real Number On Greece's Economy
July 07, 2015 5:11 AM ET
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A Showdown Looms At South Korea's Gay Pride Parade</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/06/26/417310709/a-showdown-looms-at-south-koreas-gay-pride-parade?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In Seoul, a parade that has gone on for 15 years is at the heart of a bitter standoff between organizers and Christian activists. Church groups threaten to stop the parade — in the name of God.</Description>
        <MainBody>A Showdown Looms At South Korea's Gay Pride Parade
June 26, 2015 5:00 AM ET
A religious activist is carried away by police after he tried to stop a gay pride parade in Seoul last year. Christian activists are planning to disrupt the parade again this year. Ed Jones/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Ed Jones/AFP/Getty Images
A religious activist is carried away by police after he tried to stop a gay pride parade in Seoul last year. Christian activists are planning to disrupt the parade again this year.
Ed Jones/AFP/Getty Images
In Seoul, a gay pride parade 15 years in the running is at the center of heated controversy between LGBT groups and Christian activists, who threaten to do what it takes to stop the marchers.
The growing visibility of South Korea's gays and lesbians has led to louder opposition from church groups in recent years, and this weekend's event has organizers preparing for confrontation.
"In the Bible, homosexuality is sin. And to publicize your personal, private identity like that is a problem," says Pastor Jonah Lee of Calvary Church in Seoul. He is part of the religious opposition to gay culture, and calls himself formerly gay  cured of 43 years of homosexuality.
Gay rights in South Korea have become so contentious that at a pride month kickoff event earlier in June, more anti-gay protesters showed up than LGBT participants.
The Christian groups blared a Korean version of the Battle Hymn of the Republic to try and drown out pride event speakers. They also handed out leaflets, shouted into megaphones, and held up signs with messages like "Homosexuality will destroy humanity."
"Churches oppose the festival and parade because it's too decadent," says Lee. "Korea is not as open and free so as you could walk around with your bottom hanging out like that."
Public polls seem to back up the pastor. A Pew Research Center survey on moral issues found that 57 percent of South Koreans thought that homosexuality was unacceptable, while 18 percent said it was acceptable.
Disruptions Last Year
At last year's parade, Christian protesters laid down in the streets, singing songs and stalling LGBT marchers for hours. This year, religious groups tried to stop the parade from happening at all. They flooded the police with permit applications to rally on the same day as the pride parade. It jammed up the permitting process, leading the Seoul Police to ban the parade altogether , citing safety reasons.
But a court last week overturned the ban  upholding the LGBT group's right to assemble.
"Everybody has a right to protest, including the religious groups. What they don't have the right to do is to stop other people gathering in the way that they express themselves," says Graeme Reid. He's the LGBT rights director for Human Rights Watch.
"As there's progress on one level, and in this instance, internationally, we see an overall trend toward more inclusive policies. But then, we often see a reaction to those gains. And I think that's what we're seeing in South Korea," Reid says.
Now, all eyes turn to Sunday, when as many as 20,000 are expected to turn out for the parade and festivities around it. Organizers  like Kang Myeong-jin  say they have to prepare for confrontation.
"There's the possibility of unpredicted behaviors from the haters. And their sole purpose is to stop the parade, but it's a matter of how they're going to stop it, what they're going to do, so we need to prepare against that," Kang says.
Organizers have warned participants to be ready for flying objects, long stalls along the route and other potential safety hazards. For his part, the pastor says he doesn't condone physical or violent confrontations.
"Extreme measures to LGBT parades will only breed social conflict. I try to convince the church on this matter, but I get a lot of contempt from them," Lee says.
HaeRyun Kang contributed to this story. For behind-the-scenes photos and observations from our Seoul bureau, check out our East Asia Tumblr, Elise Goes East .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 11:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Polio Is Active In Only 3 Countries. Soon It Could Be Down To 2</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/06/26/417113319/polio-is-active-in-only-3-countries-soon-it-could-be-down-to-2?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Nigeria is one of three places where polio is still a problem. But there hasn't been a case in almost a year. So Africa is on the verge of being polio-free.</Description>
        <MainBody>Polio Is Active In Only 3 Countries. Soon It Could Be Down To 2
June 26, 2015 4:58 AM ET
At the health clinic in Minjibir, Nigeria, a child is immunized for polio. David Gilkey/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption David Gilkey/NPR
At the health clinic in Minjibir, Nigeria, a child is immunized for polio.
David Gilkey/NPR
Nigeria is on the verge of being polio-free. And that would mean that for the first time ever there's no ongoing polio transmission on the African continent.
Nigeria is one of just three countries in the world, along with Pakistan and Afghanistan, where polio transmission has never been fully stopped. But no trace of the virus has been found in Nigeria since a child was paralyzed with the disease on July 24, 2014. If the West African nation reaches a full year with no new cases, the World Health Organization will strike Nigeria off the list of countries with active polio transmission.
"It would be a major milestone in the global polio eradication initiative," says Hamid Jafari, the head of polio eradication at WHO in Geneva.
Over the last 20 years Nigeria has been the primary obstacle to eradicating polio on the African continent. Every other African nation managed to extinguish polio at one point or another, but many of those countries were hit with new outbreaks linked to polio from Nigeria.
Nigeria didn't just fail to vaccinate children. At times communities actively fought polio immunization campaigns. Religious leaders denounced the vaccination drops as part of a Western plot to sterilize Muslim children. Vaccinators were shot and killed.
"They [Nigerian health officials] did not have the political commitment," says Jon Andrus, the executive vice president of the Sabin Vaccine Institute. Andrus spent 30 years working on polio eradication for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the World Health Organization, including in Nigeria.
"They did not have good supervision and management of field staff," he says. "They did not have the engagement of the community probably the most important factor in making sure all children get vaccinated."
He says 15 years ago Nigeria was an incredibly frustrating place to work. Andrus remembers meeting with politicians in Northern Nigeria back in 2001 and finally getting the governor to agree to launch a polio vaccination campaign.
"Sure enough a month later the government refused to do the campaign and then Nigeria started exporting the viruses to the rest of Africa so it was quite a setback,"
Nigeria came under huge international pressure to get polio under control. Aid agencies used carrots and sticks and shame to try to get the West African nation to contain the virus. They promised additional international funds for other pressing health needs. but the additional assistance was contingent on Nigeria tackling polio. Local religious leaders were courted, wooed and cajoled in to supporting the vaccination campaigns.
Then the public had to be brought on board too. At one point the Emir of Kano publicly immunized his own children and drank a vial of polio vaccine to prove it was safe.
Hamid Jafari, the polio chief at the WHO, doesn't want to declare victory too quickly. He speaks like a man afraid he might jinx this whole thing. Nigeria's come close to wiping out polio before. In 2010 the West African nation had just 21 cases only to see the virus come roaring back.
"We are not yet certain that the wild polio virus is gone from the African continent," he says. "We have not yet completed the full surveillance time of 12 months in Nigeria. And there are areas in the African region in the northeast of Nigeria, Lake Chad, the north of Cameroon where the situation is uncertain security-wise. We may have undetected transmission of polio virus there."
In parts of northern Nigeria controlled by Boko Haram it's impossible for health officials to vaccinate children or monitor for new cases of polio. Jafari says polio could possibly be spreading undetected in some pockets.
Even if the last reservoirs of polio on the African continent have been wiped out, Jafari says mass polio vaccination campaigns will have to continue globally until the virus is stopped completely in Afghanistan and Pakistan.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. Army Begins Training Ukrainian Soldiers</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/06/25/417511636/u-s-army-begins-training-ukrainian-soldiers?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The U.S. won't give the Ukrainian army lethal weapons to fight separatists and their Russian allies, but it has sent 300 trainers to help the beleaguered, bedraggled Ukrainian military.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. Army Begins Training Ukrainian Soldiers
June 25, 2015 5:50 PM ET
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice protecting and recovering wounded comrades as American military trainers watch. Corey Flintoff/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Corey Flintoff/NPR
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice protecting and recovering wounded comrades as American military trainers watch.
Corey Flintoff/NPR
Fighting surged again this week in eastern Ukraine, where government troops are battling separatist militias and their Russian allies.
NATO is responding by sending troops and equipment to eastern Europe, and it's also giving defensive training to Ukraine's beleaguered army.
First, you need to know how bad things were for the Ukrainian army when separatist militias and their Russian allies began the fight in eastern Ukraine in April 2014.
Miroslav Gai volunteered for the army last winter.
I met him in Kiev, and this is how he described its state of readiness: "The army gave me just my weapon and uniform, and bring me with my friends to Slovyansk and say, 'OK, fight.' "
Gai saw many of his friends killed around the eastern city of Slovyansk in the winter and spring of 2014. He says he wouldn't have survived without food and warm clothing provided by volunteers from Kiev.
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice skills shared by U.S. trainers. A U.S. brigade commander says the mission is as much a learning experience for the Americans as it is for the Ukrainians. Corey Flintoff/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Corey Flintoff/NPR
Ukrainian national guardsmen practice skills shared by U.S. trainers. A U.S. brigade commander says the mission is as much a learning experience for the Americans as it is for the Ukrainians.
Corey Flintoff/NPR
He now runs a volunteer foundation that helps supply Ukrainian soldiers with body armor and clothing.
The Ukrainian military says it's doing everything it can to make its army combat-ready.
That's happening on a sprawling base and firing range near the Polish border.
I'm here to watch about 300 American paratroopers from the U.S. Army's 173rd Airborne Brigade, who've arrived to work with about 750 Ukrainian national guardsmen.
Practice ranges on all sides of us are crackling with weapons fire, everything from hand grenades to heavy machine guns.
"Part of what we really want to do here is just to help these guys in terms of survivability, in terms of flexibility," says Army Capt. Steven Modugno.
He says the Americans were surprised to find that most of their initial trainees already had combat experience in the war in eastern Ukraine.
Two Ukrainian soldiers in the first group, he says, were actually decorated war heroes from their service in the east.
Modugno says what started as basic infantry training quickly grew more complex, when the trainees started asking questions like, "When we know that there's a potentially hostile drone monitoring us, how do we react?"
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>For Poland's Gay Community, A Shift In Public Attitudes, If Not Laws</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/parallels/2015/06/25/417446107/for-polands-gay-community-a-shift-in-public-attitudes-if-not-laws?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Poland does not allow gay marriage or same-sex unions, and is unlikely to amend these laws anytime soon. But the city of Gdansk elected an openly gay mayor and has hosted its first gay pride march.</Description>
        <MainBody>For Poland's Gay Community, A Shift In Public Attitudes, If Not Laws
June 25, 2015 5:09 PM ET
Marchers carried a multicolor flag during Warsaw's annual gay pride parade earlier this month. Poland prohibits gay marriage but activists say attitudes toward gays have improved in recent years. Alik Keplicz/AP hide caption
itoggle caption Alik Keplicz/AP
Marchers carried a multicolor flag during Warsaw's annual gay pride parade earlier this month. Poland prohibits gay marriage but activists say attitudes toward gays have improved in recent years.
Alik Keplicz/AP
Around the world, gay marriage is allowed in more than 20 countries. Many European Union nations are enhancing rights for their gay, bisexual and transgender citizens. But Catholic Poland isn't one of them.
This former Soviet satellite constitutionally restricts marriage to a man and a woman. Recent efforts to pass laws to protect the LGBT community in Poland from discrimination and violence have gone nowhere.
But there is one notable change these days  in Polish attitudes.
Ireland Votes Overwhelmingly To Approve Same-Sex Marriage
The Polish city of Gdansk, on the country's Pomeranian coast, is famous for being first. World War II is widely regarded as having started here in 1939. So did the Solidarity workers' movement of the 1980s, which helped precipitate the demise of the Soviet Union.
Last month, Gdansk celebrated another first  a gay rights march that attracted about 1,000 participants.
"Gdansk is a symbol of freedom," says psychologist Marta Kosinska, who helped organize the event. "And we are fighting for freedom, too."
Yet even two years ago, a gay rights march in this city would have been unthinkable.
At that time, its most famous native  Polish democracy icon Lech Walesa, founder of the Solidarity movement  said on TV that gays had no right to impose their will on the Polish majority. Nor should they play a prominent role in Polish politics, he added.
Homophobic attitudes were prevalent among Polish lawmakers when Robert Biedron was elected as a member of parliament back in 2011.
i
Slupsk Mayor Robert Biedron (from left) and LGBT activists Marta Abramowicz and Marta Kosinska stand next to a symbolic Gdansk lion statue painted in rainbow colors in honor of the city's first gay rights march, held in May. Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson/NPR
Slupsk Mayor Robert Biedron (from left) and LGBT activists Marta Abramowicz and Marta Kosinska stand next to a symbolic Gdansk lion statue painted in rainbow colors in honor of the city's first gay rights march, held in May.
Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson/NPR
"I was the first member of the Polish parliament who was openly gay," Biedron says, "and they would not be brave enough to shake hands publicly because somebody would think they're gay."
Nor did his colleagues take him seriously.
"I remember when I went to the parliament and had my first speech," he says. "I was defending one issue and I said, 'Your arguments are below the belt.' They all started to laugh. ... They thought I'm talking about sexuality. And when they asked them why they are laughing, they said, 'What else can a gay guy talk about?' "
But Biedron, 39, says attitudes toward gays are improving, in part because the Catholic Church's influence is shrinking in Poland and because more Poles are coming out of the closet.
Take, for example, Biedron's own successful run last year for mayor of the northern city of Slupsk. Biedron was one of about 30 gay candidates who ran in local races across Poland. He says his opponents never made his sexual orientation a campaign issue.
His partner of 12 years attended Biedron's swearing-in ceremony  the first time he's done so.
"To go finally with my partner for the public ceremony was one of the greatest things, and I had my mother with me," Biedron says.
Polish gay rights activists say there are other changes, too, including the opening of central Europe's first homeless shelter for LGBT teens earlier this year in Warsaw.
Marianna Szczygielska, the project coordinator for the Warsaw-based Campaign against Homophobia, says attitudes toward gays here began to change when Poland joined the European Union in 2004.
"Also with [the] opening of borders after joining the European Union, things have changed, especially for queer youth," she says. "Even LGBT characters being featured in popular TV series, that already makes a difference in social acceptance towards LGBT."
But the group's vice president, Miroslawa Makuchowska, fears that progress could be short-lived, as happened in Ukraine following the annexation of Crimea and the lingering war in the east.
"The public discourse [in Ukraine] has said, 'Look, you are not important right now. We cannot discuss gay issues right now. Stop talking about it.' It's all about the war."
She predicts that real equality for Poland's LGBT community could be generations away.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:37:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The Cycling World May Soon Bow Down Before Nairo Quintana</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/06/25/417115274/the-cycling-world-may-soon-bow-down-before-nairo-quintana?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In 2013, a newcomer from Colombia passed almost everyone else and came in second in the Tour de France. This year, many think he'll take home the winning yellow jersey.</Description>
        <MainBody>The Cycling World May Soon Bow Down Before Nairo Quintana
June 25, 2015 4:37 PM ET
John Otis
Colombian cyclist Nairo Quintana poses for a snapshot during a training session this month in Colombia. LUIS ACOSTA/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption LUIS ACOSTA/AFP/Getty Images
Colombian cyclist Nairo Quintana poses for a snapshot during a training session this month in Colombia.
LUIS ACOSTA/AFP/Getty Images
He began biking to get to high school. The return trip was a 10-mile uphill slog. That didn't deter Nairo Quintana. Sometimes he'd even attach a cable to his sister's bike and haul her up the mountain with him.
And now some pundits think that the 25-year-old Colombian athlete could win the grueling, three-week Tour de France, which kicks off on July 4.
When Quintana was growing up, there were few signs he would become an elite athlete. He was raised on a farm 10,000 feet high in the Andes near the village of Combita. As a toddler he nearly died from a bad case of diarrhea. Rather than sports, he used his free time he helped his father, Luis, who raised cows and sold fruit and vegetables.
A Tour De France First: An African Team Will Compete This Year
His school bicycle commutes led him to competitive cycling. Soon, Nairo was winning local races on a second-hand clunker.
"You could earn up to $50 per race," he says. "There were two races per week. So that's $100. I would use the money to buy new parts for my bike."
The pint-sized Quintana weighs just 130 pounds but has a monster cardiovascular system. Jenaro Leguizamo, a Colombian sports trainer, once tested Quintana's VO2 max, which shows how efficiently athletes use oxygen and is a key performance indicator. He says the level was better than any of today's top cyclists.
As Nairo Quintana trains on a twisting mountain road, Colombian children cheer him on. When he stops to drink water, he's surrounded by fans who take souvenir photos.
Quintana first pedaled to glory in 2013. Riding in his first Tour de France when he was just 23, he came in second.
It was the highest-ever finish for a Latin American. Addressing Quintana, an ecstatic Colombian race announcer shouted: "The whole world bows down before you!"
Last year, Quintana became the first Latin American to win the Giro D'Italia, cycling's second most important road race.
It helps that Quintana grew up in a country with a strong network of cycling clubs and teams. In addition, Colombia is home to Latin America's oldest multistage bike race with mountain passes far higher than those in the Tour de France.
Colombia is the only Latin American nation that consistently produces world-class bike racers. One of the most famous  and gutsiest  was Luis Herrera.
In 1985, Herrera crashed on a descent. A TV announced reporter: "His eye is absolutely streaming with blood." But he hung on to win this mountain stage of the Tour de France, inspiring a generation of Colombian cyclists.
That's a role Quintana now fills. While following him in a taxi, we pull up beside a junior cyclist, 16-year-old Danilo Ardila. He's pedaling hard to catch up to Quintana.
"He's an example," Ardila says. "Everyone who rides a bike wants to be like him."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:37:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French Taxi Drivers Launch Nationwide Uber Protest</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/25/417516427/french-taxi-drivers-launch-nationwide-uber-protest?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>French taxi drivers stage a nationwide strike to protest UberPop's encroachment on their market.  It turned nasty after an Uber driver and passenger were beaten up.</Description>
        <MainBody>French Taxi Drivers Launch Nationwide Uber Protest
June 25, 2015 4:37 PM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Tama, The Cat That Saved A Japanese Train Station, Dies</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417440765/tama-the-cat-that-saved-a-japanese-train-station-dies?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Tourists would come to the Kishi train station near Wakayama City to see the feline hanging out in her office — a converted ticket booth — wearing a railway hat and collar.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tama, The Cat That Saved A Japanese Train Station, Dies
June 25, 2015 2:55 PM ET
Tama had held sway as stationmaster of the Kishi train station since 2007. Toru Yamanaka/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Toru Yamanaka/AFP/Getty Images
Tama had held sway as stationmaster of the Kishi train station since 2007.
Toru Yamanaka/AFP/Getty Images
A calico cat in southeastern Japan has left some big paw prints to fill. Tama, who served as "stationmaster" of the Kishi train station near Wakayama City, died Monday from acute heart failure, according to CNN. She was 16 (about 80 in cat years), the network reports.
Tama is credited with saving the train station from financial ruin. Tourists would come to the station to see her hanging out in her office  a converted ticket booth  wearing a railway hat and collar. (A stationmaster is, generally, the human in charge of running the facility.)
@airlineflyer Hmm. You need to ride on Tama the cat train. #StationCat http://t.co/Vps0D6MEET pic.twitter.com/mn7XWJ3TNi
 Kevin-Economy&amp;Beyond (@EconomyBeyond) April 29, 2015
The railway system's president, Mitsonubu Kojima, said he visited Tama the day before she died and that she "stood up and let out a strong meow."
Tama's station is on the outskirts of Wakayama City, according to a CNN report in 2013. Aside from local residents, not many people traveled through the station. The current railway operator selected Tama, who was owned by a local family, as stationmaster in 2007 to try to bring in more travelers.
She had a noticeable impact, according to Kyodo News :
"The number of passengers on the line jumped to 2.27 million in fiscal 2014 from 1.92 million in fiscal 2005. Photos of Tama and other merchandise also sold well, leading to her appointment to acting president of Wakayama Electric Railway in January 2013."
Here's more from CNN's 2013 story:
"Kishi station currently houses a Tama-themed cafe, as well as a souvenir shop with items ranging from the usual array of pens, staplers and other supplies, to Kishi Station uniforms.
"Tama's cuteness is exploited wherever possible  from the chairs to the cakes in the cafe to the cat-shaped station building itself.
"There's also a cat stationmaster apprentice, Nitama, who shoulders some responsibilities for Tama. Sleeping and doing nothing is hard work, you know?"
A memorial service reportedly is set for Sunday.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope: Sometimes Marital Separation 'Morally Necessary'</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417459458/pope-sometimes-marital-separation-morally-necessary?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Francis, speaking during his weekly general audience, said couples splitting may be needed to protect "the weaker spouse" and children.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nuns greet Pope Francis as he arrives to lead the weekly audience in Saint Peter's Square at the Vatican on Thursday. The pope, speaking at his weekly general audience, said sometimes separation is "morally necessary." Tony Gentile/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Tony Gentile/Reuters/Landov
Nuns greet Pope Francis as he arrives to lead the weekly audience in Saint Peter's Square at the Vatican on Thursday. The pope, speaking at his weekly general audience, said sometimes separation is "morally necessary."
Tony Gentile/Reuters/Landov
Pope Francis, speaking on family issues, says that sometimes marriages are so damaged that it is "morally necessary" for a husband and wife to separate.
"There are cases in which separation is inevitable," the pontiff said at his weekly general audience. "Sometimes it can become even morally necessary, precisely when it comes to subtracting the weaker spouse, or small children, from more serious injuries caused by arrogance and violence, by humiliation and exploitation ... and by indifference."
Sometimes parents need to separate for the sake of their children, @Pontifex says. http://t.co/jDIKc24yGr pic.twitter.com/5mWZKMbyyz
 NCR (@NCRonline) June 24, 2015
"Let us ask the Lord for a strong faith to see with his eyes the reality of family life, and for a deep love to approach all families with his merciful heart," he said.
The Associated Press notes: "Francis has been making a series of statements about family issues ahead of a much-anticipated October synod, or meeting, of bishops to address the topic. The bishops will take up many issues, including how the church can be more welcoming to divorced Catholics who remarry without going through the church process that declares their first marriage null."
The church has long said that divorced members cannot participate in communion. Time magazine writes: "There's no precise estimate worldwide, but according to Georgetown University's Center for Applied Research in the Apostolate, some 4.5 million Catholics in the United States (alone) are divorced and remarried without an 'annulment,' a declaration from a church court that the first marriage was invalid."
In December, speaking in an interview with the Argentine newspaper La Nacion, Francis said the church must consider ways to integrate divorced and civilly remarried people."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Stealthy' Giant Rhea Eludes Police In U.K.</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417426469/stealthy-giant-rhea-eludes-police-in-u-k?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The ostrich-like bird, native to South America, escaped from a farm in Nottinghamshire last week.</Description>
        <MainBody>'Stealthy' Giant Rhea Eludes Police In U.K.
June 25, 201510:33 AM ET
The female partner of the missing rhea bird that has been on the loose from a private collection in Carlton-in-Lindrick near Worksop, Nottinghamshire, U.K. Joe Giddens/PA Photos/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Joe Giddens/PA Photos/Landov
The female partner of the missing rhea bird that has been on the loose from a private collection in Carlton-in-Lindrick near Worksop, Nottinghamshire, U.K.
Joe Giddens/PA Photos/Landov
The giant ostrich-like rhea, despite its largely useless vestigial wings, seems to be something of a flight risk.
Last year , we brought you the story of one of the birds  native to South America  that escaped from a farm in the U.K., startling cyclists and otherwise wreaking mayhem in the English countryside.
Well, here we go again. The Daily Mail reports that another rhea is on the lam in rural Nottinghamshire after escaping last week.
The mate of a rhea bird missing in Nottinghamshire is said to be pacing their field by herself http://t.co/a1hbLF2D2C pic.twitter.com/ySMwBOaZJM
 Sky News (@SkyNews) June 25, 2015
As we mentioned last year, the rhea can sprint at 40 mph and, if provoked, deliver a nasty kick capable of seriously injuring a human.
"We are warning local people and particularly those with small children to be on their guard and not to approach the bird, which poses a very real threat to the public due to its size, aggressive nature and the unfamiliar surroundings it could find itself in," Inspector Paul Peatfield of the Nottinghamshire Police was quoted by the Mail as saying.
"Officers are working with the owner to trace the bird as we look to bring his incident to a safe conclusion," he said.
David Lindo, described as a bird expert by the BBC , says rheas are "quite stealthy and they'll be running off, hiding into the bushes ... they can melt into the countryside quite easily."
However, he said that the danger the birds pose has been "overrated."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 16:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>ISIS Launches Push To Retake Border Town Of Kobani</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/06/25/417415672/isis-launches-push-to-re-take-border-town-of-kobani?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The battle began with one or more car bombs set off inside the Syrian city. There are unconfirmed reports that Islamic State fighters hid themselves among refugees flooding into Kobani.</Description>
        <MainBody>ISIS Launches Push To Retake Border Town Of Kobani
June 25, 2015 9:04 AM ET
Civilians, reportedly wounded by fighting in Kobani, wait with their relatives to cross into Turkey at the Syrian-Turkish border crossing of Tel Abyad, Syria, on Thursday. Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Reuters/Landov
Civilians, reportedly wounded by fighting in Kobani, wait with their relatives to cross into Turkey at the Syrian-Turkish border crossing of Tel Abyad, Syria, on Thursday.
Reuters/Landov
Islamic State fighters, who were ousted from the Kurdish border town of Kobani in January, have launched an offensive to recapture the Syrian city  setting off car bombs as a prelude to an attack, NPR's Deborah Amos reports.
Deborah, reporting from southern Turkey near the Syrian border, says thousands of Kurdish civilians have been coming to Kobani from Ar Raqqa, the de facto capital of the self-declared Islamic State, after being forced out of the city by the Islamist extremists. Deborah says there are unconfirmed reports that Islamic State militants hid themselves among the returning refugees.
Al-Jazeera says its sources report that Islamic State fighters "were wearing Kurdish and Free Syrian Army uniforms ... as they attacked from three sides and took several positions inside the battleground town."
This latest attack comes as ISIS had lost ground due to the Kurdish militia backed by the U.S.
The Associated Press says that "in Kobani ... an activist group said 10 people died in fighting Thursday  the first time in six months the [Islamic State] had managed to enter the town along the Syria-Turkey border." The BBC put the number of dead at 30 and says that ISIS militants killed another 20 in a nearby village.
Meanwhile, "in the city of Hassakeh, Redur Khalil, a spokesman for the Kurdish People's Protection Units, or YPG, said [ISIS] militants attacked government-held neighborhoods on the southern edge of the city, and captured some areas. Hassakeh is divided between Syrian President Bashar Assad's forces and Kurdish fighters," the AP says.
According to the BBC: "The apparent two-pronged IS offensive came as Kurdish fighters from the Popular Protection Units (YPG) cut a major supply line for IS near [Ar] Raqqa."
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Will Greece Stay In The Eurozone? Citizens Set To Vote On Bailout Deal</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/28/418261952/will-greece-stay-in-the-eurozone-citizens-set-to-vote-on-bailout-deal?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Greeks react to their Prime Minister's announcement of a snap referendum to be held on July 5 on the bailout deal offered by European leaders.</Description>
        <MainBody>Will Greece Stay In The Eurozone? Citizens Set To Vote On Bailout Deal
June 28, 2015 7:48 AM ET
Joanna Kakissis
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 12:02:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Chasing Food Dreams Across U.S., Nigerian Chef Tests Immigration System</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2015/07/07/411472179/chasing-food-dreams-across-u-s-nigerian-chef-tests-immigration-system?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Tunde Wey wanted to share the food of his West African childhood. So he crossed the U.S. by bus, hosting pop-up dinners along the way. But Wey, like many immigrants, found success can unravel quickly.</Description>
        <MainBody>Tunde Wey prepares a pop-up Nigerian dinner in the kitchen of Toki Underground, a ramen restaurant in Washington, D.C., in December 2014. Eliza Barclay/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Eliza Barclay/NPR
Tunde Wey prepares a pop-up Nigerian dinner in the kitchen of Toki Underground, a ramen restaurant in Washington, D.C., in December 2014.
Eliza Barclay/NPR
Most aspiring chefs long for the white hat, the gleaming kitchen, the fancy menu.
But Nigeria-born Tunde Wey stumbled into a different version of the (American) chef's dream. He wanted to see the country, and share the food of his West African childhood with friends and strangers along the way.
So a few months ago, he packed up his knives and his spices at his home in Detroit, and started crisscrossing the U.S. by Greyhound bus.
He wowed diners in New Orleans, Chicago and Buffalo with his one-man pop-up dinner events, Lagos , named after his hometown in Nigeria. He cooked his way up and down the East Coast.
Word got around. His one-night cooking gigs began selling out.
But then, like many immigrants to the U.S., Tunde Wey discovered how quickly success can come tumbling down.
I caught up with him the day he was preparing dinner in Washington, D.C., and getting rhapsodic about his ingredients.
"Palm oil is like the sexier, more full-bodied oil to, like, regular cooking oil," he tells me. "It just has soul, you know."
Wey is kind of like a traveling showman. For every dinner party he throws in a new city, he has to scramble to find, and then borrow, a space. Sometimes it's a restaurant, sometimes it's a communal kitchen where food entrepreneurs smoke and bake and boil their wares.
On the day we meet up, he has taken over a restaurant called Toki Underground . Its stove usually has broth and ramen noodles simmering on it, but Wey has replaced them with a huge vat of goat head stew.
A photo posted by Lagos: Dope Nigerian Food (@lagos_restaurant) on
Jan 18, 2015 at 6:35pm PST
"Gonna be some eyeballs in this, and some mandibles  just the jaw of the goat," he says as he stirs. "People are going to eat some teeth today."
Wey has been at it since 9 a.m. It's now mid-afternoon, and he's moving between a blender, four massive pots slick with that sexy palm oil, and his spice bag.
"A doctor has a medicine bag; I have a spice bag," he says.
"A doctor has a medicine bag; I have a spice bag," Wey says. Eliza Barclay/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Eliza Barclay/NPR
"A doctor has a medicine bag; I have a spice bag," Wey says.
Eliza Barclay/NPR
This bag is Wey's most important prop, and it's filled with things like alligator pepper seeds, calabash nutmeg and uda, a kind of pepper.
"So all of this stuff is in here, and sometimes I'll have stock fish, which smells so bad," he says.
Wey never actually planned to become a chef. His parents dreamed that he would become a doctor, and they sent him to the U.S. when he was 16 to study science. But 15 years later, after a string of college majors and false starts, he realized he wanted to cook. He didn't have any formal training, though.
"I learned how to cook from watching my parents, my aunt, a lot of YouTube videos in between all that," he says. "The benefit that I have is that I grew up with this food, so I know exactly what it's supposed to taste like."
The idea for the Nigerian pop-up came to him after a brief stint at an American restaurant he co-founded in Detroit called Revolver .
A photo posted by Lagos: Dope Nigerian Food (@lagos_restaurant) on
Jan 7, 2015 at 2:35pm PST
As Wey spent more time in the kitchen, he found that he missed his family more and more  he hadn't seen his parents and his eldest brother back in Nigeria for seven years. So as he planned the pop-up, he turned to his parents for help with everything from recipes to music.
"My family was interested in the details of the business, and I had these conversations with them," he says. "And I felt more connected, actually, infinitely more connected."
And he shares that connection when he makes his food for other people.
"When I was younger, my mom used to give me kisses on my cheek, and she would be like, you know, be all sloppy and I would do the same. Just that feeling of being kissed  I get that when I'm eating. So it's evocative; that's how food affects me."
And he hopes his diners will feel it, too.
When I met him in D.C. in December, Wey had been on the road cooking for two months. And he'd pretty much got his rhythm down.
It's 7 p.m., and the show is on. "That spinach dish I am holding in my hand right now is absolutely amazing, and I would kill for the recipe," says Sarah Moulton. "And my mouth has burned off from the goat pepper soup."
One of Wey's staple menu items is Jollof rice, made with rosy palm oil. Eliza Barclay/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Eliza Barclay/NPR
One of Wey's staple menu items is Jollof rice, made with rosy palm oil.
Eliza Barclay/NPR
She's here with her friend Tiffany Farchione, who chimes in about the goat pepper soup: "It's hot and it hurts, but you still want more because it's so delicious."
And as for the goat head? Diner Dave Grossman pronounces it "delicious, expertly stewed, really quite thrilling."
That night, Wey was on a roll. He had a string of gigs lined up in several other cities, some seating up to 50 people at $55 a head.
Soon after, he got his biggest break: The celebrity chef Roy Choi invited him to his Los Angeles restaurant on February 5. The New York Times' Sam Sifton told Wey he was flying out to be there.
But Wey never made it.
On the way to LA, when his Greyhound bus stopped outside of El Paso, Texas, Border Patrol agents climbed aboard. They were not impressed with his old Nigerian passport.
As Wey remembers it, "I had this uncontrollable chill, I was so cold. And there was so much adrenaline rushing through my body."
The thing was, back in 2007, while he was figuring out what to do with his life, he'd let his student visa expire.
"I just thought, I'll fix this: I'm going to go back to school, finish school, and adjust my status somehow," he says. "And so it was something I kept putting off."
But instead of cooking in LA, he was locked up in an El Paso detention center in early February for several weeks. Wey said it seemed like everything  from the pop-up to his life in America  he'd built was tumbling down.
But Wey has been lucky.
Almost half the people in the U.S. illegally are like him  they let visas expire. But Wey had a clean record and a network of friends and family. They raised $6,000. And so he wasn't deported, and he's now out on bail.
"I'm sometimes frustrated that it's limiting, but I mean, I'm comfortable with the reality that is my life," he says. "I'm not ashamed of it."
Because there's such a backlog in the immigration courts, Wey has a bit of a reprieve.
His next appointment with an immigration judge isn't until 2017. The judge will decide then whether he's allowed to stay. Or must go.
In the meantime, he's planning more dinners. And he's just opened a Nigerian food stall in the St. Roch Market in New Orleans.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:20:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European Commission Official: No Vote Puts Greece In Weaker Position</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420595008/european-commission-official-no-vote-puts-greece-in-weaker-position?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>NPR's Robert Siegel interviews European Commission Vice President for the Euro Valdis Dombrovskis about how Sunday's vote on the Greek referendum complicates negotiations between Greece and Europe.</Description>
        <MainBody>NPR's Robert Siegel interviews European Commission Vice President for the Euro Valdis Dombrovskis about how Sunday's vote on the Greek referendum complicates negotiations between Greece and Europe.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
Greece still owes its creditors almost 250 billion euros, and yesterday's no vote has sent shockwaves through Brussels, the capital of the European Union. Joining us now on the line is the vice president of the European Commission for the euro and social dialogue - that's his title. He is Valdis Dombrovskis, a Latvian. Welcome to the program, sir.
VALDIS DOMBROVSKIS: Good afternoon.
SIEGEL: You've said that the vote in Greece widens the gap, provides no easy way out and that too much time and too many opportunities have been lost. Bottom line - does that mean, as far as you're concerned, Greece is probably leaving the euro right now?
DOMBROVSKIS: Well, if both sides are working seriously and constructively, there is always a possibility to find a solution. But it's also true that yesterday's referendum had made things more complicated, and the gap we need to breach has become wider.
SIEGEL: Wider - the Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras seems to think that with 60 percent of Greeks backing him up, he's in a stronger position negotiating with Europe. Has he got that wrong? Is he in a weaker position?
DOMBROVSKIS: Well, it's certainly emphasized by European Commission, also by president of the Eurogroup already before the referendums that, actually, the no vote would dramatically weaken the negotiating position of the Greek government. And it will be more difficult to found a solution which all 19 - well, 19 including Greece - eurozone countries could support.
SIEGEL: But how do you answer the argument that if Greece adopts the policies that its creditors want it to pursue, it will cut spending, it will raise taxes, it will diminish growth and be even less able to pay back the debts that are saddling the country?
DOMBROVSKIS: Well, that's why institutions are so much stressing the need for a credible strategy out of the crisis because the first thing for Greece is to regain financial stability because without financial stability, there is no economic growth. Banks are worried. They are not lending to the real economy. Citizens are worried. They are not spending. Companies are worried. They are not investing. And if you restore financial stability, banks start lending to the economy, citizens start spending, companies start investing. It's something we saw in other pilgrim countries, like in Ireland, like in Portugal. And those countries which were implementing reforms were actually able to return to economic growth.
SIEGEL: Mr. Dombrovskis, just before you go, I want to ask you what you thought as you saw scenes of crowds of Greeks celebrating the victory of the no vote - the rejection of the terms that had been on the table but had expired. What was your reaction to those scenes of jubilation on behalf of a majority of Greek voters?
DOMBROVSKIS: Well, it's clear that there's not going to be quick and easy solutions to the problem. And I think it's very important that, also, the Greek government is constructive and honest to its citizens and tells the Greek citizens what are the consequences of different decision government is taking.
SIEGEL: Do you think they were less than honest in this case?
DOMBROVSKIS: Well, I'm not entirely convinced that all Greek citizens were explained what implications different decisions may create.
SIEGEL: Valdis Dombrovskis, vice president of the European Commission, thank you very much for talking with us today.
DOMBROVSKIS: Thank you. Thank you so much.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 00:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Recent Islamic State Losses Show It Can Be Defeated, Obama Says</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/06/420626902/obama-says-recent-islamic-state-losses-show-it-can-be-defeated?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>But the president warned that the campaign against the group that controls large parts of Syria and Iraq "will not be quick."</Description>
        <MainBody>Recent Islamic State Losses Show It Can Be Defeated, Obama Says
July 06, 2015 5:03 PM ET
President Obama delivers remarks Monday at the Pentagon after a briefing on U.S. efforts against the Islamic State. Jonathan Ernst/Reuters /Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Jonathan Ernst/Reuters /Landov
President Obama delivers remarks Monday at the Pentagon after a briefing on U.S. efforts against the Islamic State.
Jonathan Ernst/Reuters /Landov
Updated at 5:26 p.m. ET
President Obama has warned that the campaign against the so-called Islamic State "will not be quick" as he cited gains made in Iraq and Syria by the coalition fighting the militant group.
"This will not be quick," Obama said at the Pentagon. "This is a long-term campaign."
He said the coalition against the Islamic State, also known as ISIS or ISIL, has hit the group with more than 5,000 airstrikes, destroying thousands of fighting positions, tanks, vehicles, bomb factories and training camps and killing thousands of fighters, including senior commanders. The Islamic State, Obama said, has lost more than a quarter of the populated areas it had seized in Iraq, and parts of Syria that it controlled, too.
"ISIL's recent losses in both Syria and Iraq prove that ISIL can and will be defeated," Obama said.
Obama said the U.S. continues to ramp up the training and support of local forces fighting the Islamic State on the ground in Iraq, and will "do more to train and equip the moderate opposition in Syria."
The Islamic State is one of several factions involved in the civil war in Syria. Obama said the only way for that civil war to end was if President Bashar Assad stepped down; a move, he said, that would unite the remaining factions against the Islamic State.
Obama said the coalition would also continue to target the oil and gas, and financial infrastructure that funds the Islamic State's operations, and to speed up the delivery of military equipment to Iraqi forces battling the organization. But, he added: "No amount of military force will end the terror that is ISIL unless it's matched by a broader effort  political and economic."
Obama said the U.S. was doing a better job of preventing large-scale attacks on the homeland, but that so-called lone-wolf terrorists are harder to detect.
"Here in the United States, we have seen all kinds of home-grown terrorism and tragically recent history reminds us how even a single individual motivated by a hateful ideology with access to dangerous weapons can inflict horrendous harm on Americans," he said. "Our efforts to counter violent extremism must not target any one community because of their faith or background, including patriotic Muslim Americans who are partners in keeping our country safe.
"That said, we also have to acknowledge that ISIL has been particularly effective at reaching out to and recruiting vulnerable people around the world, including here in the United States. And they are targeting Muslim communities around the world."
Obama said that in order to defeat groups such as the Islamic State, the U.S. must also "discredit their ideology, the twisted thinking that draws vulnerable people into their ranks."
"Ideologies are not defeated with guns, they are defeated by better ideas  a more attractive, more compelling vision," he said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. Report Highlights Surprising Global Progress On Poverty Goals</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420595036/u-n-report-highlights-surprising-global-progress-on-poverty-goals?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>In 2000 the world's leaders agreed on an ambitious plan for attacking global poverty by 2015. Called the Millennium Development Goals, these time-bound targets spurred an unprecedented aid effort that helped slash the share of people living in extreme poverty in half. Now nations are hammering out an even broader set of goals for 2030, but this time the task is proving highly controversial. The Millennium Development Goals were drafted in a highly casual way and that simple process proved the key to their success.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. Report Highlights Surprising Global Progress On Poverty Goals
July 06, 2015 4:30 PM ET
Transcript
In 2000 the world's leaders agreed on an ambitious plan for attacking global poverty by 2015. Called the Millennium Development Goals, these time-bound targets spurred an unprecedented aid effort that helped slash the share of people living in extreme poverty in half. Now nations are hammering out an even broader set of goals for 2030, but this time the task is proving highly controversial. The Millennium Development Goals were drafted in a highly casual way and that simple process proved the key to their success.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
The last 15 years have brought unprecedented improvements to the lives of the world's poorest people. A report by the United Nations today highlights the progress. The number of people who live in extreme poverty has dropped by more than half. Many say a catalyst for this was a commitment by world leaders back in 2000. They vowed to a meet an ambitious set of goals to reduce poverty by this year, 2015. NPR's Nurith Aizenman brings us the first of a two-part report on these Millennium Development Goals, as they're called. Today - why the goals proved so surprisingly successful.
NURITH AIZENMAN, BYLINE: For an agreement that's widely credited with bringing millions of people life-saving medications and access to clean drinking water in schools, the Millennium Development Goals had a pretty humdrum beginning. Mark Malloch-Brown was part of a small group of top U.N. officials who largely wrote the Millennium Development Goals. He sums up the process with the word simple.
MARK MALLOCH-BROWN: It's brilliantly simple. It was myself with some chums in a room kind of thing.
AIZENMAN: They came up with a short list of goals to be met by 2015. The process was so casual they almost forgot something.
MALLOCH-BROWN: You know, happily having sent these things to press, I ran into a smiling German colleague in the corridor who was the head of the environment program. I remember my blood falling to my ankles as I said, oh, goodness me, we've forgotten the environment goal.
AIZENMAN: They stopped the presses, added the goal ensure environmental sustainability, bringing the total to eight. Now, a big reason this could all be so low-key was that, at the time, people didn't expect much to come of the goals. Mark Suzman oversees global policy advocacy for the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.
MARK SUZMAN: It's not as if 2000 was the first time that the U.N. has come out and set lofty global goals.
AIZENMAN: But Suzman, who once worked with Malloch-Brown at the U.N., says the very simplicity of the Millennium Development Goals ended up making them uniquely powerful. International aid to poor countries had gotten kind of chaotic and scattershot during the 1990s. And by reducing the global agenda to eight narrowly defined priorities, the goals helped channel everyone's energies and money.
SUZMAN: What the goals did, by prioritizing and focusing, was actually put together major international donors, civil society partners on the ground, national governments focusing on the same sets of issues. And that allowed for a focusing of both policy change and resources and attention.
AIZENMAN: Countries and donors could track how they were measuring up against the targets. And this often spurred them to try harder. The upshot - 12 million people in poor countries now have access to HIV/AIDS aids drugs. More than 6 million lives have been saved thanks to malaria prevention and treatments. Now, the world hasn't met every single Millennium Development Goal, and a lot of the rise in poor people's incomes was the result of economic growth in China and India. Still, says Suzman...
SUZMAN: The last decade has seen arguably the greatest improvements for the largest number of people on the planet in the most countries than has ever happened in human history.
AIZENMAN: So as people started talking about what should replace these goals when they expire this year, there was one thing everyone agreed on - something this important should no longer be drafted by a bunch of technocrats in a room at the U.N. This time, they've reached out to every member country, local activists. They've polled 7 million people. All those cooks have added a lot of new ingredients. The latest draft has double the number of goals, quadruple the number of sub-goals. Nurith Aizenman, NPR News.
SIEGEL: Tomorrow on this program, we'll hear about fears that this longer, broader list of goals could prove unworkable.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Germany, France Keep Door Open To Greek Requests For Economic Help</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420595015/germany-france-keep-door-open-to-greek-requests-for-economic-help?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande meet in Paris Monday to discuss their response to the result of Sunday's referendum in Greece.</Description>
        <MainBody>Germany, France Keep Door Open To Greek Requests For Economic Help
July 06, 2015 4:30 PM ET
German Chancellor Angela Merkel and French President Francois Hollande meet in Paris Monday to discuss their response to the result of Sunday's referendum in Greece.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
And in Paris, French and German leaders met today to discuss the Greek crisis. They said they're still open to helping Greece solve its debt problem. But a growing number of Germans say there's only one solution they're interested in, and that's getting Greece to give up the euro. NPR's Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson reports from Berlin.
SORAYA SARHADDI NELSON, BYLINE: While French President Francois Hollande spoke of European solidarity, German Chancellor Angela Merkel made it clear no new money is heading to Athens.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
ANGELA MERKEL: (Speaking German).
NELSON: She says conditions needed to start talks for a bailout just aren't there at the moment.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
MERKEL: (Speaking German).
NELSON: The chancellor adds to keep this a single currency, we need joint responsibility, not just joint solidarity. That news came as the European Central Bank announced it would not expand its emergency assistance either. The chancellor's ironclad stance is in part because she is under intense pressure at home. There are growing demands from her conservative allies and the German public that Greece be booted out of the eurozone. Many here are irked by the Greek government's snubbing of its creditors - in particular, Germany, whose leaders some Greeks have likened to Nazis. Polls last month showed nearly 3 in 5 Germans in favor of Greece leaving the eurozone. Those feelings only increased after Sunday's resounding no vote in the Greek referendum. Walter Ingenrieth, a 63-year-old from Monchengladbach, who was touring Berlin this afternoon, says his resentment towards Athens has been building over several months.
WALTER INGENRIETH: (Speaking German).
NELSON: He says, "it's time for Greece to give up the euro because I don't see it making a serious effort to share in a joint currency with Germany or other European countries with strong economies." He and many other Germans say they can't understand why five years since its bailout began, Greece has made little progress in ending corruption and tax evasion and failed at delivering enough reforms. Even Apostolos Tsalastras, the treasurer of Oberhausen, which was the most indebted city in Germany some years back, expressed impatience with the Athens government.
APOSTOLOS TSALASTRAS: (Speaking German).
NELSON: The son of Greek immigrants says it's imperative for the Greek government not only to focus on how serious the situation is, but to take responsibility and lead the country out of crisis. That's not going to happen with its constant refusal to engage its eurozone partners, Tsalastras adds. Nevertheless, he hopes Greece will stay in the eurozone.
TSALASTRAS: (Speaking German).
NELSON: Tsalastras, like many financial experts here, says if Greece were to leave, it would set a dangerous precedent for other member countries facing debt issues. That would result not only in financial turmoil within the eurozone, but could mean an end of the currency. Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson, NPR News, Berlin.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Despite Uncertainty, Greeks Show Pride In Rejecting Bailout Plan</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420595001/despite-uncertainty-greeks-show-pride-in-rejecting-bailout-plan?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Greeks in Athens react to the resounding no vote on a bailout plan. Many are proud to have poked Europe in the eye after years of austerity, but the banks remain closed, hurting many local businesses.</Description>
        <MainBody>Despite Uncertainty, Greeks Show Pride In Rejecting Bailout Plan
July 06, 2015 4:30 PM ET
Greeks in Athens react to the resounding no vote on a bailout plan. Many are proud to have poked Europe in the eye after years of austerity, but the banks remain closed, hurting many local businesses.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
Europe is reacting to yesterday's historic referendum in Greece. Greeks overwhelmingly voted down the latest terms for a bailout by their European creditors, but many Greeks who rejected the offer are eager to see a new deal they like better.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
That will be a tall order if the no vote drives the two sides even farther apart. In a moment, we'll hear from a member of the European leadership on that.
MCEVERS: But first, to Athens - that's where Greece's combative finance minister resigned early this morning, as a concession to EU negotiators. And it's where Greeks are attempting to go about their business, as NPR's Chris Arnold reports.
CHRIS ARNOLD, BYLINE: A loud no - or ohi in Greek - echoed around Europe last night, and Athenians celebrated around their city. But today, people were trying to get back to a regular Monday morning - only it's not a regular Monday. The doors to the banks are still shut here, and many locals are still too nervous to go out and buy much of anything, including meats.
ALEXANDRA DIALYNA: We are at the meat market. It's very loud every day.
ARNOLD: And that guy has a very large knife that he's chopping meat up with.
DIALYNA: Yeah.
ARNOLD: My interpreter, Alexandra Dialyna, and I are walking past sides of lamb hanging on hooks. It is loud here, but the merchants calling out to sell their lamb and beef and pork far outnumber the shoppers. Back behind one of the meat counters, business owner Tsironis Cleanthis is having a snack of fresh cherries. He owns his family business here, and he voted yes.
TSIRONIS CLEANTHIS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: A lot of people last night were celebrating, but he doesn't understand why because, again today, the market is very slow, and people don't come here as they used to.
ARNOLD: Cleanthis says basically the referendum didn't accomplish anything. It just scared people, angered European leaders and forced the banks to close before panicked people in Greece pulled out all of their money. Now, he says, he's got his family's life savings - half a million euros - locked inside of a Greek bank with a lot of questions hanging in the air.
CLEANTHIS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: He has children who are doing their studies, so he's worried.
ARNOLD: Oh, to be able to pay for school.
DIALYNA: Yes.
ARNOLD: But many savers were a bit reassured this morning when Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras said the no vote is not a mandate to break with Europe's single currency, the euro. And, of course, unlike Cleanthis, most people voted no, and they're proud of that.
SPIROU CHRISTOS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: He says that from today, Greece has written a new course in history.
ARNOLD: At a fish market up the street, Spirou Christos is selling gleaming pink squid and octopus that are laid out on a bed of ice. He says he has about 30,000 euros in the bank. But he says even when the bank reopens, he is not pulling out his money.
CHRISTOS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: No, never - he would never do that.
CHRISTOS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: He would never put his money outside of Greece because our country needs those type of money. And if everyone did that, then Greece would collapse.
ARNOLD: At the meat and fish market, some merchants can at least do some business in cash, but others aren't so lucky.
MARIA AGGELEPOULOS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: We cannot do our job and the market has frozen.
ARNOLD: Maria Aggelepoulos runs a wholesale sewing and fabric supply store. She imports big boxes of German-made sewing needles for resale, for example. And all of her business, she says, is done in checks - not cash. And she says right now, she can't deposit any of those checks in her bank.
AGGELEPOULOS: (Speaking Greek).
DIALYNA: No, banks are closed for everything.
ARNOLD: Meanwhile, even with people in Greece limited to just pulling out 60 euros a day from the ATMs, the Greek banks are thought to be almost out of money. In fact, some are out of 20-euro bills and people are only getting a single 50-euro bill. Others are just completely empty for the moment. So with the country's banks on the verge of collapse, Greece is clearly desperate for more emergency assistance from Europe. Chris Arnold, NPR News, Athens.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pope Francis Begins South America Tour With Mass In Ecuador</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420594987/pope-francis-begins-south-america-tour-with-mass-in-ecuador?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>Pope Francis kicks off a three-nation South America tour with a mass in Ecuador on Monday. Aiding the poor is at the center of his mission, which will include stops in Bolivia and Paraguay. It is his second South American trip since becoming pope.</Description>
        <MainBody>Pope Francis Begins South America Tour With Mass In Ecuador
July 06, 2015 4:30 PM ET
John Otis
Transcript
Pope Francis kicks off a three-nation South America tour with a mass in Ecuador on Monday. Aiding the poor is at the center of his mission, which will include stops in Bolivia and Paraguay. It is his second South American trip since becoming pope.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
Pope Francis is in South America for what's turning out to be a joyous homecoming. Not only does the Argentine-born pope speak Spanish, he loves to break protocol by greeting and hugging average people who've come to see him. That happened this afternoon in the Ecuadorian port city of Guayaquil, where reporter John Otis filed this report.
UNIDENTIFIED WOMEN: (Singing in Spanish).
JOHN OTIS, BYLINE: Pilgrims sing church hymns as they make their way to the cavernous Samanes Park in Guayaquil. People are coming for the first outdoor mass of Francis' three-country South America trip. One of them is salesman Harold Andrade.
HAROLD ANDRADE: Yeah, yeah, yeah - really, really happy - really excited, and I believe that I'm going to cry because I'm very excited.
OTIS: For security, many streets have been blocked off, forcing Mass-goers to walk for miles. Still, they come. Hundreds of thousands are making the trek, including these elderly people in wheelchairs.
UNIDENTIFIED MAN: (Speaking in Spanish).
OTIS: Along the way, people hawk pope T-shirts with the smiling image of Francis. Also on sale are baseball caps, buttons, posters, rosaries, wooden crosses and incense. With the huge stage, the towers of speakers and the sea of people, the scene resembles a kind of religious Woodstock. But rather than rain and mud, the faithful bake under the equatorial sun.
HECTOR FREILE: My sister and my mom - they are here since 1 a.m. And they are camping here, so it's crazy. (Laughter).
OTIS: They're camping overnight?
FREILE: Yeah, they're camping overnight. Yeah, it's crazy. I'm kind of lazy, so I came later. (Laughter).
OTIS: That's Hector Freile, who's here with his girlfriend. He calls Francis a great communicator.
FREILE: The Catholic church needed someone like him, and I think this pope, Francisco, is doing a great job explaining, in simple words, what Jesus Christ wants from us.
PATRICIA PLAZA: (Speaking Spanish).
OTIS: Guayaquil lawyer Patricia Plaza tells me that Francis has taken the bull by the horns by addressing topics like divorce, homosexuality and the church's sex abuse scandal. This trip, for example, comes on the heels of the pope's landmark encyclical on the environment and global warming. In it, he slams a world economic system based on reckless development, overconsumption and the burning of fossil fuels.
UNIDENTIFIED WOMAN: (Singing in Spanish).
OTIS: But on this trip, which takes the pope to some of South America's poorest countries, Francis is focusing on problems like economic inequality and ethnic strife.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
UNIDENTIFIED CROWD: (Chanting in Spanish).
FRANCIS: (Speaking Spanish).
UNIDENTIFIED CROWD: (Chanting in Spanish).
FRANCIS: (Speaking Spanish).
UNIDENTIFIED CROWD: (Chanting in Spanish).
OTIS: In his homily, the pope spoke of the strength of families and how the human family is capable of making the world a better place.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
FRANCIS: (Speaking Spanish).
OTIS: "The good news is that the best wine has yet to be consumed," Francis said. "The deepest and most beautiful things for the family are coming." On Tuesday, the pope will deliver another outdoor Mass in Quito, the Ecuadorian capital, before traveling to Bolivia and Paraguay. For NPR News, I'm John Otis, Guayaquil, Ecuador.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hacking Team Breach Reveals Firm Sold Spying Tools To Repressive Regimes</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420594966/hacking-team-breach-reveals-firm-sold-spying-tools-to-repressive-regimes?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>What happens when one of the most notorious hacking companies gets hacked? That's the situation unfolding for one Italian company, which sells surveillance software to governments across the globe.</Description>
        <MainBody>Hacking Team Breach Reveals Firm Sold Spying Tools To Repressive Regimes
July 06, 2015 4:30 PM ET
What happens when one of the most notorious hacking companies gets hacked? That's the situation unfolding for one Italian company, which sells surveillance software to governments across the globe.
ROBERT SIEGEL, HOST:
What happens when one of the world's most notorious hacking companies gets hacked? Well, that's the situation unfolding for an Italian firm. As NPR's Elise Hu explains, it sells software to governments, large and small, with this kind of message.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
UNIDENTIFIED MAN: Rely on us.
ELISE HU, BYLINE: This is a recent advertisement for surveillance software from a company called HackingTeam. The software can track citizens, access text messages, emails and overcome data encryption.
(SOUNDBITE OF ARCHIVED RECORDING)
UNIDENTIFIED MAN: Exactly what we do - the hacking suite for governmental interception.
HU: HackingTeam sells its work as, quote, "stealth and untraceable." But the surveillance company itself just had its secrets spilled out in the form of a 500-gigabyte data dump. Whoever's behind the stolen data hasn't come forward. NPR verified that at least some of the hacked personal passwords do check out. And if the other documents are true, they show HackingTeam sells its software to private companies in at least three dozen countries. That includes the United States and some of the world's most repressive regimes.
CHRISTOPHER SOGHIAN: These documents provide, finally, a smoking gun showing that HackingTeam has, in fact, sold its technology to a number of governments with truly atrocious human rights record.
HU: Christopher Soghian is a privacy activist with the ACLU. He's reviewed 500 gigs and found evidence of hacking teams selling to Russia, Kazakhstan and Sudan the very surveillance-enabling, code-breaking, privacy-intercepting software from that dramatic commercial
SOGHIAN: What this shows us is that surveillance software - advanced surveillance capabilities are now available to the largest and smallest governments in the world. We really need to have a bigger conversation about whether these tools should be used in democracies.
(SOUNDBITE OF PHONE RINGING)
UNIDENTIFIED WOMAN: (Speaking Italian).
HU: For now, the person who answered the phone at HackingTeam's Italian headquarters directed questions to an email address. But much of the information that had been a mystery, like the company's client lists and contracts, are now published online. Elise Hu, NPR News.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:27:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Major U.S. Airlines Push Back Against Expansion Of Gulf Carriers</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/07/06/420594939/major-u-s-airlines-push-back-against-expansion-of-gulf-carriers?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>The three major U.S. airlines — American, United and Delta — are pressuring the government to stifle competition by carriers from the Persian Gulf.</Description>
        <MainBody>Major U.S. Airlines Push Back Against Expansion Of Gulf Carriers
July 06, 2015 4:27 PM ET
The three major U.S. airlines  American, United and Delta  are pressuring the government to stifle competition by carriers from the Persian Gulf.
KELLY MCEVERS, HOST:
There's a fight going on between the U.S. and the Persian Gulf. It's not about terrorism or regional security. This fight involves commercial airlines. The three big U.S. carriers - American, United and Delta - are pushing back against the swift and successful expansion of three Gulf carriers. NPR's Jackie Northam has more.
JACKIE NORTHAM, BYLINE: At any one of 15 cities across the U.S., aircraft from the big Gulf carriers - Etihad, Emirates and Qatar Airlines - take off and land daily. Over the years, all three Gulf airlines have seen rapid expansion, buying new planes and competing on lucrative international routes. Now American, Delta and United Airlines are fighting to maintain their share of those markets and are pressuring the U.S. government for help, says Erik Hansen, a senior director at the U.S. Travel Association.
ERIK HANSEN: What they've asked for is a freeze in new routes and capacity from the Gulf carriers in the United States. They want to block all expansion from these three Gulf airlines. They want a protectionist policy. They want a freeze. They want to block out competition.
NORTHAM: Hansen says the move is a direct violation of international agreements that were meant to eliminate government interference in the airline industry. But the U.S. carriers say the Gulf airlines are already violating those agreements by taking billions of dollars in government subsidies. Jeff Smisek is the head of United Airlines.
JEFF SMISEK: Qatar, Etihad and Emirates are not just airlines. They're arms of the state. They are part of state policy to drive tourism and trade through the Middle East, and these three carriers are not stimulating demand.
NORTHAM: The Gulf airlines deny they receive government subsidies. But the U.S. carriers are particularly worried about competition in the fast-growing markets, like the Indian subcontinent, Africa and Asia, for them and their alliance partners. Hansen of the U.S. Travel Association says Etihad, Qatar and Emirates Airlines have benefited greatly from the geographical location of their hubs in Abu Dhabi, Doha, and Dubai and their huge investments in modern fleets and new airports with world-class shopping.
HANSEN: And just by virtue of where they are in the world, they're providing faster connection times, shorter routes to certain parts of the globe. And when you add all that together, you often see customers voting with their wallets and deciding that they're going to fly on a Gulf airline.
NORTHAM: Timothy Clark, the head of Emirates Airlines, says instead of going after the Gulf carriers, the U.S. carriers should provide their customers with more legroom, better food and a higher standard of service.
TIMOTHY CLARK: Investing in product, investing in comfortable seats - it's not difficult, gentlemen, making the consumer enjoy their products.
NORTHAM: The campaign by the U.S. carriers is made more difficult by the news that they're making record profits and by a Justice Department investigation into allegations they colluded to limit seating and raise fares in domestic markets. Jackie Northam, NPR News, Washington.
Copyright  2015 NPR.  All rights reserved.  Visit our website terms of use and permissions pages at www.npr.org for further information.
NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPRs programming is the audio.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 15:09:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Success For U.S.-Backed Fighters In Syria Leads To Political Complications</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/06/27/418011765/success-for-u-s-backed-fighters-in-syria-leads-to-political-complications?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=world</Link>
        <Description>U.S. air strikes helped Kurdish fighters take ground from ISIS along the Syria-Turkey border. But Kurds used the advance to displace thousands and upset U.S. ally Turkey, wary of Kurdish ambitions.</Description>
        <MainBody>Success For U.S.-Backed Fighters In Syria Leads To Political Complications
June 27, 2015 8:09 AM ET

You must be signed in to leave a comment. Sign In / Register
Please keep your community civil. All comments must follow the NPR.org Community rules and terms of use , and will be moderated prior to posting. NPR reserves the right to use the comments we receive, in whole or in part, and to use the commenter's name and location, in any medium. See also the Terms of Use , Privacy Policy and Community FAQ .
NPR thanks our sponsors
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
