<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="npr">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:06:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>From The White House: A Celebration Of Great Teaching</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/ed/2015/05/01/403284177/from-the-white-house-a-celebration-of-great-teaching?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>President Obama welcomes the Teacher of the Year ... and tells how a great educator shaped his own life.</Description>
        <MainBody>President Obama escorts 2015 Teacher of the Year winner Shanna Peeples, an English teacher at Palo Duro High School in Amarillo, Texas, into the Rose Garden on Wednesday. With them is Secretary of Education Arne Duncan. Kevin Lamarque/Reuters/Landov hide caption
itoggle caption Kevin Lamarque/Reuters/Landov
President Obama escorts 2015 Teacher of the Year winner Shanna Peeples, an English teacher at Palo Duro High School in Amarillo, Texas, into the Rose Garden on Wednesday. With them is Secretary of Education Arne Duncan.
Kevin Lamarque/Reuters/Landov
No matter how high you climb in life, you never forget your favorite teacher.
This week, President Obama awarded Shanna Peeples, a high school English teacher from Amarillo, Texas, the title of the 2015 National Teacher of the Year.
We've been exploring great teaching as well, with our 50 Great Teachers Project . We even shared the stories of our own favorite teachers .
This week, the President wrote his own version:
"When I entered Ms. Hefty's fifth-grade class at Punahou School in the fall of 1971, I was just a kid with a funny name in a new school, feeling a little out of place, hoping to fit in like anyone else.
The first time she called on me, I wished she hadn't. In fact, I wished I were just about anywhere else but at that desk, in that room of children staring at me.
But over the course of that year, Ms. Hefty taught me that I had something to say  not in spite of my differences, but because of them. She made every single student in that class feel special.
And she reinforced that essential value of empathy that my mother and my grandparents had taught me. That is something that I carry with me every day as President."
Want more? Listen, watch and read a lot more about educators making a difference:
50 Great Teachers
What is great teaching? Can it be taught? How do good teachers become great ones? Join NPR Ed as we explore these questions, telling the stories of great teachers.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Freddie Gray Update: New Speculation On His Death, And Peaceful Protests</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2015/05/01/403496063/freddie-gray-update-new-speculation-on-his-death-and-peaceful-protests?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The time Gray spent in a police van is the focal point in the inquiry over how he sustained an injury that would cause his death. A man who says he was in the van spoke to the media Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>People protesting the death of Freddie Gray and demanding police accountability took to the streets in Baltimore's Sandtown neighborhood again Thursday night. Andrew Burton/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Andrew Burton/Getty Images
People protesting the death of Freddie Gray and demanding police accountability took to the streets in Baltimore's Sandtown neighborhood again Thursday night.
Andrew Burton/Getty Images
The Baltimore Police Department's report on the death of Freddie Gray is now being examined by the city's top prosecutor. The findings aren't public; police revealed only a few new details when they announced the transition in the case Thursday. Baltimore's curfew is expected to remain in effect through this weekend.
Gray died on April 19, one week after being taken into custody; police have said that during his transport, Gray wasn't buckled in properly and did not receive timely medical care. Six police officers remain suspended over the case.
As Sam reported for the Two-Way , when police turned over the documents to State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby in Baltimore, they announced that "the van transporting Freddie Gray, the 25-year-old black man who suffered a serious spine injury while in police custody and later died, made one more stop than previously thought."
The roughly 40 minutes that Gray spent in the van have emerged as the focal point in the inquiry over how he sustained an injury that would later be blamed for his death.
That extra stop was discovered through a review of recordings made by security and private cameras, Deputy Police Commissioner Kevin Davis said. He added that another detainee who was riding in the van told police that Gray was "still moving around ... kicking and making noises" until the van reached the police station.
That second detainee rode in the police van on the other side of a metal partition that divides its cargo space. When he was picked up, Gray was already in the van.
Local news WJZ-TV reports that Donta Allen, 22, was that second man  and that he came forward Thursday out of concern over how his comments were being portrayed by both the police and the media.
"When I was in the back of that van it did not stop or nothing. All it did was go straight to the station, but I heard a little banging, like he was banging his head," Allen said. " I didn't even know he was in the van until we got to the station."
Saying his words have been distorted by recent reports and that he doesn't think Gray hurt himself intentionally, Allen also told a WJZ reporter, "The only reason I'm doing this is because they put my name in a bad state."
Allen, who was reportedly taken into custody for a minor offense and was not charged with a crime, also spoke to WBAL TV . He told the station that when he got into the van, he didn't know Gray was already there. He said he heard "a little banging for like four seconds."
WBAL aired surveillance camera footage that shows officers looking into Gray's side of the van during the stop that also picked up Allen.
When the van arrived at the police station, Allen said he heard the officers say that Gray didn't have a pulse and was unresponsive  and that another officer later said, "He's got vitals now, he must've come back."
The sequence of events has led to wide-ranging questions over what happened: Was the van driven in a way that caused Gray's injury? When did he become unresponsive? Were the sounds Allen heard caused by a seizure experienced by a gravely wounded man?
The Baltimore Sun reports: "Maryland's chief medical examiner, Dr. David R. Fowler, said his office has not completed an autopsy or turned any documents over to police or prosecutors. He said homicide detectives had observed the examination, a routine practice."
When it's complete, Fowler's report will go straight to the state's attorney's office, the newspaper says.
Protesters have been calling on police to reveal more information about the case. Thursday was the third night of Baltimore's 10 p.m. curfew; before that time arrived, crowds of demonstrators marched in the city's downtown, among a large police presence.
According to the AP, here's what protesters were chanting last night:
"I love Baltimore. We want peace."
"No justice, no peace."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Oakland Laws Could Limit Police Access To Body Camera Footage</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/05/01/403316673/oakland-laws-could-limit-police-access-to-body-camera-footage?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Lawmakers want to prohibit police officers from viewing video from their body cameras before they write their reports. It's part of an effort to bring more transparency to policing.</Description>
        <MainBody>Oakland Laws Could Limit Police Access To Body Camera Footage
May 01, 2015 3:38 AM ET
Oakland police officers, wearing body cameras, form a line during demonstrations against recent incidents of alleged police brutality nationwide. Elijah Nouvelage/Getty hide caption
itoggle caption Elijah Nouvelage/Getty
Oakland police officers, wearing body cameras, form a line during demonstrations against recent incidents of alleged police brutality nationwide.
Elijah Nouvelage/Getty
The unrest in Baltimore and other cities regarding alleged police misconduct has prompted new calls for law enforcement officers to wear body cameras. Such recordings could provide accountability and transparency in potentially controversial circumstances.
At least, that's the idea.
But the recent controversies and scandals also have introduced questions about how often officers' stories line up with what's on video.
Last summer, a rookie police officer in Oakland, Calif., pulled his gun on a man and his two young sons outside a fire station at night. The action was recorded by the cop's body camera as he issued orders to them: "Put, put the bag down! Huh? Put your hands up! Put you hands up! Turn around!"
Fortunately, the cop, who was white, quickly learned that the suspect, who was black, wasn't a burglar, but rather an off-duty firefighter. The officer apologized, though like virtually any video involving police these days, the incident went viral.
The Oakland Police Department has been using body cameras since 2010, and they've had an impact  cases of use-of-force and citizen complaints are both down, says Police Chief Sean Whent.
But have officers' reports fit what their cameras have recorded?
"Our experience has been that the evidence has largely supported the actions of the police officers, in showing that they were in fact behaving appropriately," Whent says.
Whent has been at the State Capitol in Sacramento a lot lately, testifying on behalf of a hotly contested proposed law that would have prevented police officers  in cases where force was used  from reviewing their own recordings before giving a statement.
Civilians Can Record Police Encounters, But When Is It Interference?
Whent says he wants to know what a cop recalls from an incident, not what the video recorded. That's important, he says, because it goes to the cop's state of mind.
"And we believe the public has more faith in the process if the officer does not watch the video prior," he says.
It's all about transparency, says Whent.
But many law enforcement groups aren't buying that, which have rallied in opposition to the measure, saying it that would undermine accurate police reports  and that it presumes that the police will lie.
Mike Rains, an attorney who specializes in representing police officers and their unions, says that's absurd.
"It really is the only reason for not showing an officer the video, is that 'okay, we don't want you to be able to get your story straight,' he says. "And it's all premised on that. And it's crazy!"
Crazy or not, this debate is just one of the questions raised by body camera use by police officers. Throughout the nation, policymakers are talking about rules for when a cop's camera should be turned on, where the recordings should be stored, and when  if ever  they should be shared with the public.
But this issue of whether a cop can see his or her video before writing a report is the most contentious, says Laurie Levenson, a professor at Loyola Law School in Los Angeles. While she says there is a risk that some police officers will tailor their reports based on their videos, she also says that, in many instances, the possibility that other footage might be available could deter that.
"It may not be possible for them to be as much as a schemer as people think they can be, because you have lots of videos, not just the one that might be on the officer himself," she says. "In this day and age we might have videos from other perspectives, and they cannot anticipate what those will show."
Still, it appears that  for now  law enforcement is winning the debate.
Earlier this week the Los Angeles Police Commission voted to allow its officers to review their video before writing reports. Days later the California Assembly bill Oakland Police Chief Whent testified about was amended to give police around that same access  except in cities like Oakland that set their own limits.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:30:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ask The Vietnamese About War, And They Think China, Not The U.S.</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/parallels/2015/05/01/402572349/ask-the-vietnamese-about-war-and-they-think-china-not-the-u-s?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Vietnam's war with the U.S. lasted just a decade, a mere historical blip compared to its centuries-long feud with China, which has been heating up recently.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ask The Vietnamese About War, And They Think China, Not The U.S.
May 01, 2015 3:30 AM ET
Michael Sullivan
i
Vietnamese cross the Ky Cuong River on a temporary floating bridge in August 1979. The main bridge was destroyed by the Chinese during a brief border war several months earlier. Vietnam and China have been rivals for centuries and the friction continues to this day. Bettmann/CORBIS hide caption
itoggle caption Bettmann/CORBIS
Vietnamese cross the Ky Cuong River on a temporary floating bridge in August 1979. The main bridge was destroyed by the Chinese during a brief border war several months earlier. Vietnam and China have been rivals for centuries and the friction continues to this day.
Bettmann/CORBIS
In one of the many war cemeteries in Lang Son, a city in northern Vietnam, Pham Thi Ky and her family light incense and offer prayers for her brother-in-law who died 36 years ago in Vietnam's brief but bloody border war with China.
That 1979 war that left more than 50,000 dead. There are other graves here, too. Those who fought and died against the French occupiers, then the Americans. But relative to China, those were brief battles.
No country weighs on Vietnam like China, and it has been that way for centuries. Has the conflict with China ever really ended, I ask Pham Thi Ky as she lights another candle.
"No," she says. Her daughter agrees. Her sister is even more emphatic. "It will never end. With the Chinese, how can it ever end?"
Vietnam's 2,000 year history with its northern neighbor is complex. There have been countless conflicts as well as shared culture. The Temple of Literature in Hanoi is a good example. It was built by the Vietnamese King Ly Thnh Tng in 1070 to honor the Chinese philosopher Confucius. The teachings on the walls are written in Mandarin. China is also Vietnam's largest trading partner.
The two countries share a communist ideology shaped in part by their shared history, an ideology largely abandoned by the rest of the world. That helps explain why the 1979 border war is something neither government likes to talk about. But Nguyen Duy Thuc, a veteran of that war, is happy to.
"On the morning of the attack, February 17th, we were sleeping when the Chinese artillery started, then we all ran to our posts," he says. "Some were dressed, others didn't even have time to put their pants on, they just ran to their posts to fight."
Vietnamese forces travel toward the country's northern border during a brief, bloody war with China in 1979. Alan Dawson/Bettmann/CORBIS hide caption
itoggle caption Alan Dawson/Bettmann/CORBIS
Vietnamese forces travel toward the country's northern border during a brief, bloody war with China in 1979.
Alan Dawson/Bettmann/CORBIS
At least 200,000 Chinese troops poured into northern Vietnam all along the border. China was aiming to punish Vietnam for its invasion of Cambodia the month before to oust the Chinese-backed Khmer Rouge. There were so many Chinese attacking, Nguyen Duy Thuc remembers, that the soldiers in his bunker "fired our AK47s until the muzzles turned red and they couldn't fire anymore."
But the Chinese kept coming; his bunker was eventually overrun. The Chinese, he says, pumped gas into the ventilation system. There were 800 people, including soldiers, women and children, who fled the fighting in his bunker, Nguyen says.
Only he and two others managed to escape. After nearly a month, the Chinese withdrew, though border clashes continued for the next decade. And Nguyen Duy Thuc hasn't forgotten. If he catches his wife trying to watch a Chinese movie, he says he turns it off.
Memories of that war, and the many other bouts of invasion, occupation and retaliation throughout history, color Vietnam's relationship with China.
Related NPR Stories
Flight Attendant On Saigon Evacuation: You Wanted 'To Help Every Child'
That's especially true now, with the two countries at odds over what Vietnam views as Chinese expansionism in the South China Sea. When China parked an oil rig in contested waters last year, Vietnam upped its official anti-China rhetoric.
And anti-China rioting left at least a dozen dead, including four Taiwanese mistaken for Chinese. As tension grew, and Chinese and Vietnamese boats played a dangerous game of chicken near the rig, some in the border town of Lang Son grew worried. They feared a repeat of what happened in 1979.
"Last year, we were very frightened, we started stockpiling rice and food. I was very worried that there would be war," says Pham Thi Ky, the woman at the cemetery.
Back in 1979, she says she was forced to flee with nothing but the clothes on her back, so this time she wanted to be prepared. She even went to the bank to withdraw a large sum of money, just in case. But the bank wouldn't give it to her, apparently fearing a run.
Vietnam isn't the only one worried.
The Obama administration's "pivot toward Asia" is prompted in part with the idea of trying to contain China's expansionism, which has it's Southeast Asian neighbors and Japan worried.
In the South China Sea, China continues to build on several disputed islands and reefs. Earlier this month, satellite photos revealed China was constructing a 2-mile long, military grade runway on Fiery Cross Reef, prompting howls of protest from both the Philippines and Vietnam, both of which claim the island as their own.
"We think this can be solved diplomatically, but just because the Philippines or Vietnam are not as large as China doesn't mean that they can just be elbowed aside," President Obama said.
Duong Trung Quoc, a member of Vietnam's National Assembly and editor of the magazine Past &amp; Present, says, "I think China is not only Vietnam's problem, but the world's problem right now."
Duong says he admires how China appears to be the only civilization in history to have forced its way back onto the world stage after an interregnum.
"It didn't happen with Greece, or India," he says, "but China has a chance."
And that's a problem, he contends, because China still thinks the way it used to back when it was on top.
"China thinks it is at the center. The conquerer. It wants to turn everybody else into its subordinates," he says. Don't believe China, Duong says, when it appears to be playing nice. It's a trap. The Vietnamese, he says, should know.
Vietnamese in the northern province of Lang Son seek refuge after Chinese forces crossed the border entered Vietnam in February 1979. AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption AFP/Getty Images
"After the war, the Vietnamese and the Americans could reconcile. Vietnam and Franch can reconcile. Veterans from both sides can sit down together and talk. Vietnamese and Chinese veterans hardly ever sit down together," he says.
Why is this?
"The Vietnamese have had too much experience with the Chinese. The Vietnamese can't trust the Chinese. We've had too much practice," he adds.
Few in Vietnam's government talk so openly about the perceived threat from their northern neighbor, wary of igniting more protests, like those last year. And Vietnam's Communist Party still looks to China as a model of how to keep an authoritarian state in power in the Internet age. But anti-Chinese sentiment among ordinary Vietnamese continues to grow.
Vo Cao Loi, lives about a mile from the South China Sea  which the Vietnamese simply call the 'East Sea'  in the central Vietnam city of Danang, where the first U.S. combat troops landed in 1965.
He says he's a survivor of a massacre next to My Lai, one that claimed 97 lives, including his mother. He no longer considers the Americans as enemies, but friends. Allies, even, against Vietnam's longtime enemy. He believes the Chinese have taken something that belongs to Vietnam.
"The Spratly and Paracels (islands) are still partly occupied," he says. "Of course at some point we have to put our differences aside, but we have to get those islands back first. Because it belongs to our ancestors."
But it doesn't take him long to acknowledge that probably won't happen.
"They want to spread their control. They will never give back what they took," he adds. "Vietnam wants to take it back, but the Chinese are strong. So our struggle will last a long time. How long? I can't tell."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FSU Quarterback Jameis Winston Picked First In NFL Draft </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2015/04/30/403406823/fsu-quarterback-jameis-winston-picked-first-in-nfl-draft?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Winston was a embroiled in controversy during his college days. He was accused — and ultimately never charged — of raping an FSU student. Now, he's been picked by Tampa Bay.</Description>
        <MainBody>FSU Quarterback Jameis Winston Picked First In NFL Draft
April 30, 2015 8:17 PM ET
Jameis Winston of the Florida State Seminoles attempts a pass during the game against the Florida Gators on Nov. 30. Sam Greenwood/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Sam Greenwood/Getty Images
Jameis Winston of the Florida State Seminoles attempts a pass during the game against the Florida Gators on Nov. 30.
Sam Greenwood/Getty Images
The Tampa Bay Buccaneers chose Florida State University quarterback Jameis Winston as their first-round pick in the NFL draft on Thursday.
Winston was awarded the Heisman trophy in 2013 just nine days after a prosecutor declined charge him over allegations that he raped a female student at Florida State.
Here's a bit of Winston's bio from NFL.com :
"Winston started every game during his final two seasons at Florida State, winning his first 26 games as a starter before losing his final game in the 2014 national semifinal. Only QB in college football since 1964-65 to win his first 26 starts. Winston tossed at least one touchdown pass in every game of his collegiate career, throwing 65 touchdowns in 27 career games. Was a semifinalist for the Davey O'Brien Award and Walter Camp Player of the Year award in 2014. As a redshirt freshman in 2013, Winston was a Consensus All-American and was the Heisman Trophy Winner. In the first start of his career, completed 25 of 27 passes to set the Florida State all-time record for single-game completion percentage. Played two seasons with the Seminoles' baseball team and was used primarily as a relief pitcher, holding opponents to a .154 batting average as a sophomore and a .175 batting average as a freshman."
Quarterback Marcus Mariota, who led the Oregon Ducks all the way to the national title game was picked second by the Tennessee Titans.
Here's what NFL.com says about him:
"In 41 career starts, he rushed for 15 touchdowns and passed for 105 against just 14 interceptions. He also caught a pair of passes, both resulting in touchdowns. Completed requirements for his undergraduate degree in general science at the end of the 2014 fall term (in less than four years) with a GPA of 3.22. As a redshirt sophomore in 2013, he was a Manning Award finalist and a semifinalist for the Maxwell Award (college player of the year), the Davey O'Brien Award (national quarterback award) and the Walter Camp Award (most outstanding player)."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Health Insurer Aetna Raises Wages For Lowest-Paid Workers To $16 An Hour</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/04/30/403257223/health-insurer-aetna-raises-wages-for-lowest-paid-workers-to-16-an-hour?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Aetna, the giant health insurance company, raised its minimum wage this month. CEO Mark Bertolini says he expects the raise will pay for itself through increased productivity.</Description>
        <MainBody>Health Insurer Aetna Raises Wages For Lowest-Paid Workers To $16 An Hour
April 30, 2015 8:17 PM ET
Aetna recently announced one of its largest pay hikes recently. CEO Mark Bertolini says he believes it largely could pay for itself by making workers more productive. Courtesy of Aetna hide caption
itoggle caption Courtesy of Aetna
Aetna recently announced one of its largest pay hikes recently. CEO Mark Bertolini says he believes it largely could pay for itself by making workers more productive.
Courtesy of Aetna
Prospects for low-wage workers at some large companies have improved recently as both Walmart and McDonald's announced pay hikes, but one of the most significant announcements came at Aetna.
The large insurance company raised the pay of its low-wage workers to $16 an hour this month. Aetna's CEO Mark Bertolini says he believes the raise could largely pay for itself by making workers more productive.
The pay raise will affect 5,700 of Aetna's lowest-paid workers, including those like Kally Dunn at its call center in Fresno, Calif. The veteran employee teaches newcomers how to handle calls, sometimes from irate customers who can't make sense of what's covered and what's not.
"When they call, they're just ... they're angry," Dunn says. "And so it's just a lot of de-escalating, calming them down, um, you know  reassuring them."
It can be stressful work, and many low-wage workers already live stressful lives trying to make ends meet. So when all these workers got their pay raise last Friday, it was a big deal, says Dunn's co-worker, 33-year-old Fabian Arredondo.
Kally Dunn is a call center veteran at Aetna. John Ydstie/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption John Ydstie/NPR
Kally Dunn is a call center veteran at Aetna.
John Ydstie/NPR
"Couldn't have come at a better time  'cause as I mentioned I'm getting married, and we're going on the honeymoon and everything, so it's gonna be helping out a lot," he says.
Arredondo's fiance, with whom he already has a child, wants to add to the family and start saving for a house  all of which adds up to a lot of money.
"Finance can be one of the main stresses in people's lives," he says. "And when you can pull some relief away from that stress, I definitely think it makes for  you know, a happy employee is a productive employee."
Bertolini in convinced that's true.
"We wanted people at the front lines who took care of our customers to not have the kind of stress associated with being able to provide health coverage for their families and food for their families, worrying while they were on the job." he says. "To make sure that they were bringing their best selves to work everyday."
As Bertolini and his executive team worked to understand what challenges their low-wage workers face, they discovered that to make ends meet many were on public assistance, such as food stamps, or Medicaid for their children.
Bertolini says he was taken aback shocked "that we as a thriving organization, as a successful company, a Fortune 100 company, should have people that were living like that among the ranks of our employees."
Bertolini was committed to changing that, but he discovered the cost of boosting compensation for his low-paid workers would be significant  about $27 million a year.
But he also found that research shows there are costs associated with paying low wages. Low-paid workers quit more often, and the turnover is expensive. There's also evidence higher-paid employees provide better customer service. Bertolini thought the potential benefits could offset the $27 million cost and improve his company's profits in the long run.
Related NPR Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Western Hemisphere Wipes Out Its Third Virus</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/goatsandsoda/2015/04/30/403388700/western-hemisphere-wipes-out-its-third-virus?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>It took 15 years and 250 million vaccines, but this week, health authorities officially declared North America and South America free of rubella — a virus that can cause severe birth defects.</Description>
        <MainBody>Western Hemisphere Wipes Out Its Third Virus
April 30, 2015 7:00 PM ET
Health worker Jackie Carnegie delivers a rubella vaccine in Colorado in 1972. Ira Gay Sealy/Denver Post via Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Ira Gay Sealy/Denver Post via Getty Images
Health worker Jackie Carnegie delivers a rubella vaccine in Colorado in 1972.
Ira Gay Sealy/Denver Post via Getty Images
It took 15 years and hundreds of millions of vaccines. But North America and South America have officially eradicated rubella, health authorities said Wednesday. Rubella is only the third virus eradicated from people in the Western Hemisphere.
Also known as German measles, rubella causes only a mild illness in children, with a rash and sometimes a fever.
Wiping Out Polio: How The U.S. Snuffed Out A Killer
But when pregnant women catch rubella , their babies can develop serious birth defects, like heart problems, blindness and learning disabilities. The virus can also trigger miscarriages early in a pregnancy.
In the early 2000s, the Pan American Health Organization set a goal to eradicate rubella in the Americas by 2010. The last reported regional case occurred in Argentina in 2009, said PAHO's director, Dr. Carissa Etienne at a press briefing in Washington on Wednesday.
"The fight against rubella has has paid off with what I believe will be one of the important Pan American public health achievements of the 21st century," Etienne said.
Measles Vaccination Rates: Tanzania Does Better Than U.S.
In other places around the world, about 120,000 babies each year still catch a serious form of rubella, the agency said. Most of these cases occur in Africa and Southeast Asia.
The Americas wiped out rubella with huge vaccination campaigns for teenagers and adults, the PAHO said. Today most babies in the region get a shot before their first birthday, then a second shot before they go to school.
The eradication of rubella doesn't mean we'll never see the virus again in the U.S. People still bring it here from other countries. But it doesn't spread far because so many Americans are vaccinated.
Vaccination Gaps Helped Fuel Disneyland Measles Spread
The Americas have led the way when it comes to eradicating diseases. It was the first region in the world to eradicate smallpox in 1971 and then polio in 1994. And the PAHO already has its sights on another target.
"With rubella under our belt, now it's time to roll up our sleeves and finish the job of eliminating measles as well," Etienne said.
PAHO says it hopes to declare the Americas measles-free in the next year or so. The last endemic case was reported back in 2002. But recent outbreaks here in the U.S. and in Brazil have set back the effort.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Councilman's Star Rises Fast Amid Baltimore Unrest</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/codeswitch/2015/04/30/403382265/councilmans-star-rises-fast-amid-baltimore-unrest?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Nick Mosby, who represents much of West Baltimore, has become a prominent voice, turning the spotlight on chronic problems that sparked upheaval.</Description>
        <MainBody>Councilman's Star Rises Fast Amid Baltimore Unrest
April 30, 2015 6:45 PM ET
itoggle caption YouTube Screenshot
Councilman Nick Mosby spent a lot of time this week in front of the cameras, including an appearance on Sky News.
YouTube Screenshot
It's really hard to catch up with Nick Mosby.
The young Baltimore politician walks fast, which I discovered when I finally caught up with him. It was early Wednesday afternoon, and Mosby was in the lunchroom of Carver Vocational-Technical High School in West Baltimore, fresh from a TV hit on CNN .
Along with some of Carver's teachers and administrators, Mosby was joking and handing out slices of donated pizza to a stream of students. The pizza was a lure to keep the teenagers away from the uneasiness nearby. Carver was open again on Wednesday, after being closed for a day, like all the city's schools, because of concerns about unrest. Freddie Gray, the Baltimore man whose death after his arrest set off waves of protests and unrest this week, played for Carver's football team back in his school days.
Mosby burst into the national spotlight this week after a tense, on-camera exchange with a Fox News reporter. With unrest at its worst, Fox's Leland Vittert pressed Mosby: Was it right that looters had robbed and set fire to several stores in the neighborhood? Mosby kept responding that he thought looting was wrong, but that broader, historical realities  like a paucity of investment and counterproductive policies imposed on struggling inner cities just like his  were like kindling. They went back and forth like this for a few minutes until an exasperated Mosby finally had enough. "At this point, this is not productive," he said. "All you want to do is talk about this"  pointing over his shoulder to the liquor store that had been looted, and walking away from the conversation.
Just like that, Nick Mosby, a first-term city-council member representing Baltimore's 7th District, became something of a folk hero. He said what a segment of the Internet was feeling about coverage of the burning city. Video of the exchange, which documentarian Ricky Kelly posted to his Facebook page, has drawn more than 4 million views.
Back at Carver High on Wednesday, with two aides in tow, Mosby headed across the street to deliver the remaining pizza slices to the school baseball team, all suited up in blue uniforms, even though they had nobody to play against; Northwestern High School, the scheduled opponent, decided to suddenly scrap its baseball team altogether. Coach Michael Rosenband said it was the second non-game his team had suffered this week; a game on Monday was suspended when one opposing player's mother, concerned about the violence bubbling up not far from the field, plucked her kid from the game, leaving that team without enough players.
Met with @Carverbaseball team today delivering donated @PizzaBolis &amp; a quick pep talk. #CarverBears pic.twitter.com/yNWYKVrWir
 Nick J. Mosby (@councilmanmosby) April 29, 2015
Mosby had heard the story, and razzed the players when they huddled around him. "I heard y'all got saved, because Northwestern was gonna come in here and destroy you," he said. The players laughed.
Then he got serious. "I know you guys aren't part of the trouble," Mosby said. "When I look into your eyes, I see myself."
Mosby left them with an admonishment: Stay out of trouble, play the game, finish the pizza.
He walked with the last of the pizza to a busy neighborhood recreation center right by the field. Mosby introduced me to Zanes Cypress, the center's voluble director, who happened to be one of his college frat brothers. Cypress and I chatted for a moment, and when I looked up, Mosby was in the wind, off to the next thing.
-
The spotlight being shone on the police-involved killings of black men has made many of the victims in those incidents household names. But this meta-story has also given national profile to young community organizers and politicos  folks like Mosby  who were working the streets long before the incidents. They know who everyone is and where everything is, so they're indispensable to outsiders, like reporters who must catch up quickly. That was the case of Antonio French, a young, quotable St. Louis alderman. Before the Ferguson upheaval, he had around 5,000 Twitter followers. Today his list numbers more than 120,000. But French's higher profile has not come without critics. Other local officials suggested that French, who didn't live in the city of Ferguson, was an opportunist.
But in Baltimore, Mosby hasn't shirked press attention during his three years in office.
"If being a good politician means nurturing your personal brand, keeping your name out there, and promoting yourself as you propose solutions for your constituents' problems (and it does), then Nick Mosby is the exemplar," the Baltimore City Paper declared in 2012, when it dubbed him the city's best politician for his zeal for pressing the flesh and ribbon-cutting ceremonies.
Back at the rec center, I chatted with Demaune Millard of the Family League of Baltimore; he, like Cypress, had known Mosby for years before he ran for office. When I asked them if they were surprised by Mosby's political career, they shared a glance and a chuckle.
"I was," Millard said.
Mosby ran for office in 2007 and lost; Millard said Mosby's second, successful bid, was helped a bit by an adjustment of the borders of a neighboring district which happened to give Mosby a more favorable electorate in his own. Millard said Mosby was good on some of the issues, like pushing a bill that removed questions about a job-seeker's criminal history from job applications. But Millard said that politics in Baltimore is tough business, full of quagmires.
"As the issues become all the more complicated, like education issues, that will be where his bones are made," Millard said. "All the tough issues that are the third rail of Baltimore city politics are what will be the test."
Mosby ran, in part, on a vow for more police accountability  the city's police force has a well-earned reputation for excessive force . He tried to improve the relationship between the department and the folks that they police.
The Freddie Gray case falls right at the nexus of those issues.
But Mosby has another connection to the Gray case. When police completed their investigation into the confusing particulars of Gray's death on Thursday , they handed their findings over to Mosby's wife, Marilyn. She was sworn in as the city's chief prosecutor in January. Marilyn Mosby will decide what happens next: whether to call for a grand jury to seek an indictment for a criminal trial. The Freddie Gray case has thrust the Mosbys into national spotlights.

There was little media presence on Tuesday at Matthew Henson Elementary School, where Mosby presided over a community meeting on the unrest. Indeed, Mosby's press aide expressed some wariness about the media to me and my Code Switch colleague Shereen Marisol Meraji, when we arrived. ("There was this guy from Fox News and...")
About 50 people attended this meeting. Mosby dressed casually: sneakers, jeans, a zip-up pullover. As he moderated, he seemed to already know many of names of the folks in the audience.
A few people from the neighborhood lamented the destroyed or looted stores  and the many other stores that had temporarily closed to avoid the violence. This made it harder for residents to to take care of basic household needs.
"Right now we have no place to buy food," one man said to knowing head-nods in the audience. "You can't even buy toilet paper in a 50-block radius."
The neighborhood was undeserved by retailers even in times of relative calm, and when the CVS store burned down Monday, it left old folks without access to medication. There was real worry about whether the pharmacy might ever return. "This takes me back to the riots of 1968," Jack Young, the city council president said. "We still have scars from '68."
(Martin O'Malley, the city's former mayor and Maryland's former governor who is thought to be mulling a run for the White House, dropped in briefly and met folks in the auditorium. O'Malley said he'd been overseas but came home after seeing what was happening.)
In this crowd, people were ready to help. A few wondered whether anything could be done to fix the big, underlying problems fueling the unrest  the same conditions Mosby had alluded to in his truncated Fox News exchange. Mosby tried to put the conversation on a more practical footing; he agreed that those issues were at the root of all this, but since violence just the night before had been the worst, the immediate focus had to be on reaching out to folks in the streets and quelling the tension. He asked volunteers to go out that night and help keep things calm. He shouted out the elementary school's principal, Dave Guzman, for opening the auditorium for the meeting and handing out water in the neighborhood during the day. He told folks who were hungry that Whole Foods had donated meals.
Then he stepped outside to talk to some of the folks who were still milling about. It was a beautiful spring afternoon, unremarkable except for the whir of three hovering police helicopters overhead and a line of police vehicles , including an armored truck, that had formed on the corner.
Mosby joked around for a few minutes e gathered with a few folks, put on a big, goofy grin, and snapped a selfie. Then he hopped in his car with his aides and headed out to the next appointment. It looked like it was going to be another long night of fast walking.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Just Do It: Obama Tries To Sway Skeptical Democrats On Trade</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/itsallpolitics/2015/04/30/403382281/just-do-it-obama-tries-to-sway-skeptical-democrats-on-trade?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The president is finding it tough to get Democrats on board with a Pacific trade deal. He's meeting with some who might be open to it and even going to Nike headquarters next week for an event.</Description>
        <MainBody>It's proving difficult for President Obama to win over Democrats on trade so far. Brendan Smialowski/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Brendan Smialowski/AFP/Getty Images
It's proving difficult for President Obama to win over Democrats on trade so far.
Brendan Smialowski/AFP/Getty Images
President Obama met Thursday with moderate Democrats in hopes of rallying support for a controversial Asia-Pacific trade deal.
The president will need approval from at least some members of his own party to win passage of a "fast-track" bill, authorizing him to complete trade negotiations and present the agreement for an up-or-down vote in Congress.
So far, most Democratic lawmakers have been skeptical.
"I don't think enough of our issues have been resolved for us to be having a big movement of votes toward the bill," House Democratic Leader Nancy Pelosi said Thursday. "Hopefully we can have some accommodations" to make the agreement more palatable.
"What does it do to increase the paycheck of America's workers?" Pelosi asked. Democrats worry that any further liberalization of trade rules would lead to a greater exodus of U.S. jobs. And they complain past trade agreements, including NAFTA and the three-year-old pact with South Korea have not lived up to expectations.
Republican lawmakers are generally more supportive of trade deals, and House Speaker John Boehner promised "strong Republican support" for the fast-track bill. Some Tea Party members are wary, however, of giving the president any additional negotiating authority. The more House Republicans that withhold support, the bigger boost Obama will need from his own party.
"The president needs to step up his game in terms of garnering more support amongst Democrats, especially here in the House," Boehner said Thursday. "I don't think those who are involved in trade have done a very good job of helping the American [people] understand the benefits of trade and why, in fact, it's good for America."
Political operatives close to the president commissioned a poll which shows a narrow majority of Democrats  52 percent  back the Asia-Pacific trade deal. That number climbed to 82 percent when survey respondents were told the deal would make it easier for American companies to export products, and that it would raise labor and environmental standards.
The survey was released on Thursday by a group calling itself the "Progressive Coalition for American Jobs." Other progressive groups, which generally oppose the trade agreement, mocked the new coalition as an artificial vehicle for promoting the president's trade agenda.
Next week, Obama takes his trade show on the road  to Oregon. That's the home state of Sen. Ron Wyden, who's one of the top Democrats supporting the deal. Obama plans to take part in a pro-trade event at Nike. The Beaverton, Ore., company relies heavily on contract factories in Asia to produce its goods. Nike sneakers made in Vietnam could see lower tariffs if the trade deal is approved.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:16:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bill That Would Curb NSA's Bulk Collection Of Phone Data Advances In House</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2015/04/30/403377508/bill-that-would-curb-nsas-bulk-collection-of-phone-data-advances-in-house?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The USA Freedom Act would also make significant opinions from a secret court public and would allow challenges to  challenges to National Security Letters.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bill That Would Curb NSA's Bulk Collection Of Phone Data Advances In House
April 30, 2015 6:16 PM ET
Twitter
A bill that would end the National Security Agency's bulk collection of Americans' telephone data has advanced in the House, when the Judiciary Committee voted 25-2 in favor of the USA Freedom Act .
The bill would also curb a few other NSA activities that came into the spotlight after Edward Snowden leaked a cache of classified documents.
Among them: The bill would allow individual companies to challenge so-called National Security Letters, which are a type of subpoena issued by the FBI that come with a gag order; the bill would also make significant opinions from a secret court public.
The Judiciary Committee actually wrestled with a much broader bill. As The Hill reports, one of the amendments that was voted down by the committee would have curbed the government's ability to collect Americans' Internet communication without a warrant and would have prohibited the U.S. from forcing tech companies to leave a backdoors in networking devices.
The Hill reports :
"The discussion during Thursday's markup offered a fascinating glimpse into the political calculations and sacrifices lawmakers make in order to advance legislation.
"While every committee member who spoke up was in support of the amendment, it ultimately failed because of fear that it would kill the overall bill.
"'We have been assured if this amendment is attached to this bill, this bill is going nowhere,' Judiciary Committee Chairman Bob Goodlatte (R-Va.) said. 'This amendment is objected to by many in positions who affect the future of this legislation.'"
Congress has to act on this issue because some parts of the Patriot Act, which authorize certain surveillance programs, expire on June 1.
The Senate has introduced a bill similar to the USA Freedom Act.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Compton's Cowboys Keep The Old West Alive, And Kids Off The Streets</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/04/30/403353200/comptons-cowboys-keep-the-old-west-alive-and-kids-off-the-streets?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The city has seen some positive changes in recent years, including a reconnection with the city's rural past. The pastime has given youth an outlet in a region that's at the center of gang violence.</Description>
        <MainBody>Compton's Cowboys Keep The Old West Alive, And Kids Off The Streets
April 30, 2015 6:05 PM ET
Derrick Jennings never goes without his hat, boots or cowboy belt buckle. He wears them so it's clear to people that he's a hardworking cowboy. Gloria Hillard for NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Gloria Hillard for NPR
Derrick Jennings never goes without his hat, boots or cowboy belt buckle. He wears them so it's clear to people that he's a hardworking cowboy.
Gloria Hillard for NPR
In the middle of a gritty urban landscape in Southern California, some modern-day cowboys are trying  against great odds  to keep a little bit of the Old West alive.
Andrew Hosley gently tightens the bridle on Jade, a chestnut mare. More times than he can count, Jade has given kids in this Compton neighborhood a ride.
"I used to have the same reaction when I was a kid of their age," he says, "watching the guys ride by on horses, and I always wanted to touch 'em, ride 'em."
Andrew Hosley giving rides to neighborhood kids. Gloria Hillard for NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Gloria Hillard for NPR
Andrew Hosley giving rides to neighborhood kids.
Gloria Hillard for NPR
Cowboys have a long history here  going back to the late 1800s. This area of Compton, called Richland Farms, is still zoned agricultural.
Mayisha Akbar, a real estate broker moved her family here in the early eighties.
"We have about 400 homes and probably a couple of hundred horses, chickens, goats, lamas, all kinds of things," she says.
She was drawn to the quiet community, anchored by open space and backyard corrals.
But things changed when gang violence exploded.
"I stopped counting after we lost over 40 kids' lives," Akbar says.
She refers to that time as "the war."
"I just was so filled with emotion that I needed to keep the kids focused, and I needed to give them something other than the terrible daily things that they were facing," she says.
So she started going to horse auctions where she rescued horses, and, as it turned out, kids.
Today, nearly 30 years later, Compton Jr. Posse is still going strong.
In a small corral, 26-year-old Derrick Jennings is teaching some pint-size cowboys and girls about horse bridles. He looks up from under the brim of a very dusty cowboy hat, wide grin.
"Growing up, it was either gang bang or try to find something different," he says. "And thank you, Lord, I found something different."
He's never without his hat, boots or cowboy belt buckle. They let people know who he is, he says: employed, focused, hardworking  an all-around cowboy.
In Compton you'll see riders on busy streets or in a cloud of dust on one of the few dirt trails that occasionally run parallel to highways and train tracks. Some travel long distances to meet up at rodeos.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:05:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>He Carried His Mom On His Back For 5 Hours En Route To Medical Care</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/2015/04/30/403345274/he-carried-his-mom-on-his-back-for-5-hours-en-route-to-medical-care?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The epicenter of the quake that struck Nepal was in the district of Gorkha, a few hours' drive from the capital of Kathmandu. We're just beginning to see the extent of the damage in villages there.</Description>
        <MainBody>He Carried His Mom On His Back For 5 Hours En Route To Medical Care
April 30, 2015 6:05 PM ET
i
Amar Baramu carried his 70-year-old mother on his back for five hours, then rode with her on a bus for 12 more, to get her to a hospital for the head wound she suffered during the earthquake. Julie McCarthy/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Julie McCarthy/NPR
Amar Baramu carried his 70-year-old mother on his back for five hours, then rode with her on a bus for 12 more, to get her to a hospital for the head wound she suffered during the earthquake.
Julie McCarthy/NPR
He carried his 70-year-old mother on his back for five hours.
Then he traveled with her by bus for 12 more.
She suffered a severe head injury when the earthquake rumbled through her village of Thumi. He was trying to get her to a hospital in the Gorkha district in northern-central Nepal.
What You Need To Know Before Donating To Earthquake Relief For Nepal
Like many residents of Nepal's remote villages, Amar Baramu could be forgiven for thinking that cries for help have gone unheard. As the relief operation enters its sixth day, aid workers are just beginning to get to the far-off northern reaches of Gorkha, about a five-hour drive from Kathmandu. Difficult terrain, blocked roads and government confusion have slowed the effort.
I met Baramu, who's 52, as he sat on a bench in the Gorkha District Hospital, which has been turned into a triage ward for earthquake victims and a staging ground for international relief organizations. A physician from Doctors Without Borders hovered over his mother, Aitimaya, checking her injury.
Amar's forehead was creased with worry.
"There was violent shaking it seemed for 15 minutes," he said. "The older people like my mother couldn't rush out of their houses and they were badly hurt. Five days later no relief has reached us. We made shelters from leaves, straw and our clothing.
"All I have left are the clothes I'm wearing. I don't know what to do," he said, eyes welling with tears. "I came here to ask for help."
Villagers like Aitimaya and her son are connected to the outside world by a single dirt road. In normal circumstances these byways are gullied and death-defying. Reported landslides have made them impassable.
Helicopter pilot Subek Shrestha has flown more than 300 villagers to get medical care. Pragati Shahi hide caption
itoggle caption Pragati Shahi
Helicopter pilot Subek Shrestha has flown more than 300 villagers to get medical care.
Pragati Shahi
The only way to reach the decimated villages is by helicopter, a commodity in short supply in impoverished Nepal. Pilot Subek Shrestha says that weather permitting  and often this week it has not been  he's been ferrying supplies across the Gorkha district, including villages that sat on the catastrophic epicenter.
"Roads are blocked, no communication, and the area is still shaking, still shaking," Shrestha says. He shows a photo of the village Laprak, one of the most devastated in the area. It looks like a war zone. The houses are shattered and lying in heaps. Nothing looks like it's standing.
"Each and every village nearby this village  same as this, no houses standing," he says.
A post-earthquake scene in Bhaktapur, the ancient town outside Kathmandu that's a tourist attraction. Julie McCarthy/NPR hide caption
itoggle caption Julie McCarthy/NPR
A post-earthquake scene in Bhaktapur, the ancient town outside Kathmandu that's a tourist attraction.
Julie McCarthy/NPR
In the small chopper requisitioned by the government Shrestha has transported between 300 and 400 people in critical condition to nearby hospitals. Those who remain are seeking shelter in their ruined villages.
I ask him how many people in the area need a tent. "All of them, all of them," he says.
Yet there is hope, even in the middle of a disaster. A medical team from the Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation has arrived to focus on the needs of mothers and children. "Even just a few minutes ago, a lady delivered," says the team's chief, Dr. Olivier Hagon. "That is important: not all the time casualties or surgical cases. Life is going on."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 00:16:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Political Story On Breast Cancer Screenings Was Missing Some Science </title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/ombudsman/2015/04/30/403346081/political-story-on-breast-cancer-screenings-was-missing-some-science?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>A story on mammogram recommendations quotes only the opposing views in Congress.</Description>
        <MainBody>Political Story On Breast Cancer Screenings Was Missing Some Science
April 30, 2015 5:16 PM ET
iStockPhoto
iStockPhoto
A Morning Edition report on Monday with the headline " Congress May Be Forced To Intervene Again On Mammogram Recommendations " drew some sharp rebukes, many of them from physicians who expressed deep concern over missing context.
The story, from political reporter Juana Summers, looked at the latest development in the ongoing tug of war between the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force, which in 2009 recommended that women under 50 may not need to get routine mammograms, and Congress, which passed legislation to override that guidance. As the task force moves forward with an update of the guidelines, a repeat showdown is brewing, Summers reported. Her story was centered around an anecdote from Debbie Wasserman Schultz, the Florida Congressional Democrat and chair of the Democratic National Committee, who herself was treated for breast cancer.
"While stories of potential missed diagnoses are powerful, there was no attempt to investigate or explain the reasoning behind the recommendations," wrote Marika Russell of San Francisco, Calif. "A physician myself, I know firsthand how we are often faced with the challenge of balancing the greater good against individual patient needs or concerns, and would have appreciated a more nuanced look into this issue."
Jane Drummond, a primary care internist from Portland, Ore., laid out what she saw as the missing piece:
"Studies do not support screening for breast cancer in asymptomatic women without a family history of breast cancer. Mammography in this population has not been shown to decrease mortality from breast cancer and screening is associated with a significantly higher number of false positive tests leading to unnecessary biopsies and anxiety in the vast majority of women As physicians, we try to follow evidence based guidelines and especially avoid interventions that may lead to harm and unnecessary worry. A balanced discussion of this issue would include discussion of the USPSTF's rationale for their recommendations and the processes by which the evidence is reviewed."
The criticism was also taken up by HealthNewsReview.org 's Gary Schwitzer. That website says it "evaluates health care journalism, advertising, marketing, public relations and other messages that may influence consumers and provides criteria that consumers can use to evaluate these messages themselves."
Schwitzer wrote that while the NPR story quoted three current or former politicians, all of whom were opposed to the guidelines, "the four-minute piece had no interview with anyone with the Task Force. Not a quote. Not a word. That's imbalance. You can talk about bipartisan opposition all you want. But on a scientific controversy, citing bipartisan opposition doesn't equate to balanced or sound journalism."
I agree. Even as a piece about politics, not science, it needed at least a summary of the task force recommendations. The online headline is also skewed toward the Congressional critics, making it sound as though Congress has no choice but to intervene in the issue.
Ron Elving , an NPR senior editor and correspondent who stepped in to the edit the piece on a day when the staff was short-handed, told me by email that his understanding was that the piece was to be focused on the background for the expected Congressional action, and Summers had not been assigned to seek a task force interview.
"I did not expect [the piece] to be a fuller explanation of the issues or a rundown on the recommendations, which I understood had been reported on earlier," he wrote. Summers, he said, "tried to find a congressperson willing to speak up for the task force recommendations but was not able to find one. We should have made that clear."
Moreover, he wrote, lacking a Congressional voice in defense of the recommendations;
"NPR should have devoted more time in the piece to explaining why the task force has made its recommendations against these tests for younger women  and done so twice now. That would have made it clearer that these were science-based recommendations, concerned with public resources, but also concerned about the negative health effects and about false positives, etc. This would have been a better service to our listeners. We could have done a better job."
While this piece fell short of NPR's journalistic standards, NPR listeners can find more detailed information about the complicated mammogram issue elsewhere on NPR.org. Since April 13, NPR's radio newsmagazines have discussed the issue four times (including Summers' piece) and an additional two online-only stories have been posted. The pieces have examined in some depth the conflicting perspectives in the medical community, and an online story by Katherine Hobson looked in an intensely personal way at the internal debates the varying viewpoints have caused for patients. Kevin Lomangino, of HealthNewsReview.org called that piece "an insightful approach, bringing a much-needed patient perspective to the clinical weighting of benefits and harms." (He also had some quibbles with it, which you can read here .)
For those who come across Summers' story online, it might be helpful if NPR would add links on the page to a discussion of the other side of the argument.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:46:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ex-Gitmo Detainees In Uruguay Protest At U.S. Embassy</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/parallels/2015/04/30/403276388/ex-gitmo-detainees-in-uruguay-turn-to-protest-at-u-s-embassy?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>The men, resettled there after years in detention, say they aren't getting enough assistance. Camped outside the U.S. Embassy, they are seeking housing and other help reintegrating into society.</Description>
        <MainBody>Ex-Gitmo Detainees In Uruguay Protest At U.S. Embassy
April 30, 2015 4:46 PM ET
Former Guantanamo prison inmates walk between their tents and the U.S. Embassy in Montevideo, Uruguay's capital, where four former prisoners are protesting what they say is an inadequate deal in exchange for permanent asylum. Pablo Porciuncula/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Pablo Porciuncula/AFP/Getty Images
Former Guantanamo prison inmates walk between their tents and the U.S. Embassy in Montevideo, Uruguay's capital, where four former prisoners are protesting what they say is an inadequate deal in exchange for permanent asylum.
Pablo Porciuncula/AFP/Getty Images
When six Middle Eastern prisoners were freed from Guantanamo Bay prison and given refuge by the tiny South American country of Uruguay in December, they were grateful.
But four months later, four of them are camping outside the U.S. Embassy protesting as inadequate the deal they've been offered in exchange for permanent asylum.
Three small tents have been pitched on the smooth green lawn in front of the U.S. Embassy in Montevideo, Uruguay's capital.
Next to the shelters, two of the former Guantanamo prisoners pace up and down. Despite the wide area, they walk in a tight circle  almost as if they are still in a prison yard.
Among them is Abdelhadi Omar Faraj. His picture from his Guantanamo days shows him with a long beard and hair. Now, his hair is cut short.
i
Former Guantanamo prison inmates (from left) Syrian Ahmed Adnan Ahjam, Tunisian Abdul Bin Mohammed Bin Abess Ourgy and Syrians Abdelhadi Omar Faraj and Ali Husein Shaaban pray in front of the U.S. Embassy in Montevideo on Wednesday. Pablo Porciuncula/AFP/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Pablo Porciuncula/AFP/Getty Images
Former Guantanamo prison inmates (from left) Syrian Ahmed Adnan Ahjam, Tunisian Abdul Bin Mohammed Bin Abess Ourgy and Syrians Abdelhadi Omar Faraj and Ali Husein Shaaban pray in front of the U.S. Embassy in Montevideo on Wednesday.
Pablo Porciuncula/AFP/Getty Images
He initially speaks in broken Spanish. He says he has been trying to learn. But eventually, he reverts to Arabic. He says he spent one-third of his life in Guantanamo.
"Now we moved to another kind of prison where nothing has changed," he says through a translator. "We are still under the same pressure. The mental state has not changed. I don't feel settled down. This is essential for me to move on."
He's Syrian, and according to his file, was captured in Pakistan when he says he was about 20 years old. The U.S. accused him of belonging to a Syrian cell that fought with Osama Bin Laden in the Tora Bora region along the Afghanistan-Pakistan border.
In 2009 he was deemed no longer a threat and ready for release. It was five years later before he arrived in Uruguay.
Initially, there was a lot of fanfare in Uruguay. Then-President Jose Mujica  himself a former prisoner  made a big deal of taking the six men in, on what he said were humanitarian grounds.
Faraj actually wrote an open letter to the Uruguayan people when he arrived. In it he said he had "only good will and positive contributions" to make.
"If not for Uruguay, I would remain even now in that black hole in Cuba," Faraj wrote. "I am at a loss for words to express my gratitude."
But that gratitude has turned to disillusion.
"We came here and they asked us to start working right away. It's not possible to become a normal person in such a short time," he says. "We need a proper rehab program that allows us to integrate into the society and step by step we can start working and moving on with our lives."
The issue is who should pay for that. Up to now, their funding came partially from a local union that provided housing and other help. Now the United Nations is offering them a $500 monthly stipend if they sign a formal agreement.
But the men say it's not enough. They are in a country where they don't speak the language or understand the culture. They have no family. They have spent more than a decade in prison. Many have health problems.
They say they are willing and able to work, but first they need time to adapt and heal. They want their families to settle here with them in their own homes.
They say no one thought their situation through.
"We know Uruguay is a poor country. That's why we are asking the United States to give a hand to help," Faraj says. "We are not asking for them to make up for all the 13 years we spent in Guantanamo  we are just asking them for the minimum."
But it's the Uruguayan government that, for now, is assuming responsibility. It has appointed a mediator to come up with a deal. The six men have also hired a lawyer.
In an interview with NPR, mediator Christian Mirza says these men are in a difficult situation.
Related NPR Stories
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Documents Show FAA Questioned Mental Fitness of Germanwings Co-Pilot Andreas Lubitz</title>
        <Link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2015/04/30/403356547/documents-show-faa-questioned-mental-fitness-of-germanwings-co-pilot-andreas-lub?utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=news</Link>
        <Description>Newly released documents show the FAA initially declined to give Andreas Lubitz a medical certificate for his U.S. pilot's license because of his history of depression.</Description>
        <MainBody>Documents Show FAA Questioned Mental Fitness of Germanwings Co-Pilot Andreas Lubitz
April 30, 2015 4:32 PM ET
September 13, 2015 photo of Andreas Lubitz, who is believed to have deliberately crashed Germanwings flight 9525 into a mountain in southern France on March 24, 2015, killing all 150 people on board. Getty Images/Getty Images hide caption
itoggle caption Getty Images/Getty Images
September 13, 2015 photo of Andreas Lubitz, who is believed to have deliberately crashed Germanwings flight 9525 into a mountain in southern France on March 24, 2015, killing all 150 people on board.
Getty Images/Getty Images
Newly released documents from the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration show that it initially declined to grant a medical certificate to Andreas Lubitz, the pilot who is believed to have intentionally crashed an airline into the French Alps last month.
The documents, obtained under the Freedom of Information Act, provide an eerie glimpse into Lubitz's mental history and an effort to conceal that from U.S. medical examiners.
In the summer of 2010, Lubitz was enrolled in a training program for Lufthansa Airlines. As part of that program, he applied for a U.S. pilot's license so he could continue his training in Arizona, where weather conditions are favorable to flying all year round. But he needed a medical certificate to get a license.
The FAA documents show Lubitz checked "no" in response to an online application question about whether he had been treated for any mental disorders. But a later copy of the questionnaire shows it had been changed to "yes" by the aviation medical examiner after discovering Lubitz had been treated for severe depression a year earlier.
Dr. Warren Silberman, the former head of the FAA's aerospace medical certification unit, told NPR that the aviation administration declined to give Lubitz a medical certificate. But Silberman says Lubitz was offered a chance to clarify things.
"We sent a request for information, saying hey Lubitz, we see here that you had depression, please provide us with a status report," he said.
Lubitz's psychologist in Germany provided the FAA with a letter, translated from German, saying Lubitz had been treated with several drugs for his depression disorders. The psychologist, whose name is redacted, states that Lubitz was "completely recovered."
Silberman says the FAA let Lubitz know he would receive his medical certificate. "Meaning that somebody in the division reviewed the statement from the psychiatrist, thought that it was adequate and cleared him," he said.
The letter warned Lubitz that he would be prohibited from flying if his depression returned.
Lubitz was ultimately able to secure a job as a co-pilot for Germanwings.
As NPR reported earlier , it was discovered after Flight 9525 crashed into the French Alps that Lubitz had been treated for suicidal tendencies, and that investigators found boxes of medication in his home, along with torn up doctor's notes for sick leave, including one note for the day of the crash.
Silberman says in May, members of the Aerospace Medical Association will meet to discuss Lubitz's case. "We're going to get together because of the Germanwings accident and come up, you know, is there anything else we should do now," he says.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
