<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:06:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman arrested after attack with stiletto</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-arrested-after-attack-with-stiletto-1.494150</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman arrested after attack with stiletto
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 09:06 PM.
NICEVILLE - A 21-year-old Niceville woman is in custody after a warrant was issued due to charges that she attacked her boyfriend with a stiletto.
The woman, who is not being named to attack the victim's identity, was arrested on June 7.
The attack occurred on March 28, around 6:30 p.m., according to the arrest report. She and her boyfriend were reportedly living together in a room at Tisa's Friendly Inn.
The woman hit her boyfriend in the head with the heel of a four-inch stiletto shoe, the report said. He was treated for a three-inch wound to his head.
The wound went through the skin stopping at the skull (approximately three centimeters deep) and required six staples to close, a doctor reported to Niceville Police officers. A witness told police that the woman repeatedly said, "I did not mean to hurt him."
She is charged with aggravated battery causing great bodily harm.
Her next scheduled court date is July 27.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:57:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of theft of 12-pack of Corona Light</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-theft-of-12-pack-of-corona-light-1.494149</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of theft of 12-pack of Corona Light
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 08:57 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 46-year-old Fort Walton Beach man is charged with taking a 12-pack of Corona Light from a Circle K.
The man went into the store at around 3 p.m. on June 8, according to the arrest report. He picked up a 12-pack of beer and allegedly walked out of the store without paying.
He was caught on security footage and was identified by a witness, the report said.
He is charged with petit theft.
His next scheduled court date is June 30.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:55:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of stomping on woman's chest after argument over food</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-stomping-on-woman-s-chest-after-argument-over-food-1.494147</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of stomping on woman's chest after argument over food
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 08:55 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 29-year-old man is accused of stomping on his wife's chest after an argument over leftovers.
Fort Walton Beach Police officers were called to the home around 12:30 a.m. on June 8, according to the arrest report. The man and his wife had been drinking and got into an argument.
The wife said that her husband had been eating her leftover food in the kitchen and she got upset, the report said. She said she went into the kitchen and threw the food on to the floor.
At that point, she said they started arguing and her husband "pushed" her "to the ground" and "stomped on her chest," according to the report. She had redness on her sternum.
The man said the argument was only verbal and denied any physical altercation, the report said.
He is charged with misdemeanor battery.
His next scheduled court date is June 30.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:49:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Local church holds vigil to honor Charleston victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/local-church-holds-vigil-to-honor-charleston-victims-1.494143</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Local church holds vigil to honor Charleston victims
Jim Robbins, a Gregg Chapel musician, performs at Wednesday nights vigil.
Special to the Daily News
By WENDY VICTORA | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 06:49 PM.
Hundreds gathered Wednesday night for a local vigil honoring the nine victims of last weeks shooting at a Charleston, S.C., church.
The vigil was held at Gregg Chapel AME Church on Carson Drive in Fort Walton Beach.
More than 20 pastors from churches across the community led the crowd in prayer.
It was a coming together in the city that was really positive, said Pastor Cecil Williams of Gregg Chapel. It was a true prayer vigil.
It was a city in love.
Contact Daily News Managing Editor Wendy Victora at 850-315-4478 or wvictora@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @WendyVnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:44:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Petitions call for removing Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/petitions-call-for-removing-confederate-flag-1.494137</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Petitions call for removing Confederate flag
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 06:44 PM.
The push to stop flying the Confederate flag over government buildings  and other public areas  has reached Northwest Florida.
Two petitions, started on www.change.org, are urging the removal of the Confederate flag from the Walton County Courthouse lawn and from the William Uncle Bill Lundy memorial in Crestview.
The Okaloosa County NAACP launched its petition Tuesday, asking Crestview Mayor David Cadle and the City Council to remove the rebel flag from the Lundy monument, which sits at the intersection of E. First Avenue and State Road 85.
I am sure that the City Council will look at this very closely, Cadle said.
He said he has received two phone calls from local citizens on the issue.
The NAACP has attempted in years past to remove the flag from the Lundy monument. The group tried most recently in December 2013, but the City Council refused to vote on the issue.
Lundy, believed by some to be the last surviving Confederate veteran, died in 1957. The Crestview Lions Club built the memorial the following year.
The petition calling for the removal of the Confederate flag from the Walton County Courthouse lawn in Defuniak Springs was launched Tuesday by Santa Rosa Beach resident Michelle Uhlfelder.
As of Thursday evening, almost 300 people had signed the petition, which is directed at the Walton County Board of Commissioners.
Uhlfelder said she took the initiative after hearing the pastor at her church talk about the mass shooting in Charleston, South Carolina.
He said, Its a time to be bold about things like this, she said. ... I would love to get 1,000 people. A thousand people wins an election down here.
Uhlfelder said its past time for the controversial flag to come down.
It has such a soiled history, she said. ... Its of a confederacy of rebels that tried to rise up and lost. Now were flying the losers flag, essentially, on our property.
Walton County NAACP President Raymond Jackson said he supports the removal of the flag.
Its time for it to happen, said Jackson, who lives in DeFuniak Springs.  ... The Spanish were here. The British were here. And we dont fly their flags at the courthouse.
The rebel flag has flown over Walton Countys Confederate Monument since it was first erected in 1871. The monument is Floridas first memorial to Confederate war dead. In 2002, the local chapter of the NAACP lobbied to have the flag removed, but commissioners voted down the measure.
Uhlfelder, who grew up in Atlanta and Memphis and has lived in Santa Rosa Beach for seven years, also is rallying other residents to attend the July 14 commission meeting. The item has been placed on the boards agenda for discussion.
County Commission Chairman Bill Imfeld said the issue is a timely one and that he is interested in reaching a compromise.
(The flag) can mean different things to different people, and I think we should try to be judicious ... and achieve a decorum that will diffuse harsh feelings and bring the community together.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stranded leatherback turtle taken to Gulfarium (PHOTOS, VIDEO)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/stranded-leatherback-turtle-taken-to-gulfarium-photos-video-1.494117</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Stranded leatherback turtle taken to Gulfarium (PHOTOS, VIDEO)
Staff from the Gulfarium Marine Adventure Park set up a harness to lift a 5-foot, 382-pound female Leatherback sea turtle into a truck after the turtle came ashore Thursday at the north end of Rocky Bayou in Niceville.
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 05:44 PM.
NICEVILLE  A leatherback turtle took up temporary residence at Gulfarium Marine Adventure Park Thursday after stranding itself in Niceville.
The 5-foot, 5-inch, 382-pound female sea turtle was found around 9 a.m. in Niecy Cooper's backyard, which is located at the north end of Rocky Bayou.
She immediately contacted Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, who asked the Emerald Coast Wildlife Refuge and Gulfarium to respond to the scene.
VIDEO of the stranding.
Ive never been that close to a leatherback, Cooper said. Its amazing actually.
Leatherbacks are the largest sea turtle in the world and typically weigh between 500 and 1,500 pounds when fully grown. The endangered species are rarely spotted locally.
Its the second call FWC received this week about a stranded leatherback turtle. On Sunday morning, people spotted one stuck on a sandbar in Toms Bayou in Valparaiso. They pushed it back into the water with the help of an FWC officer.
Its most likely the same one, but I cant 100 percent say that it is, said FWC spokeswoman Bekah Nelson.
In spite of criticism, Nelson said FWC handled the first stranding appropriately.
The officer was there, she said. He looked over the turtle.
Before freeing it from the sandbar, the officer checked the turtles eyes, flippers and shell and found no signs of illness or trauma, Nelson said.
Amanda Wilkerson, who oversees ECWR, said they were en-route to the stranding Sunday and expressed concern it was released that day.
The turtles location in the bayou was a red flag for her agency, she said.
We predicted that she would re-strand, and she did, Wilkerson said.
While waiting for Gulfarium crew to arrive, ECWR staff kept the turtle cool and wet with moist towels.
An evaluation at the scene didnt reveal any clear reasons for the stranding, so they opted to move her to Gulfarium on Okaloosa Island, according to Allen McDowell, who is the director of the sea turtle care program there.
Leatherbacks do not do as well in rehabilitation programs as other species of turtle, but the turtles proximity to fresh water and distance from the Gulf combined with the likelihood it had twice stranded itself, prompted the decision, McDowell said.
The turtle is alert and moving, but again, were not comfortable just releasing it, he said.
Once at the facility, staff took blood tests, an ultrasound and X-rays.
Its only the third time in the last decade a leatherback has beached itself along local shores. In both the other cases, the turtles died on the beach.
Gulfarium officials said they will share updates on the turtle as they get back test results. If no issues are found, staff will release turtle in the Gulf of Mexico.
A small loggerhead turtle was also rescued by wildlife officials Thursday morning.
The Emerald Coast Wildlife Refuge was contacted around 9:30 a.m. about the sea turtle stuck in a fishing net along a beach on Eglin Air Force Base, said director Amanda Wilkerson.
It was taken to Gulf World for rehabilitation and is expected to make a full recovery.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Burned kitten recovering at PAWS</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/burned-kitten-recovering-at-paws-1.494093</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Burned kitten recovering at PAWS
Disco, an 8-week-old kitten, was rescued earlier this week in the Navarre area with severe burns on her paws. Panhandle Animal Welfare Society and Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office are trying to find out what happened.
Special to the Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 04:04 PM.
The Panhandle Animal Welfare Society is hoping to find out what happened to an 8-week-old kitten that was found in the Navarre area with severe burns earlier this week.
Shes been in pain and shes very vocal like any other kitten, said Chloe Finley, a PAWS employee who is also fostering the kitten. Shes sweet. Theres not anything bad I can say about her.
Krystal Martel found the kitten in her Midway neighborhood on Maverick Lane Sunday and later brought the cat to Navarre resident Melanie Oberlander, who took her to PAWS. She and her kids named the kitten Disco.
You could smell the infection and see the bones of her feet, she said. I took her in overnight and gave her some antiseptic and got in touch with Melanie.
Martel said her neighborhood has a number of stray cats. In the past, shes heard of other animal abuse stories.
We seem to be a place were people drop off their litters, she said.
Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office Public Information Officer Rich Aloy said deputies took a report a few days after the kitten was found, but that they are not investigating.
Dee Thompson, executive director of PAWS, said her agency couldnt investigate the case because it likely didnt occur in Okaloosa County, which is where PAWS has jurisdiction.
What PAWS can do is to take care of the kitten and share any information they receive with officials in Santa Rosa County.
Were trying to figure out if the burns are chemical or thermal, since she doesnt have singed hair, Thompson said. Thats why we want to know if anybody has seen something...this is felony level cruelty.
Thompson said Disco wears bandages on her paws that have to be changed throughout the day. She is on a high calorie/high protein diet and uses shredded paper instead of cat litter to avoid anything interfering with the bandages.
It will definitely be a little bit before they adopt her out, Thompson said.
DONATE TO DISCO: You can donate to Disco by bringing in a/d Hill brand canned cat food or make a monetary donation. More information about PAWS is available at paws-shelter.com.
Anyone with information about what happened to Disco, can anonymously report it by calling the Santa Rosa County Crime Stoppers at 850-437-STOP.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Local amateur radio club hosting field day this weekend </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/local-amateur-radio-club-hosting-field-day-this-weekend-1.494090</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Local amateur radio club hosting field day this weekend
JASON EPPINK | Special to the Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 03:55 PM.
The Playground Amateur Radio Club will host an Amateur Radio Field Day at Hurlburt Field Picnic Grounds this weekend to promote the use of ham radios.
Were trying to preserve the hobby, said Mo Hodgdon, chairman of the event. I believe winds of 90 miles per hour can take down cell phone and landlines. Without them how do you communicate?
Hodgdon pointed out during Hurricane Katrina emergency crews communicated through amateur and CB radios.
During the field day, all ages can participate using radios provided by the club to make contacts with other radios along North America as other clubs will be participating with similar events.
While ham radios may seem to be an archaic piece of technology, they have more capability than most think. Some of the more expensive models can be hooked to a computer and send emails, photos and chat.
Hodgdon said he hopes kids will attend to learn more about amateur radios and perhaps even gain interest in obtaining a radio license.
After 9/11 a 10-year-old girl with a handheld radio did communications between a shelter and New York City Emergency Operation Center for eight hours, he said.
In the local area, Hodgdon and his wife volunteer to provide communications during disasters.
We want people to see what we can do, he said. Radios can help in any emergency situation.
The PARC Field Day is from 1 p.m. Saturday until 10 a.m. Sunday at the Hurlburt Field Picnic Grounds, located at the south side of U.S. Highway 98. For more information, visit w4zbb.org.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Policyholders may lose access to two area hospitals</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/policyholders-may-lose-access-to-two-area-hospitals-1.494080</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Policyholders may lose access to two area hospitals
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 02:53 PM.
Sacred Heart Health Care System has resolved its contract negotiations with Florida Blue, but another nail-biting contract dispute has the potential to affect individuals across Northwest Florida.
Letters have gone out from Humana notifying patients of Hospital Corporation of America facilities that as of July 10 those hospitals will no longer participate in your Medicare PPO plan network.
Both Twin Cities Hospital in Niceville and Fort Walton Beach Medical Center in Fort Walton Beach are run by HCA.
We understand that changing your hospital can be difficult, but were here to help you through this transition, the letter, dated June 3, said.
Fort Walton Beach residents Eva Mae and Walter Salvatore said its kind of scary knowing they are caught in the middle of the two parties negotiations.
They have looked to see if they could find a different insurance carrier, but they havent found anyone who would accept them until open enrollments in October.
The government says you have to have insurance, Walter said. Well, weve got insurance, but how can the government allow this insurance company to quit in the middle of the year and say no hospital is going to take you?
Im 84, wife in her 70s, he added. For us to go without a hospital for the next four months is crazy.
Though the tone of the letter sounded dire enough to scare some people, Humana spokeswoman Nancy Hanewinckel said Humana and HCA still have plenty time to reach a contract agreement.
Our contract with HCA is still in existence and will not expire until July 10, she said. There is still a very active negotiation going on. Were hoping any day now we will be reporting we have signed a new agreement.
Hanewinckel said the insurance company was required to send the letter as the deadline to reach an agreement with HCA approached to within 30 days.
Humana sent a second letter to clear up some discrepancies with the first. That letter said the insurance companies are terminating its contracts with HCA hospitals, but attempted to clarify that HCA ambulatory surgery centers would remain as Humana participants.
The emphasis on are terminating further confused patients.
HCA operates 47 hospitals in Florida.
Fort Walton Beach Medical Center spokeswoman Denise Kendust provided an HCA statement on the ongoing discussions with Humana.
We remain actively engaged in continuing discussions with Humana and are optimistic that well come to an agreement before the July 10th extension date for Humana Commercial and Humana Medicare Advantage plans, the statement said.
The hospital offered two phone numbers for patients to call with questions about their coverage.
Those are 850-863-7511 or 850-863-7515.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:01:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds nationwide health care law subsidies</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/supreme-court-upholds-nationwide-health-care-law-subsidies-1.493999</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Supreme Court upholds nationwide health care law subsidies
Jessica Ellis, right, with the "yay 4 ACA" sign, and other supporters of the Affordable Care Act, react with cheers as the opinion for health care is reported outside of the Supreme Court in Washington on Thursday. The Supreme Court on Thursday upheld the nationwide tax subsidies under President Barack Obama's health care overhaul, in a ruling that preserves health insurance for millions of Americans.
JACQUELYN MARTIN | AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 11:01 AM.
WASHINGTON  The Supreme Court on Thursday upheld the nationwide tax subsidies under President Barack Obama's health care overhaul, in a ruling that preserves health insurance for millions of Americans.
The justices said in a 6-3 ruling that the subsidies that 8.7 million people currently receive to make insurance affordable do not depend on where they live, under the 2010 health care law.
The outcome is the second major victory for Obama in politically charged Supreme Court tests of his most significant domestic achievement. It came the same day the court gave the administration an unexpected victory by preserving a key tool the administration uses to fight housing bias.
Chief Justice John Roberts again voted with his liberal colleagues in support of the law. Roberts also was the key vote to uphold the law in 2012. Justice Anthony Kennedy, a dissenter in 2012, was part of the majority on Thursday.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care Act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," Roberts wrote in the majority opinion.
In a dissent he summarized from the bench, Justice Antonin Scalia said, "We should start calling this law SCOTUScare." Using the acronym for the Supreme Court, Scalia said his colleagues have twice stepped in to save the law from what Scalia considered worthy challenges.
Justices Samuel Alito and Clarence Thomas joined the dissent, as they did in 2012.
Nationally, 10.2 million people have signed up for health insurance under the Obama health overhaul. That includes the 8.7 million people who are receiving an average subsidy of $272 a month to help pay their insurance premiums.
Of those receiving subsidies, 6.4 million people were at risk of losing that aid because they live in states that did not set up their own health insurance exchanges.
The challenge devised by die-hard opponents of the law, often derided by critics as "Obamacare," relied on four words  established by the state  in the more than 900-page law.
The law's opponents argued that the vast majority of people who now get help paying for their insurance premiums are ineligible for their federal tax credits. That is because roughly three dozen states opted against creating their own health insurance marketplaces, or exchanges, and instead rely on the federal healthcare.gov to help people find coverage if they don't get insurance through their jobs or the government.
In the challengers' view, the phrase "established by the state" demonstrated that subsidies were to be available only available to people in states that set up their own exchanges. Those words cannot refer to exchanges established by the Health and Human Services Department, which oversees healthcare.gov, the opponents argued.
The administration, congressional Democrats and 22 states responded that it would make no sense to construct the law the way its opponents suggested. The idea behind the law's structure was to decrease the number of uninsured. The law prevents insurers from denying coverage because of "pre-existing" health conditions. It requires almost everyone to be insured and provides financial help to consumers who otherwise would spend too much of their paycheck on their premiums.
The point of the last piece, the subsidies, is to keep enough people in the pool of insured to avoid triggering a so-called death spiral of declining enrollment, a growing proportion of less healthy people and premium increases by insurers.
Several portions of the law indicate that consumers can claim tax credits no matter where they live. No member of Congress said that subsidies would be limited, and several states said in a separate brief to the court that they had no inkling they had to set up their own exchange for their residents to get tax credits.
The 2012 case took place in the midst of Obama's re-election campaign, when he touted the largest expansion of the social safety net since the advent of Medicare nearly a half-century earlier. But at the time, the benefits of the Affordable Care Act were mostly in the future. Many of its provisions had yet to take effect.
In 2015, the landscape has changed, although the partisan and ideological divisions remain for a law that passed Congress in 2010 with no Republican votes.
The case is King v. Burwell, 14-114.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OCSO investigating apparent homicide</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/ocso-investigating-apparent-homicide-1.493996</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>OCSO are investigating a homicide that occurred at 4 Marty Drive in Fort Walton Beach.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 10:39 AM.
Photo Galleries
Homicide
FORT WALTON BEACH  Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office is investigating the death of 39-year-old Jimmy Lee Dodd, who was shot early Wednesday morning.
Deputies responded to Dodds mobile home at 4 Marty Lane at about 5:30 a.m. after a resident of his home called 911.
When they arrived, they found Dodds body located outside the trailer, according to a press release.
Investigators said Dodd had been shot multiple times and are still in the process of interviewing various witnesses.
One of the neighbors down the street, who didnt want to give his name, said he heard about five or six gunshots around 5:20 a.m.
I woke up and checked on my daughter and grandson, he said. I could tell the shots were close.
Around 10 a.m., several vehicles from the OCSO, including a canine unit were parked in front of the mobile home alongside a van from West Florida Removal Service.
An autopsy will be conducted by Floridas District One Medial Examiners Office.
This is the fourth shooting to occur in the Fort Walton Beach area in nearly two weeks.
Anyone with information on the shooting is asked to contact the OCSO at 651-744 or Emerald Coast Crime Stoppers at 863-TIPS, emeraldcoastcrimestoppers.com, or text TIP214 plus your message to CRIMES (274637).

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sacred Heart, Florida Blue reach agreement</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/sacred-heart-florida-blue-reach-agreement-1.493872</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Sacred Heart, Florida Blue reach agreement
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 06:15 PM.
Sacred Heart Health System announced Wednesday it will continue to be a participating healthcare provider for Florida Blue insurance plans.
The two entities signed a new contract that will allow Florida Blue members with continued access to Sacred Heart services for the next three years.
Our hospitals in Miramar Beach, Port St. Joe and Pensacola, including our Childrens Hospital, will continue to be a participating provider in Florida Blue plans, said Susan Davis, president and CEO of Sacred Heart Health System.
Kirk Fischer, vice president of delivery system for Florida Blue said the Northwest Florida community is a very important market to the company.
Our new contract with Sacred Heart ensures we can continue to provide the members in the area with access to high-quality and affordable health care, he said.
The new agreement comes less than a month after Sacred Heart sent letters to some of its customers notifying them the health care system could part ways with Florida Blue by July 1. The letter said Sacred Heart and Florida Blue had been negotiating a new contract for several months and had been unable to reach an agreement.
Im very happy. Its fantastic, said Kathleen Armstrong, who is insured by Florida Blue and regularly receives health care services at Sacred Heart on the Emerald Coast.
Armstrong, who received her letter June 11, suffers from a rare genetic immune deficiency disease that requires her to have monthly treatments. She said she was never notified by Florida Blue about the potential change.
She was distraught at the prospect of no longer being able to use Sacred Heart.
I just think its exceptional care and I wouldnt want to go anywhere else, she said. Im glad its going to continue.
Armstrong spoke out about her concerns to the Daily News earlier this month.
I wanted to be a voice for the community, she said. I hope if this ever happens again, the community will band together.

Sacred Heart will continue as an in-network provider for the following Florida Blue plans:
Blue Care HMO (Health Options Inc.)
BlueChoice (Preferred Patient Care)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:11:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Popular doctor, lawyer, politician Durell Peaden passes away</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/popular-doctor-lawyer-politician-durell-peaden-passes-away-1.493870</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Popular doctor, lawyer, politician Durell Peaden passes away
Sen. Durell Peaden (center), R-Crestview, asks a question of Rep. Don Brown (far right), R-DeFuniak Springs, in 2004 in Niceville as members of the area's legislative delegation met to discuss priorities for the 2005 session.
File photo
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 06:11 PM.
CRESTVIEW  Former state Sen. Durell Peaden, a towering figure in Northwest Florida politics, passed away Tuesday. He was 69.
Peaden, who was both a physician and an attorney, represented the northern portions of several Northwest Florida counties in the state Senate from 2001 to 2010, when he left office due to term limits. From 1995 to 2000, he represented much of that same area in the state House of Representatives.
He always called Crestview home, said state Sen. Greg Evers, who was a close friend and distant cousin of Peadens. He cared so much about the people who live here.
Evers, who followed Peaden into the Florida House in 2000 and the Senate in 2010, said Peaden was the smartest man I ever knew.
He had an insightfulness that was always right on, Evers added. In any situation, you could call on him for advice, and hed always have the right answer.
Born in DeFuniak Springs in 1945, Peaden grew up in Crestview, a block away from his lifelong friend and longtime legislative aide, Roger Robinson. He later graduated from Tulane University, the medical school at Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara, and the Thomas Goode Jones School of Law at Faulkner University.
Peaden and his wife, Nancy, had three children: Durell III (Trey), Tyler and Taylen.
He was extremely brilliant, Robinson said. He just exuded compassion for his patients when he was practicing medicine, and for his constituents when he was in the legislature. I run into people all the time who say things like, Dr. Peaden saved my grandbabys life. He was always working non-stop to help people.
Like most successful politicians, Peaden was outgoing and friendly, Robinson said.
He had a photographic memory, Robinson added. If he met you once, he remembered you. He could tell you where he met you, and under what circumstances.
Evers said that while Peaden was interested in many issues, his foremost concern was providing access to medical care for his constituents.
He was probably proudest of being able to bring the FAMU pharmacy school to Crestview, Evers said. He also worked very hard to bring the Lake Erie College of Medicines dental school to DeFuniak Springs.
As one of the sponsors of Florida's Stand Your Ground law, Peaden was back in the limelight in 2012 following George Zimmermans shooting of Trayvon Martin.
He explained to people that the law was never meant to be applied in that type of circumstance, Robinson said. That law was prompted by an incident where an elderly couple in Pensacola were living in a FEMA trailer following Hurricane Ivan. An intruder broke in, and a man shot him. The senator said the man shouldn't have to wait 90 days to see if the prosecutor was going to bring charges against him.
Peaden was a dean at the Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine in Erie, Pennsylvania. He was there earlier this month for the schools graduation when he suffered a massive heart attack. Robinson said Peaden was admitted to the hospital there, where he later passed away.
Both Robinson and Evers said Peaden leaves a legacy of many behind the scenes accomplishments.
He wasnt looking for glory, Robinson said. He just did things because they were the right things to do. He is going to be greatly missed.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:49:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DOT sees light at the end of Gap Creek</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/dot-sees-light-at-the-end-of-gap-creek-1.493864</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
DOT sees light at the end of Gap Creek
Construction crews work Tuesday on the bridge at Gap Creek on Beal Parkway, which has been under construction since January 2014.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:49 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  Work has resumed on the Gap Creek bridge replacement project on Beal Parkway.
Construction crews returned to the site June 8 after being on standby for much of the spring due to a large number of underground obstructions  logs and stumps  found in the creek bed.
In March, officials with the Department of Transportation announced the bridges completion date would be pushed back to late summer.
DOT Spokesman Ian Satter said the project is still expected to meet that deadline.
The bridge substructure, the bridge superstructure and the north and southbound roadway construction are all left to do, he said.
Motorists can expect some traffic shifts in the coming months, and DOT will announce those changes before they happen, Satter added.
The $3.3 million project has slowed traffic considerably on that section of Beal Parkway.
Im very frustrated as a business owner because the worst is yet to come, said Terry Akens, who owns Southern Signs, which sits on the west side of Beal Parkway.
His main concern is that his company has to make and receive multiple deliveries each day. He said the DOT has guaranteed him access to his business from Beal Parkway, but he doesnt know exactly what that will look like.
Akens, like many locals, will be happy when its completed.
It will be better all the way around, he said. Theres no doubt about that.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:39:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida's largest insurer to ask for rate hikes in 2016</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/florida-s-largest-insurer-to-ask-for-rate-hikes-in-2016-1.493861</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Florida's largest insurer to ask for rate hikes in 2016
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By The Associated Press
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:39 PM.
TALLAHASSEE  Florida has dodged hurricanes for the last decade, but the state's largest property insurer says it needs to keep hiking the rates paid by those customers who live along the coast and in heavily populated South Florida.
The board of Citizens Property Insurance voted unanimously Wednesday to raise rates an average of 3.2 percent statewide, although the actual rates paid by homeowners could vary widely depending on where they live. Many inland customers with Citizens, for example, are expected to see a slight decrease.
Citizens officials approved the rate hike without any debate or discussion. State regulators must still sign off on the rate hike, but if it is approved the higher rates would take effect in February 2016.
Nearly half of the state-created insurer's 600,000 customers will actually see slight decreases in their rates according to figures drawn up by Citizens staff.
But those customers who live near the coast could pay an average of 8.6 percent more. Citizens officials say rate hikes are needed for homeowners in Palm Beach, Broward, Miami-Dade and Monroe counties.
Citizens officials say there are several reasons for the need for higher rates in South Florida. One reason is that Citizens is shrinking in size due to an aggressive push by the insurer to have policyholders switch to privately run companies. That leaves Citizens with customers who are at a higher risk of storm damage.
Another reason cited by Citizens is that there has been a rise in South Florida claims associated with water damage that is not storm-related.
"Every year, Citizens' actuaries calculate rates based on the same methodology used by insurance companies all over the world, which compares potential risk to the ability to pay claims," said Chris Gardner, the chairman of Citizens Board of Governors, in a statement.
Gov. Rick Scott and legislators have pushed Citizens to trim the number of its policyholders. That's because Citizens is allowed under state law to impose a surcharge on most insurance policy holders, including those with auto insurance policies, if it cannot pay off its claims following a major storm.
Several years ago legislators capped the annual rate hikes at 10 percent.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:20:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Patriots’ Trail funding still intact</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/patriots-trail-funding-still-intact-1.493849</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Patriots Trail funding still intact
File photo
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:20 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  The final phase of the Bud and Dorie Day Patriots Trail will continue as planned despite funding for the project being vetoed by Gov. Rick Scott.
When Scotts $461 million in vetoes were announced Tuesday, city officials became concerned about the fate of the trail.
But City Manager Michael Beedie confirmed Wednesday that in late May his staff had requested  and was granted  a funding extension by the state Department of Economic Opportunity.
Because weve got an agreement, which is similar to a contract, the money is there, he said. We still have, like, $90,000 left to spend.
State Rep. Matt Gaetz praised the citys forethought and said he was pleased with the extension.
Thats a good thing, he said. We should put the money to use locally.
Initially, the city had to spend the remainder of its initial $125,000 allocation by June 30. Now it will have until Sept. 15 to complete the final phase of the trail  which includes the demolition of the Docie Bass Recreation Center and the construction of a courtyard with pavilions and landscaping in its place.
Weve basically got three months to do it, Beedie said. Its going to really push us into overdrive.
He said his staff is currently working on fast-tracking the design and should bid out the work in the next few weeks.
Patriots Trail, which officially opened to the public May 28, winds down Staff Drive, Nebraska Avenue and California Drive to Ferry Park. Its first phase features 16 historical markers with information about Bud and Dorie Days life together and was paid for primarily with an $88,000 grant from the Florida Recreational Trails program.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couple sentenced in fatal stabbing case</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/couple-sentenced-in-fatal-stabbing-case-1.493834</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Couple sentenced in fatal stabbing case
Amy and Jeffrey Brandenburg
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:03 PM.
CRESTVIEW  A husband and wife charged in connection with a fatal stabbing on March 8, 2014, have been sentenced after entering into plea agreements with the State Attorneys Office.
Circuit Judge Michael Flowers sentenced Jeffrey Allen Brandenburg on Tuesday to 30 years in the Florida Department of Corrections as a habitual felony offender. According to a press release from the State Attorneys Office, Brandenburg pleaded no contest to manslaughter in the death of Samuel Cornish, who was found on State Road 85 after suffering a stab wound to the chest.
According to earlier reports, Cornish was taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center, where he was later pronounced dead. The Medical Examiners Office conducted an autopsy and determined he died from a lacerated aorta.
Brandenburg and his wife, Amy, fled to Brewton, Alabama, where they were arrested and detained on March 10.
A nearby business surveillance camera caught footage of a car that fit the description of one owned by the Brandenburgs, and a witness told investigators the couple complained about being ripped off while purchasing narcotics from Cornish, an earlier police report said.
The witness also told police the Brandenburgs said they saw Cornish walking down the road around and stopped their vehicle. The witness said Jeffrey Brandenburg got out and remained out of Amy Brandenburgs sight before he returned with blood on his hands.
The witness told investigators that Amy Brandenburg asked Jeffrey Brandenburg what had happened, and he cursed at her and told her to drive away, police reports said.
Jonathan Schlechter, who prosecuted the case, said Amy Brandenburg entered a plea to a charge of accessory after the fact to aggravated battery.
She was sentenced to 11 months and 29 days in the county jail, followed by four years of probation, Schlecter said. She also agreed to testify against her co-defendant.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:48:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Summer school middle, high students released early </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/summer-school-middle-high-students-released-early-1.493759</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Summer school middle, high students released early
By STAFF REPORT | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 12:48 PM.
Middle and high school students attending summer school in Okaloosa County were sent home early Wednesday because of issues with the computer program they use.
Students were released about two hours early after it became clear a credit recovery program students use called Edgenuity was not going to fixed quickly, according to Assistant Superintendent Marcus Chambers.
The statewide issue began around 9 a.m. It also impacted Okaloosa Online.
We waited a decent amount of time, probably an hour an half, Chambers said.
Parents were notified classes were canceled for the day just before lunchtime, according to a news release from the district.
Chambers said they have summer school programs at every high school and middle school in the county except Ruckel and Lewis, which are combined into one program.
Summer school for the older students was expected to resume normal operations on Thursday.
Its a self-paced program, so theyll be able to pick up wherever they left off, Chambers said.
Elementary school students weren't affected.
Parents are asked to contact individual schools if they have additional questions.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UPDATED: Deputy doing well after surgery</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/deputy-injured-in-crash-1.493752</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>in serious condition following the accident at 5:25 a.m., according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Austin
went to surgery mid-morning.
He came out of surgery well, Sheriffs Maj. Bob Johnson said in an email Wednesday afternoon. He is in good condition.
Austin
, 36, was westbound in his patrol vehicle when he lost control near mile marker 53 just west of Crestview, the FHP reported. The vehicle left the road, spun around and struck a tree.
He was not wearing a seat belt, according to FHP.
Emergency crews had to free
Austin
from the vehicle when they arrived, the Sheriffs Office said.
A photo shared by the Sheriffs Office showed heavy front-end damage to his Chevrolet Impala.
The Sheriffs Office noted in a news release that heavy rain reduced visibility at the time of the crash.
The FHP continues to investigate.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed Jun 24 04:15:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of trespassing after telling deputy he was going to</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-trespassing-after-telling-deputy-he-was-going-to-1.493675</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of trespassing after telling deputy he was going to
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, June 23, 2015 at 09:15 PM.
CRESTVIEW - A 20-year-old Freeport man is accused of trespassing at a home after telling an Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputy that he encountered that he was going to back to the home.
The man was issued a trespass warning at the home on June 7 around 10 p.m., according to the arrest report. The homeowner called police to report that he was at work and his daughter was home alone.
The man was knocking on all of the exterior doors and windows and had tried to use a credit card to gain entry to the home, the report said. The daughter said she'd opened the door and told the man to leave.
Crestview Police officers issued a trespass warning at the homeowner's request.
On June 8, around 4 a.m., a mere six hours later, the man encountered a deputy during an unrelated incident, according to the report. He allegedly told the deputy that he was going to return to a residence that he'd been trespassed from earlier that evening.
While conducting a security check on the home, a Crestview officer saw the man go onto the property.
The man is charged with misdemeanor trespassing.
His next scheduled court date is July 7.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
