<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:09:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman accused of taking advantage of grandma for money</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-accused-of-taking-advantage-of-grandma-for-money-1.472186</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman accused of taking advantage of grandma for money
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 09:09 PM.
NICEVILLE - A 41-year-old Niceville woman is charged with using her grandmothers credit card for more than $1,000 in charges while the woman was failing physically and mentally.
The complainant was the womans father, who reported on Oct. 24, 2014, that his now-dead mothers credit card had been used without permission while shed been alive, according to the arrest report. He named the suspect as his daughter, who was arrested April 20.
The man said his mother had been frugal and would not have given the card to her granddaughter to use, the report said. Niceville Police officers spoke to the granddaughter on March 20, 2015.
The granddaughter said her grandmother had given her the card as payment for taking care of her, according to the report. She said her grandmother knew she was there to help and that she would clean her grandmothers house every day.
How do you set a price on what you pay for that? she reportedly asked.
She said her grandmother gave her the card for bills and as soon as she got a job, she was going to pay her grandmother back, the report said. She said her grandmother hadnt wanted the complainant to know, and although the family thought the woman had a touch of dementia, she hadnt seen it.
She used the card 19 times during nine days for a total of $1,084.96 in charges, according to the report. The complainant said that the woman had failing physical and mental health and couldnt have given permission.
The grandmother has since died.
The granddaughter is charged with fraud.
Her next scheduled court date is June 2.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:08:30 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vehicle passenger arrested after traffic stop</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/vehicle-passenger-arrested-after-traffic-stop-1.472185</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Vehicle passenger arrested after traffic stop
File photo
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 09:08 PM.
NICEVILLE - The passenger in a vehicle pulled over for a faulty headlight is charged with possession of marijuana.
Niceville Police officers pulled the vehicle over on April 19 around 8 p.m., according to the arrest report. Officers could smell the odor of marijuana and the passenger, a 27-year-old Crestview man, said there was nothing in the vehicle.
The occupants got out and officers searched the vehicle, finding four grams of marijuana in the glove box in front of where the man had been sitting, the report said.
He is charged with possession of less than 20 grams of marijuana.
His next scheduled court date is May 12.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 04:06:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man charged with January 2014 burglary of church</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-charged-with-january-2014-burglary-of-church-1.472183</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man charged with January 2014 burglary of church
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 09:06 PM.
NICEVILLE - A Baker man was arrested on April 17 on charges of burglarizing Cross Roads Church in Niceville.
The burglary was reported on Jan. 17, 2014, according to the arrest report. Church officials reported more than $5,000 in property stolen, including musical instruments.
On Feb. 28, 2014, Niceville officers got a call from a Santa Rosa County Sheriffs detective in connection with a burglary they were working, the report said. The detective said they had found a safe in 26-year-old Westley Emerson Steiners vehicle that was linked to the Niceville church burglary.
A search warrant was issued and detectives found items from several burglaries in Steiners home, including items from the church, according to the report. Detectives spoke to Steiner at the Santa Rosa County Detention Center on March 20, 2014, and he allegedly admitted to breaking into the church with an accomplice.
He is charged with burglary and grand theft of more than $5,000 but less than $10,000.
His next scheduled court date is May 19.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 23:04:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Wanted: a loving home for Reba and Dillion</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/wanted-a-loving-home-for-reba-and-dillion-1.472015</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Wanted: a loving home for Reba and Dillion
Reba and Dillion
KELLI HIGGINS | Special to the Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 04:04 PM.
Reba and Dillion are a challenging but delightful brother and sister.
Reba loves to dance and listen to music. Dillion is very artistic and enjoys making craft projects. He also likes playing with Matchbox cars. Both children love getting and giving hugs and affection.
Dillion is in special classes so he can receive extra help with his work. Reba is in the fifth grade and also working below grade level but has the ability to catch up with help and encouragement.
Both Dillion and Reba are working hard to control their feelings and behaviors when they get mad or upset over all the difficult things that have happened to them in the past. Dillion is also struggling with his muscular dystrophy, which now has him almost totally confined to his wheelchair at this time.
Dillion and Reba need a loving, unconditionally accepting adoptive family who will enjoy their wonderful personalities and all the love they have to give while helping them overcome their challenges. The family will also need to be able to meet Dillions medical needs as his condition changes over time.
Dillion was born in April, 2001 and Reba was born in February 2003.
For more information on adoption, contact Peggy Custred at FamiliesFirst Network: 866-313-9874 (toll free) or 850-469-3847.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:48:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Community helps search for missing swimmer (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/community-helps-search-for-missing-swimmer-photos-1.472007</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Community helps search for missing swimmer (PHOTOS)
Kari Smith, left, Tammy Turberville, middle, and Mindy Marraffino scan the shoreline for Barnes body on Thursday in the Choctawhatchee Bay.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 03:48 PM.
DESTIN  Becky Barnes could not choke back the tears.
We loved him very much and we miss him, Barnes said of her son, Rodney Barnes.
Barnes disappeared Sunday evening while swimming with his girlfriend, Jenna Gongora, at Crab Island.
PHOTOS of the search.
His body has not been recovered.
The love felt for the 20-year-old from Pace was evident Thursday on the docks of Destin Marina as dozens of strangers joined the Barnes family in the search.
Barnes aunt, Bridget Barnes, made a plea to the public while standing with family at the marina.
If you dont have a job and you have a boat, come out here, please.
Along with Okaloosa County Sheriff deputies and officers with the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, about 40 volunteers offered their sets of eyes in the endeavor.
A Walton County Sheriffs Office helicopter also searched.
Kari Smith, shift supervisor at Krispy Kreme in Destin, served the family donuts in the morning and came out to volunteer after work.
Why not? What if it was my kid or husband, Smith said.
Destin Marina owner Terry White and his son Chris allowed the family to use the marina as a home base while they searched.
We decided to help because we could help out, White said.
Boats filtered in and out of the marina, dropping off volunteers and picking up new ones. About a dozen civilian boats were used on Thursday while looking for Rodney.
Periodically someone would point out a bird or a piece of trash, hoping to see a clue that would to help bring Barnes home to his family.
At the end of the day, Rodney Barnes was still missing.
The search was expected to continue Friday.
Contact Daily News Photographer Nick Tomecek at 850-315-4426 or ntomecek@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @NickTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:47:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Attorneys open their cases in Davis murder trial</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/attorneys-open-their-cases-in-davis-murder-trial-1.472002</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Attorneys open their cases in Davis murder trial
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 03:47 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS  Assistant State Attorney Bobby Elmore appears to face a daunting task in convincing jurors that Barry Davis killed John Greg Hughes and Heidi Rhodes on May 7, 2012 at Hughes home in Santa Rosa Beach.
Elmore has no bodies and a handful of witnesses who Davis attorney, Spiro Kypreos, seems eager to expose as serial liars.
All of these witnesses have lied time and time again, Kypreos said Thursday in his opening statement at Davis murder trial. The state is asking, essentially, that you believe their most recent versions of the facts are the truth.
But Elmore, a prosecutor for more than 30 years, is nothing if not thorough, and he laid out his plan to convict Davis on two counts of first-degree murder in a two-hour opening statement of his own.
Evidence will show he disposed of the bodies. Evidence will show they are dead. Death isnt a body. It is the absence of life, he said. Their lives were ended by Barry Davis.
Davis could face the death penalty if convicted.
The key witness likely will be Tiffani Steward, who Elmore confirmed will take the stand during the trial that could last four weeks. Steward was Davis girlfriend on the day almost three years ago that Hughes and Rhodes were last seen, and she has told Walton County sheriffs investigators she saw him kill them.
In his overview of the evidence they will be presented, Elmore described the death scene to jurors as Steward recalled it. She and Rhodes had gone to Publix to buy Margarita mix. When they returned, Davis threw Steward aside and grabbed Rhodes and smashed her against the wall.
He said Steward will testify that she screamed at what she saw and was told shut up or youre next. She left the room and saw Hughes lying in a bedroom covered in blood, Elmore told the jury.
Steward also will testify she saw Davis bind Hughes and Rhodes feet with duct tape and submerge their heads in a bathtub he filled with water.
Steward will testify, Elmore said, that Davis had made statements about disposing of the bodies by cutting them up and burning them.
Elmore also told the 14 jurors that he will show that Davis stole nearly everything of value from Hughes home, right down to the salt and pepper shakers.
He said they will see checks showing that Davis was dipping into Hughes bank account after he killed him and hear from handwriting experts who will verify forgeries on those checks.
Davis faces 12 charges of theft and fraud in addition to the murder charges.
Elmore said cadaver dogs alerted to the smell of decomposed flesh on Hughes Cadillac Escalade. Witnesses will testify they saw Davis driving the Cadillac after May 7, 2012, and evidence will show that he tried, successfully for quite some time, to hide the vehicle from authorities, Elmore added.
Stewards testimony will be backed up by people who Davis hired as unknowing dupes to help him cover his tracks, he said. Most of them lied at one time or another to deputies investigating the Hughes and Rhodes disappearances.
One thing they told investigators was that they had packed Davis home belongings into a Ryder truck, Elmore said. The company, he added had been out of business since 2002.
Kypreos told jurors that several of Elmores witnesses obtained immunity from prosecution by agreeing to testify. Steward, at least, could have faced prison for her role in helping Davis cover up the murder and thefts he is accused of, he said.
Kypreos said he would point out all the many lies that were told and leave it for the jury to find the truth, if they could.
They lied. The question youll have to resolve is when were they lying, he said. How motivated were these people to avoid prosecution.
Elmore called the first witnesses of the day to verify that Heidi Rhodes, who lived in Panama City Beach, had indeed disappeared and that her close family ties would rule out her just running away. He called several family members, a former Bay County sheriffs deputy and her former landlord to testify that the disappearance was unexpected and that it did not look when she left her home on May 7, 2012, that she had plans to be away for a long while.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:36:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Home invasion robbery under investigation</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/home-invasion-robbery-under-investigation-1.472000</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Home invasion robbery under investigation
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 03:36 PM.
DESTIN  Authorities are investigating a Wednesday night home invasion robbery in which the victims were tied up in their home and assaulted.
The victims, two residents of a home on Country Club Drive, reported that a locked back door was forced open sometime after 8:30 p.m. and the two were tied up and robbed, according to the Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office news release.
They said that three to four men dressed in black and carrying guns proceeded to search through the home for 30 minutes before leaving, the release said.
They described the robbers as all being around 5 foot, 9 inches tall with thin builds. They said the men pushed them to the ground before looking for valuables, the release said.
The victims were able to get free and go to a neighbors house for help. The neighbor called 911 at 9:12 p.m., according to the release.
One of the victims suffered head injuries that he said happened after he was repeatedly punched while on the ground, according to the release.
Anyone who saw anything suspicious in the area or has information on the robbery is asked to call the Sheriffs Office at 651-7400 or Emerald Coast
Crime Stoppers at 850-863-TIPS, visit emeraldcoastcrimestoppers.com or text TIP214 plus your message to CRIMES (274637).
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:29:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Probation search reveals 43 grams of cocaine  </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/probation-search-reveals-43-grams-of-cocaine-1.471994</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Probation search reveals 43 grams of cocaine
Deputies serving a search warrant found 43 grams of cocaine in a Sims Street home on Wednesday.
Special to the Daily News
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 03:29 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  Two men were arrested after a joint investigation by probation and parole officers and the Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office Narcotics Unit.
A search warrant was served Wednesday at the Sims Street home of Cornelius Lashan Lee, 33, according to the arrest report. Lee asked to speak to investigators away from the other man in the home, 33-year-old Mario Tremayne Banks.
Investigators took Lee to a bedroom, where he tried to hide a bag that had been laying on the bed by kicking it under the bed. However, the contents of the bag ultimately spilled out, which caused Lee to allegedly say There it go... Im going away for three years, according to the report.
Investigators collected the contents of the bag, which included 27 grams of crack cocaine, four grams of powder cocaine and one gram of crystalline powder that tested positive for methylethcathinone, according to reports. An additional bag of 12 grams of crack cocaine was reportedly found in the living room of the home.
Banks told deputies that he often visited the residence to see Lee and had spent the night on occasion while intoxicated, according to the reports.
Clothing matching his size was found in a spare room.
Banks is a registered sex offender and must report his current address to the Sheriffs Office in the county he is living in. His current registered address is in Freeport, but the landlord at the Sims Street home told deputies that Banks had been residing there for a month.
Lee was charged with trafficking cocaine, possession of a controlled substance and violating probation.
Banks was charged with failing to register his address as a sex offender.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 22:27:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man's bond set in double homicide</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-s-bond-set-in-double-homicide-1.471988</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man's bond set in double homicide
Joshua Brandyn Gaskey
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 03:27 PM.
A 28-year-old Pensacola man is being held on an $850,000 bond in Holmes County on charges of murdering a Ponce de Leon couple on April 18.
Joshua Brandyn Gaskey made his first appearance in Holmes County court Thursday morning on charges of murdering Sheley and Jacqulyn Brooks.
A Holmes County judge ordered an $850,000 bond in the case, and Gaskey currently remains in custody in the Holmes County Jail.
Gaskey allegedly went to the Brooks home on April 18, shooting both residents in the head and taking two bottles of prescription medication before fleeing, according to the arrest report.
He then returned to Escambia County and threw the gun hed used in Pensacola Bay, the report said.
Jacqulyn was found dead around 6 p.m. by a Walton County deputy, who was first on scene after a call for assistance.
Sheley was found alive, but died a few days later from his injuries.
It was previously reported that Gaskey was already wanted in Escambia County for allegedly stealing checks from a church.
Gaskey is also facing charges for violating probation in Santa Rosa County.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:50:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>School takes away child's Oreos, orders mom to pack nutritious lunch</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/weird-news/school-takes-away-child-s-oreos-orders-mom-to-pack-nutritious-lunch-1.471969</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>School takes away child's Oreos, orders mom to pack nutritious lunch
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 02:50 PM.
AURORA, Colo. A suburban Denver 4-year-old came home from school disappointed, with untouched Oreos and a note from her teacher.
Denver news station KMGH-TV reports (http://bit.ly/1P6770A ) that preschooler Natalee Pearson told her mom Friday that she wasn't allowed to eat the cookies in her lunchbox.
The note told parents to pack a nutritious lunch that includes a fruit, vegetable and healthy snack.
Natalee's mother, Leeza Pearson, says she doesn't agree with the decision by the Children's Academy in Aurora.
She says Natalie also had a sandwich and cheese and that the school took things too far.
A spokeswoman with Aurora Public Schools says they gave Natalee a healthy alternative to the cookies.
Pearson says Natalee attends the private Children's Academy as a public school student under the state's preschool option program.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:48:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman suffers home invasion by turkey</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/weird-news/woman-suffers-home-invasion-by-turkey-1.471966</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman suffers home invasion by turkey
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 02:48 PM.
WARWICK, R.I.  A Rhode Island woman thought a pipe burst when she returned home to find water pouring from her garage ceiling. But the culprit turned out to be an unusual houseguest that dropped in.
WLNE-TV reports Nancy Page went upstairs to find the source of the running water and discovered a wild turkey had crashed through a bathroom window and somehow turned on the sink. Page says she immediately realized it was a turkey, which left behind its own mess.
Police and a Department of Environmental Management officer caught the turkey and released it.
Page was forced to throw out the bathroom sink. She says it had been running for two to three hours. Page estimates the turkey caused thousands of dollars in water damage to her Warwick home.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:47:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lottery winner hid ticket in flour</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/weird-news/lottery-winner-hid-ticket-in-flour-1.471965</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Lottery winner hid ticket in flour
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 02:47 PM.
DETROIT  A postal worker says he couldn't eat or sleep for three days because of something in a container of flour.
What was keeping him up? A $1 million lottery ticket.
Fred Morgan of Detroit had five winning numbers in the April 17 Mega Millions game. He knew he had won the next day. But he told lottery officials that he stashed the ticket in flour and a few other places while he and his wife considered what to do with the windfall.
Morgan says nobody would "check for anything valuable in the flour." He says he's retiring early after 31 years as a mail carrier.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:45:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Prosecutors: Man stuffed $300 bribe into city worker's pants </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/weird-news/prosecutors-man-stuffed-300-bribe-into-city-worker-s-pants-1.471964</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Prosecutors: Man stuffed $300 bribe into city worker's pants
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 02:45 PM.
PHILADELPHIA  A Philadelphia man is facing a bribery charge after prosecutors say he stuffed $300 into a city worker's pants during a property reassessment.
Ri Quang Wu was charged Thursday with bribery in official and political matters and obstructing the function of government.
Court records with bail information or a lawyer for the 59-year-old Wu were not posted online.
Prosecutors say Wu passed the bribe during a May 2014 assessment at a property in South Philadelphia.
They say the evaluator tried to give the cash back, but Wu refused and the evaluator turned it over to his bosses at the Bureau of Revenue and Taxation.
District Attorney Seth Williams says the case shows that the city is not for sale and that employees won't tolerate dishonest behavior.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 21:12:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Destin students rally around ill classmate</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/destin-students-rally-around-ill-classmate-1.471948</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Destin students rally around ill classmate
David Quintanars classmates and teachers show of the bracelets they purchased as part of a fundraising effort for him and his family as he battles cancer.
Special to the Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 02:12 PM.
Photo Galleries
Destin young man
DESTIN  The spirit of giving is alive and well at Destin Elementary School.
Teachers, students and their parents have all come together to support a fourth grade student and his family after he was diagnosed with lymphoma last October.
To date, theyve raised nearly $5,000 for David Quintanar and his family.
There aren't enough words to describe how grateful (we) are, Davids mother, Hipolita Quintanar recently told his teachers.
The students in Diane Kellys and Dianne Goldsteins classes started out by making cards for their classmate, and it evolved from there.
First the teachers pooled their resources and bought him an iPad, next the students started bringing in care packages and then they organized two different fundraisers for the Quintanar family.
Really, every single time we get into school, were always thinking about him... and after school mostly, said Davids classmate Carter Tobik.
Students ask almost every day to make cards for him and most are sporting the blue bracelets they sold for one of the fundraisers, Kelly said.
Some of them know him well, others not at all. Those who know him said David is kind and smart. Brooklyn Rogers sat next to him in second grade and sometimes she struggled with the math.
He would always help me, she said.
Now the 10-year-old said shes focused on returning the favor. Many of the students in the two fourth grade classes echoed her sentiment and offered similar recounts of Davids generosity and their need to help him now.
The kindness in them just came out, Kelly said. We knew we had sweet students in August, but then we just really saw.
WANT TO HELP? A Gofundme page is set for David at: http://www.gofundme.com/gz3gl8
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 20:58:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Voters will be asked to OK tax-neutral measure</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/voters-will-be-asked-to-ok-tax-neutral-measure-1.471941</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Voters will be asked to OK tax-neutral measure
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, April 30, 2015 at 01:58 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS  Walton County voters will soon be asked to allow the School District to move money from one of its accounts to another.
On May 19, voters will be asked to approve the 0.5 mill referendum in a special election. If approved, it allows the district to move about $6.5 million from its capital outlay budget to its operating one. The capital budget is used to fund projects like construction and technology and the bulk of the operating budget is used to pay for teaching positions and classes.
This initiative does not raise your taxes, Superintendent Carlene Anderson said. Its revenue neutral to taxpayers.
By voting yes on the referendum, voters will allow the district to keep programs like art, music, band and chorus, and also continue to bring in additional advancement placement and dual enrollment courses, she said.
It will also help keep teacher salaries competitive with the surrounding districts, Anderson added.
Voters first OKed the shift back in 2003. Voters approved it again in 2007 and 2011.
If it is not approved this year, the district would have to reduce its workforce by 12 percent and would also be forced to consider school consolidations, extracurricular course reductions and service cutbacks, Anderson said.
We want to retain the high quality education weve had the last 12 years, Anderson said.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 04:32:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Search continues for missing man</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/search-continues-for-missing-man-1.471677</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Search continues for missing man
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, April 29, 2015 at 09:32 PM.
DESTIN - The search for a swimmer who went missing at Crab Island on Sunday afternoon continued Wednesday, although the dive search ended Tuesday.
Searchers did surface surveying Wednesday to try to find 20-year-old Rodney Barnes, according to Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office spokeswoman Michele Nicholson.
Nicholson said in addition to officials, local boaters and fishermen are watching for any sign of him.
Barnes family is organizing an independent search starting Thursday. Searchers will meet at 8 a.m. at Dewey Destin Seafood Restaurant and Destin Marina, both on Calhoun Avenue.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 04:30:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Burglars target 12 unlocked vehicles</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/burglars-target-12-unlocked-vehicles-1.471676</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Burglars target 12 unlocked vehicles
File photo
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, April 29, 2015 at 09:30 PM.
CRESTVIEW - Police are investigating 12 vehicle burglaries from early Tuesday, according to the Police Department.
The burglaries occurred around Limestone Drive and involved unlocked vehicles, Crestview police reported.
In one case, a vehicle with the keys left inside was stolen. It was recovered later in the Silver Oaks subdivision off Old Bethel Road.
Items taken from other vehicles included a firearm, electronics and cash.
Anyone with information is asked to call the Crestview Police Department at 682-3544 or Emerald Coast Crime Stoppers at 850-863-8477.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 04:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of sexual battery</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-accused-of-sexual-battery-1.471674</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of sexual battery
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, April 29, 2015 at 09:28 PM.
MILTON - A 29-year-old man is accused of molesting a child who was under the care of an acquaintance.
Kyle Devin Pearce of Milton was arrested Monday and charged with sexual assault of a victim under 12.
Pearce allegedly molested the child April 11 at the childs babysitters house, according to his arrest report.
The babysitter said he was in another room while the child played and didnt realize Pearce still was in the house, the report said.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:27:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman facing drug charges after asking deputy about identity theft</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-facing-drug-charges-after-asking-deputy-about-identity-theft-1.471669</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman facing drug charges after asking deputy about identity theft
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, April 29, 2015 at 08:27 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A Fort Walton Beach woman is facing drug charges after allegedly calling deputies to inquire about identity theft.
Okaloosa County Sheriffs deputies responded to the call on April 19 around 1 a.m., according to the arrest report. The woman, identified as 19-year-old Brianna Lashae Jones, pulled up next to deputies in her car.
While speaking to Jones, deputies noticed the smell of marijuana coming from her car and detained her, the report said. In plain view, they allegedly saw a while pill identified as alprazolam.
Jones admitted that two people who had just gotten out of her vehicle had smoked marijuana and that she didnt have a prescription for alprazolam, according to the report.
She is charged with possession of a controlled substance.
Her next scheduled court date is June 2.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu Apr 30 03:25:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>TV reported stolen from Walmart</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/tv-reported-stolen-from-walmart-1.471668</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>TV reported stolen from Walmart
Daily News file photo
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, April 29, 2015 at 08:25 PM.
NICEVILLE - Niceville Police officers were called to Walmart on April 19 for a theft from the day before.
The Asset Protection Officer reported that on April 18 around 1 a.m., a man took a 48 inch television from the electronics department, according to the incident. The man was seen in surveillance footage wearing a t-shirt from an area restaurant.
The man took the television out to the parking lot without ever attempting to pay for it, the report said. The investigation is ongoing
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
