<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:34:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Website suggests Miramar Beach as future spring break party site</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/website-suggests-miramar-beach-as-future-spring-break-party-site-1.483124</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Website suggests Miramar Beach as future spring break party site
Daily News file photo
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 06:34 PM.
When Walton County Sheriffs Office noticed an article last week on the comedy website Total Frat Move mentioning Miramar Beach, they felt compelled to respond in a press release.
The article Top 7 Spring Break Destinations Now That PCB Has Banned Alcohol suggests Destin as a spring break hot spot  although with its mention of Whales Tail, the writer, FratrickKane88, most likely meant Miramar Beach.
Destin (Miramar Beach) is PCBs pledge sister ... that isnt known for partying or being the hot girl, but you end up hooking up with her one night and dont regret it, because it was actually pretty good. You consider doing it again but it just never happens, wrote the author.
The Panama City Beach City Council voted earlier this month to ban alcohol on the beach next March during the typical spring break season.
Corey Dobridnia, spokeswoman for WCSO, was directed to write a response to the article, which was approved by Sheriff Mike Adkinson and Chief AJ Smith.
Weve seen a couple of articles that have mentioned Destin and Panama City Beach  this was just the final straw, she said.
See the response
In a press release sent out Tuesday afternoon, Dobridnia wrote to the Total Frat Move folks that ...while you need to work on your geography you also need to work on spreading a different message to your fraternity brothers.
Dobridnia said she worked on the response for a few days and that the message was not to be hateful.
You see, here in Walton County were a fraternity too. But, as its actually defined. Our fraternity is a group of people sharing common professions and interests. Our interests do not include having thousands of college students disrespect and trash our beaches. We do not support underage drinking or debauchery of any kind  as you call it.
FratrickKane88 warns readers that deputies are known to roam the beach, but just gave the advice to not get caught.
I had a friend see one from a distance and just start running, he wrote. In hindsight, the structural damage that he suffered to his face (when he fell) was probably more than the $200 or so (Minor in Possession charge) he would have received. Just dont get caught, or have better agility than my friend.
Dobrinia said she tried to find the face behind FratrickKane88 on social media and even sent an email through the websites contact link, but was met with silence.
I made sure to share the response on their Facebook page, she said.
The Total Frat Move website features mainly stories about drinking, fraternities and drinking while in a fraternity. Popular articles include The Time My Fraternitys Leadership Consultant Got Me Blackout Drunk and If You Go Home For The Summer, Youre A Moron.
We know their articles are in good faith and good fun, Dobridnia said. But its a serious issue. This years spring break in Panama City there were shootings and stabbings. We want to protect the visitors and residents in Walton County.

Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4434 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Wed May 27 01:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man gets 25 years in hotel room meth lab case</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-gets-25-years-in-hotel-room-meth-lab-case-1.483110</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man gets 25 years in hotel room meth lab case
Derek Anthony Gonzales
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 06:14 PM.
MILTON - A 37-year-old Milton man was sentenced to 25 years in prison Tuesday after being convicted of creating a meth lab in a Milton hotel room.
Derek Anthony Gonzales was convicted of first degree arson, attempting to manufacture methamphetamine and possession of drug paraphernalia by a jury on May 1, according to a media release from the State Attorney's office.
He was sentenced to 25 years in prison as a habitual felony offender on Tuesday by Judge John Simon.
The charges stemmed from a fire on May 21, 2014, the release said.
Authorities were called to the Emerald Sands Inn, 6436 U.S. Highway 90. Once there, they found that a functional methamphetamine lab in a hotel room had exploded.
The fire burned the contents of the room and endangered guests in the adjoining rooms, according to previous coverage of the case.
Gonzales was identified as a person of interest after fleeing the hotel.
He was located later by Santa Rosa County Sheriff's Office and charged.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Wed May 27 00:01:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida Senate offers health care coverage compromise </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/florida-senate-offers-health-care-coverage-compromise-1.483025</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Florida Senate offers health care coverage compromise
Senate president Andy Gardiner, R-Orlando is applauded by his fellow senators after his remarks concerning the house's adjournment during session on April 29 in Tallahassee.
AP file photo
By The Associated Press
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 05:01 PM.
TALLAHASSEE  Republican leaders in the Florida Senate offered up a revamped health care proposal Tuesday in an effort to end a budget stalemate that threatens to shut down state government.
GOP legislative leaders have been odds over health care coverage and the dispute derailed the end of the regular session. Legislators are scheduled to return to the state Capitol next week for a 20-day special session where they are expected to pass a new state budget.
Senate President Andy Gardiner announced what he called a "compromise" on health care coverage that is an attempt to win over both skeptical House leaders as well as Gov. Rick Scott.
The new Senate plan would jettison an initial proposal to expand Medicaid this summer, but instead would still call for drawing down federal money linked to President Barack Obama's health care overhaul. Low-income Floridians would be eligible to purchase coverage through a new exchange, but they would have to pay premiums and they would be required to work. The new health coverage plan would require federal approval and would not kick in until January.
"We have listened to senators, House members, constituents, and other stakeholders and incorporated their feedback to create a stronger Florida solution, the Senate, House and Gov. Scott can proudly present to Washington as Florida's best offer for a health insurance exchange that meets the unique needs of our state," Gardiner said in a statement.
House leaders and the governor have been strongly opposed to Medicaid expansion. They have called Medicaid a "broken" health care system, and have also said they don't trust the federal government to continue to paying for the program in future.
It's not clear if the Senate's latest proposal will go far enough to win them over.
The regular legislative session slammed to a halt in late April after House members abruptly adjourned early due to a stalemate over Medicaid expansion. The divide between the two chambers was sparked by the impending loss of more than $1 billion in federal aid to hospitals that is to set to expire this summer.
Federal officials told Florida that they wanted the state to consider expanding Medicaid insurance as part of the agreement to extend the hospital funds. Last week the Obama administration offered to extend Florida's hospital funds for another two years, but only at about half the amount the state received last year, saying it would not approve hospital funding for costs that that would be covered by expansion.
Sen. Rene Garcia, a Hialeah Republican who chairs the Senate health care budget committee, said the Senate plan will help the state transition as it loses the federal money for hospitals. He called it a "much better investment of our limited taxpayer dollars."

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosions, fire destroy trailer; man killed</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/explosions-fire-destroy-trailer-man-killed-1.482990</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Explosions, fire destroy trailer; man killed
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 04:15 PM.
NAVARRE  One man is dead after an explosion and fire on Colonial Avenue early Tuesday morning.
The fire was being considered an incendiary act of arson on Tuesday afternoon, according to Florida State Fire Marshal spokesperson Kayla Anderson.
Firefighters were called for a residential structure fire with reported explosions at 12:20 a.m. Tuesday, according to a media release from Holley-Navarre Fire District.
Multiple 911 callers reported explosions and fire at the residence in the 2100 block of Colonial Avenue.
Once firefighters arrived, they reported a fully involved single-wide mobile home trailer fire. A dead man was found near the home, the release said.
Shortly after, firefighters found that the fire had also spread to an adjacent mobile home.
No other injuries were reported.
Anderson reported that the elderly female woman who lived in the adjacent home was not injured, but is currently displaced.
Both homes were a total loss, with damages estimated at $25,000 to the first home and $65,000 to the second.
Samples were collected by the fire marshal's office and were sent to the lab.
An autopsy of the man is ongoing.
He had not been identified as of Tuesday afternoon.
Florida State Fire Marshal's Office and Santa Rosa County Sheriff's Office are investigating.
Navarre Beach, Midway and Florosa fire departments assisted at the scene. Avalon and East Milton fire departments were called for district coverage.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Libraries have evolved into the digital age</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/libraries-have-evolved-into-the-digital-age-1.482988</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Libraries have evolved into the digital age
Will Rogers runs a recent Story Hour with parents and their children at the Destin Library.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By DEL STONE JR. | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 04:15 PM.
Once, libraries were quiet havens where people went to read and research.
Not anymore.
Yes, people can still read and research at libraries. But with the advent of the digital age, libraries are upping their game to bring in a new generation of patrons.
From workforce development to family entertainment and small business facilities, libraries are changing in ways residents might find surprising.
Digital media
Walk into the Fort Walton Beach Library and you will see printed books. Lots of em. What you may not see at first glance are ebooks, DVDs and Blu-rays the library also loans.
We have a pretty good selection of movies on DVD and Blu-ray, said Patricia Gould, library director. And their ebooks are available through Overdrive, a service offered through the Okaloosa County Library Cooperative. People can download ebooks to their preferred device and keep them from seven to 14 days. The digital books are compatible with 99 percent of whats out there, Gould said.
The Crestview Library offers music on CDs and videogames, according to Library Director Jean Lewis.
Audio books are also a big draw, said Jurate Burns, director of the Destin Library. I have more time to listen in the car than I do to read when I get home, she said.
Logging on
Libraries have become a haven for people wanting access to the Internet who dont have the service at home. Some come every day to do here what they would do at home, Lewis said.
The Fort Walton Beach Library has 16 public-access computers people can use for a limited time. Gould said some users simply dont want to pay for web access at home. They come in, do their online business and check their email  all for free. Others are tourists who dont want to use the pricey web access at their hotels or resorts.
Yet another group is the homeless or people who cant afford Internet access, who come in to renew their benefits, food stamps or other social services, Burns said. And job-hunting is an important part of what Destins computers are used for.
Classes
Many of the libraries offer classes and workshops about a variety of subjects.
The Destin Library, for instance, in its spring series of computer workshops, offered sessions on basic computer tips, how to use Craigslist, Facebook usage, and how to organize and edit your photos, among many others. The Fort Walton Beach Library offers similar classes, such as how to work a Kindle or iPad, and how to search for a job online.
New kinds of programs
Librarians in Fort Walton Beach, Destin and Crestview stressed their facilities have become home to all kinds of new programs designed to not only provide the community with information and education opportunities, but entertainment.
Libraries are not the hushed, silent places they once were, Gould said.
The Crestview Library is striving to become more of a community center as well as a library, Lewis said. They offer music programs twice a week, which are free and presented by members of the public who come in and play. They also host poetry slams and jams, and an open mic presentation.
We are trying to provide for our community something for them to do in their leisure time without any charge, Lewis said. Other activities at the library include art displays and pre-school programs.
Workforce development
A new role local libraries have taken on is facilitators for job-finding, training and small business production. At the Destin Library, local businesses can take advantage of its instructional lab for staff training, and a digital lab where small businesses can use computers, video cameras and even a green screen for video and image production. Burns said local businesses are welcome to use their equipment for the production of commercials, ads, menus  anything that requires graphic and video production equipment. She said the library may even buy a GoPro camera for checkout.
We are looking to build a small digital studio, Gould said of the Fort Walton Beach Library. Like Destins digital lab, it would be used to make commercials for small businesses and for students to make videos.
The library also offers proctoring services for distance-learning test-taking sessions, she said.
Libraries as a third place
We want to be that third place, said Lewis at the Crestview Library. She was referring to Dr. Ray Oldenburg, University of West Florida professor emeritus, who wrote the books Celebrating the Third Place and The Great Good Place. In his books, Oldenburg contends locations like pubs, main streets and similar places represent the heart of a communitys social vitality and are essential to a functioning democracy, with home and work being the first two places.
We try to stock materials, and offer programs and services the community is interested in, Burns said. Programs vary by community. We have to be sensitive to what our community wants and what its needs are.
Wed like it to be everyones third place.
Oh, and despite what youve heard. ...
Prints not dead.
Gould said teenagers are preferring paper over digital for reading fiction, and that kids love checking out childrens books. For textbooks and magazines, and among travelers, devices are still king.
Im not finding that the ebook circulation is growing, Burns added. Its leveling off.
Our people have always continued with the print books, Lewis said. Print books are still popular.
For one job-seeker, the library was a Godsend
DESTIN  For one newly laid-off worker, the Destin Library was a Godsend.
Steve Davis of Destin lost his job in 2010. He applied for other positions but ultimately decided he needed a college degree to get the kind of job he wanted.
There were lots of distractions at home, he said, so he came to the library where he was put into a student program.
Now, hes about to graduate from Argosy University with a bachelors degree in business administration and health care administration, and is receiving job offers from around the country.
Davis said he used the librarys computers and reference materials for research, and studied in the quiet rooms to get away from the general population. He did this while working a part-time job to help pay his bills.
Davis spent so much time at the library the staff became a second family.
I could not have finished school without the library being here, he said. Thank God they are here.
Contact Daily News Online Editor Del Stone Jr. at 850-315-4433 or dstone@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @DelSnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After 36 years, Choctaw's Mrs. E is calling it a career</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/after-36-years-choctaw-s-mrs-e-is-calling-it-a-career-1.482982</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
After 36 years, Choctaw's Mrs. E is calling it a career
Choctawhatchees Linda Evanchyk stands with the staff of Smoke Signals, the school's student newspaper, recently at the school. Evanchyk will be retiring after more than 30 years with the school.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 04:08 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  It was 1987 when English teacher Linda Evanchyk asked to revive the student newspaper at Choctawhatchee High School.
Smoke Signals had fallen by the wayside some years before and its rebirth was met with some skepticism. Evanchyk was given permission to print it on an issue-by-issue basis only.
Today its going strong and Evanchyk has decided to hand over the reins.
Im going to miss the adrenaline, but its time, she said. Ive done 36 years of deadlines with teenagers.
Under her guidance, the student journalists have covered state championships, major school anniversary celebrations and even the death of one of their own.
Shes seen them through cut and paste page design and still cringes when she thinks about how much work it used to be to develop photos.
Next school year, Smoke Signals alum and English teacher Asha Kennedy will take over as the faculty advisor for the publication.
I couldnt let the paper die, Kennedy said. I know how important it was to me.
Kennedy joined the staff when her family moved to the area during her senior year of high school. From the moment she walked in the door in 2009, she knew shed found her place.
Evanchyk had been wondering who would step in when she retired when Kennedy was hired as a long-term substitute during the 2013-14 school year.
From there, the pieces fell into place and Kennedy has been working with Evanchyk and the staff this year to learn the ropes.
Evanchyks students have known this moment was coming for years, but now that its here, they cant hide a little trepidation.
Theres going to be a lot of leaning for everybody, said rising co-editor Sadie Lea.
The sophomore will work with freshman Carrie Jenkins next year to oversee the paper. Both said they hope to continue in the position until they graduate and were looking forward to working with Kennedy.
Its new experiences, but its going to be great for all of us, Jenkins said.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue May 26 23:07:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First candidate joins race for Okaloosa superintendent</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/first-candidate-joins-race-for-okaloosa-superintendent-1.482981</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
First candidate joins race for Okaloosa superintendent
Marline Van Dyke announced shed be running for superintendent of Okaloosa County Schools. Shes currently the principal of Edwins Fine &amp; Performing Arts School.
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 04:07 PM.
An elementary school principal has filed to run for the Okaloosa County Superintendent of Schools seat in 2016.
Marline Van Dyke, the principal at Edwins Fine &amp; Performing Arts School in Fort Walton Beach, filed her paperwork with the supervisor of elections Tuesday.
I had reached a point of disappointment and fear for myself and for my teachers, Van Dyke said of her decision. Im not a politician; I am a passionate educator and I want the best for the county.
Van Dyke started in the district as a teachers aide at Plew Elementary School in Niceville. She decided to finish college at age 34 so she could become a full-time teacher there.
She taught at Plew for five years, spending much of her time focused on exceptional student education, before she was named principal of Silver Sands School in Fort Walton Beach.
She spent four years there before briefly becoming principal at Riverside Elementary School and then moving to Edwins. She had originally planned to run in 2020, but then upped the time table after discussions with her husband.
We sat and talked about it and we said why not now? Van Dyke said. I feel good, Im healthy... I have nothing to lose.
Current Superintendent Mary Beth Jackson has said in several public forums she plans to run again.
Jackson was first elected to the position in 2012.
Prior to her election, Jackson oversaw career and technical education the district and was a guidance counselor and teacher.
Jackson is expected to file her paperwork with the supervisor of elections next month.
Van Dyke holds a masters in education along with a handful of educational endorsements and certifications.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue May 26 22:52:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man shot as robbers try to steal his grill</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-shot-as-robbers-try-to-steal-his-grill-1.482957</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man shot as robbers try to steal his grill
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 03:52 PM.
A Fort Walton Beach man was shot in the wrist on Memorial Day during what he described as an attempt to steal his grill.
Nathan Robinson, 26, of Baker Street, told Okaloosa County deputies he was standing outside of his car smoking a cigarette when two men armed with a handgun approached him, demanding his money and his grill, a Sheriffs Office news release said.
The release described Robinsons grill as a cosmetic set of tooth coverings made of precious or similar metal.
Robinson, who spoke to authorities at Fort Walton Beach Medical Center, said he jumped into his car as the armed men approached. One of them used the gun to shatter his drivers side window and then fired into the vehicle, the release said.
The bullet struck Robinson in the left wrist, the release said.
He said the shooting had taken place at about 5:30 p.m. Monday outside an apartment complex on Skinner Circle.
Robinson told deputies a friend had driven him to the Medical Center. His car, parked outside the emergency room entrance, had a shattered drivers side window, the release said.
Investigators found a bullet fragment on the center console.
Robinson described the shooter as a black male with an afro in his late teens, approximately 6 feet 2 inches tall, wearing a gray and black hoodie with faded black jeans.
He described the second individual as a tall, skinny, light skinned black male with a high-top haircut, wearing a black shirt with a yellow decal and khaki shorts.
Anyone with information on the shooting is asked to call the Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office at 850-651-7400 or Emerald Coast Crime Stoppers at 850-863-TIPS.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue May 26 20:23:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Report: Man exposes himself to students, grapples with deputy</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/report-man-exposes-himself-to-students-grapples-with-deputy-1.482824</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Report: Man exposes himself to students, grapples with deputy
Brian Merrill Mitchell
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, May 26, 2015 at 01:23 PM.
A naked Niceville man caused a ruckus at the Mossy Head Industrial Park before being arrested Sunday night, a Walton County Sheriffs Office news release said.
Brian Merrill Mitchell, 41, is charged with exposing himself inside the Loves Travel Shop at the industrial park and then climbing aboard a bus parked outside and showing his genitals to students between the ages of 15 and 18 years old, the release said.
Deputies arriving on the scene ordered Mitchell to the ground, but he refused to cooperate, the release said.
Mitchell instead turned his attention toward the deputy and started walking towards him, the release said. Mitchell got within 7 feet of the deputy and disobeyed commands until a Taser was drawn.
Mitchell raised his hands as if he were going to cooperate, the release said. But when he got close enough, he made a grab for the deputys Taser.
The deputy was able to subdue Mitchell after a short struggle, the release said.
Mitchell was charged with indecent exposure, lewd and lascivious behavior, battery on a law enforcement officer, resisting an officer with violence and trespassing.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:20:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Learning on their own: Students explore variety of topics in independent study </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/learning-on-their-own-students-explore-variety-of-topics-in-independent-study-1.482542</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Learning on their own: Students explore variety of topics in independent study
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Monday, May 25, 2015 at 04:20 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  The love of learning was quietly apparent this year for a group of students at Fort Walton Beach High School.
Four seniors opted to enroll in an independent study course designed to let them guide their own lessons.
The class was created by senior Jackie Orcutt for her Gold Award in Girl Scouts. Per the demands of the award, which is the equivalent of the Boy Scout Eagle Award, Jackie wrote the curriculum and then recruited three other students to do the class with her.
The thing about it, is it is solely what you want to study, the 18-year-old said.
Every two weeks, each student selected a question that they then researched on their own time. They presented their findings to their principal, an assistant principal, a teacher and each other every other week.
Their questions varied as much as the students themselves. They spanned all subject areas from history to current events and from the building blocks of modern science to the quirks of standardized testing.
It gave me motive to learn that kind of stuff, senior Jesse Arrington said of the course.
Each student also researched a larger topic throughout the class and gave a final presentation about it Friday afternoon.
No matter the topic, a roundtable discussion ensued.
Im totally sold on the whole concept, said Principal John Spolski.
They were still working out the details of how it would be offered next year, but said it had proven too valuable an asset to not continue.
Youre doing it on your own, he said to the students as they did their final presentations. This is all you... thats the beauty for us  you guys become the instructors.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:14:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Hidden Gems: Florida Park</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/hidden-gems-florida-park-1.482535</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>This waterfront park has a boat ramp and boat dock access.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Monday, May 25, 2015 at 04:14 PM.
Photo Galleries
Florida Park
VALPARAISO  Tucked away in a quiet neighborhood on Boggy Bayou, Florida Park provides 3.45 acres of peace, quiet and recreation.
If youre looking to launch a boat, go for a swim, have a picnic, let the kids burn off some energy or just sit on a shady swing and read a book, this hidden gem is just the place to visit.
Park it here: Compared to its larger neighbor, Lincoln Park, Florida Park is a less known (and therefore usually less crowded) place to play. Two barbecue grills and multiple shady places make it a great place to bring a picnic lunch. If youre really ambitious, you can try to catch your lunch from the fishing pier.
Be a good sport: In addition to swimming in the bayou, there are wide open, grassy areas ideal for a game of Frisbee, catch, or tag.
Wanna play? The park has a large playground with modern equipment, including slides, swings (regular as well ones designed for babies), cross bars and other things to climb on.
Tip: Swimming is allowed, but there are no lifeguards on duty. Pets are not allowed.
Parks Checklist:
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:09:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Miller: VA yet to deliver on promises</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/miller-va-yet-to-deliver-on-promises-1.482531</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Miller: VA yet to deliver on promises
Jeff Miller
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Monday, May 25, 2015 at 04:09 PM.
In the year since the scandals at Veterans Affairs hospitals across the country made headlines, U.S. Rep. Jeff Miller, the chairman of the House Veterans Affairs Committee, has been busy leading his committees investigation into the problem-plagued department.
He recently shared his thoughts about the process and his hopes for the future with the Daily News.
DAILY NEWS: One year later, what do you see as the committees greatest accomplishment?
MILLER: The Accountability Act, which was passed last year, was the biggest sea change in the departments history. It allocated $10 billion to give veterans a choice about where to go and who to see for medical care. Thats a big change, although VA isnt doing what it should be to make this change available to veterans.
DN: What do you see as the challenges that prevent making broad reforms at the VA?
MILLER: The sad thing is, VA has yet to deliver on its promises. We are trying to change the culture within the department. But thats just not the standard by which the VA operates. They shift people around within the agency; they put them on paid administrative leave for months at a time. The mechanisms are in place, especially since the Accountability Act gave the secretary the power to fire top people in the department, but theyre just not being utilized.
DN: One of the questions our readers asked is in regard to the obstacles that veterans face when they separate from the military. Is this an issue your committee is taking on?
MILLER: The separation point is an area weve been focusing on. I know the department is trying to get the backlog of disability claims down. My concern is that while VA claims that they have reduced the backlog, what they actually have done is shifted that burden over to the Veteran Boards of Appeals, where its no longer considered a backlog case for the VA  its now an appeals case. Regardless, the veteran is still waiting for their benefits. They are going to claim at the end of this year that theyve reduced the backlog tremendously, but thats just not the case.
DN: You have stated that you are considering running in 2016 for the U.S. Senate seat currently held by Marco Rubio. Are you any closer to making a decision?
MILLER: Im looking harder every day. There are still questions that have to be answered, but Im very encouraged by the reception I have received around the state and for that matter, the country. People are looking for somebody who is able to be true to their ideals and beliefs, but is willing to get things done in a city that is broken.
Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @Kellyhnwfdn
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon May 25 23:01:46 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Learn their stories': Hundreds gather for annual Memorial Day Ceremony </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/learn-their-stories-hundreds-gather-for-annual-memorial-day-ceremony-1.482528</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>'Learn their stories': Hundreds gather for annual Memorial Day Ceremony
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Monday, May 25, 2015 at 04:01 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH Lt. Col. of 7th Special Forces Rafael Rodriguez told the crowd at Beal Memorial Cemetery that Memorial Day is a day to share stories of the fallen.
He then spoke of his friend, Sgt. 1st Class Victor Cervantes.
"One of the best men I've ever met," Rodriguez said.
The first night they met, Cervantes helped Rodriguez during a land navigation training mission after he got lost in the middle of the night. After a year of friendship, in June 2005 Cervantes was killed while serving in Afghanistan.
Cervantes is just one of more than 1 million Americans killed in all U.S. wars.
While some were packing up their gear to head to the beach, nearly two hundred people gathered Monday for the annual Memorial Day Ceremony.
Tom Rice, a retired Army sergeant and owner of Magnolia Grill, has organized the event for nearly 25 years.
"Originally, I was the helper, working with World War II vet, Chief Master Sgt. (William) Zell," he said.
At the center of the ceremony, a flag at half-mast waved in the breeze. As Rice read the roll call of deceased veterans, community leaders and organizations walked up to place a flower at the table and salute. Rice brought hats representing all different branches of the military to place at the table. They were all plucked from his restaurant  including the helmet he wore in Desert Storm in the 1990s.
Fort Walton Beach City Councilman, Dick Rynearson and his wife Janey have attended the ceremony for about 10 years. Sitting in their red camping chairs, the two held hands throughout the entire program.
"Both of our fathers are veterans  it just seems like the right place to be today," said Dick, who is an Air Force veteran.
Rice, like so many others with deep roots in the Emerald Coast, grew up appreciating the military.
"My grandmother would always call today decoration day  we were helping decorate the veteran's graves and salute them."
Around 7:30 Monday morning, junior ROTC members were placing flags at gravesite a. They were taken down later in the day.
During his speech Rodriguez encouraged the audience to pay respects to the living veterans and thank them for their service as a way to pay homage to the fallen.
"Seek them out and learn their stories," he said. "Let them know you appreciate them."
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4434 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon May 25 00:54:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pleasant horsemanship builds community</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/pleasant-horsemanship-builds-community-1.482342</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Pleasant horsemanship builds community
Leannah McDevitt, 7, competes at the Pleasant Ridge Arena in Defuniak Springs winning one of several first-place ribbons in various classes. The arena touts helping create the positive social growth of the community.
IRINA ROGANOV | Special to the Daily News
By KAREN ROGANOV | Daily News Contributing Writer
Published: Sunday, May 24, 2015 at 05:54 PM.
Photo Galleries
Pleasant horsemanship
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS  Theres no horsefeathers about it. Little buckaroos and seasoned equestrians have a place to trot their stuff thanks to a community effort.
That little girl, that is our future, said Jim Wasson, a judge at the Pleasant Ridge Arena in DeFuniak Springs. The arenas mission is to promote good moral development, sportsmanship and civic pride.
Leannah McDevitt, 7, of Freeport bounced by the spectators almost looking like a toy doll upon her miniature paint pony.
Its really exciting, said McDevitt, who started showing equines at age 4. Its just fun.
Diana Armbruster and her husband Rex Brannon created the arena five years ago and live on part of the back 300 acres.
The entry fee is $5 and after paying for the Porta-potty, light bills and give-away ribbons, they clear enough to earn the ability to sit in the hot sun corralling riders for eight hours on another Saturday.
We do it mostly for the kids, said Armbruster, adding that the judge will let a child having a hard time, do a do-over.
Click here to see a slideshow from the arena.
Adult riders also display their abilities in halter, western, English, trail, poles, barrels and games.
Volunteers help to run the arena, which means 100 percent of the proceeds from the barbeque stand go to a local church ministry to provide baby food, formula, and diapers.
The small-town community spirit is active, Armbruster said.
Build it and they will come, said Armbruster.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon May 25 00:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>STORIES FROM THE STREET: Man accused of drunken disturbance, taking razor blade into jail</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/stories-from-the-street-man-accused-of-drunken-disturbance-taking-razor-blade-into-jail-1.482338</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>STORIES FROM THE STREET: Man accused of drunken disturbance, taking razor blade into jail
Henry Andrew Jones
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Sunday, May 24, 2015 at 05:45 PM.
Man accused of drunken disturbance, taking razor blade into jail
CRESTVIEW - A 35-year-old Alabama man is facing charges after allegedly creating a drunken disturbance at an apartment building.
On May 5 around 8:30 p.m., an off-duty officer reported nearly being struck by Henry Andrew Jones, of Castleberry, Alabama, in the parking lot of an apartment complex, according to the arrest report. The officer tried to check on Jones, who allegedly became verbally abusive and yelled ob-scenities.
Jones then tried to taunt the officer by yelling at him to follow him to his apartment, the report said. Other residents in the complex reported being disturbed by the yelling and going to the park-ing lot to check it out.
One resident reported that her three sleeping children woke because of the yelling, according to the report. Jones allegedly had a strong odor of an alcoholic beverage and became verbally abu-sive with on-duty Crestview Police officers who responded to the scene.
He was taken to jail, where he was asked twice if he had anything that would get him into trou-ble, the report said. His response was allegedly, Man check my pockets, what the (expletive) an I going to jail for.
Officers searched him and found nothing, according to the report. Once in the jail, he was searched again, and a razor blade was found in his pockets.
He is charged with felony introducing contraband into a county detention facility and misde-meanor breach of the peace.
REPORT: Witness saw woman fly out of house nude after alleged battery
NICEVILLE - A 35-year-old man is accused of attacking a woman he was living with four nights a week.
Niceville Police officers were called before 9 a.m. on May 11, when a woman walking by saw the victim fly out of the home, nude and crying, according to the arrest report.
The witness reported seeing the Niceville man scream at the victim.The victim told officers that she was awoken by the man screaming at her, the report said. When she tried to get away, he allegedly grabbed her by the neck and began choking her.
She said she was able to flee, but he pushed her out the back door, according to the report. She had substantial red marks on her chest.
The man is charged with misdemeanor battery.
Man upset about late night salesman, intoxicated purchase
NICEVILLE - Niceville Police officers responded to a Chip Lane residence around 10:45 p.m. on May 8 for a report of a vacuum salesman in a man's home.
The caller reported that the salesman had sold his intoxicated father-in-law a vacuum cleaner and would not tear up the sales paperwork, according to the call log. He also did not believe the salesman had a permit for Niceville or that the salesman should be out so late at night.
Officers responded, but the salesman had already left the area.
They found the salesman later that night and informed him that he needed a Niceville permit to solicit in the city, the log said. The salesman cooperated and left the area.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Mon May 25 00:38:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'They are my furkids' Okaloosa Kennel Club hosts annual dog show </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/they-are-my-furkids-okaloosa-kennel-club-hosts-annual-dog-show-1.482330</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
'They are my furkids' Okaloosa Kennel Club hosts annual dog show
Diana Wehry of Charleston, Tenn., and her sheepdog, Paige, prepare for photos after winning a handful of ribbons including Best of Breed.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Sunday, May 24, 2015 at 05:38 PM.
The Fort Walton Beach Fairgrounds went to the dogs this weekend as the Okaloosa Kennel Club hosted its annual dog show.
The two-day event saw various breeds of dogs compete for ribbons and points toward titles such as champion and grand champion.
They come from all over  some of the judges are even from Canada, said Karen Williams of OKC.
See more photos
Dog breeders and handlers showcase their purebred pups to earn accolades through the American Kennel Club, with which OKC is affiliated.
It's like getting the Good Housekeeping seal of approval, Williams said. The goal is to breed the best dog they possibly can.
Williams knows that dog breeding doesn't always have a positive connotation, but she said the breeders who come to shows are different from your back-yard breeders.
They will take a dog back at any time. Many rescue dogs  do not breed more than once a year.
The OKC dog show is different from the upscale shows you watch on TV. Mixed-breed dogs are able to compete in obedience trials, which was an OKC decision.
This show has been really fun. Everyone has been so friendly, said Susan Lucas of Nashville, Tenn., who came to the show with her champion Shetland sheepdog.
Nekolia Burke of Chattanooga, Tenn., has been training her Shetland sheepdogs for nearly seven years.
It's a hobby, she said of dog shows. Some people golf  but your golf clubs don't cuddle you back.
Burke's sheepdogs took home several ribbons Sunday afternoon, but it's the bonding experience she likes best.
These are my furkids  but I do have real children, too, she said with a laugh.
And since it's likely that dogs don't care much for ribbons, Burke said she always rewards the dogs with a special treat after a show weekend.
They're going to have filet mignon tonight.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4434 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon May 25 00:26:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ceremony to feature Freedom Bell, symbolic groundbreaking</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/ceremony-to-feature-freedom-bell-symbolic-groundbreaking-1.482325</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Ceremony to feature Freedom Bell, symbolic groundbreaking
By  KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Sunday, May 24, 2015 at 05:26 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  This year the citys annual Memorial Day ceremony will feature a bit more audience participation than usual.
The Monday program  which is a joint effort between the Air Force, Army and Marines  will include a symbolic groundbreaking of the future Veterans Tribute Bell Tower at Beal Memorial Cemetery.
We are going to pass entrenching tools, loaned to me by the military, from person to person, Organizer and emcee Tom Rice said. Then we will spread some of the sand that was used to cast the bell.
The Freedom Bell, which was cast locally on Sept. 11, 2014, will be rung to mark the start of the ceremony at 11 a.m.
The Veterans Tribute Tower Committee has made major strides in meeting its fundraising goal of $250,000.
Were $32,000 from the end, Rice said. Its just come from every direction.
Last week the City Council, at City Manager Michael Beedies recommendation, approved a $25,000 donation from the citys cemetery upkeep fund.
Theyre right at the finish line, Beedie told the council, calling it a great honor to be able to donate to a project honoring veterans.
Rice said he was thrilled by the citys support.
We are very grateful, he said. This is something weve been thinking about for five or six years.
Rice said the committees target is to have the tower built and installed in time for the citys Veterans Day ceremony.
WANT TO GO?The city will host its annual Memorial Day ceremony at 11 a.m. Monday at Beal Memorial Cemetery.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon May 25 00:23:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>A place to remember</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/a-place-to-remember-1.482321</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
A place to remember
Korean War and Vietnam veteran Bill Walker salutes during the reading of the Roll Call of the Deceased during last years Memorial Day ceremony at Beal Memorial Cemetery.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Sunday, May 24, 2015 at 05:23 PM.
Today is the first Memorial Day since Cindy Schellin lost her soldier son, Gage.
It wont be an easy day for her, but the Fort Walton Beach resident is grateful to live in a community where there are sacred spaces dedicated to remember-ing fallen service members.
Ordinarily, I like to go to Liza Jackson Park to sit and think about Gage, she said. I used to take him fishing there, and its a special place to me. But on Memorial Day, I want to attend the services at Beal Memorial Cemetery, because this time it wont just be me remembering that I had a son.
Its uplifting to know that I will be around other people who have lost sons and daughters, and who share my grief.
Across the country, Memorial Day is the one day a year designated for Americans to pause to remember the men and women who have fought and died in service to their country. In heavily military Northwest Florida, however, those remembrances arent limited to the federal holiday.
Residents have constructed memorials across the area, from large granite monuments to the impromptu tributes built at the site of the recent Blackhawk helicopter crash near Navarre. Some are built on local military bases, while others stand proudly in the center of a community.
For many, these spots are a place for healing and quiet reflection. Here are just some of the many monuments to be found across Northwest Florida.
Santa Rosa County Veterans Memorial Plaza, Milton: Located south of U.S. Highway 90 on Willing Street, the plaza features black granite monoliths featuring a different branch of the service or a historic battle scene. In the center of the display, a statue of a 20th century soldier crouches on a box over the words, Fallen, not Forgotten. The display faces the Blackwater River, where benches provide a spot for peaceful remembering.
Memorial Air Park, Hurlburt Field: The airpark is home to many examples of the aircraft flown at Hurlburt, the headquarters of the Air Force Special Operations Command. In addition, there are more than 25 monuments remembering specific air commandos and historic events. The park is used throughout the year for special remembrance ceremonies. Retired MSgt. Bob Buff Underwood was instrumental in the installation of the latest addition to the airpark  a memorial to fallen Combat Talon crew members.This is the proper resting place for The Rock,  Underwood said. It sits adjacent to one of the original Combat Talon aircraft, and together they offer a remembrance of the sacrifices that were made by Combat Talon airmen.
Okaloosa County War Memorial, Crestview: Built in view of the Okaloosa County Courthouse in the citys downtown area, the monument features the names of Okaloosa County residents who died in several conflicts. A small fountain adds to the display, which was dedicated in 2003. Inscribed on the monu-ments panels are the words In memory of those who made the supreme sacrifice in all wars, POW and MIA.
Explosive Ordnance Disposal Memorial, Eglin Air Force Base near Bluewater Bay: The four dark panels on the white marble wall that make up the EOD Memorial pay tribute to EOD members of every branch of the Armed Forces who were killed in the line of duty. Each year, the EOD Memorial Founda-tion hosts a special memorial service where new names are added to the plaques, and the names of those already on the wall are read and remembered.
Veterans Memorial, Doolittle Park, Valparaiso: Named in honor of World War II hero Jimmy Doolittle, the park includes a veterans memorial and flag pole. The park is Dedicated in Memory of all War Veterans Who Served Honorably in the Armed Forces of the United States of America according to the text on the marker. The park is located on John Sims Parkway, just east of the intersection with State Road 85. It is home to many Memorial Day and Veterans Day ceremonies.
Nomad Memorial, Eglin Air Force Base: This monument commemorates the twelve members of the 33rd Fighter Wing who died in the terrorist bombing at Khobar Towers, Saudi Arabia in 1996. The eternal flame sword at the center of the memorial is a symbol drawn from the wings emblem. Behind the flame are 12 panels with pictures of each member of the fallen. At the top of the monument are the words Our Nomads have ceased their wandering.
This is a very special place to me, said retired Okaloosa County Supervisor of Elections Pat Hollarn. Ive always been very involved with the 33rd Fighter Wing, and was especially so at the time of the bombing. I always make it a point to stop by and visit there on Memorial Day.
All Veterans Memorial, Eglin Air Force Base: The memorial at the head of Memorial Lake honors veterans from all wars. A multi-colored, stained-glass style image sits upon a white wall that displays several bronze plaques. Leading up to the wall is a plaza paved with bricks containing the names of hundreds of different veterans. Every year during the annual Gate to Gate run on Memorial Day, all of the runners pay tribute to the nations veterans by dropping carna-tions at the memorial as they pass by.
Freeport Veterans Memorial: Located next to City Hall on State Road 20, the memorial features a statue of a woman kneeling before the traditional fallen soldier tribute: an overturned rifle standing inside a pair of combat boots and topped by a helmet. Beneath the statue are the words All gave some  Some gave all. The statue was unveiled in 2012 by Glenda Penton, mother of fallen soldier Timothy Padgett, a Special Forces sergeant from Walton County who died in Afghanistan in 2007.
Coast Guard Memorial, Coast Guard Station Destin: This memorial honors those Coast Guard members who passed the bar while in service to their country. The station also pays special tribute to Petty Officer 3rd Class Lonnie Jones, a machinery technician, who was killed in the line of duty March 30, 1981, while responding to a search and rescue case in the vicinity of Destin.
Floridas First Confederate Monument, DeFuniak Springs: Located at 571 East Nelson Avenue on courthouse lawn, this monument was established shortly after the Civil War by the Walton County Ladies Memorial Association. The memorial was erected in 1871.
An interesting footnote: Northwest Florida is also home to what is believed to be the only memorial to Union soldiers in the South. The statue of a fully dressed Union soldier, which was built with the support of transplanted Northerners, can be found at Memorial Park in Lynn Haven. Fittingly, the soldier faces north.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4434 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun May 24 02:03:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Illegal outdoor burn blamed for wildfire</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/illegal-outdoor-burn-blamed-for-wildfire-1.482126</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Illegal outdoor burn blamed for wildfire
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Saturday, May 23, 2015 at 07:03 PM.
POINT WASHINGTON - Firefighters blame an illegal outside burn for igniting a wild land blaze Saturday.
The fire was reported about 1 p.m. after the fire got out of control, according to the South Walton Fire District.
The blaze was extinguished by 2:24 p.m. with help from the Florida Forest Service.
The fire burned one acre and damaged an abandoned shed.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun May 24 02:00:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man hospitalized after accidental shooting</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-hospitalized-after-accidental-shooting-1.482125</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man hospitalized after accidental shooting
Stock photography
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Saturday, May 23, 2015 at 07:00 PM.
MARY ESTHER - A 26-year-old man was flown to a Pensacola hospital in critical condition Saturday morning after he accidentally shot himself, authorities say.
The shooting was reported just before 10 a.m. Fort Walton Beach police, Okaloosa County sheriff's deputies, EMS and firefighters from Mary Esther and Ocean City-Wright responded to the home on Roserita Place.
Deputies cleared nearby homes until the man was taken from the scene, Mary Esther firefighters said.
He shot himself with a pistol, according to the Ocean City-Wright Fire Department.
A medical helicopter landed in the parking lot of Santa Rosa Mall to take the man to the hospital.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
