<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crestview Confederate flag coming down</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crestview-confederate-flag-coming-down-1.495837</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Crestview Confederate flag coming down
By By Tom McLaughlin
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 09:11 PM.

CRESTVIEW -- The descendants of Bill Lundy may have come up with a proposal to allow the dignified removal of the Confederate Flag from near the Okaloosa County Courthouse.
Family members have agreed to remove a memorial to Lundy, believed to have been the second longest living Civil War veteran, to private land, according to a release issued Monday by Crestview Mayor David Cadle.
The memorial is not the property of the City of Crestview and the Lundy family can claim possession, Cadle said in his release.
Okaloosa Countys NAACP leadership has been calling for years for the Confederate flag to be removed from its present location at East First Avenue and State Road 85.
A petition was circulated again this year following the racially motivated massacre of nine African-American churchgoers in Charleston S.C.
Current local chapter President Ray Nelson said though the NAACP did not directly participate in negotiations between the city and Lundy family, the end result did not shock him.
It wasnt a big surprise, I was expecting to hear it, Nelson said.
Nelson said he had spoken to Cadle Monday afternoon. The mayor couldnt be reached for comment later in the day.
Nelson said, and the news release confirmed, that details of the memorial being moved are still being ironed out.
Nelson said he has proposed that the flag itself be removed immediately while moving the memorial structure is discussed.
The problem was not with the memorial, but with the flag itself, he said.
With a compromise reached, Cadle also announced that a special meeting of the Crestview City Council, scheduled for 5:30 p.m., Tuesday, would be called off.
According to the news release the Lundy memorial was on Okaloosa County land until a Highway Patrol office was erected and the city permitted the memorial to be moved to its current location.
Daily News records indicate the memorial was originally erected in 1958, one year after Lundys death.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:04:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/photos-car-accident-at-beal-and-crewilla-1.495819</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 06:04 PM.
A car accident at the intersection of Beal Parkway and Crewilla Drive tied up traffic Monday afternoon. Nobody was injured in the wreck.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
COMMENTS
PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
http://www.nwfdailynews.com July 6, 2015 18:4
A car accident at the intersection of Beal Parkway and Crewilla Drive tied up traffic Monday afternoon. Nobody was injured in the wreck.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The highs and lows of July 4th weekend</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/the-highs-and-lows-of-july-4th-weekend-1.495781</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>The highs and lows of July 4th weekend
Hundreds of boaters crowded into the shallows of crab island near Destin on July Fourth.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KARI C. BARLOW and KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 04:08 PM.
The Fourth of July holiday weekend was, by all accounts, a hot, crowded, bumper-to-bumper success on the Emerald Coast.
Tens of thousands of tourists filled up local beaches, hotels and restaurants across Santa Rosa, Okaloosa and Walton counties.
The influx of visitors also posed challenges for law enforcement, including reckless driving, vehicle crashes and fireworks mishaps.
Keep reading for a wrap-up of the holiday weekend.
Stop-and-roll traffic
Traffic over the weekend was heavy, especially in southern Okaloosa County.
From early Friday to Sunday evening, congestion on U.S. Highway 98 was a common sight in Destin. A handful of crashes further slowed the commute.
No accidents involving pedestrians occurred despite the constant flow of weekend events in the Worlds Luckiest Fishing Village.
The Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office reported 27 traffic crashes, including two on the Mid-Bay Bridge. It had 17 calls for reckless drivers and another nine for intoxicated drivers, according to spokeswoman Michele Nicholson.
Nine car burglaries were reported in Okaloosa County and four vehicle thefts, she said.
In Walton County, U.S. 98 was particularly congested around the Silver Sands Premium Outlets as throngs of tourists opted for shopping during the rain, said Jim Bagby, executive director of the Walton County Tourist Development Council.
No major traffic crashes were reported, said Corey Dobridnia, a spokeswoman for the Walton County Sheriffs Office.
During a multi-agency checkpoint on U.S. Highway 98 in Fort Walton Beach, law enforcement made 27 arrests, but only two were for driving under the influence, according to Capt. Bill Royal with the Fort Walton County Police Department.
Officers cited one driver for not having a child properly restrained, but issued no other seat belt violations. The remaining charges were drug possession, driving with a suspended, or nonexistent license, and no proof of registration.
Pretty well packed
Visitors were highly visible on Navarre Beach during the holiday weekend, said Julie Morgan, director of the Santa Rosa County Tourist Development Council.
They were using our bike path, she said. They were walking and jogging. ... I know Juanas was busy and the pier was busy. I feel like it was very successful.
In Okaloosa County, most hotels and resorts were filled to overflowing.
There were very few, if any, lodging accommodations available, said Ed Schroeder, tourism director for the county. It was pretty well packed out.
The best part was hundreds of tourists taking advantage of local events at Fort Walton Landing and the Destin Harbor, he said.
Folks really got out and enjoyed the community, Schroeder said. There are very few areas that have what we offer.
South Waltons crowds likely set some records, Bagby said.
It was a fabulous weekend, even with the rain, he said. People were really well behaved. ... We think this will be our strongest ever June and our strongest ever July. Things are looking good.
Faulty fireworks
Destin saw three small fires related to the holiday celebrations, according to Destin Fire Department Battalion Chief James Taylor.
The first call came in around 9:20 p.m. Friday for two brush fires beside Destin Commons caused by a fireworks, he said.
Taylor said the fireworks ignited two different fires in the brush between the Commons and Regatta Bay. By the time they were extinguished, about an acre and half had burned.
As far as we know, (the firework) was ours, said Bob Perry, the general manager of the Commons.
Fire watchers brought in by Destin Commons were the first to spot the initial fire, Perry said. The Commons stations watchers on the property any time it shoots off fireworks, he added.
The third fire occurred near Destin Pointe, which a firework set some sea oats aflame, Taylor said.
No other firework-related mishaps were reported by public safety officials in the area.
The blessing of the weekend is we had plenty of rain, said Fort Walton Police Department Capt. Bill Royal.
Every agency said it received a number of calls related to illegal fireworks, but no one was citied or charged.
Generally, you show up, and they stop, said Sgt. Rich Aloy, a spokesman for the Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Retired Airman gets new SUV from Lee Automotive, VA (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/retired-airman-gets-new-suv-from-lee-automotive-va-photos-1.495780</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Retired Airman gets new SUV from Lee Automotive, VA (PHOTOS)
Air Force veteran Pedro Rodriguez of Guaynabo, Puerto sits in his 2015 Subaru Forester on Monday at Lee Volkswagen Subaru in Fort Walton Beach while he is shown the car's features by sales representative Tony Santos. Rodriguez received a $20,000-plus grant from the Department of Veteran Affairs for a new car.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 04:03 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  Air Force veteran Pedro Rodriguez of Guaynabo, Puerto Rico, received a new car from a local car lot on Monday after months of searching for dealers to honor the $20,000-plus grant he received from the Department of Veteran Affairs.
He was getting depressed because no one was going to honor that benefit, said his wife, Maria Rodriguez.
The 60-year-old Air Force veteran fought back tears as he was handed the keys to his new car, a 2015 Subaru Forester.
PHOTOS of the car giveaway.
Im happy this dealership has worked with me. Im really happy, said Rodriguez.
About three weeks ago, Rodriguez found a story about a family in Pensacola who had received the same grant and was able to purchase a car from the Lee Automotive Group in Crestview.
Rodriguez called the dealership and was told he also could use the grant money to get a new car at Lee Volkswagen Subaru in Fort Walton Beach.
A lot of dealers wont do it because it takes weeks to get paid, said Maureen Bierman, marketing director for Lee Automotive Group.
Were just trying to get the word out about the program. We want to say thank you to all of our veterans said Bierman.
Rodriguez, a retired Master Sergeant, served 31 years in the Air Force as a civil engineer. He and his wife frequently visit relatives in Florida and needed a car for their travels.
The grant requires the recipient to be a veteran or current service member and the recipient must have a qualified disability.
Rodriguez suffered a knee and lower back injury while serving a tour in 2009 in Iraq. The injury caused permanent nerve damage that leaves him in constant pain.
He is pleased with the treatment he received from the VA and hopes more dealerships will be willing to help veterans and service members who are awarded the grant.
(The grant) helps us a lot... in getting the vehicle, which practically we couldnt get.
Contact Daily News Photographer Nick Tomecek at 850-315-4426 or ntomecek@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @NickTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Firefighters battling ‘huge’ blaze at warehouse</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/firefighters-battling-huge-blaze-at-warehouse-1.495778</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Firefighters battling huge blaze at warehouse
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 04:01 PM.
A huge warehouse fire Monday destroyed an estimated 60 percent of a Gulf Breeze business called Sunny Electrical Sales.
Dark smoke from the blaze, which occurred inside a Cowen Road industrial park, billowed high above U.S. Highway 98 and the nearby Gulf Breeze Zoo.
A wind from the southprevented the smoke from causing traffic problems or threatening animals at the zoo, said Midway Fire District Battalion Chief Ernie Johnson.
Navarre Beach Fire Department Chief Mike Howard, who described the fire as huge, confirmed hed sent a truck from his department to assist the Midway firefighters.
Johnson said trucks from Navarre, Gulf Breeze and Pensacola Beach also arrived to assist the three trucks Midway brought to the fire scene.
He said the fire call came in at 1:42 p.m. and crews had it under control within about 30 minutes. Johnson said the warehouse area of the electrical business, comprising about 60 percent of the total structure, was a complete loss.
The inside office areas, however, suffered only water damage.
They had a fire wall that did a great job, Johnson said.
Sunnys Electrical Sales closest neighbor, a gymnastics facility, was not damaged by the fire.
Vendors at the Gulf Breeze Flea Market, also located close to where the fire was burning, kept a wary eye on the blaze, said flea market manager Sandra Pettelko.
Pettelko said she walked down to see what was happening and to make sure the flea market itself was safe.
Weve seen the smoke. It was black and then it turned white, she said.
No evacuation of the flea market was necessary, Pettelko said.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:56:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The anti-pot taboo shrinks in presidential politics</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/election-news/the-anti-pot-taboo-shrinks-in-presidential-politics-1.495776</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
The anti-pot taboo shrinks in presidential politics
In this photograph taken June 30, Republican presidential hopeful Sen. Rand Paul of Kentucky speaks during a campaign stop at a sports bar in the Cherry Creek area in Denver. Earlier in the day, Paul made a stop at a cannabis industry convention in downtown Denver to speak to people in the marijuana industry behind closed doors. Presidential candidates are talking about marijuana in ways unimaginable not long ago. White House hopefuls in both parties are taking donations from people in the new marijuana industry, which is investing heavily in political activism as a route to expanded legalization and landed its first major candidate, Paul, at a trade show.
AP
By KRISTEN WYATT | Associated Press
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 03:56 PM.
DENVER  Presidential candidates are talking about marijuana in ways unimaginable not long ago.
White House hopefuls in both parties are taking donations from people in the new marijuana industry, which is investing heavily in political activism as a route to expanded legalization and landed its first major candidate, Rand Paul, at a trade show last month.
Several Republicans, like Democrats, are saying they won't interfere with states that are legalizing a drug still forbidden under federal law. And at conservative policy gatherings, Republicans are discussing whether drug sentences should be eased.
A quarter century after Bill Clinton confessed he tried marijuana but insisted "I didn't inhale," the taboo against marijuana is shrinking at the highest level of politics, just as it appears to be with the public.
"When I was growing up, it was political suicide for a candidate to talk about pot being legal," said Tim Cullen, owner of Colorado Harvest Co., a chain of medical and recreational marijuana dispensaries.
Cullen attended a Hillary Rodham Clinton fundraiser in New Mexico last month and talked to the Democratic candidate about her position on legalizing pot.
"She's not outwardly hostile to the idea, which is a big step forward," Cullen said. "She's willing to openly talk about it at least."
A slim majority of Americans, 53 percent, said in a Pew Research Center survey in March that the drug should be legal. As recently as 2006, less than a third supported marijuana legalization in another measure of public opinion, the General Social Survey.
Politicians are shifting, but slowly.
Republican candidates Jeb Bush, Ted Cruz and Rick Perry are among those who say states should decide marijuana laws, even as they brand legalization a bad idea. In June, Paul became the first major-party presidential candidate to hold a fundraiser with the new marijuana industry, courting about 40 donors in Denver.
But the Kentucky senator used a private back door, and aides erected a screen so photographers couldn't see the candidate standing by a green Cannabis Business Summit sign. Paul didn't talk about pot at a public meet-and-greet afterward.
A few days earlier in the same building, six other GOP presidential contenders talked to about 4,000 people at a gathering of Western conservatives. There, Perry defended the right of states to change marijuana laws, even if they "foul it up."
"Colorado comes to mind," the former Texas governor said, to laughs and applause. "I defend the right of Colorado to be wrong on that issue."
Altogether, 23 states and the District of Columbia are flouting federal law by allowing marijuana use for medical or recreational purposes.
Not all candidates say leave it to the states. New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie and former Pennsylvania Sen. Rick Santorum say they would fight to roll back marijuana legalization efforts in states such as Colorado.
Democrats are generally less critical of states legalizing pot, but they're treading carefully, too.
Clinton said last year that more research needed to be done on marijuana's medical value, but "there should be availability under appropriate circumstances." She didn't elaborate what those circumstances should be.
As for her main Democratic rival, Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders sounds lukewarm about legalization, despite his counterculture roots and liberal social views. He told Yahoo News that pot should be decriminalized but he was not ready to go beyond that. He said he smoked pot twice in the old days and "coughed a lot."
Bush and Cruz have also acknowledged using marijuana in their youth, as has President Barack Obama.
Marijuana entrepreneurs say even tepid support for legalization is a step forward, and they're opening their wallets in hopes of seeing more change.
The largest marijuana lobbying group, Marijuana Policy Project, plans to donate tens of thousands to 2016 presidential candidates. Executive Director Rob Kampia was among those at the Denver pot fundraiser.
"We wouldn't have heard a presidential candidate talking that way four years ago," Kampia said. Attendees said Paul talked about changing federal drug-sentencing laws but stopped short of calling for nationwide legalization.
It's unclear how much money the marijuana industry will spend on the presidential race. Many pot-business owners don't list their businesses on campaign-finance disclosure forms, given the drug's federal illegality. And some marijuana activists are likely to spend not on the presidential contest but on campaigns in the six to 10 states likely to have some sort of marijuana policy on ballots next year.
Still, the presidential race appears certain to include more talk of marijuana policy than before.
"There are a lot of loose bricks in the walls of resistance to changing drug laws in America," said William Martin, who studies drug policy at Rice University. "It's no longer a silly question, legalizing marijuana."

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cat hoarder to serve 3 years for animal cruelty</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/cat-hoarder-to-serve-3-years-for-animal-cruelty-1.495773</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Cat hoarder to serve 3 years for animal cruelty
Felicia Guy and Jerry McCallum
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 03:42 PM.
Jerry McCallum, who shared a Crestview-area home with a woman and 92 cats, will serve 36 months in prison for cruelty to animals and violating his probation.
In December of 2014, McCallums probation officer entered the home at 1208 E. Chestnut Ave. and discovered that little to nothing had been done to comply with his request to clean it.
The Panhandle Animal Welfare Society was called in and removed the 92 cats. Some were already dead and nearly all were so sick they had to be put down, PAWS Director Dee Thompson said afterward.
McCallum pleaded no contest Monday to five felony counts of animal cruelty and two misdemeanor charges of animal abandonment, according to Assistant State Attorney Clifton Drake. He admitted to the probation violation.
Felicia Guy, the woman with whom McCallum shared the Chestnut Avenue trailer, did not offer a plea at her Monday docket day, but will appear in court again Friday, Drake said.
I anticipate she probably will plea, but I cant say that for sure since nothing has been signed yet, McCallum said.
First Judicial Circuit Public Defender Bruce Miller confirmed that his office negotiated the McCallum plea. Guy is represented by the Office of Regional Counsel.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Springs offer cool alternative to hot beaches</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/springs-offer-cool-alternative-to-hot-beaches-1.495766</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Springs offer cool alternative to hot beaches
PonceDeLeon2- Elizabeth McGough jumps into the springs, which are 68-degrees year-round.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 03:15 PM.
The Ponce de Leon Springs were named after the Juan Ponce de Leon, the Spanish explorer who search for the Fountain of Youth according to folklore.
While theres no evidence to show that the local springs will make you any younger, they will cool you off with waters hitting 68-degrees year-round.
Locals and daytrippers alike head to the Ponce de Leon Springs State Park to swim, walk the nature trail and enjoy a picnic  all without fighting crowds at local beaches.
Kimberly Barnett and Tim Biddle took the neighborhood kids to the park one hot afternoon last week.
When one of us goes, we take the whole group, said Barnett with a laugh.
As they take turns jumping into the springs, families around the park are playing volleyball, cooking out on grills, fishing or taking a walk down the nature trail.
Barnett, who recently moved to the area from Louisiana heard about the park online. She said she prefers the springs to beaches.
I like the fresh water. Its nice to come and relax, she said. Some days theres hardly anyone here.
Aside from swimming, some of the kids like to explore the sunken treasures at the bottom of the springs. Youll often see snorkelers in the designated areas.
I found these neat rocks, a coin and this necklace, said Daniel Robertson as he lays out his findings on the ground.
Paxton resident Maggie McKinley opted for the state park to celebrate her sons fifth birthday.
He said to me Thank you for bringing me here to swim,  she said. Weve been here three times this year so far.
WANT TO GO? Ponce de Leon Springs State Park is located at 2860 State Park Road in Ponce de Leon. Admission is $4 per vehicle. For more information, visit floridastateparks.org or call 836-4281.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Making a Difference: Rodeo chips in to fight breast cancer</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/making-a-difference-rodeo-chips-in-to-fight-breast-cancer-1.495747</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Making a Difference: Rodeo chips in to fight breast cancer
Making Strides Against Breast Cancers Donna Fought, holding check, and Kyla Pugh, right front, accept a $1,000 donation from Baker Pro Rodeo organizers Mark Stalnaker, Ernie Brewbaker, Edith Elder, Russell Moorman, Joe Fisher, Bill Graham, President Mark Todd and Jim Silcox.
BRIAN HUGHES |Crestview News Bulletin
By BRIAN HUGHES | Crestview News Bulletin
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 01:13 PM.
Note to readers: This series recognizes people who make a difference in their communities. To nominate someone, call Kari Barlow at 315-4438 or email kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com
BAKER  The Old Spanish Trail Pro Rodeo is about far more than entertainment, and the local American Cancer Society has the check to prove it.
For the second year, the Baker Pro Rodeo sponsors presented $1,000 to Making Strides Against Breast Cancer of the Emerald Coast.
The proceeds came from an April 11 Breast Cancer Awareness Night during the rodeo at the Baker Arena.
In the rodeo world, its a big event to have Saturday nights as pink night for breast cancer awareness, Baker Area Recreation Association President Mark Todd said. We joined the movement last year and we want to keep it a tradition from now out.
ACS will use the money for research and education to help save womens lives, said Donna Fought, a breast cancer survivor and member of Making Strides.
Getting the word out assures women get their mammograms, she said. Even if you encourage just one woman to have an annual mammogram, youve saved a life. The American Cancer Society saved my life. I was one of those women who didnt do what she was supposed to do.
Rodeo organizers presented the check June 29 by a truck with a pink AAA Waste trash bin as a backdrop. Company owner Russell Moorman, one of the organizers, said AAA places the pink container at various community events, particularly cancer research fundraisers.
It gets a lot of attention, Moorman said. People like to sign it.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:46:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PHOTOS: Waterspout forms near Miramar Beach</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/weather/photos-waterspout-forms-near-miramar-beach-1.495726</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PHOTOS: Waterspout forms near Miramar Beach
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 12:46 PM.
Photo Galleries
Waterspout
Jane-Claire Baker of New Orleans was visiting family in Miramar Beach over the weekend and saw this waterspout form during a morning thunderstorm.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
COMMENTS
PHOTOS: Waterspout forms near Miramar Beach By
http://www.nwfdailynews.com July 6, 2015 12:46
Jane-Claire Baker of New Orleans was visiting family in Miramar Beach over the weekend and saw this waterspout form during a morning thunderstorm.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:30:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man dies two days after driving in front of train</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-dies-two-days-after-driving-in-front-of-train-1.495724</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man dies two days after driving in front of train
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 12:30 PM.
An 85-year-old Crestview man died July 4, two days after failing to stop at a crossing and driving in front of a westbound train near Mossy Head.
Roger Eugene Anderson was driving out of the entrance for Mossy Head Auto Parts about 3 p.m. July 2 when the accident happened.
He did not stop at a stop sign prior to crossing the tracks and drove in front of the train and stopped, according to a Florida Highway Patrol media release.
The train could not stop and struck the passenger side of the 2003 Chevrolet pick-up truck, pushing it clear of the tracks.
The train's engineer, Kenneth Davis, a 57-year-old Pensacola man, was not injured.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:10:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution hasn't always worked</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/bill-campbell-s-blog-court-ordered-restitution-hasn-t-always-worked-1.495707</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution hasn't always worked
By BILL CAMPBELL | Daily News blogger
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 12:10 PM.
The oft-quoted state Rep. Matt Gaetz made headlines recently when he pushed through a bill that would  hang on, granny  require public officials convicted of corruption to make restitution.
Anyone with an IQ over room temperature is forgiven for saying, Duh?
But it hasnt always worked, even when the court order said restitution.
Which brings us to David Selby. He was the attorney for the Okaloosa County School Board until 1990. Thats when it was discovered hed absconded with $21 bucks short of $200,000 from county coffers.
He was arrested, judged guilty, sentenced to three years in prison  for which he served 67 days  and ordered to repay the money over 15 years. Didnt happen.
Selby got the court-ordered $1,137 reduced to $200 a month. Do the math. You know how long it takes to repay $199,721 at $200 a month? It was very kind of the judge to think Selby will live to be 130.
But were not quite done. After Selbys probation was over, POOF! No Selby.
I think he might be living in Alabama, said current School District attorney Jeff McInnis, an honorable man. He also said he was told we have no legal jurisdiction or resources to pursue Selby.
McInnis thinks we  thats you and I  may have gotten thirty, maybe thirty-five thousand dollars back from Selby.
So, young Gaetz, congrats on your bill. Heres hoping it has more sticking power than what was extant in 1990.
And heres a question for your dad, who was on the School Board at the time: Who the hell vetted Selby? Didnt they hear rumors he had scammed others before all this went down?
Im just a crummy blogger and I found that out.
Have the board call me when you retire, Jeff. Ill be happy to nose around.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:55:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies mediate dispute over property rights</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/deputies-mediate-dispute-over-property-rights-1.495704</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deputies mediate dispute over property rights
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 11:55 AM.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office were called to the beach Saturday night after a group of Holiday Isle residents occupying the beach allegedly blocked an Emerald Grande ferry boat from dropping off passengers, according to Michele Nicholson, public information officer for OSCO.
According to the call history record, approximately 50 people were at the beach near Gulf Shore Drive. The unidentified caller stated there has been an "ongoing property dispute between the homeowners of Destin Pointe and Legendary (LLC)."
Deputies mediated between the groups and the departed.
Peter Bos, CEO of Legendary, LLC, later arrived on the property and a confrontation ensued between him and a resident. Bos was taking photos and video of the argument when a resident raised his hand in the camera while talking to him. Bos then shoved him away.
After interviewing multiple witnesses and obtaining sworn statements, it was determined that probable cause did not exist for battery charges, said Nicholson.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 05:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two fatal accidents take local lives </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/two-fatal-accidents-take-local-lives-1.495685</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two fatal accidents take local lives
By JENNIE McKEON and WENDY VICTORA | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 10:24 PM.
A Saturday evening crash on Interstate 10 killed a young Crestview mother and left three others injured.
Amber Colson, a 28-year-old Crestview woman, was killed in the 5 p.m. crash, according to the Florida Highway Patrol media release. Although that is the name on her drivers license, she is known locally by her middle name of Nicole  or Nikki  and her maiden name of Parker, friends say.
She was a wonderful mom, said Jeanne Bloomquist, a Crestview woman who has been best friends with Parker since they were freshmen in high school. She always had a smile on her face. She cared so much about other people and did everything for everyone else.
She leaves behind two young children  8-year-old Jacob and 7-year-old Carrie.
According to the FHP report, Parker was a passenger in a 2006 Chevy Silverado driven by 29-year-old Levi Jernigan of Crestview. He was towing a large box trailer loaded with inflatable jump houses eastbound on Interstate 10 near mile marker 44.
The trailer began to sway, causing Jernigan to lose control of the vehicle. The right side of the trailer hit a 2004 Ford Focus driven by Marion Haynes, a 54-year-old Niceville woman.
Jernigans car was forced to the right and Haynes steered to the left, according to the release. Haynes regained control of the Focus and came to a stop facing north on the south shoulder.
The Chevy and the trailer rotated and entered the median, with the right side of the vehicle striking a tree. Jernigan, who was not wearing a seatbelt, was ejected and suffered serious injuries. He was taken to Baptist Hospital. Haynes and her passenger, 38-year-old Zelma Thomas of Crestview, both had minor injuries and were taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center.
Parker was taken to Sacred Heart Hospital, but died of her injuries. She was wearing a seatbelt, according to the release.
He and Parker were dating, Bloomquist said. She had talked to him in the hospital Sunday evening. He told her he did everything he could to stop the trailer from wobbling.
He was her true love, she said. They were inseparable. Hell always be her boyfriend to me.
------
Crestview man dies in Santa Rosa County Crash
A 22-year-old Crestview man died after colliding with a van Sunday afternoon around 3:12 p.m. in Santa Rosa County.
According to a press release from Florida Highway Patrol, Robert Johnson, 28, of Milton, was stopped at the intersection of Welcome Church Road and State Road 87 waiting to make a left turn as Cameron Burke, 22, of Crestview was traveling south on SR 87 on a Honda motorcycle approaching the intersection.
Johnson pulled across the south lanes of SR 87 into the path of Burke, the release said. The front of the motorcycle collided with the left side of the van. Both vehicles came to rest at the intersection.
Burke was wearing a helmet and was pronounced dead on the scene. Johnson had no injuries. He was not wearing a seatbelt.
Charges are pending a traffic homicide investigation, according to the FHP release.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 04:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Locals cheer on U.S. in the Women's World Cup final</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/locals-cheer-on-u-s-in-the-women-s-world-cup-final-1.495677</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Locals cheer on U.S. in the Women's World Cup final
Ian Yancey pours red, white and blue shots for the patrons at Rick's Crab Trap in Fort Walton Beach.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 09:41 PM.
Photo Galleries
Just one day after America celebrate its birthday, the country had another reason to cheer.
The United States has won its third Women's World Cup.
At Rick's Crab Trap in Fort Walton Beach, about a dozen patrons sat at the bar wearing red, white and blue gear and chanting "USA, USA."
"I've always been up on soccer, but I've followed this team since 1999," said Adley Vahue, who sat with his wife Meagan in a cozy booth. "Ever since I saw Brandy Chastain take off her jersey in celebration."
Mary Beth Yancey watched the entire game and hung out with her son, Ian, who is a bartender at Rick's. For every goal the U.S. scored, he prepared red, white and blue shots to hand out for free.
He had a hard time keeping up as the team scored two goals in less than six minutes in the beginning of the game.
"Can you imagine that?" Mary Beth said.
An avid soccer fan, Ian, was sporting a red and white jersey for the evening. He said he didn't mind having to work so long as he got to see the game.
"I love the technicality of the game...to watch 11 people work in unison," he said. "These are the best athletes in the world  men and women."
Kasce Terry stayed after her shift at Rick's to watch the game. She admitted it was a little disappointing to see so few people watching the Women's World Cup.
"It was packed last year for the men's games," she said. "And they didn't even get this far."
While it was no surprise to see the American women celebrate their victory after defeating Japan 5-2, Terry said it was exciting to watch.
"I never expected there would be so many goals so quickly," she said before taking a shot. "I don't think I'll be doing any more celebrating after this. I have to work tomorrow."
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4434 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 00:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>STORIES FROM THE STREET: Teens charged with burglary, arson after fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/stories-from-the-street-teens-charged-with-burglary-arson-after-fire-1.495672</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>STORIES FROM THE STREET: Teens charged with burglary, arson after fire
Shane Michael Swann
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 05:55 PM.
Man tries to buy beer with phony money
NICEVILLE - A clerk at Tom Thumb, 1001 Valparaiso Blvd., called police to report a man had tried to buy beer and an energy shot with a fake bill.
The clerk called Niceville Police officers around 9:40 p.m. on June 16, according to the call log. He said the man came into the store and picked up some beer and an energy shot.
He then tried to pay for the items with a forged $10, the log said. The clerk said he noticed the bill felt "different," didn't have the watermark and reacted to the counterfeit pen.
When the clerk made a comment to the man about the bill being forged, the man looked at it and said, "yeah, you're right it does look phony," according to the log. He then left the bill and the items on the counter and left the store.
Teens charged with burglary, arson after fire
DESTIN - Five teens between the ages of 13 and 18 are charged with burglary and three of the five with arson, after a fire at a private pool on June 27.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputies were called at 6:52 a.m. to a locked and gated pool on June 27, according to arrest reports. The pool has a 4 foot, black metal fence with gated access and a small bath house within the fenced area.
A witness who lives next door told deputies that she heard loud noises coming from the pool area around 6:30 a.m., reports said. She said she saw four teenage boys put on backpacks, get on their bicycles and leave through the south gate.
She said it appeared they had slept their overnight and were gathering their belongings, according to reports. She went down to the pool and found a life preserver ring on the pool deck on fire.
Deputies arrived and found the men's bathroom was also on fire and was still burning, reports said. Destin Fire Department arrived and put out the fire.
Two gas grills were also turned on with one burning and one "free flowing gas," according to reports. Deputies found five teens on bicycles with backpacks around 7:30 a.m. in the Best Buy parking lot.
The teens, 18-year-old man Shane Michael Swann, of Milton, and two 14-year-olds, a 15-year-old and a 13-year-old, were detained, reports said. Swann admitted to going into the gated pool area without permission to swim in the pool.
The minors are not being named due to their ages.
Swann said he'd seen the 15-year-old and one 14-year-old set the life preserver on fire, according to reports. One of the 14-year-olds admitted to setting the preserver on fire and then putting lighter fluid on the bathroom wall and floor before setting it on fire.
None of the boys could give deputies any reasons for their actions, reports said. Damage is estimated at $2,000.
The 13-year-old and one of the 14-year-olds are charged with burglary.
Swann, the other 14-year-old and the 15-year-old are charged with arson and burglary.
The 15-year-old is also charged with possession of drug paraphernalia.

Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 00:50:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HIDDEN GEMS: Bring the kids to Chipley Park</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/hidden-gems-bring-the-kids-to-chipley-park-1.495664</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>HIDDEN GEMS: Bring the kids to Chipley Park
DeFuniak Springs residents Leslie Coone and her son Easton Taylor play on the swings at Chipley Park.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 05:50 PM.
Photo Galleries
Chipley Park
Located in the center of DeFuniak Springs, Chipley Park is the perfect place to spend an afternoon outside, with plenty of things to see and do. One of the more popular activities is to walk around the nearly 40-acre Lake DeFuniak to get a 360-degree view of the park. And if you get too hot, you can always venture inside the Walton-DeFuniak Library for cool air conditioning and R&amp;R (reading and relaxation).
Park it here: Chipley Park is equipped with recreational must-haves including picnic tables (some are even shaded), grills, and more than 40 acres of land so you can spread out.
Be a good sport: Theres plenty of space for a game of catch or whatever sport you choose. Take a walk around Lake DeFuniak and gawk at the historical buildings. Anglers can also take advantage of two fishing piers. The lake is open to boat fishing as well for electric motors with 1 horsepower or less.
Wanna play? Kids can burn energy in the playground area, which includes a slide, swings, merry-go-round and sand box.
Tip: As you walk around the lake, take time for pit stops at the Chautauqua Building and the Walton-DeFuniak library. Regular events are held in the open amphitheater, located by the restrooms. Bring a camera for photo ops of the ducks and turtles hanging out by the waters edge.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 00:34:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State funding for schools serving military children gets a boost </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/state-funding-for-schools-serving-military-children-gets-a-boost-1.495662</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>State funding for schools serving military children gets a boost
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 05:34 PM.
It was a Tuesday morning when the unique needs of students with parents in military crystallized for Tim Wyrosdick.
The calendar said Sept. 11, 2001 and Wyrosdick was the principal of Navarre High School. The population of students tied to the military, specifically Hurlburt Field and the 1st Special Operations Squadron, was high.
Students became very nervous, said the now-superintendent of Santa Rosa County Schools. And for the next two years, we saw parents in and out of homes at the drop of a hat.
Earlier this year, he stood before part of the Florida legislature at the request of Sen. Don Gaetz and asked for a boost in state funding for schools serving military children.
When the governor signed the final budget last month, $13 million was set aside for the military-connected student supplement.
We had to work hard to get this done, Gaetz said. Because it disproportionately affects counties.
The funding offsets the property taxes not collected in each of the counties because the land is owned by the state and federal government, he said.
Santa Rosa County got almost $1.2 million through the grant. Okaloosa County received $2.4 million to help offset the costs of having nearly half of its land owned by the government.
Bay and Escambia counties also will benefit from the funding. Walton was not included.
I thank our entire Florida Legislature for their recognition of the needs of our military connected students, and the enhancement this will bring to our ongoing efforts to support these students and their families, said Superintendent Mary Beth Jackson in an emailed statement to the Daily News.
Okaloosa and Santa Rosa counties already have multiple programs in place to support military children and their families including special guidance counselors and teams ready to help transition them in and out quickly when their parents get military orders.
Up until now, both districts have primarily relied on their regular budgets - including limited federal impact dollars - and other grants.
This money will help districts pay for what theyre already doing without removing money from another part of their budget and open up the possibility for more.
Its a pretty intense opportunity for us, Wyrosdick said.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 02:22:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pedestrian struck while crossing road</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/pedestrian-struck-while-crossing-road-1.495633</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Pedestrian struck while crossing road
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Saturday, July 4, 2015 at 07:22 PM.
MILTON - A teenager from Pace was taken to a Pensacola hospital early Saturday after he was hit by a vehicle while walking across Willard Norris Road.
Sylvia L. Faulk, 58, of Pace, was driving a 1999 Nissan Maxima east on Willard Norris about 2:10 a.m. when she struck 17-year-old Joshua J. Jones just west of Pine Blossom Road, according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Jones was taken to Sacred Heart Hospital in serious condition.
Faulk and her passenger, 18-year-old Patrick C. Koehler were not hurt.
The FHPs investigation was continuing later Saturday.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jul 05 02:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman injured in fall from motorcycle</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/woman-injured-in-fall-from-motorcycle-1.495632</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman injured in fall from motorcycle
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Saturday, July 4, 2015 at 07:21 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS - A 27-year-old woman was flown to a Pensacola hospital early Saturday after she fell off a moving motorcycle.
Travis R. Atlow, 29, of DeFuniak Springs, was driving the 2000 Honda RVT1000 west on Sunrise Road near Pretty Pond Lane at 2:48 a.m., according to the Florida Highway Patrol. He accelerated at the same time passenger Jessica C. Cook of DeFuniak Springs was adjusting her sitting position, and she fell off, FHP said.
Cook was flown by helicopter to Sacred Heart Hospital with serious injuries.
FHP was still investigating the accident later Saturday.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
