<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:24:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two charged after burglary spree</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/two-charged-after-burglary-spree-1.484317</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two charged after burglary spree
Jonathan Hill and Joshua Gay
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, May 28, 2015 at 09:24 PM.
JAY - Two men from Jay have been arrested in connection with a business burglary spree May 20.
Several businesses, including Farmers Country Market, Exprezit and Jacks Vapor Store were burglarized, according to the Santa Rosa County Sheriff's Office.
Two people were seen on surveillance footage in the businesses taking items.
Witnesses reported seeing items from the stores at various locations and reported it. Two men, 25-year-old Jonathan Richard Hill and 18-year-old Joshua Ryder Gay, were questioned and arrested.
They are charged with two counts of criminal mischief of more than $200 but less than $1,000; one count of criminal mischief over $1,000; one count of burglary with damage over $1,000; two counts of burglary; two counts of larceny of more than $300 but less than $5,000; and one count of petit theft.
Gay also is charged with possession of burglarious tools.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:41:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gaetz considering U.S. House run</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/election-news/gaetz-considering-u-s-house-run-1.484105</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Gaetz considering U.S. House run
Florida Sen. Don Gaetz
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, May 28, 2015 at 04:41 PM.
State Sen. Don Gaetz will not be running to replace Marco Rubio in the U.S. Senate.
Dont be surprised though to see his name among the Republican candidates vying to replace U.S. Rep. Jeff Miller as the next congressman from Northwest Florida.
That is, if Miller opts to seek Rubios seat.
Gaetz, R-Niceville, said that by his calculations there are about 530 days left between now and the Senate election, which isnt a lot of time for a candidate with limited statewide name recognition to properly politic.
In order for me to be a credible statewide candidate I would have to spend every day between now and election day introducing myself to people across Florida, he said. That would require me having to resign my seat in the state Senate.
Gaetz said he has no interest in leaving the senate before he terms out in 2016 and hes unwilling to put his 500,000 constituents through a costly special election.
If asked why I was leaving the senate, the only truthful answer I could give would be that I was resigning to pursue a political campaign, he said. I believe resigning my seat to do that is wasteful and wrong.
He said hed support his fellow conservative Republican should Miller decide to pursue Rubios seat, and will hold off announcing plans on a run for Floridas first district congressional seat until he knows there will be a vacancy.
Gaetz called the House seat, which serves Okaloosa, Santa Rosa, Walton, Escambia and a slice of Holmes counties a different kettle of fish for him as a candidate for office.
I have at one time or another represented every area of the First Congressional District as it is presently drawn, he said.
He also said he would not have to resign from the state senate to run for the U.S. House.
Gaetz is the second man, and the second state senator, to say he is seriously considering a run for the U.S. House in Northwest Florida. State Sen. Greg Evers, R-Baker, has said theres no doubt he will go after Millers old job if Miller chooses to ask voters for a new one.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:33:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of threatening to blow up police during arrest</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-accused-of-threatening-to-blow-up-police-during-arrest-1.484095</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of threatening to blow up police during arrest
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Thursday, May 28, 2015 at 04:33 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS  A 47-year-old DeFuniak Springs man is in custody after allegedly threatening to blow the house up while officers tried to take him into custody.
Christopher J. Mars was wanted on a warrant for sexual battery on an under-aged mentally handicapped person, according to a media release from DeFuniak Springs Police Department.
When officers went to a home on Nowling Drive around noon Thursday to take him into custody, he spat on them and said if they touched him, he'd blow the house up, the release said.
Mars had what appeared to be a television remote in his hand when he made the threat.
He continued to resist officers and was eventually subdued with a Taser before being taken into custody, according to the release.
He was taken to Healthmark Regional Medical Center for evaluation before being taken to jail.
Mars is charged with sexual battery, as well as resisting arrest without violence, threatening to set off a destructive device and two counts of battery on a law enforcement officer.
His bond is set at $1 million.
Because of the threats, Bay County Sheriff's Office Bomb Squad and Walton County Sheriff's Office responded to assist in the case.
As of 2 p.m., the bomb squad was still clearing the residence.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:28:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>7th Special Forces soldier charged with sexual assault of a minor</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/7th-soldier-charged-with-sexual-assault-of-a-minor-1.484091</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>7th Special Forces soldier charged with sexual assault of a minor
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Thursday, May 28, 2015 at 04:28 PM.
CRESTVIEW  A 19-year-old 7th Special Forces soldier was arrested Wednesday on charges of sexually assaulting a minor.
Tyler Dean Smith is accused of having sex with a girl who reported that she asked him to stop and to get off of her, according to the arrest report from Crestview Police Department.
Smith and the girl, whose age is not in the report to protect her identity, were reportedly seen kissing in the back of a truck by mutual acquaintances on Dec. 12.
Later that night, the girl fell asleep while she, Smith and two mutual acquaintances were watching television.
She said when she woke up, Smith was touching her and she tried to push him off, but was unable to do so, the report said.
One of the acquaintances, who had left the room, reported that Smith left the bedroom at one point, made the comment, I'm going to try again, and went back into the room, according to the report.
He said Smith came back around 15 minutes after that and gave him the sign for score, the report said.
DNA from the victim's panties was tested by the Florida Department of Law Enforcement lab. On May 26, the test came back as a match to Smith's DNA, the report said.
Smith is charged with sexual assault of a victim over the age of 12 under 18 using physical force.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:21:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gulfarium releases rehabbed turtles (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/gulfarium-releases-rehabbed-turtles-photos-1.484086</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>VIDEO from the release.
Allen McDowell, director of the sea turtle program, said fishing line entanglement is often the reason for injured turtles, but efforts from the Navarre Fishing Pier and the Navarre Beach Sea Turtle Conservation Center have helped get information out to the public.
They continue to raise awareness on what to do...you dont want to just cut the line and let them go, he said. Weve also seen some get hooked and theyre pulled in, but the hook just gets deeper.
What anglers should do, McDowell said, is to catch injured turtles with a net and report the turtles to Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.
On average, the Gulfarium sees 20 to 30 turtles a year for short-term and long-term rehab. Three adult loggerheads and a loggerhead hatching, who is missing a flipper after a fishing line injury, are currently receiving care at the center.
Thursday morning at the Gulf Islands National Seashore, Behrens walked Arugula and OMalley to the shore, one by one, carrying them past the yellow-flag current so they could swim safely away from shore. Each turtle flapped their flippers excitedly as they entered the water.
After working with the turtles, Behrens said the moment was bittersweet.
Its kind of sad, she added. Even the ones that are only here for a short time you bond with. At least I got to play a positive part in their life.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:14:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>City gathers to open Bud and Dorie Day Patriots’ Trail (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/city-gathers-to-open-bud-and-dorie-day-patriots-trail-photos-1.484079</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
City gathers to open Bud and Dorie Day Patriots Trail (PHOTOS)
Dorie Day, right, and her daughters Sandra Hearn, left, and Sonja Lajeunesse react to paver stones on the Bud and Dorie Day Patriots Trail in Fort Walton Beach. The trail officially opened to the public on Thursday.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Thursday, May 28, 2015 at 04:14 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  The new Bud and Dorie Day Patriots Trail is officially open for business.
Community leaders, residents, state and local lawmakers and members of the Day family gathered on Staff Drive on Thursday morning to walk the half-mile path, which connects to Ferry Park.
What a great day here in Fort Walton Beach, said George Day, Jr., speaking to a crowd of more than 100 people. As a family, were very grateful for something that not only uplifts the community but honors dad and mom.
VIDEO from the ceremony.
The day was made even more special because it was the Days 66th wedding anniversary.
State Sen. Don Gaetz, R-Niceville, told the crowd the Days deserve to be honored not only for their patriotism but also as upstanding community members.
We know Bud and Dorie Day as parents and grandparents and neighbors, he said. They are the people who ate in our cafes and joined our clubs. They were the pillars in our churches.
The walking trail, which winds down Staff Drive, Nebraska Avenue and California Drive, features 16 historical markers with information about Bud and Dorie Days life together.
The second phase of the trail project will begin this later this summer when the city demolishes the Docie Bass recreation center. It will be replaced with a courtyard and memorial garden that will serve as the main entrance to the trail.
Fort Walton Beach Mayor Mike Anderson, who made the opening remarks at the ceremony, said the trail is something the entire city can enjoy.
Its not a monument. Its a place of reflection, he said. ... Its all about veterans and their families and recognizing what theyve done for us.
The walking trail was the brainchild of Cissy Wyninegar, president of the Fort Walton Beach Womans Club. She took her idea to the Greater Fort Walton Beach Chamber of Commerce and the city officials in the fall of 2013 and the planning began.
Wyninegar said Thursday she was pleased with the final result and excited about the additions to come.
Its beautiful, she said. Everyone worked so hard to bring this all together.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:30:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Excelling against the odds</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/excelling-against-the-odds-1.484050</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Excelling against the odds
Christian Garner graduated from Rocky Bayou Christian School on Friday. He started there as a fifth grader, and attended the younger grades at what has now become the schools Destin campus.
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, May 28, 2015 at 03:30 PM.
NICEVILLE  After a couple of scares, and a delayed grade from an online class, Christian Garner is proud to say hes a graduate of Rocky Bayou Christian School.
The 17-year-old enrolled at the Niceville campus when he was in fifth grade because he didnt want to have to switch schools over and over again.
I feel like college is going to be a huge step for him, said his mother, Christie Rogers.
At age 5, Christian was diagnosed with a type of autism called Aspergers. A few people at the time told Rogers to lower her hopes for her son, but she didnt.
Instead, she kept him enrolled in private Christian schools and focused on building a future entrenched independence and opportunity for her oldest child.
He joined the band, played soccer and discovered a knack with computers.
By the time he reached high school, Christian was taking the college-prep classes alongside his peers. In fact, until a math class his junior year, he was on-track for the highly-sought Honors diploma.
But that wasnt the defining moment for him. That same year, something magical happened that has longer reaching effects than the type of high school diploma he earns.
For years, Academy counselor Julie Mosley smiled at Christian when she encountered him on campus. Like many with Aspergers, Christian didnt smile back, but Mosley never lost hope.
One day last year, Christian started smiling back.
He started making a few jokes with his peers and let his eyes connect with his teachers when they spoke to him.
I cant really pinpoint exactly what it was, Christian said of the change. This year, I really started thinking about reactions to things.
When he starts college in the fall, Christian isnt sure which local school hell attend, but he knows hell go and that hell finish.
His plan to get a degree in computer science and see where it takes him.
Theres a whole bunch of stuff that could open up, he said.
Look for photos from the graduation in Saturdays newspaper and online at nwfdailynews.com.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Thu May 28 06:22:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two accused of fouling deputy’s watercraft</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/two-accused-of-fouling-deputy-s-watercraft-1.483787</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two accused of fouling deputys watercraft
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 11:22 PM.
MILTON - Two people have been arrested for allegedly damaging a Santa Rosa County Sheriff's Office deputys personal watercraft.
The deputy was patrolling on Coldwater Creek about 2 p.m. Monday when he noticed suspected underage drinkers on a shoal, according to the Sheriff's Office.
He parked his watercraft on the sand to investigate. He then noticed two people with the watercrafts fuel cap, the Sheriffs Office reported.
The two, identified as 20-year-olds Brent Allen Carroll and Spencer Morgan Gonzales, both of Pace, are accused of putting water and sand in the fuel system.
They ran off but were caught by the deputy and bystanders.
Damage was estimated at $1,000.
Both men are charged with felony criminal mischief of $1,000 or more.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Thu May 28 04:36:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two charged with theft of more than $300 of Walmart merchandise</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/two-charged-with-theft-of-more-than-300-of-walmart-merchandise-1.483771</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two charged with theft of more than $300 of Walmart merchandise
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 09:36 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A Fort Walton Beach man and woman are charged with the felony theft of more than $300 of Walmart merchandise.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputies were called on May 16 around 7 a.m. about the theft, according to the arrest report. When they arrived, the loss prevention officer said two people had been stopped trying to take $352.89 of merchandise without paying for it.
The man, identified as 53-year-old Michael Eugene Hunter, left the cart and fled down Clifford Street, the report said. The woman, identified as 65-year-old Florice Cooley Jenkins, allegedly said "I paid for my stuff, he didn't," when stopped.
Video showed both of them driving the car, according to the report. Hunter was found soon after in William's Trailer Court and allegedly admitted to the theft, noting he'd left the items with loss prevention.
Both are charged with theft of more than $300 but less than $5,000.
Both are scheduled to appear in court on June 16.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Thu May 28 04:34:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of attack with shower curtain rod</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-attack-with-shower-curtain-rod-1.483770</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of attack with shower curtain rod
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 09:34 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - An 18-year-old man is charged with using a shower curtain rod while attacking two people who lived with him, one of whom was his mother.
Fort Walton Beach Police officers were called for a family disturbance on May 16 around 3 p.m., according to the arrest report. They arrived to find that the people were reporting that the Fort Walton Beach teen had physically attacked his mother and a man.
The victims and a witness reported the teen had grabbed a shower curtain rod and started striking the man with it for no apparent reason, the report said. When his mother tried to intervene and step between the two, the teen allegedly punched her in the face twice.
They reported that the teen continued to fight with the man, kicking and striking him, according to the report. The man had abrasions on his legs and the teen's mother had abrasions on both sides of her face.
The teen is charged with simple battery.
His next scheduled court date is June 2.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Thu May 28 04:32:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of disturbance at Applebee's</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-disturbance-at-applebee-s-1.483766</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of disturbance at Applebee's
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 09:32 PM.
CRESTVIEW - A 32-year-old Bronson man is accused of yelling and causing a disturbance at Applebee's, 215 Raspberry Road.
Crestview Police officers were called around 7 p.m. on May 16, according to the arrest report. The caller said that the man came into the restaurant and began yelling and cursing at customers and employees.
The man was asked to leave several times before he did, the report said. He then allegedly started opening car doors in the parking lot, throwing money on a random driver who was sitting in one of the cars.
He refused to leave the property, so officers were called, according to the report. Officers wrote that the man was "sweating profusely" and appeared to be under the influence of an unknown substance.
He is charged with disorderly conduct.
His next scheduled court date is June 2.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 00:54:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputy hit by car while crossing road</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/deputy-hit-by-car-while-crossing-road-1.483704</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deputy hit by car while crossing road
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 05:54 PM.
MIRAMAR BEACH - A Walton County sheriff's deputy reportedly is in good spirits after he was hit by a car while walking across Scenic Highway 98 in a crosswalk.
Deputy Eric Traugott was hit by a car in front of the Majestic Sun, according to the Sheriff's Office.
He called dispatch himself to report that he had been hit. South Walton Fire Rescue responded.
He was taken to Sacred Heart Hospital on the Emerald Coast with pain to his knee and hand, the sheriff's office reported.
The Florida Highway Patrol is investigating.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:52:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UPDATE: Accident shuts down Mid-Bay Bridge for hours</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/update-accident-shuts-down-mid-bay-bridge-for-hours-1.483621</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
UPDATE: Accident shuts down Mid-Bay Bridge for hours
Chip Tarter of Niceville escaped unharmed when his Chevrolet pickup flipped in a four-vehicle collision on the Mid-Bay Bridge.
LASHAWN WILLIAMS | Special to the Daily News
By TOM McLAUGHILN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:52 PM.
North and southbound lanes on the Mid-Bay Bridge were closed for about two hours Wednesday after a four-vehicle collision caused a pickup truck to overturn.
The initial 911 call of a flipped vehicle in the south bound lanes of the bridge came in at 8:48 a.m., according to Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office spokeswoman Michele Nicholson.
Florida Highway Patrol troopers were dispatched to the scene of the wreck at 8:53 a.m. and arrived 15 minutes later, according to the FHP website.
Highway patrol spokesman Lt. Steve Preston announced the bridge had been reopened at 10:42 a.m.
The accident happened, according to the FHP report, when a pickup traveling behind the one that flipped failed to stop.
The impact to the first truck, driven by Chip Tarter, 47, of Niceville, caused it to strike the raised concrete barrier wall and roll onto its roof, according to the report.
After the initial impact and rollover, Tarters truck hit a third vehicle, the report said, and the pickup responsible for the initial accident, driven by Kraig Crossley of Milton, struck a trailer being towed by a fourth truck.
No one was injured in the accident. Crossley has been charged with reckless driving.
According to numbers provided by the Mid-Bay Bridge Authority, about 20,000 motor vehicles pass through the bridges toll plaza on May 27 each year. About 7,000 of those cross between the hours of 9 a.m. and 2 p.m.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:51:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Walton couple wins wedding of their dreams (VIDEO, PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/south-walton-couple-wins-wedding-of-their-dreams-video-photos-1.483620</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
South Walton couple wins wedding of their dreams (VIDEO, PHOTOS)
Kendra Davis and Vince Marasa, right, stand in the doorway of their Santa Rosa Beach home Wednesday as they learn they had won the Walton Area Chamber of Commerces Emerald Coast Wedding Contest.
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:51 PM.
SANTA ROSA BEACH  If youve seen one of those Publishers Clearing House commercials where they surprise the sweepstakes winner with balloons and a big check, youve got a pretty good idea what life was like at Kendra Davis and Vince Marasas house on Wednesday afternoon.
A swarm of media and members of the Walton County Chamber Wedding &amp; Event Council descended on their house with balloons, flowers, champagne and a cake to notify the couple that they were the winners of the councils inaugural Destination Wedding Contest.
Click here to see more photos.
The surprise announcement was the fulfillment of a dream for Davis and Marasa, who entered the contest at the urging of their friend and neighbor, Lindsay Shropshire.
I dont even know what to say, Davis said as she and Marasa embraced Shropshire and Marasas mother, Sherry Compton, in a group hug. What a wonderful way to start our life together!
Davis and Marasa were one of three finalist couples in the contest, which provides the winner with a $25,000 all-inclusive wedding package on Miramar Beach.
Out of 67 entrants from across the country, the three finalists were selected to create a video about their love story, which was posted on the Wedding &amp; Event Councils Facebook page. Supporters were invited to go online and like their favorite video.
While the finalists were selected by the council, the ultimate winner was the choice of the voters, said Nathan Wilson, the owner of 654-LIMO and the chairman of the council.
As the only local couple in the finals, Davis and Marasa were competing against a couple from Georgia and another from Arizona. In the end, they edged out the second place couple by approximately 300 votes. The contest drew more than 40,000 visitors to the councils Facebook page.
I know Im partial, but I really do think they were the most deserving couple, Compton said. We have all been working to pull together support for them, and it paid off.
Davis, a fifth-generation Northwest Florida resident, credited her familys deep roots in the community for their success.
We are so grateful to everyone who supported us, she said.
Marasa agreed. Were really looking forward to serving as ambassadors for this great area, he added. We live in paradise, and were proud to let people know what a great place this is to live and work and play in.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:48:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Medical marijuana passes last hurdle in Florida (DOCUMENT)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/medical-marijuana-passes-last-hurdle-in-florida-document-1.483614</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Medical marijuana passes last hurdle in Florida (DOCUMENT)
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:48 PM.
An administrative law judge has given the go ahead for the growth and distribution of so-called compassionate cannabis in Florida.
In a ruling announced Wednesday, Judge W. David Watkins supported the framework established by the Florida Department of Health for providing non-euphoric marijuana to those with medical needs.
He called the Departments second effort to develop the regulatory platform for the implementation of the states Compassionate Medical Cannabis Act well reasoned, deliberative and thorough.
DOCUMENT: final order
It represents a rational and coherent regulatory framework, Watkins said.
State Rep. Matt Gaetz, a leading advocate for compassionate cannabis, said the judges ruling removes the last legal obstacle the law, which was passed in 2014, faced.
I suspect applications will go out in the next 21 days for licenses to legally grow low-THC cannabis in the state of Florida, Gaetz, R-Fort Walton Beach, said.
As written, the law will allow the distribution of non-euphoric medical marijuana to children suffering debilitating seizures as well as to adults suffering some forms of cancer, Parkinsons Disease, Alzheimers, ALS, multiple sclerosis and post-traumatic stress disorder.
Gaetz said it could still be three to four months before seeds are planted, product is grown and oil is extracted, for distribution.
But now were talking about three to four months rather than facing litigation for the next three to four years, he said.
The Health Departments second set of rules governing growth and distribution of the non-euphoric was challenged by Baywood Nurseries of Apopka.
The nursery charged the rules were an invalid exercise of delegated legislative authority that would illegally modify provisions of the Compassionate Medical Cannabis Act.
Asked to respond to the ruling Raymond Hogshead, owner of Baywood Nurseries, said the judge has ruled and offered no further comment.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:45:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>‘This is the big time’ Navarre resident heads to Nashville for CMA Festival</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/this-is-the-big-time-navarre-resident-heads-to-nashville-for-cma-festival-1.483608</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
This is the big time Navarre resident heads to Nashville for CMA Festival
Cortni Bird outside her home in Navarre. The singer/songwriter will be performing at the CMA Fest June 11 through 14.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:45 PM.
NAVARRE  Cortni Bird is ready to rock and roll... again.
The 24-year-old singer/songwriter hasnt been on the stage for nearly three years, but when she was asked to perform at next months County Music Awards Festival in Nashville, she didnt hesitate to say yes.
This is the big time  I couldnt say no, she said.
Bird  formally Potapowicz before she was married in March  grew up singing to the radio and writing poetry. When she was 7, her parents noticed her talent as she sang along to No Doubts Tragic Kingdom album.
In 2010, she recorded an EP titled Its Complicated, featuring five original songs she penned throughout high school and college.
These are songs I wanted to listen to, but couldnt find on the radio, she said. They were written about my life experiences...and other peoples experiences.
Its Complicated ranges from alternative rock to pop with some modern country mixed in. Bird admits shes a little more rock and roll than country, but is looking forward to adding a new element to the CMA festival next month.
My music is just me, she said with a laugh. I think countrys evolving and I can bring something different.
After she graduated college in 2011, she went on a small tour of the east coast.
It was the biggest high I have ever experienced, she said. It didnt seem real.
After the tour, Bird went to back to the real world. She left her hometown in Rainbow City, Alabama, and moved to Navarre, where she got a job at a local staffing agency. Is the CMA Fest a second chance for a music career?
Id love to be on tour full time, but Im just going by my faith, she said.
Bird does know that she doesnt want to take another three-year hiatus again. Shes in the process of planning a music festival for Navarre called Country on the Sound in September.
I am so pumped to be performing again, she said. But really  just send me outdoors with a piece of paper and something to write with and Im fine.
WANT TO LISTEN: Hear Cortni Birds EP on Spotify at open.spotify.com/artist/4K39C0rErNahJ0gv5xqeib . You can also download Its Complicated on iTunes.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>4 sentenced on home invasion charges</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/4-sentenced-on-home-invasion-charges-1.483607</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>4 sentenced on home invasion charges
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:44 PM.
Photo Galleries
Home invasion
GULF BREEZE  Three men and a woman were sentenced Tuesday for their involvement in a home invasion robbery and high speed chase.
Robert Falcon Fraser, Teandre Lanell Altman, Frank Anthony Rogers and Holly Elizabeth Caudle were sentenced by Judge John Simon.
The four were charged after an Aug. 26 incident in which a Gulf Breeze man met Caudle at his home after meeting her while looking for a female companion on Craigslist.
The four robbed the man of 15 guns, cash and a large quantity of ammunition, according to previous reports.
Once they left the home, they got into a high speed chase with law enforcement in Santa Rosa and Escambia counties before abandoning their vehicle and eventually getting caught.
Fraser was sentenced to 30 years in prison, to be served concurrent to the 262 months he was sentenced to for federal charges stemming from the same case.
Caudle was sentenced to 20 years in prison for her part.
Altman and Rogers were each sentenced to 15 years in prison to be served consecutive to the federal sentences they previously received.
In January, a federal judge sentenced Altman to 200 months and Rogers to 121 months.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Trista Pruett at 850-315-4445 or tpruett@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @TristaPnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Valparaiso reaches decision on private docks</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/valparaiso-reaches-decision-on-private-docks-1.483572</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Valparaiso reaches decision on private docks
Paul and Britt Walker talk about some of the frustrations they have had dealing with the City of Valparaiso over the dock across from their house on Bayshore Drive.
File photo
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:04 PM.
VALPARAISO  After hearing from a roomful of people who are unhappy with the citys policies regarding private dock ownership on public land, the City Commission voted Tuesday to make some changes.
For the past month, the city has been involved in a dispute with Paul and Britt Walker of North Bayshore Drive over the ownership and the right to maintain the dock that sits on city-owned shoreline across the street from their house. Last month, the Walkers received a notice that recent repairs to their dock were illegal, in part because the city said that they do not have the required encroachment agreement to build on public property.
The Walkers, who dispute the citys findings, were originally set to have their case heard before special magistrate J. Bruce Bowman on May 20. The hearing was postponed, however, when Bowman recused himself after the Walkers expressed concern that he had a conflict of interest. Bowman is a law partner of city attorney Hayward Dykes
The city then scheduled a special commission meeting to address issues regarding private dock ownership in general, which has been a controversial subject for several years. A large contingent of citizens spoke in support of the Walkers, and questioned the citys policies regarding docks.
There seems to be a number of conflicting city ordinances leading to confusion, said North Bayshore Drive resident Bill Cunningham. Hopefully we can get one clear directive, instead of suddenly enforcing rules that have not been enforced in the past.
City Commissioner Joe Morgan, who is working on a new ordinance to address dock ownership issues, wanted to be clear that the commission would not change the laws overnight.
The truth is, weve had lapses in enforcing encroachment agreements in the past, due to issues on both sides, he said. But I recognize that we need to do something to clarify this issue.
Morgan put forward a motion that would instruct the city administrator and the citys code enforcement officials to allow current dock owners to perform normal repair and maintenance of docks, and to renew their encroachment agreements if necessary. The motion was approved 4-1, with Mayor Bruce Arnold dissenting.
Although it hasnt been determined if the commissions decision means that her hearing has been canceled, Britt Walker expressed cautious optimism after the meeting.
I certainly feel better than I did before, she said. Im very grateful to all of my neighbors for showing up and supporting us.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Wed May 27 23:00:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First batch of STEMM students wrapping up final weeks (VIDEO)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/first-batch-of-stemm-students-wrapping-up-final-weeks-1.483567</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
First batch of STEMM students wrapping up final weeks (VIDEO)
Christopher Loffler, right, and Frankie Muldowney, glue together pieces for an earthquake proof structure during class on Wednesday at the STEMM Academy in Valparaiso. The school will be graduating the first group of students who have attended class for all three years of middle school.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 04:00 PM.
VALPARAISO  Three school years ago, a group of students and parents took a chance on a new Okaloosa County middle school.
Today, almost all of those first students are wrapping up their final weeks at the Okaloosa STEMM Academy.
Im glad I took the chance, said 14-year-old Sydney Lederman. It let me take more advanced classes.
VIDEO: See the STEMM kids launch a rocket.
The Science, Technology, Engineering, Math and Medical-focused program was designed to provide hands-on experience as well as advanced classes for students with a passion for math and science.
Jewel LaCross wanted to play sports and attend the STEMM Academy. She was able to play softball at Meigs, but her parents had to drive her there for practice.
Between balancing her school work and softball, shes gotten very good at time management and isnt worried about enrolling in Choctawhatchee High Schools International Baccalaureate program in high school.
Its all worth it, the 14-year-old said. It so is.
Of the 61 eighth graders at the school, 53 attended it in the first year, said Assistant Principal Neely Calhoun.
The upcoming freshman class already has 69 students enrolled.
People are starting to hear about us, Calhoun said. The biggest misconception about this school is that its a private school.
Last week, officials from the Florida Department of Education paid a visit to the school. Before leaving, they told Calhoun the academy would serve as the states model for science, technology, engineering and math schools.
Eighth-grader Christopher Loffler said the first year wasnt without issue, but it was worth the growing pains.
They keep working on making it better and better, he said.
His classmate Frankie Muldowney, urged the incoming students to be patient during the adjustment to middle school and the rigor of classes at the STEMM Academy.
Its a big change, the 13-year-old said.
With a growing student body, the school plans to add new programs and classes for students next year, Calhoun said.
Among the new options will be an music technology class focused on Apples Garage Band and more opportunities for students to earn industry certifications.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Wed May 27 19:29:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Five reasons to have “A Cold One with the Commissioner”</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/five-reasons-to-have-a-cold-one-with-the-commissioner-1.483428</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Five reasons to have A Cold One with the Commissioner
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2015 at 12:29 PM.
NICEVILLE  Okaloosa County Commissioner Nathan Boyles tries to meet quarterly with his constituents in an informal setting. These gatherings, sometimes called Coffee with the Commissioner or A Cold One with the Commissioner, attract local residents who are eager to share their thoughts on a myriad of subjects.
On Tuesday, a few dozen folks made their way to Ernies Dockside Caf. These were some of their issues:
Birds, not boardwalks: Valparaiso resident Wendy Green wanted Boyles to know how strongly she feels about the plan to build more boardwalks at Veterans Park on Okaloosa Island.
We have documented 32 herons nests there at the site, and we believe building those boardwalks will disturb them, Green said. I want to urge the county commissioners to reconsider the plan, because it wont add any value to the park, and it will damage the habitat for the wildlife that people are hoping to see when they visit there.
A troubled bridge over local waters: Fort Walton Beach residents Tom Downey and former county commissioner Jackie Burkett are tired of the seemingly endless debate over where to build a new bridge between Fort Walton Beach and Okaloosa Island.
The congestion in downtown Fort Walton Beach has to be addressed, Downey said. These long delays are just making things worse.
Someone needs to make a decision, one way or another, added Burkett. Weve been discussing this since I was in office. Instead of paying for these expensive studies that just delay the process, we need to choose a solution and implement it. Someones going to be unhappy, no matter what you do.
Economy over environment: Bluewater Bay resident Mitch Newton came to the meeting to discuss the RESTORE Act, and the funding the county will receive as a result of the 2010 BP oil spill.
Im hoping that the funding will be used for projects that will address the economic losses our community suffered, he said. Thats where our area was affected the most, unlike areas to the west of us.
A stinky subject: Don and Maurie Ockerman came in search of some straight talk on sewers. The Lake Pippin residents are adamantly opposed to a plan to install a sewer system that would include lift stations in their neighborhood.
Everyone in our subdivision has septic tanks, and weve never had any problems, Don Ockerman said. We are afraid that installing lift stations will threaten Lake Pippin, which to our knowledge has never had any pollution problems. You hear about lift stations failing all the time when theres power outages or heavy rains. We dont want that.
Centennial crusade: Bluewater Bay resident Steve Czonstka stopped by to lobby for more funding for the Heritage Museum of Northwest Florida. As the chairman of the museums board of trustees, he wanted to remind everyone that Okaloosa Countys 100 anniversary is approaching.
These are for sale at the museum, he said as he modeled a commemorative T-shirt.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
