<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="nwfdailynews">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 04:11:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Crestview Confederate flag coming down</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crestview-confederate-flag-coming-down-1.495837</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Crestview Confederate flag coming down
By By Tom McLaughlin
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 09:11 PM.

CRESTVIEW -- The descendants of Bill Lundy may have come up with a proposal to allow the dignified removal of the Confederate Flag from near the Okaloosa County Courthouse.
Family members have agreed to remove a memorial to Lundy, believed to have been the second longest living Civil War veteran, to private land, according to a release issued Monday by Crestview Mayor David Cadle.
The memorial is not the property of the City of Crestview and the Lundy family can claim possession, Cadle said in his release.
Okaloosa Countys NAACP leadership has been calling for years for the Confederate flag to be removed from its present location at East First Avenue and State Road 85.
A petition was circulated again this year following the racially motivated massacre of nine African-American churchgoers in Charleston S.C.
Current local chapter President Ray Nelson said though the NAACP did not directly participate in negotiations between the city and Lundy family, the end result did not shock him.
It wasnt a big surprise, I was expecting to hear it, Nelson said.
Nelson said he had spoken to Cadle Monday afternoon. The mayor couldnt be reached for comment later in the day.
Nelson said, and the news release confirmed, that details of the memorial being moved are still being ironed out.
Nelson said he has proposed that the flag itself be removed immediately while moving the memorial structure is discussed.
The problem was not with the memorial, but with the flag itself, he said.
With a compromise reached, Cadle also announced that a special meeting of the Crestview City Council, scheduled for 5:30 p.m., Tuesday, would be called off.
According to the news release the Lundy memorial was on Okaloosa County land until a Highway Patrol office was erected and the city permitted the memorial to be moved to its current location.
Daily News records indicate the memorial was originally erected in 1958, one year after Lundys death.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:06:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman arrested after attack with stiletto</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-arrested-after-attack-with-stiletto-1.494150</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman arrested after attack with stiletto
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 09:06 PM.
NICEVILLE - A 21-year-old Niceville woman is in custody after a warrant was issued due to charges that she attacked her boyfriend with a stiletto.
The woman, who is not being named to attack the victim's identity, was arrested on June 7.
The attack occurred on March 28, around 6:30 p.m., according to the arrest report. She and her boyfriend were reportedly living together in a room at Tisa's Friendly Inn.
The woman hit her boyfriend in the head with the heel of a four-inch stiletto shoe, the report said. He was treated for a three-inch wound to his head.
The wound went through the skin stopping at the skull (approximately three centimeters deep) and required six staples to close, a doctor reported to Niceville Police officers. A witness told police that the woman repeatedly said, "I did not mean to hurt him."
She is charged with aggravated battery causing great bodily harm.
Her next scheduled court date is July 27.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:50:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>FHP: 1 person suffered serious injuries in bus crash</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/fhp-1-person-suffered-serious-injuries-in-bus-crash-1.494417</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>FHP: 1 person suffered serious injuries in bus crash
Stock photography
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:50 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS  One passenger on a church bus that crashed on Interstate 10 on Friday suffered serious injuries, according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Madison Brennan, 18, of Pineville, La., was taken to Sacred Heart Hospital in Pensacola, the FHP reported Saturday.
Brennan was one of 21 people who were taken to several hospitals after the 2010 Ford bus crashed at 2:50 p.m. just west of U.S. Highway 331.
The bus was traveling east when it veered off the highway and hit two trees, according to the FHP. The driver, 50-year-old Derek Griffin of Pineville, apparently lost control on a slight curve in the road.
The bus was carrying 23 passengers ranging from 15 to 18 years old.
Griffin, who suffered minor injuries, was one of seven people who were taken to Healthmark Regional Medical Center in DeFuniak Springs.
The other 13 passengers who were hurt were taken to Twin Cities Hospital in Niceville, North Okaloosa Medical Center in Crestview and Sacred Heart Hospital on the Emerald Coast in Miramar Beach.
Emergency responders said Friday that none of the injuries was life-threatening. No further details were available from the hospitals Saturday.
The bus, which sustained $10,000 in damage, was traveling with another bus and a passenger van from the church. The FHP report did not identify the church.
Passengers in the other vehicles were taken to the DeFuniak Springs Community Center after the accident.
The FHP said Saturday that its investigation was continuing.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 01:04:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/photos-car-accident-at-beal-and-crewilla-1.495819</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 06:04 PM.
A car accident at the intersection of Beal Parkway and Crewilla Drive tied up traffic Monday afternoon. Nobody was injured in the wreck.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:57:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of theft of 12-pack of Corona Light</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-theft-of-12-pack-of-corona-light-1.494149</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of theft of 12-pack of Corona Light
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 08:57 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 46-year-old Fort Walton Beach man is charged with taking a 12-pack of Corona Light from a Circle K.
The man went into the store at around 3 p.m. on June 8, according to the arrest report. He picked up a 12-pack of beer and allegedly walked out of the store without paying.
He was caught on security footage and was identified by a witness, the report said.
He is charged with petit theft.
His next scheduled court date is June 30.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:30:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Local homicides are up in 2015</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/local-homicides-are-up-in-2015-1.494415</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Local homicides are up in 2015
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:30 PM.
In the past six months, Santa Rosa and Okaloosa Counties have seen what seems, anecdotally, to be a spike in violence, with five homicides and a non-fatal shooting between three departments.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office shared some numbers, noting that crime had actually gone down in the last couple of years.
There was a 55 percent increase from 2009 to 2010 and another 15 percent increase from 2011 to 2012.
However, 2013 brought an increase in the budget and a drop in violent crime of more than 10 percent, they said.
Violent crime went down another 3 percent in 2014.
We are tremendously concerned anytime any one is a victim of violent crime, said Okaloosa County Sheriff Larry Ashley. An ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure. We need resources to work to prevent crime, not just react. We have the same manpower levels we had in 2007.
Below is a look back at each shooting by department:
Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office
The first shooting was that of 18-year-old Mark Anthony Williams, whose body was seen by a passing motorist along the wood line of State Road 85 South of Duke Field on Jan. 21.
His body was autopsied and Williams was found to have died from a gunshot wound, Okaloosa County Sheriffs Department announced less than a week later.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office spokesperson Michele Nicholson said Friday they are still waiting on some forensics results from the Florida Department of Law Enforcement Lab.
However, she said they are constantly working on the case, re-interviewing people and reviewing evidence.
The second from Okaloosa County was more recent.
On June 24, residents around a Marty Lane mobile home heard multiple gunshots around 5:20 a.m. When deputies arrived, they found 39-year-old Jimmy Lee Dodds body outside of his mobile home.
Investigators brought in K-9s, and Dodds body was taken in for autopsy.
Both deaths remain under investigation.
As these are all active criminal investigations, we are not able to release additional details publicly. We do not want to jeopardize any of the evidence weve gathered to this point, Nicholson said Friday.
The Sheriffs Office is also investigating a non-fatal shooting on Carmel Drive on June 18.
The Sheriffs Office reported that two men were shot by a homeowner during an attempted home invasion. One of the men later told deputies that hed had no idea the other was going to attempt to break into a home.
Both men were hospitalized later that day with gunshots wounds.
No charges have been filed against anyone.
The Sheriff's Office reported two homicides in 2014: the man charged with killing his mother in Mary Esther and the woman charged with killing her newborn in Fort Walton Beach.
She noted that they have also had two men arrested for attempted murder this year, both in the first full week of May.
We are actively working both the Williams and Dodd murder cases as well as the Carmel Drive shooting as vigorously as possible, Nicholson said. We want to continue to encourage anyone with information, no matter how minor they think it is, to contact our agency either via a call to the OCSO at 850-651-7400 or through Emerald Coast Crime Stoppers at 850-863-TIPS.
Fort Walton Beach Police Department
Fort Walton Beach added two homicides in less than a week to those numbers.
Fort Walton Beach Police Capt. Tom Matz noted that last year, there were no homicides in the city departments jurisdiction.
On June 11, late in the evening, a man heard a single gunshot outside of his Cape Drive residence.
He looked out the window to find that Randy Campbell, also known as Randy Shareef Ali, was dead outside.
At the time, Police Chief Ted Litzchauer said people of interest had been identified and were being interviewed.
Less than a week later, on June 17, 89-year-old Freddie Cason was shot and killed in the home hed lived in for more than 40 years.
A man then barricaded himself in the home until eventually surrendering to police. He was interviewed multiple times as a person of interest before being released.
Matz said there is not believed to be any connection between the two.
Were concerned about all homicides, he said. We respond the same way on each homicide. We devote all available resources towards the investigation in seeking the truth.
He said they had no updates to release on either case as of Friday, but said citizens should know law enforcement is doing all they can to address all crime issues.
The citizens should remain cognizant, keeping aware of the activities around them at all times, Matz said. Please remember it takes a partnership between the citizens and law enforcement to address crime.
He asked that anyone with information about either case call the department at 833-9546 or Emerald Coast Crime Stoppers.
Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office
In Santa Rosa County, 43-year-old Stephen Richmond Rice was found dead in his home on Persimmon Hollow Road on March 26.
Soon after his body was discovered, Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office said hed been dead for an undetermined amount of time and foul play was suspected.
On April 29, they asked for any former customers of Rice, who ran a business via the internet and person to person sales, to come forward.
The believed one of his customers might have information that could assist in the homicide investigation.
On Thursday, Sheriffs Office spokesperson Sgt. Rich Aloy said that Santa Rosa County had not had an increase in homicides.
He declined to comment further, but did encourage anyone with information to call Det. Gary Baney at 850-983-1296 or Santa Rosa County Crime Stoppers at 850-437-STOP.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
COMMENTS
PHOTOS: Car accident at Beal and Crewilla By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
http://www.nwfdailynews.com July 6, 2015 18:4
A car accident at the intersection of Beal Parkway and Crewilla Drive tied up traffic Monday afternoon. Nobody was injured in the wreck.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:08:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The highs and lows of July 4th weekend</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/the-highs-and-lows-of-july-4th-weekend-1.495781</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:55:31 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of stomping on woman's chest after argument over food</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-stomping-on-woman-s-chest-after-argument-over-food-1.494147</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of stomping on woman's chest after argument over food
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 08:55 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 29-year-old man is accused of stomping on his wife's chest after an argument over leftovers.
Fort Walton Beach Police officers were called to the home around 12:30 a.m. on June 8, according to the arrest report. The man and his wife had been drinking and got into an argument.
The wife said that her husband had been eating her leftover food in the kitchen and she got upset, the report said. She said she went into the kitchen and threw the food on to the floor.
At that point, she said they started arguing and her husband "pushed" her "to the ground" and "stomped on her chest," according to the report. She had redness on her sternum.
The man said the argument was only verbal and denied any physical altercation, the report said.
He is charged with misdemeanor battery.
His next scheduled court date is June 30.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:23:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Amateur radio operators show off their hobby at annual Field Day (PHOTOS,VIDEO)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/amateur-radio-operators-show-off-their-hobby-at-annual-field-day-photos-video-1.494413</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>The highs and lows of July 4th weekend
Hundreds of boaters crowded into the shallows of crab island near Destin on July Fourth.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
<<<<<<< HEAD
By KARI C. BARLOW and KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 04:08 PM.
The Fourth of July holiday weekend was, by all accounts, a hot, crowded, bumper-to-bumper success on the Emerald Coast.
Tens of thousands of tourists filled up local beaches, hotels and restaurants across Santa Rosa, Okaloosa and Walton counties.
The influx of visitors also posed challenges for law enforcement, including reckless driving, vehicle crashes and fireworks mishaps.
Keep reading for a wrap-up of the holiday weekend.
Stop-and-roll traffic
Traffic over the weekend was heavy, especially in southern Okaloosa County.
From early Friday to Sunday evening, congestion on U.S. Highway 98 was a common sight in Destin. A handful of crashes further slowed the commute.
No accidents involving pedestrians occurred despite the constant flow of weekend events in the Worlds Luckiest Fishing Village.
The Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office reported 27 traffic crashes, including two on the Mid-Bay Bridge. It had 17 calls for reckless drivers and another nine for intoxicated drivers, according to spokeswoman Michele Nicholson.
Nine car burglaries were reported in Okaloosa County and four vehicle thefts, she said.
In Walton County, U.S. 98 was particularly congested around the Silver Sands Premium Outlets as throngs of tourists opted for shopping during the rain, said Jim Bagby, executive director of the Walton County Tourist Development Council.
No major traffic crashes were reported, said Corey Dobridnia, a spokeswoman for the Walton County Sheriffs Office.
During a multi-agency checkpoint on U.S. Highway 98 in Fort Walton Beach, law enforcement made 27 arrests, but only two were for driving under the influence, according to Capt. Bill Royal with the Fort Walton County Police Department.
Officers cited one driver for not having a child properly restrained, but issued no other seat belt violations. The remaining charges were drug possession, driving with a suspended, or nonexistent license, and no proof of registration.
Pretty well packed
Visitors were highly visible on Navarre Beach during the holiday weekend, said Julie Morgan, director of the Santa Rosa County Tourist Development Council.
They were using our bike path, she said. They were walking and jogging. ... I know Juanas was busy and the pier was busy. I feel like it was very successful.
In Okaloosa County, most hotels and resorts were filled to overflowing.
There were very few, if any, lodging accommodations available, said Ed Schroeder, tourism director for the county. It was pretty well packed out.
The best part was hundreds of tourists taking advantage of local events at Fort Walton Landing and the Destin Harbor, he said.
Folks really got out and enjoyed the community, Schroeder said. There are very few areas that have what we offer.
South Waltons crowds likely set some records, Bagby said.
It was a fabulous weekend, even with the rain, he said. People were really well behaved. ... We think this will be our strongest ever June and our strongest ever July. Things are looking good.
Faulty fireworks
Destin saw three small fires related to the holiday celebrations, according to Destin Fire Department Battalion Chief James Taylor.
The first call came in around 9:20 p.m. Friday for two brush fires beside Destin Commons caused by a fireworks, he said.
Taylor said the fireworks ignited two different fires in the brush between the Commons and Regatta Bay. By the time they were extinguished, about an acre and half had burned.
As far as we know, (the firework) was ours, said Bob Perry, the general manager of the Commons.
Fire watchers brought in by Destin Commons were the first to spot the initial fire, Perry said. The Commons stations watchers on the property any time it shoots off fireworks, he added.
The third fire occurred near Destin Pointe, which a firework set some sea oats aflame, Taylor said.
No other firework-related mishaps were reported by public safety officials in the area.
The blessing of the weekend is we had plenty of rain, said Fort Walton Police Department Capt. Bill Royal.
Every agency said it received a number of calls related to illegal fireworks, but no one was citied or charged.
Generally, you show up, and they stop, said Sgt. Rich Aloy, a spokesman for the Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
=======
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:23 PM.
HURLBURT FIELD You cant count on phone lines or other ways to communicate during a hurricane or other natural disaster.
Thats when ham radio operators step up.
For us to ask for help, provide communication with the outside world, let your family know youre okay, this is how its going to be done, Mo Hodgdon,chairman of the Playground Amateur Radio Clubs annual Field Day, said as he sat in front of a radio powered by a battery.
For more photos, click here.
Field Day is an exercise for amateur radio operators to make as many contacts across North America as possible. About 10 operators monitored the radio wavesSaturdayat stations set up on tables at Hurlburt Fields picnic area.
Well be making some (contacts) with Morse code. Well be making some with digital. Well be making some with voice, or what we call phone, Hodgdon said.
For a video, click here.
He expected to make 300 to 400 contacts between1 p.m.Saturdayand10 a.m.today.
The Field Day also gave people not familiar with the radios a chance to see them in action and send out some signals with supervision from PARC members.
Hodgdon said hes been able to contact radio operators in France, Japan and Australia over the years. He hoped to try contact with the International Space Stationon Saturdayevening.
Some places youll never get, like North Korea, Hodgdon said.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Retired Airman gets new SUV from Lee Automotive, VA (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/retired-airman-gets-new-suv-from-lee-automotive-va-photos-1.495780</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:49:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Local church holds vigil to honor Charleston victims</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/local-church-holds-vigil-to-honor-charleston-victims-1.494143</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Local church holds vigil to honor Charleston victims
Jim Robbins, a Gregg Chapel musician, performs at Wednesday nights vigil.
Special to the Daily News
By WENDY VICTORA | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 06:49 PM.
Hundreds gathered Wednesday night for a local vigil honoring the nine victims of last weeks shooting at a Charleston, S.C., church.
The vigil was held at Gregg Chapel AME Church on Carson Drive in Fort Walton Beach.
More than 20 pastors from churches across the community led the crowd in prayer.
It was a coming together in the city that was really positive, said Pastor Cecil Williams of Gregg Chapel. It was a true prayer vigil.
It was a city in love.
Contact Daily News Managing Editor Wendy Victora at 850-315-4478 or wvictora@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @WendyVnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 01:44:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Petitions call for removing Confederate flag</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/petitions-call-for-removing-confederate-flag-1.494137</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Petitions call for removing Confederate flag
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 06:44 PM.
The push to stop flying the Confederate flag over government buildings  and other public areas  has reached Northwest Florida.
Two petitions, started on www.change.org, are urging the removal of the Confederate flag from the Walton County Courthouse lawn and from the William Uncle Bill Lundy memorial in Crestview.
The Okaloosa County NAACP launched its petition Tuesday, asking Crestview Mayor David Cadle and the City Council to remove the rebel flag from the Lundy monument, which sits at the intersection of E. First Avenue and State Road 85.
I am sure that the City Council will look at this very closely, Cadle said.
He said he has received two phone calls from local citizens on the issue.
The NAACP has attempted in years past to remove the flag from the Lundy monument. The group tried most recently in December 2013, but the City Council refused to vote on the issue.
Lundy, believed by some to be the last surviving Confederate veteran, died in 1957. The Crestview Lions Club built the memorial the following year.
The petition calling for the removal of the Confederate flag from the Walton County Courthouse lawn in Defuniak Springs was launched Tuesday by Santa Rosa Beach resident Michelle Uhlfelder.
As of Thursday evening, almost 300 people had signed the petition, which is directed at the Walton County Board of Commissioners.
Uhlfelder said she took the initiative after hearing the pastor at her church talk about the mass shooting in Charleston, South Carolina.
He said, Its a time to be bold about things like this, she said. ... I would love to get 1,000 people. A thousand people wins an election down here.
Uhlfelder said its past time for the controversial flag to come down.
It has such a soiled history, she said. ... Its of a confederacy of rebels that tried to rise up and lost. Now were flying the losers flag, essentially, on our property.
Walton County NAACP President Raymond Jackson said he supports the removal of the flag.
Its time for it to happen, said Jackson, who lives in DeFuniak Springs.  ... The Spanish were here. The British were here. And we dont fly their flags at the courthouse.
The rebel flag has flown over Walton Countys Confederate Monument since it was first erected in 1871. The monument is Floridas first memorial to Confederate war dead. In 2002, the local chapter of the NAACP lobbied to have the flag removed, but commissioners voted down the measure.
Uhlfelder, who grew up in Atlanta and Memphis and has lived in Santa Rosa Beach for seven years, also is rallying other residents to attend the July 14 commission meeting. The item has been placed on the boards agenda for discussion.
County Commission Chairman Bill Imfeld said the issue is a timely one and that he is interested in reaching a compromise.
(The flag) can mean different things to different people, and I think we should try to be judicious ... and achieve a decorum that will diffuse harsh feelings and bring the community together.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:19:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Okaloosa touts student performance</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/okaloosa-touts-student-performance-1.494412</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Retired Airman gets new SUV from Lee Automotive, VA (PHOTOS)
Air Force veteran Pedro Rodriguez of Guaynabo, Puerto sits in his 2015 Subaru Forester on Monday at Lee Volkswagen Subaru in Fort Walton Beach while he is shown the car's features by sales representative Tony Santos. Rodriguez received a $20,000-plus grant from the Department of Veteran Affairs for a new car.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 04:03 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  Air Force veteran Pedro Rodriguez of Guaynabo, Puerto Rico, received a new car from a local car lot on Monday after months of searching for dealers to honor the $20,000-plus grant he received from the Department of Veteran Affairs.
He was getting depressed because no one was going to honor that benefit, said his wife, Maria Rodriguez.
The 60-year-old Air Force veteran fought back tears as he was handed the keys to his new car, a 2015 Subaru Forester.
PHOTOS of the car giveaway.
Im happy this dealership has worked with me. Im really happy, said Rodriguez.
About three weeks ago, Rodriguez found a story about a family in Pensacola who had received the same grant and was able to purchase a car from the Lee Automotive Group in Crestview.
Rodriguez called the dealership and was told he also could use the grant money to get a new car at Lee Volkswagen Subaru in Fort Walton Beach.
A lot of dealers wont do it because it takes weeks to get paid, said Maureen Bierman, marketing director for Lee Automotive Group.
Were just trying to get the word out about the program. We want to say thank you to all of our veterans said Bierman.
Rodriguez, a retired Master Sergeant, served 31 years in the Air Force as a civil engineer. He and his wife frequently visit relatives in Florida and needed a car for their travels.
The grant requires the recipient to be a veteran or current service member and the recipient must have a qualified disability.
Rodriguez suffered a knee and lower back injury while serving a tour in 2009 in Iraq. The injury caused permanent nerve damage that leaves him in constant pain.
He is pleased with the treatment he received from the VA and hopes more dealerships will be willing to help veterans and service members who are awarded the grant.
(The grant) helps us a lot... in getting the vehicle, which practically we couldnt get.
Contact Daily News Photographer Nick Tomecek at 850-315-4426 or ntomecek@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @NickTnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 23:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Firefighters battling ‘huge’ blaze at warehouse</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/firefighters-battling-huge-blaze-at-warehouse-1.495778</Link>
        <Description/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <MainBody>Firefighters battling huge blaze at warehouse
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 04:01 PM.
A huge warehouse fire Monday destroyed an estimated 60 percent of a Gulf Breeze business called Sunny Electrical Sales.
Dark smoke from the blaze, which occurred inside a Cowen Road industrial park, billowed high above U.S. Highway 98 and the nearby Gulf Breeze Zoo.
A wind from the southprevented the smoke from causing traffic problems or threatening animals at the zoo, said Midway Fire District Battalion Chief Ernie Johnson.
Navarre Beach Fire Department Chief Mike Howard, who described the fire as huge, confirmed hed sent a truck from his department to assist the Midway firefighters.
Johnson said trucks from Navarre, Gulf Breeze and Pensacola Beach also arrived to assist the three trucks Midway brought to the fire scene.
He said the fire call came in at 1:42 p.m. and crews had it under control within about 30 minutes. Johnson said the warehouse area of the electrical business, comprising about 60 percent of the total structure, was a complete loss.
The inside office areas, however, suffered only water damage.
They had a fire wall that did a great job, Johnson said.
Sunnys Electrical Sales closest neighbor, a gymnastics facility, was not damaged by the fire.
Vendors at the Gulf Breeze Flea Market, also located close to where the fire was burning, kept a wary eye on the blaze, said flea market manager Sandra Pettelko.
Pettelko said she walked down to see what was happening and to make sure the flea market itself was safe.
Weve seen the smoke. It was black and then it turned white, she said.
No evacuation of the flea market was necessary, Pettelko said.

=======
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Villani looks ahead to retirement (VIDEO)
Okaloosa County Public Safety Director Dino Villani poses at the Emergency Operations Center at the Northwest Florida State College. Villani will retire in early July after 15 years of guiding the county through everything from wild fires and hurricanes to ice storms and floods.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:17 PM.
Hurricanes. Floods. Oil spills. Ice storms.
After 15 years of guiding Okaloosa County through some of its worst disasters, Public Safety Director Dino Villani is calling it a career.
But like a true emergency junkie, hes giving out his cell phone number  just in case.
I dont want to leave anyone in the lurch, he said with a smile. If anyone needs anything, I will be around.
For a video of Villani reflecting on his last 15 years, click here.
Villani got his start as an EMT in the Everglades and planned to be a doctor but veered off into emergency management instead. He began working for Okaloosa County in 2002 after serving as the EMS bureau chief in Tallahassee for the state Department of Health.
The job was here, so it worked out, but I came here because I wanted to live here, he said. Its beautiful.
Not even Hurricane Ivan  which tops Villanis list of disasters  could change that. In the face of washed out highways, widespread destruction and the loss of water and power for days, the county took a major hit but emerged better off.
In terms of the value of that event making us more prepared, that was immeasurable, he said. That was the ultimate test.
And it led to Villanis dream of building countys state-of-the-art Emergency Operations Center, now in use at Northwest Florida State College in Niceville.
This was the vision right here, he said, standing in the giant control room that features a 10-foot-by-34-foot screen and other smaller screens for monitoring weather and news. Its constantly being used. Its designed to hold 200 people every day for two full weeks.
The countys emergency phone and text alert system also arose out of Ivan  a time when the county was bombarded with more than 100,000 phone calls.
Almost six years after Hurricane Ivan came the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill  an event that reinforced the need to disseminate information quickly.
We had tremendous public pressure for information, and we had to answer for everything, Villani said. The public was afraid and they were reacting. ... It really makes you think on your feet.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:56:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>The anti-pot taboo shrinks in presidential politics</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/election-news/the-anti-pot-taboo-shrinks-in-presidential-politics-1.495776</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
The anti-pot taboo shrinks in presidential politics
In this photograph taken June 30, Republican presidential hopeful Sen. Rand Paul of Kentucky speaks during a campaign stop at a sports bar in the Cherry Creek area in Denver. Earlier in the day, Paul made a stop at a cannabis industry convention in downtown Denver to speak to people in the marijuana industry behind closed doors. Presidential candidates are talking about marijuana in ways unimaginable not long ago. White House hopefuls in both parties are taking donations from people in the new marijuana industry, which is investing heavily in political activism as a route to expanded legalization and landed its first major candidate, Paul, at a trade show.
AP
By KRISTEN WYATT | Associated Press
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 03:56 PM.
DENVER  Presidential candidates are talking about marijuana in ways unimaginable not long ago.
White House hopefuls in both parties are taking donations from people in the new marijuana industry, which is investing heavily in political activism as a route to expanded legalization and landed its first major candidate, Rand Paul, at a trade show last month.
Several Republicans, like Democrats, are saying they won't interfere with states that are legalizing a drug still forbidden under federal law. And at conservative policy gatherings, Republicans are discussing whether drug sentences should be eased.
A quarter century after Bill Clinton confessed he tried marijuana but insisted "I didn't inhale," the taboo against marijuana is shrinking at the highest level of politics, just as it appears to be with the public.
"When I was growing up, it was political suicide for a candidate to talk about pot being legal," said Tim Cullen, owner of Colorado Harvest Co., a chain of medical and recreational marijuana dispensaries.
Cullen attended a Hillary Rodham Clinton fundraiser in New Mexico last month and talked to the Democratic candidate about her position on legalizing pot.
"She's not outwardly hostile to the idea, which is a big step forward," Cullen said. "She's willing to openly talk about it at least."
A slim majority of Americans, 53 percent, said in a Pew Research Center survey in March that the drug should be legal. As recently as 2006, less than a third supported marijuana legalization in another measure of public opinion, the General Social Survey.
Politicians are shifting, but slowly.
Republican candidates Jeb Bush, Ted Cruz and Rick Perry are among those who say states should decide marijuana laws, even as they brand legalization a bad idea. In June, Paul became the first major-party presidential candidate to hold a fundraiser with the new marijuana industry, courting about 40 donors in Denver.
But the Kentucky senator used a private back door, and aides erected a screen so photographers couldn't see the candidate standing by a green Cannabis Business Summit sign. Paul didn't talk about pot at a public meet-and-greet afterward.
A few days earlier in the same building, six other GOP presidential contenders talked to about 4,000 people at a gathering of Western conservatives. There, Perry defended the right of states to change marijuana laws, even if they "foul it up."
"Colorado comes to mind," the former Texas governor said, to laughs and applause. "I defend the right of Colorado to be wrong on that issue."
Altogether, 23 states and the District of Columbia are flouting federal law by allowing marijuana use for medical or recreational purposes.
Not all candidates say leave it to the states. New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie and former Pennsylvania Sen. Rick Santorum say they would fight to roll back marijuana legalization efforts in states such as Colorado.
Democrats are generally less critical of states legalizing pot, but they're treading carefully, too.
Clinton said last year that more research needed to be done on marijuana's medical value, but "there should be availability under appropriate circumstances." She didn't elaborate what those circumstances should be.
As for her main Democratic rival, Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders sounds lukewarm about legalization, despite his counterculture roots and liberal social views. He told Yahoo News that pot should be decriminalized but he was not ready to go beyond that. He said he smoked pot twice in the old days and "coughed a lot."
Bush and Cruz have also acknowledged using marijuana in their youth, as has President Barack Obama.
Marijuana entrepreneurs say even tepid support for legalization is a step forward, and they're opening their wallets in hopes of seeing more change.
The largest marijuana lobbying group, Marijuana Policy Project, plans to donate tens of thousands to 2016 presidential candidates. Executive Director Rob Kampia was among those at the Denver pot fundraiser.
"We wouldn't have heard a presidential candidate talking that way four years ago," Kampia said. Attendees said Paul talked about changing federal drug-sentencing laws but stopped short of calling for nationwide legalization.
It's unclear how much money the marijuana industry will spend on the presidential race. Many pot-business owners don't list their businesses on campaign-finance disclosure forms, given the drug's federal illegality. And some marijuana activists are likely to spend not on the presidential contest but on campaigns in the six to 10 states likely to have some sort of marijuana policy on ballots next year.
Still, the presidential race appears certain to include more talk of marijuana policy than before.
"There are a lot of loose bricks in the walls of resistance to changing drug laws in America," said William Martin, who studies drug policy at Rice University. "It's no longer a silly question, legalizing marijuana."

=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 00:44:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Stranded leatherback turtle taken to Gulfarium (PHOTOS, VIDEO)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/stranded-leatherback-turtle-taken-to-gulfarium-photos-video-1.494117</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Stranded leatherback turtle taken to Gulfarium (PHOTOS, VIDEO)
Staff from the Gulfarium Marine Adventure Park set up a harness to lift a 5-foot, 382-pound female Leatherback sea turtle into a truck after the turtle came ashore Thursday at the north end of Rocky Bayou in Niceville.
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 05:44 PM.
NICEVILLE  A leatherback turtle took up temporary residence at Gulfarium Marine Adventure Park Thursday after stranding itself in Niceville.
The 5-foot, 5-inch, 382-pound female sea turtle was found around 9 a.m. in Niecy Cooper's backyard, which is located at the north end of Rocky Bayou.
She immediately contacted Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, who asked the Emerald Coast Wildlife Refuge and Gulfarium to respond to the scene.
VIDEO of the stranding.
Ive never been that close to a leatherback, Cooper said. Its amazing actually.
Leatherbacks are the largest sea turtle in the world and typically weigh between 500 and 1,500 pounds when fully grown. The endangered species are rarely spotted locally.
Its the second call FWC received this week about a stranded leatherback turtle. On Sunday morning, people spotted one stuck on a sandbar in Toms Bayou in Valparaiso. They pushed it back into the water with the help of an FWC officer.
Its most likely the same one, but I cant 100 percent say that it is, said FWC spokeswoman Bekah Nelson.
In spite of criticism, Nelson said FWC handled the first stranding appropriately.
The officer was there, she said. He looked over the turtle.
Before freeing it from the sandbar, the officer checked the turtles eyes, flippers and shell and found no signs of illness or trauma, Nelson said.
Amanda Wilkerson, who oversees ECWR, said they were en-route to the stranding Sunday and expressed concern it was released that day.
The turtles location in the bayou was a red flag for her agency, she said.
We predicted that she would re-strand, and she did, Wilkerson said.
While waiting for Gulfarium crew to arrive, ECWR staff kept the turtle cool and wet with moist towels.
An evaluation at the scene didnt reveal any clear reasons for the stranding, so they opted to move her to Gulfarium on Okaloosa Island, according to Allen McDowell, who is the director of the sea turtle care program there.
Leatherbacks do not do as well in rehabilitation programs as other species of turtle, but the turtles proximity to fresh water and distance from the Gulf combined with the likelihood it had twice stranded itself, prompted the decision, McDowell said.
The turtle is alert and moving, but again, were not comfortable just releasing it, he said.
Once at the facility, staff took blood tests, an ultrasound and X-rays.
Its only the third time in the last decade a leatherback has beached itself along local shores. In both the other cases, the turtles died on the beach.
Gulfarium officials said they will share updates on the turtle as they get back test results. If no issues are found, staff will release turtle in the Gulf of Mexico.
A small loggerhead turtle was also rescued by wildlife officials Thursday morning.
The Emerald Coast Wildlife Refuge was contacted around 9:30 a.m. about the sea turtle stuck in a fishing net along a beach on Eglin Air Force Base, said director Amanda Wilkerson.
It was taken to Gulf World for rehabilitation and is expected to make a full recovery.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:14:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>'Starting crazy early:' Some colleges are recruiting athletes in middle school</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/starting-crazy-early-some-colleges-are-recruiting-athletes-in-middle-school-1.494408</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
'Starting crazy early:' Some colleges are recruiting athletes in middle school
Tommy Johnson, left, talks with a friend in this yearbook photo following a game against Walton County in 1991.
SPECIAL TO THE DAILY NEWS
By TRAVIS MEWHIRTER | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:14 PM.
Tommy Johnson was, as he tells it, elbow deep in flour when a manager at Kentucky Fried Chicken peeled around the corner, the fast food chains phone in hand.
Its for you, she said, shrugging at the 17-year-old football player. Somebody named Joe Paterno.
Johnson was a Niceville senior. Prior to that phone call he hadnt thought much about going to school. He had decided he would go into the military.
It is difficult to comprehend now, a football player less than a year away from high school graduation, showing interest only when one of the greatest coaches in the history of football was on the other line of a phone. 
The thought of going to college was not something that was going through my mind my junior or senior years, said Johnson, who went on to play for Alabama and is now the football coach and athletic director for Fort Walton Beach. I enjoyed playing football and I loved playing football. It just wasnt as big of a thing as it is now. We didnt have all the ESPNs and things like that, highlighting everything that a kid did.
"Nowadays kids, even if theyre not that good, they just assume they should be being recruited," he added.
Nowadays, if kids dont get something by the time theyre upperclassmen, theyre surprised, discouraged, stressed.
There is a 10-year-old athlete in the area receiving interest from an SEC school. There are middle schoolers around the country receiving verbal offers.
The recruitment process has jumped down a rabbit hole that has no foreseeable way out.
Everybodys targeting the younger kids now, telling them what they want to hear and holding on to them, Paxton basketball coach Jeff Bradley said. These kids are getting dragged along and theyre just a number to them. Theyre not anything more than a number. Thats starting crazy early.
Sami Mims was, in her mind, late. A freshman at Niceville in 2012, she had just begun playing volleyball.
By then girls were already sending out highlight tapes, she said.
High school freshmen are as predictable as the weather. There is no telling what their mood will be tomorrow, much less four years from then, a point raised by Navarre football coach Jay Walls in regards to schools offering 13- and 14-year-old kids.
Sometimes you just have to wonder, he said. How do they know?
Truth is, they dont.
The more difficult truth: They may no longer have a choice.
Its absolutely gotten nuts, Northwest Florida State softball coach Jack Byerly said. When I was at a four-year school (Auburn from 2004-2008), we brought them in senior year for a visit and they committed. Now if they dont commit to you in the eighth grade, youre behind the times.
Its crazy to me. I dont understand it. You have no idea what these kids are going to do. What were you thinking about when you were 14? Youre losing the joy of it because all of a sudden its become so competitive that its all you think about," he added. "You have these big tournaments and these big time coaches coming to watch you play. Its a totally different stage.
NCAA rules regarding athletes signing have remained rigid, antiquated. An athlete still cannot sign with a school until a year prior to them leaving for college. Maybe there is a solution on the horizon, maybe not. Neither Walls nor Bradley nor Johnson nor any of the other dozen coaches interviewed for this story posed a cure-all for the anarchy that has become recruiting.
Theres no way to really stop the escalation right now, Barton Simmons, the director of scouting for 247 Sports, said. The fact that colleges are recruiting kids that are freshmen and sophomores means that everybody has to do it.
You cant really sit on the sidelines because you dont believe in it," he added. "In a perfect world, youd go after a kid after his senior year because you get the full body of work and the kid can make a sound decision but of course thats not how it works."
Note to Readers:
This series began marinating in my head when I was working for a paper in Maryland and covered an athlete who had received offers to play basketball for every ACC school as a freshman. With our schedule easing over the summer, I had time to dig into this new world of recruiting, and down the rabbit hole I went. Nearly two dozen coaches, athletes and parents were interviewed for this series, each providing a new perspective on the volatile process that has become recruiting. 
 Travis Mewhirter
Contact Daily News Sports Writer Travis Mewhirter at 850-315-4432 or tmewhirter@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TravisMnwfdn.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cat hoarder to serve 3 years for animal cruelty</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/cat-hoarder-to-serve-3-years-for-animal-cruelty-1.495773</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Cat hoarder to serve 3 years for animal cruelty
Felicia Guy and Jerry McCallum
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 03:42 PM.
Jerry McCallum, who shared a Crestview-area home with a woman and 92 cats, will serve 36 months in prison for cruelty to animals and violating his probation.
In December of 2014, McCallums probation officer entered the home at 1208 E. Chestnut Ave. and discovered that little to nothing had been done to comply with his request to clean it.
The Panhandle Animal Welfare Society was called in and removed the 92 cats. Some were already dead and nearly all were so sick they had to be put down, PAWS Director Dee Thompson said afterward.
McCallum pleaded no contest Monday to five felony counts of animal cruelty and two misdemeanor charges of animal abandonment, according to Assistant State Attorney Clifton Drake. He admitted to the probation violation.
Felicia Guy, the woman with whom McCallum shared the Chestnut Avenue trailer, did not offer a plea at her Monday docket day, but will appear in court again Friday, Drake said.
I anticipate she probably will plea, but I cant say that for sure since nothing has been signed yet, McCallum said.
First Judicial Circuit Public Defender Bruce Miller confirmed that his office negotiated the McCallum plea. Guy is represented by the Office of Regional Counsel.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 22:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Springs offer cool alternative to hot beaches</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/springs-offer-cool-alternative-to-hot-beaches-1.495766</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Springs offer cool alternative to hot beaches
PonceDeLeon2- Elizabeth McGough jumps into the springs, which are 68-degrees year-round.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 03:15 PM.
The Ponce de Leon Springs were named after the Juan Ponce de Leon, the Spanish explorer who search for the Fountain of Youth according to folklore.
While theres no evidence to show that the local springs will make you any younger, they will cool you off with waters hitting 68-degrees year-round.
Locals and daytrippers alike head to the Ponce de Leon Springs State Park to swim, walk the nature trail and enjoy a picnic  all without fighting crowds at local beaches.
Kimberly Barnett and Tim Biddle took the neighborhood kids to the park one hot afternoon last week.
When one of us goes, we take the whole group, said Barnett with a laugh.
As they take turns jumping into the springs, families around the park are playing volleyball, cooking out on grills, fishing or taking a walk down the nature trail.
Barnett, who recently moved to the area from Louisiana heard about the park online. She said she prefers the springs to beaches.
I like the fresh water. Its nice to come and relax, she said. Some days theres hardly anyone here.
Aside from swimming, some of the kids like to explore the sunken treasures at the bottom of the springs. Youll often see snorkelers in the designated areas.
I found these neat rocks, a coin and this necklace, said Daniel Robertson as he lays out his findings on the ground.
Paxton resident Maggie McKinley opted for the state park to celebrate her sons fifth birthday.
He said to me Thank you for bringing me here to swim,  she said. Weve been here three times this year so far.
WANT TO GO? Ponce de Leon Springs State Park is located at 2860 State Park Road in Ponce de Leon. Admission is $4 per vehicle. For more information, visit floridastateparks.org or call 836-4281.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 23:04:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Burned kitten recovering at PAWS</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/burned-kitten-recovering-at-paws-1.494093</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Burned kitten recovering at PAWS
Disco, an 8-week-old kitten, was rescued earlier this week in the Navarre area with severe burns on her paws. Panhandle Animal Welfare Society and Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office are trying to find out what happened.
Special to the Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 04:04 PM.
The Panhandle Animal Welfare Society is hoping to find out what happened to an 8-week-old kitten that was found in the Navarre area with severe burns earlier this week.
Shes been in pain and shes very vocal like any other kitten, said Chloe Finley, a PAWS employee who is also fostering the kitten. Shes sweet. Theres not anything bad I can say about her.
Krystal Martel found the kitten in her Midway neighborhood on Maverick Lane Sunday and later brought the cat to Navarre resident Melanie Oberlander, who took her to PAWS. She and her kids named the kitten Disco.
You could smell the infection and see the bones of her feet, she said. I took her in overnight and gave her some antiseptic and got in touch with Melanie.
Martel said her neighborhood has a number of stray cats. In the past, shes heard of other animal abuse stories.
We seem to be a place were people drop off their litters, she said.
Santa Rosa County Sheriffs Office Public Information Officer Rich Aloy said deputies took a report a few days after the kitten was found, but that they are not investigating.
Dee Thompson, executive director of PAWS, said her agency couldnt investigate the case because it likely didnt occur in Okaloosa County, which is where PAWS has jurisdiction.
What PAWS can do is to take care of the kitten and share any information they receive with officials in Santa Rosa County.
Were trying to figure out if the burns are chemical or thermal, since she doesnt have singed hair, Thompson said. Thats why we want to know if anybody has seen something...this is felony level cruelty.
Thompson said Disco wears bandages on her paws that have to be changed throughout the day. She is on a high calorie/high protein diet and uses shredded paper instead of cat litter to avoid anything interfering with the bandages.
It will definitely be a little bit before they adopt her out, Thompson said.
DONATE TO DISCO: You can donate to Disco by bringing in a/d Hill brand canned cat food or make a monetary donation. More information about PAWS is available at paws-shelter.com.
Anyone with information about what happened to Disco, can anonymously report it by calling the Santa Rosa County Crime Stoppers at 850-437-STOP.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:03:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man walks out of store to find someone else in car</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-walks-out-of-store-to-find-someone-else-in-car-1.494401</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man walks out of store to find someone else in car
Stock photography
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:03 PM.
NICEVILLE - A man finished a shopping trip with his son to find a strange man sitting in his car.
The man called Niceville Police officers on June 15 around 10 p.m. to report that he'd come out of Walmart with his son and found a man sitting in his front seat, according to the call log. He said the man appeared to be trying to start his car.
The caller said he confronted the man, the man apologized, the log said. The caller waited to see if the other man would get in to a similar vehicle, but the man got into a blue van and drove off.
The caller drove a Ford Fusion, according to the log. The man requested officers make contact with the man and find out why he was in another vehicle.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 22:55:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Local amateur radio club hosting field day this weekend </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/local-amateur-radio-club-hosting-field-day-this-weekend-1.494090</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Local amateur radio club hosting field day this weekend
JASON EPPINK | Special to the Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 03:55 PM.
The Playground Amateur Radio Club will host an Amateur Radio Field Day at Hurlburt Field Picnic Grounds this weekend to promote the use of ham radios.
Were trying to preserve the hobby, said Mo Hodgdon, chairman of the event. I believe winds of 90 miles per hour can take down cell phone and landlines. Without them how do you communicate?
Hodgdon pointed out during Hurricane Katrina emergency crews communicated through amateur and CB radios.
During the field day, all ages can participate using radios provided by the club to make contacts with other radios along North America as other clubs will be participating with similar events.
While ham radios may seem to be an archaic piece of technology, they have more capability than most think. Some of the more expensive models can be hooked to a computer and send emails, photos and chat.
Hodgdon said he hopes kids will attend to learn more about amateur radios and perhaps even gain interest in obtaining a radio license.
After 9/11 a 10-year-old girl with a handheld radio did communications between a shelter and New York City Emergency Operation Center for eight hours, he said.
In the local area, Hodgdon and his wife volunteer to provide communications during disasters.
We want people to see what we can do, he said. Radios can help in any emergency situation.
The PARC Field Day is from 1 p.m. Saturday until 10 a.m. Sunday at the Hurlburt Field Picnic Grounds, located at the south side of U.S. Highway 98. For more information, visit w4zbb.org.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 01:01:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman accused of hitting deputy</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-accused-of-hitting-deputy-1.494399</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman accused of hitting deputy
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 06:01 PM.
MARY ESTHER - A 36-year-old woman is charged with striking a deputy after a fight with another woman.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputies were called for a disturbance between two women around 2 p.m. on June 10, according to the arrest report. When deputies arrived, they broke up the two women.
Chesney Leigh Anderson turned away from the other woman and started a verbal argument with a deputy, the report said. She allegedly hit the deputy's shoulder in an attempt to avoid being detained.
She was restrained and taken to a chair, showing signs of being under the influence of a narcotic, according to the report. Deputies reportedly noticed a small amount of white powder around her mouth.
Anderson is charged with battery on an officer.
Her next scheduled court date is July 21.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 20:13:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Making a Difference: Rodeo chips in to fight breast cancer</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/making-a-difference-rodeo-chips-in-to-fight-breast-cancer-1.495747</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Making a Difference: Rodeo chips in to fight breast cancer
Making Strides Against Breast Cancers Donna Fought, holding check, and Kyla Pugh, right front, accept a $1,000 donation from Baker Pro Rodeo organizers Mark Stalnaker, Ernie Brewbaker, Edith Elder, Russell Moorman, Joe Fisher, Bill Graham, President Mark Todd and Jim Silcox.
BRIAN HUGHES |Crestview News Bulletin
By BRIAN HUGHES | Crestview News Bulletin
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 01:13 PM.
Note to readers: This series recognizes people who make a difference in their communities. To nominate someone, call Kari Barlow at 315-4438 or email kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com
BAKER  The Old Spanish Trail Pro Rodeo is about far more than entertainment, and the local American Cancer Society has the check to prove it.
For the second year, the Baker Pro Rodeo sponsors presented $1,000 to Making Strides Against Breast Cancer of the Emerald Coast.
The proceeds came from an April 11 Breast Cancer Awareness Night during the rodeo at the Baker Arena.
In the rodeo world, its a big event to have Saturday nights as pink night for breast cancer awareness, Baker Area Recreation Association President Mark Todd said. We joined the movement last year and we want to keep it a tradition from now out.
ACS will use the money for research and education to help save womens lives, said Donna Fought, a breast cancer survivor and member of Making Strides.
Getting the word out assures women get their mammograms, she said. Even if you encourage just one woman to have an annual mammogram, youve saved a life. The American Cancer Society saved my life. I was one of those women who didnt do what she was supposed to do.
Rodeo organizers presented the check June 29 by a truck with a pink AAA Waste trash bin as a backdrop. Company owner Russell Moorman, one of the organizers, said AAA places the pink container at various community events, particularly cancer research fundraisers.
It gets a lot of attention, Moorman said. People like to sign it.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 21:53:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Policyholders may lose access to two area hospitals</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/policyholders-may-lose-access-to-two-area-hospitals-1.494080</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Policyholders may lose access to two area hospitals
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By TOM McLAUGHLIN | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 02:53 PM.
Sacred Heart Health Care System has resolved its contract negotiations with Florida Blue, but another nail-biting contract dispute has the potential to affect individuals across Northwest Florida.
Letters have gone out from Humana notifying patients of Hospital Corporation of America facilities that as of July 10 those hospitals will no longer participate in your Medicare PPO plan network.
Both Twin Cities Hospital in Niceville and Fort Walton Beach Medical Center in Fort Walton Beach are run by HCA.
We understand that changing your hospital can be difficult, but were here to help you through this transition, the letter, dated June 3, said.
Fort Walton Beach residents Eva Mae and Walter Salvatore said its kind of scary knowing they are caught in the middle of the two parties negotiations.
They have looked to see if they could find a different insurance carrier, but they havent found anyone who would accept them until open enrollments in October.
The government says you have to have insurance, Walter said. Well, weve got insurance, but how can the government allow this insurance company to quit in the middle of the year and say no hospital is going to take you?
Im 84, wife in her 70s, he added. For us to go without a hospital for the next four months is crazy.
Though the tone of the letter sounded dire enough to scare some people, Humana spokeswoman Nancy Hanewinckel said Humana and HCA still have plenty time to reach a contract agreement.
Our contract with HCA is still in existence and will not expire until July 10, she said. There is still a very active negotiation going on. Were hoping any day now we will be reporting we have signed a new agreement.
Hanewinckel said the insurance company was required to send the letter as the deadline to reach an agreement with HCA approached to within 30 days.
Humana sent a second letter to clear up some discrepancies with the first. That letter said the insurance companies are terminating its contracts with HCA hospitals, but attempted to clarify that HCA ambulatory surgery centers would remain as Humana participants.
The emphasis on are terminating further confused patients.
HCA operates 47 hospitals in Florida.
Fort Walton Beach Medical Center spokeswoman Denise Kendust provided an HCA statement on the ongoing discussions with Humana.
We remain actively engaged in continuing discussions with Humana and are optimistic that well come to an agreement before the July 10th extension date for Humana Commercial and Humana Medicare Advantage plans, the statement said.
The hospital offered two phone numbers for patients to call with questions about their coverage.
Those are 850-863-7511 or 850-863-7515.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Tom McLaughlin at 850-315-4435 or tmclaughlin@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @TomMnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 00:42:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mythbusting Vibrio</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/mythbusting-vibrio-1.494396</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Saturday, June 27, 2015 at 05:42 PM.
The headlines about the "flesh-eating" bacteria that waits for you at the beach are over-hyped.
"There's a few misnomers," said Ryan Mims, public information officer for the Florida Department of Health in Okaloosa County. "Those headlines cause a lot of panic, but if you're a healthy individual and practice good hygiene there's a low risk of you contracting vibrio vulnificus."
Here's the facts about vibrio:
First, what is vibrio vulnificus?
Vibrio Vulnificus, or vibrio, is a bacterium that is normally found in warm saltwater. Coastlines throughout the U.S. can be a host for vibrio. There's two ways to contract vibrio, said Mims. First, by entering saltwater with open wounds and second, by ingesting undercooked shellfish and oysters. So far this year, Santa Rosa County has had one case of vibrio. Walton and Okaloosa County have not any cases.
How do I know if I have vibrio?
According to the Center for Disease Control and Prevention, symptoms of vibrio is acute illness, which can begin one to three days after exposure or as late as seven days in a small percentage of cases. If exposed by an open wound, you may see increased swelling, redness and pain at the site of the wound. You may also notice swelling and redness on arms and legs with blood-tinged blisters and low blood pressure or shock.
"It's not a flesh-eating bacteria," Mims said.
There is a chance of amputation in severe cases, but if treated in a timely and effective manner , those who recover should see no long-term effects, Mims added.
How do I prevent vibrio?
Don't immediately fret if you get a paper cut at the beach. Vibrio is preventable.
"It can be a serious disease and even lead to death, but if you take proper care, your risk should be minimal," said Dr. Carina Blackmore, deputy state epidemiologist in a video on the DOH-Okaloosa website.
With that being said, those with underlying health conditions and compromised immune deficiencies, especially those with chronic liver disease, have a higher risk of contracting vibro, said Blackmore. Perform first aid before wounds become infected and keep wounds covered with dry, clean bandages. And cook your shellfish thoroughly. Oysters can also be carriers if the bacteria is present in their environment, but can only legally be harvested in from waters free from contamination.
Safety and oysters
Follow these tips from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration when cooking at home for safe meals
When you purchase oysters the shells should be closed. Throw away any oysters with shells already opened.
In the shell: After the shells open, boil live oysters for another 3-5 minutes. (Use small pots to boil or steam oysters. Do not cook too many oysters in the same pot because the ones in the middle may not get fully cooked. Discard any oysters that do not open during cooking).
In a steamer: Add oysters to water that is already steaming and cook live oysters for another 4-9 minutes.
Shucked Oysters:
Boil or simmer shucked oysters for at least 3 minutes or until the edges curl.
Fry at 375 degrees for at least 3 minutes.
Broil 3 inches from heat for 3 minutes.
Bake at 450 degrees for 10 minutes.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4432 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:46:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>PHOTOS: Waterspout forms near Miramar Beach</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/weather/photos-waterspout-forms-near-miramar-beach-1.495726</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>PHOTOS: Waterspout forms near Miramar Beach
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 12:46 PM.
Photo Galleries
Waterspout
Jane-Claire Baker of New Orleans was visiting family in Miramar Beach over the weekend and saw this waterspout form during a morning thunderstorm.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 18:01:42 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court upholds nationwide health care law subsidies</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/supreme-court-upholds-nationwide-health-care-law-subsidies-1.493999</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Supreme Court upholds nationwide health care law subsidies
Jessica Ellis, right, with the "yay 4 ACA" sign, and other supporters of the Affordable Care Act, react with cheers as the opinion for health care is reported outside of the Supreme Court in Washington on Thursday. The Supreme Court on Thursday upheld the nationwide tax subsidies under President Barack Obama's health care overhaul, in a ruling that preserves health insurance for millions of Americans.
JACQUELYN MARTIN | AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 11:01 AM.
WASHINGTON  The Supreme Court on Thursday upheld the nationwide tax subsidies under President Barack Obama's health care overhaul, in a ruling that preserves health insurance for millions of Americans.
The justices said in a 6-3 ruling that the subsidies that 8.7 million people currently receive to make insurance affordable do not depend on where they live, under the 2010 health care law.
The outcome is the second major victory for Obama in politically charged Supreme Court tests of his most significant domestic achievement. It came the same day the court gave the administration an unexpected victory by preserving a key tool the administration uses to fight housing bias.
Chief Justice John Roberts again voted with his liberal colleagues in support of the law. Roberts also was the key vote to uphold the law in 2012. Justice Anthony Kennedy, a dissenter in 2012, was part of the majority on Thursday.
"Congress passed the Affordable Care Act to improve health insurance markets, not to destroy them," Roberts wrote in the majority opinion.
In a dissent he summarized from the bench, Justice Antonin Scalia said, "We should start calling this law SCOTUScare." Using the acronym for the Supreme Court, Scalia said his colleagues have twice stepped in to save the law from what Scalia considered worthy challenges.
Justices Samuel Alito and Clarence Thomas joined the dissent, as they did in 2012.
Nationally, 10.2 million people have signed up for health insurance under the Obama health overhaul. That includes the 8.7 million people who are receiving an average subsidy of $272 a month to help pay their insurance premiums.
Of those receiving subsidies, 6.4 million people were at risk of losing that aid because they live in states that did not set up their own health insurance exchanges.
The challenge devised by die-hard opponents of the law, often derided by critics as "Obamacare," relied on four words  established by the state  in the more than 900-page law.
The law's opponents argued that the vast majority of people who now get help paying for their insurance premiums are ineligible for their federal tax credits. That is because roughly three dozen states opted against creating their own health insurance marketplaces, or exchanges, and instead rely on the federal healthcare.gov to help people find coverage if they don't get insurance through their jobs or the government.
In the challengers' view, the phrase "established by the state" demonstrated that subsidies were to be available only available to people in states that set up their own exchanges. Those words cannot refer to exchanges established by the Health and Human Services Department, which oversees healthcare.gov, the opponents argued.
The administration, congressional Democrats and 22 states responded that it would make no sense to construct the law the way its opponents suggested. The idea behind the law's structure was to decrease the number of uninsured. The law prevents insurers from denying coverage because of "pre-existing" health conditions. It requires almost everyone to be insured and provides financial help to consumers who otherwise would spend too much of their paycheck on their premiums.
The point of the last piece, the subsidies, is to keep enough people in the pool of insured to avoid triggering a so-called death spiral of declining enrollment, a growing proportion of less healthy people and premium increases by insurers.
Several portions of the law indicate that consumers can claim tax credits no matter where they live. No member of Congress said that subsidies would be limited, and several states said in a separate brief to the court that they had no inkling they had to set up their own exchange for their residents to get tax credits.
The 2012 case took place in the midst of Obama's re-election campaign, when he touted the largest expansion of the social safety net since the advent of Medicare nearly a half-century earlier. But at the time, the benefits of the Affordable Care Act were mostly in the future. Many of its provisions had yet to take effect.
In 2015, the landscape has changed, although the partisan and ideological divisions remain for a law that passed Congress in 2010 with no Republican votes.
The case is King v. Burwell, 14-114.

=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:17:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>20 injured in church bus crash on I-10</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/20-injured-in-church-bus-crash-on-i-10-1.494384</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>20 injured in church bus crash on I-10
Stock photography
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 09:17 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS  Twenty people were taken to area hospitals Friday after authorities say a church school bus traveling on Interstate 10 veered off the highway and hit a tree.
The crash was reported at 3:10 p.m. just west of State Road 331 near DeFuniak Springs, according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
The bus was one of three vehicles from a church in Louisiana that were heading east on I-10, said Bryan Pierce, a battalion chief from Walton County Fire Rescue. He was not sure why the bus left the road.
Twenty people were taken to hospitals, although none of them suffered life-threatening injuries, Pierce said.
Seven were taken to Healthmark Regional Medical Center in DeFuniak Springs; one was taken to Twin Cities Hospital in Niceville; seven were taken to Sacred Heart on the Emerald Coast in Miramar Beach; and five were taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center in Crestview.
About 40 people were in a second bus and a passenger van that were traveling with the bus that wrecked. They were taken to DeFuniak Springs Community Center for the night, according to Pierce and the Walton County Sheriffs Office.
Many of the people who were hurt were youths. The bus driver and chaperones were adults, Pierce said.
The wreck closed one eastbound lane of I-10.
We did back up traffic for miles, Im afraid, Pierce said.
FHP was investigating the crash, but had released no details Friday night.
Walton County sheriffs deputies and DeFuniak Springs police and firefighters assisted at the scene.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
COMMENTS
PHOTOS: Waterspout forms near Miramar Beach By
http://www.nwfdailynews.com July 6, 2015 12:46
Jane-Claire Baker of New Orleans was visiting family in Miramar Beach over the weekend and saw this waterspout form during a morning thunderstorm.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:30:29 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man dies two days after driving in front of train</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/man-dies-two-days-after-driving-in-front-of-train-1.495724</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 17:39:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>OCSO investigating apparent homicide</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/ocso-investigating-apparent-homicide-1.493996</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>OCSO are investigating a homicide that occurred at 4 Marty Drive in Fort Walton Beach.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 10:39 AM.
Photo Galleries
Homicide
FORT WALTON BEACH  Okaloosa County Sheriffs Office is investigating the death of 39-year-old Jimmy Lee Dodd, who was shot early Wednesday morning.
Deputies responded to Dodds mobile home at 4 Marty Lane at about 5:30 a.m. after a resident of his home called 911.
When they arrived, they found Dodds body located outside the trailer, according to a press release.
Investigators said Dodd had been shot multiple times and are still in the process of interviewing various witnesses.
One of the neighbors down the street, who didnt want to give his name, said he heard about five or six gunshots around 5:20 a.m.
I woke up and checked on my daughter and grandson, he said. I could tell the shots were close.
Around 10 a.m., several vehicles from the OCSO, including a canine unit were parked in front of the mobile home alongside a van from West Florida Removal Service.
An autopsy will be conducted by Floridas District One Medial Examiners Office.
This is the fourth shooting to occur in the Fort Walton Beach area in nearly two weeks.
Anyone with information on the shooting is asked to contact the OCSO at 651-744 or Emerald Coast Crime Stoppers at 863-TIPS, emeraldcoastcrimestoppers.com, or text TIP214 plus your message to CRIMES (274637).

=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 04:00:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Police called for fight at Tom Thumb</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/police-called-for-fight-at-tom-thumb-1.494381</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man dies two days after driving in front of train
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
<<<<<<< HEAD
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 12:30 PM.
An 85-year-old Crestview man died July 4, two days after failing to stop at a crossing and driving in front of a westbound train near Mossy Head.
Roger Eugene Anderson was driving out of the entrance for Mossy Head Auto Parts about 3 p.m. July 2 when the accident happened.
He did not stop at a stop sign prior to crossing the tracks and drove in front of the train and stopped, according to a Florida Highway Patrol media release.
The train could not stop and struck the passenger side of the 2003 Chevrolet pick-up truck, pushing it clear of the tracks.
The train's engineer, Kenneth Davis, a 57-year-old Pensacola man, was not injured.

=======
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 09:00 PM.
NICEVILLE - Police were called for a fight at Tom Thumb between two women during a custody exchange.
Niceville Police officers were called around June 10 for a disturbance at Tom Thumb, according to the call log. The disturbance started out as a verbal argument during a child exchange.
The man's ex wife and his current wife had an argument that became physical in the parking lot, the log said. The current wife put her arm up to "keep the ex wife out of her face" and the ex wife grabbed her arm and scratched her.
The man left both women at Tom Thumb and took the children home before going to the police department, according to the log. No charges were filed because both women were found to have an equal part in the fight.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 19:10:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution hasn't always worked</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/bill-campbell-s-blog-court-ordered-restitution-hasn-t-always-worked-1.495707</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:15:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Sacred Heart, Florida Blue reach agreement</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/sacred-heart-florida-blue-reach-agreement-1.493872</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Sacred Heart, Florida Blue reach agreement
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 06:15 PM.
Sacred Heart Health System announced Wednesday it will continue to be a participating healthcare provider for Florida Blue insurance plans.
The two entities signed a new contract that will allow Florida Blue members with continued access to Sacred Heart services for the next three years.
Our hospitals in Miramar Beach, Port St. Joe and Pensacola, including our Childrens Hospital, will continue to be a participating provider in Florida Blue plans, said Susan Davis, president and CEO of Sacred Heart Health System.
Kirk Fischer, vice president of delivery system for Florida Blue said the Northwest Florida community is a very important market to the company.
Our new contract with Sacred Heart ensures we can continue to provide the members in the area with access to high-quality and affordable health care, he said.
The new agreement comes less than a month after Sacred Heart sent letters to some of its customers notifying them the health care system could part ways with Florida Blue by July 1. The letter said Sacred Heart and Florida Blue had been negotiating a new contract for several months and had been unable to reach an agreement.
Im very happy. Its fantastic, said Kathleen Armstrong, who is insured by Florida Blue and regularly receives health care services at Sacred Heart on the Emerald Coast.
Armstrong, who received her letter June 11, suffers from a rare genetic immune deficiency disease that requires her to have monthly treatments. She said she was never notified by Florida Blue about the potential change.
She was distraught at the prospect of no longer being able to use Sacred Heart.
I just think its exceptional care and I wouldnt want to go anywhere else, she said. Im glad its going to continue.
Armstrong spoke out about her concerns to the Daily News earlier this month.
I wanted to be a voice for the community, she said. I hope if this ever happens again, the community will band together.

Sacred Heart will continue as an in-network provider for the following Florida Blue plans:
Blue Care HMO (Health Options Inc.)
BlueChoice (Preferred Patient Care)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu Jun 25 01:11:22 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Popular doctor, lawyer, politician Durell Peaden passes away</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/popular-doctor-lawyer-politician-durell-peaden-passes-away-1.493870</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Popular doctor, lawyer, politician Durell Peaden passes away
Sen. Durell Peaden (center), R-Crestview, asks a question of Rep. Don Brown (far right), R-DeFuniak Springs, in 2004 in Niceville as members of the area's legislative delegation met to discuss priorities for the 2005 session.
File photo
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 06:11 PM.
CRESTVIEW  Former state Sen. Durell Peaden, a towering figure in Northwest Florida politics, passed away Tuesday. He was 69.
Peaden, who was both a physician and an attorney, represented the northern portions of several Northwest Florida counties in the state Senate from 2001 to 2010, when he left office due to term limits. From 1995 to 2000, he represented much of that same area in the state House of Representatives.
He always called Crestview home, said state Sen. Greg Evers, who was a close friend and distant cousin of Peadens. He cared so much about the people who live here.
Evers, who followed Peaden into the Florida House in 2000 and the Senate in 2010, said Peaden was the smartest man I ever knew.
He had an insightfulness that was always right on, Evers added. In any situation, you could call on him for advice, and hed always have the right answer.
Born in DeFuniak Springs in 1945, Peaden grew up in Crestview, a block away from his lifelong friend and longtime legislative aide, Roger Robinson. He later graduated from Tulane University, the medical school at Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara, and the Thomas Goode Jones School of Law at Faulkner University.
Peaden and his wife, Nancy, had three children: Durell III (Trey), Tyler and Taylen.
He was extremely brilliant, Robinson said. He just exuded compassion for his patients when he was practicing medicine, and for his constituents when he was in the legislature. I run into people all the time who say things like, Dr. Peaden saved my grandbabys life. He was always working non-stop to help people.
Like most successful politicians, Peaden was outgoing and friendly, Robinson said.
He had a photographic memory, Robinson added. If he met you once, he remembered you. He could tell you where he met you, and under what circumstances.
Evers said that while Peaden was interested in many issues, his foremost concern was providing access to medical care for his constituents.
He was probably proudest of being able to bring the FAMU pharmacy school to Crestview, Evers said. He also worked very hard to bring the Lake Erie College of Medicines dental school to DeFuniak Springs.
As one of the sponsors of Florida's Stand Your Ground law, Peaden was back in the limelight in 2012 following George Zimmermans shooting of Trayvon Martin.
He explained to people that the law was never meant to be applied in that type of circumstance, Robinson said. That law was prompted by an incident where an elderly couple in Pensacola were living in a FEMA trailer following Hurricane Ivan. An intruder broke in, and a man shot him. The senator said the man shouldn't have to wait 90 days to see if the prosecutor was going to bring charges against him.
Peaden was a dean at the Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine in Erie, Pennsylvania. He was there earlier this month for the schools graduation when he suffered a massive heart attack. Robinson said Peaden was admitted to the hospital there, where he later passed away.
Both Robinson and Evers said Peaden leaves a legacy of many behind the scenes accomplishments.
He wasnt looking for glory, Robinson said. He just did things because they were the right things to do. He is going to be greatly missed.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 03:52:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man claims paraphernalia belongs to his 'hooker girlfriend'</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-claims-paraphernalia-belongs-to-his-hooker-girlfriend-1.494380</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>BILL CAMPBELL'S BLOG: Court-ordered restitution hasn't always worked
By BILL CAMPBELL | Daily News blogger
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 12:10 PM.
The oft-quoted state Rep. Matt Gaetz made headlines recently when he pushed through a bill that would  hang on, granny  require public officials convicted of corruption to make restitution.
Anyone with an IQ over room temperature is forgiven for saying, Duh?
But it hasnt always worked, even when the court order said restitution.
Which brings us to David Selby. He was the attorney for the Okaloosa County School Board until 1990. Thats when it was discovered hed absconded with $21 bucks short of $200,000 from county coffers.
He was arrested, judged guilty, sentenced to three years in prison  for which he served 67 days  and ordered to repay the money over 15 years. Didnt happen.
Selby got the court-ordered $1,137 reduced to $200 a month. Do the math. You know how long it takes to repay $199,721 at $200 a month? It was very kind of the judge to think Selby will live to be 130.
But were not quite done. After Selbys probation was over, POOF! No Selby.
I think he might be living in Alabama, said current School District attorney Jeff McInnis, an honorable man. He also said he was told we have no legal jurisdiction or resources to pursue Selby.
McInnis thinks we  thats you and I  may have gotten thirty, maybe thirty-five thousand dollars back from Selby.
So, young Gaetz, congrats on your bill. Heres hoping it has more sticking power than what was extant in 1990.
And heres a question for your dad, who was on the School Board at the time: Who the hell vetted Selby? Didnt they hear rumors he had scammed others before all this went down?
Im just a crummy blogger and I found that out.
Have the board call me when you retire, Jeff. Ill be happy to nose around.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 18:55:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Deputies mediate dispute over property rights</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/deputies-mediate-dispute-over-property-rights-1.495704</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Deputies mediate dispute over property rights
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
<<<<<<< HEAD
Published: Monday, July 6, 2015 at 11:55 AM.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office were called to the beach Saturday night after a group of Holiday Isle residents occupying the beach allegedly blocked an Emerald Grande ferry boat from dropping off passengers, according to Michele Nicholson, public information officer for OSCO.
According to the call history record, approximately 50 people were at the beach near Gulf Shore Drive. The unidentified caller stated there has been an "ongoing property dispute between the homeowners of Destin Pointe and Legendary (LLC)."
Deputies mediated between the groups and the departed.
Peter Bos, CEO of Legendary, LLC, later arrived on the property and a confrontation ensued between him and a resident. Bos was taking photos and video of the argument when a resident raised his hand in the camera while talking to him. Bos then shoved him away.
After interviewing multiple witnesses and obtaining sworn statements, it was determined that probable cause did not exist for battery charges, said Nicholson.

=======
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 08:51 PM.
NICEVILLE - Niceville Police officers responded to a series of vehicle burglaries on July 8.
A woman called at 6:06 a.m. to report she and her neighbor on Nathey Avenue had both had their vehicles broken into overnight.
A woman called at 7:27 a.m. to report her vehicle had been broken into while in her driveway on Nathey Avenue. An inverter, GPS and a Gameboy were taken. They were reportedly found around the corner broken.
A woman called at 8 a.m. to report her vehicle had been broken into at her home on St. Charles Street. Change and a bottle of rum were missing from the vehicle.
A woman called at 11:02 a.m. to report her vehicle had been broken into at her home on Judith Avenue. Three pairs of sunglasses and other miscellaneous items were reported stolen.
A man called at 1:42 p.m. to report his vehicle had been broken into at his Florida Street home.
A man called police at 2:05 p.m. to report his vehicle had been rummaged through while parked at his Nathey Avenue home. Nothing was reported taken.
A woman called police at 5:34 p.m. to report her vehicle was burglarized overnight on Big Oaks Lane, but she had needed to drive it to work. She wanted to file a report. An iPod, two pairs of headphones and a pair of gloves were reported missing. There were no signs of forced entry.
A woman called at 5:55 p.m. to report her vehicle had been burglarized overnight on Azalea Drive. Nothing was stolen, but her center console had been and things taken out.
A woman called at 6:15 p.m. to report her vehicle had been burglarized overnight on Azalea Drive. She just wanted police to be aware that someone had gone through the center console.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 05:24:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two fatal accidents take local lives </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/two-fatal-accidents-take-local-lives-1.495685</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Two fatal accidents take local lives
By JENNIE McKEON and WENDY VICTORA | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 10:24 PM.
A Saturday evening crash on Interstate 10 killed a young Crestview mother and left three others injured.
Amber Colson, a 28-year-old Crestview woman, was killed in the 5 p.m. crash, according to the Florida Highway Patrol media release. Although that is the name on her drivers license, she is known locally by her middle name of Nicole  or Nikki  and her maiden name of Parker, friends say.
She was a wonderful mom, said Jeanne Bloomquist, a Crestview woman who has been best friends with Parker since they were freshmen in high school. She always had a smile on her face. She cared so much about other people and did everything for everyone else.
She leaves behind two young children  8-year-old Jacob and 7-year-old Carrie.
According to the FHP report, Parker was a passenger in a 2006 Chevy Silverado driven by 29-year-old Levi Jernigan of Crestview. He was towing a large box trailer loaded with inflatable jump houses eastbound on Interstate 10 near mile marker 44.
The trailer began to sway, causing Jernigan to lose control of the vehicle. The right side of the trailer hit a 2004 Ford Focus driven by Marion Haynes, a 54-year-old Niceville woman.
Jernigans car was forced to the right and Haynes steered to the left, according to the release. Haynes regained control of the Focus and came to a stop facing north on the south shoulder.
The Chevy and the trailer rotated and entered the median, with the right side of the vehicle striking a tree. Jernigan, who was not wearing a seatbelt, was ejected and suffered serious injuries. He was taken to Baptist Hospital. Haynes and her passenger, 38-year-old Zelma Thomas of Crestview, both had minor injuries and were taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center.
Parker was taken to Sacred Heart Hospital, but died of her injuries. She was wearing a seatbelt, according to the release.
He and Parker were dating, Bloomquist said. She had talked to him in the hospital Sunday evening. He told her he did everything he could to stop the trailer from wobbling.
He was her true love, she said. They were inseparable. Hell always be her boyfriend to me.
------
Crestview man dies in Santa Rosa County Crash
A 22-year-old Crestview man died after colliding with a van Sunday afternoon around 3:12 p.m. in Santa Rosa County.
According to a press release from Florida Highway Patrol, Robert Johnson, 28, of Milton, was stopped at the intersection of Welcome Church Road and State Road 87 waiting to make a left turn as Cameron Burke, 22, of Crestview was traveling south on SR 87 on a Honda motorcycle approaching the intersection.
Johnson pulled across the south lanes of SR 87 into the path of Burke, the release said. The front of the motorcycle collided with the left side of the van. Both vehicles came to rest at the intersection.
Burke was wearing a helmet and was pronounced dead on the scene. Johnson had no injuries. He was not wearing a seatbelt.
Charges are pending a traffic homicide investigation, according to the FHP release.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:49:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>DOT sees light at the end of Gap Creek</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/dot-sees-light-at-the-end-of-gap-creek-1.493864</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
DOT sees light at the end of Gap Creek
Construction crews work Tuesday on the bridge at Gap Creek on Beal Parkway, which has been under construction since January 2014.
NICK TOMECEK | Daily News
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:49 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  Work has resumed on the Gap Creek bridge replacement project on Beal Parkway.
Construction crews returned to the site June 8 after being on standby for much of the spring due to a large number of underground obstructions  logs and stumps  found in the creek bed.
In March, officials with the Department of Transportation announced the bridges completion date would be pushed back to late summer.
DOT Spokesman Ian Satter said the project is still expected to meet that deadline.
The bridge substructure, the bridge superstructure and the north and southbound roadway construction are all left to do, he said.
Motorists can expect some traffic shifts in the coming months, and DOT will announce those changes before they happen, Satter added.
The $3.3 million project has slowed traffic considerably on that section of Beal Parkway.
Im very frustrated as a business owner because the worst is yet to come, said Terry Akens, who owns Southern Signs, which sits on the west side of Beal Parkway.
His main concern is that his company has to make and receive multiple deliveries each day. He said the DOT has guaranteed him access to his business from Beal Parkway, but he doesnt know exactly what that will look like.
Akens, like many locals, will be happy when its completed.
It will be better all the way around, he said. Theres no doubt about that.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 00:06:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>One escaped murderer fatally shot; other is on run</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/one-escaped-murderer-fatally-shot-other-is-on-run-1.494282</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
One escaped murderer fatally shot; other is on run
Authorities search an area in Constable, N.Y,. for convicted murderers Richard Matt and David Sweat on Friday. Police shifted a focus of their three-week search closer to the Canadian border.
AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 05:06 PM.
MALONE, N.Y.  One of two convicted killers who staged a brazen escape from an upstate maximum-security prison and had been hunted for three weeks was shot and killed Friday, but the other is still on the run.
An official with knowledge of the manhunt said Richard Matt was killed and David Sweat is still on the run. The official wasn't authorized to talk about the development publicly and spoke to The Associated Press on the condition of anonymity.
Gov. Andrew Cuomo says Matt and Sweat used power tools to saw through a steel cell wall and several steel steam pipes, bashed a hole through a 2-foot-thick brick wall, squirmed through pipes and escaped early on June 6 from Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, near the Canadian border.
Sweat was serving a sentence of life without parole in the killing of a sheriff's deputy in Broome County in 2002. Matt was serving 25 years to life for the killing and dismembering of his former boss.
A civilian worker at the prison was charged with helping the killers flee by giving them hacksaw blades, chisels and other tools.
Prosecutors said Joyce Mitchell, a prison tailoring shop instructor who got close to the men while working with them, had agreed to be their getaway driver but backed out because she felt guilty for participating. Mitchell pleaded not guilty on June 15 to charges including felony promoting prison contraband.
Authorities said the men had filled their beds in their adjacent cells with clothes to make it appear they were sleeping when guards made overnight rounds. On a cut steam pipe, the prisoners left a taunting note containing a crude caricature of an Asian face and the words "Have a nice day."
Clinton County District Attorney Andrew Wylie said they apparently used tools stored by prison contractors, taking care to return them to their toolboxes after each night's work.
Authorities also said Mitchell had discussed killing her husband, Lyle Mitchell, as part of the plot.
"Joyce Mitchell tells us that was discussed between her and Matt and that upon their escape they were going to return back to Joyce Mitchell's home at which time Matt and Sweat were going to kill her husband," Wylie said.
Lyle Mitchell's lawyer, Peter Dumas, said June 18 that his client was shocked by word of the plot and that Joyce Mitchell had told her husband she couldn't go through with it and the inmates threatened to harm him.
"Toward the end, Joyce had told Lyle  and we have no reason to doubt it  that she told Sweat and Matt that she wasn't going to go through with it," he said. "At that point, they threatened her by threatening Lyle, saying they were going to have someone on the outside do something to him or someone on the inside when he was back at work do something to him, so I think it was a point of control."
Lyle Mitchell was cooperating with authorities and wasn't facing charges.
On June 24, authorities charged Clinton correction officer Gene Palmer with promoting prison contraband, tampering with physical evidence and official misconduct. Officials said he gave the two prisoners the frozen hamburger meat Joyce Mitchell had used to hide the tools she smuggled to Sweat and Matt. Palmer's attorney said he had no knowledge that the meat contained hacksaw blades, a bit and a screwdriver.
Dannemora, built in 1845, occupies just over 1 square mile within the northern reaches of the Adirondack Forest Preserve and is surrounded by forest and farmland. The stark white perimeter wall of the prison, topped with guard towers, borders a main street in the village's business district.
The escape was the first in history from Clinton Correctional's maximum-security portion. In July 2003, two convicted murderers used tools from a carpentry shop at Elmira Correctional Facility to dig a hole in the roof of their cell and a rope of bedsheets to go over the wall. They were captured within three days, and a subsequent state investigation cited lax inmate supervision, poor tool control and incomplete cell searches.

>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 04:41:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Locals cheer on U.S. in the Women's World Cup final</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/locals-cheer-on-u-s-in-the-women-s-world-cup-final-1.495677</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:39:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Florida's largest insurer to ask for rate hikes in 2016</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/florida-s-largest-insurer-to-ask-for-rate-hikes-in-2016-1.493861</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Florida's largest insurer to ask for rate hikes in 2016
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By The Associated Press
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:39 PM.
TALLAHASSEE  Florida has dodged hurricanes for the last decade, but the state's largest property insurer says it needs to keep hiking the rates paid by those customers who live along the coast and in heavily populated South Florida.
The board of Citizens Property Insurance voted unanimously Wednesday to raise rates an average of 3.2 percent statewide, although the actual rates paid by homeowners could vary widely depending on where they live. Many inland customers with Citizens, for example, are expected to see a slight decrease.
Citizens officials approved the rate hike without any debate or discussion. State regulators must still sign off on the rate hike, but if it is approved the higher rates would take effect in February 2016.
Nearly half of the state-created insurer's 600,000 customers will actually see slight decreases in their rates according to figures drawn up by Citizens staff.
But those customers who live near the coast could pay an average of 8.6 percent more. Citizens officials say rate hikes are needed for homeowners in Palm Beach, Broward, Miami-Dade and Monroe counties.
Citizens officials say there are several reasons for the need for higher rates in South Florida. One reason is that Citizens is shrinking in size due to an aggressive push by the insurer to have policyholders switch to privately run companies. That leaves Citizens with customers who are at a higher risk of storm damage.
Another reason cited by Citizens is that there has been a rise in South Florida claims associated with water damage that is not storm-related.
"Every year, Citizens' actuaries calculate rates based on the same methodology used by insurance companies all over the world, which compares potential risk to the ability to pay claims," said Chris Gardner, the chairman of Citizens Board of Governors, in a statement.
Gov. Rick Scott and legislators have pushed Citizens to trim the number of its policyholders. That's because Citizens is allowed under state law to impose a surcharge on most insurance policy holders, including those with auto insurance policies, if it cannot pay off its claims following a major storm.
Several years ago legislators capped the annual rate hikes at 10 percent.
=======
        <date>Sat Jun 27 00:01:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman gets to cross century plant off her bucket list (PHOTOS)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/woman-gets-to-cross-century-plant-off-her-bucket-list-photos-1.494257</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Locals cheer on U.S. in the Women's World Cup final
Ian Yancey pours red, white and blue shots for the patrons at Rick's Crab Trap in Fort Walton Beach.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 09:41 PM.
Photo Galleries
<<<<<<< HEAD
Just one day after America celebrate its birthday, the country had another reason to cheer.
The United States has won its third Women's World Cup.
At Rick's Crab Trap in Fort Walton Beach, about a dozen patrons sat at the bar wearing red, white and blue gear and chanting "USA, USA."
"I've always been up on soccer, but I've followed this team since 1999," said Adley Vahue, who sat with his wife Meagan in a cozy booth. "Ever since I saw Brandy Chastain take off her jersey in celebration."
Mary Beth Yancey watched the entire game and hung out with her son, Ian, who is a bartender at Rick's. For every goal the U.S. scored, he prepared red, white and blue shots to hand out for free.
He had a hard time keeping up as the team scored two goals in less than six minutes in the beginning of the game.
"Can you imagine that?" Mary Beth said.
An avid soccer fan, Ian, was sporting a red and white jersey for the evening. He said he didn't mind having to work so long as he got to see the game.
"I love the technicality of the game...to watch 11 people work in unison," he said. "These are the best athletes in the world  men and women."
Kasce Terry stayed after her shift at Rick's to watch the game. She admitted it was a little disappointing to see so few people watching the Women's World Cup.
"It was packed last year for the men's games," she said. "And they didn't even get this far."
While it was no surprise to see the American women celebrate their victory after defeating Japan 5-2, Terry said it was exciting to watch.
"I never expected there would be so many goals so quickly," she said before taking a shot. "I don't think I'll be doing any more celebrating after this. I have to work tomorrow."
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Jennie McKeon at 850-315-4434 or jmckeon@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @JennieMnwfdn.
=======
Century plant
All she wanted was a bloom from her plant.
Unfortunately for Mickey Patterson, those blooms stood at least 20 feet in the air atop a century plant that she had placed in her yard in 1972. After years of waiting, the plant started putting up its massive stalk in March as it began its first and only blooming.
I thought if that thing had limbs I could climb up and cut a bloom, said the 94-year-old Fort Walton Beach resident.
But it didnt. Instead she called the Ocean City-Wright Fire Department, who brought out a fire truck equipped with a bucket, and lifted Patterson high enough up to cut a bloom herself.
Ive waited to pick that bloom for 43 years, remarked Patterson Thursday, as she showed off the large and unusual looking bloom to family and friends for photographs. It was worth it all.
Contact Daily News Photographer Devon Ravine at 850-315-4427 or dravine@nwfdailynews.com. Follow him on Twitter @DevonRnwfdn.
DEVON RAVINE | Daily News
Mickey Patterson, center, gazes up at the century plant in her Stewart Circle home Thursday afternoon. Patterson planted the cactus in 1972 and it finally started to bloom this year.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f

>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 00:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>STORIES FROM THE STREET: Teens charged with burglary, arson after fire</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/stories-from-the-street-teens-charged-with-burglary-arson-after-fire-1.495672</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>STORIES FROM THE STREET: Teens charged with burglary, arson after fire
Shane Michael Swann
By TRISTA PRUETT | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 05:55 PM.
Man tries to buy beer with phony money
NICEVILLE - A clerk at Tom Thumb, 1001 Valparaiso Blvd., called police to report a man had tried to buy beer and an energy shot with a fake bill.
The clerk called Niceville Police officers around 9:40 p.m. on June 16, according to the call log. He said the man came into the store and picked up some beer and an energy shot.
He then tried to pay for the items with a forged $10, the log said. The clerk said he noticed the bill felt "different," didn't have the watermark and reacted to the counterfeit pen.
When the clerk made a comment to the man about the bill being forged, the man looked at it and said, "yeah, you're right it does look phony," according to the log. He then left the bill and the items on the counter and left the store.
Teens charged with burglary, arson after fire
DESTIN - Five teens between the ages of 13 and 18 are charged with burglary and three of the five with arson, after a fire at a private pool on June 27.
Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputies were called at 6:52 a.m. to a locked and gated pool on June 27, according to arrest reports. The pool has a 4 foot, black metal fence with gated access and a small bath house within the fenced area.
A witness who lives next door told deputies that she heard loud noises coming from the pool area around 6:30 a.m., reports said. She said she saw four teenage boys put on backpacks, get on their bicycles and leave through the south gate.
She said it appeared they had slept their overnight and were gathering their belongings, according to reports. She went down to the pool and found a life preserver ring on the pool deck on fire.
Deputies arrived and found the men's bathroom was also on fire and was still burning, reports said. Destin Fire Department arrived and put out the fire.
Two gas grills were also turned on with one burning and one "free flowing gas," according to reports. Deputies found five teens on bicycles with backpacks around 7:30 a.m. in the Best Buy parking lot.
The teens, 18-year-old man Shane Michael Swann, of Milton, and two 14-year-olds, a 15-year-old and a 13-year-old, were detained, reports said. Swann admitted to going into the gated pool area without permission to swim in the pool.
The minors are not being named due to their ages.
Swann said he'd seen the 15-year-old and one 14-year-old set the life preserver on fire, according to reports. One of the 14-year-olds admitted to setting the preserver on fire and then putting lighter fluid on the bathroom wall and floor before setting it on fire.
None of the boys could give deputies any reasons for their actions, reports said. Damage is estimated at $2,000.
The 13-year-old and one of the 14-year-olds are charged with burglary.
Swann, the other 14-year-old and the 15-year-old are charged with arson and burglary.
The 15-year-old is also charged with possession of drug paraphernalia.

=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:20:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Patriots’ Trail funding still intact</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/patriots-trail-funding-still-intact-1.493849</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Patriots Trail funding still intact
File photo
By KARI C. BARLOW | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:20 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  The final phase of the Bud and Dorie Day Patriots Trail will continue as planned despite funding for the project being vetoed by Gov. Rick Scott.
When Scotts $461 million in vetoes were announced Tuesday, city officials became concerned about the fate of the trail.
But City Manager Michael Beedie confirmed Wednesday that in late May his staff had requested  and was granted  a funding extension by the state Department of Economic Opportunity.
Because weve got an agreement, which is similar to a contract, the money is there, he said. We still have, like, $90,000 left to spend.
State Rep. Matt Gaetz praised the citys forethought and said he was pleased with the extension.
Thats a good thing, he said. We should put the money to use locally.
Initially, the city had to spend the remainder of its initial $125,000 allocation by June 30. Now it will have until Sept. 15 to complete the final phase of the trail  which includes the demolition of the Docie Bass Recreation Center and the construction of a courtyard with pavilions and landscaping in its place.
Weve basically got three months to do it, Beedie said. Its going to really push us into overdrive.
He said his staff is currently working on fast-tracking the design and should bid out the work in the next few weeks.
Patriots Trail, which officially opened to the public May 28, winds down Staff Drive, Nebraska Avenue and California Drive to Ferry Park. Its first phase features 16 historical markers with information about Bud and Dorie Days life together and was paid for primarily with an $88,000 grant from the Florida Recreational Trails program.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kari C. Barlow at 850-315-4438 or kbarlow@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KariBnwfdn.
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 23:17:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Shelter-in-progress gets first guest</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/shelter-in-progress-gets-first-guest-1.494228</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Shelter-in-progress gets first guest
Richard Whittington was the first official resident of One Hopeful Place, which will open this fall. He stayed in a camper at the old sewage plant at the organizers request.
WENDY VICTORA | Daily News
By WENDY VICTORA | Daily News
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 04:17 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH  Richard Whittington fell asleep Thursday night in a small camper parked at what will become the areas first permanent cold night shelter.
Whittington, who has been living in his van since 2012, was the first official resident of the facility that will become One Hopeful Place.
The 61-year-old stayed at the plant, which is at the end of North Beal Extension, at the request of Community Solutions, the nonprofit developing the shelter.
The Community Development Corporation had stipulated in its grant that someone had to stay on site before the end of June to verify the sites worthiness and to make sure organizers were on pace.
Whittington was selected by local homeless advocates in the community.
I think its marvelous, said Whittington, who moved onto the streets after his mother died and he lost her home. The only drawback I see is its so out of the way.
Transportation can be such a fragile thing, he added. It can come and go on a whim.
The first phase of the shelter  a cold night shelter  is expected to be complete by the end of October. Subsequent phases will expand the facility.
Whittington works as a telemarketer, which helps him keep his car and pays for his basic needs. He doesnt make enough to get off the streets and hasnt had luck getting more substantial employment.
He says he hopes he doesnt have to use One Hopeful Place when it opens, but guesses he might still be on the streets.
The location is remote, he said, but beautiful
It was quiet, he said. It cooled off and was marvelous. You could hear the frogs and crickets. The rainfall on the roof put me to sleep. It was great.
Contact Daily News Managing Editor Wendy Victora at 850-315-4478 or wvictora@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @WendyVnwfdn.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Mon Jul 06 00:50:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>HIDDEN GEMS: Bring the kids to Chipley Park</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/hidden-gems-bring-the-kids-to-chipley-park-1.495664</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>HIDDEN GEMS: Bring the kids to Chipley Park
DeFuniak Springs residents Leslie Coone and her son Easton Taylor play on the swings at Chipley Park.
JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
By JENNIE McKEON | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 05:50 PM.
Photo Galleries
Chipley Park
Located in the center of DeFuniak Springs, Chipley Park is the perfect place to spend an afternoon outside, with plenty of things to see and do. One of the more popular activities is to walk around the nearly 40-acre Lake DeFuniak to get a 360-degree view of the park. And if you get too hot, you can always venture inside the Walton-DeFuniak Library for cool air conditioning and R&amp;R (reading and relaxation).
Park it here: Chipley Park is equipped with recreational must-haves including picnic tables (some are even shaded), grills, and more than 40 acres of land so you can spread out.
Be a good sport: Theres plenty of space for a game of catch or whatever sport you choose. Take a walk around Lake DeFuniak and gawk at the historical buildings. Anglers can also take advantage of two fishing piers. The lake is open to boat fishing as well for electric motors with 1 horsepower or less.
Wanna play? Kids can burn energy in the playground area, which includes a slide, swings, merry-go-round and sand box.
Tip: As you walk around the lake, take time for pit stops at the Chautauqua Building and the Walton-DeFuniak library. Regular events are held in the open amphitheater, located by the restrooms. Bring a camera for photo ops of the ducks and turtles hanging out by the waters edge.

</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Mon Jul 06 00:34:58 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>State funding for schools serving military children gets a boost </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/state-funding-for-schools-serving-military-children-gets-a-boost-1.495662</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>State funding for schools serving military children gets a boost
By KATIE TAMMEN | Daily News
Published: Sunday, July 5, 2015 at 05:34 PM.
It was a Tuesday morning when the unique needs of students with parents in military crystallized for Tim Wyrosdick.
The calendar said Sept. 11, 2001 and Wyrosdick was the principal of Navarre High School. The population of students tied to the military, specifically Hurlburt Field and the 1st Special Operations Squadron, was high.
Students became very nervous, said the now-superintendent of Santa Rosa County Schools. And for the next two years, we saw parents in and out of homes at the drop of a hat.
Earlier this year, he stood before part of the Florida legislature at the request of Sen. Don Gaetz and asked for a boost in state funding for schools serving military children.
When the governor signed the final budget last month, $13 million was set aside for the military-connected student supplement.
We had to work hard to get this done, Gaetz said. Because it disproportionately affects counties.
The funding offsets the property taxes not collected in each of the counties because the land is owned by the state and federal government, he said.
Santa Rosa County got almost $1.2 million through the grant. Okaloosa County received $2.4 million to help offset the costs of having nearly half of its land owned by the government.
Bay and Escambia counties also will benefit from the funding. Walton was not included.
I thank our entire Florida Legislature for their recognition of the needs of our military connected students, and the enhancement this will bring to our ongoing efforts to support these students and their families, said Superintendent Mary Beth Jackson in an emailed statement to the Daily News.
Okaloosa and Santa Rosa counties already have multiple programs in place to support military children and their families including special guidance counselors and teams ready to help transition them in and out quickly when their parents get military orders.
Up until now, both districts have primarily relied on their regular budgets - including limited federal impact dollars - and other grants.
This money will help districts pay for what theyre already doing without removing money from another part of their budget and open up the possibility for more.
Its a pretty intense opportunity for us, Wyrosdick said.
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Katie Tammen at 850-315-4440 or ktammen@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @KatieTnwfdn.
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Thu Jun 25 00:03:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Couple sentenced in fatal stabbing case</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/couple-sentenced-in-fatal-stabbing-case-1.493834</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Couple sentenced in fatal stabbing case
Amy and Jeffrey Brandenburg
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 05:03 PM.
CRESTVIEW  A husband and wife charged in connection with a fatal stabbing on March 8, 2014, have been sentenced after entering into plea agreements with the State Attorneys Office.
Circuit Judge Michael Flowers sentenced Jeffrey Allen Brandenburg on Tuesday to 30 years in the Florida Department of Corrections as a habitual felony offender. According to a press release from the State Attorneys Office, Brandenburg pleaded no contest to manslaughter in the death of Samuel Cornish, who was found on State Road 85 after suffering a stab wound to the chest.
According to earlier reports, Cornish was taken to North Okaloosa Medical Center, where he was later pronounced dead. The Medical Examiners Office conducted an autopsy and determined he died from a lacerated aorta.
Brandenburg and his wife, Amy, fled to Brewton, Alabama, where they were arrested and detained on March 10.
A nearby business surveillance camera caught footage of a car that fit the description of one owned by the Brandenburgs, and a witness told investigators the couple complained about being ripped off while purchasing narcotics from Cornish, an earlier police report said.
The witness also told police the Brandenburgs said they saw Cornish walking down the road around and stopped their vehicle. The witness said Jeffrey Brandenburg got out and remained out of Amy Brandenburgs sight before he returned with blood on his hands.
The witness told investigators that Amy Brandenburg asked Jeffrey Brandenburg what had happened, and he cursed at her and told her to drive away, police reports said.
Jonathan Schlechter, who prosecuted the case, said Amy Brandenburg entered a plea to a charge of accessory after the fact to aggravated battery.
She was sentenced to 11 months and 29 days in the county jail, followed by four years of probation, Schlecter said. She also agreed to testify against her co-defendant.
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 22:55:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Google's search for test facility led to climatic lab (VIDEO)</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/google-s-search-for-test-facility-led-to-climatic-lab-video-1.494217</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Google's search for test facility led to climatic lab (VIDEO)
Special to the Daily News
By KELLY HUMPHREY | Daily News
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 03:55 PM.
EGLIN AFB  For two years researchers at Google have been working on a project using balloons to send wireless signals to underserved corners of the world.
Google describes it's "Project Loon" as "a network of balloons traveling on the edge of space, designed to connect people in rural and remote areas, help fill coverage gaps, and bring people back online after disasters."
The project marked the second anniversary of its inception by moving into the massive McKinley Climatic Laboratory.
VIDEO: See a Google video of the balloon concept.
"The McKinley Climatic Lab provides testing for commercial companies throughout the year," base spokeswoman Sara Vidoni said. "This testing ensures our engineers, machinists and staff remain well-equipped and prepared for when a military test needs to be accomplished. While in the facility, the customer sets the parameters needed to test the limits of their item and our team creates the weather conditions that will make that happen."
Vidoni added that while the main chamber at the McKinley Climatic Lab routinely tests items down to -65 degrees Fahrenheit, for the Google balloon test the chamber was lowered down to -83 degrees.
In an interview with Wired magazine, Google engineer Mahesh Krishnaswamy described the lab as a "giant refrigerator in Florida."
The lab's ability to produce sub-zero temperatures, high winds, rain and other challenging weather allows Google to simulate the conditions that its balloons might encounter while flying through the stratosphere.
"Our earliest tests started back in 2011, using a weather balloon and basic, off-the-shelf radio parts," a post on the company's Google+ page explained.
"These tests showed that balloon-powered Internet might just work, but the team knew that weather balloons wouldnt be a long term solution since they arent built to last in the stratosphere."
The Internet giant waited two years to get access to the McKinley lab. According to Krishnaswamy, the wait was worth it.
Weve never been able to look at the balloon in the cold, he told Wired. This allows us to get up close and personal at these temperatures  . The idea is to try and get a good understanding of how the materials behave.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
Contact Daily News Staff Writer Kelly Humphrey at 850-315-4443 or khumphrey@nwfdailynews.com. Follow her on Twitter @kellyhnwfdn.
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:48:11 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Summer school middle, high students released early </title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/summer-school-middle-high-students-released-early-1.493759</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Summer school middle, high students released early
By STAFF REPORT | Daily News
Published: Wednesday, June 24, 2015 at 12:48 PM.
Middle and high school students attending summer school in Okaloosa County were sent home early Wednesday because of issues with the computer program they use.
Students were released about two hours early after it became clear a credit recovery program students use called Edgenuity was not going to fixed quickly, according to Assistant Superintendent Marcus Chambers.
The statewide issue began around 9 a.m. It also impacted Okaloosa Online.
We waited a decent amount of time, probably an hour an half, Chambers said.
Parents were notified classes were canceled for the day just before lunchtime, according to a news release from the district.
Chambers said they have summer school programs at every high school and middle school in the county except Ruckel and Lewis, which are combined into one program.
Summer school for the older students was expected to resume normal operations on Thursday.
Its a self-paced program, so theyll be able to pick up wherever they left off, Chambers said.
Elementary school students weren't affected.
Parents are asked to contact individual schools if they have additional questions.
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 17:32:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Supreme Court rules gay marriage legal nationwide</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/breaking-news-supreme-court-rules-gay-marriage-legal-nationwide-1.494168</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>COMMENTS
Supreme Court rules gay marriage legal nationwide
The crowd reacts as the ruling on same-sex marriage was announced outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, Friday. The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the US.
JACQUELYN MARTIN | AP
By The Associated Press
Published: Friday, June 26, 2015 at 10:32 AM.
WASHINGTON  Same-sex couples won the right to marry nationwide Friday as a divided Supreme Court handed a crowning victory to the gay rights movement, setting off a jubilant cascade of long-delayed weddings in states where they had been forbidden.
"No longer may this liberty be denied," said Justice Anthony Kennedy.
The vote was narrow  5-4  but Kennedy's majority opinion was clear and firm: "The court now holds that same-sex couples may exercise the fundamental right to marry."
The ruling will put an end to same-sex marriage bans in the 14 states that still maintain them, and provide an exclamation point for breathtaking changes in the nation's social norms in recent years. As recently as last October, just over one-third of the states permitted gay marriages.
Kennedy's reading of the ruling elicited tears in the courtroom, euphoria outside and the immediate issuance of marriage licenses to same-sex couples in at least eight states. In Dallas, Kenneth Denson said he and Gabriel Mendez had been legally married in 2013 in California but "we're Texans; we want to get married in Texas."
In praise of the decision, President Barack Obama called it "justice that arrives like a thunderbolt."
Four of the court's justices weren't cheering. The dissenters accused their colleagues of usurping power that belongs to the states and to voters, and short-circuiting a national debate about same-sex marriage.
"This court is not a legislature. Whether same-sex marriage is a good idea should be of no concern to us," Chief Justice John Roberts wrote in dissent. Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in nearly 10 years as chief justice.
"If you are among the many Americans  of whatever sexual orientation  who favor expanding same-sex marriage, by all means celebrate today's decision," Roberts said. "But do not celebrate the Constitution. It had nothing to do with it."
Justice Antonin Scalia said he was not concerned so much about same-sex marriage as "this court's threat to American democracy." He termed the decision a "judicial putsch." Justices Samuel Alito and Clarence Thomas also dissented.
Several religious organizations criticized the decision.
The U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops said it was "profoundly immoral and unjust for the government to declare that two people of the same sex can constitute a marriage."
Kennedy said nothing in the court's ruling would force religions to condone, much less perform, weddings to which they object. And he said the couples seeking the right to marry should not have to wait for the political branches of government to act.
The 14th Amendment to the Constitution requires states to allow same-sex couples to marry on the same basis as heterosexuals, he said
"The dynamic of our constitutional system is that individuals need not await legislative action before asserting a fundamental right. The nation's courts are open to injured individuals who come to them to vindicate their own direct, personal stake in our basic charter," Kennedy wrote in his fourth major opinion in support of gay rights since 1996. It came on the anniversary of two of those earlier decisions.
"No union is more profound than marriage," Kennedy wrote, joined by the court's four more liberal justices.
The stories of the people asking for the right to marry "reveal that they seek not to denigrate marriage but rather to live their lives, or honor their spouses' memory, joined by its bond," Kennedy said.
As he read his opinion, spectators in the courtroom wiped away tears when the import of the decision became clear. One of those in the audience was James Obergefell, the lead plaintiff in the Supreme Court fight.
Outside, Obergefell held up a photo of his late spouse, John Arthur, and said the ruling establishes that "our love is equal." He added, "This is for you, John."
Obama placed a congratulatory phone call to Obergefell, which he took amid a throng of reporters outside the courthouse.
Speaking a few minutes later at the White House, Obama praised the decision as an affirmation of the principle that "all Americans are created equal."
The crowd in front of the courthouse at the top of Capitol Hill grew in the minutes following the ruling. The Gay Men's Chorus of Washington, D.C., sang the "Star-Spangled Banner." Motorists honked their horns in support as they passed by the crowd, which included a smattering of same-sex marriage opponents.
The ruling will not take effect immediately because the court gives the losing side roughly three weeks to ask for reconsideration. But county clerks in Alabama, Georgia, Mississippi, Ohio, North Dakota, South Dakota, Tennessee and Texas began issuing licenses to same-sex couples within hours of the decision.
The cases before the court involved laws from Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee that define marriage as the union of a man and a woman. Those states have not allowed same-sex couples to marry within their borders, and they also have refused to recognize valid marriages from elsewhere.
Just two years ago, the Supreme Court struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law that denied a range of government benefits to legally married same-sex couples.
Justices Stephen Breyer, Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Elena Kagan and Sonia Sotomayor formed the majority with Kennedy on Friday, the same lineup as two years ago.
The earlier decision in United States v. Windsor did not address the validity of state marriage bans, but courts across the country, with few exceptions, said its logic compelled them to invalidate state laws that prohibited gay and lesbian couples from marrying.
There are an estimated 390,000 married same-sex couples in the United States, according to UCLA's Williams Institute, which tracks the demographics of gay and lesbian Americans. Another 70,000 couples living in states that do not currently permit them to wed would get married in the next three years, the institute says. Roughly 1 million same-sex couples, married and unmarried, live together in the United States, the institute says.
The Obama administration backed the right of same-sex couples to marry. The Justice Department's decision to stop defending the federal anti-marriage law in 2011 was an important moment for gay rights, and Obama declared his support for same-sex marriage in 2012.
The states affected by Friday's ruling are Alabama, Arkansas, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Michigan, Mississippi, most of Missouri, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, South Dakota, Tennessee and Texas.

WASHINGTON  The Supreme Court declared Friday that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States.
Gay and lesbian couples already could marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia. The court's 5-4 ruling means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote the majority opinion, just as he did in the court's previous three major gay rights cases dating back to 1996. It came on the anniversary of two of those earlier decisions.
"No union is more profound than marriage," Kennedy wrote, joined by the court's four more liberal justices.
The four dissenting justices each filed a separate opinion explaining their views.
"But this court is not a legislature. Whether same-sex marriage is a good idea should be of no concern to us," Chief Justice John Roberts wrote in dissent. Roberts read a summary of his dissent from the bench, the first time he has done so in nearly 10 years as chief justice.
Justice Antonin Scalia said he is not concerned so much about same-sex marriage, but about "this court's threat to American democracy." Justices Samuel Alito and Clarence Thomas also dissented.
The ruling will not take effect immediately because the court gives the losing side roughly three weeks to ask for reconsideration. But some state officials and county clerks might decide there is little risk in issuing marriage licenses to same-sex couples.
The cases before the court involved laws from Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Tennessee that define marriage as the union of a man and a woman. Those states have not allowed same-sex couples to marry within their borders and they also have refused to recognize valid marriages from elsewhere.
Just two years ago, the Supreme Court struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law that denied a range of government benefits to legally married same-sex couples.
The decision in United States v. Windsor did not address the validity of state marriage bans, but courts across the country, with few exceptions, said its logic compelled them to invalidate state laws that prohibited gay and lesbian couples from marrying.
The number of states allowing same-sex marriage has grown rapidly. As recently as October, just over one-third of the states permitted same-sex marriage.
There are an estimated 390,000 married same-sex couples in the United States, according to UCLA's Williams Institute, which tracks the demographics of gay and lesbian Americans. Another 70,000 couples living in states that do not currently permit them to wed would get married in the next three years, the institute says. Roughly 1 million same-sex couples, married and unmarried, live together in the United States, the institute says.
The Obama administration backed the right of same-sex couples to marry. The Justice Department's decision to stop defending the federal anti-marriage law in 2011 was an important moment for gay rights and President Barack Obama declared his support for same-sex marriage in 2012.
10:15 a.m.
The Supreme Court ruling that grants same-sex couples the right to marry nationwide comes on a date with legal significance.
Two previous rulings by the high court also came on June 26. Both were also written by Justice Anthony Kennedy 
In 2003, the court issued its ruling in the case Lawrence versus Texas, striking down state laws that made gay sex a crime.
And on the same date in 2013, it struck down part of the federal anti-gay marriage law in the case U.S. versus Windsor.
10:05 a.m.
The Supreme Court has declared that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States.
Gay and lesbian couples already can marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia. The court's ruling on Friday means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote the majority opinion, just as he did in the court's previous three major gay rights cases dating back to 1996.10:05 a.m.
The Supreme Court has declared that same-sex couples have a right to marry anywhere in the United States.
Gay and lesbian couples already can marry in 36 states and the District of Columbia. The court's ruling on Friday means the remaining 14 states, in the South and Midwest, will have to stop enforcing their bans on same-sex marriage.
The outcome is the culmination of two decades of Supreme Court litigation over marriage, and gay rights generally.
Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote the majority opinion, just as he did in the court's previous three major gay rights cases dating back to 1996.

>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jul 05 02:22:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Pedestrian struck while crossing road</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/pedestrian-struck-while-crossing-road-1.495633</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Wed Jun 24 19:31:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UPDATED: Deputy doing well after surgery</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/deputy-injured-in-crash-1.493752</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>in serious condition following the accident at 5:25 a.m., according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Austin
went to surgery mid-morning.
He came out of surgery well, Sheriffs Maj. Bob Johnson said in an email Wednesday afternoon. He is in good condition.
Austin
, 36, was westbound in his patrol vehicle when he lost control near mile marker 53 just west of Crestview, the FHP reported. The vehicle left the road, spun around and struck a tree.
He was not wearing a seat belt, according to FHP.
Emergency crews had to free
Austin
from the vehicle when they arrived, the Sheriffs Office said.
A photo shared by the Sheriffs Office showed heavy front-end damage to his Chevrolet Impala.
The Sheriffs Office noted in a news release that heavy rain reduced visibility at the time of the crash.
The FHP continues to investigate.
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 04:06:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman arrested after attack with stiletto</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/woman-arrested-after-attack-with-stiletto-1.494150</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Pedestrian struck while crossing road
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
<<<<<<< HEAD
Published: Saturday, July 4, 2015 at 07:22 PM.
MILTON - A teenager from Pace was taken to a Pensacola hospital early Saturday after he was hit by a vehicle while walking across Willard Norris Road.
Sylvia L. Faulk, 58, of Pace, was driving a 1999 Nissan Maxima east on Willard Norris about 2:10 a.m. when she struck 17-year-old Joshua J. Jones just west of Pine Blossom Road, according to the Florida Highway Patrol.
Jones was taken to Sacred Heart Hospital in serious condition.
Faulk and her passenger, 18-year-old Patrick C. Koehler were not hurt.
The FHPs investigation was continuing later Saturday.
=======
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 09:06 PM.
NICEVILLE - A 21-year-old Niceville woman is in custody after a warrant was issued due to charges that she attacked her boyfriend with a stiletto.
The woman, who is not being named to protect the victim's identity, was arrested on June 7.
The attack occurred on March 28, around 6:30 p.m., according to the arrest report. She and her boyfriend were reportedly living together in a room at Tisa's Friendly Inn.
The woman hit her boyfriend in the head with the heel of a four-inch stiletto shoe, the report said. He was treated for a three-inch wound to his head.
The wound went through the skin stopping at the skull (approximately three centimeters deep) and required six staples to close, a doctor reported to Niceville Police officers. A witness told police that the woman repeatedly said, "I did not mean to hurt him."
She is charged with aggravated battery causing great bodily harm.
Her next scheduled court date is July 27.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Sun Jul 05 02:21:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Woman injured in fall from motorcycle</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/woman-injured-in-fall-from-motorcycle-1.495632</Link>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Wed Jun 24 04:15:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of trespassing after telling deputy he was going to</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-trespassing-after-telling-deputy-he-was-going-to-1.493675</Link>
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Man accused of trespassing after telling deputy he was going to
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
Published: Tuesday, June 23, 2015 at 09:15 PM.
CRESTVIEW - A 20-year-old Freeport man is accused of trespassing at a home after telling an Okaloosa County Sheriff's deputy that he encountered that he was going to back to the home.
The man was issued a trespass warning at the home on June 7 around 10 p.m., according to the arrest report. The homeowner called police to report that he was at work and his daughter was home alone.
The man was knocking on all of the exterior doors and windows and had tried to use a credit card to gain entry to the home, the report said. The daughter said she'd opened the door and told the man to leave.
Crestview Police officers issued a trespass warning at the homeowner's request.
On June 8, around 4 a.m., a mere six hours later, the man encountered a deputy during an unrelated incident, according to the report. He allegedly told the deputy that he was going to return to a residence that he'd been trespassed from earlier that evening.
While conducting a security check on the home, a Crestview officer saw the man go onto the property.
The man is charged with misdemeanor trespassing.
His next scheduled court date is July 7.
=======
        <date>Fri Jun 26 03:57:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Man accused of theft of 12-pack of Corona Light</title>
        <Link>http://www.nwfdailynews.com/local/crime/police-blotters/man-accused-of-theft-of-12-pack-of-corona-light-1.494149</Link>
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
        <Description/>
        <MainBody>Woman injured in fall from motorcycle
STOCK PHOTOGRAPHY
By STAFF REPORTS | Daily News
<<<<<<< HEAD
Published: Saturday, July 4, 2015 at 07:21 PM.
DeFUNIAK SPRINGS - A 27-year-old woman was flown to a Pensacola hospital early Saturday after she fell off a moving motorcycle.
Travis R. Atlow, 29, of DeFuniak Springs, was driving the 2000 Honda RVT1000 west on Sunrise Road near Pretty Pond Lane at 2:48 a.m., according to the Florida Highway Patrol. He accelerated at the same time passenger Jessica C. Cook of DeFuniak Springs was adjusting her sitting position, and she fell off, FHP said.
Cook was flown by helicopter to Sacred Heart Hospital with serious injuries.
FHP was still investigating the accident later Saturday.
=======
Published: Thursday, June 25, 2015 at 08:57 PM.
FORT WALTON BEACH - A 46-year-old Fort Walton Beach man is charged with taking a 12-pack of Corona Light from a Circle K.
The man went into the store at around 3 p.m. on June 8, according to the arrest report. He picked up a 12-pack of beer and allegedly walked out of the store without paying.
He was caught on security footage and was identified by a witness, the report said.
He is charged with petit theft.
His next scheduled court date is June 30.
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
Reader comments posted to this article may be published in our print edition. All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published                          without permission. Links are encouraged.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
