<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:28:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK takes hard line on EU reform as Cameron starts European tour</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/GHa5YioMe1s/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON/PARIS (Reuters) - Prime Minister David Cameron said Britain's relationship with the European Union was "not good enough" after his foreign minister warned the bloc had to change its founding treaties and give London a meaty reform deal to keep it as a member.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK takes hard line on EU reform as Cameron starts European tour
LONDON/PARIS | By Andrew Osborn and Ingrid Melander
LONDON/PARIS Prime Minister David Cameron said Britain's relationship with the European Union was "not good enough" after his foreign minister warned the bloc had to change its founding treaties and give London a meaty reform deal to keep it as a member.
Speaking in Paris on the first day of a whirlwind European tour to try to drum up support for EU reform, Cameron said he was confident he could get a settlement, something he has promised to secure before giving Britons an EU membership in-out referendum by the end of 2017.
"My priority is to reform the European Union to make it more competitive and address the concerns of the British people about our membership. The status quo is not good enough," said Cameron, flanked by French President Francois Hollande.
"What matters is that the European Union and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative enough to respond to these issues."
Cameron has various demands, the thrust of which are to claw back powers from Brussels to allow Britain to opt out of what he sees as a dangerous shift to greater political integration.
Cameron met Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte in The Hague earlier on Thursday before starting talks with Hollande. He is due in Warsaw and Berlin on Friday for talks with Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz and German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
Hollande said France wanted Britain to stay in the EU, something he said was in the best interests of the bloc and of London. He indicated he was ready to listen to Cameron's reform proposals.
Earlier, British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond had warned the EU needed to amend its founding treaties to accommodate Britain and make substantive concessions to keep it in.
"If our partners do not agree with us, do not work with us to deliver that (reform) package, then we rule nothing out," Hammond told BBC radio.
Speaking at a G7 meeting in Germany, finance minister George Osborne struck a softer tone, saying he sensed "a real willingness" among other EU countries to negotiate.
POTENTIAL SETBACK
Cameron's government introduced a law into parliament on Thursday to guarantee the EU referendum will be held by the end of 2017. It also disclosed the question voters will be asked, making it "Yes" to stay in, "No" to leave.
Some EU countries have made clear they have no appetite to re-open the bloc's treaties to suit Britain, which wants to alter them so it can restrict and delay EU migrants' access to its welfare system.
But London has long asserted that the treaties would need to be overhauled anyway as part of an inevitable drive to further integrate the euro zone.
In a potential setback for Cameron, a Franco-German paper seen by Reuters shows the two countries have agreed plans to strengthen cooperation among the 19 countries using the euro currency, without changing existing treaties.
Hammond said he expected some EU states initially to adopt a hardline negotiating position.
"What matters is getting it right rather than doing it quickly," Hammond said of the renegotiation. "We're certainly not going to trade substantive reform just for getting it done quickly."
(Additional reporting by William James and Michael Holden in London, John Irish in Paris and William Schomberg in Dresden; Editing by Guy Faulconbridge and Andrew Heavens )
The Union Flag flies next to the European Flag outside the European Commission building in central London May 25, 2014.
Reuters/Neil Hall
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 29 04:07:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter defies calls to quit as FIFA scandal widens</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/YUO5AFNHbdo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ZURICH (Reuters) - The corruption charges engulfing world soccer's governing body have heaped shame and humiliation on the game, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said on Thursday, although he flatly rejected calls to resign over the widening scandal.</Description>
        <MainBody>ZURICH | By Mike Collett and Brian Homewood
ZURICH The corruption charges engulfing world soccer's governing body have heaped shame and humiliation on the game, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said on Thursday, although he flatly rejected calls to resign over the widening scandal.
With FIFA facing the worst crisis in its 111-year history, Michel Platini, who heads Europe's soccer confederation UEFA, said he had told Blatter to go "with tears in my eyes", but the 79-year-old had refused.
"I said, 'I'm asking you to leave, FIFA's image is terrible.' He said that he couldn't leave all of a sudden," Platini, a former French international, told reporters.
In a bullish speech opening a FIFA Congress in Zurich, Blatter said the turbulence of the last two days, which included the arrest of leading soccer officials at their luxury Swiss hotel, had brought "shame and humiliation" to world soccer.
Making his first public appearance since Wednesday's dramatic events, which were triggered by a U.S.-led investigation into allegations of rampant bribe-taking, Blatter said there was no room "for corruption of any kind".
"The events of (Wednesday) have cast a long shadow over football and this Congress," said Blatter, who is standing for a fifth mandate as FIFA president in Friday's election, in which Prince Ali bin Al Hussein of Jordan is his only challenger.
Ignoring calls to step down, Blatter said: "I know many people hold me ultimately responsible ... (but) I cannot monitor everyone all the time. If people want to do wrong, they will also try to hide it."
Platini said 45 or 46 of UEFA's 53 member associations would vote for Prince Ali. But it appeared that Blatter still commanded enough of FIFA's 209 national associations to secure victory.
SPONSOR CONCERNS
Adding to the pressure, there were growing concerns about the allegations from major sponsors, many of whom have solidly backed FIFA despite nearly 20 years of bribery and corruption allegations.
German sportswear company Adidas said FIFA should do more to establish transparent compliance standards. Anheuser-Busch InBev, whose Budweiser brand is a sponsor of the 2018 World Cup, said it was closely monitoring developments.
Credit card company Visa Inc urged immediate reforms.
In a strongly worded statement, Visa said: "Our sponsorship has always focused on supporting the teams, enabling a great fan experience, and inspiring communities to come together and celebrate the spirit of competition and personal achievement ... it is important that FIFA makes changes now so that the focus remain on these going forward. Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship".
Coca-Cola Co, another sponsor, said the charges had "tarnished the mission and ideals of the FIFA World Cup and we have repeatedly expressed our concerns about these serious allegations".
INVESTIGATIONS WIDENING
In countries whose nationals were indicted in the United States, more investigations were under way.
An judge in Argentina ordered the arrest of three businessmen accused of conspiring to win and keep hold of lucrative media rights contracts from regional soccer federations through the payment of up to $110 million in bribes.
In Brazil, the Senate, led by former national soccer star Romario, now a legislator, moved to open a formal inquiry into bribes that authorities said were paid obtain contracts with the Brazilian Soccer Federation.
Meanwhile, the Miami-based Confederation of North, Central American and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF) president Jeffrey Webb, who was among those arrested, has been provisionally dismissed from his role, the confederation said on Thursday.
CONFIDENT BLATTER
Blatter appeared confident despite the dawn raid by plainclothes police on Wednesday that left seven of the most powerful figures in international football in Swiss custody and facing extradition to the United States on corruption charges.
All seven are contesting extradition, but lawyers said the process could be completed within months.
Nine soccer officials and five sports media and promotions executives were charged by U.S. prosecutors with corruption they said involved more than $150 million in bribes.
Swiss authorities have also announced a criminal investigation into the awarding of the next two World Cup tournaments, which are being hosted in Russia in 2018 and Qatar in 2022.
Both countries have denied any suggestion of wrongdoing over their bids to host one of the world's top sporting events, and Russian President Vladimir Putin accused the United States on Thursday of meddling in an effort to prevent the re-election of Blatter.
"This is yet another blatant attempt to extend its jurisdiction to other states," Putin said, adding that Russia would continue to support Blatter.
FIFA CONGRESS
The FIFA Congress formally got under way on Thursday evening. In the past, the likes of Grace Jones have set the hearts racing of the older men in suits who comprise most of the gathering's constituency.
But times have changed.
The evening was billed as a rather more subdued affair than normal under the banner "Game of Joy, Game of Hope" with dancers and musicians on stage followed by a grand buffet afterward.
The serious business starts on Friday morning in Zurich's Hallenstadion, which is where the announcement of the 2018 and 2022 World Cup venues was made in 2010, decisions which lie at the heart of much of FIFA's current malaise.
With splits opening in the world game, the Asian and African confederations backed Blatter for president, while Western countries said he must go.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said Friday's vote should be delayed in light of the corruption investigation.
British Prime Minister David Cameron backed Prince Ali's candidacy and said there was a strong case for a change of leadership at FIFA. Britain has long been a critic of FIFA and bid for the 2018 World Cup which was awarded to Russia.
Les Murray of Australia, a former FIFA ethics committee member, also called for Blatter to resign.
(Reporting by Mike Collett, writing by Giles Elgood; editing by Peter Millership , Crispian Balmer , Grant McCool and G Crosse)
FIFA President Sepp Blatter arrives for the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
1 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter makes a speech during the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
2 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter leaves the stage after making a speech during the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015. Blatter rejected an emotional plea to resign  from one of the world's soccer greats on Thursday as the corruption...
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
3 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter arrives for the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
4 of 27
right
FBI agents bring out boxes after an operation inside the CONCACAF (Confederation of North, Central America and Caribbean Association Football) offices in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Javier Galeano
5 of 27
right
A combination photo shows eight of the nine football officials indicted for corruption charges in these file photos. From L-R: (top row) then President of the Brazilian Football Confederation Jose Maria Marin, President of the Venezuelan Football Federation Rafael Esquivel,...
Reuters/Staff/Files
6 of 27
right
Federal and local investigators carry boxes from the offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
7 of 27
right
Federal agents walk outside the offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
8 of 27
right
Miami Beach police officers stand outside the headquarters of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, after it was raided by FBI agents in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
9 of 27
right
Security guards stand at the entrance of the headquarters of Traffic Sports in Sao Paulo, Brazil May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Nacho Doce
10 of 27
right
Trinidad and Tobago's former National Security Minister and former FIFA Vice President, Jack Warner, gestures after leaving the offices of the Sunshine Newspaper which he owns, in Arouca, East Trinidad, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Andrea De Silva
11 of 27
right
FBI agents prepare to enter the offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
12 of 27
right
U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch walks by display panels during a news conference at the U.S. Attorney's Office of the Eastern District of New York in Brooklyn, New York May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Shannon Stapleton
13 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter (R) poses with CONMEBOL President Nicolas Leoz after a news conference at the end of the extraordinary congress of the CONMEBOL in Luque near Asuncion, Paraguay in this file picture taken February 5, 2012.
Reuters/Jorge Adorno/Files
14 of 27
right
Acting President of the South American Soccer Federation (CONMEBOL) Eugenio Figueredo gives his first news conference since taking charge in Asuncion, Paraguay, in this April 30, 2013 file photo.
Reuters/Jorge Adorno/Files
15 of 27
right
FIFA President Joseph 'Sepp' Blatter (R) gestures next to CONCACAF President Jeffrey Webb during a news conference at the CONCACAF congress in Panama City in this April 19, 2013 file photo.
Reuters/Carlos Jasso/Files
16 of 27
right
Eduardo Li, President of Costa Rica's Football Federation, speaks to the media in San Antonio de Belen in Costa Rica, in this May 17, 2011 file photo.
Reuters/Juan Carlos Ulate/Files
17 of 27
right
Rafael Esquivel, Venezuela's national soccer federation president, attends a news conference in Caracas, in Venezuela, in this May 10, 2012 file photo.
Reuters/Jorge Silva/Files
18 of 27
right
Jose Maria Marin, president of the Brazilian Football Confederation (CBF), attends a news conference in Asuncion, Paraguay in this April 23, 2013 file photo.
Reuters/Jorge Adorno/Files
19 of 27
right
Walter De Gregorio, FIFA Director of Communications and Public Affairs listens during a news conference at FIFA headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
20 of 27
right
The building housing offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, is seen during a search by FBI agents in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
21 of 27
right
A staff walks past a logo of soccer's international governing body FIFA at their headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
22 of 27
right
Security guards stand at the entrance of the headquarters of Traffic Sports in Sao Paulo, Brazil May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Nacho Doce
23 of 27
right
Flags are pictured in front of the headquarters of soccer's international governing body FIFA in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
24 of 27
right
Members of the media stand outside the Baur au Lac hotel in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
25 of 27
right
FIFA flags are pictured outside the Marritot hotel, where a meeting of the Confederation of African Football (CAF) is taking place, in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
26 of 27
right
Journalists take pictures before a news conference of Walter De Gregorio, FIFA Director of Communications and Public Affairs at FIFA headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 29 03:19:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/NC8e7m04gdo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>AMMAN (Reuters) - The Syrian army has pulled back from the northwestern city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province
AMMAN | By Suleiman Al-Khalidi
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front carry their weapons as they move towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
1 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front gather before moving towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
2 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front ride on a tank as they head towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
3 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front prepare themselves before moving towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
4 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front move towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
5 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front carry their weapons as they move towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
6 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front carry an injured fellow fighter during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
7 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front carry their weapons as they move towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015..
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
8 of 14
right
A member of al Qaeda's Nusra Front carries his weapon as he moves towards his position during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
9 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front fire their weapon during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
10 of 14
right
A member of al Qaeda's Nusra Front stands behind a vehicle before heading towards his position during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
11 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front carry their weapons as they move towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
12 of 14
right
Members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front ride on a pick-up truck as they head towards their positions during an offensive to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
13 of 14
right
Smoke rises during an offensive by members of al Qaeda's Nusra Front to take control of the northwestern city of Ariha from forces loyal to Syria's President Bashar al-Assad, in Idlib province May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Ammar Abdullah
14 of 14
right
AMMAN The Syrian army has pulled back from the northwestern city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
A coalition of rebel groups called Jaish al Fateh, or Conquest Army, said it had taken over the city. Syria's al Qaeda offshoot Nusra Front is a major part of the coalition.
The coalition said it had overrun several checkpoints that defended the city. The Syrian army said intense fighting was going on with Nusra forces that had infiltrated Ariha.
"There are heavy clashes between the army and the terrorists of Jabahat al Nusra who infiltrated inside the city," said an army statement released on state television.
Later the army admitted its forces had pulled back from the city, the latest string of defeats by the Syrian army and a big blow to the morale of President Assad's government forces who have vowed to defeat Sunni militants financed by Saudi Arabia, Qatar and Turkey who seek to overthrow his rule.
"Units of our armed forces evacuated their positions in Ariha and withdrew to defensive positions in the vicinity of the city after battles it fought facing large number of Nusra terrorists," the army source was quoted as saying.
A rebel source from Ahrar al Sham confirmed that street fighting was going on inside the city between army fighters and the insurgents. "There are many bodies that litter the streets," he said, adding that the rebels were searching for Assad's government forces inside the city.
Many civilians have hidden inside shelters.
Syria accuses Turkey of financing and aiding rebels seeking to topple the government. Damascus says foreign jihadi fighters  allowed into Syrian territory by Turkey have played a pivotal role in recent rebel gains.
Rebel sources say they have secured more U.S.-made TOW missiles in recent months that have helped them to gain a military edge over the Syrian army.
The Nusra Front has made gains in northwestern Syria alongside other insurgent groups in recent weeks, seizing the city of Idlib, the town of Jisr al-Shughour and bringing them closer to government-held coastal areas north of the capital.
The loss of Ariha would leave the insurgents in control of  most of Idlib a region that borders Turkey and neighbors President Assad's heartland in Latakia province on the Mediterranean coast.
The city, once home to more than 80,000 people, is strategically located on the main army supply lines between Idlib and Latakia.
Rebel sources said that convoys carrying army forces had fled to Oroum al Jouz, an area west of Ariha and in areas closer to President Assad's ancestral homeland. The army did not comment.
Nusra Front is also a major force against government forces and allied militia around the northern city of Aleppo. It is fighting in southern Syria as well, and its combatants have frequently clashed with Islamic State.
Syria's four-year-old civil war has killed a quarter of a million people and driven nearly 8 million from their homes.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi; Editing by Larry King)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:52:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Blatter defies calls to quit as FIFA scandal widens</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/_6CfV2SLzLE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ZURICH (Reuters) - The corruption charges engulfing world soccer's governing body have heaped shame and humiliation on the game, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said on Thursday, although he flatly rejected calls to resign over the widening scandal.</Description>
        <MainBody>ZURICH | By Mike Collett and Brian Homewood
ZURICH The corruption charges engulfing world soccer's governing body have heaped shame and humiliation on the game, FIFA President Sepp Blatter said on Thursday, although he flatly rejected calls to resign over the widening scandal.
With FIFA facing the worst crisis in its 111-year history, Michel Platini, who heads Europe's soccer confederation UEFA, said he had told Blatter to go "with tears in my eyes", but the 79-year-old had refused.
"I said, 'I'm asking you to leave, FIFA's image is terrible.' He said that he couldn't leave all of a sudden," Platini, a former French international, told reporters.
In a bullish speech opening a FIFA Congress in Zurich, Blatter said the turbulence of the last two days, which included the arrest of leading soccer officials at their luxury Swiss hotel, had brought "shame and humiliation" to world soccer.
Making his first public appearance since Wednesday's dramatic events, which were triggered by a U.S.-led investigation into allegations of rampant bribe-taking, Blatter said there was no room "for corruption of any kind".
"The events of (Wednesday) have cast a long shadow over football and this Congress," said Blatter, who is standing for a fifth mandate as FIFA president in Friday's election, in which Prince Ali bin Al Hussein of Jordan is his only challenger.
Ignoring calls to step down, Blatter said: "I know many people hold me ultimately responsible ... (but) I cannot monitor everyone all the time. If people want to do wrong, they will also try to hide it."
Platini said 45 or 46 of UEFA's 53 member associations would vote for Prince Ali. But it appeared that Blatter still commanded enough of FIFA's 209 national associations to secure victory.
SPONSOR CONCERNS
Adding to the pressure, there were growing concerns about the allegations from major sponsors, many of whom have solidly backed FIFA despite nearly 20 years of bribery and corruption allegations.
German sportswear company Adidas said FIFA should do more to establish transparent compliance standards. Anheuser-Busch InBev, whose Budweiser brand is a sponsor of the 2018 World Cup, said it was closely monitoring developments.
Credit card company Visa Inc urged immediate reforms.
In a strongly worded statement, Visa said: "Our sponsorship has always focused on supporting the teams, enabling a great fan experience, and inspiring communities to come together and celebrate the spirit of competition and personal achievement ... it is important that FIFA makes changes now so that the focus remain on these going forward. Should FIFA fail to do so, we have informed them that we will reassess our sponsorship".
Coca-Cola Co, another sponsor, said the charges had "tarnished the mission and ideals of the FIFA World Cup and we have repeatedly expressed our concerns about these serious allegations".
INVESTIGATIONS WIDENING
In countries whose nationals were indicted in the United States, more investigations were under way.
An judge in Argentina ordered the arrest of three businessmen accused of conspiring to win and keep hold of lucrative media rights contracts from regional soccer federations through the payment of up to $110 million in bribes.
In Brazil, the Senate, led by former national soccer star Romario, now a legislator, moved to open a formal inquiry into bribes that authorities said were paid obtain contracts with the Brazilian Soccer Federation.
Meanwhile, the Miami-based Confederation of North, Central American and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF) president Jeffrey Webb, who was among those arrested, has been provisionally dismissed from his role, the confederation said on Thursday.
CONFIDENT BLATTER
Blatter appeared confident despite the dawn raid by plainclothes police on Wednesday that left seven of the most powerful figures in international football in Swiss custody and facing extradition to the United States on corruption charges.
All seven are contesting extradition, but lawyers said the process could be completed within months.
Nine soccer officials and five sports media and promotions executives were charged by U.S. prosecutors with corruption they said involved more than $150 million in bribes.
Swiss authorities have also announced a criminal investigation into the awarding of the next two World Cup tournaments, which are being hosted in Russia in 2018 and Qatar in 2022.
Both countries have denied any suggestion of wrongdoing over their bids to host one of the world's top sporting events, and Russian President Vladimir Putin accused the United States on Thursday of meddling in an effort to prevent the re-election of Blatter.
"This is yet another blatant attempt to extend its jurisdiction to other states," Putin said, adding that Russia would continue to support Blatter.
FIFA CONGRESS
The FIFA Congress formally got under way on Thursday evening. In the past, the likes of Grace Jones have set the hearts racing of the older men in suits who comprise most of the gathering's constituency.
But times have changed.
The evening was billed as a rather more subdued affair than normal under the banner "Game of Joy, Game of Hope" with dancers and musicians on stage followed by a grand buffet afterward.
The serious business starts on Friday morning in Zurich's Hallenstadion, which is where the announcement of the 2018 and 2022 World Cup venues was made in 2010, decisions which lie at the heart of much of FIFA's current malaise.
With splits opening in the world game, the Asian and African confederations backed Blatter for president, while Western countries said he must go.
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius said Friday's vote should be delayed in light of the corruption investigation.
British Prime Minister David Cameron backed Prince Ali's candidacy and said there was a strong case for a change of leadership at FIFA. Britain has long been a critic of FIFA and bid for the 2018 World Cup which was awarded to Russia.
Les Murray of Australia, a former FIFA ethics committee member, also called for Blatter to resign.
(Reporting by Mike Collett, writing by Giles Elgood; editing by Peter Millership , Crispian Balmer , Grant McCool and G Crosse)
FIFA President Sepp Blatter arrives for the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
1 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter makes a speech during the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
2 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter leaves the stage after making a speech during the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015. Blatter rejected an emotional plea to resign  from one of the world's soccer greats on Thursday as the corruption...
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
3 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter arrives for the opening ceremony of the 65th FIFA Congress in Zurich, Switzerland, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
4 of 27
right
FBI agents bring out boxes after an operation inside the CONCACAF (Confederation of North, Central America and Caribbean Association Football) offices in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Javier Galeano
5 of 27
right
A combination photo shows eight of the nine football officials indicted for corruption charges in these file photos. From L-R: (top row) then President of the Brazilian Football Confederation Jose Maria Marin, President of the Venezuelan Football Federation Rafael Esquivel,...
Reuters/Staff/Files
6 of 27
right
Federal and local investigators carry boxes from the offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
7 of 27
right
Federal agents walk outside the offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
8 of 27
right
Miami Beach police officers stand outside the headquarters of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, after it was raided by FBI agents in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
9 of 27
right
Security guards stand at the entrance of the headquarters of Traffic Sports in Sao Paulo, Brazil May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Nacho Doce
10 of 27
right
Trinidad and Tobago's former National Security Minister and former FIFA Vice President, Jack Warner, gestures after leaving the offices of the Sunshine Newspaper which he owns, in Arouca, East Trinidad, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Andrea De Silva
11 of 27
right
FBI agents prepare to enter the offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
12 of 27
right
U.S. Attorney General Loretta Lynch walks by display panels during a news conference at the U.S. Attorney's Office of the Eastern District of New York in Brooklyn, New York May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Shannon Stapleton
13 of 27
right
FIFA President Sepp Blatter (R) poses with CONMEBOL President Nicolas Leoz after a news conference at the end of the extraordinary congress of the CONMEBOL in Luque near Asuncion, Paraguay in this file picture taken February 5, 2012.
Reuters/Jorge Adorno/Files
14 of 27
right
Acting President of the South American Soccer Federation (CONMEBOL) Eugenio Figueredo gives his first news conference since taking charge in Asuncion, Paraguay, in this April 30, 2013 file photo.
Reuters/Jorge Adorno/Files
15 of 27
right
FIFA President Joseph 'Sepp' Blatter (R) gestures next to CONCACAF President Jeffrey Webb during a news conference at the CONCACAF congress in Panama City in this April 19, 2013 file photo.
Reuters/Carlos Jasso/Files
16 of 27
right
Eduardo Li, President of Costa Rica's Football Federation, speaks to the media in San Antonio de Belen in Costa Rica, in this May 17, 2011 file photo.
Reuters/Juan Carlos Ulate/Files
17 of 27
right
Rafael Esquivel, Venezuela's national soccer federation president, attends a news conference in Caracas, in Venezuela, in this May 10, 2012 file photo.
Reuters/Jorge Silva/Files
18 of 27
right
Jose Maria Marin, president of the Brazilian Football Confederation (CBF), attends a news conference in Asuncion, Paraguay in this April 23, 2013 file photo.
Reuters/Jorge Adorno/Files
19 of 27
right
Walter De Gregorio, FIFA Director of Communications and Public Affairs listens during a news conference at FIFA headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
20 of 27
right
The building housing offices of CONCACAF, the soccer federation that governs North America, Central America and the Caribbean, is seen during a search by FBI agents in Miami Beach, Florida May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Gaston De Cardenas
21 of 27
right
A staff walks past a logo of soccer's international governing body FIFA at their headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
22 of 27
right
Security guards stand at the entrance of the headquarters of Traffic Sports in Sao Paulo, Brazil May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Nacho Doce
23 of 27
right
Flags are pictured in front of the headquarters of soccer's international governing body FIFA in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
24 of 27
right
Members of the media stand outside the Baur au Lac hotel in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
25 of 27
right
FIFA flags are pictured outside the Marritot hotel, where a meeting of the Confederation of African Football (CAF) is taking place, in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Arnd Wiegmann
26 of 27
right
Journalists take pictures before a news conference of Walter De Gregorio, FIFA Director of Communications and Public Affairs at FIFA headquarters in Zurich, Switzerland, May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:48:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Exclusive: Mexican president misrepresented personal land deal, records show</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/oRd3yLdg3AU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico (Reuters) - Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to the controversy surrounding his personal finances.</Description>
        <MainBody>Exclusive: Mexican president misrepresented personal land deal, records show
VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico | By Simon Gardner
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto reacts during a ceremony to sign into law a new-anti corruption legislation, at the National Palace in Mexico City May 4, 2015.
Reuters/Henry Romero
1 of 8
right
This is the first of two pages in President Enrique Pena Nieto's 2014 public declaration of his assets that assert he was donated six properties by his parents. Public registry documents show that one of those properties was not donated to him by his father, but was...
Reuters/Mexican National Registry Handout via Reuters
left
2 of 8
right
This is the second of two pages in Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto's 2014 public declaration of his assets that assert he was donated six properties by his parents. Public registry documents show that one of those properties was not donated to him by his father, but was...
Reuters/Mexican National Registry Handout via Reuters
left
3 of 8
right
A Mexican public registry document dated March 23, 2015 and obtained by Reuters details how Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto purchased a property in Valle de Bravo in 1988 from a third party and paid 11.2 million pesos at the time.
Reuters/Mexican National Registry Handout via Reuters
left
4 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto and first lady Angelica Rivera wave during the military parade celebrating Independence Day at the Zocalo square in downtown Mexico City in this September 16, 2014 file photo.
Reuters/Edgard Garrido/Files
5 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto looks on during the oath ceremony for new Secretary of the Public Administration Virgilio Andrade Martinez at Los Pinos Presidential house in Mexico City, in this February 3, 2015 file picture. Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto...
Reuters/Edgard Garrido/Files
6 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto looks on after addressing the media about a private meeting with the relatives of the 43 missing students of Ayotzinapa Teacher Training College Raul Isidro Burgos, at Los Pinos presidential residence in Mexico City in this October 29,...
Reuters/Bernardo Montoya/Files
7 of 8
right
Mexico's President Enrique Pena Nieto speaks during a military parade in celebration of the 104th anniversary of the Mexican Revolution, at Campo Marte in Mexico City in this November 20, 2014 file photo. Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the...
Reuters /Henry Romero/Files
8 of 8
right
VALLE DE BRAVO, Mexico Mexican President Enrique Pena Nieto misrepresented to authorities the circumstances under which he acquired one of his properties, public documents reviewed by Reuters show, a discrepancy that could add to the controversy surrounding his personal finances.
According to an official asset declaration first made in 2013, Pena Nieto stated that he acquired the property through a "donation" or gift from his father. Pena Nieto, who made his asset declaration public in 2013 as part of a transparency and accountability push, has since updated and ratified this declaration twice.
Under a public information request, Reuters reviewed documents showing that Pena Nieto actually purchased the property in question - a 1,000 square meter piece of land in the town of Valle de Bravo - in 1988 from a third party. He paid 11.2 million pesos, equivalent to around $5,000 at the time, the registry shows. His wealth declaration lists the property as being valued at just 11,200 "old" pesos, the equivalent to around $5 at the time.
Reuters was unable to determine why Pena Nieto's declaration mischaracterized the purchase as a gift and understated the price. The declaration lists eight other real estate properties, five of which are also listed as donations. Reuters couldn't determine if those five properties, which include houses and land, are accurately characterized.
Mexican public officials face no requirement to explain the source of any funds that were used to obtain properties they receive as gifts, but they are required to accurately declare how they acquire their properties.
The president's office, asked to explain the discrepancies in the documents, declined repeated requests to comment.
Pena Nieto has been under pressure in recent months over aseries of conflict-of-interest scandals centered on properties he, his wife Angelica Rivera and Finance Minister Luis Videgaray acquired from government contractors.
Mexican journalist Carmen Aristegui and her colleagues reported last year that Rivera was acquiring a multi-million dollar home from a unit of a government contractor which was part of a Chinese-led consortium that had won a $3.75 billion high speed rail contract. The Wall Street Journal later reported that Pena Nieto purchased a home from a developer which, the newspaper said, went on to win millions of dollars in state public works contracts.
The president has denied any wrongdoing. But the scandals have overshadowed a major economic reform drive that Pena Nieto was hoping would boost the world's 15th biggest economy.
UPDATE COMING
Pena Nieto will publish his annual asset declaration update later this week with more details, an official at the presidential palace said. He will not reveal his wife's assets, because she is neither a public servant nor financially dependent on him, the official added.
Ten lawyers and law professors at top Mexican law firms and law schools consulted by Reuters said the incorrect asset declaration could spell legal trouble for the president. The discrepancy between the registry documents and his official declaration constitute a false statement to authorities, they said.
Several lawyers pointed to the Federal Law of Public Servants' Responsibilities. Article 80 of the law lists which officials, including "even the president of the republic," must declare their wealth to authorities under oath. "The public servant whose wealth declaration lacks truth ... will be suspended, and when its importance merits it, removed from office and disqualified for three months to three years," the law states.
Several lawyers said they thought the president's wealth declaration should be audited given the discrepancy.
"The property is declared as a donation from the father, when it is in reality the result of a purchase," said Victor Blanco, a Mexican lawyer and academic. "It is incurring falsehood."
Officials who are unable to justify the source of their wealth can face an audit for suspected illicit enrichment. If proven, that would be a crime under Article 224 of Mexico's Federal Penal Code.
One lawyer, speaking on condition of anonymity, said he believed the president could argue that the money used to buy the property was donated to him, and that the discrepancy would not be a major worry.
Lawyers added that there are few precedents for prosecuting senior officials under these laws.
Reuters was unable to check Pena Nieto's other real estate holdings because his wealth declaration doesn't list the addresses of the properties. Mexico's opaque and decentralized property registry makes it difficult to verify the ownership and purchase details of land and buildings. There are more than 220 public registry offices across the country, many of which lack searchable electronic databases. Even modernized registries can be of limited use.
At some public registry offices, members of the public can search an intranet of property records. However, to request a copy of a particular property registration, the user must know the number of the "folio," a compendium of paper records in which properties are originally listed. Searching on an individual's name sometimes turns up no information.
In the case of the president's property identified by Reuters, a computer search in the public registry in Valle de Bravo, a leafy upmarket retreat a two hour drive southwest of Mexico City, initially came up empty for Pena Nieto. A reporter then reviewed old paper files at the registry office, and found the president's name along with a folio number. That enabled the reporter to find the records for the Valle de Bravo property.
FURTHER DISCREPANCIES
There are other discrepancies in Pena Nieto's declaration of assets.
 He reported the value of the Valle de Bravo property as 11,200 so-called "old pesos," when the property registry shows he originally paid 11.2 million old pesos. Mexico was gripped by a deep economic crisis in the 1980s, and in the early 1990s the peso was revalued by lopping three zeros off the hyper-inflated currency.
Pena Nieto's declaration includes two other properties registered in old pesos, which lawyers said appeared to underplay their real worth.
One of those properties is a 560 square meter piece of land containing a 492 square meter house. The president's declaration says he acquired the property in cash in 1982, when he was a 16-year-old schoolboy. The other property is a 24,000 square meter piece of farmland.
Converting the declared amounts using today's exchange rate, those two properties are valued in his declaration at a total of just $102.
Not counting these three properties, Pena Nieto declared assets totaling around $3 million in May 2014.
Pena Nieto made his first declaration of assets as president in early 2013. At that time, he listed nine properties, six of which were described as donations. He didn't report their locations or values or name any of the donors.
In May 2013, he amended his declaration to specify that the donated properties came from his mother or father, and assigned them values. Pena Nieto ratified his declaration again last year, but still withheld the location of the properties.
Shortly after filing his first asset declaration with the government, Pena Nieto followed his two immediate predecessors and made the report public. He vowed his government would be open.
"I am doing this, not just because of a legal mandate, but also as an ethical obligation ... to do with accountability," he said at the time. "Above all I reaffirm my democratic conviction to conduct myself with absolute transparency."
(Edited by Michael Williams)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:31:01 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin classifies information on deaths of Russian troops in peacetime</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/icdvn0h80xE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MOSCOW (Reuters) - President Vladimir Putin ordered on Thursday that deaths of Russian soldiers during special operations in peacetime should be classified as a state secret, a move that comes as Moscow stands accused of sending troops to fight in eastern Ukraine.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin classifies information on deaths of Russian troops in peacetime
MOSCOW | By Gabriela Baczynska
Russian President Vladimir Putin speaks during a meeting of the Lomonosov Moscow State University Supervisory Board at the Kremlin in Moscow, Russia, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Alexei Druzhinin/RIA Novosti/Kremlin
1 of 2
right
A visitor holds a photo at the site where Boris Nemtsov was recently murdered, in central Moscow, February 28, 2015.
Reuters/Sergei Karpukhin
2 of 2
right
MOSCOW President Vladimir Putin ordered on Thursday that deaths of Russian soldiers during special operations in peacetime should be classified as a state secret, a move that comes as Moscow stands accused of sending troops to fight in eastern Ukraine.
Putin, who has repeatedly denied any involvement of Russian troops in a pro-Russian separatist rebellion there, amended a decree that had previously classified only deaths during war time as secret.
Asked to explain the rationale behind Putin's move, his spokesman Dmitry Peskov denied any link to Ukraine. "The improvement of the state secret law is under way," he said in a conference call.
U.S. State Department spokesman Jeff Rathke said at a news briefing the law was a blow to free press and transparency.
"We see this as a misplaced effort to cover up what everyone knows, and that is that Russian active duty military personnel are fighting and dying in eastern Ukraine and that the Russian government is denying it," he said.
Russia's role in the turmoil in east Ukraine, where more than 6,100 people have been killed in over a year of fighting, has been one of the most contentious issues in a conflict that has thrown ties between Moscow and the West into disarray.
Russian opposition activists released a report this month saying at least 220 serving Russian soldiers were killed in fighting in two hot spots in east Ukraine last summer and earlier this year.
Boris Nemtsov, an opposition leader who initiated work on the report, was gunned down in February. His close aide who helped finalize the document, Ilya Yashin, told Reuters by telephone: "This shows that the war with Ukraine - undeclared but ongoing - is a major sore spot for Putin."
The presidential decree refers to information held by the defense ministry, but could, he said, find broader application.
"This...should be seen as a threat to activists, politicians and journalists who deal with this."
Sergei Krivenko, who heads a soldiers' rights group and sits on the Kremlin's advisory council on human rights, termed the presidential decree "within the logic of the current situation in Russia"
"If Russian authorities officially say there are no Russian troops in Ukraine, then, all the more so, there can be no losses," he said.
Both cited the case of Svetlana Davydova, a Russian national charged with treason after calling the Ukrainian embassy to say she had overheard a soldier's conversation about troops from a nearby military base being sent to Ukraine.
TROOPS ON BORDER
Russia annexed Crimea from Ukraine last year after wresting control over the peninsula using troops with no insignia. Moscow initially vehemently denied they were Russian.
Putin only publicly admitted Russian soldiers' involvement nearly a month after signing legislation formally completing the peninsula's annexation.
A Reuters reporter witnessed earlier this week the Russian army massing troops without insignia and hundreds of pieces of unmarked weaponry on the border with Ukraine.
Asked by Reuters if this indicated Russia planned an invasion of Ukraine, Peskov said: "I find the wording of this question...inappropriate as such."
A fragile ceasefire has been in force in east Ukraine since February, but each side accuses the other of violations. Kiev fears Russia could commit troops to a push to extend control by separatist forces deeper into Ukrainian territory.
(Additional reporting by Vladimir Soldatkin; Editing by Ralph Boulton )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:27:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK police arrest two people suspected of preparing terrorism acts</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/WTtHMGy-52E/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>(Reuters) - UK police arrested a man and a woman in two towns west of London on Thursday who were suspected of preparing terrorist attacks, the West Midlands Police said in a Facebook posting.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related: World
UK police arrest two people suspected of preparing terrorism acts
UK police arrested a man and a woman in two towns west of London on Thursday who were suspected of preparing terrorist attacks, the West Midlands Police said in a Facebook posting.
The man, age 24, and woman, age 23, who are believed to be friends, were "arrested on suspicion of preparing for acts of terrorism in the UK," the police said in the posting. (( on.fb.me/1LOaJn8 )
The man was arrested in Reading, where he lives, and the woman was arrested in the nearby town of Wokingham, where she lives, the West Midlands Police said in a posting on Twitter. ( twitter.com/wmpolice )
The two were arrested based on intelligence information at around 7.30 p.m. (2030 GMT), the police said.
Reading is located about 66 kilometers (41 miles) west of London, while Wokingham is about 11 km (8.7 miles) southeast of Reading.
The West Midlands Police Counter Terrorism Unit made the arrests, assisted by the South East Counter Terrorism Unit, the West Midlands Police said on Facebook.
The West Midlands Police said the arrests were pre-planned and that the two people "did not pose any imminent threat."
The two, who were not identified, were arrested under terrorism legislation, which gives police "an initial 48 hours to charge, release or apply for a warrant of further detention," the West Midlands Police said.
The West Midlands Police could not be reached immediately for further comment.
(Reporting by Ankush Sharma in Bangalore; Editing by Leslie Adler)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:25:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/NY1_EytCSUE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bombs outside two five-star Baghdad hotels kill at least 10
BAGHDAD
BAGHDAD Car bombs exploded in the parking lots of two heavily fortified five-star hotels in central Baghdad late on Thursday, killing at least 10 people, police and medical sources said.
A further 30 people were wounded in the blasts, which were around seven minutes apart.
The first bomb targeted the Babylon hotel, where government officials often hold meetings and news conferences, and the second hit the Meridian.
Iraqi authorities lifted a decade-old night-time curfew on Baghdad early this year, seeking to restore a sense of normality to the capital as security forces battle Islamic State militants who have overrun large parts of the country.
But the rate of bombings in Baghdad has increased since then.
Insurgents seized the city of Ramadi, west of Baghdad, on May 17 in the most significant military setback to the government since a U.S.-led coalition launched a campaign of airstrikes against Islamic State last August.
(Reporting by Baghdad Bureau; Writing by Isabel Coles; Editing by Chris Reese )
Smoke rises from the site of car bomb attack in Baghdad, May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Ahmed Saad
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 29 02:00:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Korea to ban taxi services by private drivers in blow to Uber</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/MeFAMdGDjuo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SEOUL (Reuters) - South Korean lawmakers passed a bill early on Friday to ban taxi services provided by private drivers, marking what is likely the first nationwide legislation to outlaw Uber Technologies Inc's low-cost uberX service.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Korea to ban taxi services by private drivers in blow to Uber
SEOUL | By Se Young Lee and Sohee Kim
The logo of car-sharing service app Uber on a smartphone over a reserved lane for taxis in a street is seen in this photo illustration taken in Madrid on December 10, 2014.
Reuters/Sergio Perez
SEOUL South Korean lawmakers passed a bill early on Friday to ban taxi services provided by private drivers, marking what is likely the first nationwide legislation to outlaw Uber Technologies Inc's low-cost uberX service.
The ban, which will take effect by the year-end, marks the latest setback for the U.S. company. Though the firm has expanded rapidly and commands a valuation of around $40 billion, its business practice of matching passengers with private drivers without a taxi license has triggered legal and regulatory battles across the globe.
"Uber respects this decision by the National Assembly and looks forward to continuing its conversations with Seoul City on how to best serve Seoul and its citizens within the legal framework allowed by Korean Law," the U.S. company said in a statement to Reuters ahead of the floor vote.
While the legislation, which amends an existing law on transportation services, imposes a blanket ban rather than explicitly mentioning Uber, it was pushed by lawmakers to block uberX. The bill also bans any parties from offering services that match passengers with drivers without a taxi license.
The move may be largely symbolic, however: Uber suspended its uberX service in Seoul in March following a backlash from authorities and taxi unions, and local competitors match riders with taxi drivers only.
Uber founder and Chief Executive Travis Kalanick, as well as the Korean subsidiary, were indicted by local prosecutors in December, while the Transport Ministry rejected Uber's February proposal to create a separate registration system for its drivers.
The company faces regulatory scrutiny elsewhere: an Italian court on Tuesday banned Uber's uberPOP service and others that match private drivers with passengers, adding to a growing list of challenges it faces in Europe.
Authorities in the southern Chinese city of Guangzhou also raided the U.S. firm's local office on suspicion of "unlicensed operation."
The firm also pulled out of the Kansas after the state's lawmakers pushed through a bill imposing stricter regulations.
Uber still offers two services in South Korea: uberTaxi, which matches users with licensed taxi drivers, and the upscale UberBLACK service that can only be used by certain types of passengers including those with disabilities, foreigners, or people 65 and older based on local rules.
(Reporting by Se Young Lee and Sohee Kim; Editing by Chris Reese and Christian Plumb )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:11:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Libya's rival government conducts air strikes on Islamic State in Sirte: official</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/O5UXQOG80Hc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TRIPOLI (Reuters) - Military aircraft belonging to a rival Libyan government on Thursday attacked Islamic State positions in and around the central city of Sirte, where the radical group claimed to have seized an air base, a government official said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Libya's rival government conducts air strikes on Islamic State in Sirte: official
TRIPOLI
TRIPOLI Military aircraft belonging to a rival Libyan government on Thursday attacked Islamic State positions in and around the central city of Sirte, where the radical group claimed to have seized an air base, a government official said.
Islamic State has exploited the general turmoil and security vacuum in Libya to build up a presence in several cities, where two governments are vying for power four years after the ousting of Muammar Gaddafi.
The militants earlier this year seized Gaddafi's home town of Sirte, pushing to its suburbs a force loyal to a rival government in Tripoli which had expelled the official Premier Abdullah al-Thinni to the east in August.
War planes attacked Islamic State positions in Sirte, a government spokesman in Tripoli said, adding he was not aware of reports that the militants had seized the al-Qardhabia air base, located near Sirte's civilian airport, south of the city.
Islamic State militants said in a statement on Twitter that they were in control of the base, adding that both sides were clashing at key points in Sirte.
A nearby resident said the base appeared to be under control of Islamic State, but Reuters was unable to confirm this independently.
Militant fighters in Libya loyal to Islamic State have claimed since the start of the year the killing of dozens of Egyptian and Ethiopian Christians as well attacks on Tripoli's luxury Corinthia hotel, embassies and oilfields.
Libya's internationally recognized government has been working out of the east of the country since losing control of Tripoli and western Libya in August.
(Reporting by Ahmed Elumami and Ahmed Tolba, writing by Ulf Laessing, Tripoli newsrooom; editing by G Crosse)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 29 01:08:18 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/8GoSJiVW2y8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>AMMAN (Reuters) - The Syrian army has pulled back from the northwestern city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rebels capture last Syrian town in Idlib province
AMMAN | By Suleiman Al-Khalidi
A general view shows the northern town of Ariha, as seen from the rebel-held area of Jabal al-Arbaeen May 26, 2015.
Reuters/Khalil Ashawi
AMMAN The Syrian army has pulled back from the northwestern city of Ariha after a coalition of insurgent groups seized the last city in Idlib province in northwestern Syria near the Turkish border that was still held by the government.
A coalition of rebel groups called Jaish al Fateh, or Conquest Army, said it had taken over the city. Syria's al Qaeda offshoot Nusra Front is a major part of the coalition.
The coalition said it had overrun several checkpoints that defended the city. The Syrian army said intense fighting was going on with Nusra forces that had infiltrated Ariha.
"There are heavy clashes between the army and the terrorists of Jabahat al Nusra who infiltrated inside the city," said an army statement released on state television.
Later the army admitted its forces had pulled back from the city, the latest string of defeats by the Syrian army and a big blow to the morale of President Assad's government forces who have vowed to defeat Sunni militants financed by Saudi Arabia, Qatar and Turkey who seek to overthrow his rule.
"Units of our armed forces evacuated their positions in Ariha and withdrew to defensive positions in the vicinity of the city after battles it fought facing large number of Nusra terrorists," the army source was quoted as saying.
A rebel source from Ahrar al Sham confirmed that street fighting was going on inside the city between army fighters and the insurgents. "There are many bodies that litter the streets," he said, adding that the rebels were searching for Assad's government forces inside the city.
Many civilians have hidden inside shelters.
Syria accuses Turkey of financing and aiding rebels seeking to topple the government. Damascus says foreign jihadi fighters  allowed into Syrian territory by Turkey have played a pivotal role in recent rebel gains.
Rebel sources say they have secured more U.S.-made TOW missiles in recent months that have helped them to gain a military edge over the Syrian army.
The Nusra Front has made gains in northwestern Syria alongside other insurgent groups in recent weeks, seizing the city of Idlib, the town of Jisr al-Shughour and bringing them closer to government-held coastal areas north of the capital.
The loss of Ariha would leave the insurgents in control of  most of Idlib a region that borders Turkey and neighbors President Assad's heartland in Latakia province on the Mediterranean coast.
The city, once home to more than 80,000 people, is strategically located on the main army supply lines between Idlib and Latakia.
Rebel sources said that convoys carrying army forces had fled to Oroum al Jouz, an area west of Ariha and in areas closer to President Assad's ancestral homeland. The army did not comment.
Nusra Front is also a major force against government forces and allied militia around the northern city of Aleppo. It is fighting in southern Syria as well, and its combatants have frequently clashed with Islamic State.
Syria's four-year-old civil war has killed a quarter of a million people and driven nearly 8 million from their homes.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi; Editing by Larry King)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:43:57 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State photos purport to show unharmed Palmyra ruins</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/_zGTtxx7ads/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamic State posted photographs online which it said were taken in the central Syrian city of Palmyra and appeared to show its ancient ruins unharmed since the hardline group seized it from government forces.</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State photos purport to show unharmed Palmyra ruins
BEIRUT
BEIRUT Islamic State posted photographs online which it said were taken in the central Syrian city of Palmyra and appeared to show its ancient ruins unharmed since the hardline group seized it from government forces.
Reuters was not able to independently confirm the authenticity of the photographs posted on jihadi forums by the  Islamic State's media branch. Activists in contact with people inside the city have also said there has been no damage to the UNSECO World Heritage site since the takeover.
Islamic State is an offshoot of al Qaeda that has seized territory in Syria and Iraq and is the target of a U.S.-led air strike campaign in both countries.
The group has destroyed antiquities in neighboring Iraq and Syria's antiquities chief has voiced fears it might now devastate Palmyra, home to renowned Roman ruins including temples, colonnades and an amphitheatre.
On Wednesday the group shot dead around 20 men in the amphitheatre, accusing them of being government supporters, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group said.
It has said the group has killed at least 200 people and taken around 600 captive in and around the city, which is also known as Tadmur.
The 10 images were published as a photographic report entitled "The ancient city of Tadmur" and showed the inside and entrance to the amphitheatre.
It appeared to have an Islamic State flag flying on top of it. There were also pictures of columns and arches.
A separate photo report claimed to show the city's prison in control of the group. It included images of an entrance, cell doors, an empty single cell and collective detention room. A picture of an empty office inside the jail had an image of late Syrian President Hafez al-Assad on the wall.
The Syrian air force has carried out airstrikes in and around Palmyra. U.S.-led forces, whose campaign U.S. officials say is not coordinated with Damascus, have not bombed the city, which sits on a crossroads leading westwards to Homs city and the capital.
(Reporting by Sylvia Westall in Beirut and Omar Fahmy in Cairo; Editing by Angus MacSwan )
Tourists walk in the historical city of Palmyra, April 14, 2007.
Reuters/Nour Fourat/Files
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:36:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Outgoing U.N. aid chief paints harrowing portrait of Syria war</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/ZWD2JIdAgOU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - The United Nations' outgoing humanitarian chief on Thursday painted a harrowing portrait of savagery in Syria's civil war, now in its fifth year, and urged the Security Council to take collective action to put an end to the carnage.</Description>
        <MainBody>UNITED NATIONS | By Louis Charbonneau
Outgoing United Nations' humanitarian chief Valerie Amos speaks to the media during her final news conference at United Nations Headquarters in the Manhattan borough New York May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Carlo Allegri
1 of 5
right
Outgoing United Nations' humanitarian chief Valerie Amos speaks to the media during her final news conference at United Nations Headquarters in the Manhattan borough New York May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Carlo Allegri
2 of 5
right
Outgoing United Nations' humanitarian chief Valerie Amos speaks to the media during her final news conference at United Nations Headquarters in the Manhattan borough New York May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Carlo Allegri
3 of 5
right
Outgoing United Nations' humanitarian chief Valerie Amos speaks to the media during her final news conference at United Nations Headquarters in the Manhattan borough New York May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Carlo Allegri
4 of 5
right
Outgoing United Nations' humanitarian chief Valerie Amos speaks to the media during her final news conference at United Nations Headquarters in the Manhattan borough New York May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Carlo Allegri
5 of 5
right
UNITED NATIONS The United Nations' outgoing humanitarian chief on Thursday painted a harrowing portrait of savagery in Syria's civil war, now in its fifth year, and urged the Security Council to take collective action to put an end to the carnage.
The Syrian war has killed more than 220,000 people. Of the country's roughly 23 million people, some 12.2 million are in need of humanitarian aid, including 5 million children.
"For more than four years, we have watched Syria descend into deeper depths of despair surpassing even what the most pessimistic observers thought possible," Valerie Amos said in her final briefing to the U.N. Security Council before handing over the post to her fellow Briton Stephen O'Brien.
"In the past weeks, we have seen more and more heinous acts. Innocent men, women and children killed, maimed, displaced, and subjected to a savagery that no human should have to endure."
She cited an aerial bomb attack on a market in Darkoush late last month which killed between 40 and 50 civilians and referred to reports of Islamic State militants executing dozens of civilians over the past week after capturing Palmyra.
"The use of chlorine continues to be reported, killing, injuring and terrorizing civilians," she said. "Schools and hospitals continue to be attacked."
She urged the council to take action to protect civilians and end the sieges, ensure aid workers have access, and bring war criminals to account. Last month she called for an arms embargo and sanctions on Syria.
Amos said aid workers were unable to access any of the 422,000 people under siege in Syria in April. She accused the government of introducing new rules and regulations, causing unnecessary delays in delivery of urgently needed aid.
"ISIL's (Islamic State) advance brings with it new depths of depravity to Syria with indiscriminate killing and maiming, raping and destroying," she said. "They have forcibly recruited children and made the delivery of humanitarian assistance more and more difficult."
Amos said the warring sides have "ignored practically all aspects" of a February 2014 Security Council resolution authorizing cross-border aid access and requiring parties to the conflict to allow aid workers to help those in need.
Syria's U.N. Ambassador Bashar Ja'afari dismissed Amos' criticism of his government, saying the real problem was terrorist groups getting support from the United States, Turkey, Saudi Arabia and Qatar.
U.S., European and other unilateral sanctions were making the humanitarian situation worse, he said, adding that "such unjust measures must end."
(Reporting by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Marguerita Choy)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:11:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Fractious handover clouds Buhari's Nigeria succession</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/yyCxZM9LD9M/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ABUJA, Nigeria - As he entered his final week in office, Nigerian President Goodluck Jonathan offered up a prayer for the success of Muhammadu Buhari, the former military ruler who takes the helm of Africa's biggest economy on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>By Julia Payne
ABUJA, Nigeria - As he entered his final week in office, Nigerian President Goodluck Jonathan offered up a prayer for the success of Muhammadu Buhari, the former military ruler who takes the helm of Africa's biggest economy on Friday.
However, if Buhari's All Progressives Congress (APC) is to be believed, that goodwill did not stretch as far as the thousands of pro-Jonathan bureaucrats preparing for Nigeria's first democratic transfer of power.
Citing weeks of strike action by fuel distributors that crippled the economy, the APC accused outgoing officials of creating an "atmosphere of contrived chaos" to sully 72-year-old Buhari's moment of political triumph.
"The whole scenario reeks of sabotage," APC spokesman Lai Mohammed said in a statement that laid bare the party's frustrations with the behavior of Jonathan's outgoing and scandal-plagued administration.
"This is the most vivid manifestation of the old saying that literally translates to a departing office holder defecating on the chair he is vacating," Mohammed concluded.
Although the strike by fuel distributors, who said they were owed $1 billion by the government, ended this week, it caused massive disruption to Nigeria's 170 million people, grounding flights, forcing banks to close and cutting phone signals.
It also served as a reminder to Buhari of the challenges he will face in Africa's top crude producer, including a weakening currency and an insurgency by Boko Haram Islamist militants that has claimed thousands of lives.
On Thursday, Jonathan took Buhari on a short tour of the presidential villa in Abuja, at the end of which he urged unity to "build a stronger and more prosperous nation".
Buhari responded by thanking Jonathan for swiftly conceding defeat in the March 28 election, rather than challenging or disputing the result -- an outcome that could have unleashed political violence.
"You could had made things difficult, but you choose the path of peace and honor," he said. "Thank you very much".
SPAT
Jonathan's People's Democratic Party (PDP) disputed the accusations from the APC that they were hindering the transfer of power, saying their political foes were being too demanding -- especially given that the constitution says outgoing officials need not hand over anything other than simple notes.
"The APC transition committee were asking for too much, more than was appropriate," said PDP spokesman and former aviation minister, Femi Fani-Kayode.
However, APC insiders told Reuters they did not receive handover notes from the various ministries until Monday -- just five days before Buhari's inauguration -- and what they did get was virtually worthless.
"The outgoing government is not committed to handing over information of significance," one APC source told Reuters.     "Nobody is putting a lot of value in what is being handed over."
The confusion and bad blood is casting a shadow over the return to high office of Buhari, who first came to power after a military coup in 1983.
Reports that Buhari, a sandal-wearing Muslim ascetic who has pledged to fight corruption, might look into allegations of wrongdoing during Jonathan's tenure are also unlikely to have helped relations between APC and PDP grandees.
However, analysts said end-of-administration apathy and malaise has not been uncommon in Nigeria, even when the baton is being passed inside the ruling party.
"The 'end of term' feel that has characterized the last few weeks is a familiar part of the political culture," said Anthony Goldman of Nigeria-focused PM Consulting.
"Often neither outgoing nor incoming governments have reliable data to work with. Sometimes it's systemic, sometimes deliberate," he added.
CORRUPTION CLAIMS
Many Nigerians believe that already widespread corruption became rampant under Jonathan, further undermining an economic system that sees Africa's top oil producer import most of the 40 million liters consumed every day at heavily subsidized prices.
"There is nothing to handover (to the APC) because there was nothing really being run. No accountability," said a source with a long history in Nigerian politics, who declined to be named.
Jonathan's efforts to revamp the dilapidated power grid won praise from economists and investors, but the renovations have yet to bear fruit, leaving the economy reliant on expensive diesel generators for electricity.
Repairing Nigeria's decrepit refineries after decades of neglect will be high on Buhari's list of priorities.
The nationwide impact of the fuel strike crystallized some of the problems Buhari will have to confront, said Rolake Akinkugbe, head of energy and natural resources at FBN Capital.
"The current low global oil price trend, and past consensus on the need to prioritize long-term investment in infrastructure should set the scene for a phasing out of subsidies," said Akinkugbe. "Government finances are strained and Nigeria is clearly at an economic crossroads."
(Additional reporting by Camillus Eboh, Felix Onuah and Alexis Akwagyiram; Writing by Alexis Akwagyiram; Editing by Ed Cropley and Crispian Balmer )
Nigeria's President-elect Muhammadu Buhari departs after meeting with Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron at Downing Street in London, England, May 23, 2015.
Reuters/Neil Hall
1 of 2
right
Nigeria's President Goodluck Jonathan casts his ballot in his ward at Otuoke, Bayelsa State March 28, 2015.
Reuters/Afolabi Sotunde
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:07:52 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. hopes Chinese island-building will spur Asian response</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/HRtzuapiaPM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - By releasing video of Beijings island reclamation work and considering more assertive maritime actions, the United States is signaling a tougher stance over the South China Sea and trying to spur Asian partners to more action.</Description>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By David Alexander
WASHINGTON By releasing video of Beijings island reclamation work and considering more assertive maritime actions, the United States is signaling a tougher stance over the South China Sea and trying to spur Asian partners to more action.
The release last week of the surveillance plane footage - showing dredgers and other ships busily turning remote outcrops into islands with runways and harbors - helps ensure the issue will dominate an Asian security forum starting on Friday attended by U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter as well as senior Chinese military officials.
As it pushes ahead with a military pivot to Asia partly aimed at countering China, Washington wants Southeast Asian nations to take a more united stance against China's rapid acceleration this year of construction on disputed reefs.
The meeting, the annual Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore, will be overshadowed by the tensions in the South China Sea, where Beijing has added 1,500 acres to five outposts in the resource-rich Spratly islands since the start of this year.
"These countries need to own it (the issue)," one U.S. defense official said on condition of anonymity, adding that it was counterproductive for the United States to take the lead in challenging China over the issue.
More unified action by the partners, including the 10-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), needed to happen soon because "if you wait four years, it's done," the official said.
While some ASEAN members, including U.S. ally the Philippines and fellow claimant Vietnam, have been vocal critics of Chinese maritime actions, the group as a whole has been divided on the issue and reluctant to intervene.
But in a sign of growing alarm, the group's leaders last month jointly expressed concern that reclamation activity had eroded trust and could undermine peace in the region.
Experts dismiss the idea of ASEAN-level joint action any time soon in the South China Sea. "It's absolute fantasy," said Ian Storey of Singapores Institute on South East Asian Studies.
But stepped-up coordination between some states is possible. Japan's military is considering joining the United States in maritime air patrols over the sea. Japan and the Philippines are expected to start talks next week on a framework for the transfer of defense equipment and technology and to discuss a possible pact on the status of Japanese military personnel visiting the Philippines.
Carter, speaking in Honolulu en route to Singapore, repeated Washington's demand that the island-building stop, saying China was violating the principles of the region's "security architecture" and the consensus for "non-coercive approaches."
China claims 90 percent of the South China Sea, which is believed to be rich in oil and gas, with overlapping claims from Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Vietnam and Taiwan.
SHOWING CHINA SOME "RESOLVE"
As part of Washington's drive to energize its allies, a   U.S. Navy P-8 reconnaissance plane allowed CNN and Navy camera crews to film Chinese land reclamation activity in the Spratly islands last week and release the footage.
 "No one wants to wake up one morning and discover that China has built numerous outposts and, even worse, equipped them with military systems," Assistant Secretary of State Daniel Russel said.
Ernest Bower, a Southeast Asia expert at the Center for Strategic and International Studies think tank in Washington, said the U.S. goal was to convince China to buy into the international system for dispute resolution rather than impose its sweeping territorial claims on the region.
But in the near term, he added: "I think the Americans are going to have to show China some resolve."
U.S. officials have said Navy ships may be sent within 12 miles (19 kms) of the Chinese-built islands to show that Washington does not recognize Beijing's insistence that it has territorial rights there.
Washington is also pressing ahead with its rebalancing towards Asia, four years after President Barack Obama announced the strategic shift, even as some countries say it is slow to take shape.
The United States has updated its security agreements with treaty allies Japan and the Philippines and is bolstering missile defenses in Japan with an eye on North Korea.
U.S. Marines are training in Australia on a rotational basis, littoral combat ships are operating out of Singapore and new P-8 reconnaissance planes stationed in Japan have flown missions across the region.
Overall, defense officials said, the Navy will increase its footprint by 18 percent between 2014 and 2020. The aim is to have 60 percent of Navy ships oriented toward the Pacific by 2020, compared to 57 percent currently.
Military officials in the Philippines say the U.S. shift has been noticeable, including military exercises, training and ship and aircraft visits. The emphasis has shifted from anti-terrorism to maritime security, one official said.
China has not shown any sign of being deterred. On Tuesday it held a groundbreaking ceremony for two lighthouses in the South China Sea, vowed to increase its "open seas protection," and criticized neighbors who take "provocative actions" on its reefs and islands.
(Additional reporting by Greg Torode in Hong Kong, Nobuhiro Kubo in Tokyo, Manuel Mogato in Manila, Sui Lee Wee in Beijing; editing by David Storey and Stuart Grudgings.)
Chinese dredging vessels are purportedly seen in the waters around Mischief Reef in the disputed Spratly Islands in the South China Sea in this still image from video taken by a P-8A Poseidon surveillance aircraft provided by the United States Navy May 21, 2015.
Reuters/U.S. Navy/Handout via Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Thu May 28 23:04:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State settles into Ramadi, but the lull unlikely to last</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/u2eC6PmL2O8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - The blind man with just one hand arrived at the main mosque in the center of the Iraqi city of Ramadi at dusk on Wednesday, flanked by Islamic State fighters.</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamic State settles into Ramadi, but the lull unlikely to last
BAGHDAD
BAGHDAD The blind man with just one hand arrived at the main mosque in the center of the Iraqi city of Ramadi at dusk on Wednesday, flanked by Islamic State fighters.
When the evening prayer was over, the man, whose head was shrouded in black, delivered a speech to the faithful, hailing the Islamic State's capture of the capital of Anbar Province -- its greatest victory over Iraqi forces in almost a year.
Ali Attiya al-Jubouri, widely known as "the blind judge", is one of Islamic State's most senior figures and his presence in the mosque signaled the group's dominance over the city, which it seized on May 17 from hapless government forces.
"By the blessing of God, we now have an open road between Ramadi and Raqqa," he said, referring to the ultra hardline group's de-facto capital in neighboring Syria.
"You are free to travel there and work in trade, and we will help you by all means," he said, according to a resident of the city who was in the audience.
The Sunni Muslim group has declared a caliphate, or Islamic state, across wide areas of Syria and Iraq, defying hostile government forces and U.S.-led airstrikes in both countries.
Despite a fearsome reputation for inflicting savage violence on foes, Islamic State militants have gone out of their way to try to win over residents of Ramadi, providing basic services and governance, said locals speaking to Reuters by telephone.
Most residents have fled, but those who stayed are savoring what they describe as a semblance of order and tranquility in a city that had been a warzone for more than a year.
We are having a pleasant dream now of living in peace without hearing gunfire or bombs and walking freely through open streets," said teacher Abdul Wahab Ahmed, 45, who compared the new order to "passing a glass of chilled water to the thirsty".
However, the lull is unlikely to last, with government security forces and Shi'ite paramilitaries already preparing to launch a counter-offensive to retake the city.
"The dream wont last long, and soon well wake up to the bitter reality of being stuck in the crossfire between government forces and (IS) fighters," he said.
MASS GRAVES
Residents said no sooner had the militants claimed victory earlier this month than they set about removing blast walls and barricades from the streets with cranes, just as they did in Mosul, the northern Iraqi city they captured last June.
"Its good to see some normality restored to life in Ramadi," said Abu Abdul Rahman. "We were living in a military barracks when government forces were in control. Now we can taste a minimum level of freedom."
Islamic State reopened the municipality, and militants accompanied employees from the department of health to collect the bodies of unknown number of policemen and soldiers lying in the streets where they had died.
They were buried in mass graves on the city's outskirts, while burned-out vehicles were towed away to a scrap yard in a rural area north of Ramadi.
Under the militants' supervision, teams of plumbers repaired broken drinking water pipes, and free food and vegetables were handed out from refrigerated trucks.
Two tankers escorted by Islamic State fighters dispensed fuel to the owners of electricity generators in each neighborhood and instructed them to keep their prices in check.
The unemployed were urged to take work at the municipality for a monthly wage of 350,000 Iraqi dinars ($270), and repeated calls were made for female doctors to treat women patients at Ramadi hospital.
Following the surprise visit by the blind judge, fighters withdrew from the city streets, handing control to the Islamic morality police, or Hisba, multiple sources inside Ramadi said.
"Some of the fighters said goodbye and apologized if they had done anything wrong, it was not purpose," said one resident.
"They told us they will go to bolster defenses on Ramadis outskirts".
As elsewhere under their sway, Islamic State has wasted no time in imposing their unyielding interpretation of Islamic Sharia law. They also appointed their own preachers to run the city's mosques, empowering them to resolve civilian disputes.
Male shopowners who stock womenswear were ordered to bring a wife, sister or mother to attend to female customers, limiting contact between the sexes. Orders were given for shop windows displaying women's clothing to be covered and manikins removed.
One cigarette seller recalled how he was approached by a militant who said: "Brother, we dont like you to sell something harmful to the health of Muslims: stop selling cigarettes and we are prepared to help you find another, decent occupation".
The cigarette seller, who refused to be identified, was skeptical: "I know this trick very well: to begin with Daesh ask you very politely, but when they grow stronger they wont even talk to you, they will just wave a knife at your neck".
Daesh is the unflattering Arabic acronym for Islamic State.
Video posted online earlier this year appeared to show militants elsewhere whipping men who had been found smoking.
PLANTING BOMBS
Islamic State fighters have warned residents not to venture outside the city because they say they have laid a web of bombs to hinder any incursion by government forces.
Residents who went to find relatives displaced by fighting east of the city saw men embedding dozens of explosive devices in the road, using small mobile generators to power electrical cutters to slice open the asphalt.
Asked why they were also planting mines on either side of the road, a local militant leader said: "We learned a lesson from Tikrit, where our brothers only planted bombs on key roads. Government forces and rejectionist militia.... used dirt tracks to enter the city."
In a setback to the militants, Iraqi troops and Shi'ite paramilitaries drove Islamic State out of Tikrit -- the hometown of former dictator Saddam Hussein -- in late March.
"We will not allow the same scenario to be repeated in Ramadi," the militant leader was quoted as saying.
However, Iraqi security expert Hisham al-Hashimi, who tracks the radical insurgents, said he did not expect Islamic State to keep Ramadi for long as well-armed, opposing forces muster for an assault on the city.
Despite the impending attack, residents said they had chosen to stay because they did not want to leave their homes or be treated in the way that others fleeing Ramadi had complained of.
Most of those displaced from the region had sought refuge in Baghdad, but they were not allowed into the city without a sponsor. Those who managed to get through said they were harassed by security forces and Shi'ite militias who suspected them of being infiltrators.
"We are sure that the control of the (IS) fighters is temporary, and sooner or later the government will be back," said Ramadi resident Abu Omar al-Obeidi.
"Our main concern is that the security forces will accuse us of supporting Daesh because we stayed in the city".
Retired civil servant Said Kamil, 68, who owns a food shop in central Ramadi said he had resigned himself to his fate: "For me, dying in dignity is better than living in humiliation."
(Reporting by Baghdad Bureau; Writing by Isabel Coles; Editing by Crispian Balmer )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Thu May 28 22:41:51 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK takes hard line on EU reform as Cameron starts European tour</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/n5vlaYGHLds/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON/PARIS (Reuters) - Prime Minister David Cameron said Britain's relationship with the European Union was "not good enough" after his foreign minister warned the bloc had to change its founding treaties and give London a meaty reform deal to keep it as a member.</Description>
        <MainBody>UK takes hard line on EU reform as Cameron starts European tour
LONDON/PARIS | By Andrew Osborn and Ingrid Melander
The Union Flag flies next to the European Flag outside the European Commission building in central London May 25, 2014.
Reuters/Neil Hall
LONDON/PARIS Prime Minister David Cameron said Britain's relationship with the European Union was "not good enough" after his foreign minister warned the bloc had to change its founding treaties and give London a meaty reform deal to keep it as a member.
Speaking in Paris on the first day of a whirlwind European tour to try to drum up support for EU reform, Cameron said he was confident he could get a settlement, something he has promised to secure before giving Britons an EU membership in-out referendum by the end of 2017.
"My priority is to reform the European Union to make it more competitive and address the concerns of the British people about our membership. The status quo is not good enough," said Cameron, flanked by French President Francois Hollande.
"What matters is that the European Union and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative enough to respond to these issues."
Cameron has various demands, the thrust of which are to claw back powers from Brussels to allow Britain to opt out of what he sees as a dangerous shift to greater political integration.
Cameron met Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte in The Hague earlier on Thursday before starting talks with Hollande. He is due in Warsaw and Berlin on Friday for talks with Polish Prime Minister Ewa Kopacz and German Chancellor Angela Merkel.
Hollande said France wanted Britain to stay in the EU, something he said was in the best interests of the bloc and of London. He indicated he was ready to listen to Cameron's reform proposals.
Earlier, British Foreign Secretary Philip Hammond had warned the EU needed to amend its founding treaties to accommodate Britain and make substantive concessions to keep it in.
"If our partners do not agree with us, do not work with us to deliver that (reform) package, then we rule nothing out," Hammond told BBC radio.
Speaking at a G7 meeting in Germany, finance minister George Osborne struck a softer tone, saying he sensed "a real willingness" among other EU countries to negotiate.
POTENTIAL SETBACK
Cameron's government introduced a law into parliament on Thursday to guarantee the EU referendum will be held by the end of 2017. It also disclosed the question voters will be asked, making it "Yes" to stay in, "No" to leave.
Some EU countries have made clear they have no appetite to re-open the bloc's treaties to suit Britain, which wants to alter them so it can restrict and delay EU migrants' access to its welfare system.
But London has long asserted that the treaties would need to be overhauled anyway as part of an inevitable drive to further integrate the euro zone.
In a potential setback for Cameron, a Franco-German paper seen by Reuters shows the two countries have agreed plans to strengthen cooperation among the 19 countries using the euro currency, without changing existing treaties.
Hammond said he expected some EU states initially to adopt a hardline negotiating position.
"What matters is getting it right rather than doing it quickly," Hammond said of the renegotiation. "We're certainly not going to trade substantive reform just for getting it done quickly."
(Additional reporting by William James and Michael Holden in London, John Irish in Paris and William Schomberg in Dresden; Editing by Guy Faulconbridge and Andrew Heavens )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:52:07 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. council has first-ever briefing on rights in Myanmar</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/t-WcoAf0nvQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>UNITED NATIONS (Reuters) - The United Nations Security Council on Thursday held its first closed-door briefing on the human rights situation in Myanmar, focusing on the dire situation of the country's Rohingya Muslim minority, council diplomats said.</Description>
        <MainBody>UNITED NATIONS | By Louis Charbonneau
Abdhulami (C), 22, who was released from a human trafficking boat, points at pictures of people he recognises from the boat as he rests at a refugee camp outside Sittwe, Myanmar May 27, 2015.
Reuters/Soe Zeya Tun
UNITED NATIONS The United Nations Security Council on Thursday held its first closed-door briefing on the human rights situation in Myanmar, focusing on the dire situation of the country's Rohingya Muslim minority, council diplomats said.
U.N. human rights chief Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein briefed the council via video link in a meeting that U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Samantha Power welcomed on her Twitter feed as a "historic first" for the 15-nation body.
"Zeid gave a powerful briefing on the dire situation and 'institutional discrimination' faced by the Rohingya in Myanmar," a council diplomat present at the meeting told Reuters on condition of anonymity.
"They are often violently abused by smugglers, hundreds recently dying at sea," the diplomat said, summarizing Zeid's remarks about the country formerly called Burma. "This demands a comprehensive response. Must look at root causes."
Another diplomat confirmed the readout, adding that no immediate council action was expected.
Council members responded to Zeid by calling for the problem to be tackled at its root causes and welcoming a crisis meeting in Bangkok aimed at addressing Southeast Asia's migrant crisis.
According to participants, that meeting of 17 countries from across the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and elsewhere in Asia is unlikely to produce a binding agreement or plan of action to save thousands of people believed stranded at sea.
A delegate from Russia said the Security Council was not the appropriate forum for discussing human rights, suggesting it should be handled by the U.N. Human Rights Council in Geneva, a diplomat said.
China, Myanmar's traditional ally, said it was an internal matter for the country's authorities but expressed concern about the situation.
More than 3,000 migrants from Myanmar and Bangladesh have landed in Indonesia and Malaysia in recent weeks since Thailand launched a crackdown on human trafficking gangs earlier this month. About 2,600 are believed to be still adrift on abandoned boats, relief agencies have said.
Many of those who have made it to shore are members of Myanmar's 1.1 million-member Rohingya Muslim minority who live in apartheid-like conditions in Myanmar's Rakhine state.
Recently Zeid said the Rohingyas' situation was "one of the principal motivators of these desperate maritime movements."
The Myanmar government regards most Rohingyas as illegal immigrants from Bangladesh. They enjoy few rights and have suffered violence at the hands of members of the Buddhist majority over the past few years.
(Reporting by Louis Charbonneau; Editing by Jonathan Oatis )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:13:50 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. think tank urges continued human rights pressure on Sri Lanka</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/0QQtDKhYJ2M/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - There is little hope of post-war reconciliation in Sri Lanka unless the new government acts to end the oppression of minority Tamils and ensure reconciliation, a U.S. think tank said on Thursday, urging continued pressure on the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. think tank urges continued human rights pressure on Sri Lanka
WASHINGTON
WASHINGTON There is little hope of post-war reconciliation in Sri Lanka unless the new government acts to end the oppression of minority Tamils and ensure reconciliation, a U.S. think tank said on Thursday, urging continued pressure on the country.
President Mathripala Sirisena's government was elected earlier this year with promises of reconciliation, and secured the delay of a United Nations report due in March after the U.N. human rights chief praised its willingness to open the country up to scrutiny.
However, the California-based Oakland Institute said no progress had been made in resolving pressing human rights issues, including the fate of tens of thousands of people missing since a long civil war ended in 2009, and in investigating and prosecuting war crimes.
It said six years after the war ended with victory by the
Sinhalese over the Tamil Tiger separatists, thousands of Tamils were still displaced and the military occupation of the north and east of the country continued.
An "aggressive" process of "Sinhalization" over the past six years had seen Tamil culture systematically replaced by victory monuments dedicated to Sinhalese hegemony and the majority Buddhist religion, the report said.
"A new government was elected in early 2015 with the promise that it will engage in a process of truth and reconciliation," the report said. "It is unclear how such a process could effectively take place, given the current level of military occupation and the ongoing Sinhalization efforts."
Despite the problems, both the United States and India have said they want to cooperate with the government, raising fears they might not press enough to ensure it lives up to its commitments.
"International pressure will be critical for any decisive action," the report said.
Estimates of the number of people who remain missing since the end war ranged from 70,000, cited in a 2012 U.N. report, to a study by the bishop of Mannar of 147,000 for the Vanni region alone.
While the institute was unable to provide its own estimate, its researchers gathered "dozens of testimonies that confirm that large numbers of individuals are still missing," the report said.
In early May, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry visited Colombo and said Washington wanted to renew ties with Sri Lanka, while urging the government to work with the U.N. to ensure the war crimes investigation met international standards.
(Reporting by David Brunnstrom. Editing by Andre Grenon)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Thu May 28 21:10:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>UK's Cameron tells France's Hollande EU status quo 'not good enough'</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/JNHRX7SVr3g/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (Reuters) - France wants Britain to remain in the European Union, President Francois Hollande said on Thursday after talks with UK Prime Minister David Cameron, who insisted the status quo in Europe was "not good enough".</Description>
        <MainBody>UK's Cameron tells France's Hollande EU status quo 'not good enough'
PARIS
French President Francois Hollande (L) accompanies Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron as he leaves the Elysee Palace after a meeting in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
1 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) accompanies Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron as he leaves the Elysee Palace after a meeting in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
2 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) accompanies Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron as he leaves the Elysee Palace after a meeting in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
3 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) and Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron meet at the Elysee Palace in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Etienne Laurent/Pool
4 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) and Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron meet at the Elysee Palace in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Etienne Laurent/Pool
5 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) and Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron meet at the Elysee Palace in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Etienne Laurent/Pool
6 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) and Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron meet at the Elysee Palace in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Etienne Laurent/Pool
7 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) greets Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron at the Elysee Palace ahead of a meeting in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Philippe Wojzaer
8 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (L) greets Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron at the Elysee Palace ahead of a meeting in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Philippe Wojzaer
9 of 10
right
French President Francois Hollande (R) greets Britain's Prime Minister David Cameron at the Elysee Palace ahead of a meeting in Paris, France, May 28, 2015.
Reuters/Philippe Wojzaer
10 of 10
right
PARIS France wants Britain to remain in the European Union, President Francois Hollande said on Thursday after talks with UK Prime Minister David Cameron, who insisted the status quo in Europe was "not good enough".
"France wants the UK to remain in the European Union," Hollande said at a joint news conference with Cameron in Paris.   "We think it's in the interest of Europe and in the interest of the United Kingdom to be together but the people must always be respected."
Cameron said that his priority was to reform the EU to make it more competitive and address the concerns of the British people.
"The status quo is not good enough," he said. "I believe there are changes we can make that will benefit not just Britain, but the rest of Europe, too."
He added: "We have different priorities but we share a common objective, which is to find solutions to these problems and what matters is that the European Union and its 28 members are flexible and imaginative enough to respond to these issues and to work together to find answers that will make the European Union more successful."
Cameron was starting a two-day European tour to try to charm EU leaders into backing his reform drive, something he has promised to complete before giving Britons an EU membership in-out referendum by the end of 2017.
(Reporting by Ingrid Melander ; Editing by James Regan )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
