<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:29:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin out to seize control of Ukraine, says Kiev defense chief</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Nij594_Bx9s/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KIEV (Reuters) - The West should not drop its guard over Ukraine, the country's defense minister said on Friday, saying a build-up of Russian forces in support of separatists showed President Vladimir Putin was bent on seizing control of the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin out to seize control of Ukraine, says Kiev defense chief
KIEV
Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a session of the Civic Chamber at the Kremlin in Moscow, Russia, June 23, 2015.
Reuters/Sergei Karpukhin
KIEV The West should not drop its guard over Ukraine, the country's defense minister said on Friday, saying a build-up of Russian forces in support of separatists showed President Vladimir Putin was bent on seizing control of the country.
Stepan Poltorak spoke alongside visiting Canadian Defense Minister Jason Kenney as Kiev military chiefs reported intensified attacks by separatists in the east, despite a ceasefire, with another Ukrainian soldier killed.
"There is a threat still because the military groups of the (separatists)... and Russian troops continue to build up their forces, bringing additional equipment and ammunition and of course their plans are not peaceful," Poltorak said.
"One should not be naive and think that Putin has given up his plans to seize Ukraine, to destabilize the situation in Ukraine. He's just changing his tactics and strategies, but his goal remains the same: to seize Ukraine."
Putin denies accusations by Kiev and the West that Russia has provided pro-Russian separatists in east Ukraine with soldiers and weapons.
Although he is often accused of wanting control of Ukraine, he supports a February peace deal under which rebel-held areas of east Ukraine would be given more autonomy from Kiev but remain part of Ukraine.
Poltorak was expected to use Kenney's visit to press for the U.S.-led NATO alliance to provide further military assistance to shore up Kiev's forces in a conflict in which more than 6,400 people have been killed, according to U.N. estimates.
Canada, like many other NATO members, has provided the ex-Soviet republic only with non-lethal aid. Canadian military trainers are also expected to run programs for new Ukrainian conscripts inside Ukraine this summer.
Government forces and the Russian-backed separatists have accused each other of truce violations since February's deal,  brokered by the leaders of Russia, Ukraine, Germany and France.
Poltorak, in his remarks on Friday, accused the separatists of carrying out 5,000 shelling attacks on government positions since the deal was signed in Minsk, Belarus.
Separately on Friday Kiev military spokesman Andriy Lysenko said that one Ukrainian soldier had been killed in separatist rocket and artillery attacks since Thursday.
"The intensity of attacks is growing. They are going on around the clock," he told a briefing, saying hotspots were near the airport of the rebel-held city of Donetsk city and at Shyrokyne east of the government-held port city of Mariupol.
(Reporting by Serhiy Karazy and Natalia Zinets; additional reporting by Timothy Heritage in Moscow; Writing By Richard Balmforth ; editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:24:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/2oe2_CBFRVw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France (Reuters) - A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France | By Catherine Lagrange
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.
Speaking from a European Union summit in Brussels, French President Francois Hollande described it at a terrorist attack and said all measures would be taken to stop any future attacks on a country still reeling from Islamist assaults in January.
One suspect had been arrested and was already known to French intelligence sources, Hollande said.
"Two individuals deliberately rammed a car into the gas containers to trigger an explosion," a police source said.
It was not known whether the victim, so far the only known fatality in the incident that also injured two people, was decapitated before or after the car smashed into the building, or whether the victim had been on site at the time of the attack, or killed elsewhere.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," Hollande told the news conference.
ISLAMIST FLAG
Police sources earlier said the decapitated body was found at the site, along with a flag bearing Islamist inscriptions.
Local newspaper Le Dauphine said the head covered in Arabic writing was found on a fence.
The French public prosecutor said its anti-terrorist section had been deployed to investigate.
France, which has deployed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since the Charlie Hebdo killings in January.
Then, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalized by Islamist fighters, Valls said "never has the threat been so high".
The site belonged to Air Products, a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company, according to a spokeswoman for Air Liquide, a French company in the same sector. It was immediately ringfenced by police and emergency services.
The chairman and CEO of Air Products is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a U.S. Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born. Mainly Shi'ite Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State.
No group claimed responsibility for the attack and the motive was unknown.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was at the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30 km (20 miles) southeast of the city of Lyon.
French media said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around sensitive sites in the surrounding Rhone-Alpes region.
(Reporting by Sophie Louet, Dominique Vidalon and Leigh Thomas ; Editing by Mark John and Alison Williams )
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
1 of 15
right
French President Francois Hollande (foreground on L) arrives in a press room to give a statement at the European Council headquarters in Brussels, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Yves Herman
2 of 15
right
French President Francois Hollande gives a statement at the European Council headquarters in Brussels, June 26, 2015, following an attack at a U.S. gas company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast France, where two assailants rammed a car into the premises, and a...
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
3 of 15
right
French President Francois Hollande leaves the EU Council headquarters during a European Union leaders summit in Brussels, Belgium, June 26, 2015 following an attack at a U.S. gas company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast France, where an explosion took place.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
4 of 15
right
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
5 of 15
right
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
6 of 15
right
French Gendarmes and rescue forces stand next to a black plastic sheet (R) outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
7 of 15
right
French Gendarmes and rescue forces stand near a black plastic sheet (R) outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
8 of 15
right
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
9 of 15
right
A French Gendarme stands guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
10 of 15
right
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
11 of 15
right
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
12 of 15
right
French crime scene investigators, Gendarmes and rescue forces are seen at work next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
13 of 15
right
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve addresses a news conference outside Air Products gas facory site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
14 of 15
right
A general view shows the Air Products gas facory site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:22:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 19 killed in gun attack on Tunisian tourism hotel: official</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/JTSNFwgVDdE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS (Reuters) - At least 19 people have been killed after at least one gunman attacked a Tunisian tourist hotel in the popular resort of Sousse, an interior ministry official said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thomson Reuters is the world's largest international multimedia news agency, providing investing news , world news , business news , technology news , headline news, small business news , news alerts, personal finance , stock market , and mutual funds information available on Reuters.com, video , mobile , and interactive television platforms. Thomson Reuters journalists are subject to an Editorial Handbook which requires fair presentation and disclosure of relevant interests.
NYSE and AMEX quotes delayed by at least 20 minutes. Nasdaq delayed by at least 15 minutes. For a complete list of exchanges and delays, please click here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:09:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey summons Israeli diplomat after journalists, NGO workers refused entry</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/jYtNqNTHhuA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkey's Foreign Ministry said on Friday it summoned the highest-ranking Israeli diplomat in Ankara to explain why a group of Turkish journalists and civil society workers were refused entry at Ben Gurion Airport.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkey summons Israeli diplomat after journalists, NGO workers refused entry
ISTANBUL
ISTANBUL Turkey's Foreign Ministry said on Friday it summoned the highest-ranking Israeli diplomat in Ankara to explain why a group of Turkish journalists and civil society workers were refused entry at Ben Gurion Airport.
The incident occurred three days after diplomats from Israel and Turkey, both U.S. allies, held talks to explore prospects of repairing their relationship after a Turkish election earlier this month.
Ties between the erstwhile allies were wrecked after Israeli commandoes killed 10 Turkish activists trying to break the blockade on Gaza in 2010. Turkey soon after recalled its ambassador and ejected Israel's.
A group of nine Turks had traveled to Israel on Thursday to attend an event marking the Islamic holy month of Ramadan in Jerusalem, the Foreign Ministry said in an e-mailed statement.
They were questioned for nine hours and, despite having the required visas, seven of them were sent back. Two journalists with the state TRT broadcaster were allowed in, it said, condemning the decision to eject the group.
"To show our reaction to the treatment of our citizens and to receive an explanation, the Israeli charge d'affaires has been summoned to the Foreign Ministry," it said. The charge d'affaires is Israel's most senior official at the embassy.
Some Israeli media said the seven Turks were suspected of ties with the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas.
"The seven people were sent back for security reasons," Israeli Foreign Ministry Spokesman Emmanuel Nahshon told Reuters, declining to elaborate.
President Tayyip Erdogan is one of Israel's most vocal critics. The June 7 election deprived his Islamist-rooted AK Party of its majority in parliament for the first time since 2002, which may pave the way for reconciliation with Israel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:58:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea to foreigners: don't bring in subversive media, porn</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/gmh4HAOq5_E/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SEOUL (Reuters) - North Korea has warned foreigners living in Pyongyang not to share outside media on memory sticks with its citizens, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a note, cracking down on what the isolated country called "undesirable content".</Description>
        <MainBody>SEOUL | By James Pearson
SEOUL North Korea has warned foreigners living in Pyongyang not to share outside media on memory sticks with its citizens, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a note, cracking down on what the isolated country called "undesirable content".
The vast majority of North Koreans have no access to outside Internet or foreign media, but people regularly share films, music and literature on easily-concealed USB sticks that are passed from person to person.
The note, a copy of which was seen by Reuters, said foreigners in Pyongyang would not be allowed to import "all kinds of data media, including printed matter, mobile phones, and memory sticks" which contain "false propaganda" and "photos, movies, and literature regarding sexual relations".
Some foreigners entering the country had left printed materials and memory sticks containing "undesirable content" at tourist sites, or passed them to North Koreans, the note added.
"We regard these practices as a serious problem directly related to the security of the State," said the note, which was dated Thursday and addressed to diplomatic and international missions in Pyongyang.
"Accordingly concerned authorities of the DPRK are taking such measures as strict censorship over printed matters and memory media at every port of entry to the DPRK, including the airport."
DPRK is short for the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, North Korea's official title.
The note warned that although those holding diplomatic passports were exempt from direct censorship, anyone found with offending material "must bear all the blame to themselves, entailing appropriate measures here".
Embassies in Pyongyang were looking into whether the note infringed the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, a diplomatic source in Pyongyang told Reuters. The 1961 convention forms the basis of diplomatic immunity.
In recent months, North Korean security services have stepped up scrutiny of Pyongyang's foreign residents.
During a fire in early June at the popular Koryo Hotel, a source in Pyongyang told Reuters that several foreigners had been apprehended by security services for taking photos.
Later, foreigners were briefly unable to access the country's 3G mobile internet network.
In April, North Korea expelled the country director of German NGO Welthungerhilfe, without warning or saying why.
(Editing by Tony Munroe and Clarence Fernandez)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:56:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. mediator to visit Kuwait, Riyadh in search of Yemen deal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/R8dB9yyc0SY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>GENEVA (Reuters) - A United Nations envoy will hold talks in Kuwait and Saudi Arabia in the coming days on a draft peace proposal for Yemen with the aim of reaching a "preliminary agreement" with Houthi fighters, a U.N. spokesman said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. mediator to visit Kuwait, Riyadh in search of Yemen deal
GENEVA
United Nations envoy to Yemen Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed talks to reporters upon arrival at the international airport of Sanaa, Yemen May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
GENEVA A United Nations envoy will hold talks in Kuwait and Saudi Arabia in the coming days on a draft peace proposal for Yemen with the aim of reaching a "preliminary agreement" with Houthi fighters, a U.N. spokesman said on Friday.
More than 2,800 people have been killed in Yemen during three months of air strikes by a Saudi-led coalition, including Kuwait, that aims to restore President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi who is currently living in exile in the Saudi capital Riyadh.
Iranian-backed Houthi fighters control large areas of Yemen,  including the capital Sanaa.
U.N.-sponsored talks in Geneva on a ceasefire between Yemen's warring parties broke up a week ago without a deal as the coalition staged further airstrikes.
U.N. envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed, who led the Geneva talks, will travel to Kuwait on Saturday and then spend a week in Riyadh before moving on to Sanaa for a further week of consultations, U.N. spokesman Ahmad Fawzi told reporters.
"He intends to spend more time in the two capitals (Riyadh and Sanaa) to discuss the draft principles paper which was developed here in Geneva - as he said, 'until we reach a preliminary agreement'," said U.N. spokesman Ahmad Fawzi.
"As you know, before leaving us here in Geneva, he said both sides had shown signs of constructive engagement regarding the possibility of reaching a humanitarian truce and that there was emerging common ground upon which to build an eventual ceasefire coupled with the withdrawal of combatants," Fawzi told a news briefing in Geneva.
The United Nations has estimated that more than 21 million people, or 80 percent of the Yemeni population, are now in need of humanitarian assistance.
The U.N. Security Council and U.N. aid chief Stephen O'Brien pressed on Thursday for more aid and commercial access to Yemen, where a near-total blockade by Saudi Arabia has slowed shipments to the Arabian Peninsula country to a trickle.
The World Health Organization (WHO) said on Friday it would provide essential medicines for treating non-communicable diseases such as heart and chronic respiratory illnesses for more than one million people in Yemen for six months.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:52:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack, at least eight wounded: newspaper</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/b0MZBtgmr24/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - A suicide bomber blew himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said on social media.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack, at least eight wounded: newspaper
DUBAI
DUBAI A suicide bomber blew himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said on social media.
The newspaper said the attack targeted Imam al-Sadeq Mosque in the Sawaber district.
"Eight casualties have been taken to the Emiri hospital, two in critical condition," al-Jarida said on its Twitter feed, without giving a source.
Arab television stations al-Arabiya and Al Jazeera earlier reported that an explosion hit the mosque and caused several casualties.
(Reporting by Hadeel al-Sayegh and Omar Fahmy, writing by Sami Aboudi; Editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:46:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/n-f-9oecgo4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BANGKOK (Reuters) - Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest
BANGKOK
BANGKOK Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.
Thailand's military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations for three days in Bangkok this week to protest against the junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
"We've caught them all, according to the arrest warrants, and the next step is to tell them what they are accused of," Wutthichai Suponthawit, deputy superintendent of the capital's Samran Rat police station, told Reuters.
"We will now jail them."
Thailand's army chief accused some politicians of backing the student groups, but did not identify them.
"They are the group that is not satisfied with the administration of this government," General Udomdej Sitabutr told reporters earlier on Friday.
Around 80 students held a 10-hour protest outside a Bangkok police station on Wednesday, brandishing signs that read "Peace" and "We want power for the people" or banners reading "No coup".
Last month, 40 student activists were arrested after holding peaceful rallies on the first anniversary of the May 22 coup.
All were released but at least 11 were charged with violating the junta's ban on political activity and face trial in military court, with jail terms of a year, if found guilty.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand's first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Thailand has been bitterly divided for a decade between supporters of Yingluck and her brother, former Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, who was himself ousted by the army in 2006, and the traditional establishment in the capital and the south.
(Reporting by Panarat Thepgumpanat and Aukkarapon Niyomat; Writing by Amy Sawitta Lefevre; Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:41:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli forces shoot and kill Palestinian gunman in West Bank: army</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/GIxAIk0JEm4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israeli forces shoot and kill Palestinian gunman in West Bank: army
JERUSALEM
JERUSALEM Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.
It was the third such violent incident in eight days.
On Sunday a Palestinian stabbed and wounded an Israeli paramilitary policeman outside the walled Old City of Jerusalem. The policeman shot back and wounded him. Last Friday a suspected Palestinian gunman shot at two Israeli hikers near a Jewish settlement in the West Bank and killed one. The assailant escaped.
There were no Israeli casualties in the latest incident.
Palestinians seek a state in East Jerusalem, the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, territories Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war. The last round of peace talks between the sides broke down in April 2014.
Palestinian militants this month fired rockets into Israel from Gaza, drawing Israeli return fire. That frontier has been largely quiet since the Gaza war last year in which more than 2,100 Palestinians and 73 on the Israeli side were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:23:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After China's Glastonbury complaint, UK source says it is Dalai Lama's call</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/b6QTrqJaB9c/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - After China complained about a Glastonbury Festival invite for the exiled Tibetan spiritual leader, a British government source said on Friday his appearance was a decision for festival-goers and for the Dalai Lama.</Description>
        <MainBody>After China's Glastonbury complaint, UK source says it is Dalai Lama's call
BRUSSELS
BRUSSELS After China complained about a Glastonbury Festival invite for the exiled Tibetan spiritual leader, a British government source said on Friday his appearance was a decision for festival-goers and for the Dalai Lama.
"It's a decision for the festival-goers and the Dalai Lama," the source said, when asked about China's caution that inviting him to visit one of Europe's largest music festivals was tantamount to giving him a platform to engage in anti-China activities.
The office of the Dalai Lama said on Thursday he would speak at Glastonbury during a three-day trip to Britain. He is not due to meet any government officials.
Festival organizers declined to comment on Friday or even confirm that the Dalai Lama would be appearing.
Beijing denounces him as a dangerous separatist who wants an independent Tibet. He denies espousing violence and says he only wants genuine autonomy for his Himalayan homeland.
In 2012, Prime Minister David Cameron had to put a trip to China on hold after Beijing took offense at him holding a meeting with the Dalai Lama.
The Dalai Lama is also going to Britain again in September, just ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's trip to the country in October.
Xi's state visit is the first to Britain in a decade by a Chinese head of state.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:15:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lebanese army says kills militants trying to infiltrate border town</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/66q7cWeO2FQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Lebanese soldiers killed two gunmen during a clash with militants who were trying to infiltrate the town of Arsal from the nearby border zone with Syria, the army said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Lebanese army says kills militants trying to infiltrate border town
BEIRUT
BEIRUT Lebanese soldiers killed two gunmen during a clash with militants who were trying to infiltrate the town of Arsal from the nearby border zone with Syria, the army said on Friday.
A security source said the militants were members of the Nusra Front, al Qaeda's wing in the Syrian war.
The militants were trying to reach Arsal when the army targeted them, it said in a statement. One of the dead was identified as a Syrian. The other was unidentified.
The Nusra Front and the Islamic State jihadist group staged an incursion into Arsal last August that triggered several days of deadly battles with the Lebanese security forces.
The Lebanese group Hezbollah, which is fighting alongside President Bashar al-Assad in the Syrian war, is mounting a joint operation with the Syrian army aimed at driving both Nusra and Islamic State from the border zone.
(Writing by Tom Perry ; Editing by Ruth Pitchford)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:08:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State commits major massacre in Syria's Kobani: monitor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/znO_A7mNq2w/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamic State has committed its second-biggest civilian massacre in Syria with an attack on the town of Kobani and a nearby village, killing at least 146 civilians so far, a conflict monitor said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>BEIRUT | By Sylvia Westall
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
1 of 5
right
Smoke rises in the Syrian town of Kobani as it is seen from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 25, 2015.
Reuters/Ali Sahin
2 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
3 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani who need medical help are taken to an ambulance on the Turkish-Syrian border in Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
4 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
5 of 5
right
BEIRUT Islamic State has committed its second-biggest civilian massacre in Syria with an attack on the town of Kobani and a nearby village, killing at least 146 civilians so far, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Fighting between the Kurdish YPG militia and Islamic State fighters who infiltrated the town at the Turkish border on Thursday continued into a second day, said Rami Abdulrahman, head of the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
A separate Islamic State attack on government-held areas of the northeastern city of Hasaka was reported to have forced 60,000 people to flee their homes, the United Nations said, warning that up to 200,000 people may eventually try to flee.
The twin attacks launched in the early hours of Thursday marked an Islamic State attempt to go back on the offensive after Kurdish-led forces, supported by U.S.-led air strikes, advanced to within 50 km (30 miles) of Raqqa city, the de facto capital of its self-declared "caliphate".
In both cases, Islamic State has picked targets where it is complicated for the U.S.-led alliance to provide air support. In Kobani, also known as Ayn al-Arab, aerial bombardment risks civilian casualties in residential areas targeted in the attack.
The U.S.-led alliance has meanwhile avoided bombing Islamic State targets in areas controlled by President Bashar al-Assad, such as government-held Hasaka - one of his last footholds in the northeast.
The United States and its European and Arab allies have been carrying out air strikes on Islamic State since last year in an effort to roll back the group that has seized wide areas of Syria and Iraq. Washington has ruled out cooperation with Assad.
The attack on the predominantly Kurdish town of Kobani and the nearby village of Brakh Bootan marked the biggest single massacre of civilians by Islamic State since it killed hundreds of members of the Sunni Sheitaat tribe in eastern Syria last year, the Observatory's Abdulrahman said.
The assault included at least three suicide car bombs. The dead included the elderly, women and children, Abdulrahman said.
The Islamic State fighters were reported to number in the low dozens and entered the town in five cars disguised as members of the YPG and Syrian rebel groups.
Fighting was ongoing inside the town, Abdulrahman said.
Kobani was the site of one of the biggest battles against Islamic State in 2014. The Kurdish forces eventually drove the militants out of the town in January with the help of U.S. air strikes and Iraqi Kurdish fighters after months of fighting.
Islamic State advanced rapidly last month, seizing cities in Syria and Iraq. But recent Kurdish advances in Syria shifted the momentum once more. Islamic State fighters have often adopted a tactic of attacking elsewhere when they lose ground.
The group wrested control of at least one district of Hasaka city in its raid there on Thursday. The city is divided into zones run separately by the Syrian government and the Kurdish administration that controls the YPG.
The U.N. Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs said an estimated 50,000 people had been displaced within Hasaka city while 10,000 had left northwards toward Amuda town, close to the Turkish border.
Speaking to Syrian state TV, the governor of Hasaka said the city was "safe and secure". He urged people to return home.
But the Observatory said fighting continued in the city. Government forces were carrying out air strikes targeting areas south of Hasaka controlled by Islamic State, it added.
Assad has since late March lost additional areas of northwestern, southern and central Syria to a patchwork of armed groups, including Islamic State, other jihadists, and rebels who profess a more secular vision for Syria.
The government has meanwhile focused on shoring up control over the main population centers of the west, including Damascus, with crucial military support from the Iranian-backed Lebanese group, Hezbollah.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:06:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican signs first treaty with 'State of Palestine', backs two-state solution</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/F1Is4kj5nZE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VATICAN CITY (Reuters) - The Vatican signed its first treaty with the "State of Palestine" on Friday, calling for "courageous decisions" to end the Israeli-Palestinian conflict with a two-state solution.</Description>
        <MainBody>VATICAN CITY | By Philip Pullella
VATICAN CITY The Vatican signed its first treaty with the "State of Palestine" on Friday, calling for "courageous decisions" to end the Israeli-Palestinian conflict with a two-state solution.
The treaty concerned the Catholic Church's activities in areas controlled by the Palestinian Authority.
The Israeli foreign ministry said it regretted the move, calling the signing of a treaty, which implies there is an official Palestinian state, "a hasty step (that) damages the prospects for advancing a peace agreement".
But Archbishop Paul Gallagher, the Vatican's foreign minister, said he hoped the agreement could be a "stimulus to bringing a definitive end to the long-standing Israeli-Palestinian conflict, which continues to cause suffering for both Parties".
He said he hoped that a peace process directly negotiated between Israelis and Palestinians could resume and lead to a two-state solution.
"This certainly requires courageous decisions, but it will also offer a major contribution to peace and stability in the region," he said..
The U.N. General Assembly adopted a resolution in 2012 recognizing Palestine as an observer non-member state. This was welcomed at the time by the Vatican, which has the same observer non-member status at the United Nations.
Since then the Vatican has de facto recognized a "State of Palestine" and Pope Francis referred to it by that name when he visited the Holy Land last year.
(Additional reporting by Maayan Lubell in Jerusalem Editing by Jeremy Gaunt)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:05:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. urges EU states to make 'concrete commitments' on refugees</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/l9I9bTn8iBg/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday welcomed the European Union's decisions on the migrant crisis but said much more needs to be done, including "concrete commitments" by member states.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. urges EU states to make 'concrete commitments' on refugees
GENEVA
A group of migrants gather near a line of lorries waiting on the motorway which leads to the Channel Tunnel terminal in Calais, northern France, June 24, 2015. Traffic was suspended on Tuesday after striking ferry workers accessed the terminal on the French side and set fire...
Reuters/Christian Hartmann
GENEVA The United Nations refugee agency on Friday welcomed the European Union's decisions on the migrant crisis but said much more needs to be done, including "concrete commitments" by member states.
European leaders argued into the early hours of Friday over how to handle the crisis in the Mediterranean, agreeing a plan to share out the care of desperate people fleeing war and poverty in North Africa and the Middle East.
They eventually agreed a voluntary scheme aimed at taking in 60,000 people and granted an exclusion for Hungary, which had earlier described the plan as absurd, and Bulgaria, one of the EU's poorest countries.
"This clearly is an important step along the way to finding answers to this crisis but clearly much more will have to be done, including addressing the root causes," Adrian Edwards of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) told a news briefing.
With agreement to relocate 40,000 asylum seekers now in Italy and Greece who are in need of international protection, "the participation of all member states will be key to success", he said.
"With regard to the proposal for EU-wide resettlement of 20,000 refugees, UNHCR urges member states to make concrete commitments toward this goal," Edwards said. "There does need to be a joined up response by Europe focused on the asylum priorities."
The plan was meant as an emergency response to the tragedy of 2,000 migrants dying in the Mediterranean this year but has been overshadowed by divisions, particularly in Eastern Europe.
In all, 153,000 migrants have entered Europe by land, air and sea this year, a jump of 149 percent compared to the same period last year, Joel Millman of the International Organization for Migration (IOM) said. "We expect this to be the start of a very busy summer."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:03:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey's AKP names defense minister as speaker candidate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Y1BlegFxmWg/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ANKARA (Reuters) - Turkey's governing AK Party nominated Defense Minister Ismet Yilmaz for parliamentary speaker on Friday, the first step in a closely watched contest likely to give insight into how talks to form a government are progressing.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkey's AKP names defense minister as speaker candidate
ANKARA | By Tulay Karadeniz
ANKARA Turkey's governing AK Party nominated Defense Minister Ismet Yilmaz for parliamentary speaker on Friday, the first step in a closely watched contest likely to give insight into how talks to form a government are progressing.
After losing its majority in parliament in a June 7 election, the Islamist-rooted AK Party founded by President Tayyip Erdogan must now find a junior partner to form a coalition government.
There has been some speculation of a partnership with long-time rival Republican People's Party (CHP), the secular, main opposition seen as representing the business elite. Those hopes have helped bolster the lira currency this week.
Some commentators have even said the AKP might ultimately be willing to back CHP candidate Deniz Baykal as speaker, in what could be a sign of the rival parties moving toward a grand coalition.
However, Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu on Friday named Yilmaz, a veteran politician and an engineer and lawyer by profession, as the AKP's candidate, saying that any coalition talks would start later.
"The subject of the parliament speaker is not a part of the coalition talks," he told reporters after announcing Yilmaz's candidacy.
He said coalition talks would only begin after Erdogan had mandated him to form a government, after the speaker was elected.
If Davutoglu fails to form a government, Erdogan could then ask the CHP to try to establish a working government.
The first two rounds of voting on the post of speaker are scheduled to be held in parliament on Tuesday, with candidates requiring the support of at least 367 MPs in the 550-seat assembly in those two votes.
In a third round of voting on Wednesday a minimum of 276 votes is needed. In the fourth and final round the candidate with the most votes will be elected speaker.
Aside from the AKP's Yilmaz and Baykal, the two other candidates are Dengir Mir Mehmet Firat for the pro-Kurdish HDP and former presidential candidate Ekmeleddin Ihsanoglu for the nationalist MHP.
AKP officials have privately said Erdogan may view a snap election as the best hope for the AKP to win back a majority and help him realize his vision for constitutional change to give him greater power.
However, a survey this week by pollsters Metropoll indicated Turks are unlikely to change their vote in any snap election soon, showing support for AKP stood at 41.6 percent, compared to the 40.7 percent it received at the election.
Media reports on Friday said another Metropoll survey showed Erdogan's approval rating had dipped to 37.5 percent in June, little more than half the 71.1 percent level at which it stood at the end of 2011 and down from 47.4 percent before he took over as president last August.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:45:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. criticizes Myanmar military veto after law change fails</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/7KNIXTNYUpU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>YANGON (Reuters) - The United States said on Friday that an effective legislative veto held by Myanmar's military was undemocratic and reiterated calls for changes to the constitution, a day after lawmakers from the armed forces bloc rejected any significant amendments to the charter.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. criticizes Myanmar military veto after law change fails
YANGON | By Timothy Mclaughlin and Hnin Yadana Zaw
YANGON The United States said on Friday that an effective legislative veto held by Myanmar's military was undemocratic and reiterated calls for changes to the constitution, a day after lawmakers from the armed forces bloc rejected any significant amendments to the charter.
Washington has re-engaged with Myanmar since a quasi-civilian government took power in 2011, ending 49 years of military rule, with President Barack Obama investing substantial personal effort and prestige in promoting democratic reform.
The United States has pushed for the country's military to be reined in, submitting to civilian control and stepping back from the political arena.
But Thursday's parliamentary vote, in which a proposed amendment to the veto provision failed to gain the necessary support, showed the military has no immediate plans to give up its powerful influence over public affairs.
"There are provisions in Burma's constitution, such as the lack of civilian control of the military and the military's veto power over constitutional amendments, that contradict fundamental democratic principles," a spokesman from the U.S. Embassy in Yangon said.
"It will be important to the ultimate success of Burma's democratic transformation that the constitution be amended to make it appropriate for a democratic nation."
In order for proposed changes to the military-drafted constitution to be accepted, more than 75 percent of lawmakers must support the amendment. With 25 percent of Myanmar's parliament seatsreserved for unelected military MPs, the bloc has an effective veto power.
A proposed amendment voted would have seen the threshold of support lowered to 70 percent, but failed, as expected, to gain enough support with lawmakers.
Military MPs said that while they did not opposed changing the constitution in the future, the time was not right and doing so now might risk instability.
"We are making the country's situation stable by putting 25 percent military MPs in the parliament," said Brigadier General Tin San Hlaing, a military MP.
"If these articles really need to be amended, the military representatives would not hesitate to do so."
The country's military has not given any indication when it might consider stepping back from its powerful political position.
Myanmar's seven-point road map for a "disciplined democracy" was first laid out more than a decade ago and former strongman Than Shwe stepped aside in 2011, but military officials have shown little will to move away from politics.
In addition to the military's seats in parliament, the commander-in-chief appoints the ministers of defense, border affairs and home affairs.
Five of the 11 members of the country's high-level National Defense and Security Council are also active military members.
A proposed change to a separate section of the constitution, which includes a provision that bars opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi from becoming president because her children are foreign citizens, also failed to pass.
The proposed change however, would not have gone far enough in helping secure Suu Kyi's presidential hopes, as it would only have allowed for individuals with children married to foreign citizens to hold the president's office, leaving her out.
Both amendments, if accepted, would have then needed the support of a national referendum.
Suu Kyi said after the vote that the military appeared opposed to even the slightest changes to its position.
"If we are going to amend the constitution, we have to make big moves. Today, we can see clearly that they don't even want to make small changes," she said.
(Editing by Alex Richardson )
Opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi speaks during a news conference after a vote for changes to the section of the constitution that bars her from becoming president in Naypyitaw, Myanmar June 25, 2015.
Reuters/Hnin Yadana Zaw
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:31:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Africa's mine massacre town sees little change three years on</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/hH6yo-kG6n4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MARIKANA, South Africa (Reuters) - Almost three years after South African police shot 34 striking miners dead outside platinum producer Lonmin's Marikana mine, little has changed in this hardscrabble town that has become a symbol of post-apartheid hardship and inequities.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Africa's mine massacre town sees little change three years on
MARIKANA, South Africa | By Zandi Shabalala
Cows graze in front of the koppie, where police killed 34 miners in 2012 in the ''Marikana massacre'', near the Lonmin mine in Rustenburg, northwest of Johannesberg June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Siphiwe Sibeko
MARIKANA, South Africa Almost three years after South African police shot 34 striking miners dead outside platinum producer Lonmin's Marikana mine, little has changed in this hardscrabble town that has become a symbol of post-apartheid hardship and inequities.
Cows and pigs root through litter-strewn dirt roads that snake past corrugated iron shacks - a picture of grinding poverty atop one of the world's wealthiest mineral deposits.
A long-awaited probe into the slayings, unveiled on Thursday by President Jacob Zuma, found Lonmin "did not respond appropriately" to the escalating violence during a wildcat strike in August of 2012.
Though the report slammed Lonmin for failing to comply with its social and housing obligations, few in Marikana felt it would make much difference.
Labor tensions in South Africa's mines continue, stemming in part from squalid living conditions that have persisted two decades after the end of apartheid.
"I understand that the report is out but it's not making me very happy. Nothing has changed here," said Samkelo Mkhize, 33, a former Lonmin miner.
"People were killed that day, and the government admits that they did something wrong but they don't act (as if) they will do something to change it," he said.
The commission, chaired by retired judge Ian Farlam, found "Lonmin's failure to comply with the housing obligations under the Social and Labor Plans should be drawn to the attention of the Department of Mineral Resources."
It further said the department "should take steps to enforce the performance of these obligations by Lonmin."
Mining companies in South Africa are required to meet a number of social requirements aimed at community and employee upliftment. But Lonmin may be hard pressed to meet such demands in the face of soaring costs and falling prices.
Lonmin's share price was down 3.5 percent on Friday to 3-1/2 month lows. Platinum's spot price is below $1,100 an ounce, some 25 percent lower than August 16, 2012, when police opened fire on the wildcat strikers.
Lonmin said in a statement that it has focused on "living conditions and employee indebtedness, two burning issues that we believe will make a profound impact on the wellbeing of our employees. Much work has been done in this regard."
But families of Lonmin employees in the grim shantytown the edge of Marikana, 120 kms (70 miles) northwest of Johannesburg, say much more needs to be done.
"Nothing has changed, we have no roads. If it was raining you could not even drive in here. This is a mine but we are living in shacks," Bongiwe Gumede, 30, a mother of three who said her husband was a Lonmin miner.
The commission also blamed police and unions for the vortex of violence that saw 10 people killed, including police and security guards hacked to death, before miners were slain in a hail of bullets.
It found allegations that Deputy President Cyril Ramaphosa had used his influence to trigger the police action were "groundless". Ramaphosa, seen as the potential successor to Zuma, was a non-executive director at Lonmin during the violence, which was rooted in a turf war between rival unions.
(Writing by Ed Stoddard ; Editing by Sophie Walker)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:15:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China military to investigate who owns its land</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/xp62ZcNbPdY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - China's military has launched a three-year project to try to work out who owns the land it uses after finding that a quarter of it lacked ownership documents, which has led to disputes with civilians, the Defense Ministry said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>China military to investigate who owns its land
BEIJING
BEIJING China's military has launched a three-year project to try to work out who owns the land it uses after finding that a quarter of it lacked ownership documents, which has led to disputes with civilians, the Defense Ministry said on Friday.
China's armed forces, the world's largest, have become a focus of President Xi Jinping's campaign to root out deeply-ingrained graft including bribery, which often takes the form of lavish gifts to officials or extravagant spending of government funds.
The military has warned repeatedly that buildings on its bases must be simple, cheap and unostentatious.
"Just like a citizen must have an identity card and a household registration documents, military land also needs its own 'proof of identity'," the ministry quoted an unidentified officer in charge of base and barracks building as saying.
With a quarter of land the military uses lacking such documentation, this has led to ownership disputes, the ministry added.
"This not only involves the legal use of land resources, but it also affects the harmonious relationship between the military and the government and the military and the people," it said.
These issues are "extremely sensitive", the ministry added.
The anti-graft drive in the military comes as Xi steps up efforts to modernize forces that are projecting power across the disputed waters of the East and South China Seas, though China has not fought a war in decades.
China intensified its crackdown on corruption in the military in the late 1990s, banning the People's Liberation Army from engaging in business. But the military has been involved in commercial dealings in recent years due to a lack of checks and balances, military analysts have said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:29:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bulgarian church joins calls for cancellation of Sofia gay march</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/rQq9mccyQ1I/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SOFIA (Reuters) - The Bulgarian Orthodox Church joined anti-gay activists in calling for the cancellation of a gay march in the capital Sofia planned for Saturday, adding to tensions over an event which has faced threats from protesters.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bulgarian church joins calls for cancellation of Sofia gay march
SOFIA
SOFIA The Bulgarian Orthodox Church joined anti-gay activists in calling for the cancellation of a gay march in the capital Sofia planned for Saturday, adding to tensions over an event which has faced threats from protesters.
"Our irrevocable belief is that homosexuality is unnatural lust, which undoubtedly damages the individual, the family and society and causes detrimental effects on physical, mental and spiritual state of people," the church said in a statement.
Thousands of people in the Balkan country, including politicians, editors and publishers of leading media, sociologists, actors and sportsmen, wrote a letter to Sofia mayor Yordanka Fandakova, urging her to cancel the event.
Homosexuality remains a sensitive issue across the Balkans and the annual gay march in Bulgaria has a history of violence with clashes between homosexuals and conservatives.
Ten years ago Bulgarian officials banned the country's first planned gay parade and about 60 far-right extremists were arrested for throwing a petrol bomb and trying to break up the march in 2008.
A homophobic attack was held against a gay film fest in the southern city of Plovdiv in 2013 while last year's Sofia march was blocked by Bulgarian nationalists.
"The Church strongly condemns any propaganda of homosexuality and oppose attempts to impose sinful acts as a norm, as a source of pride and an example to follow," the church said.
It said that such public gatherings encourage immoral behavior and destroy Orthodox Christian values.
In recent years Western ambassadors have supported the march. Last year several Sofia-based embassies issued a statement of support for Sofia pride, encouraging people and institutions in Bulgaria to stand up for and support open-mindedness and tolerance towards LGBTI people.
Some 80 percent of Bulgarians say they are Orthodox Christians - the mainstream religion also in Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, Greece, Romania and Serbia, but only few see churchgoing as important to their lives.
Trust in the Orthodox Church was shaken after a history commission showed a few years ago that many bishops collaborated with the former communist era secret police.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:16:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China moves controversial oil rig back towards Vietnam coast</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Syx685i_e5Y/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - China has moved an oil rig at the center of last year's violent dispute with Vietnam closer to Vietnam's coast in the disputed South China Sea, just weeks ahead of the first visit by a chief of Vietnam's Communist Party to Washington.</Description>
        <MainBody>China moves controversial oil rig back towards Vietnam coast
BEIJING
BEIJING China has moved an oil rig at the center of last year's violent dispute with Vietnam closer to Vietnam's coast in the disputed South China Sea, just weeks ahead of the first visit by a chief of Vietnam's Communist Party to Washington.
The move, announced by China's maritime safety authorities, comes soon after the country indicated it was close to setting up new outposts in the maritime heart of Southeast Asia, as it nears completion of land reclamation in the South China Sea.
China claims most of the potentially energy-rich South China Sea, through which $5 trillion in ship-borne trade passes every year. The Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan also have overlapping claims.
China's deployment of the rig last year in what Vietnam called its exclusive economic zone and on its continental shelf, about 120 nautical miles off its coast, led to the worst breakdown in relations since a brief border war in 1979.
Vietnam's people remain embittered over a perceived history of Chinese bullying and territorial claims in the South China Sea, although China said at the time the rig was operating completely within its waters.
The rig now appears to be in an area where the exclusive economic zones (EEZ) of Vietnam and China overlap, but further away than last year, said Le Hong Hiep, a visiting fellow at Singapore's Institute of South East Asian Studies.
In an online statement posted on Thursday, China's Maritime Safety Administration said the 'Haiyang Shiyou 981' rig would carry out "ocean drilling operations" 75 nautical miles south of the resort city of Sanya on southern Hainan island.
( here )
Experts estimate the drilling site is about 104 miles (167 km) east of the Vietnam coast. The $1-billion rig will remain there from June 25 until August 20, the statement said, telling  ships to stay 2,000 m (6,562 ft) away for safety reasons.
Vietnam's maritime authorities were monitoring the rig's placement, the website of the country's state-controlled Tuoi Tre newspaper on Friday quoted unidentified sources as saying.
The rig movement comes weeks before Vietnam's top leader, Nguyen Phu Trong, is expected to visit the United States, in the first such trip by a general secretary of the nation's Communist Party.
His mission is expected to further boost warming strategic ties between Washington and Hanoi - a relationship eyed warily in Beijing.
It also comes amid rising concerns at China's rapid creation of artificial islands on South China Sea reefs - construction criticized by the U.S. and protested by Vietnam.
However, Le Hong Hiep, the Singapore-based analyst, said he felt Hanoi would not protest as strongly as it did last year if China said the rig was placed within an EEZ claimed from Hainan Island rather than one from the hotly disputed Paracel Islands, as it did last year.
Vietnam and China agreed on an equal split of the maritime boundary of the Gulf of Tonkin in 2000 but have yet to agree on demarcating waters further south, near the rig's current site.
Earlier this year, the rig was drilling in the Andaman Sea off the coast of Myanmar, tackling the deepest exploration well it has so far undertaken, its owner, state energy group China National Offshore Oil Corporation (CNOOC), said in an earlier statement.
CNOOC could not immediately be reached for comment on Friday.
(Reporting by Ben Blanchard and Adam Rose in Beijing; Greg Torode in Hong Kong; Editing by James Pomfret and Clarence Fernandez)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
