<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Fri May 01 16:04:09 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Nepal quake toll passes 6,200; $2 billion needed for reconstruction</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/ic2hW2XjK_g/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KATHMANDU (Reuters) - The death toll from Nepal's devastating earthquake rose steadily past 6,200 on Friday as fresh aftershocks and the stench of rotting bodies made it hard for nervous survivors to return to their homes.</Description>
        <MainBody>Nepal quake toll passes 6,200; $2 billion needed for reconstruction
KATHMANDU | By Rupam Jain Nair and Gopal Sharma
KATHMANDU (Reuters) - The death toll from Nepal's devastating earthquake rose steadily past 6,200 on Friday as fresh aftershocks and the stench of rotting bodies made it hard for nervous survivors to return to their homes.
Disposal of the hundreds of bodies still being found six days after the 7.9 magnitude quake devastated the Himalayan nation of 28 million people was becoming a problem for officials, who have ordered immediate cremations.
"Morgues are full beyond capacity and we have been given instruction to incinerate bodies immediately after they are pulled out," said Raman Lal, an Indian paramilitary force official working in coordination with Nepali forces.
Aid was slowly beginning to reach remote towns and villages nestled in the mountains and foothills but the overpowering smell of bodies trapped beneath the rubble of collapsed buildings in the capital was making it hard for residents to return to their homes.
Related Video
Doctors treating quake survivor
Many Nepalis have been sleeping in the open since Saturday's quake. According to the United Nations, 600,000 houses have been destroyed or damaged.
Finance Minister Ram Sharan Mahat said Nepal would need at least $2 billion to rebuild homes, hospitals, government offices and historic buildings and appealed for help from international donors.
"This is just an initial estimate and it will take time to assess the extent of damage and calculate the cost of rebuilding," Mahat told Reuters.
The United Nations has said 8 million people had been affected, with at least 2 million in need of tents, water, food and medicines over the next three months.
Related Coverage
 Teenager rescued five days after Nepal quake
A home ministry official said the death toll had risen to 6,204, with 13,924 injured.
Information Minister Minendra Rijal said the government would provide $1,000 in immediate assistance to the families of those killed, as well as $400 for cremation or burial.
Prime Minister Sushil Koirala told Reuters earlier this week the death toll from the quake could reach 10,000.
That would surpass the 8,500 who died in a 1934 earthquake, the last disaster on this scale to hit the Himalayan nation sandwiched between India and China.
UNPRECEDENTED SCALE
Home ministry official Laxmi Prasad Dhakal said that, even though the 1934 quake was more powerful, there were fewer people living in the Kathmandu valley then.
"The scale of reconstruction will be unprecedented," Dhakal said. "We have still not even been able to assess the damage in remote areas, which have been completely devastated."Officials have said the chances of finding any more survivors were fading, even though a boy and a woman had on Thursday been pulled from the rubble where they had lain trapped for five days.
As rescuers slowly started reaching outlying areas, witnesses reported seeing 70 to 80 percent of buildings severely damaged in Chautara, northeast of Kathmandu towards the border with China's Tibet.
Anger over the pace of the rescue has flared in some areas, with Nepalis accusing the government of being too slow to distribute international aid that has flooded into the country.
It has yet to reach many in need, particularly in areas hard to reach given the quake damage, poor weather and aftershocks.Tensions between foreigners and Nepalis desperate to be evacuated have also surfaced. In Ashrang village in Gorkha, one of the worst-hit districts about four hours by road west of Kathmandu, hundreds of villagers were living outdoors with little food and water even as boxes of biscuits, juice and sacks of rice and wheat were stored in a nearby government office.Nepal is also appealing to foreign governments for more helicopters help the 20 at work in rescue operations. China was expected to send more, home ministry official Dhakal said.
In the Himalayas, climbing is set to reopen on Mount Everest next week after damage caused by avalanches triggered by the quake is repaired, although many have abandoned their ascents.
A massive avalanche killed 18 climbers and sherpa mountain guides at the Everest base camp.
(Additional reporting by Andrew MacAskill, Sanjeev Miglani , Ross Adkin, Frank Jack Daniel , Andrew Marshall, Adnan Abidi and Christophe Van Der Perre in Nepal; Writing by Paul Tait ; Editing by Alex Richardson )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:54:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>On Clinton's age, Republican rivals imply -- but never say -- she's old</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/mrfKdK44IMc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Her campaign barely three weeks old, Hillary Clinton already has been attacked by Republicans on everything from donations to her family's charitable foundation, to her tenure as secretary of state and her ties to Wall Street. But her rivals, and the political action committees that support them, are treading more carefully on one incendiary subject: her age.</Description>
        <MainBody>On Clinton's age, Republican rivals imply -- but never say -- she's old
WASHINGTON | By James Oliphant
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Her campaign barely three weeks old, Hillary Clinton already has been attacked by Republicans on everything from donations to herfamily's charitablefoundation, to her tenureassecretary of state andherties to Wall Street. But her rivals, and the political action committees that support them, are treading more carefully on one incendiary subject: her age.
If electedinNovember 2016, Clinton would be, at 69, the second-oldest person to take the presidential oath for the first time, behind only Ronald Reagan, who turned 70 weeks after being sworn into office in 1981.
Questions of health and fitness for the presidency dogged two former candidates of a similar age, Bob Dole in the 1996 election and John McCain in 2008,each of whom was 71 at this point in the race. Time magazine featured Dole on the cover asking whether he was"too old"for the job. McCain was so determined to show that he was healthy that he often put in back-breaking campaign days.
Get more campaign news from Tails from the Trail.
"I do think age is an issue in a presidential campaign,"said Steve Schmidt, who was McCains campaign manager."There is a thin line between seasoned and decrepit."
But several Republican campaigns that seem best positioned to exploit itdon'twant to touch the issue - at least directly.That's a shift from just a few months ago, when presidential hopefuls Senator Rand Paul, 52, and Wisconsin Governor Scott Walker, 47, explicitly referenced Clintons age as a possible disqualifier, and Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell likened her to a cast member of the hit TV show The Golden Girls, which featured four older women living together.
"Its a rigorous physical ordeal, I think, to be able to campaign for the presidency," Paulsaid in November, referring to Clinton's age. Now, however, Paulspresidentialcampaign doesnt want to talk about the issue. It declined further comment. As did Walkers political action committee, even though last fall, he, too, noted that he could run for president "20 years from now" and be the same age Clinton is today.
Campaign aides toPaul,Walker and Senator Marco Rubio, 43, as well as Republican strategists, told Reuters there was little appetite in the party at the moment for a direct assault on Clinton on the issues of her age and fitness for office, even after a 2012 fall that gave her a concussion and caused a potentially life-threatening blood clot.
Similarly, anti-Clinton politicalaction committees such as American Crossroads, America Rising, and Citizens United said they had no plans to launch ads centered on her age.
POLL SHOWS DEMOCRATS UNFAZED
"Its unwise to attack a political opponent based on her immutable characteristics, like race, gender and age," said Republican pollster Kellyanne Conway. She said she has met with at least five Republican presidential campaigns seeking her services and none of themhas indicated they want to go after Clinton on issues involving her age.
With Clinton swamped by questions about foreign donations to the Clinton Foundation and criticism of her use of a private email server while at the State Department, there is also simply no reason at the moment to engage in an attack that could be more divisive than beneficial, Republican strategistssaid.
They fear thathighlighting Clintons age could alienate women voters whom Republicans need to be competitive in next years general election.
Democratic pollster Anna Greenbergsaidwomen older than 50 wouldlikelycomprise the largest bloc of voters in 2016.
There is little evidence that Democrats and independent voters are concerned about having another president in their 70s. A Reuters/Ipsos poll conducted this month showed that Clintons age would not influence how 67percentof Democrats and 72percentof independents voted in November 2016.
And rather than downplay her age, Clinton in recent campaign events in Iowa and New Hampshire embraced herrole as a grandmother, striking sympathetic notes with other older women in the roomabout the responsibility of raising a grandchild.
Supporters have also sought to dismiss any concerns about her age as sexist, noting that shes the same age as Mitt Romney when he ran four years ago. Romney largely avoided any protracted discussion about his health.
IT'S A GENERATIONAL THING
While eschewing direct attacks, some of the Republican presidential hopefuls have found other ways to strongly hint that Clinton's age should be an issue for voters. They have repackaged the issue as "generational" and suggested she is a product of the politics of the 20th Century. That argument will grow more vivid should Clinton face a candidate who could be a generation younger than her in the general election.
When you look at Hilary Clintons age, it becomes an issue in a general election if shes running against a 40-something new face as opposed to Governor Bush, said Schmidt. Jeb Bush, the former Florida governor, is 62.
Rubio, a quarter century younger than Clinton, referred to her as a"leader from yesterday"when he announced his candidacy last month.
"We welcome the contrast (with Clinton)," said a top adviser to Rubio. "This election is going to be about the future."
Clinton's campaign declined to comment on the various statements by the Republican hopefuls, referring questions to Correct the Record, a rapid-response operation run by the pro-Clinton group American Bridge. A spokeswoman, Adrienne Watson, said it was Clinton's rivals, not her, who were behind the times.
"Republican politicians are stuck in the 90s - the 1890s," Watson said. "I'm sure all Americans, Republicans included, would appreciate it if Republican leaders would join (Clinton) in talking about our future."
She saw Rubio's comments as a coded attack on Clinton's age.
"Marco Rubio basically disqualifies himself to be president when he diminishes any American for being too young or old or anything else," Watson said.

BILL CLINTON'S PLAYBOOK
Yet Rubio's approach is similar to the one employed by Clintons husband, Bill, in his reelection campaign against Dole in 1996.
"I don't think SenatorDole is too old to be president, Clinton said at one debate. It's the age of his ideas that I question."
Dick Morris, who served asBillClintons campaign manager, said it was a subtle enough way to remind voters of the age difference between the two candidates.
"We obviously couldnt attack age directly because of older voters," Morris told Reuters. "What we did is adopt a whole strategy based on issues that would summon the memories and ideas of age without articulating it."
Dole released his medical records in 1995 to assuage concerns about his age. Butthe damage control was not entirely successful: hemistakenly called the Los Angeles Dodgers baseball team Brooklyn, and he tumbled off a stage during a rally.
Hillary Clinton, too, had what her husband seemed to term a senior moment in 2008 whenshe erroneously claimed she had come under sniper fire while on a trip to Bosnia as first lady.
Bill Clinton blamed the episode on his wife being exhausted, adding that her critics, when theyre 60, theyll forget something when theyre tired at 11 at night, too.
(Editing by Ross Colvin )
Video: The rioting in Baltimore this week spills into the 2016 race as candidates struggle to find an appropriate response.
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:23:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Dollar dips, trade thins on May Day after stormy week</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/QC-uAkB0w-g/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - A holiday in most of Europe thinned trade on Friday after a tumultuous week when the dollar dove, bond yields soared and stock markets in Europe and the United States weakened.</Description>
        <MainBody>Markets | Fri May 1, 2015 8:23am EDT
Dollar dips, trade thins on May Day after stormy week
LONDON | By Patrick Graham
Women wearing Hakama, or Japanese traditional Kimono, are reflected in an electronic board, showing various stock prices, outside a brokerage in Tokyo, March 23, 2015.
Reuters/Yuya Shino
LONDON (Reuters) - A holiday in most of Europe thinned trade on Friday after a tumultuous week when the dollar dove, bond yields soared and stock markets in Europe and the United States weakened.
Analysts struggled for clarity on what was driving the moves. The changes seemed rooted in concern that recent softer numbers on the U.S. economy were not just caused by winter weather, as they were a year ago.
That means no-one is betting heavily on a swift recovery of the U.S. and European economies, but bond yields have jumped this week, driven by worries among investors that they are getting no interest on their money.
The resulting action, driven on by poor U.S. first-quarter growth numbers on Wednesday, has sent the dollar down 6 percent in just over a week. Bund yields racked up the biggest two-day jump since the euro zone crisis in 2011 and European stock markets have fallen for four days in a row.
All major European markets except London, its biggest, were closed on Friday, but the euro was up another 0.3 percent to a two-month high of $1.1270, its best week since October 2011.
U.S. stock markets looked set to open higher.
"Weak U.S. data, a bounce in oil prices and a pick-up in European growth ... all weighed on positioning and the fallout has been seen in higher Bund yields, a stronger euro, a weaker U.S. dollar and a bounce in the commodity-currency bloc," Societe Generale analysts wrote in a note to clients.
"Now we are back to waiting to see if the U.S. economic slowdown will reverse in the coming months."
Encouraging unemployment data were released on Thursday. The focus on Friday was the ISM survey of U.S. manufacturing sentiment survey later in the day.
Asian shares finished a touch higher on the day and London's FTSE 100 inched into positive territory after a weak start.
The dollar was roughly flat on the day against a basket of currencies at 94.649. Gains against the yen and sterling offset weakness against the euro.
"While it is true Thursday's data was good, we need a steady stream of good data for the dollar bull trend to be restored," ING FX strategist Petr Krpata said. "Right now there is a fair bit of doubt about the dollar's bull run."
Crude oil prices were lower after logging their best monthly gains in six years in April, helped by the dollar's weakening and bets that a supply glut would ease.
Brent crude stood at $66.30 a barrel, after reaching a 2015 peak of $66.93 and adding 21 percent in April. U.S. crude fell 0.2 percent to $59.52, after hitting a 2015 high of $59.85 in post-settlement trading.
(Additional reporting by Judy Hua and Pete Sweeney in Beijing, Lisa Twaronite in Tokyo; Editing by Larry King)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:14:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/W7N7CpDGBzg/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>AMMAN/BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamist rebels and the Syrian army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad's ancestral home, the army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country's northwest.</Description>
        <MainBody>Islamist rebels battle Syrian army near Assad heartland
AMMAN/BEIRUT
AMMAN/BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamist rebels and the Syrian army fought fierce battles in Latakia province overnight close to President Bashar al-Assad's ancestral home, the army and rebels said, after weeks of insurgent gains in the country's northwest.
Rebels seeking to topple Assad have in the past sought to bring their four-year-long insurgency close to coastal areas in government-held Latakia, heartland of Assad's minority Alawite community.
An army source told state news agency SANA fighter jets hit insurgent hideouts in the northern Latakia countryside with "tens killed and wounded." Latakia is the main port in Syria and along with the capital Damascus is one of the most important government-held areas in the country.
The violence follows advances in neighboring Idlib province by the hardline Ahrar al-Sham group and Syria's al Qaeda wing Nusra Front as well as other allied fighters.
Rami Abdulrahman, who runs the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group, said the Latakia battles started with an army offensive on Thursday, backed by local militias, aimed at pushing the insurgents out of the province in order to advance on captured areas of neighboring Idlib.
The Observatory, which collects information from a network of sources on the ground, said at least five insurgents were killed and an unidentified number from the pro-government side.
Two rebel sources said the fighting in Latakia was near the mountains of Jabal al-Akrad, close to some of the highest peaks in Syria including Nabi Younis that overlook Alawite villages and close to Qardaha, hometown of the Assad family.
"The capture of the peaks would make the Alawite villages in our firing range," said an Ahrar al-Sham commander based in Idlib on Skype. In August 2013, Islamist rebels and foreign fighters briefly captured Alawite villages.
The Observatory's Abdulrahman said the army wanted to secure the valley and peaks in order to advance on Jisr al-Shughour, a town in Idlib province captured by insurgents a week ago.
Battles raged around a hospital on the southwestern outskirts of the town on Friday where army forces and allied fighters have been holed up since the insurgent offensive began, the Observatory said, adding that a blast had targeted the army earlier in the day.
On Friday Syrian television said army units targeted "groups of terrorists" in the eastern and southern Idlib countryside and "eliminated a great number of them and destroyed their weapons and munitions."
Diplomats say rebels are trying to pressure the overstretched army on as many fronts as possible to spread its resources ever more thinly.
(Reporting by Suleiman Al-Khalidi in Amman and Sylvia Westall in Beirut; Editing by Dominic Evans/Hugh Lawson)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri May 01 15:08:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Protesters ready for May Day march over black man's death in Baltimore</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/sDThjX1FMlA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BALTIMORE (Reuters) - Protesters and the family of a 25-year-old black man who died of injuries sustained while in police custody planned a May Day march in Baltimore as they demanded answers and punishment for the officers involved.</Description>
        <MainBody>Baltimore police give results of Gray death investigation to state's attorney
Baltimore City State's Attorney Marilyn Mosby, a black woman who is the daughter and granddaughter of police officers, has now taken over the investigation to determine what exactly happened to Gray and whether any of the six officers involved in his arrest should face criminal charges. The six have been suspended from duty.
Mosby said her office has been conducting its own independent probe. The U.S. Justice Department is also investigating the case.
"All I want her to do is one thing: Search for the truth," said U.S. Representative Elijah Cummings, a Democrat who has been a fixture in the largely peaceful protests that followed Monday's rioting. "We must allow the process to go forward."
Gray suffered spinal injuries some time between his April 12 arrest and his arrival at a police station. Police have said Gray was not restrained during the ride, a violation of department policies. He died a week later.
Related Coverage
 SLIDESHOW Protesters ready for May Day march over black man's death in Baltimore
Despite the protests, many questions about Gray's death remain unanswered. But media reports on Thursday provided possible accounts of what may have happened.
Multiple law enforcement sources told local broadcaster WJLA that the medical examiner found Gray's neck appeared to have broken when his head slammed into the back of the van. He also suffered a head wound matching a bolt jutting from the vehicle's back door, the sources told the station.
The Washington Post cited a prisoner, who rode in the police van with Gray but could not see him, as saying he heard sounds that suggested Gray tried to hurt himself while riding in the vehicle, according to a document written by a police investigator.
Many on the streets of Baltimore were skeptical of the idea that Gray's injuries were self-inflicted.
"The police did that," said Eugene Russell, 46. "And the police are going to get away with it."
'KAFKA-ESQUE NIGHTMARE'
Roughly 270 people have been arrested since Monday's violence - which saw stores looted, dozens of buildings and cars burned, and numerous officers injured - and officials have since imposed a citywide 10:00 p.m. curfew.
Police Commissioner Anthony Batts said on Wednesday that more than 100 people had been released without being charged, because officials could not keep up with the paperwork, though he said charges would be brought later.
But public defender Marci Tarrant Johnson described the conditions endured by many of the arrestees before their release in a Facebook posting Wednesday that has since gone viral.
Johnson wrote that many had been illegally detained for more than 24 hours and that women she interviewed had taken to using slices of bread served as part of their meals as pillows.
"Interviewing these women was emotionally exhausting. Quite a few of them began crying - so happy to finally see someone who might know why they were there, or perhaps how they might get out of this Kafka-esque nightmare," she wrote.
"The cells were designed to hold people for a few hours, not a few days," she said.
Baltimore police and the state's Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services could not be immediately reached on Friday morning to comment on the allegations.
The Associated Press reported on Wednesday that one of the officers involved in Gray's arrest had been hospitalized three years ago over mental health concerns. The report could not be independently confirmed.
(Writing by Curtis Skinner; Editing by Bernadette Baum )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:52:36 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Obama administration says to provide $20 million for police body cameras</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/1hmvPzdyS7Y/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Obama administration will provide $20 million in grants to local police departments to help buy body cameras for officers, the U.S. Justice Department said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By Julia Edwards
A Colorado Springs police officer poses with a Digital Ally First Vu HD body worn camera outside the police department in Colorado Springs April 21, 2015.
Reuters/Rick Wilking
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The Obama administration will provide $20 million in grants to local police departments to help buy body cameras for officers, the U.S. Justice Department said on Friday.
The grants represent the first portion to be approved by Congress of a $75 million, three-year body camera funding program requested in December by President Barack Obama.
Demand for the cameras, which clip onto officers' uniforms to record interactions with citizens, has risen amid a series of deadly altercations between police and unarmed black men, followed by protests in several American cities.
Baltimore Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake said last week that she would launch a body-camera pilot program after a black man died from a spinal injury while in police custody.
Some critics have accused Obama of doing too little to respond to the shootings. Democratic presidential front-runner Hillary Clinton said on Wednesday that the United States should make sure every police department has body cameras.
The cameras are expensive for police departments still struggling to regain pre-recession funding levels.
Los Angeles, which plans to deploy 860 cameras this summer, will spend $1.5 million in the first year to cover equipment, maintenance and storage.
The American Civil Liberties Union has warned that body camera use must be governed by standards that protect the privacy of those being recorded.
The federal funding will match local funds and be available only to departments that already have body camera policies in place, the Justice Department said in a fact sheet.
It will match funds dedicated to buying cameras and training police on how to use them, but not for storage of the footage they capture, which can often make up the bulk of the cost.
Departments awarded the money will be part of a pilot program, overseen by the Bureau of Justice Statistics, to evaluate the impacts of body cameras.
(Reporting by Julia Edwards; Editing by Kevin Drawbaugh , Lisa Shumaker and Susan Heavey )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:11:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ratings agencies say no default if Greece misses ECB, IMF payments</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/_PCEf6LOs1I/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - Most top credit rating agencies say they would not cut Greece's rating to default if it misses a payment to the International Monetary Fund or European Central Bank, a stance that could keep vital ECB funding flowing into the financial system.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greek national flags are on display at a shop in central Athens April 17, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
LONDON (Reuters) - Most top credit rating agencies say they would not cut Greece's rating to default if it misses a payment to the International Monetary Fund or European Central Bank, a stance that could keep vital ECB funding flowing into the financial system.
Greece owes nearly 1 billion euros to the IMF in May and almost 7 billion euros to the ECB over July and August and there are concerns that the government, stuck in funding talks with official lenders, will miss the payments.
This would be an unprecedented move that could put Athens' future in the euro in doubt and has raised questions about whether it could set off a chain reaction, possibly accelerating repayments due to other official and private sector creditors and compounding Greece's problems.
But for most rating firms, whose views determine whether the ECB can still accept sovereign Greek securities as collateral for lending to its banks, a missed IMF payment would not lead them label the country in default.
This is critical to keeping the life-support mechanism, the ELA emergency cash provided by the Greek central bank with the blessing of the ECB, flowing to banks because the ECB would not accept any securities issued by a government in default.
Standard and Poor's, Fitch and DBRS, three of the top four, all say that as the IMF and ECB are not standard creditors, a missed payment to either, although likely to push Greece's rating even deeper into junk, would not be classed as a default.
"If Greece were, for whatever reason, not to make a payment to the IMF or ECB that would not constitute a default under our criteria as it is 'official' sector debt," said Frank Gill, who rates Greece for S&amp;P.
As was seen during Greece's massive 2012 debt restructuring, only when all four of the main agencies -- Moody's is the other one -- declared Athens in default, did the ECB say it would not accept Greek bonds as ELA collateral.
Even then it did a quick U-turn after euro zone countries put 35 billion euros into an escrow account to cover the central bank in case there were any problems during the restructuring.
COLLATERAL DAMAGE
Fitch's Ed Parker and Fergus McCormick, head of sovereign ratings at DBRS both say their firms hold the same view as S&amp;P.
Moody's also agrees with them on a missed IMF payment but  differs on the ECB. Its top euro zone analyst, Dietmar Hornung, says that not paying the ECB would be a default as the bonds it holds are potentially marketable and so could be looked on as the same as any other marketable debt.
Even though the ratings agency might not declare a default after a missed IMF or ECB payment, the International Swaps and Derivatives Association (ISDA) committees, which are run by banks and other bonds holders, could decide to do so which could trigger payouts on Credit Default Swaps and 'cross defaults' on other bonds.
Nevertheless, the risk of automatic 'cross defaults' from a missed payment to the IMF or ECB to other public and private sector Greek debts appears minimal according to legal experts.
The only potential impact Allen &amp; Overy's Yannis Manuelides saw from any missed payments was that they could technically give the European Financial Stability Facility (EFSF) the option to demand immediate repayment of one of its big Greek loans. But as the EFSF is government controlled, that seems highly unlikely and it would most likely waive that option.
Still, failing to make the payments to the ECB and IMF -- Fitch has said it "cannot be discounted" -- would leave the ECB in a powerful position with regard to Greece.
Although it would probably not cut off Greek banks' emergency funding completely, the ECB could raise the 'haircuts' or discounts applied to Greek government securities when they are used as collateral, reducing the amount of cash it will extend to Greek banks.
The average haircut on Greek ELA collateral is estimated to be around 35 percent although it can be smaller, particularly on government bonds with a few years left to run.
Increasing the haircut would leave Athens with less money, creating more pressure on Athens to seal a deal for more aid.
All four ratings agencies said missing the IMF or ECB payments would not be a good idea.
"Defaulting to the central bank that is propping up your banking system is not particularly prudent," said S&amp;P's Gill.
"They would be more likely to default on their T-bills (than the ECB) the only problem is that they are then defaulting mostly on their own banks... and in any case a distressed exchange on T-bills would definitely be classed as a default."
(Editing by Anna Willard)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri May 01 14:01:00 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air strikes kill civilians in Yemeni capital</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/OwyXeQjEem0/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>CAIRO (Reuters) - Warplanes from a Saudi-led coalition struck a residential district of the Yemeni capital Sanaa overnight, killing eight to 10 civilians, residents said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Air strikes kill civilians in Yemeni capital
CAIRO
People stand amidst the rubble of houses destroyed by an overnight Saudi-led air strike on a residential area in Yemen's capital Sanaa May 1, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
1 of 4
right
People look at the rubble of hosues destroyed by an overnight Saudi-led air strike on a residential area in Yemen's capital Sanaa May 1, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
2 of 4
right
People stand amidst the rubble of houses destroyed by an overnight Saudi-led air strike on a residential area in Yemen's capital Sanaa May 1, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
3 of 4
right
People stand amidst the rubble of houses destroyed by an overnight Saudi-led air strike on a residential area in Yemen's capital Sanaa May 1, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
4 of 4
right
CAIRO (Reuters) - Warplanes from a Saudi-led coalition struck a residential district of the Yemeni capital Sanaa overnight, killing eight to 10 civilians, residents said on Friday.
The Saba state news agency, controlled by the Houthi movement in charge of Sanaa, put the death toll in the Sawan district at 20 and said more than 50 people had been wounded. It said casualties included woman and children.
Warplanes also struck a military airbase near the capital.
Saba said medics rushed to Sawan to try to rescue residents trapped under the rubble of homes.
The strikes came days after jets bombed the runway to stop an Iranian aid plane landing. Damage to the airport has stopped aid deliveries, officials said.
Saudi Arabia believes the Houthi group is a proxy its regional rival Iran, and Saudi backing for the resistance in Yemen's mostly Sunni Muslim south has raised fears that Yemen could descend into all-out sectarian war.
The Houthis hail from Yemen's far north and belong to the Zaydi sect of Shi'ite Islam. They swept into the capital Sanaa in September and pushed south and east, saying they were winning a revolution against Sunni militants and corrupt officials.
On Thursday, dozens of Houthi fighters were killed in clashes with Saudi forces on Yemen's northern border, Riyadh said. Air strikes and artillery fire rocked the southern city of Aden in fighting residents said was the worst in over a month of war.
(Reporting by Mohammed Ghobari; Writing by William Maclean ; Editing by Andrew Roche )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri May 01 13:02:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Scottish nationalist Sturgeon steals the show in British election</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/jJIdNuZovFQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - Detractors have vilified her as the most dangerous woman in Britain and an existential threat to the United Kingdom.</Description>
        <MainBody>LONDON | By Angus MacSwan
Nicola Sturgeon, the leader of the Scottish National Party, departs by helicopter from Prestonfield House in Edinburgh, Scotland, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Russell Cheyne
LONDON (Reuters) - Detractors have vilified her as the most dangerous woman in Britain and an existential threat to the United Kingdom.
New-found admirers have lauded her as an astute operator who has shaken up Britain's male-dominated political establishment.
Either way, Scottish National Party leader (SNP) Nicola Sturgeon has become one of the most talked about political leaders in the campaign for next Thursday's election.
Though a familiar figure in Scotland, Sturgeon was barely known south of the border until she put in a formidable performance in a televised debate between Britains political party leaders on April 2.
"Sturgeonmania" said newspaper headlines after the debate.
Her emergence has gone hand in-hand with remarkable surge by the SNP, which lost a Scottish independence referendum in September that could have broken the United Kingdom apart, but has since quadrupled its membership.
It is now forecast to take most - perhaps even all - of the 59 Scottish seats in the 650-seat United Kingdom parliament, obliterating the Labour Party in one of its traditional strongholds and potentially making Sturgeon kingmaker if neither the Conservatives nor Labour gain a majority.
Sturgeon, 44, says the SNP occupies the leftist ground that Labour has abandoned. It promises an end to spending cuts and to protect the national health service. Although independence is still its ultimate goal, it has downplayed the issue for now and says that it wants to reflect the aspirations of all Britons.
"We wont just serve Scotlands interests - though we will most certainly do that," she told students at the London School of Economics. "But we will seek do more than that - we will also seek to play our part in bringing about positive, long-lasting and progressive change right across the UK."
All this has political leaders and right-wing media commentators fulminating from their perches in London.
The Daily Mail dubbed her the Most Dangerous Woman in Britain. Its columnist sneered at her as La Sturgeon and mocked what he called her choirboy mullet hairdo. The Sun tabloid photo-shopped a picture of her posing in a Tartan bikini, putting her head on the body of singer Miley Cyrus.
Conservative Prime Minister David Cameron said a Labour-SNP deal was a terrifying prospect" and a match made in hell. Former Prime Minister John Major said the SNP posed a clear and present danger to the future of the United Kingdom.
Yet Sturgeon has won many fans in England.
A poll in the Herald newspaper showed Sturgeon had the highest approval rating of any party leader across Scotland, England and Wales among men and women of all age groups, with a net approval rating of +33, compared to +7 for Cameron and -8 for Miliband.
Nicola Sturgeon, a woman unknown to most English people until the leaders debates, was deemed dangerous and destructive because, frankly, she seems so capable," wrote leftwing columnist Suzanne Moore in the Guardian newspaper.
In fact, it is not clear how much influence the SNP can wield in London after the election, even if, as polls predict, it controls the balance of power. Sturgeon has committed to keeping the Conservatives out, which leaves her little choice but to back Labour leader Ed Miliband as prime minister.
Miliband says he will not form a coalition with the SNP, effectively challenging Sturgeon to support him in a minority government or explain to her left-wing Scottish voters why she let Cameron keep his job.
Still, having a large and vocal party to his left could influence some of Miliband's policies, and force him to cooperate occasionally with the Conservatives to pass laws, such as renewing Britain's nuclear arsenal, which the SNP opposes.
"I AM LEADER"
Her popularity outside Scotland stands in stark contrast to her pugnacious predecessor as SNP leader, Alex Salmond, who resigned after last year's referendum defeat and is loathed in England.
An early Conservative campaign poster showed a picture of Salmond with Labour leader Ed Miliband in his jacket pocket. As Sturgeon broke onto the scene, the poster was changed to show Miliband in her pocket.
Although she played tribute to Salmond as a friend and mentor when he quit, there is still the potential for rivalry.
If he wins in his Aberdeen constituency, Salmond will take a seat in the House of Commons in London, while Sturgeon, who is not standing for a British seat, will stay in Scotland as party leader and first minister of the Scottish government.
Sturgeon has nevertheless made it clear that it will be her taking the train south for any negotiations in the event that the SNP secures the kingmaker role.
When asked if she had ever had a row with Salmond, she told the BBC: "Yes." When asked what about, she said: "I'm not telling you."
"The final say now as leader of the party is now mine.... That's how leadership works," she said. "I am the leader."
Sturgeon was born in the southern Scottish town of Irvine. Her father was electrician and her mother a dental nurse and she was educated at a state school. She graduated in law from Glasgow University and worked as a lawyer.
Her early political stirrings came through the Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament and she joined the SNP at the age of 16.  She has spoken of the scandal of soaring poverty in a country as rich as Scotland".
Elected to Scotlands devolved parliament in 1999, she became SNP deputy leader in 2004. When the SNP took power in Scotland in 2011, she became health secretary then later was in charge of infrastructure, investment and cities. When Salmond resigned, she was unopposed as the choice to succeed him.
She now speaks about a creating a progressive alliance at the seat of Britain's parliament, Westminster. But she has a warning for the British elite too: It's an opportunity to give Westminster the fright of its life.
(Writing by Angus MacSwan; Editing by Guy Faulconbridge and Peter Graff )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri May 01 12:47:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China's struggles argue for stimulus all round</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/yfTKluGGuSA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SYDNEY (Reuters) - China's factories stayed stuck in the slow lane in April while Japanese output went into reverse and South Korea suffered its worst export performance in two years, adding urgency to calls for more state stimulus in all three economies.</Description>
        <MainBody>SYDNEY | By Wayne Cole
Smoke rises from a chimney among houses as new high-rise residential buildings are seen under construction on a hazy day in the city centre of Tangshan, Hebei province in this February 18, 2014 file photo.
Reuters/Petar Kujundzic/Files
SYDNEY (Reuters) - China's factories stayed stuck in the slow lane in April while Japanese output went into reverse and South Korea suffered its worst export performance in two years, adding urgency to calls for more state stimulus in all three economies.
Thailand has already surprised by cutting interest rates this week, while speculation is mounting that the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) will chop its rates to a record low of 2 percent at a May 5 policy meeting.
The need for action is all the greater as China, the former engine of global growth, remains jammed in neutral.
China's official Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI) held at 50.1 in April, just a fraction above the 50-point mark that separates growth from contraction on a monthly basis.
"As the economy still faces strong headwinds and the risk of deflation has not diminished, the authorities will need to continue to roll out easing measures in the coming months," said Li-Gang Liu, chief economist for Greater China at ANZ.
Following an aggressive one-percentage-point cut in banks' reserve requirement ratios last month, ANZ expects China's central bank will lower its interest rates further this quarter.
China's annual economic growth slowed to a six-year low of 7 percent in the first quarter, hurt by a housing slump and a downturn in investment and manufacturing.
In just the latest effort to turn the ship around, China's cabinet unveiled new measures on Friday to boost employment, offering more flexible tax breaks to companies to hire and preferential loans to business starters.
Beijing aims to create at least 10 million new jobs in 2015 and keep the urban jobless rate below 4.5 percent.
NOT ENOUGH INFLATION
In Japan, the Markit/JMMA version of the PMI fell to 49.9 in April, from 50.3 in March, taking it into contractionary territory for the first time since May last year.
Japan is emerging from recession at a snail's pace as companies remain wary of ramping up spending despite record profits and consumers keep their wallets shut.
That is challenging the Bank of Japan's bold pledge to accelerate inflation to 2 percent through massive money printing.
While core inflation did edge up a tick to an annual 2.2 percent in April, it is set to fall back toward zero in May when the impact of last year's rise in sales taxes drop out.
Neither have wages benefited as the BOJ hoped. Data out on Friday showed wage earners' total cash earnings were almost flat in March and inflation-adjusted real wages marked a two-year stretch of declines.
Across in South Korea, government figures showed exports fell 8.1 percent in April from a year earlier, the sharpest drop since February 2013, as shipments to China, the United States and the European Union all lost ground.
Consumer price inflation there is running at a 16-year trough of just 0.4 percent.
"The government will be sure to focus policy on boosting consumption as exports are no longer performing as they did in the past," said Stephen Lee, an economist at Samsung Securities.
The doleful data follows news the United States grew a bare 0.2 percent annualized in the first quarter of the year, held back by wild weather, a port strike and a strong dollar.
Yet there were glints of light in more recent data.
The number of Americans filing new claims for jobless benefits fell to a 15-year low last week and consumer spending rose in March, aided in part by a pick up in wage growth.
An upturn in wages has long been a key goal of the Federal Reserve and revived market expectations that interest rates would start to rise later this year, albeit not until September at the earliest.
(Reporting by Wayne Cole; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri May 01 10:54:38 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armani fetes 40 years in fashion with VIP gala, new museum</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/hB4cj66VHmA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MILAN (Reuters) - Italy's Giorgio Armani celebrated 40 years in fashion with a star-studded gala and opening of a museum dedicated to his designer business.</Description>
        <MainBody>Armani fetes 40 years in fashion with VIP gala, new museum
MILAN
Special fashion ambassador for Milan's Expo 2015 Italian designer Giorgio Armani poses during a photo call before his fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
1 of 15
right
Australian actress Cate Blanchett before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
2 of 15
right
Indian actress Aishwarya Rai pose before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
3 of 15
right
U.S. pop singer Tina Turner pose with Italian designer Roberta Armani before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
4 of 15
right
U.S. actress Glenn Close pose before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
5 of 15
right
U.S. actor Leonardo Di Caprio pose before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
6 of 15
right
U.S. actress Hilary Swank poses before the Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
7 of 15
right
U.S. actor Pierce Brosnan poses before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
8 of 15
right
U.S. actress Lauren Hutton pose before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
9 of 15
right
Italian designer Roberta Armani, niece of Giorgio, poses before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
10 of 15
right
Italian actress Sophia Loren pose before the Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
11 of 15
right
U.S. pop singer Tina Turner pose with her husband Erwin Bach before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
12 of 15
right
U.S. actor Chris Pine pose before the Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of Armani's career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
13 of 15
right
Pirelli's Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Marco Tronchetti Provare pose with his wife Afef before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of Armani's career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
14 of 15
right
Australian actress Cate Blanchett pose before Giorgio Armani's fashion show to celebrate the 40th anniversary of his career and to mark the opening of the Expo 2015 in Milan, April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Garofalo
15 of 15
right
MILAN (Reuters) - Italy's Giorgio Armani celebrated 40 years in fashion with a star-studded gala and opening of a museum dedicated to his designer business.
The 80-year old designer, known for his clean cut and elegant collections, was joined by celebrities such as Leonardo Di Caprio, Cate Blanchett, Hilary Swank and Tina Turner for the bash in Milan, headquarters to his fashion empire.
Nicknamed King Giorgio, the designer, who once worked as a window dresser, is known for being hands-on in creating one of the most recognized fashion brands in the world.
"There have been many moments, from the beginning until today," Armani told reporters upon arrival at the gala on Thursday evening. "Maybe my most emotional moment was when I saw my cover on 'Time'," he added referring to the magazine.
Armani, who designs both couture and ready-to-wear, has dressed celebrities, royals as well as sportsmen. Stars such as Beyonce, David Beckham and Megan Fox have modeled his perfumes or underwear.
"Madison Avenue in 1985, I think it was, so not very long after he came to our country and I have a closetful still of those beautiful suits, those classic suits, and I still wear them," actress Glenn Close said of when she bought her first Armani piece.
"James Bond" actor Pierce Brosnan paid tribute to the stylist, calling him "a mighty man" while Italian actress Sophia Loren simply said the designer "is my friend".
For the anniversary, Armani has converted a 1950s building that once stored cereals for a new exhibition dedicated of his designs.
The event took place ahead of the Friday opening of Milan Expo, of which Armani is special ambassador for fashion.
Officials are counting on some 20 million people visiting the six month exhibition of worldwide products and technologies.
(Reporting By Reuters Television; Writing by Marie-Louise Gumuchian ; Editing by Toby Chopra)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:20:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Ovechkin scores, sets up late winner as Caps beat Rangers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/Z1N2TQB5f8s/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>(The Sports Xchange) - Joel Ward scored with 1.3 seconds left to give the Washington Capitals a 2-1 victory over the New York Rangers in Game One of their Eastern Conference semi-final series at Madison Square Garden on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Related: Sports
Ovechkin scores, sets up late winner as Caps beat Rangers
Apr 30, 2015; New York, NY, USA; Washington Capitals left wing Alex Ovechkin (8) celebrates a goal scored by Joel Ward (42) (not pictured) against the New York Rangers during the third period in game one of the second round of the 2015 Stanley Cup Playoffs at Madison Square...
left
1 of 3
right
Apr 30, 2015; New York, NY, USA; Washington Capitals right wing Joel Ward (42) celebrates with Washington Capitals left wing Alex Ovechkin (8) after scoring the game-winning goal against the New York Rangers during the third period in game one of the second round of the 2015...
left
2 of 3
right
Apr 30, 2015; New York, NY, USA; Washington Capitals left wing Alex Ovechkin (8) is congratulated by teammates after scoring against the New York Rangers during the first period in game one of the second round of the 2015 Stanley Cup Playoffs at Madison Square Garden....
left
3 of 3
right
(The Sports Xchange) - Joel Ward scored with 1.3 seconds left to give the Washington Capitals a 2-1 victory over the New York Rangers in Game One of their Eastern Conference semi-final series at Madison Square Garden on Thursday.
Alex Ovechkin scored the opener and set up the winner when he centered the puck from behind the net to Ward, who beat Rangers goaltender Henrik Lundqvist along the ice.
Ward's goal was the second-latest winner in NHL playoff history. Jussi Jokinen scored with 0.2 seconds left for the Carolina Hurricanes against New Jersey Devils in 2009.
It was the second big play of the game by Ovechkin, who scored late in the first period to give the Capitals a 1-0 lead that held until the final five minutes when New York fourth-line winger Jesper Fast equalized.
Ovechkin's goal came when he unleashed a wrist shot from the top of the left face-off circle that beat Lundqvist, who was screened on the shot, high to the stick side.
The puck was out of the net so quickly some fans were not sure it was a goal.
Ovechkin nearly made it 2-0 early in the second when his wrist shot whistled past Lundqvist but the puck rang off the crossbar.
Despite playing a key role in the winning goal, Ovechkin said he did not see it go in.
"I'll be honest with you," Ovechkin said. "I didn't see what happened there on the puck. Obviously, you see them celebrating, so (I knew) it went in the net."
(Compiled by Andrew Both; Editing by Peter Rutherford )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri May 01 07:13:02 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Heisman winners Winston, Mariota go 1-2 in draft</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/agvmezC6yMM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>CHICAGO (Reuters) - Jameis Winston was taken by the Tampa Bay Buccaneers with the first pick of the National Football League Draft on Thursday and was followed by fellow quarterback Marcus Mariota in a Heisman 1-2.</Description>
        <MainBody>Heisman winners Winston, Mariota go 1-2 in draft
CHICAGO
Dec 6, 2014; Charlotte, NC, USA; Florida State Seminoles quarterback Jameis Winston (5) runs the ball during the second quarter against the Georgia Tech Yellow Jackets at Bank of America Stadium. Mandatory Credit: Jeremy Brevard-USA TODAY Sports
CHICAGO (Reuters) - Jameis Winston was taken by the Tampa Bay Buccaneers with the first pick of the National Football League Draft on Thursday and was followed by fellow quarterback Marcus Mariota in a Heisman 1-2.
Winston won the 2013 Heisman Trophy as top U.S. collegiate player, and Mariota, taken by the Tennessee Titans with the second pick, was the 2014 winner, marking the first time Heisman recipients went 1-2 in the NFL Draft.
The draft itself also struck an historic note as it was staged in Chicago's Auditorium Theater, shifting the proceedings away from New York City for the first time since 1964.
The 21-year-old Winston, who became the youngest winner of the coveted college award at 19, one month before leading Florida State to a national championship, was the consensus top choice.
Winston, who joins a Bucs team that selected first by dint of a league-worst 2-14 record, was widely seen as the most pro-ready quarterback available after thriving in a pro-style offense at Florida State.
The 6-foot-4, 230-pound, strong-armed Winston has all the tools for NFL success and the Bucs showed their confidence in him by overlooking a list of off-field incidents, including a sexual assault allegation and a shoplifting citation, as Tampa Bay background checks convinced them he could be counted on.
Winston skipped the draft proceedings to watch on television back home in Bessemer, Alabama, with family and friends and donned a red Tampa Bay cap in honor of his new team.
Tennessee followed by grabbing University of Oregon's Mariota, who watched from even farther away, in Honolulu.
Mariota, a mobile quarterback who ran a college-style spread offense, led Oregon to 36 wins in three seasons and steered the team to January's national championship game.
Related Coverage
 Selections in the first round of the NFL Draft
With the third pick, the Jacksonville Jaguars selected defensive end Dante Fowler Jr. of the Florida Gators.
"Since I was 10 I started watching the draft on TV and I told myself I want to be on that stage," the pass-rushing Fowler said. "My hard work paid off and I have a lot of great things to do.
"They know who I am," the Florida native said about expectations in Jacksonville. "Florida know who I am."
The Oakland Raiders took wide receiver Amari Cooper of Alabama with the fourth pick, and the Washington Redskins followed by taking offensive tackle Brandon Scherff of Iowa.
Two running backs were taken in the first round, bucking a recent trend, as Todd Gurley of Georgia was taken with the 10th pick by the St. Louis Rams, and Melvin Gordon of Wisconsin went to the San Diego Chargers with the 15th choice.
Adding some international flavor, defensive tackle Danny Shelton, taken 12th by the Cleveland Browns, wore a lava-lava sarong and an ula fala ceremonial necklace to honor his Samoan heritage.
Nigerian-born wide receiver Nelson Agholor of USC went with the 20th pick to the Philadelphia Eagles, and Jamaican-born guard Laken Tomlinson from Duke was taken at 28 by the Detroit Lions.
Rounds two and three will be held on Friday, with the last four rounds of the draft to be conducted on Saturday.
(Reporting by Larry Fine in New York; Editing by Frank Pingue/Peter Rutherford)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:58:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. government to pay New Mexico $73 million over radiation leak</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/SZK8zyB88N0/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>(Reuters) - The U.S. Energy Department will pay New Mexico $73 million in road and other infrastructure projects for violations by an underground nuclear waste dump and nuclear research lab that led to a radiation leak last year, officials said on Thursday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. government to pay New Mexico $73 million over radiation leak
By Laura Zuckerman
(Reuters) - The U.S. Energy Department will pay New Mexico $73 million in road and other infrastructure projects for violations by an underground nuclear waste dump and nuclear research lab that led to a radiation leak last year, officials said on Thursday.
The deal struck between the department and New Mexico forgoes fines and instead applies funds to upgrades to federal nuclear facilities and surrounding communities in the state, according to settlement documents.
Projects include construction of a $5 million emergency operations center in Carlsbad, near where the nuclear waste dump leaked radiation in February 2014.
The leak at the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant, or WIPP, exposed 22 workers to radiation in amounts not expected to threaten their health, and indefinitely suspended key operations at the site, the Energy Department's only permanent underground disposal facility for certain types of radiological waste from U.S. nuclear labs.
The radiation accident was caused by "chemically incompatible" contents, including cat litter, which reacted in a barrel of waste and caused it to rupture, according to a federal probe of the mishap.
The breached drum containing radioisotopes such as plutonium was improperly packaged with the wrong sort of kitty litter  used as an absorbent  at the Los Alamos National Laboratory near Santa Fe before it arrived at WIPP for disposal, investigators found.
New Mexico Governor Susana Martinez said in a statement that funds from the settlement "will be used to continue ensuring the safety and success of these important facilities, the people who work there, and their local communities."
The deal includes $34 million to improve roads around the WIPP site, $12 million to improve nuclear waste transportation routes in and around Los Alamos, and $9.5 million in storm-water management upgrades at the lab's complex.
In addition, it provides $10 million for improvements to water infrastructure in and around Los Alamos, and $2.75 million for an independent compliance and operational review.    In a statement, U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz said: "I am pleased that we were able to find a solution that will allow the Department to focus on resuming operations at WIPP and improving our waste management operations, while providing benefit to the environment and to local communities in New Mexico."
Energy Department officials have estimated the cost of the initial recovery of the dump at $240 million and said it might be two years or more before it is fully operational.
(Reporting by Laura Zuckerman in Salmon, Idaho; Editing by Daniel Wallis )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri May 01 05:02:37 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China says U.S. welcome to use civilian facilities in South China Sea</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/QsBAFIjMKzk/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - The United States and other countries will be welcome to use civilian facilities China is building in the South China Sea for search and rescue and weather forecasting "when conditions are right", China's navy chief has told a senior U.S. officer.</Description>
        <MainBody>China says U.S. welcome to use civilian facilities in South China Sea
BEIJING
BEIJING (Reuters) - The United States and other countries will be welcome to use civilian facilities China is building in the South China Sea for search and rescue and weather forecasting "when conditions are right", China's navy chief has told a senior U.S. officer.
China claims 90 percent of the South China Sea, which is believed to be rich in oil and gas, with overlapping claims from Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Vietnam and Taiwan.
Recent satellite images show China has made rapid progress in building an airstrip suitable for military use in the disputed Spratly Islands and may be planning another.
Those moves, along with other reclamations, have caused alarm around the region and in Washington too, with the issue dominating a summit of Southeast Asian leaders this week, to China's displeasure.
In a teleconference with the U.S. Chief of Naval Operations Jonathan Greenert, China's navy chief Wu Shengli said China's building work in the South China Sea would not affect freedom of navigation or overflight.
"Instead, it will improve the ability in these seas of public services like weather forecasting and maritime search and rescue, fulfilling international obligations to maintain the security of international seas," Wu said, according to a Chinese Defence Ministry statement released late on Thursday.
"(We) welcome international organizations, the United States and relevant countries to use these facilities in the future when conditions are right, to have cooperation on humanitarian search and rescue and disaster relief," Wu added.
The statement cited Greenert as saying he hoped China could explain to countries in the region in a timely manner the aim of the building work. It would also be good for maintaining stability and freedom of navigation if other countries could use such facilities for joint humanitarian operations, he said.
Disputes over how to tackle an increasingly assertive stance by China - an ally of several Southeast Asian states - in the strategic South China Sea make the issue the region's biggest potential military flashpoint.
China this week accused Vietnam, the Philippines and others of carrying out their own illegal building work.
While the militaries of China and the United States have worked hard to improve communication and cooperation, there is still deep mistrust. In 2013, a U.S. guided missile cruiser narrowly avoided a collision with a Chinese warship in the South China Sea.
Wu said U.S. surveillance operations were "totally out of step" with efforts to improve their military relations.
(Reporting by Ben Blanchard ; Editing by Paul Tait )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:29:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>New York mayor refutes allegations that police adopting tougher strategy for protests</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/YmAB5rLduug/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NEW YORK (Reuters) - New York Mayor Bill de Blasio denied that the city had toughened its policing strategy in response to the riots in Baltimore after some lawmakers accused the city's police force of overly aggressive tactics in its handling of protests on Wednesday night.</Description>
        <MainBody>New York mayor refutes allegations that police adopting tougher strategy for protests
NEW YORK | By Hilary Russ
New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio speaks to guests during the Whitney Museum of American Art Dedication Ceremony in New York April 30, 2015.
Reuters/Eduardo Munoz
NEW YORK (Reuters) - New York Mayor Bill de Blasio denied that the city had toughened its policing strategy in response to the riots in Baltimore  after some lawmakers accused the city's police force of overly aggressive tactics in its handling of protests on Wednesday night.
During a series of marches across Manhattan to protest the death of Freddie Gray, a black man who suffered severe spinal injuries while in police custody in Baltimore, there were 143 arrests, mainly for obstructing traffic. Riots in Baltimore after Gray's funeral on Monday led to arson and looting, as well as injuries to about 20 police officers.
"The strategic approach is exactly the same," de Blasio told a news conference. "We won't tolerate illegality, we won't tolerate disorder. We will not allow the few to undermine the honest efforts of the many to express their views."
Some lawmakers had a different view.
"It was overly aggressive," said New York State Assemblyman Michael Blake, who participated in Wednesday's protests, which started from Union Square.
"Most officers acted responsibly. However, there were too many unjust, incredibly inexcusable acts by officers last night without explanation," he said in a phone interview.
Priscilla Gonzalez, a spokeswoman for Communities United for Police Reform, said in a statement it is "unacceptable that Mayor de Blasio refused to take responsibility for the systemic lack of respect that the NYPD showed for the rights of peaceful protesters."
Last year, New York City Police Commissioner Bill Bratton was criticized for allowing groups of protesters to disrupt traffic by marching down the middle of major thoroughfares without getting a permit beforehand. Those protests were about the deaths of Eric Garner on Staten Island and Michael Brown in Ferguson, Missouri, who both died at the hands of police.
Speaking at a press event, James O'Neill, the Chief of Department of the NYPD, said that officers used tough tactics on Wednesday only in response to the crowd - when they defied orders to stay out of the streets or resisted arrest - but that there was no directive to crack down harder on protests in the wake of violence in Baltimore.
"Throughout the night we were extremely flexible, and we will continue to be flexible," said Police Commissioner William Bratton at the same event. "Our response often times is dictated by the circumstances."
De Blasio said the police approached incidents on a case-by-case basis and that run-ins were a result of a handful of protesters who were either intent on violence or disobeyed police orders.
The city's broader approach to policing is based on conversations, frequently several times daily, between the mayor's office and police leadership, de Blasio said. "We'll make tactical adjustments, but the strategy remains the same," he said.
During those talks, they have "reflected on some of what we saw in Baltimore, but it was not part of our decision-making about the situation here," he said.
Additional New York City protests over Gray's death are planned for Friday.
(Reporting by Hilary Russ; Additional reporting by Laila Kearney; Editing by Martin Howell )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri May 01 03:01:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Republicans pass deep spending cuts, aim at Obamacare</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/0RL2Bl83AJM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Republicans in the U.S. House of Representatives passed the first joint House-Senate budget plan in six years on Thursday, a measure that aids the party's goal of dismantling President Barack Obama's signature healthcare reform law this year.</Description>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By David Lawder
The U.S. Capitol building is seen before President Barack Obama arrives to deliver his State of the Union address to a joint session of the U.S. Congress on Capitol Hill in Washington, January 20, 2015.
Reuters/Jim Bourg
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Republicans in the U.S. House of Representatives passed the first joint House-Senate budget plan in six years on Thursday, a measure that aids the party's goal of dismantling President Barack Obama's signature healthcare reform law this year.
The Republican-authored plan would eliminate deficits by 2024 through deep cuts to social programs while increasing military spending by nearly $40 billion next year.
It passed 226-197 with no Democrats supporting it and 14 Republicans opposing it.
The Republican-controlled Senate is expected to pass the budget plan next week. Because it is a non-binding resolution, Obama does not sign it into law and most of its prescribed cuts are cast aside.
The House quickly pivoted to follow-on spending bills, passing a $76.6 billion measure to fund the Veterans Affairs Department and military construction projects.
But that normally popular bill drew much more opposition from Democrats than in previous years and a veto threat from the White House, which said the measure would fail to provide adequate funding for veterans health care and military facilities.
The White House also said Obama's advisers would recommend he veto any other spending bills based on the Republican budget framework because it keeps "sequester" spending caps in place.
A protracted standoff over spending levels would raise the risk of another government shutdown when the 2016 fiscal year starts Oct. 1, with a debt limit increase needed perhaps a month later.
The Republican budget seeks to slash about $5.3 trillion from domestic spending over 10 years, with deep cuts to programs that serve the poor, education and infrastructure. It contains no tax increases.
"It will not only get Washington's fiscal house in order but pave the way for stronger economic growth, more jobs and more opportunity," Republican Budget Committee Chairman Tom Price said on the House floor.
Democrats criticized its use of an off-budget war funding account to boost military spending next year.
"This agreement uses gimmicks to balance the budget, and does so on the backs of the poor and the middle class and senior citizens," said Representative Bill Pascrell, a New Jersey Democrat.
Passage of the budget gives Republicans a rare opportunity to use a procedural tool that would ease the repeal or replacement of "Obamacare."
This will allow them to pass such legislation with only a simple majority in the Senate, rather than a nearly impossible 60-vote threshold that would require the support of some Democrats.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:40:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Republican amendment fight threatens Iran bill in Senate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/EyIDY46OO2g/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - A dispute among Republican senators over changes to an Iran nuclear review bill on Thursday threatened the measure's chances of being passed by the U.S. Congress, leaving Senate leaders scrambling for a way to advance the legislation.</Description>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By Patricia Zengerle
Senate Foreign Relations Committee Chairman Senator Bob Corker (R-TN) uses the phones before meeting with Secretary of State John Kerry (not pictured) on nuclear negotiations with Iran on Capitol Hill in Washington April 14, 2015.
Reuters/Gary Cameron
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - A dispute among Republican senators over changes to an Iran nuclear review bill on Thursday threatened the measure's chances of being passed by the U.S. Congress, leaving Senate leaders scrambling for a way to advance the legislation.
Two Republican senators, Tom Cotton and Marco Rubio, used an unorthodox procedural move to try to force the Senate to vote on their amendments to a bill authored by another Republican senator, Bob Corker, that would give Congress the right to review an international nuclear agreement with Iran.
Rubio, a 2016 presidential hopeful, and Cotton, a leading congressional critic of President Barack Obama's Iran policy, want to toughen the bill with amendments including adding a requirement that Iran recognize Israel's right to exist as part of any nuclear deal.
Senate aides said the two made their move on Thursday just as Republicans and Democrats were finalizing an agreement on how to handle at least 66 amendments proposed by Republicans to the Iran Nuclear Review Act.
"I have a sense that the context of this has just changed," Corker said. "I regret that."
The Senate has been engaged in intense debate over the legislation, a compromise version of the bill reached in the Senate Foreign Relations Committee last week in an effort to avoid a presidential veto.
The White House had said some of the stronger provisions of the original measure would have threatened delicate international talks between Iran and world powers over Tehran's nuclear program. The negotiators have given themselves until the end of June to reach a final agreement, which members of Congress want to review.
Corker and Ben Cardin, the committee's Republican chairman and top Democrat, have been arguing against so-called poison pill amendments. They say such amendments would alienate many Democrats who now support the measure and prompt a veto.
Senators voted down two such controversial amendments  earlier this week.
There was some optimism about the bill's long-term prospects, however. Senate aides said they expected the  Republican Majority Leader, Mitch McConnell, would take steps as early as Monday to stop debate on the bill and allow a vote on a "clean" version, without amendments.
But a spokesman said late on Thursday that McConnell had not yet said whether he would do so, and that Senate leaders were still trying to find a way to have votes on amendments.
(Reporting by Patricia Zengerle; Editing by Cynthia Osterman )
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri May 01 02:16:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. data suggest economy picking up steam after weak first quarter</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/oyoMlYVko9A/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The number of Americans filing new claims for jobless benefits tumbled to a 15-year low last week and consumer spending rose in March, signs the economy was regaining momentum after stumbling badly in the first quarter.</Description>
        <MainBody>Markets | Thu Apr 30, 2015 7:16pm EDT
U.S. data suggest economy picking up steam after weak first quarter
WASHINGTON | By Lucia Mutikani
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The number of Americans filing new claims for jobless benefits tumbled to a 15-year low last week and consumer spending rose in March, signs the economy was regaining momentum after stumbling badly in the first quarter.
The economic outlook was brightened further by another report on Thursday showing a solid increase in wages in the first quarter, which should keep the Federal Reserve on track to raise interest rates this year.
"This morning's reports all point to an economy that is doing a lot better than the near-stagnation in first-quarter GDP suggests," said Paul Ashworth, chief U.S. economist at Capital Economics in Toronto.
Initial claims for state unemployment benefits fell 34,000 to a seasonally adjusted 262,000 for the week ended April 25, the lowest reading since April 2000, the Labor Department said.
Related Video
We'll see a rebound in hiring - Moody's Analytics Garber
Though the decline, which far exceeded Wall Street's expectations for a drop to 290,000, likely exaggerates the labor market's health, it bolstered views that March's sharp moderation in job growth was probably an aberration.
Separately, the Commerce Department said consumer spending, which accounts for more than two-thirds of U.S. economic activity, rose 0.4 percent last month as households stepped up purchases of big-ticket items like automobiles.
The increase followed a 0.2 percent gain in February and indicated that consumer spending picked up momentum at the end of the first quarter, which bodes well for consumption in the April-June period.
While that should boost growth in the second quarter, the rebound in economic activity could be crimped by an inventory overhang, a strong dollar and ongoing spending cuts in the energy sector, which has been hit by lower oil prices.
Related Coverage
 U.S. second-quarter GDP on track to grow 0.9 percent: Atlanta Fed
Another report showed that factory activity in the Midwest accelerated in April, pushing further away from a 5-1/2-year low hit in February.
The Institute for Supply Management-Chicago's business barometer rose to 52.3 from a March reading of 46.3. A reading above 50 indicates an expansion in the region's factory sector.
Stocks on Wall Street fell despite the fairly upbeat economic data, as Colgate-Palmolive (CL.N) cut its full-year profit forecast for the second time because of the buoyant dollar.
Sentiment was also hurt as ConocoPhillips (COP.N), the largest independent U.S. energy company, reported that its first-quarter profit fell to $272 million from $2.1 billion a year earlier due to lower crude prices.
Prices for U.S. government debt fell, with the yield on benchmark 10-year Treasury notes touching near a seven-week high. The dollar slipped against a basket of currencies.
WAGES ACCELERATING
When adjusted for inflation, consumer spending rose 0.3 percent in March after being flat in the prior month.
The economy slowed to a crawl in the first quarter as it struggled with severe winter weather, a now-settled labor dispute at normally busy West Coast ports, the strong dollar and lower energy prices, which have cut into domestic oil production.
The Fed on Wednesday acknowledged the first quarter's sharp growth moderation, but dismissed it as partly the result of transitory factors.
Spending last month picked up despite personal income being flat. But the income weakness will likely prove temporary as the labor market gradually tightens.
In a fourth report, the Labor Department said the Employment Cost Index, the broadest measure of labor costs, advanced 0.7 percent after a 0.5 percent rise in the fourth quarter.
The ECI is widely viewed by policymakers and economists as one of the better measures of labor market slack.
In the 12 months through March, labor costs jumped 2.6 percent, the largest rise since the fourth quarter of 2008. They are approaching the 3 percent threshold that economists say is needed to bring inflation closer to the Fed's 2 percent target.
Private sector wages and salaries increased 0.7 percent after gaining 0.5 percent in the prior quarter. They rose 2.8 percent in the 12 months through March, the biggest gain since the third quarter of 2008.
"The conditions seem to be in place for labor costs to start breaking out on the upside, and that would be enough to provide the Fed with the confidence that the inflation target will be reached," said Joel Naroff, chief economist at Naroff Economic Advisors in Holland, Pennsylvania.
(Reporting by Lucia Mutikani; Editing by Paul Simao)
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri May 01 01:51:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Republicans pass deep spending cuts, aim at Obamacare</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/reuters/topNews/~3/fSgz3bO3d0k/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Republicans in the U.S. House of Representatives passed the first joint House-Senate budget plan in six years on Thursday, a measure that aids the party's goal of dismantling President Barack Obama's signature healthcare reform law this year.</Description>
        <MainBody>WASHINGTON | By David Lawder
The U.S. Capitol building is seen before President Barack Obama arrives to deliver his State of the Union address to a joint session of the U.S. Congress on Capitol Hill in Washington, January 20, 2015.
Reuters/Jim Bourg
WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Republicans in the U.S. House of Representatives passed the first joint House-Senate budget plan in six years on Thursday, a measure that aids the party's goal of dismantling President Barack Obama's signature healthcare reform law this year.
The Republican-authored plan would eliminate deficits by 2024 through deep cuts to social programs while increasing military spending by nearly $40 billion next year.
It passed 226-197 largely on party lines. No Democrats supported it, while 14 Republicans voted against it.
The Republican-controlled Senate is expected to pass the budget plan next week. Because it is a non-binding resolution, Obama does not sign it into law.
The budget seeks to slash about $5.3 trillion from domestic spending over 10 years, with deep cuts to programs that serve the poor, education and infrastructure. It contains no tax increases.
Republicans hailed it as the first balanced budget plan since a brief period of U.S. surpluses from 1998 through 2001.
"It will not only get Washington's fiscal house in order but pave the way for stronger economic growth, more jobs and more opportunity," Republican Budget Committee Chairman Tom Price said on the House floor.
Democrats derided the plan as claiming a "phony" balance by calling for repeal of the Affordable Care Act but maintaining tax revenue levels associated with the law. The plan also skirts "sequester" spending caps to boost military budgets by funneling $38 billion to an off-budget war operations account next year.
"This agreement uses gimmicks to balance the budget, and does so on the backs of the poor and the middle class and senior citizens," said Representative Bill Pascrell, a New Jersey Democrat.
While most of the prescribed cuts in the blueprint will be ignored as Congress pivots to annual government agency spending bills, its passage gives Republicans a rare opportunity to use a budget procedural tool that would ease the repeal or replacement of "Obamacare."
This will allow them to pass such legislation with only a simple majority in the Senate, rather than a nearly impossible 60-vote threshold that would require the support of some Democrats.
While Obama has vowed to veto any attempt to dismantle Obamacare, he may be forced to compromise with Republicans if a Supreme Court ruling in June strikes down the health insurance subsidy structure at the heart of the law.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
