<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:41:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/shp9xvRkjbQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI (Reuters) - The number of party revelers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a colored powder thrown on those attending the party.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498
TAIPEI | By J.R. Wu and Pichi Chuang
TAIPEI The number of party revelers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a colored powder thrown on those attending the party.
Six foreigners and seven visitors from Hong Kong, mainland China and Macau were among those injured after about 1,000 people dancing at Saturday's event were sprayed with the powder, as a special feature of a festival also held in previous years.
The figure released late Sunday by local authorities was lower than an earlier estimate of 519 injured due to patients being transferred between hospitals and being double-counted, a government official said.
The blaze, which broke out at around 8.30 p.m. at the Formosa Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the colored powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder explode," he said.
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed and its safety can be assured.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters. All of the 498 injured were still being treated in 43 hospitals across the island, according to the latest figures provided by the New Taipei City government.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, who wore wet swimsuits and lay on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
A video posted online by Apple Daily showed dancers in front of the stage engulfed in clouds of colored powder a moment before a fireball erupted, followed by pockets of flame, triggering panic and screams.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man  said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims suffered burns on limbs and torsos, with some passing out from the pain while others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and pictures showed.
"Her whole life is ruined," sobbed the father of Chu Li, an 18-year-old girl with burns on 80 percent of her body, during a visit by President Ma Ying-jeou to victims in a Taipei hospital.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on its website on Sunday.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in recent weeks.
(Additional reporting by Faith Hung; Editing by Clarence Fernandez and Digby Lidstone)
A person helps an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wang Wei
1 of 4
right
People carry an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Chen Bo
2 of 4
right
Injured victims from an accidental explosion during a music concert lie on the ground at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wang Wei
3 of 4
right
People carry an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wu Chia
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:36:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Gunmen kill senior Iraqi oil official in Iraq's Kirkuk</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/ZQ8VpDIqvdY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BAGHDAD (Reuters) - Gunmen shot dead a senior oil official working for Iraq's state-run North Oil Company (NOC) on Sunday, police and company officials said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Gunmen kill senior Iraqi oil official in Iraq's Kirkuk
BAGHDAD
BAGHDAD Gunmen shot dead a senior oil official working for Iraq's state-run North Oil Company (NOC) on Sunday, police and company officials said.
NOC's chief of operations, Saad al-Karbalaie, was killed in the northern oil city of Kirkuk after gunmen forced him to stop his vehicle as he was leaving his office and then shot him, police sources said.
There was no immediate claim of responsibility for the attack on Karbalaie, who was supervising production and export facilities in Kirkuk.
Major oil producer and OPEC member Iraq faces security challenges from the ultra-hardline Sunni Islamic State which controls a third of the country, and a sectarian conflict exacerbated by the group's presence.
Baiji refinery, north of Baghdad, is a focal point for government efforts to slow the advance of Islamic State. The complex has changed hands several times in months of fighting.
(Reporting by Baghdad bureau; writing by Michael Georgy; editing by Jason Neely )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:35:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Historic meeting of pope and Russian Orthodox head seen nearer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/VYkB68Cdh5c/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ROME (Reuters) - An historic meeting between Pope Francis and Patriarch Kirill of the Russian Orthodox Church is "getting closer every day," a senior Orthodox prelate said in an interview published on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Historic meeting of pope and Russian Orthodox head seen nearer
ROME
Pope Francis waves as he leads his Sunday Angelus prayer in Saint Peter's square at the Vatican June 28, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Bianchi
ROME An historic meeting between Pope Francis and Patriarch Kirill of the Russian Orthodox Church is "getting closer every day," a senior Orthodox prelate said in an interview published on Sunday.
The unprecedented meeting would be a significant step towards healing the 1,000-year-old rift between the Western and Eastern branches of Christianity, which split in the Great Schism of 1054.
"Now such a meeting is getting closer every day but it must be well prepared," Metropolitan Hilarion, the head of the Russian Orthodox Church's foreign relations department, said in an interview with Italy's Corriere della Sera newspaper.
He said the meeting between the head of the 1.2 billion member Roman Catholic Church and the head of Russian Orthodox Church - which counts some 165 million of the world's 250 million Orthodox Christians - would take place in a "neutral" country, not in Moscow or the Vatican. Austria or Hungary were possibilities, he said.
Hilarion, one of the most influential people in world Orthodoxy, said he could not say if the meeting could take place as early as this year, but there was currently "a good dynamic" between the two Churches.
Francis told reporters on the plane returning from a trip to Turkey last year that he had sent word to Kirill that he was willing to meet the Russian patriarch "wherever you want, you call me and I'll come".
The Russian Orthodox Church has accused Catholics of using
their new freedoms of religion following the break-up of the Soviet Union in the early 1990s to try to convert people from the Orthodox, a charge the Vatican has denied.
One of the biggest bones of contention is the fate of many church properties that Soviet dictator Josef Stalin confiscated from Eastern Rite Catholics, who worship in an Orthodox rite but owe their allegiance to Rome.
Stalin gave the property to the Russian Orthodox Church but after the fall of communism, Eastern Rite Catholics took back many church properties, mostly in western Ukraine.
(Reporting by Philip Pullella ; Editing by Rosalind Russell)
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:33:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>French attack suspect admits to killing his boss: source</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/iHbCvP7S3JQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PARIS (Reuters) - The suspected Islamist militant held over an attack against a French chemical plant has admitted killing his boss, a source close to the investigation said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>French attack suspect admits to killing his boss: source
PARIS
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
1 of 3
right
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
2 of 3
right
French Gendarmes are seen at work next to a black plastic sheet (unseen) outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Ruben Sprich
3 of 3
right
PARIS The suspected Islamist militant held over an attack against a French chemical plant has admitted killing his boss, a source close to the investigation said on Sunday.
Yassin Salhi, 35, told detectives he had killed Herve Cornara in a parking area before arriving at the plant in Saint Quentin-Fallavier, 30 km (20 miles) south of Lyon, where he attempted to cause an explosion on Friday, the source told Reuters.
Police found the 54-year-old victim's decapitated body and head, framed by Islamic inscriptions, at the plant owned by U.S. group Air Products. There were no other casualties.
Examination of one of Salhi's mobile phones revealed that he took a "selfie" with the severed head before his arrest and sent the image via a messaging application to a Canadian phone number. Canadian police are now investigating.
According to French media reports, Salhi told police he had clashed with his boss as well as his own wife before the killing. One of their work colleagues, quoted on the website of television station i-Tele, also said the two men had argued days earlier after Salhi dropped a pallet of fragile equipment.
The suspect, whose wife and sister are also being questioned, is known to have associated with hardline Islamists over more than a decade and had previously been flagged by French security services as a potential risk.
Earlier on Sunday, French Prime Minister Manuel Valls said the government was increasing resources in law enforcement and domestic intelligence to combat Islamic extremism.
"We cannot lose this war, because it is essentially a war of civilisation," Valls said in an interview broadcast on Europe 1 radio and i-Tele. "It is our society, our civilisation and our values that we must defend."
(Reporting by Gregory Blachier, Writing by Laurence Frost,; Editing by Angus MacSwan )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:11:33 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Iran nuclear talks set to go beyond deadline as differences remain</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/43PZVEIDTbs/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - The six world powers seeking to negotiate an historic agreement with Iran to curb its nuclear program plan to carry on negotiating beyond a Tuesday deadline, a senior U.S. official</Description>
        <MainBody>European Union foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini arrives at the EU Council headquarters at the start of a European Union leaders summit in Brussels, Belgium, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Eric Vidal
VIENNA The six world powers seeking to negotiate an historic agreement with Iran to curb its nuclear program plan to carry on negotiating beyond a Tuesday deadline, a senior U.S. official
said on Sunday.
Iranian Foreign Minister Mohammad Javad Zarif was to leave Vienna and return to Tehran for consultations with the country's leadership on the state of negotiations, Iran said.
Officials from both sides said big differences still remained.
European Union foreign policy chief Frederica Mogherini said earlier on Sunday it was not impossible to get an accord by the self-imposed deadline but that a few extra days may be needed.
Foreign ministers from the negotiating countries were gathering in Vienna on Sunday to assess where the talks stood.
They expected them to spill over into July.
"Zarif will return to Tehran tonight and will come back to Vienna tomorrow," Iran's Tasnim news agency said, citing an unnamed Iranian official.
An Iranian official told Reuters that Zarif would "consult with the leadership" over the talks in Vienna.
The U.S. official, who spoke to reporters on condition of
anonymity, said Washington was not troubled by Zarif's decision to return to Tehran overnight, saying it was always expected that ministers would come and go from Vienna as the talks heated up.
The negotiations aim to limit Tehran's nuclear program in exchange for a lifting of U.S., European Union and United Nations sanctions on Tehran.
The United States, Israel and some Western nations fear that Iran has been trying to develop a nuclear weapons capability, but Tehran says its program is for peaceful purposes only.
The main differences are on the pace and timing of sanctions relief for Iran and on the nature of monitoring mechanisms to ensure Tehran does not cheat on any agreement.
U.S. and European negotiators also want to ensure there is a mechanism for restoring sanctions if Tehran fails to meet its commitments under any future accord.
In November, the seven nations involved in the talks set a late March deadline for a framework agreement, which they ultimately reached on April 2, and a June 30 deadline for a comprehensive deal.
Highlighting how much work remains, British Foreign Minister Philip Hammond said on arrival in Vienna that major challenges remained, including on the parameters already agreed in April.
"There are a number of different areas where we still have major differences of interpretation in detailing what was agreed in Lausanne)," Hammond told reporters.
"There is going to have to be some give or take if we are to get this done in the next few days," he said. "No deal is better than a bad deal."
In addition to Britain, Iran and the United States, the talks include China, France, Germany and Russia.
Speaking after a cabinet meeting in Jerusalem, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said too many concessions were being made to Tehran.
"We see before our very eyes a stark retreat from the red lines that the world powers set themselves only recently, and publicly," said Netanyahu, whose country is generally believed to have the Middle East's only nuclear arsenal.
"There is no reason to hasten into signing this bad deal, which is getting worse by the day."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:10:19 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air strikes in northwest Pakistan kill 20 militants: officials</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/erFvO4bco_4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BANNU, Pakistan (Reuters) - Air strikes killed at least 20 suspected militants in Pakistan's northwestern Shawal Valley on Sunday, intelligence officials said, more than a month after security forces moved in on Pakistani Taliban strongholds in the region.</Description>
        <MainBody>Air strikes in northwest Pakistan kill 20 militants: officials
BANNU, Pakistan | By Haji Mujtaba
BANNU, Pakistan Air strikes killed at least 20 suspected militants in Pakistan's northwestern Shawal Valley on Sunday, intelligence officials said, more than a month after security forces moved in on Pakistani Taliban strongholds in the region.
The deeply forested ravines are a smuggling route between Pakistan and neighboring Afghanistan, and are dotted with militant bases used as launch pads for attacks on Pakistani forces.
Two intelligence officials, who declined to be identified as they are not authorized to speak on the record, said the latest air strikes occurred in the Zoinari area of North Waziristan.
"We got information that local and foreign fighters were hiding in this area," said one of the officials. "Three hideouts were also completely destroyed."
Initially, 10 militants were reported killed but the intelligence officials later raised the toll to 20.
The hard-line Islamist Taliban's Pakistani wing used to control all of North Waziristan, a mountainous region that includes the Shawal Valley and runs along the Afghan border. But the Pakistani military has recaptured most of it in an operation launched last June.
NATO forces had long urged Pakistan for such an offensive, saying Taliban safe havens in Pakistan were being used to attack NATO and Afghan forces in Afghanistan.
Since last month, the military has stepped up operations in Shawal Valley, where the Taliban still operates freely.
The area is a stronghold of Khan "Sajna" Said, the leader of a Taliban faction whose name was added to a sanctions list of "specially designated global terrorists" by U.S. authorities last year.
Most phone lines to the area have been cut and military roadblocks curtail civilian movement.
The Pakistani Taliban mainly fight against the government in Islamabad and are separate from, but allied with, the Afghan Taliban that ruled Afghanistan in the late 1990s before being expelled in a U.S.-led intervention.
Both groups send fighters against Afghanistan's Western-backed government. Afghan officials have said the Pakistani army offensive has driven large numbers of fighters over the border, complicating the war in Afghanistan's east and north.
(Writing by Mehreen Zahra-Malik ; Editing by Clarence Fernandez and Digby Lidstone)
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:01:47 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Armed Tunisian police swarm streets of tourist towns</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/iAjP7TUUaHQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Hundreds of armed police patrolled the streets of Tunisia's beach resorts on Sunday and the government said it will deploy hundreds more inside hotels after the Islamist militant attack in Sousse that killed 39 foreigners, mostly Britons.</Description>
        <MainBody>Armed Tunisian police swarm streets of tourist towns
SOUSSE, Tunisia | By Zoubier Souissi
SOUSSE, Tunisia Hundreds of armed police patrolled the streets of Tunisia's beach resorts on Sunday and the government said it will deploy hundreds more inside hotels after the Islamist militant attack in Sousse that killed 39 foreigners, mostly Britons.
Thousands of tourists have left Tunisia since Friday's attack, which has shocked the North African country that relies heavily on tourism for jobs and foreign currency revenues.
Britain's Foreign Office warned late on Saturday that Islamist militants may launch further attacks in Tunisia after a gunman opened fire on the Imperial Marhaba resort in the deadliest such attack in Tunisia's modern history.
At least 15 Britons were among the dead and wounded along with German, Irish and Belgian nationals in Sousse. The health ministry says at least 40 people were wounded without giving any details of their nationalities.
"We are going to deploy 1,000 armed police to protect hotels and tourists," Tunisian Interior Minister Najem Gharsalli told reporters late on Saturday night.
Since its 2011 uprising to oust Zine El-Abidine Ben Ali, Tunisia has made a peaceful transition to democracy with a new constitution and free elections. It is seen as a model for the region.
But its young democracy has also been tested by the rise of  hardline Islamist movements, some of which have turned to violence. The army has been fighting a campaign against pockets of Islamist militants near the Algerian border.
State news agency TAP said gunmen raided houses for food in El Kef, a northeastern city about 160 km (100 miles) from the coast and 40 km from the Algerian border, before heading to the mountains that separate the two countries. TAP gave no further details.
Islamic State has claimed the Sousse attack. But officials say the gunman, named as Saif Rezgui, was not any watchlist of known potential militants. One source said he appeared to have been radicalised over the last six months by recruiters.
It was the second major attack in Tunisia this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
The tourism minister has described the Sousse attack as a catastrophe for the industry, which accounts for about seven percent of the country's gross domestic product.
"Germans, French and British officials informed us they would not prevent tourists from coming to Tunisia, but they want to participate in the investigation and to see clear security decisions," tourism minister, Salma Loumi, told reporters on Sunday.
"We will receive all ambassadors on Tuesday to inform them of all security measures taken to protect tourists," she said.
Loumi noted that many British tourists had decided to stay in Tunisia until the end of their holidays.
More than 3,000 tourists had already left the country a day after the attack.
"Tunisia is a beautiful country, and we will come back, but right now we need to leave, we need to forget what happened," said Lucy, a young British tourist leaving from a local airport near Sousse. "It's clear it is not safe here at the moment."
Islamist jihadists have attacked North African tourist sites before, seeing them as legitimate targets because they allow for a Western way of life and are tolerant of alcohol. Tunisia is one of the most secular countries in the Arab world.
Prime Minister Habib Essid said his government plans within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control, for inciting violence, and crack down on financing for certain associations, in order to counter jihadi rectruiters.
(Additional reporting by Tarek Amara; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Louise Ireland )
Police officers patrol the beach near the Imperial Marhabada resort, which was attacked by a gunman in Sousse, Tunisia, June 28, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
1 of 2
right
A woman attends a protest to condemn an attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada  hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 15:42:43 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Venezuela's struggling socialists hold primaries for parliamentary vote</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/JKriuUMUbB0/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>CARACAS (Reuters) - Venezuela's ruling socialists held primaries on Sunday ahead of December's parliamentary election they are forecast to lose due to a biting recession and discontent with the late Hugo Chavez's uncharismatic successor.</Description>
        <MainBody>Venezuela's struggling socialists hold primaries for parliamentary vote
CARACAS | By Alexandra Ulmer
Supporters of Venezuela's United Socialist Party (PSUV) arrive to a final campaign rally in Caracas, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jorge Dan Lopez
CARACAS Venezuela's ruling socialists held primaries on Sunday ahead of December's parliamentary election they are forecast to lose due to a biting recession and discontent with the late Hugo Chavez's uncharismatic successor.
The South American country is suffering shortages of basic goods ranging from spare parts to milk and medicines, annual inflation possibly in the triple-digits, and unchecked violent crime.
Low-income "Chavistas" who benefit from oil-fueled social programs now also spend hours in queues for scarce goods and see their salaries gobbled up by roaring inflation.
"The revolution doesn't work like it used to. You don't feel that emotion anymore," said a teacher at a state-run school in a low-income part of Caracas, who is disappointed with President Nicolas Maduro, the former bus driver and union leader she helped elect in 2013.
Still, the 50 year-old woman who asked not to be named, was voting on Sunday, in part because she fears for her job if she does not support the government.
The growing ranks of disillusioned ruling party supporters means Venezuela's MUD opposition coalition has its strongest shot in over a decade at recouping the National Assembly in the Dec. 6 vote.
However, the opposition has struggled to articulate policy proposals, its often wealthy politicians fail to connect with normal Venezuelans and 2014 protests that turned violent tarred its reputation.
The government also boasts a remarkable state propaganda machine, electoral district geography seen as favorable, and, crucially, a hardcore of unflinching loyalists who blame right-wing foes for engineering the economic crisis.
"I'm a die-hard voter," said Marcos Mirabal, 77, who proudly displays a Chavez figurine in his coconut store in the 23 de Enero hillside slum.
REVOLUTION ROCKED
Ruling party candidates include former ministers, Chavez's brother, an ex-military intelligence head briefly detained in Aruba last year over U.S accusations of drug-trafficking, and Mister Venezuela 2014.
Around 60 percent of them are 35 or younger, the government says. The electoral board mandated this week that a minimum of 40 percent of parliamentary candidates be women.
An outraged opposition, who held primaries last month and is now scrambling to get enough female candidates to meet the new requirement, slammed the move as an illegal last-minute change designed to stave off defeat.
Socialist candidates would only pocket 21.3 percent of votes for the National Assembly versus the opposition's 40.1 percent, a recent survey by pollster Datanalisis showed.
With Maduro's popularity down at 25.8 percent according to Datanalisis, some government campaigns appear to be lowering the visibility of the leader who commands nothing of the messiah-like allure of his mentor Chavez.
Their election song, for instance, features popstar Daniella Cabello, daughter of National Assembly boss Diosdado Cabello, who passionately croons about Chavez and the Socialist Party.
Unlike his predecessor, however, Maduro is not mentioned in the song or featured in the video.
(Reporting by Alexandra Ulmer; Additional reporting by Mircely Guanipa; Editing by Andrew Cawthorne )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:57:41 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Flash floods, landslides kill 23 in southeastern Bangladesh</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Rg8nzxmANdA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DHAKA (Reuters) - At least 23 people have died in flash floods and landslides triggered by heavy rains that lashed southeastern Bangladesh, officials said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Flash floods, landslides kill 23 in southeastern Bangladesh
DHAKA
DHAKA At least 23 people have died in flash floods and landslides triggered by heavy rains that lashed southeastern Bangladesh, officials said on Sunday.
Tens of thousands of people were marooned on higher ground as flood waters submerged areas around Cox's Bazar and the hilly district of Bandarban.
Local police official Habibur Rahman confirmed the toll to reporters after four more bodies were recovered from a river on Sunday.
Bangladesh - one of the world's most densely populated countries - is highly vulnerable to natural disasters, including cyclones, droughts, floods and earthquakes.
India, Bangladesh and China are most at risk from river floods, with an increasing number of people threatened because of climate change and economic growth in low-lying regions, a study said in March.
(Reporting by Ruma Paul; Editing by Rosalind Russell)
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 14:36:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bus carrying British children crashes in Belgium, driver dead</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Ea7wLCnGrqQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - A British bus with 34 children on board overturned and crashed on a motorway in Belgium on Sunday morning, killing a driver, a local mayor said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bus carrying British children crashes in Belgium, driver dead
BRUSSELS
Children stand next to rescuers after a British bus, which was transporting 34 children before it overturned and crashed on a motorway, near the city of Middelkerke, Belgium, June 28, 2015.
Reuters/Dominique Jauquet
1 of 4
right
Rescue personnel are seen working along a road after a British bus, which was transporting 34 children, overturned and crashed on a motorway, near the city of Middelkerke, Belgium, June 28, 2015.
Reuters/Dominique Jauquet
2 of 4
right
A British bus, which was transporting 34 children before it overturned and crashed on a motorway, is seen near the city of Middelkerke, Belgium, June 28, 2015.
Reuters/Dominique Jauquet
3 of 4
right
A British bus, which was transporting 34 children before it overturned and crashed on a motorway, is seen near the city of Middelkerke, Belgium, June 28, 2015.
Reuters/Dominique Jauquet
4 of 4
right
BRUSSELS A British bus with 34 children on board overturned and crashed on a motorway in Belgium on Sunday morning, killing a driver, a local mayor said.
None of children nor six accompanying adults were seriously injured in the accident, which happened when the driver lost control of the vehicle on a stretch of the E40 motorway near the Belgian coast.
"One driver has been killed, the other is seriously injured. Some of the children with light injuries have been taken to hospital and local medical centers," Janna Rommel-Opstaele, the mayor of the nearby coastal town of Middelkerke, told Reuters.
She said the bus was operated by British company NST, which organizes school tours.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 13:51:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Rouhani aims to bring transparency to Iran's legal system</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/6GHCd4hKdDc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Iran's judicial system must become more transparent and political crimes should be clearly defined, President Hassan Rouhani said on Sunday, in some of his strongest comments on domestic reform since taking office.</Description>
        <MainBody>Rouhani aims to bring transparency to Iran's legal system
DUBAI | By Sam Wilkin
Iran's President Hassan Rouhani arrives for a bilateral meeting with Indonesia's President Joko Widodo on the sideline of the Asian African Conference in Jakarta April 23, 2015. The 60th Asian-African Conference is held in Jakarta and Bandung from 19 to 24 April 2015.
Reuters/Mast Irham/Pool
DUBAI Iran's judicial system must become more transparent and political crimes should be clearly defined, President Hassan Rouhani said on Sunday, in some of his strongest comments on domestic reform since taking office.
The president, elected in 2013 with a promise to enact social reforms and create a more open political environment, has so far seen his efforts thwarted by powerful conservative factions, particularly in the judiciary.
Speaking at a televised judicial conference in Tehran, Rouhani called for more transparency in the prosecution of so-called political and security crimes that have seen large numbers of Iranian activists and journalists put behind bars.
"I hope we can define and codify political crimes during this government, with the cooperation of the judiciary, and put forward and approve a bill so it is clear what is a political or security crime," he said.
Rouhani also took aim at the judiciary's sometimes capricious application of other laws, a phenomenon that frequently disrupts daily life in Iran.
"Our judicial system must be transparent for everyone... even if the law is transparent, our judicial processes must also be transparent and accessible to the people," Rouhani said.
"We can see that a single law can have many interpretations, and the judge can make his own presumptions when he delivers a verdict."
Rouhani has spent most of his political capital in the past two years selling nuclear talks with the West, cajoling a skeptical population and combating powerful factions opposed to his policy of engagement.
CONCERTS CANCELED
But in recent weeks, with those negotiations entering their final days, he appears to have turned his attention to domestic issues.
Two weeks ago, he criticized law enforcement authorities for cancelling several concerts at short notice and without explanation, even after the Ministry of Culture and Islamic Guidance had given them licenses.
"When a license is given, it is completely inappropriate for another body to cancel it without the right authority," Rouhani said in a televised news conference on June 13.
"In cases where the judiciary wants to get involved, there must be legal justification for it to do so."
But he will continue to face resistance. Ayatollah Sadeq Larijani, the head of the judiciary, took the stage shortly after Rouhani on Sunday and insisted there was legal justification for cancelling the concerts.
"Cancelling concerts is within the law... if (the government) gives permission for concerts where young men and women will be dancing together, that is not right," Larijani said.
(Reporting by Sam Wilkin, Editing by William Maclean and Rosalind Russell)
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:57:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/NUfVCt80wXU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack
SOUSSE, Tunisia | By Tarek Amara
SOUSSE, Tunisia Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Tunisia's Prime Minister Habib Essid said most of the dead were British, and Britain's foreign office said 15 Britons had been confirmed killed in the attack in the resort town of Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis.
A German, a Belgian and an Irish woman have also been identified, foreign and Tunisian officials said.
It was the second major attack in the North African country this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
Tunisia has undergone a largely peaceful transition to democracy since its 2011 Arab Spring uprising, but its army has been fighting a rise in Islamist militancy.
Tunisia's tourism minister called Friday's attack in one of the country's most popular resorts for Europeans a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Saloua Kadri, Sousse tourism commissioner, said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had fled the town on Saturday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
Dozens of tourists were waiting to take flights out from the nearby Ennfida airport.
"We don't want to stay any longer, we just want to see our family, parents ... so leaving as soon as possible," said Hannah Russel, an British tourist.
Sarah Maeson, another Briton flying back to Manchester, said: "We don't feel safe. Constantly hearing sirens and helicopters is not really helping your nerves."
EXTRA FLIGHTS
Tunisian authorities named the gunman as Saif Rezgui, a student who they say was not known to them. Dressed in shorts and T-shirt, Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel on Friday, picking out foreigners and leaving Tunisians alive.
Witnesses said he made his way to the pool and hotel, his killing spree ending only when he was shot dead by police.
Tour operators Thomson and First Choice, which are owned by German travel group TUI, said they had about 6,400 customers across Tunisia at the time of the attack, including several of the people killed and injured.
They sent 10 planes to evacuate tourists and said 1,000 had already been repatriated. They also said they would cancel all their holiday packages to Tunisia for at least the next week.
TUI's German tour operator TUI also organized flights for tourists wishing to return home and TUI's Belgian airline, Jetairfly, sent six empty planes to bring tourists back from the island of Djerba and from Ennfida airport on Saturday.
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier confirmed one German had been killed, but said there may be others.
Tobias Ellwood, a junior minister at Britain's foreign office, told reporters in London the British death toll could rise as there were several who had been seriously wounded.
"This is the most significant terrorist attack on British people since 7/7," he said, referring to attacks on the London transport system on July 7, 2005, that killed 52 people.
NOT ON WATCHLIST
Tunisian authorities said the gunman was not on any watchlist of known potential militants. But one source said Rezgui appeared to have been radicalized over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
As one countermeasure, Prime Minister Essid said that Tunisia planned within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control for inciting violence.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighboring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan and was one of three linked to Islamist militants on three different continents on Friday.
In France, a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found, and in Kuwait a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait.
(Additional reporting by Estelle Shirbon in London and Erik Kirschbaum in Berlin; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Susan Fenton and Raissa Kasolowsky )
A boy holds a candle and flowers as he attends a protest to condemn the attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
1 of 7
right
People attend a protest to condemn an attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:50:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait says mosque bomber was Saudi, detains driver</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/DnbraqVcQHs/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KUWAIT (Reuters) - Kuwait on Sunday identified a suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst militant attack as a Saudi citizen and said it had detained the driver of the vehicle that took him to a Shi'ite Muslim mosque where he killed 27 people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait says bomber was young Saudi man, detains driver
KUWAIT | By Ahmed Hagagy
Mourners hold flags as the bodies of victims of Friday's bombing are buried in Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
1 of 5
right
Mourners hold flags with names of Prophet Mohammad's family members as the bodies of victims of the Friday bombing are transferred to vehicles to be transported to Karbala, Iraq, at  Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
2 of 5
right
Son of the Emir of Kuwait Sheikh Nasser Sabah al Ahmed al Sabah (C, 5th R) and Speaker of Parliament Marzouk al Ghanim (6th R) and other dignitaries attend the funerals of victims of a bombing at a mosque on Friday, at Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27,...
Reuters/Stringer
3 of 5
right
Inspectors work at the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Kuwait News Agency
4 of 5
right
Kuwaiti Information Minister Sheikh Salman al-Humoud al-Sabah (C) consoles worshippers outside the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a suicide bomb attack following Friday prayers, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
5 of 5
right
KUWAIT Kuwait on Sunday identified the suicide bomber behind its worst militant attack as a young Saudi Arabian man, and said it had detained the driver of the vehicle that took him to a Shi'ite Muslim mosque where he killed 27 people.
The disclosure of the bomber's Saudi nationality is likely to focus the attention of authorities investigating Friday's suicide bombing on ties between Islamists in the small Gulf state and those in its larger, more conservative neighbor.
The interior ministry named the bomber as Fahd Suliman Abdul-Muhsen al-Qabaa and said he flew into Kuwait's airport at dawn on Friday, only hours before he detonated an explosives-laden vest at Kuwait City's Imam al-Sadeq mosque.
It was not immediately known where Qabaa had arrived from, but the timing of his arrival suggests he had a network already in place in Kuwait. The ministry said it was searching for more partners and aides in this "despicable crime", adding Qabaa had been born in 1992, putting him in his early 20s.
Islamic State's Saudi Arabian arm claimed responsibility for the attack on the mosque, where 2,000 worshippers were praying at the time. It was one of three attacks on three continents that day apparently linked to hardline Islamists.
The attack was the most significant act of Sunni militant violence in Kuwait since 2005, when an al-Qaeda linked group calling itself the Peninsula Lions clashed with security forces in the streets of Kuwait City. Nine Islamists and four security force members were killed in the gun battles.
The bombing has sharply heightened regional security concerns because Islamic State appears to be making good on its threat to step up attacks in the holy fasting month of Ramadan.
The group, seeking to expand from strongholds in Iraq and Syria, says its priority target is the Arabian peninsula and in particular Saudi Arabia, home of Islam's holiest places, from where it plans to expel Shi'ite Muslims.
Islamic State subscribes to a puritanical school of Sunni Islam that considers Shi'ites as heretics.
The ministry said the driver of the Japanese-made car, who left the mosque immediately after Friday's bombing, was an illegal resident named Abdul-Rahman Sabah Aidan. The phrasing of its statement suggests Aidan is belongs to the "Bidoon", a large underclass in Kuwait lacking citizenship and access to jobs.
"DEVIANT" IDEAS
The interior ministry, which had earlier reported the vehicle owner's arrest, said Aidan, 26, was found hiding in one of the houses in the al-Riqqa residential area.
"Initial investigations showed that the owner of the house is a supporter of the deviant ideology," the ministry said, employing a term often used by authorities in the Gulf Arab region to refer to hardline Islamist militants.
The owner of the house, a Kuwaiti citizen, was also detained, the ministry said.
Officials said the bombing was clearly meant to stir enmity between majority Sunnis and minority Shi'ites and harm the comparatively harmonious ties between the sects in Kuwait.
Shi'ites are between 15 and 30 percent of the population of Kuwait, a mostly Sunni country where members of both communities live side by side with little apparent friction.
Kuwait is a conservative Muslim country where alcohol is banned, but it is less strict than Saudi Arabia on issues such as women's rights and freedom of religion.
Kuwaitis reacted with outrage to the bombing. Some said citizens who fund Islamist armed groups fighting in Syria and Iraq were to blame for any militancy in Kuwait.
"The wrath of God will come upon ISIS and everyone who is supporting them and collecting funds for them under the cover of helping refugees and orphans," wrote Hamad al-Baghli, aKuwaiti, on Twitter.
Kuwait has been one of the biggest humanitarian donors to Syrian refugees through the United Nations, but it has also struggled to control unofficial fund-raising for opposition groups in Syria by private individuals.
Abdulrahman al-Jeeran, a parliamentarian and member of the ultra conservative Salafi branch of Islam, told Reuters lawmakers should stop "sectarian discourse" and be prevented from using sectarian issues for electoral gains.
(Additional reporting by Rania el Gamal, Sami Aboudi, Noah Browning andf Taghreed al-Madani in Dubai; Writing by William Maclean ; Editing by Raissa Kasolowsky )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:48:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Albanian police arrest brothers suspected of killing officer</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/ebKElodaSoc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TIRANA (Reuters) - Albanian police have arrested two brothers suspected of leading the group of youths that shot dead an elite police officer in a raid on a village known until last year for producing cannabis worth hundred of millions of dollars.</Description>
        <MainBody>TIRANA | By Benet Koleka
TIRANA Albanian police have arrested two brothers suspected of leading the group of youths that shot dead an elite police officer in a raid on a village known until last year for producing cannabis worth hundred of millions of dollars.
A search party of about 500 policemen, backed by helicopters, found the two men from the southern village of Lazarat hiding in a communist-era army shelter in woodland 18 kms (11 miles) north of their home.
Prosecutors say Arbion Aliko, 20, and Alban Aliko, 18, were in charge of training a dozen young men over a period of six months to attack the police to restore cannabis production in Lazarat after a massive crackdown on the village a year ago.
Cannabis from Lazarat was exported across Europe for two decades until last June when the Socialist-led government of Prime Minister Edi Rama launched a crackdown. Albania is a NATO member state and is trying to join the European Union.
"Finally, justice for you Ibrahim. Your colleagues did the job. Those who dared attack you were arrested to face justice," Interior Minister Saimir Tahiri said after the arrest.
Ibrahim Basha, 31, a former soldier who had fought in Afghanistan and Iraq, was shot with a Russian sniper rifle when his team was helping colleagues under fire. The shooters had torn down a wall of breeze blocks to get a clear view.
The brothers had hiked along a cannabis smugglers' route over a mountain ridge to escape. They came out of the shelter with their hands in the air after negotiating with their father and a police mediator.
"I talked to my sons, and they surrendered. They had no weapons, they are fasting (for the holy Muslim month of Ramadan) and did not shoot the police," their father, Adil Aliko, said.
Police destroyed 71 tonnes of cannabis and 133,567 plants, five kg of heroin, four tonnes of cannabis seed and 17 liters of cannabis oil after the raid last June. About 500 weapons, some heavy, and a quarter of a million bullets were also seized.
Italian police estimate that Lazarat produced 4.5 billion euros ($5 billion) worth of cannabis in 2013.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 12:42:04 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kurds secure Syria's Kobani as Islamic State targets northeast</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/9U2gXjh6-IE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Syrian Kurdish fighters said they had fully secured the town of Kobani near the Turkish border on Saturday and killed more than 60 Islamic State militants, two days after the hardline group launched an incursion with suicide bombers.</Description>
        <MainBody>BEIRUT | By Sylvia Westall
BEIRUT Syrian Kurdish fighters said they had fully secured the town of Kobani near the Turkish border on Saturday and killed more than 60 Islamic State militants, two days after the hardline group launched an incursion with suicide bombers.
Further east, Islamic State pressed another assault on government-held areas of Hasaka city, clashing with the Syrian army after blowing up a security building late on Friday and triggering a government appeal for residents to take up arms.
"The people of the governorate and its surroundings continue to sign up with the Syrian Arab Army in its fight against terror," state television said in a news flash on Saturday and played archive footage of soldiers set to rousing music.
Hasaka's governor described the situation as "fine" but also called on residents to defend it in a phone call with state TV.
The twin assaults on Kobani and Hasaka came after Islamic State suffered two weeks of defeats at the hands of Kurdish-led forces, supported by U.S.-led air strikes.
Redur Xelil, spokesman for the Kurdish YPG militia, said Kobani was quiet and the YPG was combing the town for any hidden Islamic State fighters.
The YPG blew up a school building used by Islamic State in the town earlier on Saturday, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights monitoring group said, and plumes of smoke could be seen from the Turkish side of the border rising into the air.
The Observatory said a U.S-led airstrike killed at least 18 Islamic State fighters near Kobani. Islamic State killed around 200 civilians since the assault which started on Thursday, the Observatory said, describing it as one of the worst massacres committed by the group in Syria.
BATTLE FOR HASAKA CITY
In Syria's northeast, Kurdish forces and the army fought separate battles with the group around the city overnight. The YPG's Xelil said the Kurds were not fighting with Islamic State on Saturday.
The Observatory said fierce battles continued in the southwest, south and southeast on Saturday.
Islamic State launched its offensive on government-held areas of Hasaka on Thursday and the United Nations says the violence is estimated to have displaced up to 120,000 people.
"We want to reassure people in the governorate...Hasaka is fine," Governor Mohammad Zaal al-Ali told state TV but also echoed a government call for people to come back and defend their homes alongside the army.
"All of the people of the governorate who want to, pick up arms to defend it," he added. He said the air force had been carrying out frequent bombardments against Islamic State.
Hasaka province is important because it sits between Islamic State-held territory in Syria and Iraq and reaches north to the Turkish border. The city is divided into areas run separately by President Bashar al-Assad's government and Kurdish authorities.
The assault will test the army's capacity to hold on to areas far from the major government-held cities in the west. The YPG, which controls northern parts of the city, says it does not cooperate with government forces.
Islamic State said in statements posted online on Saturday it had attacked areas east of the city and in a video posted on YouTube said it had entered western areas.
Late on Friday Damascus called on Hasaka residents to take up arms in defense.
"I call on every man, every young woman and every young man able to carry weapons to move immediately and join the frontline positions to defend the city," Syrian Information Minister Omran al-Zoubi said on state television.
(Additional reporting by Murad Sezer in SURUC, Turkey and David Dolan in ANKARA; Editing by Ralph Boulton )
Smoke rises in the Syrian town of Kobani, as pictured from the Turkish side of the border near Suruc, Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
1 of 5
right
A Turkish Kurdish boy stands near the Mursitpinar border gate in Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, as smoke rises in the Syrian town of Kobani in the background June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
2 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani walk to the border fences as seen from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
3 of 5
right
Turkish soldiers stand guard near the Mursitpinar border gate in Suruc in Sanliurfa province as smoke rises in the Syrian town of Kobani in the background June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
4 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 11:13:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi: state media</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/eBIP5-Q5epI/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - Kuwait has identified the suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst attack as a Saudi citizen, Kuwait state media reported on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait says mosque suicide bomber was Saudi: state media
DUBAI
Mourners chant as they march during the funeral of the victim's of Friday's bombing at al Jafariya cemetery, in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
1 of 3
right
Men react next to coffins of victims of Friday's bombing at the Imam Sadeq mosque in Kuwait City, at the international airport in Najaf, south of Baghdad, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Alaa Al-Marjani
2 of 3
right
Police cordon off the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion following Friday prayers, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
3 of 3
right
DUBAI Kuwait has identified the suicide bomber who carried out the country's worst attack as a Saudi citizen, Kuwait state media reported on Sunday.
The interior ministry named the bomber as Fahd Suliman Abdul-Muhsen al-Qabaa and said he flew into Kuwait's airport at dawn on Friday, only hours before he detonated explosives at a Shi'ite Muslim mosque killing at least 27 people.
(Reporting by Rania El Gamal; editing by William Maclean )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 10:21:44 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Senior Uighur official investigated for graft in China's Xinjiang</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/vQNeL5qCH_Q/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - A senior ethnic Uighur official in China's unruly far western region of Xinjiang is being investigated for suspected serious "discipline violations", the Communist Party's anti-graft watchdog said on Sunday, using a euphemism for corruption.</Description>
        <MainBody>Senior Uighur official investigated for graft in China's Xinjiang
BEIJING
BEIJING A senior ethnic Uighur official in China's unruly far western region of Xinjiang is being investigated for suspected serious "discipline violations", the Communist Party's anti-graft watchdog said on Sunday, using a euphemism for corruption.
Alimjan Maimaitiming, 55, is secretary general of the regional government. The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection gave no other details in its brief statement.
According to his official biography he is from Cherchen, also known by its Chinese name of Qiemo, in the heavily Uighur deep south of Xinjiang. He had previously been editor-in-chief of the official Xinjiang Daily.
Hundreds of people have been killed in the region in the past few years, most in violence between the Muslim Uighur people who call Xinjiang home and ethnic majority Han Chinese.
President Xi Jinping has vowed to combat deep-seated corruption since assuming power in late 2012, although parts of China with big minority populations like Xinjiang and Tibet have largely escaped the campaign so far.
The ethnic Uighur mayor of Hotan, also in Xinjiang's deep south, was put under investigation for graft last year.
The officially atheist Communist Party has striven to appoint and promote more minority officials but, in Xinjiang especially, the Han Chinese-dominated party faces deep suspicion.
Some recent attacks have targeted Uighurs aligned with the government, including the killing of a state-backed Uighur imam last July.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 09:00:03 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Saudi soldier killed in cross-border shelling from Yemen</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/tfD0Mw-fVsY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - A Saudi soldier was killed and another wounded by shelling from forces loyal to former Yemeni president Ali Abdullah Saleh and Houthi rebels near the Yemen border, Saudi state news agency SPA said on Sunday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Saudi soldier killed in cross-border shelling from Yemen
DUBAI
DUBAI A Saudi soldier was killed and another wounded by shelling from forces loyal to former Yemeni president Ali Abdullah Saleh and Houthi rebels near the Yemen border, Saudi state news agency SPA said on Sunday.
The shelling on Saturday morning was directed at security guards in the southwestern Saudi border area of Jizan, according to a statement by the Interior Ministry on SPA.
An alliance of Gulf Arab nations has been bombing Houthi militia and army units loyal Saleh, which control much of Yemen,  since March 26 in what they say is an attempt to restore exiled President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi.
Saudi forces and the Houthis have been trading fire across the border since the Arab alliance began its operations.
On Saturday, Houthi fighters fired missiles at storage tanks in an Aden refinery, starting a large fire, and 14 people were killed in clashes between the Houthis and the Saudi-led forces near the southern port city, witnesses and residents said.
(Reporting by Ahmed Tolba; Writing by Rania El Gamal; Editing by Paul Tait )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:57:34 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwait arrests suspects in mosque attack, mourns dead</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/BMvkNPk8GKI/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KUWAIT (Reuters) - Kuwait detained the owner of a car that took a bomber to a Shi'ite mosque to carry out the country's worst ever militant attack, officials said on Saturday, as thousands calling for national unity turned out to bury some of the 27 killed.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwait arrests suspects in mosque attack, mourns dead
KUWAIT | By Ahmed Hagagy and Angus McDowall
Mourners hold flags as the bodies of victims of Friday's bombing are buried in Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
1 of 13
right
Mourners hold flags with names of Prophet Mohammad's family members as the bodies of victims of the Friday bombing are transferred to vehicles to be transported to Karbala, Iraq, at  Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
2 of 13
right
Son of the Emir of Kuwait Sheikh Nasser Sabah al Ahmed al Sabah (C, 5th R) and Speaker of Parliament Marzouk al Ghanim (6th R) and other dignitaries attend the funerals of victims of a bombing at a mosque on Friday, at Al Jafariya cemetery in Suleibikhat, Kuwait June 27,...
Reuters/Stringer
3 of 13
right
Paramedics rush a victim of a suicide bomb attack at Imam al-Sadeq Mosque, to the Amiri hospital in Al Sharq, Kuwait City, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
4 of 13
right
A Kuwaiti police officer stands next to a sniffer dog as investigations take place after a suicide bomb attack at the Imam Sadiq Mosque in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
5 of 13
right
Police cordon off the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion following Friday prayers, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
6 of 13
right
A resident looks at the damage at the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Kuwait News Agency
7 of 13
right
A victim of a suicide bomb attack at Imam al-Sadeq Mosque arrives at the Amiri hospital in Al Sharq, Kuwait City, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
8 of 13
right
Police inspect the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Kuwait News Agency
9 of 13
right
Inspectors work at the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Kuwait News Agency
10 of 13
right
Kuwaiti Information Minister Sheikh Salman al-Humoud al-Sabah (C) consoles worshippers outside the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a suicide bomb attack following Friday prayers, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
11 of 13
right
Ambulances park in front of the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion following Friday prayers, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
12 of 13
right
Crowds surround the Imam Sadiq Mosque after a bomb explosion following Friday prayers, in the Al Sawaber area of Kuwait City June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Jassim Mohammed
13 of 13
right
KUWAIT Kuwait detained the owner of a car that took a bomber to a Shi'ite mosque to carry out the country's worst ever militant attack, officials said on Saturday, as thousands calling for national unity turned out to bury some of the 27 killed.
Militant group Islamic State claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing against 2,000 worshippers praying at the Imam al-Sadeq mosque on Friday, one of three attacks on three continents that day apparently linked to hardline Islamists.
In Tunisia, a gunman killed 37 people including Western tourists on a beach, and in France a decapitated body was found after an attacker rammed his car into a gas container, triggering an explosion.
Officials said the bombing was clearly meant to stir enmity between majority Sunnis and minority Shi'ites and harm the comparatively harmonious ties between the sects in Kuwait.
In a statement, the information ministry said Kuwait would faced the situation with "unity and solidarity". It reiterated what it called the government's strong stance on the freedom of religion and opinion, noting these were rights protected by the constitution.
The interior ministry, which reported the vehicle owner's arrest, said it was now looking for the driver who vanished shortly after Friday's blast in Kuwait, which has been spared the rampant violence of neighboring Iraq and the recent spate of Islamic State bombings of Shi'ite mosques in Saudi Arabia, another neighbor.
A security source told Reuters "numerous arrests" had been made in connection with Friday's bombing.
At the burial site in the Sulaibikhat district, some waved Kuwaiti flags while others bore the large mourning banners, in red, black or green, that are typical of Shi'ite funerals.
Chants from the crowd included "Brothers of Sunni and Shia, we will not sell out our country," "No Sunni, no Shia, we are one Islam", "The martyrs are the beloved of God" and "Down with Daesh! Down with Daesh", an acronym for Islamic State.
One group of mourners said they had traveled from Qatif in Saudi Arabia where 21 people were killed by an Islamic State suicide bombing in May.
Two Iranian nationals were among those killed, foreign ministry spokeswoman Marzieh Afkham was quoted as saying by Iranian state media on Saturday.
Relatives of seven of those killed wept and prayed over their shrouded corpses at a mosque on Saturday, where they were waiting to be taken to the Shi'ite holy cities of Najaf and Karbala in Iraq for burial.
OIL SECURITY STEPPED UP
Shi'ites are between 15 and 30 percent of the population of Kuwait, a mostly Sunni country where members of both communities live side by side with little apparent friction.
"We will cut the evil hand that interferes with our homeland's security," Interior Minister Sheikh Mohammed al Khaled al Sabah was quoted as saying by state news agency KUNA.
Kuwait has stepped up security to the highest level at state-run oil conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) and its affiliates, KUNA also reported.
Islamic State named the bomber as Abu Suleiman al-Muwahed and said on social media that he had targeted a "temple of the apostates" -- a term the group uses to refer to Shi'ites, whom it regards as heretics. It did provide details of his nationality.
Islamic State had urged its followers on Tuesday to step up attacks during the Ramadan fasting month against Christians, Shi'ites and Sunni Muslims fighting with a U.S.-led coalition against the ultra-hardline jihadist group.
There was no evidence Friday's three attacks were deliberately coordinated. But coming so close together, they underscored the far-reaching, fast-growing influence of Islamic State, Western politicians said.
(Additional reporting by Reem Shamseddine, William Maclean , Sam Wilkin and Stephanie McGehee; Editing by Raissa Kasolowsky )
Our top news photos from the past week.  Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:20:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/fbhV6ybpF6k/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack
SOUSSE, Tunisia | By Tarek Amara
SOUSSE, Tunisia Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Tunisia's Prime Minister Habib Essid said most of the dead were British, and Britain's foreign office said 15 Britons had been confirmed killed in the attack in the resort town of Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis.
A German, a Belgian and an Irish woman have also been identified, foreign and Tunisian officials said.
It was the second major attack in the North African country this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
Tunisia has undergone a largely peaceful transition to democracy since its 2011 Arab Spring uprising, but its army has been fighting a rise in Islamist militancy.
Tunisia's tourism minister called Friday's attack in one of the country's most popular resorts for Europeans a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Saloua Kadri, Sousse tourism commissioner, said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had fled the town on Saturday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
Dozens of tourists were waiting to take flights out from the nearby Ennfida airport.
"We don't want to stay any longer, we just want to see our family, parents ... so leaving as soon as possible," said Hannah Russel, an British tourist.
Sarah Maeson, another Briton flying back to Manchester, said: "We don't feel safe. Constantly hearing sirens and helicopters is not really helping your nerves."
EXTRA FLIGHTS
Tunisian authorities named the gunman as Saif Rezgui, a student who they say was not known to them. Dressed in shorts and T-shirt, Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel on Friday, picking out foreigners and leaving Tunisians alive.
Witnesses said he made his way to the pool and hotel, his killing spree ending only when he was shot dead by police.
Tour operators Thomson and First Choice, which are owned by German travel group TUI, said they had about 6,400 customers across Tunisia at the time of the attack, including several of the people killed and injured.
They sent 10 planes to evacuate tourists and said 1,000 had already been repatriated. They also said they would cancel all their holiday packages to Tunisia for at least the next week.
TUI's German tour operator TUI also organized flights for tourists wishing to return home and TUI's Belgian airline, Jetairfly, sent six empty planes to bring tourists back from the island of Djerba and from Ennfida airport on Saturday.
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier confirmed one German had been killed, but said there may be others.
Tobias Ellwood, a junior minister at Britain's foreign office, told reporters in London the British death toll could rise as there were several who had been seriously wounded.
"This is the most significant terrorist attack on British people since 7/7," he said, referring to attacks on the London transport system on July 7, 2005, that killed 52 people.
NOT ON WATCHLIST
Tunisian authorities said the gunman was not on any watchlist of known potential militants. But one source said Rezgui appeared to have been radicalized over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
As one countermeasure, Prime Minister Essid said that Tunisia planned within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control for inciting violence.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighboring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan and was one of three linked to Islamist militants on three different continents on Friday.
In France, a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found, and in Kuwait a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait.
(Additional reporting by Estelle Shirbon in London and Erik Kirschbaum in Berlin; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Susan Fenton and Raissa Kasolowsky )
A boy holds a candle and flowers as he attends a protest to condemn the attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
1 of 7
right
People attend a protest to condemn an attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
