<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:22:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air strikes, ground combat in Yemen killed nearly 200</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/0yyuwAhnpDY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SANAA (Reuters) - Saudi-led coalition air strikes and clashes killed at least 176 fighters and civilians in Yemen on Monday, residents and media run by the Houthi movement said, the highest daily toll since the Arab air offensive began more than three months ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Air strikes, ground combat in Yemen killed nearly 200
SANAA
Guards walk through a damaged gate of the house of Brigadier Khaled al-Anduli, an army commander loyal to the Houthi movement, after it was hit by Saudi-led air strikes in Yemen's capital Sanaa July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
SANAA Saudi-led coalition air strikes and clashes killed at least 176 fighters and civilians in Yemen on Monday, residents and media run by the Houthi movement said, the highest daily toll since the Arab air offensive began more than three months ago.
The United Nations has been pushing for a halt to air raids and intensified fighting that began on March 26. Almost 3,000 people have been killed since then as the Arab coalition tries stop the Houthis spreading across the country from the north.
The Iran-allied Shi'ite Houthis say they are rebelling against a corrupt government, while local fighters say they are defending their homes from Houthi incursions. Sunni Saudi Arabia says it is bombing the Houthis to protect the Yemeni state.
On Monday, about 63 people were killed in air strikes on Amran province in the north, among them 30 people at a market, Houthi-controled state media agency Saba said.
In the same province, about 20 fighters and civilians were killed at a Houthi checkpoint outside the main city, also named Amran, about 50 km (30 miles) northwest of the Yemeni capital of Sanaa, local residents said.
Arab alliance war planes also killed about 60 people at a livestock market in the town of al-Foyoush in the south.
Also in the south, residents reported a further 30 killed in a raid they said apparently targeted a Houthi checkpoint on the main road between Aden and Lahj. They said 10 of the dead were Houthi fighters.
Tribal sources in the central desert province of Marib said about 20 Houthi fighters and soldiers fighting alongside them were killed in air raids and gun battles with tribal fighters, who support Yemen's president in exile Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi.
On Tuesday, U.N. envoy to Yemen Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed continues meetings with Houthi officials in Sanaa to try to broker a ceasefire to allow aid deliveries. One Houthi official said Monday's attacks had dealt a blow to peace efforts.
"Even as the U.N. envoy is present, there are a hundred martyrs and hundreds of wounded ... No truce, no retreat, no surrender. Forward, forward heroes of Yemen, for victory is coming," Yahya Ali al-Qahoom wrote on his Twitter account.
Neither side has offered concessions as civil war rages.
Fighting, bombing and a near-blockade by the Arab coalition has deepened suffering in what is one of the poorest countries in the region.
The U.N. says more than 80 percent of Yemen's 25 million people need some form of humanitarian aid.
(Reporting by Mohammed Ghobari and Noah Browning; Editing by Louise Ireland )
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:29:24 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Putin out to seize control of Ukraine, says Kiev defense chief</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Nij594_Bx9s/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KIEV (Reuters) - The West should not drop its guard over Ukraine, the country's defense minister said on Friday, saying a build-up of Russian forces in support of separatists showed President Vladimir Putin was bent on seizing control of the country.</Description>
        <MainBody>Putin out to seize control of Ukraine, says Kiev defense chief
KIEV
Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a session of the Civic Chamber at the Kremlin in Moscow, Russia, June 23, 2015.
Reuters/Sergei Karpukhin
KIEV The West should not drop its guard over Ukraine, the country's defense minister said on Friday, saying a build-up of Russian forces in support of separatists showed President Vladimir Putin was bent on seizing control of the country.
Stepan Poltorak spoke alongside visiting Canadian Defense Minister Jason Kenney as Kiev military chiefs reported intensified attacks by separatists in the east, despite a ceasefire, with another Ukrainian soldier killed.
"There is a threat still because the military groups of the (separatists)... and Russian troops continue to build up their forces, bringing additional equipment and ammunition and of course their plans are not peaceful," Poltorak said.
"One should not be naive and think that Putin has given up his plans to seize Ukraine, to destabilize the situation in Ukraine. He's just changing his tactics and strategies, but his goal remains the same: to seize Ukraine."
Putin denies accusations by Kiev and the West that Russia has provided pro-Russian separatists in east Ukraine with soldiers and weapons.
Although he is often accused of wanting control of Ukraine, he supports a February peace deal under which rebel-held areas of east Ukraine would be given more autonomy from Kiev but remain part of Ukraine.
Poltorak was expected to use Kenney's visit to press for the U.S.-led NATO alliance to provide further military assistance to shore up Kiev's forces in a conflict in which more than 6,400 people have been killed, according to U.N. estimates.
Canada, like many other NATO members, has provided the ex-Soviet republic only with non-lethal aid. Canadian military trainers are also expected to run programs for new Ukrainian conscripts inside Ukraine this summer.
Government forces and the Russian-backed separatists have accused each other of truce violations since February's deal,  brokered by the leaders of Russia, Ukraine, Germany and France.
Poltorak, in his remarks on Friday, accused the separatists of carrying out 5,000 shelling attacks on government positions since the deal was signed in Minsk, Belarus.
Separately on Friday Kiev military spokesman Andriy Lysenko said that one Ukrainian soldier had been killed in separatist rocket and artillery attacks since Thursday.
"The intensity of attacks is growing. They are going on around the clock," he told a briefing, saying hotspots were near the airport of the rebel-held city of Donetsk city and at Shyrokyne east of the government-held port city of Mariupol.
(Reporting by Serhiy Karazy and Natalia Zinets; additional reporting by Timothy Heritage in Moscow; Writing By Richard Balmforth ; editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:24:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/2oe2_CBFRVw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France (Reuters) - A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.</Description>
        <MainBody>Severed head found in suspected French Islamist attack
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France | By Catherine Lagrange
SAINT-QUENTIN FALLAVIER, France A severed head covered in Arabic writing was found at a U.S. gas company in southeast France on Friday, police sources and French media said, after two assailants rammed a car into the premises, exploding gas containers.
Speaking from a European Union summit in Brussels, French President Francois Hollande described it at a terrorist attack and said all measures would be taken to stop any future attacks on a country still reeling from Islamist assaults in January.
One suspect had been arrested and was already known to French intelligence sources, Hollande said.
"Two individuals deliberately rammed a car into the gas containers to trigger an explosion," a police source said.
It was not known whether the victim, so far the only known fatality in the incident that also injured two people, was decapitated before or after the car smashed into the building, or whether the victim had been on site at the time of the attack, or killed elsewhere.
"The attack was of a terrorist nature since a body was discovered, decapitated and with inscriptions," Hollande told the news conference.
ISLAMIST FLAG
Police sources earlier said the decapitated body was found at the site, along with a flag bearing Islamist inscriptions.
Local newspaper Le Dauphine said the head covered in Arabic writing was found on a fence.
The French public prosecutor said its anti-terrorist section had been deployed to investigate.
France, which has deployed aircraft to the international coalition fighting Islamic State insurgents in Iraq, has long been named on Islamist sites as a primary target for attacks.
In April, Prime Minister Manuel Valls said no fewer than five attacks had been thwarted in the country since the Charlie Hebdo killings in January.
Then, Islamist gunmen killed 17 people in the offices of the Charlie Hebdo satirical weekly and a Jewish food store.
Noting that hundreds of French nationals are in Syria where they risked being radicalized by Islamist fighters, Valls said "never has the threat been so high".
The site belonged to Air Products, a U.S. industrial gases and chemicals company, according to a spokeswoman for Air Liquide, a French company in the same sector. It was immediately ringfenced by police and emergency services.
The chairman and CEO of Air Products is Seifi Ghasemi, who in 2011 testimony to a U.S. Senate committee described himself as Iranian-born. Mainly Shi'ite Iran is a sworn enemy of Sunni-dominated Islamic State.
No group claimed responsibility for the attack and the motive was unknown.
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve was at the site in the town of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, around 30 km (20 miles) southeast of the city of Lyon.
French media said the government had ordered security to be stepped up around sensitive sites in the surrounding Rhone-Alpes region.
(Reporting by Sophie Louet, Dominique Vidalon and Leigh Thomas ; Editing by Mark John and Alison Williams )
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
1 of 15
right
French President Francois Hollande (foreground on L) arrives in a press room to give a statement at the European Council headquarters in Brussels, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Yves Herman
2 of 15
right
French President Francois Hollande gives a statement at the European Council headquarters in Brussels, June 26, 2015, following an attack at a U.S. gas company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast France, where two assailants rammed a car into the premises, and a...
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
3 of 15
right
French President Francois Hollande leaves the EU Council headquarters during a European Union leaders summit in Brussels, Belgium, June 26, 2015 following an attack at a U.S. gas company in Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, southeast France, where an explosion took place.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
4 of 15
right
A French Gendarme blocks the access road to the Saint-Quentin-Fallavier industrial area, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
5 of 15
right
French Gendarmes block the access road to the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
6 of 15
right
French Gendarmes and rescue forces stand next to a black plastic sheet (R) outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
7 of 15
right
French Gendarmes and rescue forces stand near a black plastic sheet (R) outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, outside Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
8 of 15
right
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
9 of 15
right
A French Gendarme stands guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
10 of 15
right
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
11 of 15
right
French Gendarmes stand guard next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
12 of 15
right
French crime scene investigators, Gendarmes and rescue forces are seen at work next to a black plastic sheet outside a gas company site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
13 of 15
right
French Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve addresses a news conference outside Air Products gas facory site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
14 of 15
right
A general view shows the Air Products gas facory site at the industrial area of Saint-Quentin-Fallavier, near Lyon, France, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Emmanuel Foudrot
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:22:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>At least 19 killed in gun attack on Tunisian tourism hotel: official</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/JTSNFwgVDdE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TUNIS (Reuters) - At least 19 people have been killed after at least one gunman attacked a Tunisian tourist hotel in the popular resort of Sousse, an interior ministry official said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thomson Reuters is the world's largest international multimedia news agency, providing investing news , world news , business news , technology news , headline news, small business news , news alerts, personal finance , stock market , and mutual funds information available on Reuters.com, video , mobile , and interactive television platforms. Thomson Reuters journalists are subject to an Editorial Handbook which requires fair presentation and disclosure of relevant interests.
NYSE and AMEX quotes delayed by at least 20 minutes. Nasdaq delayed by at least 15 minutes. For a complete list of exchanges and delays, please click here .
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 15:09:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey summons Israeli diplomat after journalists, NGO workers refused entry</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/jYtNqNTHhuA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkey's Foreign Ministry said on Friday it summoned the highest-ranking Israeli diplomat in Ankara to explain why a group of Turkish journalists and civil society workers were refused entry at Ben Gurion Airport.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkey summons Israeli diplomat after journalists, NGO workers refused entry
ISTANBUL
ISTANBUL Turkey's Foreign Ministry said on Friday it summoned the highest-ranking Israeli diplomat in Ankara to explain why a group of Turkish journalists and civil society workers were refused entry at Ben Gurion Airport.
The incident occurred three days after diplomats from Israel and Turkey, both U.S. allies, held talks to explore prospects of repairing their relationship after a Turkish election earlier this month.
Ties between the erstwhile allies were wrecked after Israeli commandoes killed 10 Turkish activists trying to break the blockade on Gaza in 2010. Turkey soon after recalled its ambassador and ejected Israel's.
A group of nine Turks had traveled to Israel on Thursday to attend an event marking the Islamic holy month of Ramadan in Jerusalem, the Foreign Ministry said in an e-mailed statement.
They were questioned for nine hours and, despite having the required visas, seven of them were sent back. Two journalists with the state TRT broadcaster were allowed in, it said, condemning the decision to eject the group.
"To show our reaction to the treatment of our citizens and to receive an explanation, the Israeli charge d'affaires has been summoned to the Foreign Ministry," it said. The charge d'affaires is Israel's most senior official at the embassy.
Some Israeli media said the seven Turks were suspected of ties with the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas.
"The seven people were sent back for security reasons," Israeli Foreign Ministry Spokesman Emmanuel Nahshon told Reuters, declining to elaborate.
President Tayyip Erdogan is one of Israel's most vocal critics. The June 7 election deprived his Islamist-rooted AK Party of its majority in parliament for the first time since 2002, which may pave the way for reconciliation with Israel.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:58:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>North Korea to foreigners: don't bring in subversive media, porn</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/gmh4HAOq5_E/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SEOUL (Reuters) - North Korea has warned foreigners living in Pyongyang not to share outside media on memory sticks with its citizens, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a note, cracking down on what the isolated country called "undesirable content".</Description>
        <MainBody>SEOUL | By James Pearson
SEOUL North Korea has warned foreigners living in Pyongyang not to share outside media on memory sticks with its citizens, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a note, cracking down on what the isolated country called "undesirable content".
The vast majority of North Koreans have no access to outside Internet or foreign media, but people regularly share films, music and literature on easily-concealed USB sticks that are passed from person to person.
The note, a copy of which was seen by Reuters, said foreigners in Pyongyang would not be allowed to import "all kinds of data media, including printed matter, mobile phones, and memory sticks" which contain "false propaganda" and "photos, movies, and literature regarding sexual relations".
Some foreigners entering the country had left printed materials and memory sticks containing "undesirable content" at tourist sites, or passed them to North Koreans, the note added.
"We regard these practices as a serious problem directly related to the security of the State," said the note, which was dated Thursday and addressed to diplomatic and international missions in Pyongyang.
"Accordingly concerned authorities of the DPRK are taking such measures as strict censorship over printed matters and memory media at every port of entry to the DPRK, including the airport."
DPRK is short for the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, North Korea's official title.
The note warned that although those holding diplomatic passports were exempt from direct censorship, anyone found with offending material "must bear all the blame to themselves, entailing appropriate measures here".
Embassies in Pyongyang were looking into whether the note infringed the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, a diplomatic source in Pyongyang told Reuters. The 1961 convention forms the basis of diplomatic immunity.
In recent months, North Korean security services have stepped up scrutiny of Pyongyang's foreign residents.
During a fire in early June at the popular Koryo Hotel, a source in Pyongyang told Reuters that several foreigners had been apprehended by security services for taking photos.
Later, foreigners were briefly unable to access the country's 3G mobile internet network.
In April, North Korea expelled the country director of German NGO Welthungerhilfe, without warning or saying why.
(Editing by Tony Munroe and Clarence Fernandez)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:56:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. mediator to visit Kuwait, Riyadh in search of Yemen deal</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/R8dB9yyc0SY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>GENEVA (Reuters) - A United Nations envoy will hold talks in Kuwait and Saudi Arabia in the coming days on a draft peace proposal for Yemen with the aim of reaching a "preliminary agreement" with Houthi fighters, a U.N. spokesman said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. mediator to visit Kuwait, Riyadh in search of Yemen deal
GENEVA
United Nations envoy to Yemen Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed talks to reporters upon arrival at the international airport of Sanaa, Yemen May 29, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
GENEVA A United Nations envoy will hold talks in Kuwait and Saudi Arabia in the coming days on a draft peace proposal for Yemen with the aim of reaching a "preliminary agreement" with Houthi fighters, a U.N. spokesman said on Friday.
More than 2,800 people have been killed in Yemen during three months of air strikes by a Saudi-led coalition, including Kuwait, that aims to restore President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi who is currently living in exile in the Saudi capital Riyadh.
Iranian-backed Houthi fighters control large areas of Yemen,  including the capital Sanaa.
U.N.-sponsored talks in Geneva on a ceasefire between Yemen's warring parties broke up a week ago without a deal as the coalition staged further airstrikes.
U.N. envoy Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed, who led the Geneva talks, will travel to Kuwait on Saturday and then spend a week in Riyadh before moving on to Sanaa for a further week of consultations, U.N. spokesman Ahmad Fawzi told reporters.
"He intends to spend more time in the two capitals (Riyadh and Sanaa) to discuss the draft principles paper which was developed here in Geneva - as he said, 'until we reach a preliminary agreement'," said U.N. spokesman Ahmad Fawzi.
"As you know, before leaving us here in Geneva, he said both sides had shown signs of constructive engagement regarding the possibility of reaching a humanitarian truce and that there was emerging common ground upon which to build an eventual ceasefire coupled with the withdrawal of combatants," Fawzi told a news briefing in Geneva.
The United Nations has estimated that more than 21 million people, or 80 percent of the Yemeni population, are now in need of humanitarian assistance.
The U.N. Security Council and U.N. aid chief Stephen O'Brien pressed on Thursday for more aid and commercial access to Yemen, where a near-total blockade by Saudi Arabia has slowed shipments to the Arabian Peninsula country to a trickle.
The World Health Organization (WHO) said on Friday it would provide essential medicines for treating non-communicable diseases such as heart and chronic respiratory illnesses for more than one million people in Yemen for six months.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:52:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack, at least eight wounded: newspaper</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/b0MZBtgmr24/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>DUBAI (Reuters) - A suicide bomber blew himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said on social media.</Description>
        <MainBody>Kuwaiti mosque hit by suicide attack, at least eight wounded: newspaper
DUBAI
DUBAI A suicide bomber blew himself up at a Kuwaiti Shi'ite Muslim mosque in Kuwait city during Friday prayers, wounding at least eight people, Kuwaiti newspaper al-Jarida said on social media.
The newspaper said the attack targeted Imam al-Sadeq Mosque in the Sawaber district.
"Eight casualties have been taken to the Emiri hospital, two in critical condition," al-Jarida said on its Twitter feed, without giving a source.
Arab television stations al-Arabiya and Al Jazeera earlier reported that an explosion hit the mosque and caused several casualties.
(Reporting by Hadeel al-Sayegh and Omar Fahmy, writing by Sami Aboudi; Editing by John Stonestreet)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:46:55 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/n-f-9oecgo4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BANGKOK (Reuters) - Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thai police arrest 14 students in anti-junta protest
BANGKOK
BANGKOK Police in Thailand on Friday arrested 14 students who had been protesting against the ruling junta, in defiance of a ban on public gatherings.
Thailand's military overthrew the previous democratic government last year after months of political unrest. The junta has since stifled dissent, barring political gatherings and debate.
The students, part of a coalition of university groups from around Thailand, held street demonstrations for three days in Bangkok this week to protest against the junta, known as the National Council for Peace and Order.
"We've caught them all, according to the arrest warrants, and the next step is to tell them what they are accused of," Wutthichai Suponthawit, deputy superintendent of the capital's Samran Rat police station, told Reuters.
"We will now jail them."
Thailand's army chief accused some politicians of backing the student groups, but did not identify them.
"They are the group that is not satisfied with the administration of this government," General Udomdej Sitabutr told reporters earlier on Friday.
Around 80 students held a 10-hour protest outside a Bangkok police station on Wednesday, brandishing signs that read "Peace" and "We want power for the people" or banners reading "No coup".
Last month, 40 student activists were arrested after holding peaceful rallies on the first anniversary of the May 22 coup.
All were released but at least 11 were charged with violating the junta's ban on political activity and face trial in military court, with jail terms of a year, if found guilty.
The 2014 coup ousted the government of Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, Thailand's first female prime minister and a scion of the Shinawatra political family.
Thailand has been bitterly divided for a decade between supporters of Yingluck and her brother, former Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, who was himself ousted by the army in 2006, and the traditional establishment in the capital and the south.
(Reporting by Panarat Thepgumpanat and Aukkarapon Niyomat; Writing by Amy Sawitta Lefevre; Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:41:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Israeli forces shoot and kill Palestinian gunman in West Bank: army</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/GIxAIk0JEm4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Israeli forces shoot and kill Palestinian gunman in West Bank: army
JERUSALEM
JERUSALEM Israeli soldiers shot and killed a Palestinian gunman in the occupied West Bank on Friday after he opened fire on them at a checkpoint, the Israeli military said.
It was the third such violent incident in eight days.
On Sunday a Palestinian stabbed and wounded an Israeli paramilitary policeman outside the walled Old City of Jerusalem. The policeman shot back and wounded him. Last Friday a suspected Palestinian gunman shot at two Israeli hikers near a Jewish settlement in the West Bank and killed one. The assailant escaped.
There were no Israeli casualties in the latest incident.
Palestinians seek a state in East Jerusalem, the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, territories Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war. The last round of peace talks between the sides broke down in April 2014.
Palestinian militants this month fired rockets into Israel from Gaza, drawing Israeli return fire. That frontier has been largely quiet since the Gaza war last year in which more than 2,100 Palestinians and 73 on the Israeli side were killed.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:23:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>After China's Glastonbury complaint, UK source says it is Dalai Lama's call</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/b6QTrqJaB9c/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - After China complained about a Glastonbury Festival invite for the exiled Tibetan spiritual leader, a British government source said on Friday his appearance was a decision for festival-goers and for the Dalai Lama.</Description>
        <MainBody>After China's Glastonbury complaint, UK source says it is Dalai Lama's call
BRUSSELS
BRUSSELS After China complained about a Glastonbury Festival invite for the exiled Tibetan spiritual leader, a British government source said on Friday his appearance was a decision for festival-goers and for the Dalai Lama.
"It's a decision for the festival-goers and the Dalai Lama," the source said, when asked about China's caution that inviting him to visit one of Europe's largest music festivals was tantamount to giving him a platform to engage in anti-China activities.
The office of the Dalai Lama said on Thursday he would speak at Glastonbury during a three-day trip to Britain. He is not due to meet any government officials.
Festival organizers declined to comment on Friday or even confirm that the Dalai Lama would be appearing.
Beijing denounces him as a dangerous separatist who wants an independent Tibet. He denies espousing violence and says he only wants genuine autonomy for his Himalayan homeland.
In 2012, Prime Minister David Cameron had to put a trip to China on hold after Beijing took offense at him holding a meeting with the Dalai Lama.
The Dalai Lama is also going to Britain again in September, just ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's trip to the country in October.
Xi's state visit is the first to Britain in a decade by a Chinese head of state.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:15:56 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Lebanese army says kills militants trying to infiltrate border town</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/66q7cWeO2FQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Lebanese soldiers killed two gunmen during a clash with militants who were trying to infiltrate the town of Arsal from the nearby border zone with Syria, the army said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Lebanese army says kills militants trying to infiltrate border town
BEIRUT
BEIRUT Lebanese soldiers killed two gunmen during a clash with militants who were trying to infiltrate the town of Arsal from the nearby border zone with Syria, the army said on Friday.
A security source said the militants were members of the Nusra Front, al Qaeda's wing in the Syrian war.
The militants were trying to reach Arsal when the army targeted them, it said in a statement. One of the dead was identified as a Syrian. The other was unidentified.
The Nusra Front and the Islamic State jihadist group staged an incursion into Arsal last August that triggered several days of deadly battles with the Lebanese security forces.
The Lebanese group Hezbollah, which is fighting alongside President Bashar al-Assad in the Syrian war, is mounting a joint operation with the Syrian army aimed at driving both Nusra and Islamic State from the border zone.
(Writing by Tom Perry ; Editing by Ruth Pitchford)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:08:59 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Islamic State commits major massacre in Syria's Kobani: monitor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/znO_A7mNq2w/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Islamic State has committed its second-biggest civilian massacre in Syria with an attack on the town of Kobani and a nearby village, killing at least 146 civilians so far, a conflict monitor said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>BEIRUT | By Sylvia Westall
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
1 of 5
right
Smoke rises in the Syrian town of Kobani as it is seen from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 25, 2015.
Reuters/Ali Sahin
2 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
3 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani who need medical help are taken to an ambulance on the Turkish-Syrian border in Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
4 of 5
right
Syrian Kurds from Kobani wait behind the border fences to cross into Turkey as they are pictured from the Turkish border town of Suruc in Sanliurfa province, Turkey, June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Murad Sezer
5 of 5
right
BEIRUT Islamic State has committed its second-biggest civilian massacre in Syria with an attack on the town of Kobani and a nearby village, killing at least 146 civilians so far, a conflict monitor said on Friday.
Fighting between the Kurdish YPG militia and Islamic State fighters who infiltrated the town at the Turkish border on Thursday continued into a second day, said Rami Abdulrahman, head of the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights.
A separate Islamic State attack on government-held areas of the northeastern city of Hasaka was reported to have forced 60,000 people to flee their homes, the United Nations said, warning that up to 200,000 people may eventually try to flee.
The twin attacks launched in the early hours of Thursday marked an Islamic State attempt to go back on the offensive after Kurdish-led forces, supported by U.S.-led air strikes, advanced to within 50 km (30 miles) of Raqqa city, the de facto capital of its self-declared "caliphate".
In both cases, Islamic State has picked targets where it is complicated for the U.S.-led alliance to provide air support. In Kobani, also known as Ayn al-Arab, aerial bombardment risks civilian casualties in residential areas targeted in the attack.
The U.S.-led alliance has meanwhile avoided bombing Islamic State targets in areas controlled by President Bashar al-Assad, such as government-held Hasaka - one of his last footholds in the northeast.
The United States and its European and Arab allies have been carrying out air strikes on Islamic State since last year in an effort to roll back the group that has seized wide areas of Syria and Iraq. Washington has ruled out cooperation with Assad.
The attack on the predominantly Kurdish town of Kobani and the nearby village of Brakh Bootan marked the biggest single massacre of civilians by Islamic State since it killed hundreds of members of the Sunni Sheitaat tribe in eastern Syria last year, the Observatory's Abdulrahman said.
The assault included at least three suicide car bombs. The dead included the elderly, women and children, Abdulrahman said.
The Islamic State fighters were reported to number in the low dozens and entered the town in five cars disguised as members of the YPG and Syrian rebel groups.
Fighting was ongoing inside the town, Abdulrahman said.
Kobani was the site of one of the biggest battles against Islamic State in 2014. The Kurdish forces eventually drove the militants out of the town in January with the help of U.S. air strikes and Iraqi Kurdish fighters after months of fighting.
Islamic State advanced rapidly last month, seizing cities in Syria and Iraq. But recent Kurdish advances in Syria shifted the momentum once more. Islamic State fighters have often adopted a tactic of attacking elsewhere when they lose ground.
The group wrested control of at least one district of Hasaka city in its raid there on Thursday. The city is divided into zones run separately by the Syrian government and the Kurdish administration that controls the YPG.
The U.N. Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs said an estimated 50,000 people had been displaced within Hasaka city while 10,000 had left northwards toward Amuda town, close to the Turkish border.
Speaking to Syrian state TV, the governor of Hasaka said the city was "safe and secure". He urged people to return home.
But the Observatory said fighting continued in the city. Government forces were carrying out air strikes targeting areas south of Hasaka controlled by Islamic State, it added.
Assad has since late March lost additional areas of northwestern, southern and central Syria to a patchwork of armed groups, including Islamic State, other jihadists, and rebels who profess a more secular vision for Syria.
The government has meanwhile focused on shoring up control over the main population centers of the west, including Damascus, with crucial military support from the Iranian-backed Lebanese group, Hezbollah.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:06:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Vatican signs first treaty with 'State of Palestine', backs two-state solution</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/F1Is4kj5nZE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VATICAN CITY (Reuters) - The Vatican signed its first treaty with the "State of Palestine" on Friday, calling for "courageous decisions" to end the Israeli-Palestinian conflict with a two-state solution.</Description>
        <MainBody>VATICAN CITY | By Philip Pullella
VATICAN CITY The Vatican signed its first treaty with the "State of Palestine" on Friday, calling for "courageous decisions" to end the Israeli-Palestinian conflict with a two-state solution.
The treaty concerned the Catholic Church's activities in areas controlled by the Palestinian Authority.
The Israeli foreign ministry said it regretted the move, calling the signing of a treaty, which implies there is an official Palestinian state, "a hasty step (that) damages the prospects for advancing a peace agreement".
But Archbishop Paul Gallagher, the Vatican's foreign minister, said he hoped the agreement could be a "stimulus to bringing a definitive end to the long-standing Israeli-Palestinian conflict, which continues to cause suffering for both Parties".
He said he hoped that a peace process directly negotiated between Israelis and Palestinians could resume and lead to a two-state solution.
"This certainly requires courageous decisions, but it will also offer a major contribution to peace and stability in the region," he said..
The U.N. General Assembly adopted a resolution in 2012 recognizing Palestine as an observer non-member state. This was welcomed at the time by the Vatican, which has the same observer non-member status at the United Nations.
Since then the Vatican has de facto recognized a "State of Palestine" and Pope Francis referred to it by that name when he visited the Holy Land last year.
(Additional reporting by Maayan Lubell in Jerusalem Editing by Jeremy Gaunt)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:05:21 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.N. urges EU states to make 'concrete commitments' on refugees</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/l9I9bTn8iBg/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday welcomed the European Union's decisions on the migrant crisis but said much more needs to be done, including "concrete commitments" by member states.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.N. urges EU states to make 'concrete commitments' on refugees
GENEVA
A group of migrants gather near a line of lorries waiting on the motorway which leads to the Channel Tunnel terminal in Calais, northern France, June 24, 2015. Traffic was suspended on Tuesday after striking ferry workers accessed the terminal on the French side and set fire...
Reuters/Christian Hartmann
GENEVA The United Nations refugee agency on Friday welcomed the European Union's decisions on the migrant crisis but said much more needs to be done, including "concrete commitments" by member states.
European leaders argued into the early hours of Friday over how to handle the crisis in the Mediterranean, agreeing a plan to share out the care of desperate people fleeing war and poverty in North Africa and the Middle East.
They eventually agreed a voluntary scheme aimed at taking in 60,000 people and granted an exclusion for Hungary, which had earlier described the plan as absurd, and Bulgaria, one of the EU's poorest countries.
"This clearly is an important step along the way to finding answers to this crisis but clearly much more will have to be done, including addressing the root causes," Adrian Edwards of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) told a news briefing.
With agreement to relocate 40,000 asylum seekers now in Italy and Greece who are in need of international protection, "the participation of all member states will be key to success", he said.
"With regard to the proposal for EU-wide resettlement of 20,000 refugees, UNHCR urges member states to make concrete commitments toward this goal," Edwards said. "There does need to be a joined up response by Europe focused on the asylum priorities."
The plan was meant as an emergency response to the tragedy of 2,000 migrants dying in the Mediterranean this year but has been overshadowed by divisions, particularly in Eastern Europe.
In all, 153,000 migrants have entered Europe by land, air and sea this year, a jump of 149 percent compared to the same period last year, Joel Millman of the International Organization for Migration (IOM) said. "We expect this to be the start of a very busy summer."
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 14:03:40 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkey's AKP names defense minister as speaker candidate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Y1BlegFxmWg/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ANKARA (Reuters) - Turkey's governing AK Party nominated Defense Minister Ismet Yilmaz for parliamentary speaker on Friday, the first step in a closely watched contest likely to give insight into how talks to form a government are progressing.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkey's AKP names defense minister as speaker candidate
ANKARA | By Tulay Karadeniz
ANKARA Turkey's governing AK Party nominated Defense Minister Ismet Yilmaz for parliamentary speaker on Friday, the first step in a closely watched contest likely to give insight into how talks to form a government are progressing.
After losing its majority in parliament in a June 7 election, the Islamist-rooted AK Party founded by President Tayyip Erdogan must now find a junior partner to form a coalition government.
There has been some speculation of a partnership with long-time rival Republican People's Party (CHP), the secular, main opposition seen as representing the business elite. Those hopes have helped bolster the lira currency this week.
Some commentators have even said the AKP might ultimately be willing to back CHP candidate Deniz Baykal as speaker, in what could be a sign of the rival parties moving toward a grand coalition.
However, Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu on Friday named Yilmaz, a veteran politician and an engineer and lawyer by profession, as the AKP's candidate, saying that any coalition talks would start later.
"The subject of the parliament speaker is not a part of the coalition talks," he told reporters after announcing Yilmaz's candidacy.
He said coalition talks would only begin after Erdogan had mandated him to form a government, after the speaker was elected.
If Davutoglu fails to form a government, Erdogan could then ask the CHP to try to establish a working government.
The first two rounds of voting on the post of speaker are scheduled to be held in parliament on Tuesday, with candidates requiring the support of at least 367 MPs in the 550-seat assembly in those two votes.
In a third round of voting on Wednesday a minimum of 276 votes is needed. In the fourth and final round the candidate with the most votes will be elected speaker.
Aside from the AKP's Yilmaz and Baykal, the two other candidates are Dengir Mir Mehmet Firat for the pro-Kurdish HDP and former presidential candidate Ekmeleddin Ihsanoglu for the nationalist MHP.
AKP officials have privately said Erdogan may view a snap election as the best hope for the AKP to win back a majority and help him realize his vision for constitutional change to give him greater power.
However, a survey this week by pollsters Metropoll indicated Turks are unlikely to change their vote in any snap election soon, showing support for AKP stood at 41.6 percent, compared to the 40.7 percent it received at the election.
Media reports on Friday said another Metropoll survey showed Erdogan's approval rating had dipped to 37.5 percent in June, little more than half the 71.1 percent level at which it stood at the end of 2011 and down from 47.4 percent before he took over as president last August.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:45:13 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>U.S. criticizes Myanmar military veto after law change fails</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/7KNIXTNYUpU/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>YANGON (Reuters) - The United States said on Friday that an effective legislative veto held by Myanmar's military was undemocratic and reiterated calls for changes to the constitution, a day after lawmakers from the armed forces bloc rejected any significant amendments to the charter.</Description>
        <MainBody>U.S. criticizes Myanmar military veto after law change fails
YANGON | By Timothy Mclaughlin and Hnin Yadana Zaw
YANGON The United States said on Friday that an effective legislative veto held by Myanmar's military was undemocratic and reiterated calls for changes to the constitution, a day after lawmakers from the armed forces bloc rejected any significant amendments to the charter.
Washington has re-engaged with Myanmar since a quasi-civilian government took power in 2011, ending 49 years of military rule, with President Barack Obama investing substantial personal effort and prestige in promoting democratic reform.
The United States has pushed for the country's military to be reined in, submitting to civilian control and stepping back from the political arena.
But Thursday's parliamentary vote, in which a proposed amendment to the veto provision failed to gain the necessary support, showed the military has no immediate plans to give up its powerful influence over public affairs.
"There are provisions in Burma's constitution, such as the lack of civilian control of the military and the military's veto power over constitutional amendments, that contradict fundamental democratic principles," a spokesman from the U.S. Embassy in Yangon said.
"It will be important to the ultimate success of Burma's democratic transformation that the constitution be amended to make it appropriate for a democratic nation."
In order for proposed changes to the military-drafted constitution to be accepted, more than 75 percent of lawmakers must support the amendment. With 25 percent of Myanmar's parliament seatsreserved for unelected military MPs, the bloc has an effective veto power.
A proposed amendment voted would have seen the threshold of support lowered to 70 percent, but failed, as expected, to gain enough support with lawmakers.
Military MPs said that while they did not opposed changing the constitution in the future, the time was not right and doing so now might risk instability.
"We are making the country's situation stable by putting 25 percent military MPs in the parliament," said Brigadier General Tin San Hlaing, a military MP.
"If these articles really need to be amended, the military representatives would not hesitate to do so."
The country's military has not given any indication when it might consider stepping back from its powerful political position.
Myanmar's seven-point road map for a "disciplined democracy" was first laid out more than a decade ago and former strongman Than Shwe stepped aside in 2011, but military officials have shown little will to move away from politics.
In addition to the military's seats in parliament, the commander-in-chief appoints the ministers of defense, border affairs and home affairs.
Five of the 11 members of the country's high-level National Defense and Security Council are also active military members.
A proposed change to a separate section of the constitution, which includes a provision that bars opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi from becoming president because her children are foreign citizens, also failed to pass.
The proposed change however, would not have gone far enough in helping secure Suu Kyi's presidential hopes, as it would only have allowed for individuals with children married to foreign citizens to hold the president's office, leaving her out.
Both amendments, if accepted, would have then needed the support of a national referendum.
Suu Kyi said after the vote that the military appeared opposed to even the slightest changes to its position.
"If we are going to amend the constitution, we have to make big moves. Today, we can see clearly that they don't even want to make small changes," she said.
(Editing by Alex Richardson )
Opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi speaks during a news conference after a vote for changes to the section of the constitution that bars her from becoming president in Naypyitaw, Myanmar June 25, 2015.
Reuters/Hnin Yadana Zaw
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:31:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>South Africa's mine massacre town sees little change three years on</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/hH6yo-kG6n4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MARIKANA, South Africa (Reuters) - Almost three years after South African police shot 34 striking miners dead outside platinum producer Lonmin's Marikana mine, little has changed in this hardscrabble town that has become a symbol of post-apartheid hardship and inequities.</Description>
        <MainBody>South Africa's mine massacre town sees little change three years on
MARIKANA, South Africa | By Zandi Shabalala
Cows graze in front of the koppie, where police killed 34 miners in 2012 in the ''Marikana massacre'', near the Lonmin mine in Rustenburg, northwest of Johannesberg June 26, 2015.
Reuters/Siphiwe Sibeko
MARIKANA, South Africa Almost three years after South African police shot 34 striking miners dead outside platinum producer Lonmin's Marikana mine, little has changed in this hardscrabble town that has become a symbol of post-apartheid hardship and inequities.
Cows and pigs root through litter-strewn dirt roads that snake past corrugated iron shacks - a picture of grinding poverty atop one of the world's wealthiest mineral deposits.
A long-awaited probe into the slayings, unveiled on Thursday by President Jacob Zuma, found Lonmin "did not respond appropriately" to the escalating violence during a wildcat strike in August of 2012.
Though the report slammed Lonmin for failing to comply with its social and housing obligations, few in Marikana felt it would make much difference.
Labor tensions in South Africa's mines continue, stemming in part from squalid living conditions that have persisted two decades after the end of apartheid.
"I understand that the report is out but it's not making me very happy. Nothing has changed here," said Samkelo Mkhize, 33, a former Lonmin miner.
"People were killed that day, and the government admits that they did something wrong but they don't act (as if) they will do something to change it," he said.
The commission, chaired by retired judge Ian Farlam, found "Lonmin's failure to comply with the housing obligations under the Social and Labor Plans should be drawn to the attention of the Department of Mineral Resources."
It further said the department "should take steps to enforce the performance of these obligations by Lonmin."
Mining companies in South Africa are required to meet a number of social requirements aimed at community and employee upliftment. But Lonmin may be hard pressed to meet such demands in the face of soaring costs and falling prices.
Lonmin's share price was down 3.5 percent on Friday to 3-1/2 month lows. Platinum's spot price is below $1,100 an ounce, some 25 percent lower than August 16, 2012, when police opened fire on the wildcat strikers.
Lonmin said in a statement that it has focused on "living conditions and employee indebtedness, two burning issues that we believe will make a profound impact on the wellbeing of our employees. Much work has been done in this regard."
But families of Lonmin employees in the grim shantytown the edge of Marikana, 120 kms (70 miles) northwest of Johannesburg, say much more needs to be done.
"Nothing has changed, we have no roads. If it was raining you could not even drive in here. This is a mine but we are living in shacks," Bongiwe Gumede, 30, a mother of three who said her husband was a Lonmin miner.
The commission also blamed police and unions for the vortex of violence that saw 10 people killed, including police and security guards hacked to death, before miners were slain in a hail of bullets.
It found allegations that Deputy President Cyril Ramaphosa had used his influence to trigger the police action were "groundless". Ramaphosa, seen as the potential successor to Zuma, was a non-executive director at Lonmin during the violence, which was rooted in a turf war between rival unions.
(Writing by Ed Stoddard ; Editing by Sophie Walker)
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 13:15:17 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China military to investigate who owns its land</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/xp62ZcNbPdY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - China's military has launched a three-year project to try to work out who owns the land it uses after finding that a quarter of it lacked ownership documents, which has led to disputes with civilians, the Defense Ministry said on Friday.</Description>
        <MainBody>China military to investigate who owns its land
BEIJING
BEIJING China's military has launched a three-year project to try to work out who owns the land it uses after finding that a quarter of it lacked ownership documents, which has led to disputes with civilians, the Defense Ministry said on Friday.
China's armed forces, the world's largest, have become a focus of President Xi Jinping's campaign to root out deeply-ingrained graft including bribery, which often takes the form of lavish gifts to officials or extravagant spending of government funds.
The military has warned repeatedly that buildings on its bases must be simple, cheap and unostentatious.
"Just like a citizen must have an identity card and a household registration documents, military land also needs its own 'proof of identity'," the ministry quoted an unidentified officer in charge of base and barracks building as saying.
With a quarter of land the military uses lacking such documentation, this has led to ownership disputes, the ministry added.
"This not only involves the legal use of land resources, but it also affects the harmonious relationship between the military and the government and the military and the people," it said.
These issues are "extremely sensitive", the ministry added.
The anti-graft drive in the military comes as Xi steps up efforts to modernize forces that are projecting power across the disputed waters of the East and South China Seas, though China has not fought a war in decades.
China intensified its crackdown on corruption in the military in the late 1990s, banning the People's Liberation Army from engaging in business. But the military has been involved in commercial dealings in recent years due to a lack of checks and balances, military analysts have said.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:29:25 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Bulgarian church joins calls for cancellation of Sofia gay march</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/rQq9mccyQ1I/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SOFIA (Reuters) - The Bulgarian Orthodox Church joined anti-gay activists in calling for the cancellation of a gay march in the capital Sofia planned for Saturday, adding to tensions over an event which has faced threats from protesters.</Description>
        <MainBody>Bulgarian church joins calls for cancellation of Sofia gay march
SOFIA
SOFIA The Bulgarian Orthodox Church joined anti-gay activists in calling for the cancellation of a gay march in the capital Sofia planned for Saturday, adding to tensions over an event which has faced threats from protesters.
"Our irrevocable belief is that homosexuality is unnatural lust, which undoubtedly damages the individual, the family and society and causes detrimental effects on physical, mental and spiritual state of people," the church said in a statement.
Thousands of people in the Balkan country, including politicians, editors and publishers of leading media, sociologists, actors and sportsmen, wrote a letter to Sofia mayor Yordanka Fandakova, urging her to cancel the event.
Homosexuality remains a sensitive issue across the Balkans and the annual gay march in Bulgaria has a history of violence with clashes between homosexuals and conservatives.
Ten years ago Bulgarian officials banned the country's first planned gay parade and about 60 far-right extremists were arrested for throwing a petrol bomb and trying to break up the march in 2008.
A homophobic attack was held against a gay film fest in the southern city of Plovdiv in 2013 while last year's Sofia march was blocked by Bulgarian nationalists.
"The Church strongly condemns any propaganda of homosexuality and oppose attempts to impose sinful acts as a norm, as a source of pride and an example to follow," the church said.
It said that such public gatherings encourage immoral behavior and destroy Orthodox Christian values.
In recent years Western ambassadors have supported the march. Last year several Sofia-based embassies issued a statement of support for Sofia pride, encouraging people and institutions in Bulgaria to stand up for and support open-mindedness and tolerance towards LGBTI people.
Some 80 percent of Bulgarians say they are Orthodox Christians - the mainstream religion also in Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, Greece, Romania and Serbia, but only few see churchgoing as important to their lives.
Trust in the Orthodox Church was shaken after a history commission showed a few years ago that many bishops collaborated with the former communist era secret police.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Fri Jun 26 12:16:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China moves controversial oil rig back towards Vietnam coast</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Syx685i_e5Y/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIJING (Reuters) - China has moved an oil rig at the center of last year's violent dispute with Vietnam closer to Vietnam's coast in the disputed South China Sea, just weeks ahead of the first visit by a chief of Vietnam's Communist Party to Washington.</Description>
        <MainBody>China moves controversial oil rig back towards Vietnam coast
BEIJING
BEIJING China has moved an oil rig at the center of last year's violent dispute with Vietnam closer to Vietnam's coast in the disputed South China Sea, just weeks ahead of the first visit by a chief of Vietnam's Communist Party to Washington.
The move, announced by China's maritime safety authorities, comes soon after the country indicated it was close to setting up new outposts in the maritime heart of Southeast Asia, as it nears completion of land reclamation in the South China Sea.
China claims most of the potentially energy-rich South China Sea, through which $5 trillion in ship-borne trade passes every year. The Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan also have overlapping claims.
China's deployment of the rig last year in what Vietnam called its exclusive economic zone and on its continental shelf, about 120 nautical miles off its coast, led to the worst breakdown in relations since a brief border war in 1979.
Vietnam's people remain embittered over a perceived history of Chinese bullying and territorial claims in the South China Sea, although China said at the time the rig was operating completely within its waters.
The rig now appears to be in an area where the exclusive economic zones (EEZ) of Vietnam and China overlap, but further away than last year, said Le Hong Hiep, a visiting fellow at Singapore's Institute of South East Asian Studies.
In an online statement posted on Thursday, China's Maritime Safety Administration said the 'Haiyang Shiyou 981' rig would carry out "ocean drilling operations" 75 nautical miles south of the resort city of Sanya on southern Hainan island.
( here )
Experts estimate the drilling site is about 104 miles (167 km) east of the Vietnam coast. The $1-billion rig will remain there from June 25 until August 20, the statement said, telling  ships to stay 2,000 m (6,562 ft) away for safety reasons.
Vietnam's maritime authorities were monitoring the rig's placement, the website of the country's state-controlled Tuoi Tre newspaper on Friday quoted unidentified sources as saying.
The rig movement comes weeks before Vietnam's top leader, Nguyen Phu Trong, is expected to visit the United States, in the first such trip by a general secretary of the nation's Communist Party.
His mission is expected to further boost warming strategic ties between Washington and Hanoi - a relationship eyed warily in Beijing.
It also comes amid rising concerns at China's rapid creation of artificial islands on South China Sea reefs - construction criticized by the U.S. and protested by Vietnam.
However, Le Hong Hiep, the Singapore-based analyst, said he felt Hanoi would not protest as strongly as it did last year if China said the rig was placed within an EEZ claimed from Hainan Island rather than one from the hotly disputed Paracel Islands, as it did last year.
Vietnam and China agreed on an equal split of the maritime boundary of the Gulf of Tonkin in 2000 but have yet to agree on demarcating waters further south, near the rig's current site.
Earlier this year, the rig was drilling in the Andaman Sea off the coast of Myanmar, tackling the deepest exploration well it has so far undertaken, its owner, state energy group China National Offshore Oil Corporation (CNOOC), said in an earlier statement.
CNOOC could not immediately be reached for comment on Friday.
(Reporting by Ben Blanchard and Adam Rose in Beijing; Greg Torode in Hong Kong; Editing by James Pomfret and Clarence Fernandez)
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 16:41:20 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/shp9xvRkjbQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TAIPEI (Reuters) - The number of party revelers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a colored powder thrown on those attending the party.</Description>
        <MainBody>Taiwan probes water park fire as tally of injured put at 498
TAIPEI | By J.R. Wu and Pichi Chuang
TAIPEI The number of party revelers injured in a fire at a Taiwan water park was put at 498 on Sunday as authorities began investigating the cause, suspected to be a sudden explosion of a colored powder thrown on those attending the party.
Six foreigners and seven visitors from Hong Kong, mainland China and Macau were among those injured after about 1,000 people dancing at Saturday's event were sprayed with the powder, as a special feature of a festival also held in previous years.
The figure released late Sunday by local authorities was lower than an earlier estimate of 519 injured due to patients being transferred between hospitals and being double-counted, a government official said.
The blaze, which broke out at around 8.30 p.m. at the Formosa Fun Coast water park on the outskirts of the capital, Taipei, is suspected to have been caused by an explosion of the colored powder, local government official Lin Chieh-yu told Reuters.
"It remains under investigation as to what made the powder explode," he said.
Authorities have banned the use of the powder until the investigation is completed and its safety can be assured.
"The next few days will be a critical time for the injured," Taiwan Premier Mao Chi-kuo told reporters. All of the 498 injured were still being treated in 43 hospitals across the island, according to the latest figures provided by the New Taipei City government.
In the immediate aftermath of the explosion, rescuers treated hundreds of people, most of them aged between 20 and 30, who wore wet swimsuits and lay on inflatable plastic doughnuts.
A video posted online by Apple Daily showed dancers in front of the stage engulfed in clouds of colored powder a moment before a fireball erupted, followed by pockets of flame, triggering panic and screams.
"There was blood and people were on fire," one injured man  said.
No death has yet been reported, but victims suffered burns on limbs and torsos, with some passing out from the pain while others had burned clothes stuck to their skin, media reports and pictures showed.
"Her whole life is ruined," sobbed the father of Chu Li, an 18-year-old girl with burns on 80 percent of her body, during a visit by President Ma Ying-jeou to victims in a Taipei hospital.
Soldiers, army vehicles and medical services joined the rescue effort, while hospitals in four municipal precincts, along with Taipei, are treating sufferers.
The amusement park has been closed temporarily, it said on its website on Sunday.
Taipei has sweltered in temperatures exceeding 30 degrees Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in recent weeks.
(Additional reporting by Faith Hung; Editing by Clarence Fernandez and Digby Lidstone)
A person helps an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wang Wei
1 of 4
right
People carry an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Chen Bo
2 of 4
right
Injured victims from an accidental explosion during a music concert lie on the ground at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wang Wei
3 of 4
right
People carry an injured victim from an accidental explosion during a music concert at the Formosa Water Park in New Taipei City, Taiwan, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Wu Chia
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:20:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/W3YzksZcxZM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out
BRUSSELS | By Paul Taylor and Renee Maltezou
BRUSSELS Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorize negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labor reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the euro zone."
He did not name names but may have been referring to German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his scepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrival for a preparatory meeting of finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule out other forms of restructuring.
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian Finance Minister Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
CONCESSIONS UNCLEAR
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 percent 'No' vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek government has an interest in coming up with serious and credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply skeptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 percent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and delay defense spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines". It is also resisting raising VAT on restaurants to 23 percent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the center-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favor a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
(Additional reporting by Costas Pitas , Angeliki Koutantou and George Georgiopoulos in Athens, Julia Fioretti and Alastair Macdonald in Brussels, Paul Carrel in Berlin John O'Donnell in Frankfurt and Mark John in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor; editing by John Stonestreet and Giles Elgood )
Outgoing Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis (R) shows newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos his chair at the Finance Ministry before a handover ceremony in Athens, Greece July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Yannis Behrakis
1 of 7
right
Newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos looks on during his swearing in ceremony as Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras (L) stands next to him at the Presidential Palace in Athens, Greece July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
2 of 7
right
Newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos (R) and outgoing Yannis Varoufakis address a news conference at the Finance Ministry during a handover ceremony in Athens, Greece July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Yannis Behrakis
3 of 7
right
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis leaves after making a statement in Athens, Greece July 5, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
4 of 7
right
French President Francois Hollande and German Chancellor Angela Merkel arrive at a joint statement at the Elysee Palace in Paris, France, July 6, 2015 following the Greek people's resounding 'No' to a European cash-for-reform deal in a referendum in Greece.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:19:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syrian Kurds retake northern villages from Islamic State: monitor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/O1t0eZB4KQE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Syrian Kurdish fighters have recaptured more than 10 villages seized by Islamic State north of its de facto capital of Raqqa city, aided by U.S.-led coalition air strikes, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian Kurds retake northern villages from Islamic State: monitor
BEIRUT
BEIRUT Syrian Kurdish fighters have recaptured more than 10 villages seized by Islamic State north of its de facto capital of Raqqa city, aided by U.S.-led coalition air strikes, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported on Tuesday.
Intensified air strikes across northern Syria and clashes on the ground have killed at least 78 Islamic State fighters since Sunday night, the Britain-based Observatory said.
The strikes are some of the most sustained since they began in September, according to U.S. officials who say they are aimed at curbing the militants' ability to operate out of Raqqa and to prevent it from fighting back against Kurdish advances.
But, on Tuesday, the ultra-hardline group was still in control of Ain Issa, the Observatory said. The town, 50 km (30 miles) north of Raqqa city, was seized by Islamic State fighters from the Kurdish YPG militia in an attack on Monday.
That attack on YPG-held areas followed an intensification of air strikes on Raqqa city over the weekend, which U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter said on Monday were aimed at disrupting the militants' ability to respond to YPG advances north of Raqqa.
The YPG, a militia operating mostly in predominantly Kurdish areas of northern Syria towards the Turkish border, has emerged as the only significant partner in Syria for U.S.-led alliance fighting to tackle Islamic State both there and in Iraq.
The Observatory, a British-based organization reporting on Syria's four-year-old civil war, said the coalition had played an "effective role" in helping YPG forces recover 11 villages northeast of Ain Issa.
The YPG, backed by small Syrian rebel groups, has made significant gains against Islamic State in Raqqa province in recent weeks, seizing Tel Abyad at the Turkish border on June 15 before advancing south to Ain Issa.
The YPG captured Ain Issa on June 23.
While the YPG has shown itself to be a potent force in the fight against Islamic State, its effectiveness is seen to diminish beyond the predominantly Kurdish areas it was set up to defend in northern and northeastern Syria.
The United States aims to train and equip Syrian rebel fighters it deems politically moderate in order to fight Islamic State in Syria. But the Pentagon said on June 18 the effort was moving more slowly than expected.
U.S. President Barack Obama said on Monday the United States would do more to train and equip "the moderate opposition".
(Writing by Tom Perry and Sylvia Westall ; Editing by Louise Ireland )
A general view is seen of Ain Issa in the suburb of Raqqa, eastern Syria September 13, 2013.
Reuters/Nour Fourat
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:18:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Six powers and Iran to continue nuclear talks past deadline: EU</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/vHQ0Tdkfgks/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a U.N. arms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Head of the Iranian Atomic Energy Organization Ali Akbar Salehi (2nd R) walks near the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria in Vienna, Austria July 4, 2015.
Reuters/Carlos Barria
1 of 2
right
Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif stands on the balcony of Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria, July 2, 2015.
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
2 of 2
right
VIENNA Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a U.N. arms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said outside the hotel where the talks between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States are taking place.
The spokeswoman for the U.S. delegation, Marie Harf, said the terms of an interim deal between Iran and the six would be extended through Friday to give negotiators a few more days to finish their work.
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time," Harf said. "That is why we are continuing to negotiate."
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said there was "every reason" to believe a deal would be done within "a few days", and that there was an "understanding" that most of the current sanctions against Iran would be lifted.
"There is only one big problem in terms of sanctions - it is the problem of a weapons embargo," he told journalists, according to the news agency Interfax.
He said it was important to reach agreement on this as soon as possible, telling journalists that "ending the bans on supplies to Iran of the weapons required to fight terrorism is a very, very relevant objective".
It is the fourth time the parties have extended the terms of the interim deal, which was struck in November 2013 and provided Iran with limited sanctions relief in exchange for a halt to the production of uranium enriched to a purity level of 20 percent.
EXTENSION EXTENDED
The comprehensive deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from economic sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalize the agreement," Mogherini said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve.
Among these, officials said, are Iranian demands for a U.N. arms embargo and ballistic missiles sanctions to be lifted, the timing of U.S. and EU sanctions relief, and disagreements over future Iranian nuclear research and development.
"We have entered the most difficult, but also the most real, part of the negotiations," Mogherini added.
"We knew it would be difficult, challenging and sometimes hard and some things get tense and others we make progress."
She said foreign ministers now in Vienna might come and go.
"Dont get too excited if you see ministers leaving. They might come back. They will come back. And it doesnt mean that we are stopping the work we are doing inside. On the contrary, on the contrary."
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius confirmed that he would leave, and return to Vienna on Wednesday night.
The United States and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear program as a cover to develop a nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its program is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the United States and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal would also reduce the chances of a U.S. military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington refuses to rule out, and of a wider regional war.
(Reporting by John Irish, Louis Charbonneau , Arshad Mohammed and Parisa Hafezi ; Writing by Arshad Mohammed)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:16:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brazil's Rousseff tells paper she is uncowed by opposition calls to quit</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/sn8EODjWELc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SAO PAULO (Reuters) - Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff told newspaper Folha de S. Paulo in an interview published Tuesday that she plans to finish her term and continue with efforts to narrow the budget deficit in spite of growing calls among opponents for her resignation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Brazil's Rousseff tells paper she is uncowed by opposition calls to quit
SAO PAULO
Brazil's President Dilma Rousseff arrives to tour the NASA Advanced Supercomputing Facility at NASA's Ames Research Center at Moffett Field in Mountain View, California July 1, 2015.
Reuters/Stephen Lam
SAO PAULO Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff told newspaper Folha de S. Paulo in an interview published Tuesday that she plans to finish her term and continue with efforts to narrow the budget deficit in spite of growing calls among opponents for her resignation.
When asked repeatedly by Folha reporters about heightening pressure for her to step down amid revelations that members of her ruling coalition received bribes from state contractors in recent years, Rousseff said she would not back down and was uncowed by calls for her resignation.
"I am not going to fall. I won't, I won't. That's too wimpy, this is a political fight," she told Folha. "There's no basis for me to fall."
"Try me, try me," she added.
In the interview, Rousseff said part of the opposition are trying to instigate an impeachment process.
"To oust a president you have to explain why. They are mixing their wishes with reality. Is there any real basis to do that? I don't believe there is any at all," she added.
According to Folha, she lauded efforts by the PMDB party, the largest in her coalition after her Workers' Party, to support her program. She also refrained from criticizing her predecessor and political mentor, Luiz Incio Lula da Silva, who in recent weeks said she was "running on fumes."
Rousseff, who began her second, four-year term in January, said the government is working on new measures to adjust public finances, although declined to specify any of them, according to the newspaper. She also reaffirmed her commitment to narrowing the country's budget deficit in the Folha interview.
The government "is preparing structural measures that can contribute to the adjustment in the mid-and-long terms," she told the newspaper.
Efforts by the central bank to meet the 4.5 percent inflation target next year will help consumer price inflation in Brazil converge to international standards, Rousseff said, although she urged the bank to remain attentive to any potential deflation signals. Rousseff said that the intensity of Brazil's downturn caught her by surprise and that she would do "whatever it takes" to attenuate it.
A spokeswoman for the presidential palace confirmed the accuracy of the content of Folha's interview.
(Reporting by Alexandre Caverni and Guillermo Parra-Bernal; Additional reporting by Asher Levine in So Paulo Editing by W Simon)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:06:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cholera kills 32 in South Sudan, education key to stemming outbreak: U.N.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Cu8-wW1PtfQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Thomson Reuters Foundation) - A cholera outbreak in war-torn South Sudan has killed at least 32 people, a fifth of them children under five, and schools have a major role to play in stemming the spread of the disease, the United Nations said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cholera kills 32 in South Sudan, education key to stemming outbreak: U.N.
By Kieran Guilbert
LONDON (Thomson Reuters Foundation) - A cholera outbreak in war-torn South Sudan has killed at least 32 people, a fifth of them children under five, and schools have a major role to play in stemming the spread of the disease, the United Nations said on Tuesday.
More than 700 cholera cases have been reported in the capital Juba and Bor, the capital of Jonglei state, in the last five weeks, according to the U.N. children's agency UNICEF.
"Cholera is a deadly disease that inordinately affects young children," Jonathan Veitch, UNICEF representative in South Sudan, said in a statement.
"One of the most powerful ways we can respond to this outbreak is by equipping schoolchildren with the information and tools they need to protect themselves and their families."
An intestinal infection often linked to contaminated drinking water, cholera causes diarrhea and vomiting, leaving small children especially vulnerable to death from dehydration.
As many as 5,000 children under five are at risk of dying from cholera unless urgent action is taken to contain the outbreak, the U.N. humanitarian agency OCHA said last week.
Children are being encouraged to raise awareness about the disease among their families and communities in a country where only one in four adults are literate, according to UNICEF.
UNICEF is also broadcasting cholera prevention messages, hosting talk shows on radio stations, conducting vaccination campaigns and training volunteers, teachers and religious leaders about prevention and early detection of cholera.
Veitch said the cholera outbreak could lead to a devastating loss of life if it spreads into conflict-hit states where almost 200 health facilities have been closed or destroyed.
"It's a race against time to prevent the spread of cholera up the river Nile, especially during the rainy season. Our priority right now is reaching the most vulnerable children who urgently need clean water and vaccinations," Veitch said.
Health Minister Riek Gai Kok said last month that one of the casualties had died at a United Nations facility housing civilians seeking refuge from the civil war raging in the world's youngest nation state.
The conflict pits forces loyal to President Salva Kiir against rebels allied with former vice president Riek Machar, and more than 10,000 people have been killed since the fighting first erupted in December 2013.
The conflict has also created a humanitarian crisis, as more than 730,000 people have fled to neighboring countries and some 1.5 million people have been uprooted within the country, according to the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR.
At least 167 people died in South Sudan in a cholera outbreak last year, according to the World Health Organization.
(Reporting By Kieran Guilbert, Editing by Tim Pearce. Please credit the Thomson Reuters Foundation, the charitable arm of Thomson Reuters, that covers humanitarian news, women's rights, trafficking, corruption and climate change. Visit www.trust.org)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:04:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al Shabaab gunmen kill 14 in attack on Kenyan workers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/F-ak425FEpo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MOMBASA, Kenya (Reuters) - Al Shabaab gunmen killed 14 people, mostly quarry workers, officials said, in an overnight attack on a residential complex in northeast Kenya that the Islamic militant group said had targeted Christians.</Description>
        <MainBody>Al Shabaab gunmen kill 14 in attack on Kenyan workers
MOMBASA, Kenya | By Joseph Akwiri
Kenyan police officers and Kenya Red Cross workers carry the body of a man killed during an overnight attack on a residential complex in Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
1 of 4
right
A man rests on a hospital bed as he awaits treatment after he was injured during an overnight attack on a residential complex in Soko Mbuzi village of Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
2 of 4
right
Kenya Defence Forces soldiers walk near the scene of an overnight attack on a residential complex in Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
3 of 4
right
Kenya Defence Forces soldiers and policemen gather at the entrance of a residential complex that was attacked in Soko Mbuzi village of Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
4 of 4
right
MOMBASA, Kenya Al Shabaab gunmen killed 14 people, mostly quarry workers, officials said, in an overnight attack on a residential complex in northeast Kenya that the Islamic militant group said had targeted Christians.
Many died in their sleep, the Kenya Red Cross said. The raid, in the town of Mandera, mirrored one in the same county in December in which 36 quarry workers died.
Al Shabaab has made a series of deadly incursions into Kenya, which it says will continue until Nairobi withdraws its troops from an African Union force fighting the militants in their home base of Somalia.
The group's military operations spokesman, Sheikh Abdiasis Abu Musab, told Reuters its gunmen killed more than 10 Kenyan Christians in Tuesday's raid. It has in the past singled out non-Muslims to be executed.
"The area ... is a plot where quarry workers live. They attacked at around 1 a.m. Most of those killed are workers from upcountry," Alex Nkoyo, commissioner for Mandera County, told Reuters by phone. He put the death toll at 14.
Among the dead was a woman who had tried to plead with the gunmen before being shot, he said.
Abbas Gullet, the secretary general of Kenya Red Cross, said the workers were attacked as they slept, and that at least 11 people were wounded.
Tuesday's raid will heighten pressure on President Uhuru Kenyatta to beef up security in response to al Shabaab attacks, the worst of which killed 148 people at a university in eastern Kenya's Garissa County in April.
"This attack is a clear reminder that al Shabaab and its collaborators are determined to disrupt and subvert our way of life," Interior Minister Joseph Nkaisserry said in a statement.
He said security reacted swiftly to prevent a higher death toll after the group opened their attack by blowing up an entrance gate to the residential area.
After the Garissa attack, critics accused the security forces responding too slowly, one reason cited for the number killed in that attack.
Kenya's northeast border with Somalia is widely considered a security weak spot, given the challenge of policing such a long frontier, poor coordination between security services, and a culture of corruption that allows anyone prepared to pay a bribe to pass unchallenged.
Al Shabaab aims to topple Somalia's Western-backed government and wants to impose its own strict version of Islamic law on the country.
(Additional reporting by George Obulutsa in Nairobi; Writing by George Obulutsa and Edmund Blair ; Editing by Larry King)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:02:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands brave Andean downpours in Ecuador for papal Mass</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/csQlc-k0XwY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>QUITO (Reuters) - Thousands of pilgrims braved wind and rain to camp out overnight for a Mass to be given by Pope Francis on Tuesday in Ecuador's highland capital Quito for an expected million people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thousands brave Andean downpours in Ecuador for papal Mass
QUITO | By Girish Gupta
Pope Francis blesses faithfuls during his visit to the Presidential Palace in Quito, Ecuador, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Bianchi
QUITO Thousands of pilgrims braved wind and rain to camp out overnight for a Mass to be given by Pope Francis on Tuesday in Ecuador's highland capital Quito for an expected million people.
Political protests had been rocking the socialist-ruled nation of 15 million people prior to the pontiff's arrival, but his presence has brought a temporary halt to demonstrations.
Francis is visiting three of the smallest and poorest nations during a week-long tour of his native South America.
At the Bicentenario Park, a former airport where he was due to give Mass mid-morning, some bedraggled faithful camped out for two nights in the extremes of Andean weather - torrential rain, biting wind and blazing sun.
For some, it became too much and at least one fight broke out as people attempted to push in.
Yet most thought the wait worthwhile.
"He is somebody who has really changed the church, changed young people's way of thinking," said Veronica Calderon, a 23-year-old civil engineering student who had arrived at six in the morning the day before the Mass.
"He's not been afraid to be tough with those who are corrupt, those who have damaged the church."
Hawkers walked up and down the lines selling wooden crosses, flags and t-shirts made especially for the trip as well as food and drink. Many used umbrellas to shield themselves both from the downpours and blazing sun when the rain cleared.
CORREA MEETING
Argentine-born Francis spent most of Monday in the coastal city of Guayaquil, delivering a Mass to some 800,000 people before going to a Jesuit-run school to visit a friend he had not seen for three decades.
In the evening, Francis flew back to Quito and met with leftist President Rafael Correa at the presidential palace, specially adorned with 120,000 roses, before blessing those gathered in the square below.
Recent protests over tax hikes have marred the visit somewhat for Correa, though demonstrators declared a moratorium during the trip as a mark of respect.
The pope flies on Wednesday to La Paz, Bolivia, another highland city where oxygen tanks are kept at the airport for arriving passengers who may struggle with the thin air.
That will focus attention on the 78-year-old pope's health as he had part of one lung removed when he was younger after a serious infection.
In Bolivia, Francis is to visit a notoriously violent prison before going to Paraguay where he will meet with social activists.
"It's very important for us that the pope is Latin American. It shows that faith is universal," said Victor Hugo Lobato, a 43-year-old teacher who camped out with his family overnight at the Quito park after a bus trip through the previous night.
Not all in Latin America are impressed with the church. Some say it has curbed progress on issues including women's and gay rights in a traditionally macho region.
"It's not good that the church has so much weight in political decisions," said Andres Caicedo, 35, spokesman for the Ecuadorean Atheist Association.
"It's also inappropriate that in a country that is supposedly secular, we spend so much money on such a visit."
(Editing by Andrew Cawthorne and Jeffrey Benkoe)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:26:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan president says peace delegation meeting Taliban in Pakistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/whZkm9cXYq0/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - The Afghan government has sent a peace delegation to Pakistan for negotiations with the Taliban, the president's office said in a statement on Twitter on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan president says peace delegation meeting Taliban in Pakistan
KABUL
Afghanistan President Ashraf Ghani speaks during a news conference in Kabul, Afghanistan May 11, 2015.
Reuters/Mohammad Ismail/Files
KABUL The Afghan government has sent a peace delegation to Pakistan for negotiations with the Taliban, the president's office said in a statement on Twitter on Tuesday.
The meeting could be a step towards starting a formal peace process with the insurgent group that was ousted from power by a U.S. led invasion in 2001.
(Reporting by Kabul bureau, Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:20:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkish opposition accuses Erdogan of stalling on government mandate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/D89FSyR-T3w/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ANKARA (Reuters) - Turkish opposition MPs accused President Tayyip Erdogan on Tuesday of stalling efforts to form a coalition government as he seeks to maintain his grip on power, a month after the AK Party he founded lost its parliamentary majority.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkish opposition accuses Erdogan of stalling on government mandate
ANKARA | By Gulsen Solaker and Ercan Gurses
Turkey's President Tayyip Erdogan greets parliamentarians as he arrives at the Turkish parliament to watch a swearing-in ceremony in Ankara, Turkey, June 23, 2015
Reuters/Umit Bektas
ANKARA Turkish opposition MPs accused President Tayyip Erdogan on Tuesday of stalling efforts to form a coalition government as he seeks to maintain his grip on power, a month after the AK Party he founded lost its parliamentary majority.
The June 7 vote left the AKP unable to rule alone for the first time in over a decade, plunging Turkey into political uncertainty not seen since the 1990s and thwarting for now Erdogan's ambition to amass greater power.
Formal coalition talks cannot begin until Erdogan gives Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu the mandate to form a new government, at which point he has 45 days to do so or face the prospect of another election.
Some opposition MPs have suggested Erdogan is stalling to sow opposition disarray and to ensure the AKP is still firmly in power for a High Military Council (YAS) meeting in August, where key army commanders are appointed.
"He wants the changes to be made at the YAS to be done by him alone without debate, with the old cabinet and the old political climate," Ozgur Ozel, an MP with the main opposition Republican People's Party (CHP), told Reuters.
"He thinks the slow process will trigger disputes in the opposition, rather than in his own party," he said, adding the aim was to boost AKP support in case of another election.
Reining in a military which forced four governments from power in the second half of the 20th Century was one of Erdogan's priorities during his 12 years as prime minister.
YAS meetings - at which retirements, transfers and disciplinary actions are decided - were a key element of that process. The current head of the armed forces, General Necdet Ozel, is set to retire at the August meeting.
Deputy Prime Minister Numan Kurtulmus poured cold water on claims of a deliberate delay, telling broadcaster Haberturk on Tuesday that Erdogan would "most probably" give the mandate to Davutoglu this week.
Davutoglu meanwhile last week rejected suggestions that the AKP would wait until after the YAS to form a new government, while Erdogan himself has said he will only give the mandate once parliament's new administration is in place.
A speaker was elected last week but an administrative board is yet to be agreed.
As president, Erdogan is constitutionally bound to remain above party politics but effectively turned the June election into a referendum on his ambitions for an executive presidency, campaigning around the country.
He chaired a cabinet meeting in his controversial new palace on Monday, something which opposition parties have said must end if they are to enter any coalition.
"The president has given the message since the beginning that 'this process will advance under my control'," Meral Danis Bestas, deputy chairwoman of the pro-Kurdish Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP), told Reuters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:17:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two Taliban attacks in Afghan capital kill one, wound three</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/5awa22cA6UQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - Taliban suicide bomb attacks in Afghanistan's capital targeted a convoy of foreign troops and a compound of the country's intelligence agency, wounding three people and killing at least one, Afghan and foreign officials said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Two Taliban attacks in Afghan capital kill one, wound three
KABUL | By Mirwais Harooni and Hamid Shalizi
KABUL Taliban suicide bomb attacks in Afghanistan's capital targeted a convoy of foreign troops and a compound of the country's intelligence agency, wounding three people and killing at least one, Afghan and foreign officials said on Tuesday.
Taliban and other insurgents have stepped up attacks on Afghan and foreign forces this year, after most coalition troops withdrew from Afghanistan at the end of 2014.
As security has deteriorated, some Afghan districts have fallen under Taliban control. A growing presence of forces loyal to Islamic State has fueled concern that parts of the country are slipping out of Kabul's grasp.
In the first attack, late on Tuesday morning, a suicide car bomber slammed into a land cruiser carrying foreign forces in the Shah Shaheed area of eastern Kabul, wounding at least two people, Afghan and foreign officials said.
The cruiser caught fire after the explosion, said an Afghan security official at the scene. The blast blew the vehicle off course and into a wall, leaving behind an empty, charred hulk.
"I can confirm that a suicide car bomber targeted foreign forces," interior ministry spokesman Sediq Sediqqi told Reuters.
In a statement, the coalition said there were no fatalities from the attack, but declined to give details.
A foreigner and a bystander were wounded in the incident, a police spokesman, Ebadullah Karimi, said.
In the second attack, Taliban insurgents raided a compound used by Afghanistan's intelligence agency, Karimi said, killing one security guard and wounding another.
"Three suicide bombers were involved in the attack," he added. "One detonated his explosives, two were shot dead by security forces."
On Twitter, the Taliban claimed responsibility for both attacks, which came a week after last Tuesday's strike by a suicide bomber on a convoy of U.S. troops close to the U.S. embassy.
About 9,800 U.S troops remain in Afghanistan, down from a peak of around 100,000 in 2011. The majority are training Afghan forces but a few thousand are still engaged in combat operations against the Taliban and others.
On a visit to Kabul on Saturday, U.S. Senator John McCain of Arizona called for U.S. troops to stay longer than planned to prevent gains by the militants.
The current schedule is for the military to draw down to an embassy presence by the end of 2016.
(Writing by Jessica Donati; Editing by Kay Johnson and Clarence Fernandez)
A member of the Afghan security forces investigates next to a destroyed vehicle at the site of a suicide attack in Kabul, Afghanistan July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Mohammad Ismail
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge quits Cambodia's troubled Khmer Rouge trials</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/SN4QGBf6CdA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PHNOM PENH (Reuters) - An international judge announced his resignation from the U.N.-backed war crimes trials in Cambodia on Tuesday, the fourth to quit so far and another blow for the troubled tribunal probing the atrocities of the 1970s Khmer Rouge regime.</Description>
        <MainBody>Judge quits Cambodia's troubled Khmer Rouge trials
PHNOM PENH
Multi-colored bracelets commemorating Khmer Rouge victims are tied on poles at a former mass graves site at Choeung Ek, a ''Killing Fields'' site located on the outskirts of Phnom Penh July 2, 2015.
Reuters/Samrang Pring
PHNOM PENH An international judge announced his resignation from the U.N.-backed war crimes trials in Cambodia on Tuesday, the fourth to quit so far and another blow for the troubled tribunal probing the atrocities of the 1970s Khmer Rouge regime.
Mark Harmon, from the United States, said in a statement his reasons for stepping down after three years in Phnom Penh were "strictly personal" and "with considerable regret". He did not elaborate.
Several of Harmon's predecessors at the hybrid United Nations-Cambodian court have alleged political interference and a lack of cooperation by Cambodia's government, which contains remnants of the Khmer Rouge regime.
Prime Minister Hun Sen, a former Khmer Rouge soldier, has warned more trials could cause anarchy and a return to civil war. He has promised to thwart new indictments and once said he would be happy if the U.N. packed up and left.
The decade-old tribunal has so far delivered verdicts involving three high-profile leaders from the 1975-1979 "killing fields" era. Attempts to pursue more cases have been met by strong government resistance.
Cambodian police have refused to act on an arrest warrant Harmon has issued for Meas Muth, a former navy chief alleged to have sent detainees to a torture center where some 14,000 people died.
Court spokesman Lars Olsen said Harmon's resignation was unrelated to any development in cases he was working on. Harmon would continue his role until his replacement was sworn in.
(Reporting by Prak Chan Thul; Editing by Martin Petty)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:06:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China kicks off war commemorations with graphic exhibition</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/WdEjO_4aoVE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MARCO POLO BRIDGE, China (Reuters) - With dioramas of heroic Communist soldiers and graphic pictures of massacres, China formally kicked off its commemorations for the 70th anniversary of the end of World War Two on Tuesday with the unveiling of a new exhibition.</Description>
        <MainBody>China kicks off war commemorations with graphic exhibition
MARCO POLO BRIDGE, China | By Ben Blanchard
MARCO POLO BRIDGE, China With dioramas of heroic Communist soldiers and graphic pictures of massacres, China formally kicked off its commemorations for the 70th anniversary of the end of World War Two on Tuesday with the unveiling of a new exhibition.
Sino-Japan relations have long been affected by what China sees as Japan's failure to atone for its occupation of parts of the country before and during World War Two, and China rarely misses an opportunity to push that message.
The new exhibition, called "Great Victory, Historical Contribution", is located at a war museum next to the Marco Polo Bridge, the site of a skirmish in Beijing's outlying suburbs 78 years ago that sparked an all-out Sino-Japanese war.
Speaking in front of armed forces personnel, children and veterans, propaganda chief Liu Yunshan said people should draw inspiration from the "splendid annals" of the war.
"We must use this platform and classroom to guide officials and the people to draw sustenance from the hard struggles of the past," said Liu, who is ranked number five in the Communist Party's hierarchy.
The exhibition highlights some of the horrors of war, including a skull from a person killed in the 1937 Nanjing Massacre and a spiked metal cage used to torture captured Chinese.
Another picture shows a woman raped by Japanese soldiers and then disemboweled and dumped on the road.
Almost all the exhibits have English translations, underscoring the government's desire to get its message about Japanese brutality and Communist bravery to a worldwide audience.
The Communist Party's role is in sharp focus - exhibit captions are peppered with references to the reluctance or refusal of the Nationalist Chinese government to fight Japan.
In China's official narrative the contribution of Nationalist troops - who later fled to Taiwan after loosing a civil war with the Communists in 1949 - is barely mentioned.
Over the weekend, Taiwan's president said it was Nationalist Chinese forces who won the war, decrying attempts to "distort" history.
"Our exhibition clearly shows that our Communist Party was the cornerstone in the war to oppose Japanese aggression, and we have a lot facts here to show that," deputy museum director Luo Cunkang told reporters, when asked about the Taiwan comments.
China's commemorations will reach a crescendo in September with a parade of Chinese and Russian troops through central Beijing.
No senior Western leaders are expected to attend.
(Editing by Jeremy Laurence )
A picture showing a mother holding her son bombed by the Japanese troops in Wuhan, is displayed at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of Beijing, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jason Lee
1 of 5
right
A visitor stands above Japanese soldiers' weapons which were seized by the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) during World War Two, during a new exhibition at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on...
Reuters/Jason Lee
2 of 5
right
Students walk past statues at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of Beijing, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jason Lee
3 of 5
right
A visitor walks past pictures of Chinese Communist Party's top leaders (L-R) Mao Zedong, Deng Xiaoping, Jiang Zemin, Hu Jintao and Xi Jinping at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of...
Reuters/Jason Lee
4 of 5
right
Chinese Communist Party's propaganda chief Liu Yunshan speaks at the opening ceremony of a new exhibition outside the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of Beijing, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jason Lee
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:56:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant sailboat sinks in Aegean, at least 17 missing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Oe0tqaoALDc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS (Reuters) - A sailboat carrying migrants sank in the Aegean sea between Turkey and Greece on Tuesday and at least 17 people were missing, Greek authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant sailboat sinks in Aegean, at least 17 missing
ATHENS
ATHENS A sailboat carrying migrants sank in the Aegean sea between Turkey and Greece on Tuesday and at least 17 people were missing, Greek authorities said.
Greece's maritime ministry said Greek and Turkish rescue efforts had saved 16 of the between 33 and 37 migrants believed to be on board when the boat went down between the Greek islands of Farmakonisi and Agathonisi.
Their nationalities were not known.
"The operation is ongoing," said a spokeswoman for Greece's maritime ministry. "We are still looking for 17 to 21 people."
More than 135,000 refugees and migrants have arrived in Europe by sea in the first half of this year, many of them fleeing war, repression and poverty in Africa and the Middle East. Most are Syrians.
Greece is the largest arrival point, putting a huge strain on the country as it wrestles with one of the worst economic crises of modern times.
(Reporting by Lefteris Karagiannopoulos; Writing by Matt Robinson; Editing by Andrew Heavens )
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:54:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosives stolen from army base in France</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/ZndWs-S-DP4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MARSEILLE (Reuters) - Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Explosives stolen from army base in France
MARSEILLE
MARSEILLE Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.
The theft came even though France has heightened security after a suspected Islamist beheaded his boss and tried to blow up a gas plant near Lyon on June 26. Six months earlier, gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish foodstore in January.
The Marseille prosecution office has begun an investigation into the robbery, which was discovered on Monday. France's defense ministry ordered a review of the army's military supplies and the protection of ammunition storage units.
The Miramas site serves as a logistical base for the French army's external operations, the source said.
(Reporting by Francois Revilla, Nicolas Bertin, Chine Labbe, writing by Astrid Wendlandt; editing by Larry King)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:50:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain pays tribute to 7/7 victims 10 years after London bombings</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/CcIeMzs1jgY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - Prime Minister David Cameron led somber tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.</Description>
        <MainBody>LONDON | By Michael Holden
LONDON Prime Minister David Cameron led somber tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.
Relatives of the victims, survivors, and senior politicians gathered to remember those killed in the July 7 2005 bombings with emotions still raw after a massacre in Tunisia last month, Britain's worst loss of life in a militant assault since London.
"Today the country comes together to remember the victims of one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain," Cameron said in a statement.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly  the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact.But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
In the early hours of July 7 a decade ago, four young British Muslims traveled down to London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus during the morning rush-hour.
Inspired by al Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others. Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
Cameron and London mayor Boris Johnson stood silently, heads bowed, before laying a wreath at the 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park. They will later join other senior figures, victims' families, survivors and members of the emergency services caught up in the bombings for a service of remembrance at St Paul's Cathedral.
This will include a national minute of silence, which comes just four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
"LEARNING LESSONS"
A further service will be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives which Prince William, Queen Elizabeth's grandson, will attend.
Esther Hyman, 46, whose sister Miriam was killed on the Number 30 bus when it was blown up at Tavistock Square, told Reuters many young people seemed unaware of the bombings.
"The events of 7/7 do seem to have slipped out of public consciousness," said Hyman, who with her mother last week  launched an educational program to help teach school pupils about the attacks and to steer them away from violent extremism.
"It's worth remembering an event like 7/7 and learning lessons from it so that it didn't happen in vain."
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe", meaning a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by Islamic State (IS) fighters and Britons who have joined them.
Andrew Parker, head of Britain's domestic spy agency MI5,
said only a "tiny fraction of the population" posed a threat.
"But the continuing fact that some people, born in the UK, with all the opportunities and freedoms that modern Britain offers, can nonetheless make those sorts of warped choices presents a serious societal and security challenge," Parker said in a rare public statement.
The government plans new measures to counter extremism and Mark Rowley, Britain's most senior counter-terrorism police officer, said the country was better prepared than 10 years ago, although the threat itself had morphed.
He said IS was creating an "enormous" list of potential targets, focused on propaganda value.
A memorial plaque is attached to railings in Tavistock Square, in memory of those who lost their lives on a number 30 double-decker bus during the 7/7 attack in 2005, in London, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Peter Nicholls
1 of 3
right
A woman shows her emotions as she visits and pays her respects at the 7 July Memorial monument in Hyde Park, to those who lost their lives in the 7/7 attack in 2005, in London, Britain, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Peter Nicholls
2 of 3
right
Passers-by look at a memorial plaque attached to railings in Tavistock Square, in memory of those who lost their lives on a number 30 double-decker bus during the 7/7 attack in 2005, in London, Britain, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Peter Nicholls
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:31:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery deaths in India recruitment scam pressure Modi's party</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/6wrdQQSFlgw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NEW DELHI (Reuters) - The deaths of a number of witnesses in a massive fraud case surrounding cheating at college and government jobs has become the latest source of discomfort for India's ruling party, already on the defensive over influence trafficking allegations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mystery deaths in India recruitment scam pressure Modi's party
NEW DELHI | By Chiara Saldanha
Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi gestures while addressing the gathering during the launch of ''Digital India Week'' in New Delhi, India, July 1, 2015.
Reuters/Adnan Abidi
NEW DELHI The deaths of a number of witnesses in a massive fraud case surrounding cheating at college and government jobs has become the latest source of discomfort for India's ruling party, already on the defensive over influence trafficking allegations.
Investigators say thousands of people got jobs or medical degrees from systematic exam cheating that generated millions of dollars in bribes in the state of Madhya Pradesh.
At least 36 people connected to the case in the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) run state have died since the scam was first brought to light. More than 2,000 have been arrested in relation to the scam.
Four more people connected to the case have died since the weekend, just days before a Supreme Court hearing and amid opposition accusations that a regional unit of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's party was protecting the accused.
"They are not arresting the real culprits," said Vivek Tankha, a lawyer representing three whistle blowers who exposed the scam in 2013.
State Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan, a popular BJP leader, denies wrongdoing. But on Tuesday he buckled to pressure and said the inquiry should be handed to the Central Bureau of Investigation to avoid suspicion of political meddling.
The latest deaths included a national television journalist who began foaming at the mouth soon after interviewing the parents of Namrata Damor, a student who had obtained a college seat as part of the scam and was herself later found dead on train tracks in January 2012. The journalist died in hospital.
In the past few days, a policeman was found hanging from a ceiling fan, a trainee policewoman was found dead in a pond, and the dean of a college involved in the scam was found dead, with a half empty liquor bottle in a hotel room.
Chouhan denies accusations made by the opposition Congress party that he and other officials benefited from the fraud.
"There are very powerful big people involved in this," said the Congress party's Digvijaya Singh, a former Madhya Pradesh chief minister who wants the case be investigated by federal agents monitored by the Supreme Court.
On Tuesday, the Supreme Court said it would consider his petition along with several other relating to the case, at a hearing on July 9.
The scandal broke just as Indian media was lowering the pressure on the government over help given by the foreign minister and another regional leader to a controversial cricket-tycoon who fled a corruption probe and lives in London.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:14:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan's Abe faces growing risk on security shift: opposition leader</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/do2Vk2kN7U8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (Reuters) - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe will be taking a big risk if he pushes through a dramatic change in security policy despite objections from most citizens, who want a better explanation why the change is needed, a top opposition figure said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>TOKYO | By Linda Sieg
Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe speaks to the media at his official residence in Tokyo in this photo taken by Kyodo March 19, 2015.
Reuters/Kyodo
TOKYO Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe will be taking a big risk if he pushes through a dramatic change in security policy despite objections from most citizens, who want a better explanation why the change is needed, a top opposition figure said on Tuesday.
Abe's ratings have slipped over the security policy shift, which could let Japanese troops fight abroad for the first time since Tokyo's defeat in World War Two, and which he hopes to enact into law in a parliament session that runs until Sept. 27.
The ruling bloc has a majority that would allow it to enact Abe's bills, but any perception of high-handedness could erode support further even as the prime minister eyes re-election as head of his Liberal Democratic Party in September.
"Ultimately, it depends on public opinion," Katsuya Okada, the head of the main opposition Democratic Party of Japan (DPJ), told Reuters, when asked if Abe's bloc could be kept from forcing a vote in parliament's lower house.
That step could come as soon as next week.
"Pressure on the administration is mounting," Okada, a former foreign minister, said in an interview.
Abe's support fell three points, to 42 percent, in a Mainichi newspaper survey published on Monday.
Sixty-one percent of respondents opposed passage of legislation in the current session to end a ban on exercising the right of collective self-defense, or militarily aiding a friendly country under attack.
"Basically, I think we face a choice between two paths," Okada added. Will we stick to the pacifism of the constitution or become a 'normal' country?"
Conservatives say Japan's post-war constitution puts limits on its ability to defend itself that are too severe. Proponents say it has kept the nation at peace, and reinterpreting it outside formal amendment procedures sets a dangerous precedent.
Okada, 61, acknowledged Japan faces a tough security climate and said collective self-defense might be a future option.
But conditions set in the bills were too abstract and there was a high likelihood it violated the constitution's pacifist Article 9, he said.
Some analysts say Abe's ratings could slip as much as 10 points if the bills go through, possibly encouraging a rival to challenge him in the LDP leadership race.
But the Democrats, ousted in 2012 after three rocky years in power, have made few gains. Seven percent backed the DPJ in the Mainichi poll, versus 31 percent for the LDP.
(Reporting by Linda Sieg; Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drone strikes target Islamic State fighters in eastern Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/j_soAXdyTPE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Kabul (Reuters) - Two drone strikes targeted militants loyal to Islamic State in Afghanistan on Tuesday, killing between 25 and 49 insurgents, according to differing estimates by Afghan and foreign officials.</Description>
        <MainBody>Drone strikes target Islamic State fighters in eastern Afghanistan
Kabul
Kabul Two drone strikes targeted militants loyal to Islamic State in Afghanistan on Tuesday, killing between 25 and 49 insurgents, according to differing estimates by Afghan and foreign officials.
An increasing number of militants are pledging allegiance to the Islamic State in Afghanistan, making them a target of deadly strikes there by the U.S. unmanned aircraft.
A total of 49 militants were killed in the strikes in the eastern province of Nangarhar, which targeted the village of Mamd Dara in Achin district, where the fighters routinely held gatherings, a spokesman for the governor said.
"The first drone strike took place at 12 a.m. on Monday... the second one happened at 02:00 p.m," said Ahmad Zia Abdulzai.
However, the foreign official, who asked not to be named in order to be able to speak freely, said the number of dead was believed to be closer to 25.
One of the most high profile figures to have been targeted in drone strikes so far was former Guantanamo Bay detainee Mullah Abdul Rauf, who had defected to Islamic State and was killed by a strike in southern Helmand province in February.
(Reporting by Mirwais Harooni; Editing by Jessica Donati and Clarence Fernandez)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:57:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First victims of deadliest migrant shipwreck given funeral in Italy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/gC_fHExHFCw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>CATANIA, Italy (Reuters) - Italy held a funeral service on Tuesday for 13 migrants who died in the worst shipwreck in the Mediterranean in recent history, while the navy continued its search for other victims of the disaster.</Description>
        <MainBody>First victims of deadliest migrant shipwreck given funeral in Italy
CATANIA, Italy
CATANIA, Italy Italy held a funeral service on Tuesday for 13 migrants who died in the worst shipwreck in the Mediterranean in recent history, while the navy continued its search for other victims of the disaster.
More than 700 people, most of them locked below deck, were believed to have drowned in April. Their overloaded fishing boat capsized after colliding with a ship that had come to their aid some 70 nautical miles off the coast of Libya.
The Italian navy last week retrieved the first bodies from the wreck, which is lying at a depth of about 370 meters (1,200 feet), using remote-controlled vehicles and a submersible basket to haul up the remains.
With the recovery mission still in full swing, simple wooden coffins carrying the bodies of 13 unidentified migrants were carried into the Palazzo della Cultura in Catania, in eastern Sicily, for an inter-religious service.
"Today, we are gathering here to mark the loss of the lives of other human beings, taken away by the sea. Every time it happens we think it is the last time, but unfortunately that is not the case," said Ismail Bouchafa, the imam of Catania.
The bodies were later taken to Catania cemetery but were not immediately buried. The authorities are still deciding where all the victims should be interred.
Tens of thousands of migrants have crossed the Mediterranean so far this year in the hope of reaching Italy or Greece. An estimated 2,000 have drowned.
(Reporting by Antonio Parrinello, writing by Isla Binnie; Editing by Crispian Balmer and Digby Lidstone)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
=======
        <date>Sun Jun 28 02:20:05 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/fbhV6ybpF6k/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SOUSSE, Tunisia (Reuters) - Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.</Description>
        <MainBody>European tour operators evacuate thousands from Tunisia after attack
SOUSSE, Tunisia | By Tarek Amara
SOUSSE, Tunisia Tour companies were evacuating thousands of foreign holidaymakers from Tunisia on Saturday, a day after a gunman killed 39 people at a beach hotel in an attack claimed by Islamic State.
Tunisia's Prime Minister Habib Essid said most of the dead were British, and Britain's foreign office said 15 Britons had been confirmed killed in the attack in the resort town of Sousse, 140 km (90 miles) south of the capital Tunis.
A German, a Belgian and an Irish woman have also been identified, foreign and Tunisian officials said.
It was the second major attack in the North African country this year, following an Islamist militant assault on the Bardo Museum in Tunis in March when gunmen killed a group of foreign visitors as they arrived by bus.
Tunisia has undergone a largely peaceful transition to democracy since its 2011 Arab Spring uprising, but its army has been fighting a rise in Islamist militancy.
Tunisia's tourism minister called Friday's attack in one of the country's most popular resorts for Europeans a "catastrophe" and authorities vowed to toughen security, drafting in army reserves and arming tourism police at beaches and hotels.
Saloua Kadri, Sousse tourism commissioner, said more than 3,000 foreign tourists had fled the town on Saturday, including around 2,200 British and nearly 600 Belgians.
Dozens of tourists were waiting to take flights out from the nearby Ennfida airport.
"We don't want to stay any longer, we just want to see our family, parents ... so leaving as soon as possible," said Hannah Russel, an British tourist.
Sarah Maeson, another Briton flying back to Manchester, said: "We don't feel safe. Constantly hearing sirens and helicopters is not really helping your nerves."
EXTRA FLIGHTS
Tunisian authorities named the gunman as Saif Rezgui, a student who they say was not known to them. Dressed in shorts and T-shirt, Rezgui opened fire on the beach of the Imperial Marhaba hotel on Friday, picking out foreigners and leaving Tunisians alive.
Witnesses said he made his way to the pool and hotel, his killing spree ending only when he was shot dead by police.
Tour operators Thomson and First Choice, which are owned by German travel group TUI, said they had about 6,400 customers across Tunisia at the time of the attack, including several of the people killed and injured.
They sent 10 planes to evacuate tourists and said 1,000 had already been repatriated. They also said they would cancel all their holiday packages to Tunisia for at least the next week.
TUI's German tour operator TUI also organized flights for tourists wishing to return home and TUI's Belgian airline, Jetairfly, sent six empty planes to bring tourists back from the island of Djerba and from Ennfida airport on Saturday.
German Foreign Minister Frank-Walter Steinmeier confirmed one German had been killed, but said there may be others.
Tobias Ellwood, a junior minister at Britain's foreign office, told reporters in London the British death toll could rise as there were several who had been seriously wounded.
"This is the most significant terrorist attack on British people since 7/7," he said, referring to attacks on the London transport system on July 7, 2005, that killed 52 people.
NOT ON WATCHLIST
Tunisian authorities said the gunman was not on any watchlist of known potential militants. But one source said Rezgui appeared to have been radicalized over the last six months by Islamist militant recruiters.
As one countermeasure, Prime Minister Essid said that Tunisia planned within a week to close down 80 mosques that remain outside state control for inciting violence.
Several thousand Tunisian jihadists have gone to fight in Syria, Iraq and neighboring Libya, where some have set up training camps and vowed to return to attack their homeland.
The attack took place during the holy Muslim month of Ramadan and was one of three linked to Islamist militants on three different continents on Friday.
In France, a decapitated body daubed with Arabic writing was found, and in Kuwait a suicide bomber killed two dozen people at a mosque in Kuwait.
(Additional reporting by Estelle Shirbon in London and Erik Kirschbaum in Berlin; Writing by Patrick Markey; Editing by Susan Fenton and Raissa Kasolowsky )
A boy holds a candle and flowers as he attends a protest to condemn the attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
1 of 7
right
People attend a protest to condemn an attack by a gunman at the beach of the Imperial Marhabada hotel in Sousse, Tunisia, June 27, 2015.
Reuters/Zohra Bensemra
>>>>>>> cae8ddae84433650e63f1b14a36950d69141457f
>>>>>>> b0d9700a571c203eac335d065afaefc885316d4c
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
