<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<site name="Reuters">
    <Article id="0">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:22:53 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Air strikes, ground combat in Yemen killed nearly 200</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/0yyuwAhnpDY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SANAA (Reuters) - Saudi-led coalition air strikes and clashes killed at least 176 fighters and civilians in Yemen on Monday, residents and media run by the Houthi movement said, the highest daily toll since the Arab air offensive began more than three months ago.</Description>
        <MainBody>Air strikes, ground combat in Yemen killed nearly 200
SANAA
Guards walk through a damaged gate of the house of Brigadier Khaled al-Anduli, an army commander loyal to the Houthi movement, after it was hit by Saudi-led air strikes in Yemen's capital Sanaa July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Khaled Abdullah
SANAA Saudi-led coalition air strikes and clashes killed at least 176 fighters and civilians in Yemen on Monday, residents and media run by the Houthi movement said, the highest daily toll since the Arab air offensive began more than three months ago.
The United Nations has been pushing for a halt to air raids and intensified fighting that began on March 26. Almost 3,000 people have been killed since then as the Arab coalition tries stop the Houthis spreading across the country from the north.
The Iran-allied Shi'ite Houthis say they are rebelling against a corrupt government, while local fighters say they are defending their homes from Houthi incursions. Sunni Saudi Arabia says it is bombing the Houthis to protect the Yemeni state.
On Monday, about 63 people were killed in air strikes on Amran province in the north, among them 30 people at a market, Houthi-controled state media agency Saba said.
In the same province, about 20 fighters and civilians were killed at a Houthi checkpoint outside the main city, also named Amran, about 50 km (30 miles) northwest of the Yemeni capital of Sanaa, local residents said.
Arab alliance war planes also killed about 60 people at a livestock market in the town of al-Foyoush in the south.
Also in the south, residents reported a further 30 killed in a raid they said apparently targeted a Houthi checkpoint on the main road between Aden and Lahj. They said 10 of the dead were Houthi fighters.
Tribal sources in the central desert province of Marib said about 20 Houthi fighters and soldiers fighting alongside them were killed in air raids and gun battles with tribal fighters, who support Yemen's president in exile Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi.
On Tuesday, U.N. envoy to Yemen Ismail Ould Cheikh Ahmed continues meetings with Houthi officials in Sanaa to try to broker a ceasefire to allow aid deliveries. One Houthi official said Monday's attacks had dealt a blow to peace efforts.
"Even as the U.N. envoy is present, there are a hundred martyrs and hundreds of wounded ... No truce, no retreat, no surrender. Forward, forward heroes of Yemen, for victory is coming," Yahya Ali al-Qahoom wrote on his Twitter account.
Neither side has offered concessions as civil war rages.
Fighting, bombing and a near-blockade by the Arab coalition has deepened suffering in what is one of the poorest countries in the region.
The U.N. says more than 80 percent of Yemen's 25 million people need some form of humanitarian aid.
(Reporting by Mohammed Ghobari and Noah Browning; Editing by Louise Ireland )
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="1">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:20:16 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/W3YzksZcxZM/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.</Description>
        <MainBody>Greece faces last chance to stay in euro as cash runs out
BRUSSELS | By Paul Taylor and Renee Maltezou
BRUSSELS Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras had a final chance to present credible reform proposals to an emergency euro zone summit on Tuesday to persuade skeptical creditors to reopen aid talks before his country's banks run out of money.
With Greek lenders down to their last few days of cash and the European Central Bank tightening the noose on their funding, Tsipras must convince the bloc's other 18 leaders, many of whom are exasperated with five years of crisis, to authorize negotiations fast on a new loan to rescue Greece.
But Greek officials said the leftist premier's proposals would not go far beyond a plan he sent to the euro zone last week before Greek voters overwhelmingly rejected the austerity terms of a bailout in a referendum on Sunday.
The leaders of Germany and France, the currency area's two main powers, said after conferring on Monday that the door was still open to a deal to save Greece from plunging into economic turmoil and ditching the euro.
Chancellor Angela Merkel, under pressure in Germany to cut Greece loose, made clear it was up to Tsipras to come up with convincing proposals after Athens spurned the tax rises, spending cuts and pension and labor reforms that were on the table before its 240 billion euro bailout expired last week.
European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker, under suspicion from both sides for trying to broker a last-minute deal, told the European Parliament: "There are some in the European Union who openly or secretly are working to exclude Greece from the euro zone."
He did not name names but may have been referring to German Finance Minister Wolfgang Schaeuble, who has made no secret of his scepticism about Greece's fitness to stay in the euro and last week suggested a possible "temporary" exit.
From the Greek side, the key to making any deal politically acceptable will be to win a stronger commitment from Merkel and other lenders to reschedule Greece's giant debt burden, which the International Monetary Fund says is unsustainable.
Without some firmer pledge of debt relief, neither Greece nor the IMF is likely to accept a deal. But that may be more than Germany and its northern allies can swallow.
Schaeuble said on arrival for a preparatory meeting of finance ministers that anyone who had read the EU treaty knew debt write-offs were forbidden in the euro zone. He did not rule out other forms of restructuring.
Asked about reports that Greece was seeking an immediate bridging loan of several billion euros, Italian Finance Minister Pier Carlo Padoan the creditors would listen to Greek requests.
"The door is open to negotiations, but there isn't much time left and the situation is urgent both for Greece and for Europe," French President Francois Hollande said in a joint media appearance with Merkel in Paris on Monday.
At stake at the emergency summit beginning at 6 p.m. in Brussels is more than just the future of Greece, a nation of 11 million that makes up just 2 percent of the euro zone's economic output and population.
If Greek banks run out of money and the country has to print its own currency, it could mean a state leaving the euro for the first time since it was launched in 1999, creating a precedent and fuelling doubts about the long-term viability of an incomplete European monetary union.
"Even if it did not trigger a short-term domino effect, the integrity of the euro zone would come under fresh threat with each episode of political uncertainty within member countries," said Thibault Mercier, an analyst at BNP Paribas.
Even in France, the euro zone country most sympathetic to Athens, an opinion poll published on Tuesday showed one in two people want Greece to leave the euro zone.
CONCESSIONS UNCLEAR
Strengthened by the overwhelming 61.3 percent 'No' vote in Sunday's referendum, the leftist Tsipras won the unprecedented support of all other Greek party leaders on Monday and replaced his abrasive Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis with the soft-spoken negotiator Euclid Tsakalotos.
Tsakalotos entered the euro zone finance ministers' meeting without comment. Eurogroup chairman Jeroen Dijsselbloem said it was up to Greece to show a credible way forward.
"The pressure is especially on the Greeks, the banks are closed and the situation is difficult. I guess the Greek government has an interest in coming up with serious and credible solutions soon," Dijsselbloem told reporters.
In an intensive round of telephone diplomacy, Tsipras spoke to the heads of the ECB, the IMF and the European Commission, as well as Merkel, Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. Treasury Secretary Jack Lew.
The United States, China and Japan all called for a solution in which Greece stays in the euro zone.
Tsipras gave little clue of what reform concessions he would make to try to convince deeply skeptical European leaders to lend Athens more money after five months of acrimonious and fruitless negotiations with his leftist administration.
Even with the country on the brink of economic collapse, Greek officials said the government was still seeking exceptions from its reform pledges for special interests.
Athens wants to keep a 30 percent discount on value added tax on Greek islands and delay defense spending from cuts, which rightist junior coalition partners the Independent Greeks have called "red lines". It is also resisting raising VAT on restaurants to 23 percent, and wants to wait until 2019 to phase out an income supplement for poorer pensioners, officials said.
Juncker told EU lawmakers he was working night and day to get negotiations reopened and chided the Greeks for their aggressive approach, saying it was unacceptable to accuse the EU of behaving like "terrorists", as Varoufakis did last week.
"Throwing Greece out of the monetary union or indeed the European Union is not something we want or indeed should want," the EU's chief executive said.
European Central Bank policymaker Ewald Nowotny suggested the bank might be able to provide some sort of bridge funding while Greece negotiated a longer-term conditional loan to see it over a crucial July 20 bond redemption to the ECB.
Greek newspapers dramatized the make-or-break nature of the Brussels showdown.
Centrist daily Ethnos headlined: "Time has run out for a solution before catastrophe," while the center-right Eleftheros Typos said: "Tsipras games finish at today's council: Time of crisis: deal or Grexit."
A clear majority of Greece's 18 partners favor a hard line at the summit, arguing that they too are democracies and that Greeks should not get easier money because they had rejected the austerity terms, casting further doubt on whether they would implement any reforms agreed now.
The ECB left unchanged its emergency liquidity lifeline for Greek banks but raised the discount it charges on collateral they present for funds - a measure banking sources said was largely symbolic since the total they could borrow was capped.
A bank closure in force since the talks collapsed was prolonged until Thursday at least, and cash withdrawals remain limited to 60 euros a day, with 20 euro notes running out.
The Athens stock exchange was also ordered closed for two days in Tuesday and Wednesday to throttle speculation.
(Additional reporting by Costas Pitas , Angeliki Koutantou and George Georgiopoulos in Athens, Julia Fioretti and Alastair Macdonald in Brussels, Paul Carrel in Berlin John O'Donnell in Frankfurt and Mark John in Paris; Writing by Paul Taylor; editing by John Stonestreet and Giles Elgood )
Outgoing Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis (R) shows newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos his chair at the Finance Ministry before a handover ceremony in Athens, Greece July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Yannis Behrakis
1 of 7
right
Newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos looks on during his swearing in ceremony as Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras (L) stands next to him at the Presidential Palace in Athens, Greece July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
2 of 7
right
Newly-appointed Finance Minister Euclid Tsakalotos (R) and outgoing Yannis Varoufakis address a news conference at the Finance Ministry during a handover ceremony in Athens, Greece July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Yannis Behrakis
3 of 7
right
Greek Finance Minister Yanis Varoufakis leaves after making a statement in Athens, Greece July 5, 2015.
Reuters/Alkis Konstantinidis
4 of 7
right
French President Francois Hollande and German Chancellor Angela Merkel arrive at a joint statement at the Elysee Palace in Paris, France, July 6, 2015 following the Greek people's resounding 'No' to a European cash-for-reform deal in a referendum in Greece.
Reuters/Philippe Wojazer
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="2">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:19:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Syrian Kurds retake northern villages from Islamic State: monitor</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/O1t0eZB4KQE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>BEIRUT (Reuters) - Syrian Kurdish fighters have recaptured more than 10 villages seized by Islamic State north of its de facto capital of Raqqa city, aided by U.S.-led coalition air strikes, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Syrian Kurds retake northern villages from Islamic State: monitor
BEIRUT
BEIRUT Syrian Kurdish fighters have recaptured more than 10 villages seized by Islamic State north of its de facto capital of Raqqa city, aided by U.S.-led coalition air strikes, the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported on Tuesday.
Intensified air strikes across northern Syria and clashes on the ground have killed at least 78 Islamic State fighters since Sunday night, the Britain-based Observatory said.
The strikes are some of the most sustained since they began in September, according to U.S. officials who say they are aimed at curbing the militants' ability to operate out of Raqqa and to prevent it from fighting back against Kurdish advances.
But, on Tuesday, the ultra-hardline group was still in control of Ain Issa, the Observatory said. The town, 50 km (30 miles) north of Raqqa city, was seized by Islamic State fighters from the Kurdish YPG militia in an attack on Monday.
That attack on YPG-held areas followed an intensification of air strikes on Raqqa city over the weekend, which U.S. Defense Secretary Ash Carter said on Monday were aimed at disrupting the militants' ability to respond to YPG advances north of Raqqa.
The YPG, a militia operating mostly in predominantly Kurdish areas of northern Syria towards the Turkish border, has emerged as the only significant partner in Syria for U.S.-led alliance fighting to tackle Islamic State both there and in Iraq.
The Observatory, a British-based organization reporting on Syria's four-year-old civil war, said the coalition had played an "effective role" in helping YPG forces recover 11 villages northeast of Ain Issa.
The YPG, backed by small Syrian rebel groups, has made significant gains against Islamic State in Raqqa province in recent weeks, seizing Tel Abyad at the Turkish border on June 15 before advancing south to Ain Issa.
The YPG captured Ain Issa on June 23.
While the YPG has shown itself to be a potent force in the fight against Islamic State, its effectiveness is seen to diminish beyond the predominantly Kurdish areas it was set up to defend in northern and northeastern Syria.
The United States aims to train and equip Syrian rebel fighters it deems politically moderate in order to fight Islamic State in Syria. But the Pentagon said on June 18 the effort was moving more slowly than expected.
U.S. President Barack Obama said on Monday the United States would do more to train and equip "the moderate opposition".
(Writing by Tom Perry and Sylvia Westall ; Editing by Louise Ireland )
A general view is seen of Ain Issa in the suburb of Raqqa, eastern Syria September 13, 2013.
Reuters/Nour Fourat
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="3">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:18:06 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Six powers and Iran to continue nuclear talks past deadline: EU</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/vHQ0Tdkfgks/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>VIENNA (Reuters) - Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a U.N. arms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Head of the Iranian Atomic Energy Organization Ali Akbar Salehi (2nd R) walks near the hotel where the Iran nuclear talks meetings are being held in Vienna, Austria in Vienna, Austria July 4, 2015.
Reuters/Carlos Barria
1 of 2
right
Iranian Foreign Minister Javad Zarif stands on the balcony of Palais Coburg, the venue for nuclear talks in Vienna, Austria, July 2, 2015.
Reuters/Leonhard Foeger
2 of 2
right
VIENNA Iran and six major powers will keep negotiating past Tuesday's deadline for a long-term nuclear agreement as they tackle the most contentious issues, including the continuation of a U.N. arms embargo on Iran, the big powers said.
"We are continuing to negotiate for the next couple of days. This does not mean we are extending our deadline," EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini said outside the hotel where the talks between Iran, Britain, China, France, Germany, Russia and the United States are taking place.
The spokeswoman for the U.S. delegation, Marie Harf, said the terms of an interim deal between Iran and the six would be extended through Friday to give negotiators a few more days to finish their work.
"We're frankly more concerned about the quality of the deal than we are about the clock, though we also know that difficult decisions won't get any easier with time," Harf said. "That is why we are continuing to negotiate."
Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said there was "every reason" to believe a deal would be done within "a few days", and that there was an "understanding" that most of the current sanctions against Iran would be lifted.
"There is only one big problem in terms of sanctions - it is the problem of a weapons embargo," he told journalists, according to the news agency Interfax.
He said it was important to reach agreement on this as soon as possible, telling journalists that "ending the bans on supplies to Iran of the weapons required to fight terrorism is a very, very relevant objective".
It is the fourth time the parties have extended the terms of the interim deal, which was struck in November 2013 and provided Iran with limited sanctions relief in exchange for a halt to the production of uranium enriched to a purity level of 20 percent.
EXTENSION EXTENDED
The comprehensive deal under discussion is aimed at curbing Tehran's most sensitive nuclear work for a decade or more, in exchange for relief from economic sanctions that have slashed Iran's oil exports and crippled its economy.
The negotiators missed a June 30 deadline for a final agreement and then gave themselves until Tuesday.
"We are interpreting in a flexible way our deadline, which means that we are taking the time, the days we still need, to finalize the agreement," Mogherini said, adding that there remained several difficult issues to resolve.
Among these, officials said, are Iranian demands for a U.N. arms embargo and ballistic missiles sanctions to be lifted, the timing of U.S. and EU sanctions relief, and disagreements over future Iranian nuclear research and development.
"We have entered the most difficult, but also the most real, part of the negotiations," Mogherini added.
"We knew it would be difficult, challenging and sometimes hard and some things get tense and others we make progress."
She said foreign ministers now in Vienna might come and go.
"Dont get too excited if you see ministers leaving. They might come back. They will come back. And it doesnt mean that we are stopping the work we are doing inside. On the contrary, on the contrary."
French Foreign Minister Laurent Fabius confirmed that he would leave, and return to Vienna on Wednesday night.
The United States and its allies fear Iran is using its civilian nuclear program as a cover to develop a nuclear weapons capability. Iran says its program is peaceful.
An agreement would be the most important milestone in decades towards easing hostility between the United States and Iran, enemies since Iranian revolutionaries captured 52 hostages in the U.S. embassy in Tehran in 1979.
A deal would also reduce the chances of a U.S. military strike against Iran's nuclear facilities, something Washington refuses to rule out, and of a wider regional war.
(Reporting by John Irish, Louis Charbonneau , Arshad Mohammed and Parisa Hafezi ; Writing by Arshad Mohammed)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="4">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:16:10 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Brazil's Rousseff tells paper she is uncowed by opposition calls to quit</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/sn8EODjWELc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>SAO PAULO (Reuters) - Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff told newspaper Folha de S. Paulo in an interview published Tuesday that she plans to finish her term and continue with efforts to narrow the budget deficit in spite of growing calls among opponents for her resignation.</Description>
        <MainBody>Brazil's Rousseff tells paper she is uncowed by opposition calls to quit
SAO PAULO
Brazil's President Dilma Rousseff arrives to tour the NASA Advanced Supercomputing Facility at NASA's Ames Research Center at Moffett Field in Mountain View, California July 1, 2015.
Reuters/Stephen Lam
SAO PAULO Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff told newspaper Folha de S. Paulo in an interview published Tuesday that she plans to finish her term and continue with efforts to narrow the budget deficit in spite of growing calls among opponents for her resignation.
When asked repeatedly by Folha reporters about heightening pressure for her to step down amid revelations that members of her ruling coalition received bribes from state contractors in recent years, Rousseff said she would not back down and was uncowed by calls for her resignation.
"I am not going to fall. I won't, I won't. That's too wimpy, this is a political fight," she told Folha. "There's no basis for me to fall."
"Try me, try me," she added.
In the interview, Rousseff said part of the opposition are trying to instigate an impeachment process.
"To oust a president you have to explain why. They are mixing their wishes with reality. Is there any real basis to do that? I don't believe there is any at all," she added.
According to Folha, she lauded efforts by the PMDB party, the largest in her coalition after her Workers' Party, to support her program. She also refrained from criticizing her predecessor and political mentor, Luiz Incio Lula da Silva, who in recent weeks said she was "running on fumes."
Rousseff, who began her second, four-year term in January, said the government is working on new measures to adjust public finances, although declined to specify any of them, according to the newspaper. She also reaffirmed her commitment to narrowing the country's budget deficit in the Folha interview.
The government "is preparing structural measures that can contribute to the adjustment in the mid-and-long terms," she told the newspaper.
Efforts by the central bank to meet the 4.5 percent inflation target next year will help consumer price inflation in Brazil converge to international standards, Rousseff said, although she urged the bank to remain attentive to any potential deflation signals. Rousseff said that the intensity of Brazil's downturn caught her by surprise and that she would do "whatever it takes" to attenuate it.
A spokeswoman for the presidential palace confirmed the accuracy of the content of Folha's interview.
(Reporting by Alexandre Caverni and Guillermo Parra-Bernal; Additional reporting by Asher Levine in So Paulo Editing by W Simon)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="5">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:06:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Cholera kills 32 in South Sudan, education key to stemming outbreak: U.N.</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Cu8-wW1PtfQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Thomson Reuters Foundation) - A cholera outbreak in war-torn South Sudan has killed at least 32 people, a fifth of them children under five, and schools have a major role to play in stemming the spread of the disease, the United Nations said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Cholera kills 32 in South Sudan, education key to stemming outbreak: U.N.
By Kieran Guilbert
LONDON (Thomson Reuters Foundation) - A cholera outbreak in war-torn South Sudan has killed at least 32 people, a fifth of them children under five, and schools have a major role to play in stemming the spread of the disease, the United Nations said on Tuesday.
More than 700 cholera cases have been reported in the capital Juba and Bor, the capital of Jonglei state, in the last five weeks, according to the U.N. children's agency UNICEF.
"Cholera is a deadly disease that inordinately affects young children," Jonathan Veitch, UNICEF representative in South Sudan, said in a statement.
"One of the most powerful ways we can respond to this outbreak is by equipping schoolchildren with the information and tools they need to protect themselves and their families."
An intestinal infection often linked to contaminated drinking water, cholera causes diarrhea and vomiting, leaving small children especially vulnerable to death from dehydration.
As many as 5,000 children under five are at risk of dying from cholera unless urgent action is taken to contain the outbreak, the U.N. humanitarian agency OCHA said last week.
Children are being encouraged to raise awareness about the disease among their families and communities in a country where only one in four adults are literate, according to UNICEF.
UNICEF is also broadcasting cholera prevention messages, hosting talk shows on radio stations, conducting vaccination campaigns and training volunteers, teachers and religious leaders about prevention and early detection of cholera.
Veitch said the cholera outbreak could lead to a devastating loss of life if it spreads into conflict-hit states where almost 200 health facilities have been closed or destroyed.
"It's a race against time to prevent the spread of cholera up the river Nile, especially during the rainy season. Our priority right now is reaching the most vulnerable children who urgently need clean water and vaccinations," Veitch said.
Health Minister Riek Gai Kok said last month that one of the casualties had died at a United Nations facility housing civilians seeking refuge from the civil war raging in the world's youngest nation state.
The conflict pits forces loyal to President Salva Kiir against rebels allied with former vice president Riek Machar, and more than 10,000 people have been killed since the fighting first erupted in December 2013.
The conflict has also created a humanitarian crisis, as more than 730,000 people have fled to neighboring countries and some 1.5 million people have been uprooted within the country, according to the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR.
At least 167 people died in South Sudan in a cholera outbreak last year, according to the World Health Organization.
(Reporting By Kieran Guilbert, Editing by Tim Pearce. Please credit the Thomson Reuters Foundation, the charitable arm of Thomson Reuters, that covers humanitarian news, women's rights, trafficking, corruption and climate change. Visit www.trust.org)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="6">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:04:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Al Shabaab gunmen kill 14 in attack on Kenyan workers</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/F-ak425FEpo/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MOMBASA, Kenya (Reuters) - Al Shabaab gunmen killed 14 people, mostly quarry workers, officials said, in an overnight attack on a residential complex in northeast Kenya that the Islamic militant group said had targeted Christians.</Description>
        <MainBody>Al Shabaab gunmen kill 14 in attack on Kenyan workers
MOMBASA, Kenya | By Joseph Akwiri
Kenyan police officers and Kenya Red Cross workers carry the body of a man killed during an overnight attack on a residential complex in Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
1 of 4
right
A man rests on a hospital bed as he awaits treatment after he was injured during an overnight attack on a residential complex in Soko Mbuzi village of Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
2 of 4
right
Kenya Defence Forces soldiers walk near the scene of an overnight attack on a residential complex in Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
3 of 4
right
Kenya Defence Forces soldiers and policemen gather at the entrance of a residential complex that was attacked in Soko Mbuzi village of Mandera town at the Kenya-Somalia border July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Stringer
4 of 4
right
MOMBASA, Kenya Al Shabaab gunmen killed 14 people, mostly quarry workers, officials said, in an overnight attack on a residential complex in northeast Kenya that the Islamic militant group said had targeted Christians.
Many died in their sleep, the Kenya Red Cross said. The raid, in the town of Mandera, mirrored one in the same county in December in which 36 quarry workers died.
Al Shabaab has made a series of deadly incursions into Kenya, which it says will continue until Nairobi withdraws its troops from an African Union force fighting the militants in their home base of Somalia.
The group's military operations spokesman, Sheikh Abdiasis Abu Musab, told Reuters its gunmen killed more than 10 Kenyan Christians in Tuesday's raid. It has in the past singled out non-Muslims to be executed.
"The area ... is a plot where quarry workers live. They attacked at around 1 a.m. Most of those killed are workers from upcountry," Alex Nkoyo, commissioner for Mandera County, told Reuters by phone. He put the death toll at 14.
Among the dead was a woman who had tried to plead with the gunmen before being shot, he said.
Abbas Gullet, the secretary general of Kenya Red Cross, said the workers were attacked as they slept, and that at least 11 people were wounded.
Tuesday's raid will heighten pressure on President Uhuru Kenyatta to beef up security in response to al Shabaab attacks, the worst of which killed 148 people at a university in eastern Kenya's Garissa County in April.
"This attack is a clear reminder that al Shabaab and its collaborators are determined to disrupt and subvert our way of life," Interior Minister Joseph Nkaisserry said in a statement.
He said security reacted swiftly to prevent a higher death toll after the group opened their attack by blowing up an entrance gate to the residential area.
After the Garissa attack, critics accused the security forces responding too slowly, one reason cited for the number killed in that attack.
Kenya's northeast border with Somalia is widely considered a security weak spot, given the challenge of policing such a long frontier, poor coordination between security services, and a culture of corruption that allows anyone prepared to pay a bribe to pass unchallenged.
Al Shabaab aims to topple Somalia's Western-backed government and wants to impose its own strict version of Islamic law on the country.
(Additional reporting by George Obulutsa in Nairobi; Writing by George Obulutsa and Edmund Blair ; Editing by Larry King)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="7">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 16:02:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Thousands brave Andean downpours in Ecuador for papal Mass</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/csQlc-k0XwY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>QUITO (Reuters) - Thousands of pilgrims braved wind and rain to camp out overnight for a Mass to be given by Pope Francis on Tuesday in Ecuador's highland capital Quito for an expected million people.</Description>
        <MainBody>Thousands brave Andean downpours in Ecuador for papal Mass
QUITO | By Girish Gupta
Pope Francis blesses faithfuls during his visit to the Presidential Palace in Quito, Ecuador, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Alessandro Bianchi
QUITO Thousands of pilgrims braved wind and rain to camp out overnight for a Mass to be given by Pope Francis on Tuesday in Ecuador's highland capital Quito for an expected million people.
Political protests had been rocking the socialist-ruled nation of 15 million people prior to the pontiff's arrival, but his presence has brought a temporary halt to demonstrations.
Francis is visiting three of the smallest and poorest nations during a week-long tour of his native South America.
At the Bicentenario Park, a former airport where he was due to give Mass mid-morning, some bedraggled faithful camped out for two nights in the extremes of Andean weather - torrential rain, biting wind and blazing sun.
For some, it became too much and at least one fight broke out as people attempted to push in.
Yet most thought the wait worthwhile.
"He is somebody who has really changed the church, changed young people's way of thinking," said Veronica Calderon, a 23-year-old civil engineering student who had arrived at six in the morning the day before the Mass.
"He's not been afraid to be tough with those who are corrupt, those who have damaged the church."
Hawkers walked up and down the lines selling wooden crosses, flags and t-shirts made especially for the trip as well as food and drink. Many used umbrellas to shield themselves both from the downpours and blazing sun when the rain cleared.
CORREA MEETING
Argentine-born Francis spent most of Monday in the coastal city of Guayaquil, delivering a Mass to some 800,000 people before going to a Jesuit-run school to visit a friend he had not seen for three decades.
In the evening, Francis flew back to Quito and met with leftist President Rafael Correa at the presidential palace, specially adorned with 120,000 roses, before blessing those gathered in the square below.
Recent protests over tax hikes have marred the visit somewhat for Correa, though demonstrators declared a moratorium during the trip as a mark of respect.
The pope flies on Wednesday to La Paz, Bolivia, another highland city where oxygen tanks are kept at the airport for arriving passengers who may struggle with the thin air.
That will focus attention on the 78-year-old pope's health as he had part of one lung removed when he was younger after a serious infection.
In Bolivia, Francis is to visit a notoriously violent prison before going to Paraguay where he will meet with social activists.
"It's very important for us that the pope is Latin American. It shows that faith is universal," said Victor Hugo Lobato, a 43-year-old teacher who camped out with his family overnight at the Quito park after a bus trip through the previous night.
Not all in Latin America are impressed with the church. Some say it has curbed progress on issues including women's and gay rights in a traditionally macho region.
"It's not good that the church has so much weight in political decisions," said Andres Caicedo, 35, spokesman for the Ecuadorean Atheist Association.
"It's also inappropriate that in a country that is supposedly secular, we spend so much money on such a visit."
(Editing by Andrew Cawthorne and Jeffrey Benkoe)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="8">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:26:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Afghan president says peace delegation meeting Taliban in Pakistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/whZkm9cXYq0/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - The Afghan government has sent a peace delegation to Pakistan for negotiations with the Taliban, the president's office said in a statement on Twitter on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Afghan president says peace delegation meeting Taliban in Pakistan
KABUL
Afghanistan President Ashraf Ghani speaks during a news conference in Kabul, Afghanistan May 11, 2015.
Reuters/Mohammad Ismail/Files
KABUL The Afghan government has sent a peace delegation to Pakistan for negotiations with the Taliban, the president's office said in a statement on Twitter on Tuesday.
The meeting could be a step towards starting a formal peace process with the insurgent group that was ousted from power by a U.S. led invasion in 2001.
(Reporting by Kabul bureau, Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="9">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:20:27 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Turkish opposition accuses Erdogan of stalling on government mandate</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/D89FSyR-T3w/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ANKARA (Reuters) - Turkish opposition MPs accused President Tayyip Erdogan on Tuesday of stalling efforts to form a coalition government as he seeks to maintain his grip on power, a month after the AK Party he founded lost its parliamentary majority.</Description>
        <MainBody>Turkish opposition accuses Erdogan of stalling on government mandate
ANKARA | By Gulsen Solaker and Ercan Gurses
Turkey's President Tayyip Erdogan greets parliamentarians as he arrives at the Turkish parliament to watch a swearing-in ceremony in Ankara, Turkey, June 23, 2015
Reuters/Umit Bektas
ANKARA Turkish opposition MPs accused President Tayyip Erdogan on Tuesday of stalling efforts to form a coalition government as he seeks to maintain his grip on power, a month after the AK Party he founded lost its parliamentary majority.
The June 7 vote left the AKP unable to rule alone for the first time in over a decade, plunging Turkey into political uncertainty not seen since the 1990s and thwarting for now Erdogan's ambition to amass greater power.
Formal coalition talks cannot begin until Erdogan gives Prime Minister Ahmet Davutoglu the mandate to form a new government, at which point he has 45 days to do so or face the prospect of another election.
Some opposition MPs have suggested Erdogan is stalling to sow opposition disarray and to ensure the AKP is still firmly in power for a High Military Council (YAS) meeting in August, where key army commanders are appointed.
"He wants the changes to be made at the YAS to be done by him alone without debate, with the old cabinet and the old political climate," Ozgur Ozel, an MP with the main opposition Republican People's Party (CHP), told Reuters.
"He thinks the slow process will trigger disputes in the opposition, rather than in his own party," he said, adding the aim was to boost AKP support in case of another election.
Reining in a military which forced four governments from power in the second half of the 20th Century was one of Erdogan's priorities during his 12 years as prime minister.
YAS meetings - at which retirements, transfers and disciplinary actions are decided - were a key element of that process. The current head of the armed forces, General Necdet Ozel, is set to retire at the August meeting.
Deputy Prime Minister Numan Kurtulmus poured cold water on claims of a deliberate delay, telling broadcaster Haberturk on Tuesday that Erdogan would "most probably" give the mandate to Davutoglu this week.
Davutoglu meanwhile last week rejected suggestions that the AKP would wait until after the YAS to form a new government, while Erdogan himself has said he will only give the mandate once parliament's new administration is in place.
A speaker was elected last week but an administrative board is yet to be agreed.
As president, Erdogan is constitutionally bound to remain above party politics but effectively turned the June election into a referendum on his ambitions for an executive presidency, campaigning around the country.
He chaired a cabinet meeting in his controversial new palace on Monday, something which opposition parties have said must end if they are to enter any coalition.
"The president has given the message since the beginning that 'this process will advance under my control'," Meral Danis Bestas, deputy chairwoman of the pro-Kurdish Peoples' Democratic Party (HDP), told Reuters.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="10">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:17:23 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Two Taliban attacks in Afghan capital kill one, wound three</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/5awa22cA6UQ/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>KABUL (Reuters) - Taliban suicide bomb attacks in Afghanistan's capital targeted a convoy of foreign troops and a compound of the country's intelligence agency, wounding three people and killing at least one, Afghan and foreign officials said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Two Taliban attacks in Afghan capital kill one, wound three
KABUL | By Mirwais Harooni and Hamid Shalizi
KABUL Taliban suicide bomb attacks in Afghanistan's capital targeted a convoy of foreign troops and a compound of the country's intelligence agency, wounding three people and killing at least one, Afghan and foreign officials said on Tuesday.
Taliban and other insurgents have stepped up attacks on Afghan and foreign forces this year, after most coalition troops withdrew from Afghanistan at the end of 2014.
As security has deteriorated, some Afghan districts have fallen under Taliban control. A growing presence of forces loyal to Islamic State has fueled concern that parts of the country are slipping out of Kabul's grasp.
In the first attack, late on Tuesday morning, a suicide car bomber slammed into a land cruiser carrying foreign forces in the Shah Shaheed area of eastern Kabul, wounding at least two people, Afghan and foreign officials said.
The cruiser caught fire after the explosion, said an Afghan security official at the scene. The blast blew the vehicle off course and into a wall, leaving behind an empty, charred hulk.
"I can confirm that a suicide car bomber targeted foreign forces," interior ministry spokesman Sediq Sediqqi told Reuters.
In a statement, the coalition said there were no fatalities from the attack, but declined to give details.
A foreigner and a bystander were wounded in the incident, a police spokesman, Ebadullah Karimi, said.
In the second attack, Taliban insurgents raided a compound used by Afghanistan's intelligence agency, Karimi said, killing one security guard and wounding another.
"Three suicide bombers were involved in the attack," he added. "One detonated his explosives, two were shot dead by security forces."
On Twitter, the Taliban claimed responsibility for both attacks, which came a week after last Tuesday's strike by a suicide bomber on a convoy of U.S. troops close to the U.S. embassy.
About 9,800 U.S troops remain in Afghanistan, down from a peak of around 100,000 in 2011. The majority are training Afghan forces but a few thousand are still engaged in combat operations against the Taliban and others.
On a visit to Kabul on Saturday, U.S. Senator John McCain of Arizona called for U.S. troops to stay longer than planned to prevent gains by the militants.
The current schedule is for the military to draw down to an embassy presence by the end of 2016.
(Writing by Jessica Donati; Editing by Kay Johnson and Clarence Fernandez)
A member of the Afghan security forces investigates next to a destroyed vehicle at the site of a suicide attack in Kabul, Afghanistan July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Mohammad Ismail
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="11">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:16:15 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Judge quits Cambodia's troubled Khmer Rouge trials</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/SN4QGBf6CdA/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>PHNOM PENH (Reuters) - An international judge announced his resignation from the U.N.-backed war crimes trials in Cambodia on Tuesday, the fourth to quit so far and another blow for the troubled tribunal probing the atrocities of the 1970s Khmer Rouge regime.</Description>
        <MainBody>Judge quits Cambodia's troubled Khmer Rouge trials
PHNOM PENH
Multi-colored bracelets commemorating Khmer Rouge victims are tied on poles at a former mass graves site at Choeung Ek, a ''Killing Fields'' site located on the outskirts of Phnom Penh July 2, 2015.
Reuters/Samrang Pring
PHNOM PENH An international judge announced his resignation from the U.N.-backed war crimes trials in Cambodia on Tuesday, the fourth to quit so far and another blow for the troubled tribunal probing the atrocities of the 1970s Khmer Rouge regime.
Mark Harmon, from the United States, said in a statement his reasons for stepping down after three years in Phnom Penh were "strictly personal" and "with considerable regret". He did not elaborate.
Several of Harmon's predecessors at the hybrid United Nations-Cambodian court have alleged political interference and a lack of cooperation by Cambodia's government, which contains remnants of the Khmer Rouge regime.
Prime Minister Hun Sen, a former Khmer Rouge soldier, has warned more trials could cause anarchy and a return to civil war. He has promised to thwart new indictments and once said he would be happy if the U.N. packed up and left.
The decade-old tribunal has so far delivered verdicts involving three high-profile leaders from the 1975-1979 "killing fields" era. Attempts to pursue more cases have been met by strong government resistance.
Cambodian police have refused to act on an arrest warrant Harmon has issued for Meas Muth, a former navy chief alleged to have sent detainees to a torture center where some 14,000 people died.
Court spokesman Lars Olsen said Harmon's resignation was unrelated to any development in cases he was working on. Harmon would continue his role until his replacement was sworn in.
(Reporting by Prak Chan Thul; Editing by Martin Petty)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="12">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 15:06:08 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>China kicks off war commemorations with graphic exhibition</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/WdEjO_4aoVE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MARCO POLO BRIDGE, China (Reuters) - With dioramas of heroic Communist soldiers and graphic pictures of massacres, China formally kicked off its commemorations for the 70th anniversary of the end of World War Two on Tuesday with the unveiling of a new exhibition.</Description>
        <MainBody>China kicks off war commemorations with graphic exhibition
MARCO POLO BRIDGE, China | By Ben Blanchard
MARCO POLO BRIDGE, China With dioramas of heroic Communist soldiers and graphic pictures of massacres, China formally kicked off its commemorations for the 70th anniversary of the end of World War Two on Tuesday with the unveiling of a new exhibition.
Sino-Japan relations have long been affected by what China sees as Japan's failure to atone for its occupation of parts of the country before and during World War Two, and China rarely misses an opportunity to push that message.
The new exhibition, called "Great Victory, Historical Contribution", is located at a war museum next to the Marco Polo Bridge, the site of a skirmish in Beijing's outlying suburbs 78 years ago that sparked an all-out Sino-Japanese war.
Speaking in front of armed forces personnel, children and veterans, propaganda chief Liu Yunshan said people should draw inspiration from the "splendid annals" of the war.
"We must use this platform and classroom to guide officials and the people to draw sustenance from the hard struggles of the past," said Liu, who is ranked number five in the Communist Party's hierarchy.
The exhibition highlights some of the horrors of war, including a skull from a person killed in the 1937 Nanjing Massacre and a spiked metal cage used to torture captured Chinese.
Another picture shows a woman raped by Japanese soldiers and then disemboweled and dumped on the road.
Almost all the exhibits have English translations, underscoring the government's desire to get its message about Japanese brutality and Communist bravery to a worldwide audience.
The Communist Party's role is in sharp focus - exhibit captions are peppered with references to the reluctance or refusal of the Nationalist Chinese government to fight Japan.
In China's official narrative the contribution of Nationalist troops - who later fled to Taiwan after loosing a civil war with the Communists in 1949 - is barely mentioned.
Over the weekend, Taiwan's president said it was Nationalist Chinese forces who won the war, decrying attempts to "distort" history.
"Our exhibition clearly shows that our Communist Party was the cornerstone in the war to oppose Japanese aggression, and we have a lot facts here to show that," deputy museum director Luo Cunkang told reporters, when asked about the Taiwan comments.
China's commemorations will reach a crescendo in September with a parade of Chinese and Russian troops through central Beijing.
No senior Western leaders are expected to attend.
(Editing by Jeremy Laurence )
A picture showing a mother holding her son bombed by the Japanese troops in Wuhan, is displayed at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of Beijing, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jason Lee
1 of 5
right
A visitor stands above Japanese soldiers' weapons which were seized by the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) during World War Two, during a new exhibition at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on...
Reuters/Jason Lee
2 of 5
right
Students walk past statues at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of Beijing, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jason Lee
3 of 5
right
A visitor walks past pictures of Chinese Communist Party's top leaders (L-R) Mao Zedong, Deng Xiaoping, Jiang Zemin, Hu Jintao and Xi Jinping at the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of...
Reuters/Jason Lee
4 of 5
right
Chinese Communist Party's propaganda chief Liu Yunshan speaks at the opening ceremony of a new exhibition outside the Museum of the War of Chinese People's Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, near the Marco Polo Bridge on the outskirts of Beijing, July 7, 2015.
Reuters/Jason Lee
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="13">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:56:49 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Migrant sailboat sinks in Aegean, at least 17 missing</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/Oe0tqaoALDc/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>ATHENS (Reuters) - A sailboat carrying migrants sank in the Aegean sea between Turkey and Greece on Tuesday and at least 17 people were missing, Greek authorities said.</Description>
        <MainBody>Migrant sailboat sinks in Aegean, at least 17 missing
ATHENS
ATHENS A sailboat carrying migrants sank in the Aegean sea between Turkey and Greece on Tuesday and at least 17 people were missing, Greek authorities said.
Greece's maritime ministry said Greek and Turkish rescue efforts had saved 16 of the between 33 and 37 migrants believed to be on board when the boat went down between the Greek islands of Farmakonisi and Agathonisi.
Their nationalities were not known.
"The operation is ongoing," said a spokeswoman for Greece's maritime ministry. "We are still looking for 17 to 21 people."
More than 135,000 refugees and migrants have arrived in Europe by sea in the first half of this year, many of them fleeing war, repression and poverty in Africa and the Middle East. Most are Syrians.
Greece is the largest arrival point, putting a huge strain on the country as it wrestles with one of the worst economic crises of modern times.
(Reporting by Lefteris Karagiannopoulos; Writing by Matt Robinson; Editing by Andrew Heavens )
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="14">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:54:14 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Explosives stolen from army base in France</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/ZndWs-S-DP4/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>MARSEILLE (Reuters) - Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>Explosives stolen from army base in France
MARSEILLE
MARSEILLE Explosives, 180 detonators and around 40 grenades were stolen from an army base in the southern French town of Miramas, near Marseille, a source close to investigation said on Tuesday.
The theft came even though France has heightened security after a suspected Islamist beheaded his boss and tried to blow up a gas plant near Lyon on June 26. Six months earlier, gunmen killed 17 people at the offices of satirical weekly Charlie Hebdo and a Jewish foodstore in January.
The Marseille prosecution office has begun an investigation into the robbery, which was discovered on Monday. France's defense ministry ordered a review of the army's military supplies and the protection of ammunition storage units.
The Miramas site serves as a logistical base for the French army's external operations, the source said.
(Reporting by Francois Revilla, Nicolas Bertin, Chine Labbe, writing by Astrid Wendlandt; editing by Larry King)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="15">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:50:12 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Britain pays tribute to 7/7 victims 10 years after London bombings</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/CcIeMzs1jgY/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>LONDON (Reuters) - Prime Minister David Cameron led somber tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.</Description>
        <MainBody>LONDON | By Michael Holden
LONDON Prime Minister David Cameron led somber tributes on Tuesday as Britain commemorated the 10th anniversary of attacks that killed 56 people in London, the first suicide bombings by Islamist militants in western Europe.
Relatives of the victims, survivors, and senior politicians gathered to remember those killed in the July 7 2005 bombings with emotions still raw after a massacre in Tunisia last month, Britain's worst loss of life in a militant assault since London.
"Today the country comes together to remember the victims of one of the deadliest terrorist atrocities on mainland Britain," Cameron said in a statement.
"Ten years on from the 7/7 London attacks, the threat from terrorism continues to be as real as it is deadly  the murder of 30 innocent Britons whilst holidaying in Tunisia is a brutal reminder of that fact.But we will never be cowed by terrorism."
In the early hours of July 7 a decade ago, four young British Muslims traveled down to London where they detonated homemade bombs hidden in rucksacks on three underground trains and a bus during the morning rush-hour.
Inspired by al Qaeda, they killed themselves and 52 other people and wounded around 700 others. Citizens from Poland, Israel, Australia, France, Italy, Afghanistan, Nigeria, New Zealand and a Vietnamese-American were among the victims.
Cameron and London mayor Boris Johnson stood silently, heads bowed, before laying a wreath at the 7/7 memorial in Hyde Park. They will later join other senior figures, victims' families, survivors and members of the emergency services caught up in the bombings for a service of remembrance at St Paul's Cathedral.
This will include a national minute of silence, which comes just four days after Britain paid a similar tribute to those killed when an Islamist gunman opened fire at the Tunisian resort of Sousse.
"LEARNING LESSONS"
A further service will be held later at the memorial site for survivors and relatives which Prince William, Queen Elizabeth's grandson, will attend.
Esther Hyman, 46, whose sister Miriam was killed on the Number 30 bus when it was blown up at Tavistock Square, told Reuters many young people seemed unaware of the bombings.
"The events of 7/7 do seem to have slipped out of public consciousness," said Hyman, who with her mother last week  launched an educational program to help teach school pupils about the attacks and to steer them away from violent extremism.
"It's worth remembering an event like 7/7 and learning lessons from it so that it didn't happen in vain."
Britain is currently on its second highest alert level of "severe", meaning a militant attack is considered highly likely, mainly due to the danger the authorities say is posed by Islamic State (IS) fighters and Britons who have joined them.
Andrew Parker, head of Britain's domestic spy agency MI5,
said only a "tiny fraction of the population" posed a threat.
"But the continuing fact that some people, born in the UK, with all the opportunities and freedoms that modern Britain offers, can nonetheless make those sorts of warped choices presents a serious societal and security challenge," Parker said in a rare public statement.
The government plans new measures to counter extremism and Mark Rowley, Britain's most senior counter-terrorism police officer, said the country was better prepared than 10 years ago, although the threat itself had morphed.
He said IS was creating an "enormous" list of potential targets, focused on propaganda value.
A memorial plaque is attached to railings in Tavistock Square, in memory of those who lost their lives on a number 30 double-decker bus during the 7/7 attack in 2005, in London, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Peter Nicholls
1 of 3
right
A woman shows her emotions as she visits and pays her respects at the 7 July Memorial monument in Hyde Park, to those who lost their lives in the 7/7 attack in 2005, in London, Britain, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Peter Nicholls
2 of 3
right
Passers-by look at a memorial plaque attached to railings in Tavistock Square, in memory of those who lost their lives on a number 30 double-decker bus during the 7/7 attack in 2005, in London, Britain, July 6, 2015.
Reuters/Peter Nicholls
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="16">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:31:39 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Mystery deaths in India recruitment scam pressure Modi's party</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/6wrdQQSFlgw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>NEW DELHI (Reuters) - The deaths of a number of witnesses in a massive fraud case surrounding cheating at college and government jobs has become the latest source of discomfort for India's ruling party, already on the defensive over influence trafficking allegations.</Description>
        <MainBody>Mystery deaths in India recruitment scam pressure Modi's party
NEW DELHI | By Chiara Saldanha
Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi gestures while addressing the gathering during the launch of ''Digital India Week'' in New Delhi, India, July 1, 2015.
Reuters/Adnan Abidi
NEW DELHI The deaths of a number of witnesses in a massive fraud case surrounding cheating at college and government jobs has become the latest source of discomfort for India's ruling party, already on the defensive over influence trafficking allegations.
Investigators say thousands of people got jobs or medical degrees from systematic exam cheating that generated millions of dollars in bribes in the state of Madhya Pradesh.
At least 36 people connected to the case in the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) run state have died since the scam was first brought to light. More than 2,000 have been arrested in relation to the scam.
Four more people connected to the case have died since the weekend, just days before a Supreme Court hearing and amid opposition accusations that a regional unit of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's party was protecting the accused.
"They are not arresting the real culprits," said Vivek Tankha, a lawyer representing three whistle blowers who exposed the scam in 2013.
State Chief Minister Shivraj Singh Chouhan, a popular BJP leader, denies wrongdoing. But on Tuesday he buckled to pressure and said the inquiry should be handed to the Central Bureau of Investigation to avoid suspicion of political meddling.
The latest deaths included a national television journalist who began foaming at the mouth soon after interviewing the parents of Namrata Damor, a student who had obtained a college seat as part of the scam and was herself later found dead on train tracks in January 2012. The journalist died in hospital.
In the past few days, a policeman was found hanging from a ceiling fan, a trainee policewoman was found dead in a pond, and the dean of a college involved in the scam was found dead, with a half empty liquor bottle in a hotel room.
Chouhan denies accusations made by the opposition Congress party that he and other officials benefited from the fraud.
"There are very powerful big people involved in this," said the Congress party's Digvijaya Singh, a former Madhya Pradesh chief minister who wants the case be investigated by federal agents monitored by the Supreme Court.
On Tuesday, the Supreme Court said it would consider his petition along with several other relating to the case, at a hearing on July 9.
The scandal broke just as Indian media was lowering the pressure on the government over help given by the foreign minister and another regional leader to a controversial cricket-tycoon who fled a corruption probe and lives in London.
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="17">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:14:54 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Japan's Abe faces growing risk on security shift: opposition leader</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/do2Vk2kN7U8/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>TOKYO (Reuters) - Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe will be taking a big risk if he pushes through a dramatic change in security policy despite objections from most citizens, who want a better explanation why the change is needed, a top opposition figure said on Tuesday.</Description>
        <MainBody>TOKYO | By Linda Sieg
Japan's Prime Minister Shinzo Abe speaks to the media at his official residence in Tokyo in this photo taken by Kyodo March 19, 2015.
Reuters/Kyodo
TOKYO Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe will be taking a big risk if he pushes through a dramatic change in security policy despite objections from most citizens, who want a better explanation why the change is needed, a top opposition figure said on Tuesday.
Abe's ratings have slipped over the security policy shift, which could let Japanese troops fight abroad for the first time since Tokyo's defeat in World War Two, and which he hopes to enact into law in a parliament session that runs until Sept. 27.
The ruling bloc has a majority that would allow it to enact Abe's bills, but any perception of high-handedness could erode support further even as the prime minister eyes re-election as head of his Liberal Democratic Party in September.
"Ultimately, it depends on public opinion," Katsuya Okada, the head of the main opposition Democratic Party of Japan (DPJ), told Reuters, when asked if Abe's bloc could be kept from forcing a vote in parliament's lower house.
That step could come as soon as next week.
"Pressure on the administration is mounting," Okada, a former foreign minister, said in an interview.
Abe's support fell three points, to 42 percent, in a Mainichi newspaper survey published on Monday.
Sixty-one percent of respondents opposed passage of legislation in the current session to end a ban on exercising the right of collective self-defense, or militarily aiding a friendly country under attack.
"Basically, I think we face a choice between two paths," Okada added. Will we stick to the pacifism of the constitution or become a 'normal' country?"
Conservatives say Japan's post-war constitution puts limits on its ability to defend itself that are too severe. Proponents say it has kept the nation at peace, and reinterpreting it outside formal amendment procedures sets a dangerous precedent.
Okada, 61, acknowledged Japan faces a tough security climate and said collective self-defense might be a future option.
But conditions set in the bills were too abstract and there was a high likelihood it violated the constitution's pacifist Article 9, he said.
Some analysts say Abe's ratings could slip as much as 10 points if the bills go through, possibly encouraging a rival to challenge him in the LDP leadership race.
But the Democrats, ousted in 2012 after three rocky years in power, have made few gains. Seven percent backed the DPJ in the Mainichi poll, versus 31 percent for the LDP.
(Reporting by Linda Sieg; Editing by Clarence Fernandez)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="18">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 14:00:32 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>Drone strikes target Islamic State fighters in eastern Afghanistan</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/j_soAXdyTPE/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>Kabul (Reuters) - Two drone strikes targeted militants loyal to Islamic State in Afghanistan on Tuesday, killing between 25 and 49 insurgents, according to differing estimates by Afghan and foreign officials.</Description>
        <MainBody>Drone strikes target Islamic State fighters in eastern Afghanistan
Kabul
Kabul Two drone strikes targeted militants loyal to Islamic State in Afghanistan on Tuesday, killing between 25 and 49 insurgents, according to differing estimates by Afghan and foreign officials.
An increasing number of militants are pledging allegiance to the Islamic State in Afghanistan, making them a target of deadly strikes there by the U.S. unmanned aircraft.
A total of 49 militants were killed in the strikes in the eastern province of Nangarhar, which targeted the village of Mamd Dara in Achin district, where the fighters routinely held gatherings, a spokesman for the governor said.
"The first drone strike took place at 12 a.m. on Monday... the second one happened at 02:00 p.m," said Ahmad Zia Abdulzai.
However, the foreign official, who asked not to be named in order to be able to speak freely, said the number of dead was believed to be closer to 25.
One of the most high profile figures to have been targeted in drone strikes so far was former Guantanamo Bay detainee Mullah Abdul Rauf, who had defected to Islamic State and was killed by a strike in southern Helmand province in February.
(Reporting by Mirwais Harooni; Editing by Jessica Donati and Clarence Fernandez)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
    <Article id="19">
        <date>Tue Jul 07 13:57:45 EEST 2015</date>
        <title>First victims of deadliest migrant shipwreck given funeral in Italy</title>
        <Link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/worldNews/~3/gC_fHExHFCw/story01.htm</Link>
        <Description>CATANIA, Italy (Reuters) - Italy held a funeral service on Tuesday for 13 migrants who died in the worst shipwreck in the Mediterranean in recent history, while the navy continued its search for other victims of the disaster.</Description>
        <MainBody>First victims of deadliest migrant shipwreck given funeral in Italy
CATANIA, Italy
CATANIA, Italy Italy held a funeral service on Tuesday for 13 migrants who died in the worst shipwreck in the Mediterranean in recent history, while the navy continued its search for other victims of the disaster.
More than 700 people, most of them locked below deck, were believed to have drowned in April. Their overloaded fishing boat capsized after colliding with a ship that had come to their aid some 70 nautical miles off the coast of Libya.
The Italian navy last week retrieved the first bodies from the wreck, which is lying at a depth of about 370 meters (1,200 feet), using remote-controlled vehicles and a submersible basket to haul up the remains.
With the recovery mission still in full swing, simple wooden coffins carrying the bodies of 13 unidentified migrants were carried into the Palazzo della Cultura in Catania, in eastern Sicily, for an inter-religious service.
"Today, we are gathering here to mark the loss of the lives of other human beings, taken away by the sea. Every time it happens we think it is the last time, but unfortunately that is not the case," said Ismail Bouchafa, the imam of Catania.
The bodies were later taken to Catania cemetery but were not immediately buried. The authorities are still deciding where all the victims should be interred.
Tens of thousands of migrants have crossed the Mediterranean so far this year in the hope of reaching Italy or Greece. An estimated 2,000 have drowned.
(Reporting by Antonio Parrinello, writing by Isla Binnie; Editing by Crispian Balmer and Digby Lidstone)
Our top photos from the past 24 hours. Slideshow 
Trending On Reuters
</MainBody>
    </Article>
</site>
